<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271810" id="root" date="1996-12-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italians bid tearful farewell to Mastroianni.</title>
<headline>Italians bid tearful farewell to Mastroianni.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Donovan</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marcello Mastroianni returned home on Saturday as thousands of Romans paid their last respects to the actor who immortalised their city's exuberance in &quot;La Dolce Vita&quot;.</p>
<p>Friends and fans streamed to Rome's Capitoline city hall to bid farewell to Mastroianni, who died of cancer in Paris on Thursday at the age of 72.</p>
<p>His body was flown back to Rome earlier on Saturday and will lie in state in the Michelangelo-designed palace until a civil funeral on Sunday at his family tomb in Rome.</p>
<p>&quot;Mastroianni was a great interpreter of Italian art and as an ambassador of this art in the world, he showed exemplary humanity,&quot; said President Oscar Luigi Scalfaro, who was one of the first to file past the simple wooden coffin.</p>
<p>&quot;He was a prince,&quot; added French actress Catherine Deneuve, with whom Mastroianni had a love affair and a daughter, Chiara.</p>
<p>Deneuve, Chiara, Mastroianni's wife Flora -- whom he never divorced -- their daughter Barbara and Anna-Maria Tato, his companion of the last 22 years, sat watching as the public poured into the city hall.</p>
<p>Mastroianni starred in some 160 films opposite many of cinema's most beautiful women but he always rejected the &quot;Latin lover&quot; label.</p>
<p>He will be remembered above all as a warm, humble man.</p>
<p>&quot;He was magnificent professional and an honest man with a heart of gold,&quot; opera superstar Luciano Pavarotti was quoted as telling AGI news agency from Prague.</p>
<p>Mastroianni made 12 movies with Italian diva Sophia Loren but was best known for his role in Federico Fellini's 1960 &quot;La Dolce Vita&quot; (The Sweet Life).</p>
<p>Mastroianni starred in other films by Fellini, who died in 1993, but it was &quot;La Dolce Vita&quot; that secured him stardom as a reporter who chronicles the decadant life of contemporary Rome.</p>
<p>&quot;The sweet life for a long time meant a crazy, frivolous life,&quot; said Rome mayor Francesco Rutelli. &quot;But Mastroianni brought home the literal meaning of the term. He was a man of great irony, moderation and joy de vivre.&quot;</p>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi paid tribute to the actor at city hall, as did directors Michelangelo Antonioni, Marco Risi and Citto Maselli and musician Manuel De Sica.</p>
<p>Mastroianni had been active until the very end, starring in Milan in a play called &quot;Le Ultime Lune&quot; (The Last Moons), a work by Italian dramatist Furio Bordon that talks about old age.</p>
<p>&quot;Six days ago he told me he was sorry he had to interrupt the play but that we would start working again soon,&quot; Giulio Bosetti, the play's director, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;He knew what was happening but wanted to show he didn't believe it, that he still wanted to do theatre,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
