<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271857" id="root" date="1996-12-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Danish court jails biker for gang murder.</title>
<headline>Danish court jails biker for gang murder.</headline>
<byline>Steve Weizman</byline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-12-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two members of a Hell's Angels motorcycle gang were found gulty by a Danish jury on Friday night of murdering a rival gang leader but judges freed one of them, saying that his conviction was improper.</p>
<p>The panel of three judges jailed Michael Brokside, 23, for 16 years for the March 1996 killing of the head of the rival Bandidos gang and the attempted murder of five of his companions in an ambush at Copenhagen airport.</p>
<p>But the judges set free 34-year-old Joergen Nielsen, who faced the same charges, refusing to ratify a guilty verdict returned by the jury against him in defiance of their directions.</p>
<p>The airport shooting turned a festering vendetta between the Hell's Angels and the Bandidos into full-blooded war in which the rivals blasted each other with machine-guns, hand grenades, bombs and anti-tank missiles across the Nordic region.</p>
<p>After a six-week trial conducted amid the tightest security ever seen at a Danish court, the jury also convicted Kim Jensen, 29, and Ove Witthoeft, 32, on three counts of attempted murder. Jensen was jailed for eight years and Witthoeft for six.</p>
<p>The court cleared Johnny Nielsen and Svend 'The Swine' Holst of murder or attempted murder but found Holst guilty of weapons offences. He was given a six-momth jail term but was freed as he had already been in custody since March awaiting trial.</p>
<p>All six defednants remained impassive as the verdicts were read out, witnesses said.</p>
<p>During the trial, spectators were screened by a metal detector and scrutinised by officers familiar with the gangs, ready to weed out known bikers with criminal records.</p>
<p>Streets around the building were closed to traffic, court officials, including the three judges, wore special security badges and police bomb experts and their dogs swept the court before each sitting.</p>
<p>The biker feud claimed its first fatality in February 1994 when a member of the Hell's Angels-affiliated Rednecks was killed in a gunfight with Bandidos in the Swedish port of Helsingborg.</p>
<p>Two more Bandidos were killed in the following two years, in Sweden and in Finland, but the fighting took on a new intensity on March 10 this year.</p>
<p>Gunmen outside Copenhagen international airport shot dead Danish Bandidos leader Uffe Larsen and wounded three of his companions as they waited to meet fellow-members returning from a visit to Helsinki.</p>
<p>At almost the same time, an attacker in Norway shot and wounded a Bandido arriving at Oslo's Fornebu airport. Police arrested a member of a Hell's Angels-allied gang.</p>
<p>A Danish Bandido was shot dead newar the Norwegian city of Drammen in July.</p>
<p>Last October, as Danish legislators put the finishing touches to legislation to clamp down on the warring gangs, an anti-tank missile was fired into Hell's Angels central Copenhagen clubhouse when it was packed with partygoers.</p>
<p>A gang member and a woman party guest were killed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
