<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271934" id="root" date="1996-12-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-PATRIOTS EDGE GIANTS 23-22, RAMS NIP SAINTS.</title>
<headline>NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-PATRIOTS EDGE GIANTS 23-22, RAMS NIP SAINTS.</headline>
<dateline>EAST RUTHERFORD, N.J. 1996-12-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New England Patriots rallied from 22 points down to beat the New York Giants 23-22 on Saturday, clinch the AFC title and a first-round bye in the playoffs.</p>
<p>And in St Louis, in the season finale for both teams, The St Louis rams beat the New Orleans Saints 14-13.</p>
<p>Patriots' quarterback Drew Bledsoe, who had a miserable first half -- 12-of-20 for just 64 yards and two interceptions -- stormed back in the second half to finish 31-of-47 and 301 yards and two touchdowns. Bledsoe has thrown for more than 4,000 yards this season.</p>
<p>&quot;(In the playoffs) we know that we can't go out and play like we did in the first half. A playoff team that gets ahead 22-0 won't let us back in the game.&quot;</p>
<p>New England coach Bill Parcells, in his fourth year as Patriots coach, faced his former team for the first time at Giants Stadium. Parcells was 71-49-1 in eight years with the Giants, guiding them to victories in Super Bowl XXI and XXV.</p>
<p>&quot;I was a little emotional because I wasn't sure how I was going to react,&quot; Parcells said, &quot;but it's just very gratifying and not because it's the Giants doesn't make it sweeter. I just mean it's gratifying to see these kids rally back and do what they did today.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We were lucky to get our of here alive. Our guys regrouped and played with champions' hearts. I'm proud of them. The bye is important, very important.&quot;</p>
<p>The game also may mark the departure of Dan Reeves as Giants' coach. Reeves said earlier this week that he believed his coaching days with the Giants were coming to an end.</p>
<p>Bledsoe and Ben Coates gave New England its first lead of the game, 23-22, when they hooked up on a 13-yard touchdown with 1:23 remaining.  Bledsoe hit Coates at the 2 on a 4th-and-7, and the big tight end fought off a pair of Giant defenders to fall into the end zone.</p>
<p>&quot;There's not enough balls to go around for everybody so hey, I'm just a guy that waiting, willing to get my chance and trying to take advantage of it,&quot; Coates said.</p>
<p>New York saw its final opportunity go by when Thomas Lewis dropped a pass from Dave Brown at the first down mark on a 3rd and 21 with 13 seconds remaining.</p>
<p>Brown was 14-of-34 for 215 yards and an interception. The Giants managed only four first downs in the second half.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a tremendous disappointment. When you blow a 22-point lead, it is always disappointing,&quot; said Reeves. &quot;It signifies how the whole season has gone. You have tremendous highs and tremendous lows. The first half was a tremendous high and the second half was a tremendous low.&quot;</p>
<p>New York has now had consecutive losing seasons for the first time since the 1979-80 season.</p>
<p>The Rams' Jamie Martin replaced injured Tony Banks and threw two touchdown passes, including a 15-yarder to Eddie Kennison with 5:30 to play to take the Rams past the Saints.</p>
<p>Martin was 12-of-19 for 132 yards and one interception in the game, which was the season finale for both teams.</p>
<p>The final score was set up when Kennison's 10-yard punt return gave the Rams possession at the Saints 33. Martin kept the drive alive with an eight-yard pass to Harold Green on 3rd-and-7. He capped the six-play drive with his toss to a wide-open Kennison in the right corner of the end zone.</p>
<p>Isaac Bruce had seven receptions for 97 yards and a touchdown for St. Louis (6-10), which closed the season by winning three of four and may have saved coach Rich Brooks' job.</p>
<p>Jim Everett was 17-of-26 for 156 yards for the Saints (3-13), who ended the season with eight losses in their last nine games.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EAST RUTHERFORD, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
