<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272064" id="root" date="1996-12-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru rebels promises more hostage releases.</title>
<headline>Peru rebels promises more hostage releases.</headline>
<byline>Michael Stott</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-12-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marxist rebels promised on Saturday to continue freeing captives in Peru's hostage crisis during a dramatic walkie-talkie conversation with live television.</p>
<p>Speaking via two-way radio from the rebel-occupied Japanese ambassador's residence with Peru's Channel Four, a man identifying himself as rebel leader Nestor Cerpa said:</p>
<p>&quot;The majority (of the hostages) who are not tied to the politics of the government we are going to free gradually and (for) those who are connected to government functions everything will depend on the will of the government.&quot;</p>
<p>He set no date or time for the releases.</p>
<p>Communication between the rebels holding about 340 hostages and the TV station was established after a notice was held up to a window of the residence telling the channel to seek them on a certain radio frequency.</p>
<p>To prove he was a rebel inside the residence, the man then gave the microphone to Peru's hostage Foreign Minister Francisco Tudela and then to captive Japanese ambassador Morihisa Aoki.</p>
<p>Reporters who know Tudela said his voice and choice of words sounded genuine.</p>
<p>Police identified Cerpa as the leader of the around 20 heavily armed Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels who seized the residence last Tuesday and seized an array of high-ranking hostages including two ministers and Peru's anti- terrorism chief.</p>
<p>The rebel's words threw doubt on the authenticity of an earlier phone call to a radio station that said absolutely all the captives would be freed at 10 pm on December 24.</p>
<p>Authorities were not been able to confirm that the earlier phone call was genuine and the rebels themselves held up a notice at a residence window after reports of the call to say their phone lines had been cut.</p>
<p>Tudela said he was being well-treated by the rebels and urged President Alberto Fujimori's government to establish communications with the guerrillas to negotiate a solution.</p>
<p>He said he believed the MRTA was willing to reach a peaceful end to the crisis through negotiation but cautioned that the guerrillas were well-trained and well-armed.</p>
<p>Aoki, sounding nervous and speaking in broken Spanish, also said it was essential that the government and the MRTA negotiate.</p>
<p>The rebels' promise came as the ordeal for the hostages in Peru began a fifth day with no sign of serious negotiations about ending it.</p>
<p>A top doctor said the captives faced a possible cholera epidemic from their foul conditions but Fujimori's government stuck to its hard line.</p>
<p>Red Cross spokesman Bigler told Reuters earlier in the day that as far as he knew, no serious negotiations had started between the two sides about ending the siege.</p>
<p>Talks about humanitarian issues such as supplies of food and water have been going on but Bigler said he knew of no government message to the guerrillas via the Red Cross.</p>
<p>Well-known for his strongarm tactics, Fujimori turned down all of the MRTA's demands.</p>
<p>For their part, the roughly 20 heavily armed rebels repeated several times they will not give in until the government sets free more than 400 of their jailed comrades, some of whom were serving life sentences.</p>
<p>As a gesture of good faith the guerrillas released 38 hostages on Friday night into the arms of weeping relatives, some of whom hurled themselves onto the roofs of ambulances in their desperation to embrace their loved ones.</p>
<p>Victims still in the building on Saturday were suffering from stinking overcrowded toilets, poor food, stifling heat and a lack of room after a fourth night sleeping on the floor in crumpled and smelly suits, Red Cross officials said.</p>
<p>A Peruvian television station on Saturday showed a photograph of hostages inside the ambassador's residence.</p>
<p>The Channel 5 photograph showed at least seven men, some sitting on chairs or the floor and some standing, dressed in elegant shirts and pants and looking relaxed.</p>
<p>The television station did not say when the still was taken nor how it was obtained. None of the hostages in the photograph was identified.</p>
<p>Fujimori, closeted with generals and security advisers, gave no sign of relaxing his hawkish stance.</p>
<p>He has not made any public comment since the crisis broke but did meet a small group of local newspaper editors on Friday in private to say he had no plans to even talk to the rebels.</p>
<p>Around 900 armed police and special forces were surrounding the residence. Behind the building, a fleet of 20 ambulances waits with engines running and doctors on board.</p>
<p>In Washington, Defense Secretary William Perry declined comment on Saturday when asked about unspecified reports that elite U.S. Delta Force commandos were ready to move to help rescue the hostages.</p>
<p>&quot;Several hundred people whose lives are at stake in that hostage operation down in Peru -- and I will not comment on any action that is planned or not planned relative to dealing with that. Simply because lives of people are at stake,&quot; Perry said in a videotaped interview on CNN.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
