<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272012" id="root" date="1996-12-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Squash-Hill gets three-month ban and fine.</title>
<headline>Squash-Hill gets three-month ban and fine.</headline>
<dateline>CARDIFF 1996-12-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Anthony Hill has been banned for three months and fined 1,400 pounds sterling ($2,330) by the Professional Squash Association under their code of conduct.</p>
<p>World number nine Hill's punishment follows incidents in the World Open in Karachi in November and the Mahindra International Challenge in Bombay earlier this month.</p>
<p>Hill will be under probation for all of 1997, during which time further significant breaches of the PSA code will result in an automatic one-year ban from the PSA circuit, plus a fine of 2,000 pounds ($3,340) .</p>
<p>John Nimick, executive director of the Cardiff-based PSA, said on Saturday: &quot;We have had lengthy discussions with Hill following his actions in Pakistan and India, and have made it clear that this behaviour is unacceptable to the PSA Board and its members.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that we have taken appropriate action, with the threat of the most severe penalty ever imposed by the PSA should he step out of line during the following 12 months.&quot;</p>
<p>In the World Open, Hill was involved in public clashes with the referee Munir Shah and the tournament director Hassan Musa, and in Bombay he refused to play on in a first round match after a heated exchange with referee Gavin White.</p>
<p>Almost exactly a year ago, Hill received a similar penalty from the PSA disciplinary panel after misbehaviour in the World Open in Cyprus.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARDIFF"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
