<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272076" id="root" date="1996-12-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Four die in Colombian transport plane crash.</title>
<headline>Four die in Colombian transport plane crash.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-12-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A small cargo plane transporting newspapers crashed in northwest Colombia, killing four people, officials said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Russian-made twin-motor Antonov aircraft crashed late Saturday just a minute before it was scheduled to land at Rionegro airport, near Medellin, Colombia's third largest city.</p>
<p>Luis Fernando Duque, head of the Red Cross in Antioquia province, where the accident occurred, said all on board, three men and a woman, died on impact.</p>
<p>&quot;Nearby inhabitants said they heard a plane flying very low overhead then there was a loud bang followed by an explosion. It is not yet clear, however, what caused the crash,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The aircraft was owned by a company called Selva and transported daily newspapers from the capital Bogota to Medellin.</p>
<p>At the end of last month, a Canadian-built twin Otter plane ploughed into a mountain minutes after taking off from Enrique Oyala Herrera airport, Medellin's second airport. All but onbe of the 15 people on board were killed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
