<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272134" id="root" date="1996-12-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippines' Ramos back to hospital for checks.</title>
<headline>Philippines' Ramos back to hospital for checks.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-12-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine President Fidel Ramos was admitted to hospital for the second time in 10 days on Sunday for follow-up tests after being previously stricken with a throat infection, doctors said.</p>
<p>News that 68-year-old Ramos had returned to the Makati Medical Centre for further checks spread after he cancelled some of his engagements for the day.</p>
<p>Some hospital staff initially denied he was back at the centre.</p>
<p>&quot;We are doing more X-rays...because there were many things we saw during the previous check,&quot; hospital director Raul Fores said by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;All the tests are okay ... His blood chemistry is much better,&quot; Fores said, adding previous tests had shown Ramos had a &quot;very high&quot; level of cholesterol.</p>
<p>He said the president &quot;had been eating too much,&quot; accounting for the high cholesterol.</p>
<p>Fores said he expected Ramos to leave on Monday.</p>
<p>Presidential press undersecretary Marcelo Lagmay said Ramos was re-admitted to the hospital &quot;for a follow-up examination, for a series of X-rays.&quot; Lagmay said a medical bulletin on the president's condition was being prepared but no bulletin had been issued up to late Sunday night.</p>
<p>Ramos set off alarm bells on Manila's bourse and corporate boardrooms when he was admitted to the hospital on December 12 and some newspapers reported he had suffered a mild stroke.</p>
<p>He was released three days later after being treated for what Fores said a throat infection.</p>
<p>Ramos resumed a heavy schedule of speaking engagements and other public appearances shortly after he checked out, apparently to scotch the rumours of serious ill-health.</p>
<p>Doctors urged him to slow down, saying he was not young any more, and Ramos cancelled a series of provincial trips.</p>
<p>He told his weekly news conference on Wednesday he was in good health and that jitters in the stock market over his health appeared to be over.</p>
<p>Ramos's hospital spells coincided with a controversy over calls by a citizens' group to amend the constitution to allow him to run for re-election when his six-year term ends in June 1998. The constitution limits a president to a single term.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
