<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272190" id="root" date="1996-12-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks seen on bumpy ride to highs - poll.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks seen on bumpy ride to highs - poll.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Genevieve</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The road to new record highs could be a bumpy one for Hong Kong stocks next year, with interest rate uncertainty and rotation within Asian markets likely to lead to increased volatility, analysts said.</p>
<p>In a Reuters poll, analysts said the Hang Seng blue chip index should continue to hit all-time highs throughout 1997, spurred by earnings growth and an improving Chinese economy.</p>
<p>But the possibility of higher interest rates could prompt a decline below current levels along the way.</p>
<p>&quot;The jury is still out on interest rates and that is really the cornerstone to any investment decision for Hong Kong,&quot; said Steven Thompson, chief analyst at Nikko Research Center.</p>
<p>Nikko expects the Hang Seng index to fluctuate between 12,000 and 15,000 points next year. The index ended at 13,131.41 points on Friday, 30.4 percent higher than at the end of 1995.</p>
<p>Janice Wallace, executive director at Goldman Sachs, said U.S. interest rates could rise by 100 basis points over the course of 1997. &quot;We expect the first half will be dominated by concerns over rising interest rates,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Gary Greenberg, deputy managing director at Peregrine Asset Management, said Wall Street stocks were likely to undergo &quot;a nasty correction&quot; during the first quarter of next year. &quot;The first quarter is going to be very volatile,&quot; he said, adding that the Hang Seng index could fall to 10,500 to 10,800 points.</p>
<p>The possibility of government measures to curb speculation in Hong Kong's buoyant property market may also cause some weakness in the territory's leading property stocks, he said.</p>
<p>Some analysts said investors may start to look towards other Asian markets in 1997. &quot;All the money comes in initially to Hong Kong because that is where it can get invested fast. Then it starts to work its way round the region,&quot; said Alan Hutcheson, director of research at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>He said an expansion in global trade would lead to a pick up in earnings growth in some Asian markets. &quot;1996 has been a tough year for Asian exports and any pick up there is really going to benefit places like Indonesia, Malaysia, Korea and Taiwan.&quot;</p>
<p>Lehman Brothers senior strategist Abhijit Chakrabortti saw a shakeout in Hong Kong stocks, bringing the index to about 11,800 points by the end of 1997. He said investors were likely to seek safe havens in markets like Malaysia and Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;Having locked into two years of strong equity performance in Hong Kong, by taking profits at these levels they are likely to try and seek safe havens rather than try to look for further big leaps in returns,&quot; Chakraborrti said.</p>
<p>However, Pauline Gately, regional strategist at Merrill Lynch, said that while other Asian markets like South Korea and Thailand may benefit from fund flows in the second half of 1997, flows into Hong Kong should also increase from China and international investors. &quot;Perhaps Hong Kong's marked outperformance will be a little bit less,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Most analysts polled said that by the time Britain hands Hong Kong to China on midnight of June 30, 1997, the Hang Seng should be higher.</p>
<p>&quot;The political risk which has been attached to the market is gradually being unwound and will continue as it becomes clear that China is interested in managing its investment in Hong Kong intelligently,&quot; said Greenberg.</p>
<p>The impact of China's improving economy and liquidity flows from China to Hong Kong should buoy local stocks, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;China is in re-acceleration mode,&quot; said Gately. &quot;We have seen that there is a lot of money sloshing around in China so the idea is that some of that will find its way into Hong Kong.&quot;</p>
<p>Kwong expected earnings growth of 15 percent in Hong Kong in 1997 compared with 12 percent in 1996 and said with political fears subsiding, stocks merited a re-rating to about 16 times 1997 earnings, compared with a current 13 times.</p>
<p>The following are analysts' forecasts for the Hang Seng at the end of March 1997, the end of June 1997 and the end of 1997:</p>
<p>				     end-March   end-June   end-1997</p>
<p> Asia Equity			13,750	13,500	14,750</p>
<p> Deutsche Morgan Grenfell     14,000	14,000	14,500</p>
<p> Dharmala Securities	    14,800	15,500	16,000</p>
<p> Goldman Sachs		    13,000	14,000	15,800</p>
<p> HSBC James Capel		 12,500	13,000	15,000</p>
<p> Nikko Securities		 14,100	14,997	16,888</p>
<p> Peregrine Asset Management   13,100	14,400	15,600</p>
<p> Yamaichi International	 14,000	15,500	14,500</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong News Room (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
