<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272293" id="root" date="1996-12-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FEATURE - German toymakers aim for the &quot;grown-up child&quot;.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - German toymakers aim for the &quot;grown-up child&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Tom Heneghan</byline>
<dateline>NUREMBERG, Germany 1996-12-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Every year, at the old-fashioned Christmas markets that grace German cities in December, merchants put on dazzling displays of gingerbreads, tree ornaments and toys to highlight the holiday season.</p>
<p>Department stores are decked out in Christmas bunting. Toy shops' displays are more inviting than ever. It looks like every child's dream.</p>
<p>Behind the glitter, though, looms a problem that must keep Santa's elves awake at night worrying about their jobs.</p>
<p>There are fewer and fewer children pressing their noses against the sumptuous display windows or squealing with delight at roaring lions or teddy bears blowing soap bubbles.</p>
<p>Falling birth rates mean the toymakers' natural clientele is not dying out -- it's not even being born. Over the past three decades, their traditional market has shrunk by half.</p>
<p>But now, after a few years of falling sales, Germany's centuries-old toy industry thinks it has found a solution -- the &quot;grown-up child&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Because of the falling birth rate, we have to find adults for our toys,&quot; said Annette Grossmann of Eurotoys Market Research in Nuremberg, centre of Germany's toy trade and home to the largest annual toy fair in the world.</p>
<p>&quot;Companies are trying this more and more because they have no alternative,&quot; she said. &quot;They either have to export more or find adults in Germany for their toys.&quot;</p>
<p>GERMAN CHILDREN ARE DISAPPEARING</p>
<p>The demographic trends are dramatic.</p>
<p>&quot;There were about a million births in 1964 and just over half a million last year,&quot; said Corinna Printzen of the German Toy Industry Association, based in this mediaeval city.</p>
<p>The sales boom in eastern Germany, where pent-up consumer demand exploded after the Berlin Wall fell in 1989, also passed the toy industry by.</p>
<p>The birthrate there fell even faster -- by a stunning 60 percent in only four years -- as easterners struggled with mass unemployment and all the strains of an open society.</p>
<p>All this adds up to a bleak outlook for the toy market. Demographers expect the under-18 population to drop from 18 million now to 13 million by the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;Another problem is that kids grow up more quickly now,&quot; Printzen said. &quot;They stop playing with construction sets or toy trains at 11 or 12 rather than around 15.&quot;</p>
<p>As a result, the 5.5 billion mark ($3.5 billion) toy market has shrunk by about four percent in the past two years.</p>
<p>GROWN-UP COLLECTORS FILL MARKET GAP</p>
<p>Toymakers are now looking beyond nurseries and playgrounds for parents and grandparents ready to buy toys to share with the kids, or special collectors' models for themselves.</p>
<p>&quot;There have never been as many active senior citizens as we have now, and they have a lot of money,&quot; Printzen explained.</p>
<p>&quot;Look at the model trains, which are a real sales leader for the German toy industry. This is a toy that fathers and grandfathers buy for children.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's grandmothers just don't compare with those of 30 years ago,&quot; she added. &quot;They're very interested in board games, for example, as a contrast to the virtual world of all these computer games we have now.&quot;</p>
<p>Another German speciality -- finely-crafted stuffed toys -- has become so expensive that producers also had to go up-market to beat the competition from cheaper Asian imports.</p>
<p>Companies like Steiff, which claims to have invented the teddy bear in 1902, now aim just as much at adult collectors with limited editions of certain toys or replicas of turn-of-the-century designs.</p>
<p>Some of these collectables would cost a whole childhood's worth of pocket money to buy.</p>
<p>Maerklin, one of the world's leading model train makers, has just introduced a new metal model of the popular 1930s JU-52 airplane, retailing at 998 marks ($644). Its toy car collectables go for a more modest 750 marks ($484).</p>
<p>SECOND CHILDHOOD FOR THE OLD</p>
<p>&quot;These are definitely not for kids,&quot; said Maerklin spokesman Roland Gaugele. &quot;They're for adults who are fulfilling their childhood dreams.&quot;</p>
<p>Gaugele declined to give figures but said only about half of Maerklin's model train output was actually suitable for children. The rest are high-priced models made with the precision and detail usually reserved for fine watches.</p>
<p>Maerklin started actively targetting older buyers as early as 1972. With model trains so popular and train collectors' clubs scattered across Germany, it had little problem finding and appealing just to adults.</p>
<p>Other firms that have just discovered &quot;the grown-up child&quot; are finding it harder to advertise for him or her.</p>
<p>&quot;Senior citizens don't like to be targetted as a separate group,&quot; Printzen explained. &quot;They want to see someone 10 to 15 years younger them themselves in the advertisements.&quot;</p>
<p>So the German toy industry is unsure whether its new strategy will actually work. &quot;It will take two or three years to see if we have succeeded,&quot; Printzen said. &quot;I think our chances are good.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I49410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NUREMBERG, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
