<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272238" id="root" date="1996-12-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Dec 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Dec 22.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-12-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in Israeli newspapers on Sunday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>JERUSALEM POST</p>
<p>- U.S. envoy Dennis Ross here in effort to wrap up talks, will push Arafat to close Hebron deal.</p>
<p>- Calls for Israeli President Ezer Weizman to resign over anti-gay slurs.</p>
<p>- Palestinian Authority cool to Netanyahu adviser David Bar-Illan's statehood comments.</p>
<p>- Three held after attack on Israeli army jeep in Golan.</p>
<p>HAARETZ</p>
<p>- Ross will demand Arafat sign Hebron agreement, and of Netanyahu -- not to expand the settlements.</p>
<p>- Inter-ministry team drafting programme for stretch of settlement in the Negev, between Gaza and Hebron.</p>
<p>- Dan Meridor in interview says West Bank will receive financial benefits only at expense of something else in budget.</p>
<p>- Government coalition will try to draft a compromise on economy package in finance committee today.</p>
<p>MAARIV</p>
<p>- In Israel the charge is made: Arafat is again trying to delay negotiations.</p>
<p>YEDIOTH AHRONOTH</p>
<p>- Clinton urges Netanyahu, Arafat to finish negotiations.</p>
<p>- Treasury plans tax on petrol and cigarettes.</p>
<p>- Weizman will meet homosexual representatives tomorrow.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
