<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272254" id="root" date="1996-12-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Orange Cty Transport Authority sues Goldman Sachs.</title>
<headline>Orange Cty Transport Authority sues Goldman Sachs.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA ANA, Calif. 1996-12-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Orange County, Calif., Transportation Authority has sued Goldman Sachs &amp; Co. for allegedly failing to warn it about the risks in the county's investment portfolio, attorneys for the agency said Sunday.</p>
<p>The authority did not specify damages.</p>
<p>The authority alleged in the lawsuit, filed last week in Orange County Superior Court, that the firm was aware of the county's risky strategy, but did not warn the authority.</p>
<p>The lawsuit said Goldman Sachs should have informed the authority of the risks because the firm was an underwriter and dealer of authority debt.</p>
<p>The authority accused the firm of breaching its fiduciary duties and negligence, its attorneys said.</p>
<p>A spokesperson for Goldman Sachs was not immediately available to comment on the suit.</p>
<p>In November, the transportation authority sued auditor KPMG Peat Marwick LLP, alleging that the firm misrepresented the liquidity of the assets in the county portfolio.</p>
<p>KPMG maintains it acted properly.</p>
<p>Orange County filed for bankruptcy protection on Dec. 6, 1994, after sustaining losses of more than $1.6 billion on risky investments. The county emerged from bankruptcy in June.</p>
<p>The Orange County Transportation Authority, which provides bus and other transportation services and funds local freeway construction, said it had deposited about $1 billion in the county portfolio before its collapse.</p>
<p>The authority lost more than $225 million when the county's investments crashed in 1994, according to spokesman John Standiford. In its KPMG action, Standiford said the authority was seeking at least $400 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA ANA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
