<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="27237" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News - Sept 3.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News - Sept 3.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Following Communications Minister Richard Alston's revelation on Sunday that the Government was likely to seek a mandate for the sale of the rest of Telstra at the next election, key Independent Senator Brian Harradine has raised objections to the Governmnt's plan for partial privatisation of the telecommunications giant. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Federal Government's new approval process for health insurance premium increases will soon come under strong pressure, with at least five of 11 health insurers that fail to meet minimum reserve requirements yet to receive approval for price rises.  Eleven funds are not meeting the minimum requirements of the National Health Act - which demands reserves of either A$1 million or two month's worth of contributions - and continue to operate under an exemption from these requirements. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Qantas Airways has virtually finalised negotiations with its unions for a new enterprise agreement that will deliver pay rises totalling eight per cent over the next two years together with scope for employee share issues worth up to A$1000 for each worke. The airline has also settled negotiations with most of its unions on specific changes to work practices to apply in return for the pay rises. Page 4.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>According to Transport Minister John Sharp, former ALP Senator Mal Colston's decision to remain in the Senate as an Independent has increased the chances of the Government's industrial relations reforms being passed by the Senate as early as October, although Colston denied any deal had been struck with the Government. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>In an effort to reassure key Independent Brian Harradine, Prime Minister John Howard said yesterday he was not completely satisfied that the public would benefit from the selling of more than one third of Telstra. Howard's remarks followed the announcemet by Communications Minister Richard Alston on the weekend that the total sale of Telstra was both inevitable and desirable.  Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Federal Government will pay out A$23 million to three of Australia's biggest businesses, Mackay Refined Sugars, BHP Transport and Shell Australia, in a move that breaks an election pledge to end a construction subsidy to shipbuilders.  Although the Government was to end the subsidy from mid-1996, the three firms will now enjoy subsidies for vessels completed by mid-1997. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Health Minister Michael Wooldridge's office yesterday confirmed that the Minister was notified of private health insurance premium increases a month before the Budget, despite Prime Minister John Howard's public questioning of the Department's political judgement for failing to advise Wooldridge. The increases threaten to erode the value of the health insurance tax rebate measure that was introduced in the August 20 Budget. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Despite claims by ACTU president Jennie George that the union organisation would only accept responsibility for failure in the organisation of the rally that erupted into violence at Canberra's Parliament House last month if the Australian Federal Police dentified any liability in a report, Industrial Relations Minister Peter Reith said yesterday there would be no public report from the AFP. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Sacked by Australia Post in the middle of his legal campaign to overturn the 1994 Communication Electrical Plumbing Union (CEPU) election and last week rejected as a candidate in the upcoming September 16 election for the New South Wales branch of the postal and telecommunications section of the CEPU because he had not been a financial member of the union for 12 months before the election, Quentin Cook has filed an unfair dismissal suit in a judgement that could trigger a Federal inquiry. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a bid to save the Government's legislation to partially sell Telstra, Prime Minister John Howard yesterday publicly reprimanded Communications Minister Richard Alston and flatly denied the Government had any plans to fully privatise the telecommunicatins carrier.  Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Under a Federal Government plan to force all State housing authorities to operate as commercial landlords, tens of thousand of families in public housing face huge rent rises and many tenants may be forced to move. The proposal will convert the A$1 billion the Federal Government gives the States each year for construction and management of public housing into a direct cash payment for both public housing tenants and low income earners renting privately. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>New South Wales Labor left-wing MPs yesterday vowed to fight the plan to give police the power to break up groups of three or more young people and to demand names and addresses of suspected gang members, fearing that the policy will discriminate against young people and ethnic groups. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Following Crown Casino's announcement of a A$58.4 million profit a few weeks ago, Tabcorp Holdings has sent another signal that the gaming industry is alive and well, with a 27.3 per cent rise in profit to A$87.2 million in the year ended 30 June. Tabcor's gaming turnover jumped 37 per cent from A$3.11 billion to A$4.27 billion. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A move by the Victorian Department of Education and the Board of Studies to publish a list of the names of the top 10 per cent of secondary students and their schools has attracted criticism from some schools, who believe that ranking schools by students'grades gives a false picture of schools' performances. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Victorian Trades Hall Council secretary Leigh Hubbard yesterday accused the ACTU of leaving president Jennie George &quot;out to dry&quot; over the issue of the Parliament House riot and said the issue had been allowed to progress. Hubbard said failure to deal with the issue quickly showed a &quot;lack of collective leadership&quot; in the ACTU. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following Communications Minister Richard Alston's comments on Sunday that the total sale of Telstra was &quot;not only inevitable but it is highly desirable&quot;, Independent Senator Brian Harridine has expressed reservations over the partial sale of the telecommnications body and Prime Minister John Howard has angrily tried to limit the fallout from Alston's remarks. Page A3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
