<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272356" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wal-Mart fined $2 million in sexual harassment suit.</title>
<headline>Wal-Mart fined $2 million in sexual harassment suit.</headline>
<dateline>BENTONVILLE, Ark. 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A jury has awarded more than $1.9 million to two New Mexico women who sued Wal-Mart Stores Inc. for sexual harassment.</p>
<p>The jury in Santa Fe, N.M., on Saturday awarded $1.93 million to Madeline Duran and Cathy Coates, who worked at a Sam's Club owned by Wal-Mart, the nation's largest retailer, in Santa Fe.</p>
<p>The award included $1.75 million in punitive charges, a spokeswoman for Bentonville, Ark.-based Wal-Mart said.</p>
<p>Spokeswoman Betsy Reithemeyer said the retailer was considering an appeal. She said the women had settled out of court with the male co-worker who harassed them for $100 each even as the lawsuit against Wal-Mart continued.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not happy with it,&quot; Reithemeyer said.</p>
<p>Duran was awarded $1.3 million and Coates $613,000.</p>
<p>In the suit, they said co-worker Toby Alire had repeatedly harassed them in 1993 and that managers at Sam's Club did not adequately investigate their complaints. Alire allegedly made lurid comments to Duran and grabbed her breasts and also rubbed himself against Coates, according to trial testimony.</p>
<p>&quot;The jury heard the evidence and then sent a message that this kind of behavior will not be tolerated,&quot; Stephen Tinkler, an attorney for the women, told the Albuquerque Journal.</p>
<p>Alire was promoted after the harassment took place but was later placed on leave of absence when the lawsuit was filed and has not returned to work, Reithemeyer said.</p>
<p>She said Wal-Mart had strong policies against sexual harassment and did not expect any changes were needed as a result of the lawsuit.</p>
<p>Separately, two employees of a Wal-Mart store in San Antonio, Texas, were fired for hiding Tickle Me Elmo dolls from customers so they could buy them for themselves, a Wal-Mart store manager said Monday.</p>
<p>The two were turned in by angry customers who saw them buying the popular dolls, store manager Gerald Smith said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BENTONVILLE, Ark."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
