<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272346" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian judge rejects fetus-killing charge.</title>
<headline>Canadian judge rejects fetus-killing charge.</headline>
<byline>Courtney Tower</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A woman who fired a pellet into the head of her fetus while it was in her womb cannot be charged with attempted murder, a judge ruled on Monday.</p>
<p>Judge Inger Hansen delivered the ruling in a provincial court in the tiny Ontario town of Smiths Falls, about 37 miles (60 km) southwest of Ottawa, saying the mother, Brenda Drummond, could not be brought to trial for attempted murder for trying to kill the fetus two days before it was born.</p>
<p>Drummond, a 28-year-old postal clerk, inserted a pellet gun into her vagina in May and fired a pellet into the head of the fetus, which survived and was born two days later. The boy, Jonathan Drummond, now lives in Carleton Place, Ontario, with his father, Paul, and two sisters.</p>
<p>Hansen ruled that Canadian law does not provide for attempted murder of a fetus, but there could be a murder charge if a child subsequently born died of an injury sustained as a fetus.</p>
<p>&quot;There may still be an offense but it cannot be homicide and it cannot be attempted homicide,&quot; Hansen said. If there should be such a protection for a fetus under the law, the judge said, &quot;it is a change of law better left to Parliament.&quot;</p>
<p>The case has stirred debate in Canada on both sides of the abortion issue. Abortion is legal in Canada up to the time of delivery since a 1988 Supreme Court ruling overturned an abortion law containing some restrictions. Parliament has been reluctant to return to the emotional politics of the issue.</p>
<p>Under Canada's Criminal Code, a fetus becomes a human being only &quot;when it has completely proceeded, in a living state, from the body of its mother.&quot; Homicide can be charged only if the child dies after birth from injuries inflicted before or during its birth.</p>
<p>Hansen accepted the defense argument that there had been no offense under Canadian law and there was therefore no crime.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that there is a gap (in the law) that has to be clarified, one way or the other,&quot; prosecutor John Waugh said in a telephone interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>The decision has little impact on the abortion debate since it changes nothing in the present legal status of the fetus, Ed Ratushny, a University of Ottawa expert in criminal law, said. &quot;There would have been significant implications for the status of the fetus if the judge had gone the other way,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
