<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272301" id="root" date="1996-12-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALDIVES: FEATURE - Hang out with sharks along Maldives coral reefs.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Hang out with sharks along Maldives coral reefs.</headline>
<byline>Mark Heinrich</byline>
<dateline>THE MALDIVES 1996-12-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Imagine watching sharks chase iridescent schools of fish as you drift weightlessly with the current and breathe freely deep in a crystalline coral sea.</p>
<p>If that's your idea of a thrill, far from hurly-burly civilisation, take a scuba-diving cruise in the Indian Ocean archipelago of The Maldives.</p>
<p>&quot;Gear up, folks!&quot; shouted the Australian dive master, wearing a black baseball cap with &quot;No Fear&quot; scrawled in white across the front and a pair of eyes in the back.</p>
<p>That was the signal for our diving group to strap on air tanks and plunge from a converted Maldivian &quot;dhoni&quot; (fishing boat) into a whole new world.</p>
<p>While there are many places to dive along vivid coral reefs in the tropics, The Maldives are renowned for the big pelagic species -- sharks and rays -- that do not threaten humans, unless provoked, and normally stick to remote open waters.</p>
<p>The best way to see them, as well as exotic and colourful reef denizens like the hawksbill turtle, leopard moray eel and golden trumpet fish, is to wander the Maldives atolls on a &quot;live-aboard&quot; dive safari boat.</p>
<p>We spent two weeks on the MV Keema, a British-run, 26-metre (85-ft) vessel with six twin-berth cabins, desalinated showers, an audio-visual dive library and delectable meals of fish caught daily on the voyage.</p>
<p>There is no alcohol aboard the Keema or anywhere in the chain of 1,190 tiny islands, except on 72 reserved only for tourists, because The Maldives is a Moslem nation.</p>
<p>But no one comes to these isles to party. They zd ater won ders and heavenly white-sand beaches skirted by coconut palms.</p>
<p>Between dives on the Keema, you can sunbathe, read, list</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALDR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="THE MALDIVES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALDIVES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
