<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272407" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Blast rips Wyman-Gordon plant, 8 feared dead.</title>
<headline>Blast rips Wyman-Gordon plant, 8 feared dead.</headline>
<byline>Jeff Franks</byline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eight workers were feared dead and two others were injured after an explosion ripped through an airplane parts factory owned by the North Grafton, Mass.-based Wyman-Gordon Co, officials said on Monday.</p>
<p>The Harris County Fire Marshal's office said in a statement that the eight workers feared dead were &quot;unaccounted for,&quot; but would not elaborate.  </p>
<p>The two injured workers were said to be in stable condition at a local hospital. The Fire Marshal's office said a dollar estimate on damage to the plant was not yet available.</p>
<p>Rescue workers had been unable to reach the victims who were working on a tower 80 feet above the ground when the explosion occurred, plant president Doug Whelan told reporters.  </p>
<p>He said the explosion likely happened when the workers, who were performing maintenance operations, tried to remove the cap off a high-pressure nitrogen tank that they believed had been depressurized.</p>
<p>&quot;Apparently, the pressure was high enough that once it started (escaping) it went very rapidly and, in fact, explosive,&quot; Whelan said.</p>
<p>Television crews in helicopters above the site said the bodies of some of the victims could be seen in the plant through a gaping hole caused by the blast.  </p>
<p>Search dogs, helicopters and all-terrain vehicles were used to scour the area around the plant for clues to the blast and remains of the victims, officials said. Firefighter Eric Petocz said they hoped to find the cap that was removed from the pressurized tower.</p>
<p>He said the jumbled wreckage inside the plant reminded him of a movie set. &quot;It reminds me of Hollywood in there...You have to tell yourself 'is this really what I'm looking at?' It's pretty bad,&quot; Petocz told reporters.</p>
<p>People living near the plant, which took place just before 1300 EDT, said the explosion rattled homes several miles away.</p>
<p>&quot;It sounded like a low, low thunderstorm, just like an ordinary thunderstorm,&quot; said neighbor Loy Nelson.</p>
<p>Workers at the plant waited outside the front gates for news about their friends. They said the plant was to be shut down for two weeks at the end of the workday on Monday to give everyone time off for the holiday season.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I31000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
