<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272470" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bias charge filed against Sumitomo Bank CA.</title>
<headline>Bias charge filed against Sumitomo Bank CA.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A coalition of minority groups in California said it filed a complaint with the U.S. Labor Department on Monday charging Sumitomo Bank of California with racial discrimination in employment.</p>
<p>&quot;Sumitomo's minority and women employment record at the management and professional level is the worst of any bank in California and is likely to be the worst for any major bank in the United States,&quot; the coalition said in the complaint filed with the department's Office of Federal Contract Compliance.</p>
<p>The bank is owned by Sumitomo Bank Ltd. Sumitomo Bank officials were not immediately available for comment.  </p>
<p>The contract compliance office is charged with investigating possible violations of the Title 7 of the 1964 Civil Rights Act, which covers employment discrimination by companies receiving federal contract money, Tom Smith, spokesman for the Labor Department, said.</p>
<p>Smith declined to comment on the complaint. &quot;We don't comment on whether a company has an investigation pending or not,&quot; Smith said.</p>
<p>The coalition, including church, business and civil rights groups, said it is seeking back pay for minority employees of $20 million. The group also asked that the Federal Deposit Insurance Corp suspend Sumitomo's insurance or charge the highest premium required.</p>
<p>Labor Department officials met with members of the coalition on Dec 3 to discuss the charges, according to Robert Gnaizda, general counsel of the Greenlining Institute.</p>
<p>--Aaron Pressman((202-898-8312))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
