<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272442" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar/mark ends clutching modest gains in U.S..</title>
<headline>Dollar/mark ends clutching modest gains in U.S..</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar finished higher against the mark, but currency experts played down the very modest gains scored in quiet, pre-holiday trading.</p>
<p>&quot;I really do think that this is mainly people coming in and squaring up for the end of the year,&quot; said Elliott Dix, an assistant vice president at Signet Bank.</p>
<p>The dollar has kept its firmer tone from the past two weeks and is finishing the year near the top of its recent ranges, Dix added.</p>
<p>U.S. foreign exchange dealings are expected to finish early on Tuesday along with trading in stocks and bonds.  </p>
<p>U.S. financial markets will be closed Wednesday for the Christmas holiday and will reopen on Thursday.</p>
<p>The dollar crept to an intraday high of 1.5565 marks before closing at 1.5542/52 marks, up from 1.5530/35 marks at the open.</p>
<p>Sellers emerged when the dollar hit its peak for the day against the mark. &quot;We just had an order to sell about 50 (million) bucks when it was up there,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Usually, an order like that would be swallowed up (but) it actually moved the market,&quot; the trader added.  </p>
<p>On Monday, dollar fluctuations were also subdued versus the Japanese currency in New York. The greenback ended nearly unchannged at 114.05/10 yen versus 114.05/15 yen at the open.</p>
<p>Financial markets in Japan were closed Monday for Emperor Akihito's birthday. Weakness in the Tokyo stock market's key Nikkei 225 index had pressured the yen last week. Therefore, foreign exchange market players will watch closely how Japanese stocks fare when trading resumes on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;People want to see how the Nikkei trades tonight to get a handle on dollar/yen&quot; said David Gilmore, a partner at Foreign Exchange Analytics.  </p>
<p>Should the Nikkei index continue to weaken, investors may question how committed the Bank of Japan and Ministry of Finance are to preventing the dollar from moving above 115 yen, according to Gilmore.</p>
<p>The dollar has failed to break above 114.92 yen, it's high for the year reached on on October 29.</p>
<p>Noting that many Japanese manufacturers are exporters, Gilmore said, &quot;...if the Nikkei and share prices in Japan are sliding, what better way to prop it up than (with) a big export boost by allowing the yen to weaken further.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Nikkei 225 did manage to regain some lost ground on Friday, but the stock index still finished the week below the crucial 20,000 threshold at 19,690.46.</p>
<p>In other trade, sterling ended slightly higher, closing at $1.6760/70 compared with $1.6755/65 at the open.</p>
<p>Minutes from the monthly monetary policy meeting on October 30 between Bank of England Governor Eddie George and Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke stoked hopes for further rise in interest rates.</p>
<p>George warned one rate rise was probably not enough to quell resurgent inflationary pressures, the minutes showed.  </p>
<p>&quot;There is still talk about (an) interest rate hike in January,&quot; said Lizbeth Goldberg, an assistant vice president at Hypobank. &quot;Cable could still go higher but you're not going to see much through out year end, I think.&quot;</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the dollar ended at 1.3365/75 Swiss francs, down from 1.3378/88 at the open. But it rose to Canadian $1.3663/68 from C$1.3655/60.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar climbed to $0.7982/87 from $0.7956/61 at the open.</p>
<p>((-- Donna Sells, 212 859 1668))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
