<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="27254" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FORECAST-Boral yr net seen slumping.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FORECAST-Boral yr net seen slumping.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Building materials and energy group Boral Ltd is expected to report on Thursday a large fall in net profit before abnormals for the year to June 30 and a possible cut in its final dividend due to a weak housing market.</p>
<p>Building material analysts contacted by Reuters expect Boral to report a net profit before abnormals of between A$165 million and A$185 million for the 1995/96 year, compared with a profit of A$309.7 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>Analysts said the poor result and the demand for capital expenditure could lead to a cut in the final dividend from the 21 cents a share paid in the second half of 1994/95.  </p>
<p>Chris Haynes, a building material analyst at BT Securities, expects Boral to report a net profit before abnormals of A$185 million in 1995/96.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think things are going to be rosy for these guys,&quot; said Haynes, who has a underweight recommendation on Boral.</p>
<p>ABN AMRO Hoare Govett building material analyst Fabian Babich forecast Boral to report a net profit before abnormals of A$170 million and the second dividend to remain unchanged at the 21 cents paid a year earlier.</p>
<p>Babich said 1996/97 should also be a tough year for Boral, although a housing recovery in calendar 1997 was expected.  </p>
<p>Babich said the result would be very disappointing.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to be off the planet. When they were talking to Columbus and they said he would never make it, it wasn't a question of missing the mark - it was a question of falling off the map. Well that's what Boral has done,&quot; Babich said.</p>
<p>One Melbourne-based analyst forecast Boral to report a net profit before abnormals of A$168 million for 1995/96, but added: &quot;I think it could be worse than that.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It was a disasterous second half all together,&quot; the Melbourne analyst said. He said the fall was due to the sluggish activity in Australia's home building market.  </p>
<p>One Sydney-based analyst forecast Boral to report a net profit before abnormals of A$165 million in 1995/96.</p>
<p>Analysts said Boral may cut its second half dividend by up to four cents on the 21 cents a share paid a year earlier.</p>
<p>Boral paid a first half dividend of 10.5 cents, which was steady with the first half dividend of 1994/95.</p>
<p>Boral reported in March a net profit before abnormals of A$120 million in the six months to December 31, 1995.</p>
<p>In March, analysts were forecasting Boral to post a 1995/96 annual net profit of A$240 million to A$250 million.  </p>
<p>Analysts said Boral's energy arm should report a firm profit. Overseas earnings should be steady, but should not have much impact on the expected problems in the company's main building material operations in Australia.</p>
<p>Boral shares closed one cent down at A$3.03 on Monday.</p>
<p>The shares have fallen nearly 20 percent from their 1996 year high of A$3.75 hit on March 4.</p>
<p>-- Kevin Morrison, Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
