<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272537" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Mid-Atlantic next-day power prices extend loss.</title>
<headline>US Mid-Atlantic next-day power prices extend loss.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot wholesale electricity prices in the midsection of the Atlantic seaboard fell sharply Monday, extending Friday's decline on a plunge in natural gas prices and forecast of mild weather for the next couple of days.</p>
<p>Spot trading for Pennsylvania-New Jersey-Maryland (PJM) Interconnect electricity slowed midday after most players completed power scheduling for most of the week.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone was just into hourly and daily stuff,&quot; a Houston broker said.  </p>
<p>Spot PJM prices were also pressured by lower-than-normal power demand for much of the week amid the Christmas holiday, brokers and marketers said.</p>
<p>Firm, peak PJM electricity for Tuesday and Thursday dropped nearly $10 a megawatt hour (MWh) to $18.50-$20.00 from Friday's range of $27.50-$27.75 for Monday delivery. Most deals for firm, peak delivery Tuesday and Thursday were scheduled at $21.00-$22.00, down from $26.00-$30.00 Friday.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak PJM power for Tuesday through Thursday was notationally assessed near $14.00-$15.00 from Friday's $17.00.  </p>
<p>On Wednesday Christmas Day, firm PJM power during heavy load hours were pegged near $21.00.</p>
<p>NYMEX January Henry Hub natgas futures were last down 37.8 cents per million British thermal units at $4.195, off from a 52.3 cent loss earlier.</p>
<p>January/February 1997 PJM power deliveries were pegged at $30.30-$30.65, down from Friday's $31.30-$31.50 with deals heard done today at $31.50.</p>
<p>March PJM deliveries slipped to $25.25-$25.50 from $25.40-$25.70 Friday.  </p>
<p>First-quarter 1997 PJM fell to $29.00-$29.50 from Friday's notational quote of $29.50-$30.00.</p>
<p>Other deferred PJM prices stayed flat from Friday's levels as activities were at a stand still.</p>
<p>Second-quarter PJM remained at $23.15-$23.50, July/August 1997 $31.80-$32.10, third-quarter 1997 29.00-$29.25, fourth-quarter 1997 $24.00-$24.50 and calendar 1997 for peak hour delivery $26.40-$26.70.</p>
<p>The 1,055 megawatt (MW) Limerick 2 nuclear generating unit in Pottsdam, Pa., which was shut last Wednesday to repair a leaking seal, was scheduled to return on line today.</p>
<p>A 600 MW unit at the coal-fired Homer City, Pa., power station was heard still shut despite a planned restart this past weekend. The unit was taken off line a week ago to repair an oil feed pump problem.</p>
<p>((--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
