<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272562" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: YEAREND - Focus on U.S. small caps in 1997.</title>
<headline>YEAREND - Focus on U.S. small caps in 1997.</headline>
<byline>Andrej Gustincic</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Small cap stocks are expected to outperform large caps in early 1997, benefitting from the so-called January effect, cheaper valuations and prospects for still-explosive earnings growth.</p>
<p>But some Wall Street analysts cautioned that small caps may falter later in 1997 as interest rate jitters refocus investor attention on the safer, large cap blue chip names.</p>
<p>Small caps, generally defined by analysts as companies with capitalizations of under $1 billion, have drawn recent investor favor amid frenzied buying in the Dow industrials.  </p>
<p>Small caps historically perform best between November and January under the &quot;January effect,&quot; as investors snap up laggards and stocks with more attractive valuations and 1997 is not expected to be an exception.</p>
<p>&quot;The great speculative appetite will switch focus,&quot; said Michael Metz, chief investment strategist at Oppenheimer &amp; Co. &quot;There has been too much exploitation of top tier stocks, with momentum players and index investors focused on that area.&quot;</p>
<p>He said investors were in the process of becoming disenchanted with big names.  </p>
<p>The area has been overvalued and flows of money into large cap funds will slow as interest in smaller stock increases, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Money will go into areas perceived as offering the most excitement. The smaller cap area is generally under-owned and under-exploited and the valuations in many cases are much more reasonable,&quot; Metz said. According to data provided by First Call, small caps as measured by the Russell 2000 Index, are expected to show a year-over-year rise in operating earnings of 11 percent for 1996, while large caps, as measured by the Standard &amp; Poor's 500, will have risen eight percent.  </p>
<p>First Call said industry analysts see Russell 2000 operating earnings growing 31 percent in 1997 compared with 15 percent for large caps.</p>
<p>&quot;For over a year, blue chips have been outperforming the small caps, but going forward it looks like a very different story,&quot; said Chuck Hill, director of research at First Call.</p>
<p>Throughout 1996, large caps had outpaced smaller stocks, but the latter picked up in the fourth quarter at the end of which their operating earnings are forecast to rise 34 percent rise compared with a 10 percent increase in large caps.  </p>
<p>An improving economic picture will also boost the prospects of smaller caps, whose fate is tied to domestic economic conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;We probably will see a better economy next year. Technology investment is terrific and exports will be strong over the first three quarters of 1997,&quot; said Peter Canelo, chief investment strategist at Dean Witter.</p>
<p>He said interest rates would head lower in Europe next year and that dollar strength would benefit the small caps quarters as they are import oriented and a strong dollar reduces expenses.  </p>
<p>There is a downside, however.</p>
<p>&quot;If the economy is better, we will have interest rate problems in March or April,&quot; Canelo said. &quot;Uncertainty about interest rates and the prospect of tightening by the Federal Reserve tend to bring people back to the blue chips. I can see small caps doing well for a couple of months, but I'm not certain how long it will last.&quot; His favorites include Anadigics Inc, Vitesse Semiconductor Corp, Zions Bancorp and Baldor Electric Co</p>
<p>Hugh Johnson, chief investment officer at First Albany Corp, said that looking beyond the first few months of next year, he was still underweighted in small caps.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel good about small caps in the short-term. Looking, further into 1997, their prospects are neutral at best.&quot;</p>
<p>His favorite small caps for 1997 are RadiSys Corp, Innovex Inc and Thomas Nelson Inc.</p>
<p>Small caps are in undergoing their usual seasonal lift.</p>
<p>&quot;Although it is commonly referred to as a 'January' rally, the period of strong relative performance by smaller cap issues has moved earlier in recent years, typically to the end of November,&quot; said Abby Joseph Cohen, vice-president at Goldman Sachs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34440">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
