<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272614" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: ALPINE SKIING-CHRISTMAS A WELCOME BREAK FOR AUSTRIANS.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-CHRISTMAS A WELCOME BREAK FOR AUSTRIANS.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ALTA BADIA, Italy 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Christmas comes as a welcome break for Austrian Alpine skiers facing resurgent rivals and the return of the Alberto Tomba show.</p>
<p>The Austrian men, who started the week with the top four places in a World Cup downhill and victory in a super-giant slalom, had much to ponder as they headed home without the awesome air of invincibility they had before.</p>
<p>Although Thomas Sykora won the slalom in Madonna di Campiglio on Tuesday, ahead of world champion Tomba who returned from injury with a second place, the threatened Austrian avalanche turned out to be a false alarm.</p>
<p>They still dominated the overall World Cup -- a title that the Austrian men's team has not won since Karl Schranz in 1970 -- with Hans Knauss staying comfortably ahead after a fourth place in a giant slalom in Alta Badia on Sunday.</p>
<p>But the Swiss, the French and the Italians all showed they were ready for the battles ahead in a week when the best of the rest cut the Austrians down to size a bit.</p>
<p>Frenchman Luc Alphand took over the lead in the men's downhill standings from Fritz Strobl, winner in Val d'Isere on December 14 while Swiss Michael Von Gruenigen grabbed his first win of the season to overtake Knauss in the giant standings.</p>
<p>&quot;The Franco-Italian alliance against the Austrians really worked here,&quot; joked Italy's Kristian Ghedina after he and Alphand each won a downhill at Val Gardena.</p>
<p>Josef Strobl finished third in the second of two men's downhills run at Val Gardena on Saturday but otherwise the Austrian &quot;Eagle Knights&quot; had to watch others celebrate.</p>
<p>To add to their discomfort, Claudia Riegler -- who has dual nationality and races for New Zealand after disagreeing with the Austrian federation -- took her second World Cup win of the season in a slalom at Crans Montana on Saturday.</p>
<p>Nobody is under any illusions about the Austrians and they are sure to be back with a vengeance after the break.</p>
<p>&quot;The Austrians are still the team to beat,&quot; said Alphand.</p>
<p>Bad weather took its toll on both men and women, with rescheduled races leaving some men facing six races in two countries in the period from Sunday to Sunday.</p>
<p>A women's downhill in Crans Montana then had to be postponed to later in the season as rain fell while a giant slalom in Morzine on Sunday was called off because of soft snow. Austrian Anita Wachter was leading at the time.</p>
<p>The first men's downhill in Val Gardena, itself a postponement from earlier in the season, was threatened by bad weather and went ahead in shortened form after a delay.</p>
<p>The Norwegian men's team, with overall World Cup champion Lasse Kjus bed-ridden and in danger of missing the first race after Christmas -- a downhill in Bormio on December 29 -- as well as this week's events, protested.</p>
<p>A team statement said the calendar endangered the health of skiers and risked &quot;killing&quot; the aims of the World Cup.</p>
<p>Kjetil-Andre Aamodt, with Kjus Norway's other all-rounder, suggested a longer World Cup season might help.</p>
<p>&quot;Its difficult to ski everything for sure,&quot; he said in Alta Badia. &quot;But there's only a very few people like me who ski everything, for the specialists it's no problem.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It's a crazy programme. It's difficult with this weather and it's impossible to ski well all the time this year.</p>
<p>&quot;What we need is for them to move it out a little bit. They don't have to quit in the middle of March. They have snow. The best skiing in the world is in April.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALTA BADIA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
