<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272766" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: OPINION - IMF too optimistic on Africa - By T.Hawkins.</title>
<headline>OPINION - IMF too optimistic on Africa - By T.Hawkins.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Tony Hawkins, Professor of Business Studies at The University of Zimbabwe</p>
<p>If the International Monetary Fund is right, sub-Saharan Africa is heading for its best year in a generation with real GDP gowing at 5.6 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>Just why 1997 should be such a good year is less than obvious, since the very same set of forecasts, published in the Fund's October 1996 World Economic Outlook predicts a sharp fall in the price of the region's top export (fuel, accounting for 36 percent of total exports) which is expected to decline some 7.5 percent, allied with a 2.5 percent fall in the dollar prices of non-fuel commodities which make up another 44 percent of sub-Saharan Africa's exports.</p>
<p>Puzzling too, in a year in which output growth is set to accelerate, both import and export volume growth will slow, while the unit value of the region's exports will decline fractionally and Africa's terms of trade will worsen.</p>
<p>Add to these downside influences the rise in interest rates forecast by the IMF and the expectation of a reduction in net aid flows and the Fund's projections look overly optimistic.</p>
<p>Indeed when account is taken of a marked slowdown in economic growth in South Africa -- which accounts for a quarter of sub-Saharan GDP -- and some loss of momentum in Nigeria (accounting for 22 percent) it seems clear that the Fund's forecasts owe more to political correctness than hard-headed economics.</p>
<p>The fact is that a one percent reduction in South Africa's growth rate from just over three percent in 1996 to 2.3 percent or even less in 1997 knocks 0.25 percent off growth in sub-Saharan Africa.</p>
<p>And if the Economist Intelligence Unit's growth forecasts are adapted, using IMF weightings, it looks as if the regional economy expanded some 4.5 percent during 1996 and that this is likely to slow to four percent or slightly less in 1997 -- both figures well below the IMF's more optimistic predictions.</p>
<p>Because the IMF and the World Bank have invested so much time and effort in economic reform in Africa, it is understandable that they should &quot;talk their own book&quot; when it comes to making economic forecasts.</p>
<p>What is surprising though is the inconsistency of the IMF's projections which simply don't square with its assumptions in respect of oil and non-fuel commodity prices, export volumes growth and the growth performance of the two largest economies in the region.</p>
<p>Yet another inconsistency concerns investment.</p>
<p>Normally, higher levels of investment are associated with faster economic growth, but the IMF has investment in Africa on a plateau of around 23 percent of GDP between 1995 and 2001. Just how realistic this is, given the decline in aid inflows, is problematic.</p>
<p>The fact is that net official flows to Africa have fallen from an average of some $5.0 billion annually in the 1980s and $5.3 billion a year in the first half of the 1990s to an estimated $3.8 billion in 1995. This trend is unlikely to be reversed and with the Fund and the bank pushing sub-Saharan governments to cut public spending (which inevitably means curbing public sector investment), the region's chances of investing 23 percent of GDP each year for the rest of the decade rest heavily on its ability to attract substantially larger inflows of private sector foreign investment than in the past.</p>
<p>The IMF's optimism is based on its conviction that economic reform in Africa will pay off increasingly over the next few years. It expects lower inflation (and interest rates) and smaller budget deficits all of which should stimulate private investment.</p>
<p>Much, however, will depend on two imponderables with which no forecaster can hope to cope. The weather will have a major impact on the region's performance, as will political developments.</p>
<p>The latter are not factored in to most growth forecasts, which adds to the uncertainty. Regional and ethnic tensions in the Great Lakes region, the fragile situation in Zaire, ongoing tensions in Liberia, Nigeria, Angola and Uganda highlight the region's difficulties in attracting foreign investment.</p>
<p>Ironically, two of the region's less stable economies -- Nigeria and Angola -- have attracted the lion's share of new foreign investment flowing into sub-Saharan Africa. This is a timely reminder, if any were needed, that it is resources, and in these cases oil and gas, that have more to do with attracting foreign capital than &quot;politcal stability&quot;.</p>
<p>When all factors are taken into account, there are grounds for modest optimism about economic growth over the next year. sub-Saharan Africa's 20-year track record shows growth of 2.1 percent annually between 1978 and 1987 and 2.5 percent over the last nine years. With population growth of around three percent real per capita incomes have been falling for a generation. Even upbeat forecasts, such as the IMF's 5.3 percent (for 1996) and 5.6 percent (1997) point to a painfully slow recovery -- as distinct from growth -- in the region's real living standards.</p>
<p>On current trends it will take until 2015 or even later to regain the living standards enjoyed at the time of the first oil price crisis in the early 1970s. Whether African electorates will be prepared to wait that long for economic reforms to pay off is questionable. Indeed, the signs are that in future forecasters will have to pay far greater attention to political consideratiions, whose influence will loom large as the gap widens between Africa's haves and its have-nots.</p>
<p>			    / / / / / / /</p>
<p>(The opinions expressed in this article represent those of the author only. They should not be seen to represent the views of Reuters.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFRICA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
