<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272779" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAfrica Rovic mine on first step to recovery.</title>
<headline>SAfrica Rovic mine on first step to recovery.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The first phase of a recovery programme at South Africa's Roberts Victor Diamond Mine (Rovic), site of a recent lethal mine diaster, has begun, the mine's managers said on Monday.</p>
<p>Vancouver-listed Botswana Diamondfields Inc said the first phase of the plan will seek to secure the main and sub-vertical shaft access to the mine and also install a replacement dewatering system to prevent flooding at the main shaft bottom.</p>
<p>Late last month an inflow of mud from old open cast workings into the underground shafts killed 19 miners and a contract driller. The mine is based at Dealesville, 60 km from the Free State capital of Bloemfontein.</p>
<p>The firm said new pumps had been installed and the water level had dropped by more than 10 metres since pumping began on Sunday.</p>
<p>On the surface a contractor is injecting a chemical and cement grout into the old open workings to prevent any further mud or water inflow.</p>
<p>The firm said there were also plans to restore output at the mine and to re-establish a ventilation shaft and escape route at the south end of the mine.</p>
<p>In July the mine announced plans to raise production to 15,000 tonnes of kimberlite a month. &quot;The opportunity now exists to re-examine this plan with the objective of achieving the same result a different way,&quot; the firm said.</p>
<p>It added that the new plan will seek to restore production with an underground lay-out which will allow the mining of at least three million tonnes of kimberlite over the mine's projected life-span.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
