<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272828" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbian government, opposition mobilise support.</title>
<headline>Serbian government, opposition mobilise support.</headline>
<byline>Peter Greste</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbia's political activists have begun mobilising supporters for rival mass rallies in the capital on Tuesday -- one in favour of President Slobodan Milosevic and one against.</p>
<p>Meanwhile the independent news agency BETA reported scuffles between pro and anti-government Serbians on Monday evening in Valjevo, a town about 40 km (25 miles) southwest of Belgrade.</p>
<p>Tuesday's demonstrations were scheduled to start at the same time in the capital: 3:00 pm (1400 GMT) and in squares barely 200 metres (yards) apart.</p>
<p>The ruling Socialist Party was reported to be organising fleets of busses and trains to transport some 400,000 supporters from all over Serbia for a demonstration of loyalty to Milosevic in Belgrade's central Republic Square.</p>
<p>The opposition Zajedno (Together) coaltion called on its supporters to match the pro-Milosevic demonstration with their greatest show of strength since they began their daily marches through Belgrade more than six weeks ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Eveyone here must bring five others with you tomorrow,&quot; one of Zajedno's leaders Vuk Draskovic told 80,000 supporters at Monday's rally.</p>
<p>&quot;I have nothing but pity for those (Milosevic supporters) who will come here tomorrow for a piece of bread... Do not be afraid of them. They are all cowards and we do not want violence.&quot;</p>
<p>Zajedno has massed up to a quarter of a million people in the daily protests to demand Milosevic accept its victories in 15 major towns including Belgrade in annulled local elections held on November 17.</p>
<p>The marches have so far remained largely trouble-free if noisy demonstrations of dissent that have spread to dozens of other cities and towns across Serbia in the most serious challenge to Milosevic's nine-year-old rule.</p>
<p>BETA, monitored by the British Broadcasting Corporation in London, said fist-fights erupted when around 20,000 of Valjevo's residents Zajedno took to the streets on Monday in response to a rally organized by Milosevic's Socialist Party.</p>
<p>The agency said that although around 50 of the SPS supporters were from the town, most were bussed in under 500-strong police protection.</p>
<p>&quot;...a large fist fight broke out between the citizens of Valjevo and these outsiders, in which SPS sympathizers fared very poorly, and six of the buses that had brought them to the rally... were also demolished,&quot; the agency said.</p>
<p>Reflecting growing fears of trouble, the Serbian Orthodox Patriarch said Tuesday's twin marches could end in violence.</p>
<p>Publicly intervening in the conflict for the first time, Patriarch Pavle expressed concern at &quot;the division in our society which could lead to armed mutual confrontation&quot;.</p>
<p>The 82-year-old patriarch urged Zajedno to suspend its protest to avoid the risk of clashes and said both sides should resist confrontation, &quot;especially members of the ruling parties behind whom stand the armed forces of the present order&quot;.</p>
<p>Zajedno said police would be planted in the pro-government rally to foment trouble, but it refused to halt its own demonstration despite concerns that Milosevic was looking for a pretext to declare a state of emergency.</p>
<p>The socialists' plan to bring thousands of supporters from the provinces by bus was jeopardised by the Independent Farmers' Union which said it would block roads on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Union leaders staged a symbolic blockade between the northern towns of Novi Sad and Zrenjanin on Monday. They said the action was non-political and a demand for money the government owes farmers.</p>
<p>Workers have mostly ignored the intelligentsia-led marches, but the farmers' action bodes ill for Milosevic's efforts to regain the political initiative.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
