<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272804" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Dec 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Dec 23.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Kenyan press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY NATION</p>
<p>- Two Kiambu residents are killed as they answer a distress call in another bloody gang terror that leaves scores wounded.</p>
<p>- Sheikh Khalid Balala, exiled leader of the unregistered Islamic Party of Kenya, is issued with internationally valid travel documents by the German government and is set to return to Kenya.</p>
<p>- A woman is arrested over the lynching of a security guard among 100 people sent to demolish a slum in Lavington, Nairobi.</p>
<p>EAST AFRICAN STANDARD</p>
<p>- The unregistered Safina party denies having incited recent riots at Egerton University as alleged by the vice-chancellor.</p>
<p>- Nairobi branch of the Kenya Union of Commercial Food and Allied Workers dismisses as null and void elections held at the weekend.</p>
<p>- A suspected witch narrowly escapes death in Kitui town.</p>
<p>KENYA TIMES</p>
<p>- Villagers armed with spears kill an elephant outside a game reserve in Keiyo district.</p>
<p>- An armed gangster seriously wounds a police officer in an abortive robbery in Machakos town.</p>
<p>THE EAST AFRICAN</p>
<p>- Kenyan transporters say Tanzania is blocking the delivery of relief supplies to Rwandan refugee camps in an effort to hasten their repatriation.</p>
<p>- The Ugandan government is to set up a body to regulate the private generating of electricity once the sector is liberalised.</p>
<p>- Roman Catholic bishops from the Great Lakes region express concern about the disappearance of a former bishop of Ruhengeri in northwest Rwanda.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
