<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="272963" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks ease in pre-holiday lull.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks ease in pre-holiday lull.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican stocks closed down on Monday after drifting during a session dulled by pre-holiday apathy, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was stagnant, nothing interesting happened. Most dealers have taken positions and are hanging around just in case something happens. They're basically waiting until the new year before they reshuffle portfolios,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>The blue chip IPC index  .MXX closed down 12.19 points, or 0.37 percent, at 3,299.17. Volume  .TV.MX, at 171.2 million shares traded, was mostly accounted for by cross trades, dealers said.  </p>
<p>Most traders said foreign investors were conspicuous by their absence.</p>
<p>&quot;There's nothing to say about local investors, because they did nothing and the few that traded just sold some stock to get liquidity and buy presents. We had not a whiff of foreign dealers, They'll be out until the new year,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Dealers also said interest waned after trade balance figures were released and in the run up to inflation figures and the primary auction due later in the day.  </p>
<p>The Finance Ministry announced on Sunday a trade surplus of $280 million. Banco de Mexico announced in late trade that consumer prices rose 2.34 percent in the first half of December.</p>
<p>A Reuters survey of money market traders revealed an average forecast assigned rate of 27.55 percent for bellwether 28-day Cetes, or a gain of 28 basis points from last week's rate.</p>
<p>&quot;Trade Balance figures were good, but discounted,&quot; an equity analyst said, &quot;The inflation figures were high, and are a little worrying, but we'll have to wait until tomorrow for a reaction.&quot;</p>
<p>On the broad market, 89 stocks changed hands, of which losers outnumbered gainers by 34 to 29.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
