<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="27313" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Low stocks prompts India to boost fuel oil imports.</title>
<headline>Low stocks prompts India to boost fuel oil imports.</headline>
<byline>Marguerita Choy</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Low stocks, a cut in refinery output and the onset of winter demand will prompt India to import up to 100,000 tonnes of fuel oil per month until February, industry sources predicted on Monday.</p>
<p>India's fuel oil inventories had run low because it was importing other products, especially diesel, over the last few months, they said. Heavy port congestion has meant the government had to limit the amount of oil it could brought in.</p>
<p>&quot;We were not importing fuel oil because of the congestion. We thought we will first use our inventories,&quot; said a source at a state-owned refiner.</p>
<p>India's fuel oil imports fell sharply from 100,000 tonnes a month in April and May to 25,000 tonnes in June, 10,000 tonnes in July and 14,000 tonnes in August.</p>
<p>But scheduled maintenance from Sept 3-30 of the 160,000 barrel per day (bpd) refinery at Mathura, India's second largest and located near the Taj Mahal city of Agra, is forcing India to increase fuel oil imports again, the sources said.</p>
<p>After making minimal purchases since June, state Indian Oil Corporation (IOC) last week tendered to buy four, 25,000-tonne cargoes of high sulphur fuel oil for September delivery.</p>
<p>IOC has awarded its first tender to Swiss-based oil trader Glencore.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been running short of furnace (fuel) oil since new secondary cracking units came up last year,&quot; a trader at an Indian refinery said.</p>
<p>&quot;Refinery production of fuel oil has since then fallen by around 40,000 to 60,000 tonnes a month.&quot;</p>
<p>Cracking units break down the heavier fuel oil into lighter and more valuable products like diesel.</p>
<p>However, the source said he did not expect diesel imports to increase due to the shutdown of the Mathura refinery.</p>
<p>&quot;There is still a lot of diesel floating outside Kandla,&quot; he said in reference to ships waiting off the west coast port.</p>
<p>A source at IOC said India has a shortfall of fuel oil and has been a regular importer since last year, but the volume usually drops during the monsoon season from June to September.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now in the middle of the monsoon,&quot; he said. &quot; Once it tapers off, imports will return.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders also said winter demand for fuel oil, used as boiler fuel for heating, would rise during winter months.</p>
<p>They said they expected the high imports of up to 100,000 tonnes a month to last until at least February next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
