<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="273168" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Kurd rebel leader calls for dialogue with Turkey.</title>
<headline>Kurd rebel leader calls for dialogue with Turkey.</headline>
<dateline>DIYABAKIR, Turkey 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kurdish rebel leader Abdullah Ocalan renewed calls for a lasting solution to 12 years of conflict in southeast Turkey in a television interview broadcast on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;I want there to be a way for dialogue in 1997. Without putting forward any pre-conditions, I invite the Turkish state to a solution of the Kurdish problem by political means,&quot; the Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK) chief said in the interview broadcast by Belgian-based Med-TV.</p>
<p>Ocalan said Turkish Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan had made various initiatives for dialogue with the rebels after he came to power in June, but that these had since been abandoned.</p>
<p>Turkish governments and the military have often refused direct negotiations with the PKK, which they regard as a terrorist group. A unilateral rebel ceasefire declared last year was ignored by Turkey.</p>
<p>Ocalan said the PKK was trying to find a party leader or government official with whom they could talk and repeated assurances that he had dropped demands for a separate Kurdish state on Turkish soil.</p>
<p>&quot;I want the problem to be solved by political means, within Turkey's national borders,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ocalan, also known as &quot;Apo&quot;, threatened more suicide bombings in Turkey's major cities if what he called the repression of the Kurdish people continued.</p>
<p>&quot;This time we will send hundreds of guerrillas into the big cities. It's not a difficult thing for a guerrilla with a bomb to get on a bus or a plane, or infiltrate into a crowded place,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ten people, mostly members of the security forces, were killed in two suicide bombings in Turkish cities at the end of October and 10 soldiers were killed by a human bomb in eastern Turkey in July.</p>
<p>More than 21,000 people have died since the PKK took up arms for Kurdish independence in 1984. The group has since stressed it could settle for autonomy and cultural rights for Turkey's estimated 10 million to 15 million Kurds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DIYABAKIR, Turkey"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
