<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="273167" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: U.S. envoy Ross delays talks with Arafat.</title>
<headline>U.S. envoy Ross delays talks with Arafat.</headline>
<byline>Wafa Amr</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Middle East envoy Dennis Ross decided on Monday to remain with Israeli and Palestinian negotiators trying to clinch a Hebron deal, delaying talks with Palestinian President Yasser Arafat.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Ross will continue talks with negotiators in Jerusalem who are trying to finish drafting the (Hebron) agreement,&quot; said a Palestinian official who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>Earlier another Palestinian official said Ross would meet Arafat in self-ruled Gaza later on Monday. The official said Arafat and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu would meet on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Ross on Monday evening joined Israeli and Palestinian negotiators trying to finalise an accord on the handover of most of Hebron to Palestinian rule. Before joining the negotiations Ross conferred with Netanyahu.</p>
<p>&quot;There is work going on. There is still a lot of work to be done,&quot; Ross told reporters in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Asked if a Hebron agreement was close, he said: &quot;I think there are still issues to be resolved. I think you should focus on the fact that there is more work to be done.&quot;</p>
<p>Ross, who has shuttled between Israel, PLO-ruled Gaza and Egypt, arrived in the region on Saturday saying he hoped to re-energise the talks.</p>
<p>Palestinian chief negotiator Mahmoud Abbas, also known as Abu Mazen, said the talks had reached a critical stage.</p>
<p>&quot;I am going to Gaza to consult with President Arafat. We are at a critical stage now,&quot; he said, adding that progress had been made.</p>
<p>Asked if he had a copy of a Hebron agreement with him, Abbas said: &quot;I am taking with me the general guidelines to inform President Arafat about what has been reached until now.&quot;</p>
<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai told reporters on Monday that Israel was &quot;more optimistic&quot; now about a deal.</p>
<p>In Hebron, an Israeli truck took camp beds and equipment from the military governor's office but officials declined to say whether final preparations for a long-delayed troop redeployment were under way.</p>
<p>Only six military vehicles were left at the building, the nerve centre of Israel's military occupation of Hebron since 1967, reporters said.</p>
<p>Palestinian officials had said there was agreement on some major disputed points, but other issues were left to be resolved in a meeting yet to be arranged between Netanyahu and Arafat.</p>
<p>Israel and the PLO have accused each other of foot-dragging in more than three months of talks on Hebron, 80 percent of which was due to have been handed over to Arafat's Palestinian Authority months ago.</p>
<p>Netanyahu, who came to power in June vowing to take a tough line on Israeli security, has demanded protection for 400 Jewish militants in the heart of the city of 100,000 Arabs, a longtime flashpoint of violence between Arabs and Jews.</p>
<p>PLO officials said the Israelis had dropped their insistence on having the right of hot pursuit of Palestinian suspects into PLO-held areas, accepting instead existing language in the Hebron handover agreement signed in 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
