<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="273366" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Algiers car bomb kills three, wounds 70 - hospital.</title>
<headline>Algiers car bomb kills three, wounds 70 - hospital.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A car bomb exploded near a crowded cafe in central Algiers on Monday killing at least three people and wounding 70, Algerian hospital sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;Three people died on the spot and 70 others who were injured were ferried here in Mustapha Bacha (hospital) but more than 40 slightly injured returned home after treatment,&quot; said a medical source speaking by telephone from the Algerian capital.</p>
<p>Many of those badly injured in the rush-hour car bombing were transferred to other hospitals, another medical source added. Among the injuries were broken bones and eyes hit by shrapnel.</p>
<p>Security forces, wielding assault rifles, sealed the scene of the explosion, which wrecked a cafe, shattered windows and damaged cars. Many residents believed the bomb caused more casualties.</p>
<p>&quot;I saw much blood at the scene. I fear many people might have died,&quot; a witness said by telephone from Algiers after the explosion at 12.45 a.m. (1145 GMT)</p>
<p>There was no immediate claim of responsibility for the blast. More than 1,400 civilians have died in bomb attacks by fundamentalist Moslem rebels in the past two years, according to a government human rights body.</p>
<p>Monday's car bomb ripped through the commercial Larbi Ben Mehidi's street at rush hour, destroying the cafe and badly seriously a pizzeria and a betting office, withnesses said.</p>
<p>&quot;A young man hurriedly left a car he had just parked near Novelty cafe and a moment later the explosion hit the place,&quot; said one man, speaking from his office near the site of the blast.</p>
<p>Another witness said &quot;trails of blood covered the pavement&quot; and the cafe was wrecked. &quot;There were many people in the place as employees left offices for lunch and a lot of passers-by were also there.&quot;</p>
<p>About 60,000 people, mostly Moslem militants and security forces members, have died since early 1992 when the authorities cancelled a general election radical Islamists were set to win.</p>
<p>Monday's bomb came a day after Prime Minister Ahmed Ouyahia asserted the government had defeated the guerrillas and &quot;terrorism is living its latest convulsive moment&quot;.</p>
<p>The deadliest bomb attack was in January, 1995, when a suicide bomber slammed a car into central Algiers's main police station, killing at least 42 people and wounded nearly 300. The Armed Islamic Group, most ruthless of Algeria's fundamentalist movements, claimed responsibility.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
