<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="273422" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Renault head sees bigger losses - paper. [CORRECTED 08:44 GMT]</title>
<headline>Renault head sees bigger losses - paper. [CORRECTED 08:44 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chairman of French carmaker Renault told a French newspaper on Monday he expects the trend in losses seen in 1996 to deepen.</p>
<p>(Corrects name of company from PSA Peugeot Citreon to Renault, throughout.)</p>
<p>Asked in an interview in La Tribune about the trend of losses mentioned at the announcement of first-half results, Louis Schweitzer said, &quot;In a difficult economic context and taking into account the price wars and discounts tougher than expected in France, I can only unfortunately announce a strengthening of the trend.&quot;  </p>
<p>Schweitzer said he expected the environment in 1997 &quot;will be much more difficult than in 1996.&quot;</p>
<p>He reaffirmed a forecast that the European market would be in slight retreat and that estimated French sales would fall to 1.9 million cars from 2.1 million.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not think the price war will stop,&quot; he added. &quot;We are in a new situation where the price of cars in Europe is falling in constant francs and certainly in current francs.&quot;</p>
<p>However, Renault had two positive elements. It had cut costs and launched the Megane range and the Scenic utility vehicle.     -- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452 pnt</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
