<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="273435" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - Dec 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - Dec 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Bangladesh press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE DAILY STAR</p>
<p>The government on Sunday constituted an inquiry commission to investigate into the jail revolt in Jessore.</p>
<p>The government will hold the second round of international conference on prospect of hydrocarbon exploration in Bangladesh in February. World Bank will sponsor the conferences in London and Houston.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>The second conference of the chief justices of the SAARC countries will begin on Dcember 28 in Bangladesh.</p>
<p>Opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) has criticised the government for resorting to force in ending the revolt in Jessore jail.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>BANGLADESH OBSERVER</p>
<p>The government has offered tribal insurgent leader Jyotirindra Budhipriya Larma medicare in Dhaka. Larma is suffering from malaria fever.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina said on Sunday her government would implement specific programmes to ensure welfare of the freedom fighters and establish their dignity in society.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>FINANCIAL EXPRESS</p>
<p>A guideline on share price movement, finalised by a special committee on Sunday, may allow adjustment of prices after corporate actions but is unlilkely to widen the existing five percent range of price fluctuation.</p>
<p>	 -- Dhaka Newsroom 880-2-506363 REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
