<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="273581" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Alliant to sell unit to Hughes.</title>
<headline>Alliant to sell unit to Hughes.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alliant Techsystems said Monday it had agreed to sell its Marine Systems Group to Hughes Electronics Corp for $141 million cash.</p>
<p>The transaction, which is subject to regulatory approval, is expected to be completed during the first quarter of 1997, Alliant said in a statement.</p>
<p>Alliant's Marine Systems Group is involved in a number of U.S. Navy programs, including the Lightweight Hybrid Torpedo, the Mk 46 and MK 50 lightweight torpedoes, the NT 37 heavyweight torpedo, the Advanced Deployable Underwater Surveillance System, and the SLQ-48 Mine Neutralization System.  </p>
<p>Hughes said no changes in the Marine Systems work force are anticipated. The group employs about 650 people at facilities in California, Maryland, Minnesota, Rhode Island, Texas and Washington.  The acquisition includes the group's headquarters facility in Mukilteo, Wash.</p>
<p>Alliant said cash proceeds from the sale will be used to reduce debt, strengthen its balance sheet, and provide funds for strategic investments.</p>
<p>Alliant said the sale will enable it to exit a business that is strong and healthy but which is relatively small and in a sector of the defense industry that is overdue for consolidation.</p>
<p>Alliant said it intends to take advantage of the defense industry consolidation by continuing to be an active buyer and seller. The purchase of Hercules Aerospace Co in 1995, which strengthened its core businesses and added new businesses, is an example, Alliant said.</p>
<p>Hughes Electronics is a world leader in the design, manufacture and marketing of advanced electronic systems. It is part of General Motors Corp.</p>
<p>Alliant is a $1.2 billion aerospace and defense company with about 7,600 employees and operations in 24 states.</p>
<p>((-- Chicago Newsdesk 312 408 8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
