<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="273695" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Heat still on for more British rate rises.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Heat still on for more British rate rises.</headline>
<byline>Michael Peacock</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke will have pressure heaped on him to raise interest rates in the months ahead if the minutes from his October 30 meeting with Bank of England Governor Eddie George are anything to go by.</p>
<p>That meeting resulted in both agreeing to raise base rates by a quarter-point to six percent -- a surprise to many. But even then, George was warning one rate rise was unlikely to be enough to quell resurgent inflationary pressures.</p>
<p>&quot;That might well not be enough to moderate the upswing sufficiently to restore a better-than-evens chance of achieving the inflation target over the next two years,&quot; the minutes quoted George as saying.</p>
<p>The government has a medium-term target of 2.5 percent for underlying inflation, which has stuck stubbornly at 3.3 percent year-on-year for the past two months.</p>
<p>&quot;The comments from the Governor suggest that he will be pushing for further rate hikes in the coming months,&quot; said Nick Stamenkovic, economist at DKB International. &quot;And judging from recent data, he will certainly be increasing pressure on the Chancellor to raise at the January meeting.&quot;</p>
<p>Clarke and George hold their next monetary policy forum on January 15. With elections due within five months, Clarke's ruling Conservative Party lagging badly in opinion polls and now deprived of its parliamentary majority, he would be loath to tighten monetary policy again.</p>
<p>That would force home loans higher in a country where nearly two-thirds of households are owned not rented.</p>
<p>But at the October meeting, Clarke restated his commitment to meet the inflation target, so a further increase is not out of the question.</p>
<p>The minutes showed he said there was no reason to delay a rate rise adding that raising rates early would &quot;emphasise his determination to achieve the inflation target.&quot;</p>
<p>Stamenkovic said a rate rise in January could not be ruled out but said Clarke may want to wait for fourth quarter economic growth data before making a move. Preliminary Q4 GDP data will not be released until January 27.</p>
<p>October's monetary minutes showed Clarke had decided to postpone any decision on interest rates in September because he wished to see third quarter economic growth figures.</p>
<p>&quot;Clarke's allusion to the GDP numbers is key,&quot; said Alex Garrard, UK economist at UBS. &quot;That suggests he might want to wait until the February monetary meeting.&quot;</p>
<p>Recent economic data has certainly favoured the monetary hawks. Unemployment plunged by nearly 96,000 in November, the largest monthly fall on record. Retail sales rose by 0.7 percent, well in advance of expectations, and M4 broad money supply growth leapt to 10.8 percent year-on-year, from 10.3 in October.</p>
<p>&quot;George will be worried about the re-acceleration of M4,&quot; Garrard said. At the October meeting, George said M4 growth at around nine percent was unlikely to be consistent with underlying inflation of 2.5 percent.</p>
<p>Garrard said the arguments for biting the bullet and raising interest rates earlier rather than later were largely political.</p>
<p>&quot;An April election is quite possible so it might be tempting to get the next rate rise out of the way in January,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But either way, a pre-election tightening is just about inevitable. &quot;The world and its wife recognises that rates will have to rise further in 1997 if the inflation target is to be met,&quot;  Garrard said. &quot;And we're expecting a fairly robust Q4 GDP number.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
