<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="27372" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American Air, pilots reach contract deal.</title>
<headline>American Air, pilots reach contract deal.</headline>
<byline>Kieran Murray</byline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>AMR Corp.'s American Airlines and pilots union leaders struck a tentative labour contract deal on Monday after two years of tortuous negotiations, ending the threat of a crippling strike.</p>
<p>Jim Sovich, president of the Allied Pilots Association, said the Labour Day breakthrough came when his team decided to back the airline's &quot;final, final, final&quot; offer.</p>
<p>He said he would take the deal to the union's board of directors for approval.</p>
<p>&quot;In my opinion, it is a very fair contract that provides the pilot with job security, pension security and compensation he and she needs in exchange for the productivity enhancements the company needs to compete,&quot; Sovich said in a recorded message to the 9,400 union members.</p>
<p>He did not give details, but said the proposed package -- which would run until the year 2000 -- includes &quot;pay raises and stock options during the length of the contract that ensure the compensation package is industry-leading.&quot;</p>
<p>American Airlines President Don Carty, who joined the negotiations in mid-August in a bid to force through an agreement, said the deal would allow the company to focus on its business.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased to have reached an agreement,&quot; Carty said in a statement. &quot;With this matter behind us, we can now focus our full attention on providing the outstanding service our customers expect.&quot;</p>
<p>The Fort Worth-based airline, which is making hefty profits again after some lean years for the industry, is currently trying to win government approval for its global alliance with British Airways.</p>
<p>Union leaders had demanded a minimum 5 percent per year wage hike backdated to August 1994, while the airline wanted a 2 percent pay cut and a four-year wage freeze. But both sides recently eased their demands and swapped a series of proposals in round-the-clock negotiations over the last week.</p>
<p>Sovich said the proposed contract includes changes to boost productivity but that the airline's controversial short-haul proposal, under which it would assign 20 percent of its pilots to a small-airplane unit and pay them up to 30 percent less, did not get through.</p>
<p>&quot;The short-haul proposal is off the table,&quot; Sovich said.</p>
<p>The labour contract negotiations began in mid-1994 but showed little advance until the National Mediation Board was brought in to broker a deal earlier this year.</p>
<p>Sovich said it was &quot;ironic&quot; that the deal was finally struck on Labour Day. The package still requires ratification by the APA's board of directors and membership.</p>
<p>APA leaders had threatened strike action within weeks if a package was not agreed on and Sovich told his members the threat of industrial action had been key. &quot;Your support, your overwhelming strike vote and your strength have provided the impetus needed to force this agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>American's 21,000 flight attendants held a five-day strike in 1993 that cost the airline an estimated $190 million. They then went on to win strong pay increases under binding arbitration.</p>
<p>But the airline won some leverage in its negotiations with pilots this year when Delta Air Lines pilots accepted a 2 percent pay cut and a short-haul proposal cutting wages by 30 percent on small planes in return for stock options, a profit-sharing plan and improved retirement benefits.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
