<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="273798" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel eases limits on Palestinian workers.</title>
<headline>Israel eases limits on Palestinian workers.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Israeli army said on Monday it had eased limits on Palestinian labourers, which could allow thousands more to work in the Jewish state.</p>
<p>&quot;Workers aged 28 and above, married with at least two children will be permitted to enter Israel as part of the quota of those workers who may enter Israel,&quot; an army spokesman said.</p>
<p>Israel previously limited entrance to Palestinian workers aged 30 and above, military sources said.</p>
<p>Palestinian Labour Ministry official Said Mudallal said he had not yet been officially informed of the decision but another 1,500 to 2,000 Gazan workers could benefit from it.</p>
<p>Mudallal said the eased eligibility requirements, if implemented, would boost the number of workers who commute daily from the West Bank and Gaza to Israel from the present 42,000 closer to an Israeli quota of 50,000.</p>
<p>He said Palestinians -- despite unemployment rates of 24 percent in the West Bank and 39 percent in Gaza -- were not filling Israeli work permit quotas because of tough eligibility restrictions and repeated closures of the Palestinian areas.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a problem of the continuation of repeated closures. Each repeated closure has led the Israeli employers to fire many workers because they want workers they can rely on that will arrive every day,&quot; Mudallal told Reuters.</p>
<p>Palestinians complain that Israeli employers have replaced Arab workers with imported foreign ones because of the closures.</p>
<p>Israel, citing security reasons, has repeatedly closed off the West Bank and Gaza since limited Palestinian self-rule was launched in parts of the occupied areas in 1994.</p>
<p>A blanket closure imposed after a wave of Islamist suicide bombings killed scores in Israel 10 months ago has only recently been eased. Some 60,000 Palestinians held jobs in Israel before that closure.</p>
<p>Palestinians blast the closures -- which have caused unemployment to skyrocket and trade to plummet -- as collective punishment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
