<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="273742" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Netanyahu to meet ministers on Hebron deal.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu to meet ministers on Hebron deal.</headline>
<byline>Wafa Amr</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu met Palestinian negotiators on Monday who said that a U.S-brokered deal to break a peace deadlock over Hebron could be clinched by Christmas.</p>
<p>Netanyahu later scheduled a meeting for 1500 GMT with senior ministers to discuss Hebron, Israeli officials said.</p>
<p>In Hebron, an Israeli truck took camp beds and equipment from the military governor's office in the centre of the city but officials declined to say whether final preparations for a long-delayed troop redeployment were underway.</p>
<p>Only six military vehicles were left at the office, the nerve centre of Israel's military occupation of Hebron since 1967, reporters said.</p>
<p>Netanyahu joined talks with Palestinians while U.S. special envoy Dennis Ross flew to Cairo to brief Egypt, a key player in efforts to reach agreement on an Israeli pullback in the West Bank town.</p>
<p>Palestinian officials said there was agreement on some major disputed points, but other issues were left to be resolved in a meeting yet to be arranged between Netanyahu and Palestinian President Yasser Arafat.</p>
<p>Asked if an agreement would be reached on Monday, chief Palestinian negotiator Mahmoud Abbas, also known as Abu Mazen, said: &quot;Everything is possible.&quot;</p>
<p>Arafat himself said a meeting might take place on Monday night.</p>
<p>The U.S. envoy arrived in the Middle East on Saturday saying he hoped to re-energise talks. But he had played down hopes of a breakthrough, saying only that he expected to report to President Bill Clinton after a couple of days.</p>
<p>Only last week Arafat was questioning Ross's objectivity. But after meeting Ross for a second time in two days, Arafat expressed his thanks for the American's support.</p>
<p>&quot;The two teams and the Americans, led by Ross, met with Arafat until dawn and we can finally say there was progress,&quot; said a PLO official who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>The U.S. Consul General in Jerusalem, Edward Abington, said Ross would return on Monday after briefing the Egyptians.</p>
<p>&quot;The meetings on both sides have been positive and we are continuing our efforts,&quot; Abington quoted Ross as saying.</p>
<p>PLO officials cast doubt on an unconfirmed report that Egypt's Foreign Minister Amr Moussa might return with Ross if a a signing ceremony was held later on Monday.</p>
<p>Israel and the PLO have accused each other of foot-dragging in more than three months of talks on Hebron, 80 percent of which was due to have been handed over to Arafat's Palestinian Authority months ago.</p>
<p>Netanyahu, who came to power in June vowing to take a tough line on Israeli security, has demanded protection for 400 Jewish militants in the heart of the city of 100,000 Arabs, a longtime flashpoint of violence between Arabs and Jews.</p>
<p>Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy, asked about reports of a deal being close, told Israeli army radio: &quot;I hope that now in the wake of the news there is a readiness -- and Arafat is even emphasising the progress -- that finally we'll achieve it.&quot;</p>
<p>Talks on Hebron, the main issue blocking further progress in more than three years of Israeli-Palestinian negotiations, have had their ups and downs in the past with optimistic forecasts being dashed by new disagreements.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't say we have an agreement until everything is put on paper and we haven't done that yet,&quot; said a senior PLO official. &quot;We could have an agreement within 24 hours and we could be delayed for another month at least.&quot;</p>
<p>Another official said progress would depend on the meeting of the two teams along with Ross and Netanyahu later on Monday.</p>
<p>PLO officials said the Israelis had dropped their insistence on having the right of hot pursuit of Palestinian suspects into PLO-held areas, accepting instead existing language in the Hebron handover agreement signed in 1995.</p>
<p>One PLO official said agreement had also been reached to reopen Martyrs Street in the heart of town within four months. It has been closed to Palestinians. It was also agreed to reopen the long-closed vegetable market so long as it was a retail rather than a wholesale market.</p>
<p>&quot;As for resumption of further redeployments from the West Bank and resumption of final-status talks, there was an initial agreement to set a date for these two issues 'within weeks', and this would have to be determined in a meeting between Netanyahu and Arafat,&quot; the official said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
