<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="273811" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hughes to acquire Alliant defense unit for $141 million.</title>
<headline>Hughes to acquire Alliant defense unit for $141 million.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hughes Electronics Corp., a major defence contractor, said Monday it agreed to acquire the Marine Systems Group of Alliant Techsystems for $141 million in cash.</p>
<p>MSG will be part of the Naval and Maritime Systems of Hughes Aircraft Co., a unit of Hughes Electronics.  The acquisition is subject to government approval and is expected to be completed in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>Based in Mukilteo, Wash., Marine has about 650 employees in six states.  The agreement includes the acquisition of the Mukilteo facility and the assumption of leased facilities in California, Maryland, Hawaii, Rhode Island, Texas and Washington.</p>
<p>No change in the work force is anticipated.</p>
<p>&quot;The Marine Systems Group provides a very good fit with the existing product lines of Hughes' naval systems,&quot; said John Weaver, executive vice president of Hughes Electronics and president and chief operating officer of Hughes Aircraft.</p>
<p>&quot;Both torpedoes and undersea surveillance are core Hughes technologies, and the addition of Marine Systems will make the Hughes team more competitive, both in the domestic and international markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Marine manufactures torpedoes, an underwater surveillance system and a mine neutralisation system for anti-mine warfare.</p>
<p>Major programmes of the Hughes naval and maritime systems business unit, which employs about 1,100 people at facilities in Fullerton and San Diego, Calif., and Rhode Island, include ocean surveillance and sonar systems, torpedoes and various radar, directional and defence systems.</p>
<p>Hughes, owned by General Motors Corp., designs, manufactures and markets advanced electronics systems. The company, which has more than 84,000 employees worldwide and had 1995 revenues of $14.8 billion, comprises Hughes Aircraft Co., Hughes Telecommunications Co., Hughes Network Systems Inc., Delco Electronics Corp. and DIRECTV Inc.</p>
<p>Alliant Techsystems is a $1.2 billion aerospace and defence company that has approximately 7,600 employees in 24 states. The company, with headquarters in Hopkins, Minn., is comprised of four business groups:  Aerospace Systems, Defence Systems, Marine Systems and Emerging Business.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
