<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="273816" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: World Markets Overnight Summary - Dec 23.</title>
<headline>World Markets Overnight Summary - Dec 23.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>WORLD MARKETS ROUND-UP</p>
<p>    STOCKS			  GOLD		    METALS</p>
<p>NY Dow close		 London opening	    LME close</p>
<p>  6,473.64 (+126.87)	  $368.85	    copper per tonne</p>
<p>Nikkei latest		  CRUDE OIL		 $2,227.0</p>
<p> 19,644.94 (+74.27)	  Jan Brent	   zinc per tonne</p>
<p>FTSE close			 $24.45		  $1,033.5</p>
<p>4,051.3  (+33.1)</p>
<p>HOPING SANTA IS KIND TO WALL STREET</p>
<p>By Jeffrey Benkoe</p>
<p>Santa Claus is expected to be kind to Wall Street this week, with the rally in U.S. stocks continuing, although many traders will use the mid-week Christmas holiday to extend their vacations.</p>
<p>&quot;The sentiment is predominantly bullish,&quot; said Roy Blumberg, chief investment strategist at Josephthal Lyon &amp; Ross. &quot;Even though people are paying lip service to the idea of a correction, they are not putting their money where their mouths are.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;(Thinking) bearish and buying is not (being) bearish,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones Industrial average closed about 180 points higher last week, lending credence to the theory of the Santa Clause Rally.</p>
<p>&quot;Santa Clause comes to Wall Street nearly every year, and brings a short, sweet, respectable rally,&quot; said Yale Hirch in the Stock Trader's Almanac, noting that in the past 43 years, a bull market has failed to appear only ten times.</p>
<p>Analysts expect Santa to bring more good cheer this week. &quot;At the beginning of the week, the market is likely to pull back,&quot; said Blumberg. &quot;Typically, when you get a strong triple witching, you give back some of those gains earlier in the week.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;After that, it will pick up, and have an upside bias at the end of the week as investors try to do window dressing,&quot; Blumberg added.</p>
<p>Strategists warned that recent volatility -- including a 220-point drop in the Dow in the first two weeks of December -- will still be a factor.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we're going to have a lot of volatility, with a lot of market rotation between sectors,&quot; said Graham Tanaka, president of Tanaka Capital Management. &quot;Look for more volatility among the big-cap stocks, as people try to do window dressing.&quot;</p>
<p>Mutual fund portfolio managers who have underperformed the S&amp;P 500 Index this year will use the last days of 1996 to get rid of poor performers and bulk up on the stocks that have done well, such as International Business Machines Corp., Intel Corp., Microsoft Corp..</p>
<p>The market will get little direction from new economic data, analysts said. On Monday at 8:30 a.m. EST, the U.S. Commerce Department announces personal income data for November, with the forecast at up 0.6 percent. The October personal income was unchanged.</p>
<p>On Friday at 8:30 a.m. EST, jobless claims are due. The forecast calls for 346,000 for the week ending Dec. 21, versus 351,000 in the previous week. Also, the Commerce Department issues durable goods data for November, with the consensus at up 0.1 percent. The October durable goods orders rose 0.3 pct.</p>
<p>Some strategists see the recent hard-fought market gains as a reason for traders to seek calm.</p>
<p>&quot;Over the very short term, we see a positive trend remaining intact,&quot; said Gary Anderson of Anderson &amp; Loe, a Eugene, Ore.-based money management firm. &quot;The market has just had a couple of heroic days. After that kind of effort, the tendency is for people to rest a bit.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts also noted that the Dow was not far from the record close of 6,547.</p>
<p>&quot;We're getting up to the old highs &quot; Anderson said. &quot;Some supply needs to be worked through, so the tendency is for that supply to put a cap on the market.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
