<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="273861" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: YEAREND - &quot;Life on Mars&quot; story energizes space exploration.</title>
<headline>YEAREND - &quot;Life on Mars&quot; story energizes space exploration.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Zabarenko</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>When future historians look back on 1996, they may bypass political change and economic ferment in favour of some of the most cosmic news ever to hit the headlines: the report that there might be life on Mars.</p>
<p>Ever since the August day when U.S. space scientists unveiled a chunk of grey rock alleged to contain biological fossils from Mars, the world's imagination has been fired by the possibility we might not be alone in the solar system.</p>
<p>A later report of polar ice on the Moon -- possibly the remnant of a comet's dusty tail -- further fuelled fascination.</p>
<p>But decades-old space technology showed a troubling tendency to break down at crucial moments, sending a $300 million Russian Mars probe crashing back to Earth, keeping shuttle astronauts from taking a scheduled space walk and stranding U.S. scientist Shannon Lucid aboard the Russian Mir station.</p>
<p>These two factors -- the decline of old technology and the rise in interest in extraterrestrial life -- have helped push the National Aeronautics and Space Administration away from years of emphasis on human exploration of space and towards a focus on space-faring robots, telescopes and other machines.</p>
<p>ROBOTS WILL BLAZE THE TRAIL</p>
<p>&quot;We shouldn't be sending people until we do some reconnaissance with robots,&quot; NASA chief Dan Goldin told reporters before the launch of Sojourner, a remote-controlled vehicle the size of a large toy truck meant to survey the Martian surface like a mechanical geologist.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think a robot has the dexterity or the ability to reason like a human has, but it's unreasonable to just say let's go send a human to Mars and feel good when the nation has a whole variety of financial issues to face up to,&quot; Goldin said.</p>
<p>Goldin's best guess was that human beings could venture to Mars in the second decade of the 21st century.</p>
<p>But the tantalizing question of whether Mars might support life could be answered before that, in 2003, when the first samples of rock collected on Mars could be returned to Earth.</p>
<p>The reported biological Martian fossils were found in Antarctica, presumably from a meteorite that fell to Earth from Mars 16 million years ago. If the fossils collected on Mars match the fossils from Antarctica, scientists would have much more to go on in their quest for Martian life.</p>
<p>ANYONE OUT THERE?</p>
<p>The United States will continue to conduct staffed space flights aboard the ageing space shuttle fleet and in cooperation with the Russian Mir, and the long-delayed launch of the first element of the $17 billion international space station is set to take place in 1997.</p>
<p>However, astronomical discoveries are gaining pride of place in the global debate over outer space.</p>
<p>A spate of startling images from the repaired Hubble Space Telescope have stimulated speculation on whether life exists outside our solar system, when the universe began, how stars are born and how old the oldest heavenly bodies are.</p>
<p>In the last 12 months, Hubble has shown astronomers a Texas-sized dust storm on Mars, a movie of Neptune's wild weather, a blinking pulsar twirling at the heart of the Crab Nebula and the results of a smashup between two distant galaxies.</p>
<p>In addition to pretty pictures, NASA is also stressing the philosophical and scientific implications of the search for cosmic beginnings in its so-called Origins programme.</p>
<p>At a White House meeting on the subject, religious, scientific and policy leaders framed the essential questions they said might be answered in the next 15 years.</p>
<p>These included:</p>
<p>-- when and how primitive life emerged on Earth;</p>
<p>-- whether there is or was life on Mars;</p>
<p>-- whether the presence of water on one of Jupiter's moons might harbour primitive life;</p>
<p>-- whether other planetary systems might foster life;</p>
<p>-- how the early stages of the universe unfolded.</p>
<p>For some, the question of whether extraterrestrial life exists is not even an issue.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, definitely, there's life out there,&quot; Mike Kaplan, director of NASA's Origins programme, said earlier in the year. &quot;I don't think we're alone ... We'll take some time to contact them, but one day we will meet them and we will be surprised because they will be very different from us.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
