<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="27396" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: IATA condemns British move on airport noise.</title>
<headline>IATA condemns British move on airport noise.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Air Transport Association (IATA) said on Monday that London's key position as an world airline hub could be threatened by a British government decision to impose more stringent airport noise controls.</p>
<p>IATA, which links 232 major international carriers, said its members opposed the move which they regarded as discriminatory.</p>
<p>The measures, to be applied from next January to departures from London's three airports -- Heathrow, Gatwick and Stansted -- would have no impact on the overall perceptions of aircraft noise experienced by people living close to the airports, an IATA statement said.</p>
<p>It said aircraft engines were quieter than ever before, noise infringements had never been fewer and older and noisier so-called Chapter 2 aircraft would have disappeared altogether by the year 2002 under a long-standing international agreement.</p>
<p>Next year, IATA said, more than 90 per cent of flights at Heathrow -- the British capital's main airport and a major international hub -- would be made by the world's quietest airliners, listed as Chapter 3 aircraft.</p>
<p>The statement said IATA members concern over the British measures centred around operations with older models of the Boeing 747.</p>
<p>&quot;These, in common with other Chapter 2 aircraft, are rapidly being replaced, but at the moment they form a high proportion of the fleets of non-U.K. (United Kingdom) long-haul airlines,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.K.'s unilateral decision, without consultation with its air-trading partners, could have serious effects on foreign relations and on the pre-eminent position of London's airports in world transport,&quot; IATA added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
