<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274024" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American General to buy Home Beneficial.</title>
<headline>American General to buy Home Beneficial.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>American General Corp., one of the nation's largest diversified financial services groups, said Monday it has a definitive agreement to acquire Home Beneficial Corp. for $665 million.</p>
<p>American General, one of the most aggressive buyers in the consolidating insurance industry, said Home Beneficial shareholders can choose to be paid in either cash or common stock under the $39 per share deal.</p>
<p>Up to half the total price will be paid in cash, and up to 75 percent in American General stock.</p>
<p>The news sent Home Beneficial's stock surging $8.75 or almost 30 percent early on Nasdaq. American General edged down 12.5 cents to $40.125 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;Home Beneficial is an excellent strategic fit with our Nashville-based life insurance subsidiary,&quot; said Robert M. Devlin, president and chief executive of American General.</p>
<p>&quot;Through the combination of these two companies, we believe we can achieve economies of scale resulting in annual expense savings of $20 million.&quot;</p>
<p>The deal is expected to close at the end of March and stop weighing on earnings within a year after that, he said.</p>
<p>The deal is American General's third life insurance company acquisition in the past two years, for a total cost of $2.2 billion, and strengthens the company's position as one of the nation's five biggest life insurers on the basis of sales.</p>
<p>Moreover, the Houston-based company will gain economies of scale and a boost to earnings at a time when sales of conventional life insurance policies are falling for many companies, analysts said.</p>
<p>American General, with assets of $64 billion, is a leading provider of retirement services, consumer loans, and life insurance to nine million households.</p>
<p>Founded in 1899 and based in Richmond, Va., Home Beneficial has assets of $1.4 billion and $11 billion in life insurance in force. Home Beneficial had net income of $38 million over the past year. It is the holding company of Home Beneficial Life Insurance Co., which operates in six Mid-Atlantic states and Washington, D.C., through more than 1,000 agents and sales managers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
