<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274291" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK governor and future leader head for first talks. [CORRECTED 07:00 GMT]</title>
<headline>HK governor and future leader head for first talks. [CORRECTED 07:00 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Dominic Lau</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's Governor Chris Patten and its future leader Tung Chee-hwa prepared for first talks on Monday after a weekend of bitter exchanges over China's creation of a post-colonial legislature.</p>
<p>The two men were scheduled to meet late on Monday to explore ways to cooperate in the final six months before the British colony reverts to Beijing's sovereignty next July 1.</p>
<p>The meeting is taking place in the wake of China's snub to Britain on Saturday when a Beijing-backed panel named a provisional legislature that will replace the elected chamber when the colony is handed back to the mainland. The handover, at midnight next June 30, is 190 days away.</p>
<p>It is their first meeting since shipping magnate Tung was chosen by the China-controlled Selection Committee to succeed the governor.</p>
<p>Patten has said that for the sake of a successful transition he will do all he can to help Tung, within the confines of Sino- British treaty agreements on the handover.</p>
<p>Patten lashed out at the creation of the provisional lawmaking body on Saturday, calling its appointment by the 400-member Selection Committee &quot;a bizarre farce&quot; and a &quot;stomach-churning&quot; process.</p>
<p>&quot;What it shows about China is that here it is taking over responsibility for a First World economy but they're trying to foist on us political institutions which a Third World country would reject,&quot; Patten said.</p>
<p>&quot;Here we are having foisted on us institutions which, frankly, you wouldn't try to run a tennis club with.&quot;</p>
<p>Speaking after the legislature was created in the Chinese frontier city of Shenzhen, 59-year-old Tung clashed sharply with Patten and called on Britain to face up to reality.</p>
<p>He said it was irresponsible of Britain to threaten to take Beijing to the International Court of Justice over the interim chamber. &quot;I don't think it's a very good suggestion. We are talking about the interests of six million people. It is not good for the Hong Kong people,&quot; Tung said.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot have a legal vacuum in 1997. This is a great day for Hong Kong,&quot; Tung said, punching the air with his hand.</p>
<p>British Foreign Minister Malcolm Rifkind said last week China should go with Britain to the World Court for a ruling on the legality of the new assembly.</p>
<p>China founded the interim assembly to replace the elected chamber after the handover to reverse electoral reforms which Patten introduced in recent years, reforms which have expanded democracy in the colony.</p>
<p>The controversial new body is dominated by pro-Beijing figures -- including 33 incumbent lawmakers and many politicians who lost to pro-democracy forces in the 1995 Legislative Council election, which was the first time all seats were filled by vote, either direct or indirect (corrects to make clear not all seats were directly elected).</p>
<p>&quot;These officials will now have every incentive to pass laws to ensure that they will never again be humiliated in genuine elections,&quot; Democratic Party Chairman Martin Lee wrote in the International Herald Tribune newspaper on Monday.</p>
<p>The Democratic Party, the favourite in last year's election with 19 of the 60 council seats, boycotted moves to create the provisional body, branding it anti-democratic.</p>
<p>The Provisional Legislative Council, as it will be known, is to sit from July 1 until a new legislature can be constituted by elections, set for 1998.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
