<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274207" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks end higher on property optimism.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks end higher on property optimism.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks bounded ahead to close Monday up, with the rally fueled by a turnaround in the Dow and an improved outlook for the local real estate market, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Wall Street turned around, so Hong Kong has a squeeze on the short positions, said Andrew To, dealing director at OSK Asia Securities.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index closed 200.07 points higher at 13,331.48 after touching a high of 13,361.24. Turnover was a robust HK$9.14 billion, well up on Friday's HK$6.97 billion, although inflated by share placements.</p>
<p>&quot;The Dow Jones Industrial Average turned around so dramatically. Now it is trading about 100 points below the historical high. So the whole situation changed,&quot; added To.</p>
<p>The Dow ended 10.76 points up at 6,484.40 in volatile trade on Friday, gaining nearly 200 points in a week.</p>
<p>Brokers also said investors believed the government will now not take any action to cool down the Hong Kong property market.</p>
<p>Anti-speculation measures taken by the developers themselves, such as allowing only a number of limited companies to buy flats in each development, appeared likely to forestall direct government intervention in the real estate market.</p>
<p>The good response to Sino Land's sale of luxury residential properties over the weekend also cheered sentiment, brokers said. The latest sales price of HK$5,628 per sq ft was 15.3 percent higher than the price of units offered two months earlier.</p>
<p>Share placements by Sino Land and another property counter did not dampen market sentiment, brokers said.</p>
<p>Sino Land parent company Tsim Sha Tsui Properties placed 238 million shares at HK$9.13 each, netting Sino Land HK$2.12 billion after expenses. Sino Land closed down HK$0.30 at HK$9.30 after bouncing off a low of HK$9.15, while Tsim Sha Tsui Properties rose HK$0.30 to HK$15.20.</p>
<p>Kong Tai International placed 582 million new shares at HK$0.25 a share. The stock rose HK$0.16 to HK$0.39 on turnover of HK$296.65 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Sino Land's fund raising has long been expected. It was just a matter of time, said Y.K. Fu, property analyst at Merrill Lynch, adding this placement was an isolated case and not the start of a trend of share placements by property firms.</p>
<p>The property sector led the rally, substantially outperforming the rest of the market.</p>
<p>New World Development put on HK$3.05 to HK$51.75 and Cheung Kong advanced HK$2.75 to HK$68.75.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
