<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274323" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Rubber - Light Christmas trade seen, prices steady.</title>
<headline>Rubber - Light Christmas trade seen, prices steady.</headline>
<byline>Rene Pastor</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trading in Southeast Asia's rubber markets will probably be thin this Christmas week although prices are seen holding steady as rains pinch supplies in Malaysia and Thailand, dealers said on Monday.</p>
<p>With Japan closed on Monday to celebrate the birthday of Emperor Akihito and most other regional markets shut down on Wednesday, Christmas Day, dealers said there was very little incentive to do any kind of business.  </p>
<p>&quot;Everybody is already off on their holidays,&quot; said a dealer for a Japanese rubber trading firm in Singapore. &quot;It's going to be quiet until New Year and the show will only begin again after the holidays are over.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Producers also want to take it easy until the New Year,&quot; said another trader in Kuala Lumpur. &quot;If they're going to sell now, there has to be a good premium.&quot;</p>
<p>The only positive feature in the market was heavy rain in the main rubber-growing regions of Malaysia and Thailand that hindered tapping, resulting in tighter supplies which kept rubber prices well-supported, traders said.  </p>
<p>But regional rubber prices may start sliding if demand, already hammered by the holiday period lull, remained soft, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's been too much rain in the last few weeks and some estates (plantations) had to just stop tapping rubber at some intervals,&quot; another trader in Kuala Lumpur said.</p>
<p>&quot;The tightness in latex and supply of other materials have kept prices somewhat firm. Otherwise, we'd be seeing much lower prices,&quot; another Malaysian trader added.  </p>
<p>The Malaysian Rubber Exchange and Licensing Board quoted the benchmark RSS1 rubber at 316.50 Malaysian cents a kg and the SMR20 at 308 cents a kg, both for January buyer, at the close of the market last week.</p>
<p>In Thailand, rains and some pre-holiday buying from Japan helped shore up prices, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The tight supply could continue well into January due to this unseasonably long monsoon in the south,&quot; said Sucharit Promdej of the Rubber Research Institute. &quot;Tapping activity dropped substantially because of the rains.&quot;  </p>
<p>Only 45,942 kg of sheet rubber entered the market last week, a 9.77 percent drop from the previous week. More than 100,000 kg of sheet rubber entered the market during the same period last year, auction market sources said.</p>
<p>The benchmark RSS3 for January shipment was quoted around US$1.25-$1.26 a kg FOB Bangkok compared with the previous $1.24-$1.25 a kg, traders said. Tight supplies also pushed latex prices up to $0.94-$0.95 a kg from the previous $0.94 a kg.</p>
<p>Indonesian benchmark tyre-grade SIR20 rubber prices were also seen staying firm this week, but trading volume may be low because of the holidays, dealers said.  </p>
<p>Dealers said February/March SIR20 offer prices were likely to stay at 55.25-55.75 U.S. cents/lb FOB Medan, 55.00-55.50 cents/lb FOB Surabaya, Padang and Palembang as well as at 54.75-55.25 cents/lb FOB Pontianak and Jambi.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect further short-covering, but volume is likely to be much lighter,&quot; one dealer in Medan said.</p>
<p>A trader in Jakarta said there were fresh enquiries from Europe for January/February RSS1 at 120.00 U.S. cents/kg FOB Semarang, but they were far below his offer price of 127.00 cents/kg.  </p>
<p>He said RSS1 prices would probably weaken, with prices seen falling to around 125.00 cents/kg.</p>
<p>(With contributions from Thailand, Malaysia and Indonesia)</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
