<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274451" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: YEAR - Central banks cast big shadow over 1997 gold price.</title>
<headline>YEAR - Central banks cast big shadow over 1997 gold price.</headline>
<byline>Michael Shields</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold bugs head into 1997 gripped by the fear that European central banks will dump big chunks of their reserves to raise money to plug budget holes and qualify for Europe's single currency project.</p>
<p>So while many analysts think gold has found solid ground around $365 an ounce and should move in a relatively narrow range next year, they say the future depends largely on whether dust-covered official reserves come pouring on to the market.</p>
<p>&quot;The uncertainty surrounding central banks is a cloud that will remain over the gold market for the next 12 months,&quot; said Kevin Crisp, a metals analyst at J.P. Morgan in London who sees gold moving in a range of $350 to $400 in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;I think 1997 could actually be quite a critical year for the gold market,&quot; he said. &quot;There are some key issues that still need to be properly addressed. In 1997 we could possibly see some clarification of central banks' relationship with gold.&quot;</p>
<p>Rumours of official gold sales weighed heavily on prices in 1996, when prices above $400 early in the year would not hold, but the secretive nature of central banks kept many traders guessing about the true extent of transactions.</p>
<p>ROLLERCOASTER MARKET COULD EMERGE</p>
<p>&quot;We are almost certain that there is at least one central bank in the market selling now,&quot; said Ted Arnold at Merrill Lynch in London. &quot;But we expect to see more European central bank selling in 1997 as governments rush to try to meet their European Union monetary commitments.&quot;</p>
<p>Countries trying to be founding members of the single euro currency in 1999 must cap their budget deficits at three percent of gross domestic product in 1997, the deadline for qualifying for the first wave of economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>Arnold saw gold dropping as low as $330 next year in volatile trading that could include days of panic selling.</p>
<p>&quot;We are hoping that rising central bank sales during 1997 coupled with producer and bullion house selling will continue to erode the gold price away,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This steady price erosion should be reinforced by more and more fund selling as the technicals increasingly turn bearish,&quot; he added, but suggested a sharp plunge would trigger fresh buying that could catapult gold back toward $390.</p>
<p>UNDERLYING DEMAND SEEN AS STRONG</p>
<p>Not all analysts are convinced that central banks will be big sellers, or even sell into the market if they sell at all.</p>
<p>&quot;There are fears that central banks will sell before EMU. I tend not to believe this because the time horizon is so short. They could not because the ounce price would collapse,&quot; said Donald Feliser at CS Research in Zurich.</p>
<p>He said banks that do sell would probably do business with other central banks so supplies do not hit the open market.</p>
<p>Germany, Austria and Switzerland will also keep teaming up to prevent the International Monetary Fund from selling gold reserves, at least for the time being, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;If you remove these two negative factors, there remains robust demand, which really is robust,&quot; he said, citing Southeast Asia as a growing market for gold. He was cautiously optimistic gold would stay between $365 and $390 in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the discussion about sales by central banks will play less of a role next year and I can imagine we will move in a range between $370 and $395,&quot; said Hanspeter Hausherr at SBC Warburg in Zurich.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not completely rule out a sudden movement -- up or down -- as we saw in January and February this year, but if you look at the year as a whole than I think we will see a range similar to what we had this year.&quot;</p>
<p>GOOD GROWTH, LOW INFLATION BAD FOR GOLD</p>
<p>Fundamentally, the supply of gold should not cover demand in 1997, analysts say, but mine output is slowly rising and key consumers, especially in Asia, are not showing the appetite they once did. Scrap recycling could also cut demand for new gold.</p>
<p>&quot;If 1996 was a year of consolidation after record-breaking levels of fabrication demand in 1995, then next year hopefully we'll be back to a reasonable level of growth again, but it may be a little slower than in the past,&quot; Crisp said.</p>
<p>He and other analysts said gold could also get a boost if sizzling stock markets cool off and encourage a shift of funds out of equities into other assets. That at least would lend some lustre to gold's largely lost function as a store of value.</p>
<p>&quot;Its role as a hedge against inflation doesn't really seem to be needed at this time of the best of all worlds: reasonable levels of economic growth and low inflation,&quot; Crisp said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
