<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274438" id="root" date="1996-12-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Arthuis says franc/mark exchange rate appropriate.</title>
<headline>Arthuis says franc/mark exchange rate appropriate.</headline>
<dateline>DUSSELDORF, Germany 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>French finance minister Jean Arthuis was quoted on Monday as saying that the current exchange rate between the French franc and the German mark appropriately affected fundamental economic conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;The franc-mark exchange rate is good because it reflects the real economic situation,&quot; Arthuis told German business daily Handelsblatt in an interview published on Monday.</p>
<p>Former German Chancellor Helmut Schmidt and former French president Valery Giscard D'Estaing said in separate newspaper interviews last week that adherance to strong currencies by France and Germany was damaging growth and that both the franc and the mark were overvalued.  </p>
<p>Arthuis says franc/mark exchange rate appropriate</p>
<p>Arthuis also rejected a proposal by Giscard D'Estaing to fix the franc at a rate of seven to the Euro, a rate that would be more favourable to exporters than the current rate of about 6.5, Handelsblatt said.</p>
<p>&quot;My countrymen would not be prepared to accept the wealth loss of about eight percent that that would entail,&quot; Arthuis said.</p>
<p>Arthuis also said France would continue budgetary consolidation to qualify for launching the Euro, Handelsblatt said.</p>
<p>He said the consolidation would be painful in 1998 as the state would not again be able to resort to the one-off transfer from France Telecom to government funds, which reduced the 1997 budget deficit by 37.5 billion francs.</p>
<p>The French government would make every political effort to present a budget for 1998 that would contain structural reforms, Arthuis said.</p>
<p>Arthuis also predicted in the interview that France's budget deficit in 1997 would not exceed the ceiling of three percent of gross domestic product (GDP) set by Maastricht, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>Meeting the goal would be made easier by economic growth, he said. &quot;It seems as though the growth forecast of 2.3 percent will rather be at the lower limit of economic growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Commenting on the stability pact on budget discipline agreed by European Union leaders at the Dublin summit on December 13, Arthuis said the agreement would not open the door to a casual approach to government housekeeping.</p>
<p>Germany had wanted the pact to impose sanctions automatically on states that exceeded the fiscal criteria but in the end made concessions to France and other defenders of national sovereignty by allowing for a political judgement on whether to levy fines on those who overspend.</p>
<p>&quot;It had to be guaranteed that the Council remained sovereign in its decisions. The computers must not be allowed to decide,&quot; Arthuis said.</p>
<p>He described the Dublin compromise not as a French victory over the German position but as a &quot;victory for Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>He also denied public speculation in France that relations with Germany had been strained. The discussion over the stability pact was &quot;open and difficult but had remained friendly,&quot; Arthuis said.</p>
<p>--David Crossland, Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUSSELDORF, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
