<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="27445" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU speeds up its talks on a new treaty.</title>
<headline>EU speeds up its talks on a new treaty.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Gaunt</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Negotiations on changes to the Maastricht Treaty are to speed up over the next few months as pressure mounts for the inter-governmental conference (IGC) to stay on track.</p>
<p>A draft treaty is to be prepared by the end of the year, and EU leaders are to meet in a special European Council in Ireland in October to discuss the direction the bloc should take as it prepares for an influx of new members.</p>
<p>The idea is to wrap up the IGC by the middle of next year -- at the end of the Dutch presidency -- allowing for negotiations with applicant countries to begin by the end of 1997 or the beginning of 1998.</p>
<p>EU sources said heads of state and government were keen to wrap up this latest review of the EU treaty as soon as possible -- but for a number of differing reasons.</p>
<p>France, for example, worries that delaying the IGC would mean ratification bumping up against its next elections. British Prime Minister John Major also wants the negotiations -- highly controversial among Euro-sceptics in his Conservative Party -- out of the way.</p>
<p>Even Luxembourg, which takes over the EU presidency in the second half of next year, is said to be eager not to have to host the end of the IGC but to be able to focus on pending economic and monetary union (EMU) instead.</p>
<p>But despite the new intensity of purpose, officials in Brussels say many member states remain unwilling to show their hand in negotiations until other issues facing the bloc, including the single currency and future EU finances, have become clearer.</p>
<p>&quot;Can you expect a country to be ready to make a compromise on the treaty (without decisions on) big important issues such as structural funds, and the ins and outs (of EMU),&quot; said one EU diplomat.</p>
<p>Others have said that countries are also unwilling to begin making serious concessions before the British elections, believing a change of government will make it easier for the IGC to achieve agreement.</p>
<p>But even then, officials say, what emerges from the IGC will almost certainly be a modest adjustment to the landmark Maastricht Treaty and not a radical new step towards European integration.</p>
<p>Impetus for accelerating the negotiations has been a belief that since treaty talks began in Turin in March, they have been little more that an airing of individual countries' positions.</p>
<p>&quot;They (negotiators) have gone through the whole treaty now a couple of times,&quot; the diplomat said.</p>
<p>There has been widespread agreement on the need for a more organised approach to the bloc's Common Foreign and Security Policy (CFSP) which is likely to mean the setting up of a forward planning unit in the Council of Ministers.</p>
<p>Who will head the unit -- a top-level bureaucrat or a high-profile Mr or Ms CFSP -- remains in question.</p>
<p>Most EU countries also want the fight against unemployment to be formalised somehow by being included in the treaty, with some countries calling for a special Employment Chapter.</p>
<p>Irish Finance Minister Ruairi Quinn has suggested this might mean the creation of an Employment Committee to work something like the Monetary Committee.</p>
<p>Diplomats said at least 10 countries are in favour of some kind of employment language, although Germany and Britain remain firmly opposed to anything too stringent, fearing it could lead to centralised meddling in what they believe to be a largely local issue.</p>
<p>The five months of talks have also made it clear that the new treaty will contain some system for improving efficiency in the Third Pillar.</p>
<p>The issue is how, given strong opposition among some member states to watering down the inter-governmental nature of the justice and home affairs.</p>
<p>Some officials have suggested that what may emerge is a system in which special Third Pillar directives and regulations, rather than conventions and treaties, are issued inter-governmentally without a role for the European Commission or the European Parliament.</p>
<p>Some treaty language is also expected concerning joint defence issues, particularly in light of NATO's recent agreement to allow the Western European Union (WEU) to use its equipment for peacekeeping and humanitarian projects.</p>
<p>Britain, one of the EU's two defence powers, is firmly opposed to any move to incorporate the WEU within the Union. It has said, however, that WEU summits and EU summits could be held back to back.</p>
<p>Others envision having the EU direct the WEU in so-called Petersburg tasks (humanitarian, peace-keeping). This in part stems from an idea proposed by Sweden and Finland, two neutrals with only observer status in the WEU.</p>
<p>On internal EU decision making, there is widespread agreement that changes need to be made to allow the EU to work with another dozen or so members, but little sign yet of the required unanimity over what to do.</p>
<p>Britain remains opposed to an extension of Qualified Majority Voting. It is alone in being opposed in principle, but has allies in various areas -- for example, Greece in CFSP matters and Luxembourg concerning taxation.</p>
<p>The bloc's smaller countries also remain steadfast against any change in their representation in the Commission or as EU president.</p>
<p>What promises to be a key debate over so-called flexibility -- the right of some countries to integrate faster than others -- has also moved forward, with most countries favouring the concept being incorporated into the treaty.</p>
<p>Again, however, no agreement has been reached over how.</p>
<p>France and Germany have called for a general clause permitting flexibility across a broad swathe of issues. Others, however, have argued that flexibility should be specific and limited to certain areas.</p>
<p>A report issued last month by the London-based European Policy Forum noted that most EU leaders have come out in favour of flexibility but that each has a different notion of what it means.</p>
<p>Some countries, meanwhile, have started worrying about the process that will follow an IGC pact -- ratification.</p>
<p>Officials have noted the potential for some countries to hold up ratification in order to press the others to give them what they want -- structural funds, a smaller contribution to EU finances or preferential treatment to a particular applicant country.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
