<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274529" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London shares at third consecutive closing high.</title>
<headline>London shares at third consecutive closing high.</headline>
<byline>Ron Askew</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>London shares rang up their third consecutive record close on Tuesday but trading across the rest of Europe was featureless with many dealers finishing early for the Christmas holiday and German markets shut.</p>
<p>London's FTSE 100 index ended a truncated session 5.3 points higher at 4,092.5 after muted activity, just 7.5 points below its record intra-day high reached last Friday and with some traders predicting a January rally.</p>
<p>&quot;You couldn't tell from today because there was no interest at all but I think the market still has a good tone to it,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;Sterling is still strong and it looks like interest rates are probably going to rise soon, but that hasn't unnerved the market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Most institutions aren't in the market and those that are can't afford to sell,&quot; added another who was looking for a test of the 4,100 level for the FTSE in early January.</p>
<p>British November trade figures, broadly in line with market expectations, failed to generate interest. The October global trade deficit was 454 million pounds ($760 million) against market forecasts for a 659 million shortfall and September's revised 1.06 billion deficit.</p>
<p>In Paris, French shares ended with small gain made in modest volume on the back of gains on Wall Street, having spent most of the morning in the minus column once an initial bout of buying for the first account day was spent.</p>
<p>&quot;There's really nothing to say about this market, everybody's thinking about their capon and champagne,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index ended up 2.11 points at 2,289.55, at which point Wall Street's Dow Jones index was up 23.83 points, or around 0.37 percent, at 6512.85.</p>
<p>The dollar was steady in narrow ranges as turnover dwindled to a trickle before the Christmas break. With Germany and some other European centres closed, London was set to stop currency trading soon after midsession.</p>
<p>At 1600 GMT the dollar was at 1.5555 marks, unchanged from Monday's late level, and 114.45 yen, up from 114.12.</p>
<p>Sterling was below earlier highs on profit taking despite the narrowing of the British trade shortfall.</p>
<p>Traders said that with the last British economic data of this year now out of the way, investors had banked profits made during sterling's recent strong rally.</p>
<p>The pound was at 2.6027 marks against Monday's 2.6015 and at $1.6739 against a previous $1.6710. It earlier touched high of 2.6088 and $1.6780.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1600 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was quoted around 1.5555 marks and 114.45 yen compared with 1.5555 and 114.12 in late European trade on Monday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS CLOSING PRICES</p>
<p>The FTSE 100 index of leading British shares ended a shortened session up 5.3 points at 4,092.5.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share ended up 2.11 points at 2,289.55.</p>
<p>Frankfurt was closed for the Christmas holiday. The 30-share DAX index had fallen 8.88 points on Monday to 2,845.57.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold fixed at $368.90 during the morning compared with $368.85 an ounce in late trade on Monday.</p>
<p>($1=.5977 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
