<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274503" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA BASKETBALL-SPURS' ROBINSON BREAKS FOOT, TO MISS SIX WEEKS.</title>
<headline>NBA BASKETBALL-SPURS' ROBINSON BREAKS FOOT, TO MISS SIX WEEKS.</headline>
<dateline>SAN ANTONIO, Texas 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>San Antonio Spurs star centre David Robinson, who missed the first 18 games of the season with back pain, was placed on the injured list Tuesday after suffering a broken left foot.</p>
<p>Robinson is expected to miss approximately six weeks and was scheduled to undergo surgery Friday to insert a screw into his fifth metatarsal.</p>
<p>The seven-time All-Star centre, who this year was voted one of the 50 greatest players in NBA history, suffered the injury during the fourth quarter of Monday's 90-79 home loss to the Miami Heat. He left the court and was taken for X-rays, which revealed a non-displaced fracture.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems like I've been snake-bit all year,&quot; said Robinson following the game. &quot;I could feel it when it happened and I was praying that it wasn't broken, but it was.&quot;</p>
<p>The 1995 NBA Most Valuable Player had led the Spurs to the best record in the Midwest Division the last two seasons. But San Antonio went 3-15 over the first 18 games without Robinson this season, leading to the firing of coach Bob Hill.</p>
<p>General Manager Gregg Popovich replaced Hill for the game in which Robinson returned and the team went 3-2 before Monday's matchup with the Heat.</p>
<p>Robinson, the team's leading scorer, rebounder and shot-blocker, had 18 points and six rebounds before leaving Monday's game injured.</p>
<p>The 31-year-old Robinson averaged 25 points, 12.2 rebounds and 3.4 blocks per game last season.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN ANTONIO, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
