<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274568" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE gas oil barges firmer, cargoes pursue arbs.</title>
<headline>NWE gas oil barges firmer, cargoes pursue arbs.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A variety of widening transatlantic and Asian arbitrage plays dominated an otherwise quiet NWE gas oil cargo market on Tuesday while barges saw light end of year business, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The arbs are open everywhere. The difficulty is in finding a vessel,&quot; one cargo trader said.</p>
<p>Heating oil and low sulphur diesel was open from U.S. Gulf to NWE, while Russians were open to Asia from the Baltic port of Ventspils and reportedly to New York from other European ports.</p>
<p>Two vessel were reported fixed from U.S. Gulf to NWE for low sulphur diesel but values were not immediately available.</p>
<p>In NWE, low sulphur diesel cargoes for January were easier at Jan IPE +$10/12 for smaller parcels and around Jan IPE +$13 for larger ones. Heating oil was notionally +$4.50/5.50.</p>
<p>Jan IPE futures rose $4 to $215.50 a tonne in light book-squaring business helped by concerns over cold weather.</p>
<p>The screen rise helped firm barge heating oil premiums by around 75 cents to Jan IPE flat/+50 cents for second half December and +$1/+$2 for second half January delivery.</p>
<p>Two heating oil barges were reported sold at mid-morning at $213 and $213.25 a tonne in light book-squaring.</p>
<p>-- William Maclean London newsroom +44 1671 542 7646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
