<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274674" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Bosnia Serbs open trial against Izetbegovic.</title>
<headline>Bosnia Serbs open trial against Izetbegovic.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bosnian Serb authorities formally opened a trial on Tuesday against Bosnia's Moslem president, Alija Izetbegovic, Serb media reported.</p>
<p>Izetbegovic, chairman of the newly-elected Bosnian collective presidency which includes a Serb and a Croat member, was not present at the proceedings in Banja Luka.</p>
<p>The Bosnian Serb news agency SRNA said Serb authorities have accused Izetbegovic, who led Bosnia's bid for independence from old Yugoslavia, with &quot;war crimes&quot; against civilians, wounded, ill and prisoners of war.</p>
<p>The International Criminal Tribunal for former Yugoslavia has not charged Izetbegovic with any war crimes but has indicted 74 people so far, including wartime Serb leader Radovan Karadzic and Serb army commander Ratko Mladic.</p>
<p>The tribunal has criticised Serb authorities for refusing to extradite Karadzic, Mladic and other war crimes suspects in Bosnia's Serb republic.</p>
<p>The trial was being held in a city associated with some of the Bosnian war's worst atrocities.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of Moslems and Croats were expelled from the Banja Luka region during the war in a campaign of terror devised to carve out a separate Serb state.</p>
<p>Prosecutor Nebojsa Panic asked the court to try Izetbegovic in absentia.</p>
<p>Western diplomats said the trial could further complicate the work of the collective presidency because Serb authorities might decide to arrest Izetbegovic whenever the body meets in Serb territory on the outskirts of Sarajevo.</p>
<p>A lawyer appointed by the court to defend Izetbegovic argued that Izetbegovic enjoyed legal immunity as chairman of the collective presidency.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
