<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274646" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African stock market closing report.</title>
<headline>S.African stock market closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African shares ended largely stable on Christmas Eve, with industrials easing slightly as players squared positions. Gold shares were also softer on a steady bullion price.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has been relatively steady. There is some selling on industrials as people are squaring ahead of the year-end,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the features of the day were relatively large trades in De Beers and Anglo American, but overall volumes were thin.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not sure if we are seeing window-dressing on De Beers and Anglo or if it is real buying,&quot; one dealer said, adding that the market would firm next weeek ahead of the unit trust quartely close-out at the end of the year.</p>
<p>Golds shares were softer tracking the weaker trend in New York overnight and a dull bullion price, dealers said. Large trades took place in Kloof and Dries, they said.</p>
<p>The market was seen quiet on Friday after the two-day Christmas holiday.</p>
<p>The overall index was up 9.5 points to 6,562.1 boosted by gains in the mining financial index. The industrial index lost 10.9 points to 7,783.5 points and the gold index shed 5.6 points to 1,488.8 points.</p>
<p>De Beers added 150 cents to 135 rand, in late trade Anglos rose 750 cents to 255 rand, First National made 10 cents to 23 rand and Nampak slipped 35 cents to 17.75 rand.</p>
<p>Dries dropped 45 cents to 48.30 rand, Loraine gained 20 cents to 12.50 rand and Kloof was 75 cents weaker at 38 rand.</p>
<p>Near-term equity futures ended mixed in quiet trade, with industrials easing as players squared positions and the all-share contract firmer on the mining component of the index. Gold contracts were ignored on bullion's failure to pierce $370 per ounce.</p>
<p>Dealers said volumes traded were thin and the market was seen quiet on Friday as most players were away on holiday.</p>
<p>The March all-share contract was last at 6,065/90 from 6,046, the industrial contract was at 7,600/15 from 7,604 and the gold index was at 1,054/58 from 1,059.</p>
<p>-- Charles Phahlane, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
