<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274670" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOLDOVA: Moldova deputies back gas debt deal with Russia. [CORRECTED 12:46 GMT 26/12]</title>
<headline>Moldova deputies back gas debt deal with Russia. [CORRECTED 12:46 GMT 26/12]</headline>
<byline>Dmitry Solovyov</byline>
<dateline>CHISINAU 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Moldova's parliament on Tuesday gave its backing to a government's plan to pay a large part of the country's debt to Russia's gas monopoly Gazprom by issuing state bonds worth a total of $140 million.</p>
<p>In line with the government's agreement with Gazprom ratified by 56 votes to 14 against, the Finance Ministry will issue 2,000 bonds, worth $70,000 each, and hand them over to Gazprom.</p>
<p>Russia is the only natural gas supplier to the energy-starved and cash-short Moldova which is to get three billion (corrects from million) cubic metres of gas this year, same as in 1995.</p>
<p>By December 1, Moldova's total gas debt soared to $401 million from $281.7 million on January 1, Mihai Cebotari, head of the Energy Resources Department, told deputies.</p>
<p>He said that in line with an earlier accord with Gazprom Chisinau's officially recorded gas debt is $183.4 million. The remaining part is the debt to be paid by the country's eastern Dnepr rebel region which broke away in 1990.</p>
<p>Cebotari said the government had assumed $140 million of Chisinau's debt to Gazprom and the rest is to be paid by consumer companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Moldova is now able to pay with its goods or dollars only for some 50 percent of Russian gas imports...Gazprom has put up condition -- either we pay our debts or are disconnected from gas deliveries,&quot; he said urging the law-makers to vote.</p>
<p>Cebotari said that Moldova would get a grace period of two years during which it would only have to pay to Gazprom an annual intesrest of 7.5 percent on the $140 million bond issue.</p>
<p>But an explanatory note saying that &quot;the Moldovan side can make payments on these securities also with deliveries of material resources, stakes in its privatised companies and other means&quot;, angered some nationalist legislators.</p>
<p>&quot;This means...our children and even grandchildren will owe to, and depend on, Gazprom,&quot; said one of them, Lidia Istrati.</p>
<p>But others disagreed.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to ratify this agreement not to remain without gas this winter,&quot; said deputy parliament chairman Dumitru Motpan.</p>
<p>Cebotari said Moldova buys Russian gas much below its world price of $80 per 1,000 cubic metres because it transports large amounts to the Balkans across its territory.</p>
<p>In line with the ratified document, the bonds will be freely traded on Russian and Moldovan exchanges and over-the-counter markets, as well as in third countries. The Finance Ministry has to work out the mechanism.</p>
<p>&quot;This agreement is very advantageous for Moldova...It allows us to catch up with the necessary rate of payments for gas within the next two years,&quot; Cebotari said.</p>
<p>A delegation of Moldova's government is expected to present the ratified agreement to Gazprom officials in Moscow on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOLDV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHISINAU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOLDOVA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
