<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274729" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru prays for Christmas hostage miracle.</title>
<headline>Peru prays for Christmas hostage miracle.</headline>
<byline>Michael Stott</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marxist rebels fell silent on Tuesday on the fate that awaited their roughly 140 hostages as Peru prayed for a Christmas miracle that would set the captives free.</p>
<p>The hostages, including top Peruvian officials, Japanese businessmen and high-ranking officials from other countries, faced a nightmare Christmas in unsanitary conditions under the gun of Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels.</p>
<p>Red Cross workers brought in Italian-style cake -- traditional in many Latin American nations at Christmas -- for the captives and prepared a meal of turkey and apple sauce. A Jesuit priest held as a hostage was due to celebrate mass inside the residence.</p>
<p>Reporters outside added a seasonal touch by decorating their equipment with holiday lights and putting up a small plastic tree. Police relaxed security somewhat, allowing cars nearer to the sealed-off compound than in previous days.</p>
<p>No communication has come from the hostage-takers since Sunday, when they released most of their captives and restated demands for the release of over 400 jailed comrades -- something President Alberto Fujimori, the son of Japanese immigrants, has ruled out.</p>
<p>Rebel prisoners in various Peruvian jails chanted defiant slogans at guards, confident the mass kidnapping would secure their imminent release, a national prison source said.</p>
<p>Plunged into gloom by the crisis, Peruvians prepared for a miserable Yuletide. One local bishop, Miguel Irizar, urged his countrymen not to celebrate at all. &quot;We cannot have parties or be frivolous,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Local television played especially composed songs and messages for the captives, although the lack of electricity inside the besieged residence meant it was unlikely the hostages would hear any of them.</p>
<p>Overnight, a small group of Roman Catholic Peruvians held a candlelit vigil close to the residence.</p>
<p>&quot;The solidarity has been shown in many ways and now more than ever we pray to the Virgin Mary to soften the hearts of the captors and let all the hostages out,&quot; one woman at the ceremony said.</p>
<p>Relatives wrote seasonal messages to their loved ones on special forms, not knowing how long it would be until they were reunited.</p>
<p>Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto, whose government has most at stake in the affair after Peru because of the large number of Japanese hostages, predicted on Tuesday that the hostage crisis would be a long, drawn-out affair.</p>
<p>Lima would try to wear the guerrillas down rather than flush them out by force, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it will take time to resolve the crisis,&quot; Hashimoto told reporters shortly after speaking by telephone to Fujimori. &quot;The fact that it will take time means that no get- tough approach will be taken.&quot;</p>
<p>Fujimori's government believes the ball is now firmly in the court of the around 20 MRTA rebels and wants them to give a response before making any move, Peruvian media reported.</p>
<p>Fujimori told the rebels to surrender and release all their hostages in a stern message Saturday but since then the government has given no official information to the hordes of waiting world media.</p>
<p>Rumours have swirled thick and fast and the favourite story making the rounds among diplomats in Lima on Tuesday was that the government might be secretly negotiating a safe passage to Cuba for the rebels in exchange for the release of all the hostages.</p>
<p>A diplomat at the Cuban Embassy told Reuters that Havana's ambassador here, Pedro Diaz, conferred with Foreign Minister Roberto Robaina on Monday but declined to go into details.</p>
<p>Diaz -- who spent five days as a captive in the residence before being released with a group of 225 hostages Sunday night -- was spending Tuesday in meetings, the diplomat added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
