<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274870" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. court to let credit unions expand for now.</title>
<headline>U.S. court to let credit unions expand for now.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. appeals court Tuesday temporarily lifted portions of a lower court order that had prevented thousands of credit unions from expanding.</p>
<p>The Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia stayed part of an October order by District Court Judge Thomas Jackson arising out of a six-year legal battle between credit unions and the banking industry.</p>
<p>The stayed portion of Jackson's order had prohibited credit unions from adding new members outside a single core occupational group.  </p>
<p>Over 3,000 so-called multi-occupational credit unions will be affected by the order. While the institutions can now add members to any of their existing groups, they are still prohibited from adding new groups under a portion of Jackson's October order that remains in force.</p>
<p>&quot;This ruling recognizes the critical role credit unions play in the financial well-being of communities around our country,&quot; said Ken Robinson, president of the National Association of Federal Credit Unions.</p>
<p>The appeals court said its stay will be in effect until the U.S. Supreme Court decides whether to review the case.  </p>
<p>Banks were displeased with the order but said they were awaiting a decision by the Supreme Court and expected to prevail in the end.</p>
<p>&quot;The court of appeals did a Solomonic thing I suppose -- splitting the baby,&quot; Michael Crotty, counsel to the American Bankers Association, said. &quot;We did not get the result entirely that we wished for.&quot;</p>
<p>The Supreme Court is scheduled to discuss the credit unions' petition for certiori on January 17 and should announce if it will hear the case shortly thereafter, Crotty said.  </p>
<p>Robinson said the credit unions plan to go to Congress to seek a final resolution.</p>
<p>&quot;While this (order) is welcome, it is temporary and no substitute for congressional action that will clarify once and for all the ability of credit unions to provide choice in the financial services arena,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Jackson has scheduled a conference in the district court case for late January. If the Supreme Court agrees to review the case, Jackson is unlikely to do much more at that hearing, Crotty said.  </p>
<p>If the Supreme Court declines to hear the case, banks might ask Jackson to begin forcing credit unions to shed members served by multi-occupational credit unions.</p>
<p>&quot;There needs to be a final disposition of the case,&quot; Crotty said.</p>
<p>Traditionally, each of the non-profit credit unions had served members of a single occupation or local community. But under a 1982 policy adopted by the National Credit Union Administration, a single credit union could serve multiple distinct groups.</p>
<p>Jackson is hearing a challenge to the 1982 policy, brought by the banks in 1990 against a large North Carolina credit union, AT&amp;T Family Federal Credit.</p>
<p>((-- Aaron Pressman 202-898-8312))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
