<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274877" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dlr/Swiss firmer as pre-holiday U.S. trade wanes.</title>
<headline>Dlr/Swiss firmer as pre-holiday U.S. trade wanes.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dollar/Swiss stood higher amid fears of continued economic weakness in Switzerland as trade wound down early before Christmas, currency experts said.</p>
<p>The Swiss National Bank (SNB) already slashed its discount rate to 1.0 percent this year to help boost that nation's struggling economy. Furthermore, SNB vowed earlier in December to stick with its generous monetary policy and not raise rates until clear signs of an economic recovery emerged.</p>
<p>Diego Giurleo, vice president of Treasury at Royal Bank of Canada, said the Swiss are looking to stimulate growth by increasing demand for Swiss-made exports.  </p>
<p>&quot;And to get growth out of the export sector, one of the major tools is to get a more competitive currency, which means a weaker currency,&quot; Giurleo added.</p>
<p>The dollar surged in New York to 1.3465 francs, its highest level in nearly 28 months. At 1400 EST/1900 GMT, the dollar stood at 1.3455/65 francs, up from 1.3412/22 francs at the open.</p>
<p>The German mark also strenghtened to Swissy, trading around 0.8638/42 francs in late dealings compared with 0.8620/23 earlier in the day.  </p>
<p>The dollar registered modest gains against the mark, rising to 1.5557/62 marks at 1400 EST/1900 GMT from 1.5545/55 at the open.</p>
<p>Against the Japanese unit, the dollar climbed to 114.46/51 yen from 114.37/42 yen at the start of trade.</p>
<p>The bulk of dollar gains against the yen were scored overnight as the Nikkei 225 index tumbled 528.75 points or 2.69 percent to close at 19,161.71, a fresh 12-month low.</p>
<p>Tokyo stocks were also battered last Thursday. Mounting fears that foreign investors may flee Japanese securities weighed on the yen.  </p>
<p>&quot;This is a concern that an underpeforming equity market is not going to continue to attract foreign investors,&quot; said Alex Beuzelin, a foreign exchange trader at Ruesch International. &quot;So, what you're seeing is maybe some flight out of Japanese equities markets,&quot; Beuzelin said. &quot;Obviously, when they are doing this, they need to sell their Japanese yen and that puts some pressure on the yen.&quot;</p>
<p>Although the dollar gained ground against the yen, the U.S. unit failed to hit its high for the year of 114.92 yen reached on October 29.  </p>
<p>Foreign exchange volume was light, amplifying price movements as trading wound down early before Christmas on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Financial markets in the United States and Europe will close for Christmas. Trading reopens in France and the United States on Thursday and in other major European markets on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;You're not going to see full volume in trading resume until after the new year,&quot; Beuzelin said.</p>
<p>In other trade, sterling slid to $1.6730/40 at 1400 EST/1900 GMT from $1.6735/45 at the open.  </p>
<p>The dollar fell to Canadian $1.3646/51 at 1400 EST/1900 GMT from C$1.3659/64 at the open.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar traded around $0.7960/70 in late afternoon flow, slightly higher than 0.7955/62 at the open.</p>
<p>((-- Donna Sells, 212 859 1668))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
