<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="274933" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Southeast power mixed in thin pre-holiday trade.</title>
<headline>US Southeast power mixed in thin pre-holiday trade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot electricity prices in the southeastern U.S. were notionally mixed Tuesday in very light trade ahead of the Christmas holiday, sources said.</p>
<p>Firm, peak power prices in the northern part of the Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) territory for Thursday were assessed in the $14.00-16.00 per megawatt hour (MWh) range, as compared with Monday's $9.50-10.50 trading range.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak electricity in northern TVA was notionally assessed at $8.00-9.00, but no deals could be confirmed done.</p>
<p>At the Georgia/Florida border, prices for firm, peak electricity in 16 hour blocks for Thursday delivery were still in the $17.00-18.00 range, with deals confirmed done at $17.75.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak power for Thursday at the Ga./Fla. border was still notionally assessed at $9.00.</p>
<p>Temperatures in the Southeast are expected to drop to eight to 12 degrees below normal on Wednesday but then moderate into the weekend. This colder-than-normal weather is forecast to stretch into northern Florida on Wednesday and Thursday.</p>
<p>Like power prices, natural gas spot values in south Texas fell by at least five cents today into the $3.70s to about $3.80 per million British thermal units.</p>
<p>Separately, Virginia Power's 781 megawatt (MW) Surry 2 nuclear unit resumed full power production after synchronizing to the grid on Monday.</p>
<p>((--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
