<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="275079" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia futures bourse plans new products.</title>
<headline>Malaysia futures bourse plans new products.</headline>
<byline>Azhar Sukri</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Kuala Lumpur Options and Financial Futures Exchange (KLOFFE) has ended its first year of operation with sharp growth in volumes, an international award and plans for new stock derivative products.</p>
<p>KLOFFE said on Tuesday it would launch stock index options, individual stock options and an Islamic index futures contract in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;We should be launching individual stock options around July 1997, while the index options should be launched before that, around April or May (1997),&quot; John Duggan, KLOFFE's chief operating officer, told Reuters.</p>
<p>KLOFFE, which opened in December last year, currently trades a futures contract based on the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange (KLSE) Composite Index.</p>
<p>Duggan said KLOFFE was also looking to introduce an Islamic Index futures contract after the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange (KLSE) launches the underlying index.</p>
<p>&quot;This product is likely to raise a huge amount of interest, and should be launched around three to six months after the (underlying) index is launched,&quot; said Duggan.</p>
<p>KLSE said in September it would launch an Islamic share index which would comprise shares of Malaysian listed companies whose businesses are acceptable to Islamic principles.</p>
<p>Asked for the reason for the launch of the new products, Duggan said: &quot;Brokers are very keen for us to introduce more products. We are seeing some very strong signals from them&quot;.</p>
<p>Between three and five individual stock options were likely to be launched initially, Duggan said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will watch the market closely and wait before we launch any more contracts. We want to maintain the market's focus,&quot; he said. &quot;If there's demand for more contracts, we will launch them.&quot;</p>
<p>Stock index options are options to buy or sell a theoretical portfolio of shares, representative of a stock market index. They are traded on exchanges and can be used to manage investment risk.</p>
<p>A future is a standardised forward contract to buy or sell a quantity of an item at an agreed price on a given future date.</p>
<p>&quot;These new products will add depth to the market. Offshore participants will have more confidence in our market,&quot; said K. Sree Kumar, executive director of KAF-Refco Futures Sdn Bhd.</p>
<p>Another product that is due for launch on KLOFFE is the Second Board index futures contract.</p>
<p>&quot;We should see lots of activity on the Second Board index futures contract. It should attract more players to the market, and it should increase volumes and liquidity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>All the new products are being studied by the Securities Commission.</p>
<p>In February, the average daily traded volume on the exchange was around 105 lots a day. The figure for the week to Friday, December 20, was around 287 lots a day.</p>
<p>&quot;Volumes have picked up due to the volatility of the contract. This volatility is due to the volatility on the Dow Jones over the last month,&quot; said Kumar. On Tuesday, local media reported that U.K.-based World Equity magazine had chosen KLOFFE as the Derivatives Exchange of the Year, one of its annual awards.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
