<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="275178" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Year's housing permits seen highest since 1988.</title>
<headline>Year's housing permits seen highest since 1988.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Housing permits issued this year will exceed 1.4 million for the first time since 1988, as strong jobs growth boosted the housing market despite higher mortgage rates for much of 1996, an industry research firm said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Single-family homes are getting the biggest boost, with more permits issued in 1996 since the mid-1980s housing boom, said U.S. Housing Markets, a unit of publisher Hanley-Wood Inc.</p>
<p>Atlanta, the Phoenix-Mesa metropolitan area and Chicago will be the biggest gainers in the housing boom, the report said.</p>
<p>U.S. single-family permit volume will reach about 1.07 million this year, up from 977,268 in 1995, U.S. Housing Markets said. About 340,000 apartment building permits are expected to be issued by the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;Nationally, new home sales and construction trends moved independently of mortgage rates in 1996,&quot; said Brian Bragg, editor of U.S. Housing Markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Lending rates ran above 1995 levels for much of the year -- by a half-point or more in most months -- but Americans confounded the experts with very robust homebuying. Steady job formations bred buyer confidence. Subdivision shoppers all but ignored the high loan rates.&quot;</p>
<p>In the last four years, employment nationwide has grown by more than 2 million jobs, with the biggest gains in the Dallas-Fort Worth area, U.S. Housing Markets said.</p>
<p>Most of the single-family building records this year will be set in the Sun Belt, with new highs in the East South Central region comprising Kentucky, Tennessee, Alabama and Mississippi, the Canton, Mich.-based company said.</p>
<p>By the end of October, Georgia's one-family builders had already set a new record for the third year in a row, with Atlanta issuing 41,481 permits, up 5 percent from 1995.</p>
<p>Permits rose 11.4 percent in the Phoenix-Mesa area to 34,448, and climbed 5.8 percent in Chicago to 33,138.</p>
<p>Single-family construction in Arkansas will exceed the 24-year-old state record, U.S. Housing Markets said. Builders in South Carolina have a chance to beat their 1972 record, it added.</p>
<p>In North Carolina, an all-time single-family record is likely, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010022">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E61">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
