<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="275186" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Judge issues injunction to block Proposition 209.</title>
<headline>Judge issues injunction to block Proposition 209.</headline>
<byline>Adam Entous</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-12-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A federal judge on Monday granted a preliminary injunction blocking Proposition 209, a voter-approved initiative that would roll back affirmative action programmes in California.</p>
<p>The injunction, handed down by U.S. District Judge Thelton Henderson of San Francisco, bars Gov. Pete Wilson and Attorney General Dan Lungren from implementing Proposition 209 until the judge resolves the dispute over its constitutionality.</p>
<p>In his decision granting the injunction, Henderson said that the voter-approved measure probably violated the constitutional right to equal protection.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not for this or any other court to lightly upset the expectations of the voters,&quot; Henderson wrote. &quot;At the same time, our system of democracy teaches that the will of the people, important as it is, does not reign absolute but must be kept in harmony with our Constitution.&quot;</p>
<p>Wilson, a Republican who strongly backed the initiative, said he was &quot;deeply disappointed&quot; by the ruling.</p>
<p>Lungren vowed to appeal the injunction to higher federal courts. &quot;This is only the first of a many-round fight,&quot; the attorney general said.</p>
<p>Civil rights groups challenging the constitutionality of the initiative said the ruling was a major victory.</p>
<p>&quot;We're elated. Our position has been vindicated,&quot; said attorney Edward Chen of the American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) of northern California. &quot;This freezes everything for the foreseeable future.&quot;</p>
<p>Californians voted 54-46 percent on Nov. 5 to make Proposition 209 part of the state constitution. It would bar discrimination and preferential treatment based on race or sex in public employment, education and contracting in California.</p>
<p>The initiative, the first of its kind passed by any state, would eliminate most California affirmative action programmes designed to create opportunities for women and racial minorities.</p>
<p>The White House said last week that the Justice Department had concluded that the California initiative was unconstitutional, and would back legal action to overturn it.</p>
<p>Backers of the initiative denounced the decision, arguing that race and gender preferences are unfair, and that the judge should have honoured the vote of the public.</p>
<p>&quot;The American system of government is being severely tested,&quot; said Ward Connerly, a black California businessman who led the campaign for the initiative.</p>
<p>&quot;While I maintain an abiding faith in our system of checks and balances, the decision of Judge Thelton Henderson to issue a preliminary injunction against Proposition 209 shakes the very foundation of our system,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
