<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="275295" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Police arrest two for German apartment house fire.</title>
<headline>Police arrest two for German apartment house fire.</headline>
<byline>Peter Mueller</byline>
<dateline>KIEL, Germany 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police in the northern German town of Kiel said they arrested two youths on Tuesday after a fire broke out in the stairwell of an apartment building where many foreigners live.</p>
<p>Firefighters evacuated 35 people from the five-storey building. Thirteen people suffered smoke-related injuries and three were in intensive care in hospital but their condition was not serious, a police spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;A racist motive for the crime has not been ruled out,&quot; a he said. &quot;Most of the people living in the building were foreigners. State prosecutors have taking over the investigation.&quot;</p>
<p>The spokesman said the two youths, aged 16 and 17, had admitted starting the blaze by setting light to advertising brochures. The wooden stairs caught fire and the flames reached the first storey in the stairwell.</p>
<p>Police said the fire damaged the building's electrical wiring and residents were not able to return on Tuesday. A third youth, aged 15, was released after being questioned.</p>
<p>Police said they had not yet established the nationalities of the building's foreigners but they were not asylum-seekers. Several hundred Turks live in Kiel, a city of 245,000 people on the Baltic Sea.</p>
<p>Kiel is about 60 km (40 miles) north of Luebeck, where a fire at a foreigners' hostel killed 10 people last January. A Lebanese man who lived in the hostel is now on trial charged with aggravated arson and causing bodily harm.</p>
<p>The fire in Kiel came a day after nine women psychiatric patients were killed by a blaze in Rickling, about 50 km (30 miles) to the south.</p>
<p>The fire quickly engulfed the single-storey wooden building on Sunday night killing the victims, aged between 55 and 85, in one of post-war Germany's worst fire disasters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEL, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
