<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="275449" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FCC proposes long-distance access charge reform.</title>
<headline>FCC proposes long-distance access charge reform.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Communications Commission proposed Tuesday to trim the $23 billion a year that long-distance telephone companies pay to local service providers in access fees.</p>
<p>But the commission ducked the contentious issue of whether such charges should be imposed on Internet service providers, asking for comment on the issue without offering any proposals.</p>
<p>In a notice of proposed rule-making, the commission said it could cut the access fees in either of two ways: it could impose a schedule of long-distance access charge reductions or wait to allow market forces to drive fees lower.</p>
<p>The access charges, which make up a substantial portion of local phone company revenues, were adopted after the break-up of AT&amp;T Corp. in the 1980s that led to the creation of the regional &quot;Baby Bell&quot; local service companies.</p>
<p>New telecommunications rules signed into law in February are supposted to foster more competition for local and long-distance service and drive prices lower.</p>
<p>Long-distance companies, which say the access fees are excessive, favour deep, government-mandated cuts.</p>
<p>Local phone companies concede that the fees exceed their actual costs for carrying long-distance calls but would prefer a gradual reduction based on competition and market forces.</p>
<p>Under the FCC's market-based approach, new entrants in the local market would compete with the Baby Bells to connect long-distance calls. The FCC would gradually relax and ultimately remove price caps and access fee schedules while relying on competition to drive the fees down.</p>
<p>The alternate approach would specify the nature and timing of changes in existing rate levels.</p>
<p>Local phone companies also connect Internet users to Internet service providers over local phone lines, but they receive no access charges for those calls.</p>
<p>Recently, several Baby Bells have complained that Internet users are getting a free ride, tying up local lines with often lengthy calls.</p>
<p>The FCC did not take a position on whether Internet service providers should be required to pay access fees. In a less formal &quot;notice of inquiry,&quot; the agency asked for comment on possible reform &quot;relating to interstate information services and the Internet.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
