<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="275510" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAPUA NEW GUINEA: Landslide in Papua New Guinea kills 38.</title>
<headline>Landslide in Papua New Guinea kills 38.</headline>
<dateline>PORT MORESBY 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thirty-eight people were believed killed and eight seriously injured when a landslide engulfed a hill-side village in Papua New Guinea (PNG), disaster officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The South Pacific nation's Director of Disaster and Emergency Services Leith Anderson said the landslide had buried the village of Waiunda near Menyamya after heavy monsoon rains.</p>
<p>Anderson, who earlier put the death toll at 43, said 38 people were now thought to have died in the landslide on Sunday morning. Seventeen of the dead had been recovered and re-buried and 21 people were still missing under the rubble.</p>
<p>Eight people were in critical condition at hospital in the town of Lae, on the north coast of the PNG mainland.</p>
<p>&quot;Relief work has been hampered by bad wind and rain,&quot; Anderson told Reuters. &quot;We'll be moving in tomorrow morning. The main relief effort will commence in the morning of Christmas Day.&quot;</p>
<p>Landslides are common in the mountains around the small township of Menyamya which are so steep and fragmented that Australian explorers in the 1930s called the area &quot;broken bottle country&quot;.</p>
<p>The area was visited earlier on Tuesday by Provincial Affairs Minister Peter Barter.</p>
<p>Anderson earlier issued strong wind and heavy rain warnings for all parts of the country, warning people not to venture out into the open unnecessarily and to look out for falling trees.</p>
<p>The capital, Port Moresby, and other parts of Papua New Guinea have seen very heavy monsoon rains.</p>
<p>Anderson said the reasons for the Waiunda landslide were not yet known but the village was half-way up a mountain of around 3,000 metres (6,000 feet) and the effects of deforestation meant that gardens above the village might had slipped downhill.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT MORESBY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAPUA NEW GUINEA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
