<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="27567" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Landmark tobacco suit goes to Miss. Supreme Court.</title>
<headline>Landmark tobacco suit goes to Miss. Supreme Court.</headline>
<dateline>JACKSON, Miss. 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mississippi's Republican governor and Democratic attorney general were set to square off before the state supreme court this week over who has the authority to sue the tobacco industry to recover Medicaid payments to sick smokers.</p>
<p>The Mississippi Supreme Court will hear arguments on Wednesday in a case brought by Gov. Kirk Fordice, who says only he can sue on behalf of the state Medicaid division, which is under his authority.</p>
<p>Democratic Attorney General Mike Moore filed a landmark lawsuit against tobacco manufacturers in May 1994 to recover Medicaid money that was paid to sick smokers. Moore, the first state attorney general to sue the industry and an active recruiter of others to join the courtroom assault, called the governor's action a national embarrassment and said he has sole power to file lawsuits on behalf of state taxpayers.</p>
<p>&quot;There is one governor in America who is suing the attorney general and that's here in Mississippi,&quot; Moore said recently. &quot;George Bush ... is a Republican, last time I checked. Why didn't he sue Dan Morales?&quot; he asked, referring to Texas' Republican governor and its Democratic attorney general, who was also suing the tobacco industry.</p>
<p>A ruling in favor of Fordice would not end the lawsuit but would erase the biggest claim for damages. The attorney general's $940 million suit seeks to recover the state's costs for treating smokers through Medicaid, state employee health insurance and indigent care at University of Mississippi Medical Center and county hospitals statewide.</p>
<p>&quot;The biggest chunk of our case obviously is Medicaid,&quot; Moore said.</p>
<p>Fordice has insisted that if Moore's lawsuit was allowed to proceed, other industries will be targeted by lawsuits. &quot;The floodgates will certainly open and the progressive, pro-business reputation Governor Fordice has carefully nurtured may be ruined,&quot; said Fordice spokesman Heath Hall.</p>
<p>The 1,500-member Mississippi Manufacturers' Association filed a &quot;friend of the court&quot; brief siding with Fordice. The American College of Chest Physicians and 38 state attorneys general filed similar briefs on behalf of Moore.</p>
<p>Fifteen states, 12 of which have Republican governors, are suing tobacco manufacturers, wholesalers, industry research groups and a public relations firm. Attorneys general or governors are plaintiffs in 14 of those. Alabama's lieutenant governor filed suit as a private plaintiff.</p>
<p>Moore said that if the court rules in favor of Fordice, it could hurt the other states' tobacco lawsuits. &quot;I think it would do some damage to the national case,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tobacco industry attorneys were expected to argue that Moore lacked authority to sue for Medicaid reimbursement and that his case was in the wrong court. The industry has sought unsuccessfully to move the case to state circuit court for a jury trial.</p>
<p>Moore's lawsuit was pending in Jackson County Chancery Court, where decisions rest with a judge. If the case were moved to Circuit Court, R.J. Reynolds Tobacco attorney Joe Colingo said, &quot;the state would have to take the position of an injured party. It would be like any other cigarette case.&quot;</p>
<p>A Florida jury's $750,000 verdict for an ill smoker last month was only the second major lawsuit lost by the tobacco industry and it will be appealed. Part of the industry's defense has been that smokers have a choice and assume a risk.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JACKSON, Miss."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
