<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="27561" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pivotal post-Labor Day data week awaits US markets.</title>
<headline>Pivotal post-Labor Day data week awaits US markets.</headline>
<byline>Noah Barkin</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street investors will return from their long Labor Day weekends on Tuesday to face what is shaping up to be one of the most crucial make-or-break data weeks of the year for U.S. markets.</p>
<p>Bond yields have crept back above the 7 percent level and are precariously close to the 13-month highs set in early June of this year. Stocks meanwhile, after staging a corrective rebound in recent months, are showing signs of vulnerability just as they re-approach their record highs.</p>
<p>Recent rugged indicators have raised the specter of a short-term interest rate hike from the Federal Reserve and this week's calendar threatens to spook markets with even more conclusive evidence of U.S. economic strength.</p>
<p>Economists believe the August National Association of Purchasing Management manufacturing index, due Tuesday, and to a greater extent, the August employment report on Friday, may well fortify an already robust outlook and force the Fed's hand later this month.</p>
<p>&quot;This week is extremely significant,&quot; said Anthony Chan, chief economist at Banc One Investment Advisors Corp. &quot;It's just chock-full of information that has the potential to change policymakers' minds.&quot;</p>
<p>Ironically, it was last month's NAPM and payrolls reports that eased market fears of tighter credit and convinced many participants that the Fed's forecasts of a slowdown in the second half of 1996 would indeed come to fruition.</p>
<p>Over the past three weeks however, an incessant stream of robust economic data has sent bond yields soaring over 40 basis points and smacked stocks at a critical stage in their recent corrective rebound.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of people who thought the bull market (in stocks) had another strong leg in it,&quot; said Robert Stovall, president of Stovall/21st Advisors, in the aftermath of a two-day 95-point slide in the Dow Jones industrial average. &quot;The bulls are definitely on the defensive now.&quot;</p>
<p>Last week alone saw U.S. consumer confidence rise to its highest level in over six years, second-quarter Gross Domestic Product register the highest quarterly growth rate in two years and July single-family home sales record their largest increase since February.</p>
<p>To top it off, the regional Chicago Purchasing Managers' index, released in an abbreviated pre-Labor Day weekend session on Friday, rose to 1-1/2 year highs.</p>
<p>The report had forecasters scrambling to revise their estimates for Tuesday's national NAPM report, and at week's end, reevaluating their expectations for third-quarter growth and Fed policy.</p>
<p>&quot;It certainly doesn't feel like an economy that is slowing to a trend-like pace,&quot; Dana Johnson, managing director of economic research at First Chicago Capital Markets Inc., said Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;It feels like an economy that's moving ahead a good bit faster than that. Precisely how fast is not clear but certainly if we get an employment report where hours are up, payrolls are up, earnings are up and the unemployment rate is down it will be hard for the Fed to hold tight for very long.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists in a Reuters poll conducted on Friday called on average, for a gain of 244,000 in August non-farm payrolls. This compares with an advance of 193,000 in July.</p>
<p>The average hourly earnings component of the report -- a key gauge of inflation pressures -- is expected to rise at a 0.3 percent pace, while the unemployment rate is seen edging down to 5.3 percent from 5.4 percent last month.</p>
<p>Economists said the central bank could think twice about raising rates at its upcoming Sept. 24 policy meeting if the report is in line with these forecasts. However, anything stronger could prove to be the final straw for a Fed that has taken a wait-and-see approach to robust growth figures until now.</p>
<p>&quot;If the market is right in terms of its expectations, that could be just enough to keep them on hold,&quot; Alan Ruskin, chief economist at advisory firm I.D.E.A. Inc, said Monday. &quot;But if you get a 300,000 headline number and a 5.2 percent unemployment rate, it will be quite tough for the Fed to resist.&quot;</p>
<p>Ruskin echoed other economists in noting that Fed policymakers would prefer to wait until after the U.S. presidential elections before acting. He also said that an ongoing debate about the non-inflationary growth potential of the U.S. economy has left policy-makers divided about the risks of current growth levels.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the Fed has demonstrated a willingness, albeit modest, to adjust policy during election months, and a September rate hike is clearly in the cards.</p>
<p>&quot;At this point it could be viewed as political if they didn't raise rates,&quot; said Stovall.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
