<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="275867" id="root" date="1996-12-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo stocks slide again on economic worries.</title>
<headline>Tokyo stocks slide again on economic worries.</headline>
<byline>Hiroko Nakata</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo stocks fell sharply to a fresh 12-month low on Tuesday as the market fretted over the outlook for the Japanese economy.</p>
<p>The market's key Nikkei average opened on a lower note and saw losses accelerate as investors turned increasingly gloomy, despite optimistic comments from government officials about Japan's economic recovery.</p>
<p>The benchmark index tumbled 528.75 points, or 2.69 percent, to 19,161.71, the lowest level since December 19, 1995. This was the third biggest drop of the year.</p>
<p>Brokers said the slide reflected a lack of confidence in the government's assessment of the economy and concerns about the effects of fiscal tightening next year.</p>
<p>They said the government was too optimistic about the economic recovery and had cut back on economy-boosting measures with this rosy picture in mind.</p>
<p>&quot;The biggest reason for the sharp fall is the gap between the market's and the government's perceptions of the economy,&quot; said Hiroyuki Nakai, chief investment strategist at Nikko Securities Co Ltd.</p>
<p>Japan's snowballing public debt and dwindling tax revenues have forced the government to raise the consumption tax from next April and to end special income tax cuts from January, although this may hurt the economy.</p>
<p>The market has also been discouraged by a delay in implementing a corporate tax cut, which had been proposed to support domestic business activities, brokers said.</p>
<p>These worries took hold last week when the government unveiled a tight budget for the next fiscal year. The Nikkei dropped more than 500 points on Thursday to its lowest level since December 21, 1995, but managed a modest technical rebound on Friday. The market was closed on Monday for a holiday.</p>
<p>Kenzo Doi, a strategist at Kokusai Securities Co Ltd, said a lack of foreign investors, the backbone of past rallies, due to the holidays had further dampened the market's mood.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't hope for buying from overseas investors because they are away for the Christmas holidays,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>One trader at a foreign securities house added: &quot;Many participants held back from buying ahead of the long year-end and New Year holidays. Some started to close their positions.&quot;</p>
<p>Brokers said the market shrugged off several positive comments about the economy made by government officials on Tuesday, and said the possibility of the Nikkei index breaking below 19,000 was already in sight.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka told a news conference on Tuesday that Japan's economic recovery will likely pick up in the latter half of the next fiscal year, and that the recovery will eventually be reflected in the financial markets.</p>
<p>Mitsuzuka also said the economy was strong enough to withstand any blow from the higher consumption tax, but this cut little ice with stock market investors.</p>
<p>Japan's economy has been struggling to pull out of a protracted slump despite record low interest rates and government public works spending.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
