<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="275909" id="root" date="1996-12-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire rebels say they seized town, killing 300 troops.</title>
<headline>Zaire rebels say they seized town, killing 300 troops.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Tostevin</byline>
<dateline>GOMA, Zaire 1996-12-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zairean rebel leader Laurent Kabila said on Wednesday his forces had captured the key northeastern town of Bunia, killing 300 government troops.</p>
<p>&quot;Three-hundred dead bodies of government troops were left on the (battle) field after the 12-hour battle. We are now cleaning up,&quot; Kabila said in a interview.</p>
<p>He declined to give details of casualties on his own side.</p>
<p>The rebels previously said they had taken several towns still in government hands and the Christmas Day claim could not be independently verified. Kabila insisted his information was correct.</p>
<p>&quot;We pushed back the Zaire army at midday yesterday to three km (two miles) away from Bunia. The town is completely under our control,&quot; he told Reuters at his lakeside villa in the city of Goma.</p>
<p>He said the Zairean army drove back rebels with a counter-offensive that began on Sunday until the rebel Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire (ADFL) took Bunia.</p>
<p>The fall of Bunia, 360 km (220 miles) north of Goma, would hold great strategic significance because it is a major junction, has a tarmac airstrip and was heavily reinforced by troops.</p>
<p>It would be the first substantial advance in weeks by the Rwandan-backed rebels who launched their war in October when the government ordered Banyamulenge ethnic Tutsis expelled.</p>
<p>Bunia is also close to gold mines, which the rebels could use to fund their campaign to capture the crumbling central African state. But Kabila said the Kilo Moto gold mines near Bunia, a target of the operation, had not yet been captured.</p>
<p>Kilo Moto covers 83,000 square km (32,000 square miles) westwards from Bunia with estimated reserves of more than 100 tonnes of gold. Locally produced gold is exported from Bunia airstrip.</p>
<p>President Mobutu Sese Seko approved a new crisis government on Tuesday to guide the war effort to retake the east but he retained centrist Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo, a part Tutsi.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no change at all. Mobutu has played the same game with the people many times before. It means nothing,&quot; said Kabila of the new government that includes a new defence minister.</p>
<p>Several hundred civilians in the rebel-held east fled Goma and Bukavu last week fearing a successful counter attack after Mobutu's return to Zaire last week.</p>
<p>Aid workers say cracks are appearing in Kabila's alliance with tension between Mai-Mai fighters and Banyamulenge over control of territorial gains.</p>
<p>The Mai-Mai are unwilling to cede territory they police in North Kivu's Masisi region to the Banyamulenge, the aid workers say.</p>
<p>&quot;We are disarming all the Mai-Mai and sending them to proper training camps,&quot; said Kabila of the rebel allies. &quot;They smoke cannabis and become drunk. Then they act irresponsibly and there are even reports of them raping and brutalising local people.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We will give them some discipline and that will be good for them,&quot; said Kabila.</p>
<p>The Mai-Mai, who believe bullets fired at them will turn to water, spearheaded rebel advances north of Goma but the child warriors among them have refused orders from rebel officers.</p>
<p>Mobutu, Zaire's ruler for 31 years, has vowed to crush the revolt in the east, which erupted while he was in Europe for four months for cancer surgery. He cut short his convalescence to return.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GOMA, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
