<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="276065" id="root" date="1996-12-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: YEAREND - Demand for Asian IPOs seen cooling in 1997.</title>
<headline>YEAREND - Demand for Asian IPOs seen cooling in 1997.</headline>
<byline>Lilian Karunungan</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-12-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The demand for initial public offerings (IPOs) dominated Asian equity markets in 1996 but the trend is unlikely to be as pervasive next year, analysts in the region said.</p>
<p>IPOs in Hong Kong, Indonesia, and the Philippines are likely to capture investors' fancy but interest in those from India, Thailand and South Korea could remain low, the analysts said.</p>
<p>Overseas investors will be neutral on Malaysia, whose new listings in 1997 will mainly be small-capitalised companies, and caution will prevail in the Japanese equities market because of the economy's slower-than-expected recovery, analysts said.</p>
<p>Bullishness is expected to prevail in Hong Kong as a spate of China-related issues are expected to dominate the IPO market amid a glow of positive sentiment over the handover of Hong Kong to China in mid-1997.</p>
<p>&quot;More and more people recognise Hong Kong has always been the conduit to the flow of trade amd money in and out of China. And that role will grow after the handover,&quot; said Peter Perkins, regional strategist of Hong Kong-based Daiwa Insitute of Research. China is the largest economy in Asia outside of Japan, he pointed out.</p>
<p>Indonesia and the Philippines also offer attractive prospects due to the downward trend in domestic interest rates, analysts said.</p>
<p>But they added the IPO business in Thailand and South Korea will be dull due to their slowing economies.</p>
<p>An oversupply of shares in the Korean market will also weigh on its IPOs. The Korea Investment Trust Companies' Association had requested the government to keep the supply of new shares below one percent of Gross Domestic Product (GDP), against an estimated 2.7 percent this year.</p>
<p>In India, investors would shy away from equities due to the dismal performance of its stock markets. Political instability and poor corporate earnings have sent the Bombay Sensitivity index falling about 30 percent this year.</p>
<p>HONG KONG: Strong demand for small-cap, China-related stocks is expected into 1997, analysts said. According to the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, 42 companies have listed so far in 1996, raising about HK$28.92 billion.</p>
<p>Among the China-related issues, those linked to infrastructure should continue to attract investors due to huge demand for roads, bridges and power plants in China. Indonesia:</p>
<p>Apart from the expected decline in interest rates due to a recent cut in the Central Bank's key discount rate, the continued privatisation of state-owned companies will help boost activity in the Jakarta stock exchange and attract more funds in 1997, market followers said.</p>
<p>Toll road operator Jasa Narga is expected to be listed next year, according to analysts.</p>
<p>INDIA: The amount expected to be raised in 1997 through public issues could fall by about 15-20 percent on the lack of investor confidence in India, according to Prithyi Haldea of Prime Database, which tracks the Indian stock market.</p>
<p>A total of about 112 billion rupees ($3.1 billion) through 1,175 issues is estimated to have been raised this year, Haldea said.</p>
<p>Major tax breaks and offering of state-run issues at substantial discounts could help revive the stock markets, analysts said.</p>
<p>MALAYSIA: Another 80 to 100 new listings are expected in 1997, consisting mainly of small-capitalisation companies and some infrastructure projects, said Patrick Lim, president of the Malaysian Investors' Association.</p>
<p>A record of over 80 new companies were listed on the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange in 1996.</p>
<p>JAPAN: The Tokyo stock market in 1997 is likely to see a series of new stock issues by formerly state-owned firms which have been already listed on the Tokyo Stock Exchange, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Those new issues (by the privatised firms) are our concerns, but their impacts depend on trading levels of the Nikkei average when the issues come up,&quot; said Seiki Orimi, stock analyst at Dai-Ichi Securities Co Ltd.</p>
<p>THAILAND: &quot;I don't see any new fresh incentives to help shore up the battered stock markets in the near-term. The sluggish economy has affected all industries and reduced fund demand for new investments,&quot; Kasom Piriyakich, vice president at Pacific Finance and Securities, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Investment bankers estimate the total value of IPOs to be about 30 billion baht ($1.2 billion) for all of 1996 compared with 40.27 billion baht in 1995.</p>
<p>SOUTH KOREA: &quot;In 1997, the market looks like it will be tough. Tough on existing issues and very tough on new ones,&quot; said BZW Securities analyst Don Lee in Seoul.</p>
<p>About 31 companies raised a total of 943.34 billion won ($1.13 billion) in 1996, up from 580.14 million won gained by 36 companies in 1995, according to the Korea Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>PHILIPPINES: About 10 companies have indicated their plans to be listed at the Philippine Stock Exchange next year. Of these companies, the market eagerly awaits the IPO of cellular phone operator Smart Communications Inc and Equitable Banking Corp, brokers said.</p>
<p>Thirteen companies listed in 1996 and raised a total of about 25.3 billion pesos ($963 million,$=26.28)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
