<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="276133" id="root" date="1996-12-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BAHRAIN: Bahrain court jails two accused Qatari spies.</title>
<headline>Bahrain court jails two accused Qatari spies.</headline>
<byline>Abbas Salman</byline>
<dateline>MANAMA 1996-12-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bahrain's State Security Court on Wednesday found a Qatari man and woman guilty of spying for Doha and sentenced them to three years in prison, a government official said.</p>
<p>&quot;Two Qataris arrested for spying were sentenced to three years in prison each and were fined 1,000 dinars ($2,650) each by the court on Wednesday,&quot; the official told Reuters.</p>
<p>The court's ruling cannot be appealed.</p>
<p>A statement by Qatar's interior ministry described the ruling as &quot;futile&quot; and demanded the release of its two nationals.</p>
<p>The trial of Fahad Hamad Abdullah al-Baker and Salwa Jassim Mohammed Fakhri began on December 4. Manama has said the two confessed to the charges before an investigating judge. Qatar denies the two were spies.</p>
<p>The official said the time already spent in custody would count towards the Qataris' overall prison terms.</p>
<p>It was unclear when the two were arrested, but a source close to the court said they were detained about five months ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Qatar regrets and denounces the ruling passed today following closed door and secretive consultations by the State Security Court,&quot; said a Qatari interior minstry official in a statement carried by the state-run Qatar News Agency (QNA).</p>
<p>The official dismissed the ruling as &quot;futile as it had been passed under oppression and coercion and in violation of laws and international norms&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Qatar demands from the government of Bahrain to immediately release its two nationals, preserve their rights and ensure their safety,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Qatar has accused Bahrain of torturing al-Baker and said the trial &quot;sets a dangerous precedent in Gulf ties&quot;. Bahrain denies the allegations.</p>
<p>The case has raised tensions between Bahrain and Qatar, already at odds because of a territorial dispute over a cluster of small islands and sandbanks in the Gulf controlled by Bahrain since the 1930s but also claimed by Qatar.</p>
<p>Qatar has taken the case to the International Court of Justice in The Hague. The move has angered Bahrain, which prefers a regional solution.</p>
<p>The dispute prompted Bahrain to boycott a two-day summit of leaders of the Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC) which ended in the Qatari capital Doha on December 9.</p>
<p>The GCC, a political and economic alliance, also groups Oman, Saudi Arabia, the United Arab Emirates and Kuwait.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BAHRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BAHRAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
