<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="276208" id="root" date="1996-12-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton gives wife baseball book for Christmas.</title>
<headline>Clinton gives wife baseball book for Christmas.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton gave his wife Hillary a Christmas present of a book that takes a nostalgic look at baseball, a White House spokesman said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In the first information on the first family's exchange of gifts, the spokesman said the president gave his wife, a long-time Chicago Cubs fan, &quot;Mudville Diaries,&quot; a book of baseball memories collected by Mike Schacht.</p>
<p>Details of other gifts were not immediately available so as not to intrude on the Clintons' privacy, the spokesman, Josh Silverman, said.</p>
<p>The Clintons and their daughter Chelsea planned to spend a quiet day at the White House with relatives, including the president's brother Roger and his family, and Hillary's brother Tony Rodham and his family. Also apparently attending were Hillary's widowed mother and the president's widowed stepfather, Silverman said.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the family would sit down to a Christmas dinner of turkey with white bread and corn bread stuffing, peppered ham, mashed potatoes and sweat potatoes, dinner rolls and a relish tray. Dessert was to include cherry jello, pumpkin and lemon meringue pie and chocolate cake with white frosting.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
