<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="276467" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: HORSE RACING-DUNWOODY LANDS RECORD FOURTH KING GEORGE WIN.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-DUNWOODY LANDS RECORD FOURTH KING GEORGE WIN.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Richard Dunwoody became the first jockey to win the King George VI Chase four times when triumphing on hot favourite One Man at Kempton on Thursday.</p>
<p>Dunwoody, who won the race on One Man last year and twice previously on the great Desert Orchid, never had an anxious moment.</p>
<p>Only five ran because of the ground hardened by overnight frost but they included the Grand National winner Rough Quest.</p>
<p>Trainer Terry Casey left it until an hour before the race before finally deciding to run Rough Quest, who prefers ground with some give.</p>
<p>One Man, the 8-13 favourite, took over from the pace-making Mr Mulligan turning into the straight and won the three mile (4.8 km) event easily.</p>
<p>Mr Mulligan, ridden by champion jockey Tony McCoy, fell at the last obstacle, allowing Rough Quest to finish second at 4-1 ahead of 10-1 outsider Barton Bank, winner of this race three years ago.</p>
<p>Dunwoody, who had 12 lengths to spare at the post,  said: &quot;He gave me a great ride and he jumped superbly.&quot;</p>
<p>Owner John Hales, who could only bring himself to watch his grey horse after the final fence, said: &quot;We came into the racing knowing nothing and we&quot;ve finished up with One Man.&quot;</p>
<p>Trainer Gordon Richards has now won the prestigious King George three times, twice with One Man and once with Titus Oates back in 1969.</p>
<p>One Man will be aimed again at the Cheltenham Gold Cup in which he finished a disappointing sixth last season in a rare failure.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
