<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="276544" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Riot police force Serbian opposition off streets.</title>
<headline>Riot police force Serbian opposition off streets.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-12-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Riot police forced opposition demonstrators off the streets on Thursday as the Serbian government began a crackdown on more than five weeks of protest against President Slobodan Milosevic.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the Zajedno (Together) opposition parties said the coalition feared its three main leaders were about to be arrested as Milosevic appeared to lose patience with the disruption of the capital for at least six hours a day.</p>
<p>Thousands of police in riot gear swamped central Belgrade to enforce an interior ministry ban on marches by Zajedno and students against election fraud by the ruling Socialist Party (SPS).</p>
<p>They ignored a march through snowy streets by 5,000 students but were firm with around 30,000 Zajedno activists blocking a main street under the windows of the opposition headquarters in the city centre.</p>
<p>They forced the demonstrators into a pedestrian area at nearby Republic Square, butting those who resisted with their shields and hitting them with batons, but without severe force.</p>
<p>The three Zajedno leaders said to be threatened with arrest, Zoran Djindjic, Vuk Draskovic and Vesna Pesic, addressed the demonstrators from a platform in the square.</p>
<p>Djindjic told the whistling crowd: &quot;Can you imagine a country in which, after losing local elections, its president tries to provoke a civil war. Can you imagine what he would do if he lost a presidential election -- provoke a world war?&quot;</p>
<p>The Zajedno spokeswoman said 20,000 police equipped with water cannon were deployed in the capital to prevent a 37th day of opposition protests.</p>
<p>The police movements themselves caused traffic chaos and blocked river and motorway bridges on which the city relies.</p>
<p>The United States and other Western governments have warned Milosevic he risks economic reprisals and continued international isolation if he uses violence to restore order.</p>
<p>He had rejected a request for an emergency meeting from U.S. Charge d'Affaires Richard Miles, who saw Foreign Minister Milan Milutinovic instead.</p>
<p>At least 58 people were injured in fighting between police, opposition and SPS supporters on Tuesday when Milosevic held a counter-rally outside the Zajedno offices which flopped.</p>
<p>A man claimed by his family to have been an opposition demonstrator injured in the clashes died in hospital on Christmas Day, his doctor said.</p>
<p>Draskovic, commenting on the ban on marching, said any violence would be Milosevic's fault.</p>
<p>&quot;This responsibility will be Milosevic's because if the police and Milosevic's drunken and armed people were not on the streets there would not be any problems at all,&quot; Draskovic said in a radio interview.</p>
<p>Opposition protests were free of violence until Milosevic brought SPS supporters from outside Belgrade into the city on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Russia, traditionally more sympathetic to Serbia than the West, has warned against outside any interference in Belgrade's political turmoil.</p>
<p>The anti-government protests began after Milosevic refused to accept a stunning series of opposition victories in local elections on November 17.</p>
<p>The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe is expected to deliver its opinion on the outcome of the elections within the next few days.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
