<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="276549" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Britain deeply concerned by Belgrade violence.</title>
<headline>Britain deeply concerned by Belgrade violence.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-12-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain said on Thursday that further Serbian government moves to impede opposition demonstrations would damage the country's chances of reintegration with the international community.</p>
<p>In a statement, the British Embassy said London was &quot;deeply concerned&quot; at recent events in Belgrade.</p>
<p>&quot;The violence associated with the rival demonstrations in Belgrade on 24 December was deeply regrettable. We deplore today's (Thursday's) attempts by the Serbian authorities to impede the right of the opposition to demonstrate peacefully,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The embassy was referring to moves by thousands of riot police to enforce an interior ministry ban on marches by the opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition and students against election fraud by the ruling Socialist Party (SPS).</p>
<p>The police ignored a march through snow-covered streets by 5,000 students but were firm with around 30,000 Zajedno activists blocking a main street under the windows of the opposition headquarters in the city centre.</p>
<p>They forced the demonstrators into a pedestrian area at the nearby Republic Square, butting those who resisted with their shields and hitting them with batons but without severe force.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, pro- and anti-government protesters fought running battles through the city streets when they converged on central Belgrade for rival demonstrations.</p>
<p>The opposition had held peaceful protests for 35 days, but the violence erupted when the ruling Socialist Party chose to hold a rally of its own at the same time and place as the regular Zajedno marches.</p>
<p>&quot;Such actions can only damage the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia's prospects of improving relations with the international community,&quot; the British Embassy statement said.</p>
<p>It said it had relayed its concerns to foreign minister Milan Milutinovic, who has already received similar messages from the United States, Germany, France and Italy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
