<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="276596" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Shining Path guerrillas kill six in Peru - police.</title>
<headline>Shining Path guerrillas kill six in Peru - police.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-12-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peru's Maoist Shining Path guerrillas killed six men in the same family early on Christmas Day in the northern province of Chiclayo, a police official said.</p>
<p>The attack came on the ninth day of a hostage crisis in the capital triggered by Peru's other main rebel group, the Marxist Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA).</p>
<p>The police official, who asked not to be named, said about 20 guerrillas were involved in the provincial attack, stabbing the men to death in the early hours of Wednesday.</p>
<p>Rebels dragged the men out of the family's house in the isolated village of Huarmaca, about 500 miles (800 km) north of the capital, Lima, before killing them and burning their truck, the official said.</p>
<p>The guerrillas murdered the men because they believed they had given information about guerrilla activity in the Pacific coast region to the police, he said.</p>
<p>After the killings, the rebels left propaganda in the area praising the Shining Path's imprisoned leader, Abimael Guzman.</p>
<p>The Shining Path and the MRTA are rivals, with the MRTA drawing inspiration from Cuban communism, while the much bigger Shining Path prefers Maoism. Prisoners from the two armies have attacked one another in jail, and the two groups have never operated together.</p>
<p>Rebel violence in Peru by the two groups had died down from its bloody height in the late 1980s after the 1992 capture of guerrilla leaders.</p>
<p>But a series of Shining Path attacks this year and last Tuesday's daring MRTA assault on the residence of the Japanese ambassador to Peru have raised fears the guerrillas are making a comeback.</p>
<p>Peru's guerrilla wars have cost 30,000 lives and $25 billion in infrastructure damage since 1980.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
