<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="276762" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX JGB futures end weaker, depressed by shares.</title>
<headline>SIMEX JGB futures end weaker, depressed by shares.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Japanese Government Bond futures continued to meander lower pressured by sharp falls in the Nikkei index and fears of weakness in the Japanese economy.</p>
<p>The Nikkei 225 average fell below the critical 19,000 level for the first time in over a year, which triggered selling in the typically thin JGB futures market.</p>
<p>The JGB March contract finished at 124.85, down from the previous settlement at 125.30 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The cash Nikkei recovered mid-afternoon, rebounding from lows to end at 19,291.58, but traders said there was still room on the downside due to technical gaps near 18,500.  </p>
<p>Euroyen futures slipped in early trade but pared losses in late action due to the bearish outlook for Japanese stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;It went down and was later bought back because people don't see much change in Japan's monetary policy,&quot; a bank dealer said.</p>
<p>A weak economic scenario for Japan suggests that the low interest rate policy would be maintained, he said.</p>
<p>The June Euroyen contract ended firmer at 99.40 against its previous close at 99.39, but down against the IMM Dec 24 close at 99.41. U.S. markets were closed for the Christmas holiday.</p>
<p>September Euroyen ended at 99.27 against the IMM's 99.31.  </p>
<p>Eurodollar futures were slightly weaker in lacklustre trade with major foreign participation thinned by Christmas, year-end book closures and no significant U.S. economic data.</p>
<p>Weekly U.S. initial jobless claims are slated for release on Thursday, and Friday will see durable goods data, both not considered to be market-moving reports, dealers said.</p>
<p>March eurodollars ended at 94.44 against the IMM's 94.45, and June closed at 94.30 against 94.31.</p>
<p>-- Jacqueline Wong (65 8703088)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
