<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="276834" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia not informed of Hashimoto cancelling trip.</title>
<headline>Malaysia not informed of Hashimoto cancelling trip.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-12-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's Foreign Ministry said on Thursday it had received no confirmation that Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto might cancel next month's trip to Malaysia and several neighbouring countries.</p>
<p>Earlier, Foreign Ministry officials in Japan said the prime minister might have to cancel a five-nation Southeast Asian tour scheduled from January 7 to 14 because of the hostage crisis at the Japanese Embassy residence in the Peruvian capital of Lima.</p>
<p>A Malaysian Foreign Ministry spokesman said preparations for Hashimoto's two-day visit, from January 8, would go on &quot;until we get a confirmation&quot;, the national Bernama news agency reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as we are concerned, the visit is on...but I do understand that due to the hostage crisis in Peru, he may have to cancel his trip,&quot; the spokesman added.</p>
<p>Armed guerrillas continue to hold 104 hostages, including Malaysian Ambassador Ahmad Mokhtar, at the Japanese Embassy in Lima as the crisis entered its ninth day.</p>
<p>Hashimoto is also due to visit Singapore, Indonesia, Vietnam and Brunei in January.</p>
<p>Also, Foreign Minister Yukihiko Ikeda might cancel a scheduled trip to Britain and India early next month, Japanese ministry officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Ikeda has already scrubbed a two-day trip to South Korea that was supposed to start on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
