<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="276809" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodia vows to enforce ban on log exports.</title>
<headline>Cambodia vows to enforce ban on log exports.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1996-12-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodia's government on Thursday said it would take strong action to enforce a December 31 deadline on logging exports.</p>
<p>&quot;There is some illegal exporting and exploitation of forests in the Kingdom of Cambodia, and in order to save national resources and stop anarchic activities in the forests, we will take strong measures,&quot; said a government statement dated Wednesday but released on Thursday.</p>
<p>The measures included closing Cambodia's borders to logging exports on December 31, asking neighbors Thailand, Laos and Vietnam to help stop illegal exports, empowering the Ministry of Agriculture to take necessary enforcement measures, and removing private security forces hired by logging companies, it said.</p>
<p>The armed forces would safeguard legal operations, it added.</p>
<p>Despite the government's public resolve to end massive logging of the nation's forests, activists and the international community continued to question its will to enforce the ban.</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund recently cancelled a $20 million loan to Cambodia, citing concerns over the country's forestry policy and the lack of transparent accounting of timber revenues.</p>
<p>Sam Rainsy, leader of the opposition Khmer Nation Party, has claimed that $51 million in logging revenues was recently diverted from state coffers. Several members of parliament have publicly expressed doubts about the government's sincerity on the forestry issue.</p>
<p>The British pressure group Global Witness has said that a government-sanctioned &quot;logging frenzy&quot; continues unabated. Logs are Cambodia's major export, although the estimated amount of exports is debated.</p>
<p>The government's 1996 budget forecast $9 million in logging revenues, but international observers say the value of exported timber is far higher.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
