<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="276843" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China jails corrupt ex-Communist Party city boss.</title>
<headline>China jails corrupt ex-Communist Party city boss.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-12-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A court has rejected the appeal of the disgraced Communist Party boss of a city in eastern China and upheld a nine-year prison term for covering up his wife's smuggling racket, a court official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Shandong provincial Higher People's Court last Saturday convicted Wang Shuwen, former Communist Party secretary of Rizhao city, of accepting bribes and bending the law to benefit relatives, the official told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>His wife, Xu Fengli, was jailed for four years for smuggling and accepting bribes, the official said.</p>
<p>Wang was found guilty of accepting 49,000 yuan ($5,900) from two foreign businessmen and covering up his wife's smuggling racket, the official said. He declined to identify the foreign businessmen, who have not been arrested.</p>
<p>The Communist Party decided recently to expel Wang and warned party officials in a circular to keep their relatives in check, the China News Service said.</p>
<p>In February, the Communist Party boss of another city in Shandong province, Hu Jianxue of Tai'an city, was sentenced to death for accepting more than 610,000 yuan ($73,000) in bribes.</p>
<p>Corruption, virtually eliminated in the years after the puritan communists came to power in 1949, has staged a comeback in the past two decades in the wake of economic reforms.</p>
<p>China has declared war on corruption, which Communist Party chief Jiang Zemin has called a &quot;virus&quot; that threatens the party's grip on power.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
