<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="276833" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Nikkei futures end weak, recovers from lows.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Nikkei futures end weak, recovers from lows.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Nikkei stock index futures finished on a defensive note Thursday but bounced off intraday lows in moderately active trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>Futures drifted in the morning in sympathy with Toyko share prices, recovering later on short covering as investment trusts resumed buying to put the Nikkei index back above 19,000.</p>
<p>The key March Nikkei contract ended at 19,285, down 260 points on a total volume of 18,450 lots.</p>
<p>Traders said price volatility contributed to the relatively good post-Christmas volume from mainly Japanese institutions. Some were seen rushing to hedge year-end cash positions.  </p>
<p>&quot;Worries about a sell-off from foreigners and technicals, helped market activity,&quot; a local commission house trader said.</p>
<p>Foreigners were thought likely to liquidate yen-based assets in view of the bearish Japanese economy.</p>
<p>The market was also hit by technical selling, with a mid-point wave objective of 18,500 points the next target.</p>
<p>&quot;A major reversal pattern for the medium term is 17,500, and we nearly hit the mid-point (18,500) today,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>The cash Nikkei, which slipped below 19,000 for the first time in over a year, is both technically and fundamentally weak.</p>
<p>--Jacqueline Wong, Singapore newsroom (65) 870 3088</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
