<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="276937" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan stocks end down after four days of gains.</title>
<headline>Taiwan stocks end down after four days of gains.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-12-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan share prices opened higher but ended with a downturn on Thursday on slack-trade profit taking, ending a string of four straight days of minor gains.</p>
<p>The index ended down 46.69 points or 0.67 percent at 6,889.03 after hitting an intrasession high of 6,952.62.</p>
<p>Turnover was a modest T$38.8 billion.</p>
<p>Brokers attributed the correction mainly to relatively sluggish year-end window-dressing by institutional investors.</p>
<p>&quot;Seeing that the expected window-dressing by institutions did not emerge actively, individual investors turned to take profits first,&quot; said Golden Securities manager Albert Lin.  </p>
<p>Construction shares, which had risen recently on expected recovery in Taiwan's long-depressed property market, led the falls, with Long Bon Construction down T$1.3 to T$30.9.</p>
<p>The financial sector, another recent gainer, also was weak, with Central Insurance down T$2 to T$67.</p>
<p>Textiles and plastics also fell, but electronics, which had suffered downward corrections recently, rebounded slightly, with Compal Electronics up T$2 to T$61.5.</p>
<p>Closed-end funds rose on hopes that they would issue high cash dividends in February or March 1997, with Jardine Fleming Fund up 25 cents to T$11.55, brokers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Due to the sound performance of Taiwan's stock market in 1996, these closed-end funds are expected each to issue high cash dividends of around T$2 to T$3 per share in February or March 1997,&quot; said Nikko Securities research chief Michael Hung.</p>
<p>Brokers said the index's fall below 6,900 was something of a surprise as many had anticipated a firming trend to test the 7,000-point resistance in the final days of 1996 trading.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not so sure now if the index can make it (breaking the 7,000-point level),&quot; Hung said.</p>
<p>A 6,850-6,910 range was seen for Friday.</p>
<p>-- James Peng (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
