<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="276964" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Furious unions strike at S.Korean labour law.</title>
<headline>Furious unions strike at S.Korean labour law.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Browne</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-12-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Militant unions threatened to paralyse South Korea's key export industries with strikes after the ruling party on Thursday rammed through parliament a labour bill that gives employers the right to lay off workers.</p>
<p>The country's second largest union body, the Korea Confederation of Trade Unions, instructed its 500,000 workers to down tools after the New Korea Party adopted the legislation at a special dawn session of the National Assembly with no opposition deputies present.</p>
<p>&quot;We have called an immediate and indefinite strike,&quot; said Yoon Young-mo, an official of the outlawed umbrella union organisation.</p>
<p>&quot;All members will stay away from their work sites and hold protest rallies across the country.&quot;</p>
<p>Union workers at Kia Motors and Ssangyong Motor abandoned production lines while workers at Hyundai Group, the country's top industrial conglomerate, and six shipyards said they would walk out after lunch.</p>
<p>Vehicles and ships are two of South Korea's biggest export items.</p>
<p>Leaders of the largest and more moderate union body, the Federation of Korean Trade Unions, were huddled in a meeting to discuss possible industrial action.</p>
<p>As industrial chaos loomed, the stock market dived and economists warned of the short-term damage to the economy, already shaky because of an export slowdown.</p>
<p>&quot;The strikes will lead to production losses, export losses and a deterioration of the current account deficit,&quot; said Tae Chung, a strategist at Jardine Fleming Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a serious blow to the market.&quot;</p>
<p>However, analysts said the labour law would benefit the economy in the long term by allowing employers to cut costs and increase their competitiveness.</p>
<p>The hotly debated bill challenges near-total job security in South Korea by giving employers the right to lay off workers. It also allows flexible working hours, enabling firms to respond quickly to seasonal demand.</p>
<p>Opposition parties had earlier blocked passage of the bill by physically preventing the speaker of parliament from calling the National Assembly into session.</p>
<p>Employers have threatened to replace workers striking over the labour bill.</p>
<p>The main opposition National Congress for New Politics condemned the surprise move by President Kim Young-sam's ruling party and said it would join hands with the minor United Liberal Democrats to fight the legislation.</p>
<p>&quot;We define the New Korea Party's sneaky passage of the legislation as a 'Kim Young-sam coup',&quot; the National Congress said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;We will launch an all-out struggle together with the United Liberal Democrats to nullify and frustrate this 'Kim Young-sam coup'.&quot;</p>
<p>A statement by the Hyundai Group union described the adoption of the law as &quot;a barbarous act that ridicules and tramples on the people's request for reform&quot;.</p>
<p>The National Assembly also pushed through another controversial law giving wider powers to the National Security Planning Agency to investigate citizens suspected of sympathising with communist North Korea.</p>
<p>South Korea's version of the U.S. Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) had been stripped of many of its investigative powers by President Kim under an election pledge to curb the agency that once hounded the political opposition.</p>
<p>Opposition parties accuse Kim of rejuvenating the agency to launch attacks on his opponents ahead of presidential elections next December.</p>
<p>The ruling party insists the agency must be given sharper teeth to combat a renewed threat of subversion from Pyongyang, highlighted by the intrusion of a North Korean submarine in September and violent leftist student protests.</p>
<p>A ruling party statement said: &quot;We feel sorry to notify people that we had no choice but to take emergency steps to rescue our political activity in the National Assembly, which was drifting and blocked by the opposition.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
