<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="277161" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. voices dismay at Singapore meddling charge.</title>
<headline>U.S. voices dismay at Singapore meddling charge.</headline>
<byline>Jim Wolf</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States voiced dismay on Thursday at a charge that it had interfered in Singapore's domestic affairs and said it had no plans to discuss the matter further.</p>
<p>&quot;Frankly, we're a little surprised by the back and forth that we've seen today&quot; from Singapore over a State Department comment on Prime Minister Goh Chok Tong's election campaign tactics, a State Department spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't see that it's necessary ... to either meet with Singaporean officials here or there to discuss the issue,&quot; the spokesman, John Dinger, told reporters. He said the comment that offended the Singapore authorities was merely a restatement of a general principle &quot;with which we think few people could disagree.&quot;</p>
<p>The department touched off the trans-Pacific spat on Tuesday in reply to a question about a threat by Goh and members of his long-ruling People's Action Party to retaliate against districts that elect opposition members of parliament on Jan. 2.</p>
<p>In its two-sentence comment at the time, the department said: &quot;We understand that ruling party candidates, including the prime minister, have warned that constituencies that elect opposition candidates will receive low priority in extensive government plans to upgrade housing facilities.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that voters everywhere should be able to vote without fear of repercussions from government as a result of the exercise of their responsibilities as citizens.&quot;</p>
<p>Although the first sentence of the State Department did little more than sum up a warning to voters that Goh himself had delivered a few days before, the prime minister said on Thursday that he was &quot;furious, flabbergasted and floored&quot; over U.S. criticism of his election campaign tactics.</p>
<p>And in a statement, the Singapore Foreign Ministry called the State Department comment &quot;undisguised interference in Singapore's domestic politics.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This is not the first time that U.S. officials have tried to influence domestic politics in Singapore,&quot; the ministry said. &quot;In the U.S. the use of political advertisements to scare voters with the prospect of losing health and welfare entitlements if they should vote for the wrong party has been honed to a fine art.&quot;</p>
<p>Goh said on Sunday he would respect the voters' choice if they elected someone from the opposition, but, he added: &quot;Then you'll be left behind; then in 20, 30 years' time, the whole of Singapore will be bustling away and your estate, through your own choice, will be left behind. They become slums. That's my message.&quot;</p>
<p>Dinger shrugged off the controversy. &quot;We've, one, repeated factually what the Singaporean officials have said and, two, stated a general principle with which we think few people could disagree, including the Singaporeans and Americans and anyone else in the world.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
