<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="277279" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany warns Milosevic not to hinder protests.</title>
<headline>Germany warns Milosevic not to hinder protests.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-12-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel issued a direct warning to Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic on Thursday not to hinder opposition protests in Belgrade.</p>
<p>Kinkel said the outside world would not stand by if Milosevic banned opposition political rallies in Belgrade on the grounds they were obstructing traffic.</p>
<p>&quot;President Milosevic has to be aware of the fact that the world is keeping its eyes on Belgrade,&quot; Kinkel said.</p>
<p>&quot;He should keep his hands off the demonstrator's rights and their freedom to congregate. A further escalation won't be tolerated.&quot;</p>
<p>Yugoslavia's hopes of integrating with Europe would be setback by any attempt to stop the rallies, Kinkel warned.</p>
<p>&quot;President Milosevic should know that steps against the peaceful demonstrators would not simply be accepted by the community of nations,&quot; Kinkel said.</p>
<p>&quot;President Milosevic should definitely keep in mind Belgrade's own efforts to return to Europe if he is thinking of banning demonstrations with the justification that they are blocking traffic,&quot; the German foreign minister added.</p>
<p>&quot;The freedom to gather and the freedom to speak along with pluralism and the freedom of the press are the cornerstones of every democratic society,&quot; Kinkel said.</p>
<p>&quot;Anyone who tries to place limits on democratic freedoms will have to face the consequences.&quot;</p>
<p>Serbian police have said opposition political rallies will no longer be permitted if they obstruct traffic.</p>
<p>Opponents of Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic have blocked the centre of the capital for the past 36 days with massive protests triggered by the refusal of ruling Socialists to acknowledge opposition victories in local elections.</p>
<p>The protests were free of violence until Tuesday when crowds of pro and anti-Milosevic demonstrators clashed in Belgrade.</p>
<p>Fifty-eight people were treated for injuries, including one man who was shot in the head and critically wounded.</p>
<p>Other western European states and the United States have warned Belgrade that using force to obstruct demonstrations would jeopardise Yugoslavia's standing with the West.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
