<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="277276" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German community longs for answers to bomb blast.</title>
<headline>German community longs for answers to bomb blast.</headline>
<byline>Scott Miller</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-12-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mourners at a solemn church service struggled in vain on Thursday to come to terms with what drove a 49-year-old woman to blow herself up with hand grenades in the middle of a crowded church on Christmas Eve.</p>
<p>&quot;Christmas has brought us more questions than answers this year,&quot; a tearful Father Bernd Wangerin told 40 worshippers at a memorial church service for the victims of the Christmas Eve attack that exploded in the South Sindlingen Protestant church just up the road.</p>
<p>Gathering in a Arche community church in the Frankfurt district of Sindlingen only a half mile (one km) away from the scene of the crime, the worshippers could not understand why the suicide bomber had picked their church.</p>
<p>&quot;We have injuries among us in spirit and in body,&quot; Wangerin said in his sermon. &quot;But the injuries among us will bind us together.&quot;</p>
<p>Many of the worshippers had friends who were in the nearby South Sindlingen church for the fateful midnight service on Tuesday. None said they had ever seen the 49-year-old woman from the nearby Frankfurt district of Roedelheim in the church.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very very tragic that something like this could happen to us here,&quot; said one elderly man.</p>
<p>Worshippers in the small stone church stood and held hands when Wangerin called for them to pray for the victims of the blast -- two elderly women who were sitting next to the suicide bomber in the third to last row of the church.</p>
<p>Outside the South Sindlingen Protestant church where the attack occured police had erected barriers.</p>
<p>A small hand-written sign was hung on a posterboard outside the church informing church visitors that further services would be held down the road.</p>
<p>Juergen Pleines, who played the organ for the Thursday memorial service, recalled the horror of the Christmas Eve nightmare.</p>
<p>&quot;I saw a flash out of the left corner of my eye and then heard screaming,&quot; said Pleines, the organist at the deadly midnight church service. &quot;Everyone just ran out. It was terrible.&quot;</p>
<p>Pleines and others said the tragedy had welded together the working class community. Many of the churchgoers work nearby at the giant chemical company Hoechst AG.</p>
<p>&quot;The churches here have really come together during this tragic time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An elderly woman wearing a white fur coat on the bitter cold morning said she was worried the impact the bomb blast would have on young children and asked the same question that many have over the last day and a half.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not understand what made her do it,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>A steady stream of mourners came to front of the church where the blast took place, placing candles and flowers at the closed off gate. They gazed silently at the large leafless tree that stands in the church garden.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
