<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="277257" id="root" date="1996-12-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German police identify Christmas Eve church bomber.</title>
<headline>German police identify Christmas Eve church bomber.</headline>
<byline>Scott Miller</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-12-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>German police said on Thursday a Frankfurt woman who killed herself and two elderly sisters in a Christmas Eve church bomb attack was undergoing psychiatric treatment and was most probably driven by &quot;personal motives&quot;.</p>
<p>A police spokesman the 49-year-old suicide bomber had been separated for the last year from her husband, who lived with their nine-year-old daughter. The three had once lived together in Frankfurt near the scene of the attack.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe her motives were personal,&quot; said Frankfurt police spokesman Peter Borchardt. &quot;We have ruled out a terrorist or political motive. It appears to be a suicide.&quot;</p>
<p>The two other dead women, 59 and 61 years old, were sitting near the bomber in a rear pew when the blast shook the small stone church in the western Frankfurt district of Sindlingen shortly before midnight on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Thirteen other worshippers, including a 12-year-old girl, were badly injured when the blast sent shrapnel, oily black smoke and bits of smashed pews flying through the crowded Protestant church service.</p>
<p>The condition of the 12-year-old girl had stabilised on Thursday, but authorities said the girl's mother was still in extremely critical condition.</p>
<p>Police said they did not know if the woman's separation from her daughter and husband had anything to do with the attack. Investigators were questioning the husband on Thursday.</p>
<p>Borchardt said police believe the woman, who set off two hand grenades strapped to her abdomen after taking a seat near the back of the church, apparently did not aim to kill many people because she was leaning forward in a crouched position.</p>
<p>&quot;Apparently she underestimated the effects the hand grenades would have,&quot; Borchardt said.</p>
<p>German President Roman Herzog said he was horrified by the wanton violence. Dozens of mourners attended a memorial service for the victims in a nearby church.</p>
<p>&quot;Our holy night was destroyed in a most horrible way,&quot; Father Bernd Wangerin said in his tearful sermon at a church a half mile away (one km) from the South Sindlingen Protestant church.</p>
<p>Although the woman was blown to pieces by the blast so completely that police were unable to find any finger prints, she was identified on Thursday after police published a photograph of her severed head.</p>
<p>They had covered the neck with clothing and the mug shots of the remarkably well-preserved face were broadcast repeatedly on German networks. The pictures showed a woman who looked considerably younger than 49 with long dark hair and blue eyes.</p>
<p>Police inspecting her flat in the outlying town of Usingen did not found a suicide note. They said the woman apparently took public transport to the church.</p>
<p>The suicide bomber was not named out of respect for her family, police said.</p>
<p>They said she was from Roedelheim, a Frankfurt district a few kilometres (miles) to the east of the South Sindlingen Protestant church she attacked, but had been living in the town of Usingen north of Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Police did not know how the woman had obtained the two grenades, which were of East European origin. Illegal arms dealers have large stocks of explosives and firearms from former Soviet forces based in East Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;The burning question is how did she get two hand grenades,&quot; a police investigator said.</p>
<p>Authorities dismissed as speculation a German radio report that the woman got the idea for the bombing from a film recently broadcast on German television in which a hostage-taker sets off a bomb in a church.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
