<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="27762" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares extend losses on n.Iraqi fighting.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares extend losses on n.Iraqi fighting.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Istanbul shares extended morning losses in thin afternoon trade on Monday amid caution and poor morale caused by weekend fighting in Kurdish-held northern Iraq, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's uneasiness was due to the Iraqi fighting although all earlier (technical) indicators were in favour of the bourse. There is anxiety because the fighting may spread and the U.S. may intervene,&quot; said Semih Cetin, general manager of Bayindir Securities.</p>
<p>The IKMB-100 closed at 63,275.86, down 1,257.51 points, or 1.95 percent from Thursday. Turkish markets were closed for a holiday on Friday. Last week's loss was 0.7 percent.</p>
<p>The index brushed a low of 63,045 in the second session after finishing 1.66 percent down at 63,464.46 at midday.</p>
<p>Daily volume shrank to 4.3 trillion lira from Thursday's 6.2 trillion.</p>
<p>&quot;Besides the developments in northern Iraq, the market is also worried about the Treasury's ability to borrow in domestic markets to meet its hefty t-bill repayments in September,&quot; said Cem Yalcinkaya from Garanti investment bank.</p>
<p>The Treasury will auction 112-day t-bills on Tuesday after it sharply raised the average yield to 135 percent in last week's 189-day t-bill auction from 128.94 percent at the previous 211-day bill auction a week ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Tomorrow's auction is quite important, it will affect all the markets,&quot; Yalcinkaya said.</p>
<p>&quot;The index will test support at around 63,000 amid ongoing squeeze in the market. There is no fresh cash entry, switching of shares make up all the transactions,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The 85-share industrial index lost 2.1 percent to 69,292.48 and the 15-share financial index dropped 1.57 percent to 56,302.49. Of the 217 shares traded, losers sharply outpaced gainers by 171 to 19 and 27 ended stable.</p>
<p>Leading actives were T.Isbank's C series shares, unchanged at 9,600 lira and B series, steady at 130,000 lira, followed by utility Aktas Elektrik which fell 25,000 lira to 460,000.</p>
<p>-- Aydan Eksin, Istanbul Newsroom, +90-212-275 0875</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
