<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="277719" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech PX50 closes lower in thin trading.</title>
<headline>Czech PX50 closes lower in thin trading.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share trading on the Prague Stock Exchange (PSE) was predictably thin on Friday after a three day break for Christmas.</p>
<p>The PX50 index lost 1.6 points to 529.5 while the major issue dominated RPIX index of continuously traded shares fell 4.5 points to 1,103.5.</p>
<p>Dealers said that despite the low activity, there was some interest in investment funds. During continuous trading RIF and SPIF Cesky investment funds were two of only four shares on the RPIX to register any trade turnover.</p>
<p>RIF lost five crowns to 845 while SPIF rose two to 430.</p>
<p>Among the most heavily capitalised shares on the PX50, power utility CEZ was the biggest mover, losing 29 crowns to 956. Dealers said the fall was likely to have been caused by a small number of relatively high volume trades. CEZ did not trade on the PSE after the morning price fixing.</p>
<p>The PSE announced on Friday that three small issues on the PX50 would be replaced on January 6.</p>
<p>The shares to be removed from the index are aircraft production holding company Aero Holding a.s., ocean shipper Ceskoslovenska Namorni Plavba a.s., glass fibre maker Vertex a.s..</p>
<p>The shares to be added to the index are fats and edible oils producer Milo Olomouc a.s., heating utility Moravskoslezske Teplarny a.s, steel producer Vitkovice a.s..</p>
<p>The PSE meets to discuss changes to its indices every three months.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
