<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="277798" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUATEMALA: Guatemala president lauds army peace process role.</title>
<headline>Guatemala president lauds army peace process role.</headline>
<byline>Henry Tricks</byline>
<dateline>GUATEMALA CITY 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Guatemalan President Alvaro Arzu on Friday praised the army for supporting the peace process and criticised human rights groups for being sceptical of the landmark treaty ending a 36-year war.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't find any stumbling blocks put up by the armed forces or the business sector, both of whom had been expected to present some kind of opposition,&quot; Arzu told Reuters two days before the gala peace ceremony on Sunday.</p>
<p>He said commanders of the Guatemalan National Revolutionary Movement (URNG) rebels, who will sign the peace treaty with the government, also showed a &quot;positive and constructive attitude.&quot;</p>
<p>But Arzu, who has moved quickly to end Central America's longest-running guerrilla war after less than 12 months in office, hit out at human rights and other groups, accusing them of double standards for criticising the accords.</p>
<p>&quot;There are other sectors who we had hoped for support and an unconditional response because for 36 years they had begged for peace in Guatemala,&quot; he said, referring to these groups. &quot;When they saw it coming closer, they felt they were losing something and they were the ones who put up obstacles -- but they can all be overcome,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Over the years, in a conflict in which 140,000 people have died or disappeared, most as a result of brutal military anti-insurgency sweeps, such groups have lambasted the army, accusing it of waging a dirty war against civilians.</p>
<p>Arzu also angrily blasted the Guatemalan press for questioning the peace accords, showing flashes of the stubborn rejection of criticism that analysts say has helped him bring peace to Guatemala where past presidents have failed.</p>
<p>Left-wing groups and some of Arzu's opponents in Congress said parts of the treaty, such as a limited amnesty for combatants, were too weak. They worried that perpetrators of massacres and torture would evade justice, even though such crimes are supposedly exempt from the amnesty.</p>
<p>Explaining the amnesty, Arzu said violence has been endemic for centuries in Guatemala, where some 60 percent of the people are Indians who live in extreme poverty and have long been under the thumb of lighter-skinned overlords backed by the army. He also said massacres would not go unpunished.</p>
<p>&quot;The reality is that Guatemalans have never been reconciled,&quot; he said, adding that pardoning crimes did not mean forgetting them. He said no one could &quot;cast the first stone&quot; in a society where so many sectors have guilty pasts.</p>
<p>&quot;For 36 years (the army and the URNG rebels) have committed any amount of abuses ... All wars are dirty,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He played down his personal role in the peace accords, the signing of which is to be attended by heads of states and others from around the world including outgoing U.N. Secretary General Boutros Boutros-Ghali.</p>
<p>Besides promoting peace, Arzu, 50, a former businessman who was considered a colourless politician before he took over the blood-stained country in January, carried out an unprecedented purge of corrupt military officers and government officials.</p>
<p>On Friday, he hinted that he was likely to name a civilian defence minister to head the long-powerful military.</p>
<p>For Arzu, his first year in office has been &quot;an eternity,&quot; he said, but peace marked only the beginning of a long process of reconciliation in Guatemala that will require billions of dollars to implement, much from international donors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUATEMALA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUATEMALA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
