<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="277826" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Rio's Banerj seen sold off despite court action.</title>
<headline>Rio's Banerj seen sold off despite court action.</headline>
<byline>Fatima Cristina</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The privatization of Rio de Janeiro state bank Banerj will move ahead despite court battles to block its sale, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Court orders against the auction will continue, this is part of the process,&quot; said Alberto Furuguem, former Central Bank director and now a private consultant. &quot;But I have no doubt Banerj will be sold off, it is just a question of time.&quot;  </p>
<p>Banerj's sale was postponed Thursday for the second time in 10 days due to a court ruling but officials hope to overcome the obstacles and put the bank back on the auction block in January.</p>
<p>The fate of Banerj now hinges on a Central Bank's decision to extend for more 180 days its administration of the bank, which expires today, and allow for Banerj's privatization, preventing it from being liquidated or turned into a federal bank.  </p>
<p>The Central Bank said it and Rio state officials were likely to announce an agreement on the future of Banerj later in the day. Central Bank director Alkimar Moura told reporters the bank would extend beyond a Friday deadline its management of Banerj if asked to do so by Rio officials.</p>
<p>Analysts are confident that the Central Bank will facilitate the bank's sell-off because the federal government sees the bank as the first of many state banks to be privatized.</p>
<p>&quot;Banerj's sale would be a benchmark for other state bank privatizations,&quot; said Erivelto Rodrigues, an analyst at Austin Asis banking consulting firm.  </p>
<p>The Central Bank is also expected to decide whether private bank Bozano, Simonsen will continue to run Banerj. The bank has been managing Banerj on behalf of the Central Bank since early January but the contract expires at year's end.</p>
<p>The latest delay in Banerj's sell-off was due to a judge's decision to order the re-evaluation of the bank's assets, particularly real estate holdings.</p>
<p>The judge's ruling, based on claims by Banerj employees that the bank's assets were undervalued, forced Rio state officials to suspend the auction as it meant the winning bidder could end up paying more than the bid price if the court decided the bank's assets had been indeed underestimated.</p>
<p>Despite the court action, Rio state said it would not re-evaluate Banerj's assets, arguing that the ruling was based on non-updated figures.</p>
<p>The state said the judge's decision simply demands a clarification of the figures. It added it would also clarify for investors the assets' value in the new tender documents to be published early next year. ((-- Rio de Janeiro Newsroom, 5521 5074151))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
