<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="277923" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Attorneys warned Gingrich about projects - newspaper.</title>
<headline>Attorneys warned Gingrich about projects - newspaper.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>House Speaker Newt Gingrich was warned by two attorneys six years ago about involving charitable or educational foundations in political projects, a newspaper reported Friday.</p>
<p>As part of a negotiated settlement last week with a House ethics panel, the Georgia Republican said he was &quot;wrong&quot; not to have sought legal advice to make sure a controversial college course he later taught complied with tax laws.</p>
<p>But the Atlanta Journal-Constitution reported that two attorneys advised him against involving charity or educational funding in political projects in 1990 and urged caution on the issue. The article was based on internal memos submitted to GOPAC, Gingrich's former political action committee.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately, there has been a lot of distorted and false information being disseminated ...,&quot; Tony Blankley, Gingrich's press secretary in Washington, said in a statement. &quot;Taken in context, the two memos now being reported on in the press are not at all inconsistent with the finding of the (ethics) Subcommittee.&quot;</p>
<p>The newspaper also obtained documents from Kennesaw State College, a Georgia school where the Gingrich course &quot;Renewing American Civilisation&quot; was first taught in 1993, showing the speaker continued to consult one of the attorneys as he organised a curriculum that laid out his political philosophy.</p>
<p>In a memo to one college dean, dated five months before the course began, Gingrich introduced attorney Gordon Strauss as his &quot;lawyer for all finance, ethics and legal questions.&quot; The newspaper said the same attorney had said in a 1990 letter to GOPAC that charitable and educational groups were barred under tax laws from engaging in political activity.</p>
<p>The memo prepared by Strauss in 1990 &quot;outlined the permissible role of various organisations in pursuit of the goal to change America,&quot; Blankley said. &quot;The memo was not directly written for or specifically related to the college course Newt taught.&quot;</p>
<p>A House ethics report last week concluded that Gingrich's partisan political operatives were involved in course fund-raising and content development.</p>
<p>Blankley said Gingrich told the committee he sought and obtained legal counsel during the process of setting up his college course.</p>
<p>&quot;The Committee was aware of this. It found, however, that while Newt sought the advice of counsel, he did not seek the advice of lawyers with the necessary expertise at the appropriate time,&quot; Blankley said.</p>
<p>The ethics committee will next consider what penalty, if any, to impose on the speaker. Republicans, who have mostly rallied behind Gingrich, were hoping the penalty phase will be concluded before the House votes Jan. 7 on re-electing him as speaker. Some Democrats have called for Gingrich to step down.</p>
<p>However, due to the holiday season it was unclear when the ethics committee might be able to meet.</p>
<p>The Congressional Accountability Project, which is affiliated with consumer advocate Ralph Nader, sent a letter seeking Gingrich's ouster to ethics committee leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;He must be held accountable for his actions,&quot; the letter, signed by the project's director, Gary Ruskin, said. &quot;The Speaker must, at a minimum, be forced from the Speaker's Chair, if not expelled from the House of Representatives entirely,&quot; the letter said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
