<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="277973" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Treasuries end up on data, techs, foreigners.</title>
<headline>U.S. Treasuries end up on data, techs, foreigners.</headline>
<byline>Jose Paulo Vicente</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries closed higher in light trade, boosted by fresh market-friendly data, a solid technical picture and some foreign buying after the dollar surged to a 44-month high against the Japanese yen.</p>
<p>The 6-1/2-percent 30-year benchmark Treasury bond ended up 20/32 at 99-16/32. Its yield was at 6.54 percent, the lowest level since December 11.</p>
<p>The buying was concentrated in the long end of the yield curve, but overall volume remained fairly weak as several players were still sidelined ahead of the end of the year.  </p>
<p>Turnover was $37.69 billion in late trade as measured by GovPX, 33 percent below an average autumn Friday.</p>
<p>Coupon trade was strong, accounting for more than 60 percent of overall activity. GovPX publishes real time Treasury prices and volume from five of the six intra-dealer brokers, representing 65 percent of the intra-dealer trades.</p>
<p>Market activity was spurred early in the session by the release of a surprising 1.6 percent drop in November durable goods orders against a revised 0.5 percent rise in October.</p>
<p>The data suggested the economy might not be growing as fast as some experts had previously thought.  </p>
<p>Although no one said the data were likely to move the Federal Reserve's monetary policy one way or the other, analysts said the weak indicator provided underpinning to the market on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The report was sort of the excuse to go and do things,&quot; said William Dudley, managing director and chief U.S. economist at Goldman Sachs &amp; Co Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;It really was a soft report but ... it's not going to change my view of the world in any meaningful way,&quot; Dudley said, adding he sees the Fed remaining on hold &quot;for a while.&quot;  </p>
<p>The solid set of numbers gave the market the impetus for a break out of the 113-21/32 resistance level on the March futures bond contract.</p>
<p>&quot;It was very important to break through that level because it had been stubbornly in place for five trading sessions ... and the market had rejected that level numerous times,&quot; said Patrick Dimick, Treasury market strategist at UBS Securities.</p>
<p>The contract quickly shot up to 114-00, where it lingered for most of the day as it met a new strong resistance at that level. The technical picture, however, remained fairly positive going forward, analysts said.  </p>
<p>The new target high for the bond contract is now seen at 114-6/32 and then at 114-15/32.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we can go higher ... there are reasons to believe it. For example, there is a lot of cash that is going to have to be put to work as the first quarter of the new year begins,&quot; UBS's Dimick said.</p>
<p>&quot;You could have the catalist for putting that cash to work as soon as Tuesday, with the Chicago PMI,&quot; Dimick added, referring to the December Chicago Purchasing Managers Index which will be released on December 31.  </p>
<p>Players chose to shrug off a drop in initial jobless claims to 335,000 in the week ended December 21 from a revised 350,000 in the week before. The data suggested the U.S. labor market remained strong and tight.</p>
<p>A dollar surge to 116 yen, its highest level in almost 45 months, also bolstered the Treasury market.</p>
<p>By making dollar-denominated assets more attractive to foreign investors, a stronger dollar is seen as a positive factor to Treasuries, traders said.  </p>
<p>The greenback rise was seen as prompting some buying by foreign accounts. Traders also reported talk of &quot;under-the-table&quot; buying by the Federal Reserve</p>
<p>&quot;There was talk of the Fed buying under-the-table, which actually makes a lot of sense under the circumstances,&quot; said a trader at a major U.S. investment bank.</p>
<p>Despite the rise, flows were still very light as several hedge and pension funds remained out of the market. Retailers were also seen mostly sidelined and some traders mentioned some light money manager buying in the long end of curve.  </p>
<p>The three-month Treasury bill rate closed down one basis point at 4.97 percent. The six-month bill rate rose one point to 5.07 percent. The year bill rate was down two points at 5.18 percent.</p>
<p>The two-year note closed up 2/32 at 99-29/32, yielding 5.80 percent. The five-year note traded up 6/32 at 100-5/32 to yield 6.09 percent. The ten-year note closed up 12/32 at 101-16/32, yielding 6.29 percent.</p>
<p>(( -- 212-859-1676 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
