<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="277929" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Storm pounds western U.S., disrupts power, travel.</title>
<headline>Storm pounds western U.S., disrupts power, travel.</headline>
<byline>Adam Entous</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A powerful winter storm hit the U.S. Northwest on Friday, cutting power to homes and businesses across Washington and Oregon, while California braced for a second front that could cause flash flooding.</p>
<p>At least two deaths and several injuries were attributed to the harsh weather.</p>
<p>Snow and freezing rain fell overnight in the Seattle area, virtually shutting down the city. Major highways crossing the Cascade mountains were closed.</p>
<p>Puget Sound Power and Light Co., which services nine counties in western Washington state, said about 198,650 of its customers were without power on Friday. The outages affected about a quarter of its customers.</p>
<p>Betty Werblun, a spokeswoman for Puget Power, said 120 crews were struggling in the snow and ice to restore service, but the weather made their work nearly impossible.</p>
<p>She said freezing rain and snow was to blame for the outages. Tree limbs, heavy with snow and ice, were snapping and falling on top of power lines. It could take until Monday to restore power to every home and business that has been cut off, depending on the weather, Werblun said.</p>
<p>The storm stranded thousands for hours at the Seattle-Tacoma International Airport. About 300 people were forced to sleep overnight in the terminals.</p>
<p>The extreme conditions were causing long delays and cancellations of departing and arriving flights. Airlines cancelled most departures through midday and officials urged travelers not to come to the airport at all.</p>
<p>&quot;The icing conditions are worse than any airport veteran can remember,&quot; said Mike Merritt, spokesman for the airport. An estimated 400 arrivals and departures had been cancelled through midday because of the conditions, he said.</p>
<p>In western Washington state, a woman died in a car crash on an icy road. Local authorities blamed the storm.</p>
<p>In Oregon, tens of thousands of homes remained without power. About 60,000 of Portland General Electric Co's customers were without electricity because Thursday's ice storm downed local power lines.</p>
<p>A Portland man, while trimming trees damaged in the storm, died of an apparent heart attack.</p>
<p>Rain continued to fall around Portland, but forecasters said freezing rain was not expected on Friday because temperatures had warmed.</p>
<p>&quot;The real concern is the number of storms that are due in over this weekend that are going to bring additional rain,&quot; said Larry Raaf, program manager with Oregon Emergency Management. &quot;We'll be keeping our fingers crossed.&quot;</p>
<p>The Portland International Airport reported normal operations on Friday. Icy weather on Thursday knocked out power to the airport, forcing flight delays and cancellations that stranded some travelers overnight.</p>
<p>The skies were generally calm over northern and central California, though scattered rain and snow showers were reported. A winter storm warning was in effect in the Sierra Nevada mountains.</p>
<p>The National Weather Service warned, however, that a second Pacific storm was bearing down on California and could reach its northern coast late on Saturday.</p>
<p>The approaching storm could dump more than 10 inches (25 cm) of rain in some areas and cause flash flooding in northern and central California, forecasters said.</p>
<p>The storm, which was building north of the Hawaiian islands, could melt the snowpack in the Sierra Nevada, where residents were still digging out from the last pounding.</p>
<p>Last weekend, more than nine feet (3 metres) of snow fell in some parts of the popular Lake Tahoe ski resort area on the northern California-Nevada border.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
