<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278012" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Maine's Gov says revenues slip in Nov but on track.</title>
<headline>Maine's Gov says revenues slip in Nov but on track.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Maine Gov Angus King on Friday said that while general fund revenues were slightly lower than budgeted in November, they remain &quot;well ahead&quot; of estimates for the year.</p>
<p>Year-to-date revenues, including November's collections, which fell four percent below budget, exceeded projections by $15.4 million or two percent, King said, in prepared remarks.</p>
<p>Maine attributed the drop in November's revenues in part due to a shorter tax-processing period, and noted it does not contain sales tax revenues from Christmas, which King said many analysts said had been strong in the state.</p>
<p>&quot;State revenues continue to show the economy is on track and growing at a steady, if modest rate. We expect to see this trend continue for the foreseeable future,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In November, general fund revenues totaled $124.9 million, with sales tax receipts adding up to almost $52.9 million, slightly under projections but three percent above the year-ago period.</p>
<p>Individual income tax receipts totaled almost $42.5 million, eight percent below target for the month, but one percent above projections for the year. Corporate income tax receipts were $750,422, down 58 percent for the month, but 74 percent higher for the year-to-date.</p>
<p>((--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
