<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278027" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: World population growth could stabilize by 2025.</title>
<headline>World population growth could stabilize by 2025.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kenen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>World population is growing more slowly than in recent years and with a concerted effort to defuse a &quot;demographic time bomb&quot; population could stabilise at eight billion by 2025, an advocacy group said on Friday.</p>
<p>The Population Institute, which released the study on global population and fertility trends, urged President Bill Clinton to act by Feb. 1, under a provision that could free up global population funds that have been appropriated but may not be released by the Republican-controlled Congress.</p>
<p>Werner Fornos, president of the Washington-based institute, said the world's population is growing by almost 90 million annually, more slowly than the 100 million growth of recent years. But he said that rate was still too high for the planet to support.</p>
<p>The world's population is nearing 5.9 billion, and will be over six billion by the year 2000. But he said it was &quot;a dream and a possibility&quot; to stabilise the population at eight billion by 2025 &quot;if we keep doing what works.&quot;</p>
<p>He was encouraged by the recent slowing of the growth rate, which he attributed in part to better education and opportunities for girls and women. And he said the 1994 world population and development conference in Cairo had led to genuine progress in making voluntary family planning available to more couples.</p>
<p>&quot;Aside from universal access to affordable family planning, equity and equality for women is the most important intervention that can be taken for slowing population growth, as well as for helping the poorest to escape poverty,&quot; the institute report said.</p>
<p>Some nations, including Thailand, Turkey and Brazil, have sharply reduced their growth rates but others, among them Nigeria, Ethiopia and several Central American nations, are on a course to double their population within 30 years, the report found.</p>
<p>As other studies have found, the richer countries use a disproportionate share of the world's resources. He said the United States has four percent of the world's population, and uses 30 percent of the resources. Overall, rich countries have a fifth of the world's population but use four-fifths of the resources, he said.</p>
<p>Fornos urged China to adopt a voluntary family planning programme, instead of its current one-child per family requirements. He also said that many practicing Roman Catholics use contraception despite the ban by the Vatican.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WORLD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
