<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278158" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. spot gas prices plummet ahead of mild weather.</title>
<headline>U.S. spot gas prices plummet ahead of mild weather.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot natural gas prices plummeted Friday as well above-normal temperatures were forecast for most of the U.S. this weekend, sources said.</p>
<p>December Gulf Coast prices fell an average of 40 cents to as low as $3.00/mmBtu as temperatures were forecast to be at least 10 degrees above normal this weekend in the East, Midwest and Texas. Early deals were confirmed done around $3.20.</p>
<p>A lack of swing activity contributed to the volatility, traders said.  </p>
<p>January gas at the Gulf Coast notionally was quoted around $3.15-3.20, down sharply from Thursday's levels at $3.70.</p>
<p>At the New York city-gate, where buyers are anticipating much warmer weather over the next few days, early weekend deals were done at $3.80, but shortly before nomination deadlines prices were down in the $3.40s, falling about 50 cents from Thursday.</p>
<p>In the Appalachian region, prices ranged anywhere from the $3.60s early to the $3.20s late, down an average of 35 cents from Thursday.</p>
<p>Midcontinent prices were for the most part in convergence with Gulf values early but then slipped into the $2.60s late, pressured by mild temperatures now in most of the region and a lack of buyers.</p>
<p>In west Texas, Permian gas prices were widely talked in the $2.60-3.25 range, down from Thursday's $3.30-3.35 trading range.</p>
<p>Prices in south Texas were also widely discussed, with late deals done in the $2.70s and $2.80s, as well above-normal temperatures left buyers disinterested in the market.</p>
<p>((--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
