<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278364" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. ads use dog-droppings to curb cigar smoking.</title>
<headline>U.S. ads use dog-droppings to curb cigar smoking.</headline>
<byline>Adam Entous</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>City health officials have declared war on cigars with advertisements likening them to dog droppings in the hope of reducing their soaring popularity with young professionals, especially women.</p>
<p>San Francisco's department of public heath put up posters near popular nightspots this month reading: &quot;Cigars: They Look Like What They Smell Like. Don't Put Them in Your Mouth!&quot; And a spot on several local cable TV stations shows a dog sniffing at a discarded cigar before his owner sweeps it into a pooper-scooper.</p>
<p>The campaign was launched in response to cigars' growing popularity, particularly among women. City officials said it was designed to counter the message sent by some cigar sellers to young professional women that stogies were chic.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an awareness campaign,&quot; Alyonik Hrushow, director of San Francisco's Tobacco-Free Project, said. &quot;They (cigar marketers) are glamorizing cigar smoking. But there's nothing glamorous about it. We see this as a public health problem.&quot;</p>
<p>She said cigar smokers, although they did not inhale, were more likely to get lung cancer than nonsmokers and much more likely to develop tumors of the mouth or lips.</p>
<p>The city's campaign will have an uphill fight against a trend also visible in other major U.S. cities. Cigar sellers in San Francisco say business is booming.</p>
<p>&quot;It's getting better and better every day,&quot; Nick Zeidan, owner of the California Tobacco Center, said. &quot;It's getting so crazy it's hard to keep up with demand.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the old guys are upset because they can't get their brands anymore. We're inundated with new young buyers,&quot; Keith Lucero, assistant manager of Grant's Tobacconist, confirmed. The store boasts 100,000 &quot;fine cigars&quot; and a walk-in humidor.</p>
<p>Despite the health risks, cigar smoking, a long-established symbol of masculinity, has become gender-free, and female puffers could account for the recent jump in sales.</p>
<p>Sales of premium imported cigars exploded last year, chalking up 33 percent growth, compared with 12 percent in 1994 and 10 percent in 1993, Cigar Aficionado said. Covers of the trendy U.S. magazine have featured cigar-smoking celebrities such as supermodel Linda Evangelista.</p>
<p>Val Cordova, owner of Cigaramor, said women represented a fast-growing market. &quot;Women are experimenting to make a statement about their independence and individuality,&quot; Cordova said. &quot;The number of women smoking is increasing every month.&quot;</p>
<p>The health department's anti-cigar campaign will run through mid-January. But Hrushow admitted, &quot;You can never expect one ad campaign to make all the difference. We're just doing what we can.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
