<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278499" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Weizman to discuss phone deal during India visit.</title>
<headline>Weizman to discuss phone deal during India visit.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Israeli delegation led by President Ezer Weizman will discuss joint business ventures including a telephone services deal during a week-long visit to India next week, Indian diplomats said on Friday.</p>
<p>Weizmann is scheduled to arrive in New Delhi but will begin on Monday a six-day official visit which would focus on more than 100 joint ventures, mostly in agriculture, they said.</p>
<p>The visit by Weizman and an accompanying business delegation will mark a new high in relations that have strengthened since India established diplomatic relations with Israel in 1992 after decades of Cold War suspicions linked to the Palestine question.</p>
<p>India's business relations with Israel appeared to reach a new high after Himachal Futuristic Communications Ltd, a joint venture in which Israel's state-run Bezeq Telecom holds 49 percent, won tenders to set up telephone services in nine Indian zones under New Delhi's economic liberalisation programme.</p>
<p>But HFCL ran into a legal dispute with the Indian government over financial modalities when it was expected to bag licences to set up telephone services in four of the zones. India had put a ceiling on the number of licences a company can operate.</p>
<p>&quot;It is (the Bezeq licence) still in a formative state. It has to be formalised,&quot; K Raghunath, a senior Foreign Ministry official told reporters in New Delhi.</p>
<p>India and Israel are expected to sign four agreements during Weizmann's visit, including one on agriculture, besides cultural and technical agreements, officials said.</p>
<p>Indian companies have shown a keen in interest to form joint ventures with Israeli counterparts to make drip irrigation equipment. Indian officials say Israel's water-conservation technology could be of immense use in India's dry zones.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
