<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278525" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Dec 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Dec 27.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by  The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>-- AUDIT OFFICE READY TO PROBE CHEAP SELL-OFF OF HMSO</p>
<p>The National Audit Office is likely to launch an inquiry into the privatisation of Her Majesty's Stationery Office, sold last October for 54 million pounds stg, less than one-third of the asking price. Both the figure and the selection process of the winner have been attacked by unsuccessful bidders. The office is due to make a small profit in the financial year after losing 39.7 million pounds stg in 1995.</p>
<p>-- DELOITTE CHIEF WARNS OF NEED TO LIMIT REGULATION</p>
<p>The chairman of leading accountancy firm Deloitte &amp; Touche says British companies are in danger of being swamped by corporate governance. Martin Scicluna, speaking to Sir Ronnie Hampel's committee reviewing codes imposed on firms, said too many codes would lead to a fall in the level of compliance and ill effects on the economy.</p>
<p>-- SURVEYORS HIT AT BLOCK ON VAT LOOPHOLE</p>
<p>The Royal Institution of Chartered Surveyors has attacked a Budget measure to block a VAT loophole for financial institutions. The loophole closed a method used by banks and other institutions which cannot recover VAT, which saw buildings leased out to an associate, who recovered VAT on the construction and let the buildings back to the bank. The Institution said closing the loophole would hit the property market hard.</p>
<p>THE TIMES</p>
<p>-- BRANSON ADVISER ACCUSED OF CORRUPTION OVER BOTSWANA AIRLINE</p>
<p>An international aviation consultant working with Richard Branson on Virgin Atlantic's expansion has had a warrant put out for his arrest by the Botswanan authorities, who allege corruption. Mr Brian Pocock has been helping Virgin put together a deal to take a stake in BWIA International, the Caribbean carrier. The alleged corruption relates to Mr Pocock's actions while general manager of Air Botswana from 1989 to 1994.</p>
<p>-- LENDERS UNITE OVER BOOM IN HOUSE PRICES</p>
<p>In a rare display of combined optimism the Halifax and Nationwide building societies have each predicted a 7 per cent rise in average house prices next year. They also believe that the number of people moving home will rise by 10 per cent next year. The Abbey National also predicts prices rising by 7 per cent, while the National Association of Estate Agents see a rise of between 6 and 8 per cent. Economists at UBS and HSBC also agree.</p>
<p>-- BIFU PREDICTS HUGE FINANCE JOB LOSSES</p>
<p>The Banking Insurance and Finance Union (Bifu) said yesterday that around 150,000 more finance jobs could be lost over the next five years. This would be on top of the 130,000 jobs that have disappeared since the late 1980s. Some 5,000 bank and building society branches closing in the past five years. One of the main threats to jobs comes from the rise in home banking, with the inevitable closure of more high street branches.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>-- BOSSES' PAY RISES FASTEST</p>
<p>A new report from the TUC claims that the gap between the pay of leading directors and their workers has risen by 4 per cent. The TUC have pointed out that the gap shows that the Greenbury Committee's reforms to curtail excessive pay has failed. It says that workers at the bottom of a company are not rewarded enough in relation to those at the top.</p>
<p>-- PREDATOR GRABS NORTHERN ELECTRIC</p>
<p>After Northern Electric dramatically lost its fight to hold off a 782 million pounds stg bid from US power company CE Electric on Tuesday, only two of the original twelve privatised regional electricity companies remain independent. The two remaining companies, Southern and Yorkshire are also regarded as potential bid targets. CE Electric secured its victory by 300,000 shares, with acceptances representing 50.3 per cent of Northern's stock.</p>
<p>-- 'CLEAN BUS' READY TO ROLL</p>
<p>An environmentally friendly hybrid vehicle known as the &quot;clean bus&quot; is to be introduced on a trial basis in Portsmouth in Hampshire, in February. The bus, designed to banish petrol fumes from city centres will be powered by both diesel and electricity. The bus has been developed by Hampshire county council and FirstBus.</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>-- CHANNEL 5 EXCEEDS RETUNING TARGET FOR CORE-AREA VIEWERS</p>
<p>Owners of Britain's soon to be launched fifth terrestrial channel, Channel 5 Broadcasting, will report next week that it has exceeded its target of retuning 50 per cent of households in its core areas. The channel's backers hope that 80 per cent of the country will be retuned by 30 March next year, the switch on date. The retuning has been necessary to avoid interference of VCRs from the Channel 5 signal and will cost 180 million pounds stg.</p>
<p>-- HOSTILE BIDS 'FAIL TO BOOST BUSINESS EFFICIENCY'</p>
<p>The City view, universally held, that hostile takeovers are a vital mechanism for improving business efficiency, has been attacked by the findings of the London Business School. The LBS said the findings contradicted the view that hostile takeovers, or the threat of them, performed a valuable function in disciplining managers of poorly performing firms, and that the targets of hostile bids were not generally poor performers in need of a shake-up.</p>
<p>-- FRENCH TOBACCO GIANT SUED</p>
<p>Seita, the French tobacco giant, has been sued for the second time in a week for causing a smoker's cancer. In only the second legal case on its kind in France, the latest lawsuit has been filed by the family of a young woman who died of lung cancer last October and who had smoked Seita's Gauloises Brunes for 20 years. Despite a slight slump in shares Seita are confident about the outcome of the case.</p>
<p> For a full range of news monitoring services,   phone BMC</p>
<p>&quot;44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
