<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278560" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Equatorial advises no action on bid.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Equatorial advises no action on bid.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Equatorial Mining NL on Friday advised its shareholders to take no action pending a board recomendation on a proposed 25-cents-a-share unconditional takeover offer made by Quay Mining Ltd, a wholly-owned subsidiary of Australian Mutual Provident Society (AMP).</p>
<p>The AMP issued a formal Part A statement December 23.</p>
<p>The AMP said on Monday it held 99.3 million shares in Equatorial Mining or about 31 percent of its issued capital.  </p>
<p>Equatorial Mining is involved in the development of the El Tesoro copper project in Chile which is expected to be in production in late 1998, the AMP said.</p>
<p>Equatorial Mining also recently announced it has acquired the option to purchase the Mineral Park copper mine in Arizona and the Tonopah copper ore body in Nevada, from Cyprus Climax Metals Co, the AMP said.</p>
<p>It is expected that Equatorial Mining will fully develop these properties as soon as possible, subject to due diligence and the preparation of a bankable feasibility study for the Tonopah property.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
