<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278571" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Elite Malaysian team searches for storm victims.</title>
<headline>Elite Malaysian team searches for storm victims.</headline>
<dateline>KOTA KINABALU, Malaysia 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>An elite team led the search on Friday for victims of the tropical storm that hit Malaysia and killed at least 109 people, most of them of Indonesian origin, and left as many missing, officials said.</p>
<p>The Special Malaysian Disaster Assistance and Rescue Team (SMART) waded through swollen rivers and dug under mountainous debris in the interior of the east Malaysian state of Sabah on Borneo island to find the victims of the Christmas day storm.</p>
<p>Malaysian Information Minister Mohamed Rahmat told a news conference in Sabah's capital, Kota Kinabalu, that the death toll had risen to 109, and most of the victims were Indonesian migrant workers.</p>
<p>&quot;It's extraordinary...the worst disaster I can think of,&quot; said Mohamed, who is also the chairman of Malaysia's Natural Disaster Committee.</p>
<p>Tropical storm Greg, which blew ashore in Sabah from the South China Sea at 70 kph (44 mph) on Wednesday, triggered heavy rains and floods that swelled rivers to overflowing, downed power lines and washed out road and communications links.</p>
<p>Mohamed said the casualty rate could have been reduced if the nation had a better early warning system for storms.</p>
<p>He said the Malaysian Metereological Services Department had warned on Christmas eve that it expected heavy rain and strong winds from a tropical depression heading towards Sabah, without actually suggesting that a tropical storm was coming.</p>
<p>Storm Greg's biggest blow was to Keningau, a small logging town 150 km (95 miles) south of Kota Kinabalu. Officials said 500 houses in nine villages along four rivers in the town were washed away, leaving about 3,000 people homeless.</p>
<p>Mohamed said 105 bodies were found in Keningau and 82 of the dead were Indonesians working in sawmills there.</p>
<p>The other bodies were found in the neighbouring towns of Papar, Tuaran and Kota Kinabalu. Officials said some of the victims could be Filipinos, who also formed a large part of the migrant workers in Sabah.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who died either drowned or were crushed by heavy objects,&quot; Mohamed said. National television coverage of the disaster showed overflowing rivers, fallen trees, collapsed and roofless houses, and capsized boats.</p>
<p>Officials said 26 people were hospitalised with injuries.</p>
<p>They said some 500 workers were involved in relief operations, with about 230 assisting the 24-member SMART team.</p>
<p>SMART, drawn from members of the police, armed forces and the fire department, was formed after the 1993 collapse of the Highland Towers condominium in Kuala Lumpur that killed 48 people.</p>
<p>The team members, trained abroad in tunnelling and handling of tracker dogs, are believed to be on their first major mission, the national Bernama news agency said.</p>
<p>Officials said telecommunications and road access to Keningau, a town hidden under thick forest cover and nestled between mountains, had been cut. Helicopters were being used to make drops and pick-ups, they said.</p>
<p>Officials said Indonesian diplomats in Kota Kinabalu were arranging a mass burial in the state for their dead nationals, who were mostly Christians.</p>
<p>Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad offered his condolences to families of the victims, saying the Sabah government and federal agencies have been directed to provide assistance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KOTA KINABALU, Malaysia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
