<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278540" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Gun-toting British royals in trouble.</title>
<headline>Gun-toting British royals in trouble.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prince Charles was condemned by safety experts and the British media on Friday after he was spotted playing around with his son Harry while the 12-year-old was holding a shotgun.</p>
<p>The photograph of a smiling Charles lunging at Harry while on a Christmas expedition to shoot pheasants was plastered across the front pages of tabloid newspapers.</p>
<p>&quot;Have You Gun Mad?&quot; said the Daily Mirror. &quot;Is This Any Way To Act With A Gun?&quot; asked the Daily Mail.</p>
<p>The incident was the second time in a week the royal family has been attacked for their attitude to guns in a country still mourning 16 children and a teacher murdered at their school in Dunblane, Scotland, last March.</p>
<p>Last week Queen Elizabeth's husband, Philip, was roundly condemned for implying, while discussing the Dunblane tragedy, that guns were no more dangerous than cricket bats.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the British Safety Council said Charles was &quot;absolutely stupid&quot; to try and clip his son round the ear when he was holding a gun surrounded by other people.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen through the years that the royal family have been negligent over safety. Indulging in horseplay while carrying guns is unbelievable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The incident happened during a shoot at the royal estate at Sandringham in eastern England where the family traditionally hold their Christmas celebrations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
