<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278734" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea oil firms unaffected by labour unrest.</title>
<headline>S.Korea oil firms unaffected by labour unrest.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean oil refiners have been unaffected by the spread of union strikes in protest at a new labour law, industry officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>They said because of the industry's strategic importance to the nation's economy, it has avoided industrial strife in the past and strikes would be unlikely during this round of stoppages.</p>
<p>&quot;The oil industry is too strategically important to the nation,&quot; said one official at Yukong Ltd, South Korea's largest oil refiner. &quot;A strike would mean no production and that would deal a big blow to all industries.&quot;</p>
<p>Industry officials said considering the impact on the national economy no labour union at an oil firm could easily decide to throw down their tools.</p>
<p>&quot;Workers themselves are not considering such an action because they know how important our industry is to the country's well-being,&quot; said the Yukong official.</p>
<p>Moreover, favourable working conditions at the refiners compared with other work places would make them more difficult to head for a strike, industry officials said.  </p>
<p>&quot;People working at South Korean refiners are generally happy with the working conditions offered, which includes flexible working hours, better pay and benefits,&quot; said a labour relations manager at a local oil company.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no movement towards striking. Things are pretty quiet so far.&quot;</p>
<p>Labour strikes were spreading on Friday from important export industries such as automaking and shipbuilding to service sectors such as hospitals and subways.</p>
<p>Unions are protesting the passage of a law which gives employers the right to lay off surplus worker, introduce flexible working hours and replace striking workers.</p>
<p>-- Seoul Newsroom (822) 727 5643</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
