<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278762" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila likely to import 200,000T rice in Q1 1997.</title>
<headline>Manila likely to import 200,000T rice in Q1 1997.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippines is likely to import between 150,000 and 200,000 tonnes of rice in the first quarter of 1997, a senior Department of Agriculture official said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;There are indications that we may import as early as the first quarter but we are witholding orders until we see our production surveys for the first half,&quot; the official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, told Reuters.  </p>
<p>The result of a survey on the likely rice output in the first half of 1997 is scheduled to be released in the middle of January, he said.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Philippine Agriculture Secretary Salvador Escudero said he expected the country to import between 300,000 and 500,000 tonnes of rice next year as demand is seen outpacing production.</p>
<p>&quot;Importations should start before the rainy months of May, June, July and August. We should have learned our lesson from last year's experience,&quot; the official in the department said.</p>
<p>The official said Thailand and India have offered to supply some of the Philippines' rice requirement. &quot;We are also looking at Vietnam, but nothing is definite yet. We are just shopping for likely sources,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Shortages in rice and corn during the third quarter of 1995 sent inflation to a year-high of 11 percent in September</p>
<p>&quot;Because of last year's experience, President Fidel Ramos has ordered the National Food Authority (NFA) to see to it that rice inventories all over the country should at least be at 1.9 million tonnes, which is good for 90 days, starting on July 1,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>The state-agency said total rice inventory at NFA, commercial and household warehouses as of December 15 reached 1.7 million tonnes, which is 30 percent more than stocks at the same time last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The stocks are good for 79 days,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>The NFA also has 2.1 million 50-kg bags of unmilled rice in its warehouses. &quot;When milled, the palay (unmilled rice) yields 65 percent of rice grains,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>--Manila newsroom (632) 841-89-36, fax 817-62-67</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
