<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="278855" id="root" date="1996-12-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - Dec 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - Dec 27.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-12-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights of stories in the Danish press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>BERLINGSKE TIDENDE</p>
<p>--Following the departure from government of Centre Democrat trade minister Mimi Jakobsen and health minister Yvonne Andersen, Prime Minister Poul Nyrup Rasmussen is expected to announce his new cabinet next Monday and is seen using the opportunity to take responsibility for food matters from the health and trade ministries and give it to an expanded agriculture fisheries and food ministry.</p>
<p>--A Dane says he has found a way to prevent CD piracy by electronically reading the 'fingerprint' left on legitimate copies by the CD master. A local publisher and Italy's D'Agostini are using the technology and US giant Microsoft has sent engineers to Denmark to examine the process.</p>
<p>--The building industry expects a seven percent rise in residential construction in 1997 and mortgage lender Realkredit Denmark expects a 10 percent increase in commercial property starts.</p>
<p>POLITIKEN</p>
<p>--Realkredit Denmark's new 'flex-loan' products offer significant savings over other types of retail borrowing and pose a real threat to bank lending to private customers.</p>
<p>JYLLANDS POSTEN</p>
<p>--Rasmussen will present his new cabinet by new year.</p>
<p>--Danes are the world's heaviest users of plastic cards for shopping, the Dankort debit card now has 2.8 million users, logging 300 million transactions annually, each of an average 300 crowns ($50).</p>
<p>BORSEN</p>
<p>--Developmental Aid Minister Poul Nielson is likely to replace Mimi Jakobsen as trade and industry minister.</p>
<p>--U.S. telecoms authorities are pressing European firms to go over to cost-plus based tariffs, threatening Tele Danmark's earnings, among others.</p>
<p>DET FRI AKTUELT</p>
<p>---A new survey shows that 500,000 Danes are considering changing their bank.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
