<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="279051" id="root" date="1996-12-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peruvian rebels defy pressure to free hostages.</title>
<headline>Peruvian rebels defy pressure to free hostages.</headline>
<byline>Paul Hughes</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-12-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marxist guerrillas holding 103 VIP captives at the Japanese embassy residence in Peru defied growing international pressure to release their captives on Saturday as the crisis moved into its 11th day.</p>
<p>As security measures were tightened in Lima, eight of the world's strongest nations offered their full backing to President Alberto Fujimori and promised to help Peru end the siege with &quot;all the appropriate means that it could request.&quot;</p>
<p>But Japan, which initiated the joint statement, stressed on Saturday that the crisis must be ended without loss of life.</p>
<p>&quot;There is little advantage in reaching a compromise with terrorists, but a peaceful solution has become the key word in terms of preserving the lives of the captives,&quot; Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto told reporters during his regular daily call at a crisis room in the Foreign Ministry.</p>
<p>The strongly-worded communique issued by the Group of Seven (G7) industrialised nations and Russia in Paris on Friday brought no official response from Peru.</p>
<p>Fujimori, who has spoken only once in public since the crisis broke when gunmen stormed an exclusive reception at the residence Dec. 17, has so far brushed aside outside offers of help with the crisis.</p>
<p>The Peruvian leader has adopted a firm line of not negotiating directly with the rebels and has flatly rejected their demands.</p>
<p>But the roughly 20 heavily armed Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) guerrillas holed up inside the Japanese ambassador's home showed no signs of buckling under the pressure.</p>
<p>No hostages were released on Friday, for the first day since Monday, despite reports that three hostages -- including Supreme Court President Moises Pantoja -- were seriously ill.</p>
<p>The rebels have booby-trapped the residence against possible attack and said they would not come out until the government pardoned about 400 jailed comrades.</p>
<p>Armed rebels, including one woman guerrilla, appeared several times at windows and a Peruvian flag bearing the image of the Indian warrior after which their movement is named hung defiantly at another.</p>
<p>Outside the property in the fashionable district of San Isidro, police arrested three suspects they said had posed as street vendors to gather information for the MRTA.</p>
<p>The three, who were detained under tighter security measures announced on Friday, brought to six the number of people arrested outside the residence on suspicion of being linked to the guerrillas.</p>
<p>The government was given even furher room to manoeuvre on Friday when a special session of congress called by Fujimori voted overwhelmingly to give &quot;full support to the government and (whatever) decisions it takes to solve this grave crisis.&quot;</p>
<p>Fujimori's tough line against the rebels -- who still hold his brother Pedro Fujimori, two government ministers, Japanese businessmen and a handful of foreign diplomats -- has won broad support at home.</p>
<p>But the backing of the international community was an important triumph for the Peruvian leader after initial criticism of his handling of the crisis. Japan, whose nationals account for the largest number of hostages, after Peru, said last week there were sharp differences between Tokyo and Fujimori who is known for his hawkish stance against guerrillas.</p>
<p>Rumours that the Peruvian leader was still considering a military solution to end the standoff were fuelled on Friday by reports from Peruvian intelligence sources who told Reuters that a U.S. spyplane had made high-altitude night flights over the residence. Crack anti-terrorist units of the Peruvian police were training around a model of the building, the sources added.</p>
<p>The guerrillas have released about 400 captives since storming the building and kept those they consider most useful as bargaining chips.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
