<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="279070" id="root" date="1996-12-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Cup of tea keeps skin cancer at bay - research.</title>
<headline>Cup of tea keeps skin cancer at bay - research.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-12-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A cup of tea could become the next weapon in Australia's high-profile fight against skin cancer, according to government scientists who said on Saturday the humble &quot;cuppa&quot; halved rates of the disease in mice.</p>
<p>In a study by the Commonwealth Scientific and Industrial Research Organisation (CSIRO), laboratory mice fed black tea fared much better than mice fed water or even green tea when they were exposed to damaging ultraviolet rays, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The mice drinking black tea had quite fewer cancers or skin lesions,&quot; CSIRO research scientist Ian Record told Reuters.</p>
<p>Mice made to sip black tea suffered 54 percent fewer cancers than those that drank water and significantly fewer than mice that drank green tea, according to the research findings.</p>
<p>Overseas studies have shown tea can be effective against some forms of cancer and may even prevent heart and liver disease, but the Australian study is among the first to show the efficacy of black tea as drunk in the West compared with green tea drunk in Asian countries, such as Japan and China.</p>
<p>&quot;Previously, green tea has been thought to be the best, so we're now moving into the black tea we normally drink -- the Anglo-Saxon beverage -- and we're hoping to show that black tea can reduce the incidence of some of these cancers in humans,&quot; Record said.</p>
<p>Earlier studies on black tea in the United States have shown black tea can be effective against skin cancer in mice, but the CSIRO study is the first to use a &quot;normal&quot; range of ultraviolet radiation to mimic outdoor exposures from the sun, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Australia is the skin cancer capital of the world and we're hoping that these sorts of treatments and dietary advice can help prevent skin cancer,&quot; Record said from his home in Adelaide.</p>
<p>&quot;One in two Australians will get a skin cancer at some stage in their life.&quot;</p>
<p>Properties in green and black tea called antioxidants are thought to be the active agents against skin cancer, but more research was needed to determine how they combat skin cancer, he said.</p>
<p>Adding milk and sugar does not seem to affect the level of antioxidants in a cup of tea, co-researcher Ivor Dreosti said.</p>
<p>The CSIRO plans to set up a human trial early in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;It's early days in terms of making firm recommendations to people, but it's encouraging enough that we will certainly go on with the studies,&quot; Dreosti told local media.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
