<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="279289" id="root" date="1996-12-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-JAGUARS UPSET BILLS, COWBOYS ROMP PAST VIKINGS.</title>
<headline>NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-JAGUARS UPSET BILLS, COWBOYS ROMP PAST VIKINGS.</headline>
<dateline>ORCHARD PARK, New York 1996-12-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The precocious Jacksonville Jaguars upset the Buffalo Bills 30-27 and the defending champion Dallas Cowboys romped past the Minnesota Vikings 40-15 on the opening day of NFL playoffs Saturday.</p>
<p>Natrone Means rushed for 175 yards and Mike Hollis kicked three field goals, including a 45-yard game-winner with 3:07 remaining, as the second-year Jaguars triumphed in their first-ever playoff appearance and dealt the Bills their first loss in 10 playoff games at Rich Stadium.</p>
<p>&quot;It feels great,&quot; said Means, who had 31 carries. &quot;The offensive line did a great job all day long. Once we settled down, we played our type of ball.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Natrone was a huge force today,&quot; said Jaguars coach Tom Coughlin.</p>
<p>Hollis's game-winner bounced off the right pole but still went through as Jacksonville (10-7) beat Buffalo (10-7) in an AFC wild-card game, the first meeting between the two teams.</p>
<p>Jacksonville will play either Denver (13-3) or New England (11-5) in the second round of the AFC playoffs next weekend.</p>
<p>It appeared the Bills, in their eighth playoff appearance in nine years, were headed to victory when Jeff Burris picked off a tipped pass and returned it 38 yards for a touchdown 43 seconds into the fourth quarter to snap a 20-20 tie.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment it made an impact but they came back and did what they had to do,&quot; said Burris.</p>
<p>The Jaguars produced a 10-play, 65-yard drive capped by a two-yard touchdown pass from Mark Brunell, who completed 18-of-33 passes for 239 yards with two interceptions, to Jimmy Smith. That tied the game at 27-27 with 8:40 remaining.</p>
<p>&quot;Give Jacksonville credit,&quot; said Buffalo coach Marv Levy. &quot;They were down by seven in the fourth quarter and went the length of the field for a TD and then got the field goal.&quot;</p>
<p>On Buffalo's next possession, quarterback Jim Kelly fumbled after being hit by safety Chris Hudson. The ball was recovered by cornerback Aaron Beasley at the Jacksonville 41-yard line. Kelly was knocked out of the game on the play.</p>
<p>The Jaguars then drove 31 yards in eight plays to set up Hollis's winning field goal.</p>
<p>Todd Collins replaced Kelly on Buffalo's final two possessions. Tony Brackens sacked Collins and forced a fumble and linebacker Eddie Robinson recovered the ball deep in Buffalo territory with 11 seconds left to seal the win.</p>
<p>Kelly completed 21-of-32 passes for 239 yards with an interception. Collins was 1-of-4 for seven yards.</p>
<p>In the key matchup of the game, second-year left tackle Tony Boselli held Bills perennial All-Pro defensive end Bruce Smith without a sack. Smith led the AFC with 13 1/2 sacks in 1996 while Boselli, the second overall pick in the 1995 draft, allowed just one sack this season.</p>
<p>&quot;Bruce Smith is a great player. I knew I didn't have to play perfect, I just had to play hard,&quot; said Boselli. &quot;I thank God for giving me that confidence and the ability to do it. The only thing I was worried about was keeping my poise.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;He did a pretty good job,&quot; said Smith. &quot;I think they had a very good blocking scheme. It wasn't like he was one-on-one all day. I give him credit.&quot;</p>
<p>In Irving, Texas, George Teague forced two fumbles -- one of which prevented a touchdown -- and returned an interception 29 yards for a score as the Cowboys embarrassed the Vikings in an NFC wild-card game.</p>
<p>Troy Aikman, Emmitt Smith, Michael Irvin and Deion Sanders all had big games for the Cowboys (11-6), who despite winning a fifth straight NFC East Division title were relegated to the wild-card round for the first time since 1991.</p>
<p>The Cowboys next will face the Carolina Panthers, the NFC West champions but a second-year team that will be playing the first post-season game in franchise history. Dallas has reached the NFC Championship four straight years, winning the Super Bowl three times during that span.</p>
<p>With quarterback Brad Johnson making his first playoff start, the Vikings never got untracked. They committed four turnovers and allowed 268 yards in the first half, falling behind 30-0.</p>
<p>Minnesota (9-8) lost its playoff opener for the fourth time in four appearances under coach Dennis Green. The Vikings have lost seven straight post-season games since 1988.</p>
<p>Smith ran for 116 yards on 17 carries and had four recpetions for 26 yards. &quot;This is the best I have felt all year,&quot; said Smith, who sat out last week's game against the Redskins. &quot;I had a lot of spring in my legs.&quot;</p>
<p>Aikman scored on a 2-yard run and went 19-for-29 passing for 178 yards with one interception before yielding to Jason Garrett after the game was in hand. Irvin had eight catches for 103 yards. Sanders had a fumble recovery and an interception.</p>
<p>But the key play came when Teague punched the ball out of Amp Lee's arms as he was about to score a game-tying touchdown.</p>
<p>&quot;I have never felt this way in the NFL,&quot; said Teague. &quot;Stripping the ball was the only way to stop Lee from scoring. I took a chance. If I tackle him he falls over the goal line.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It changed the game when they stripped the ball from Amp Lee,&quot; said Minnesota coach Dennis Green. &quot;That would have tied it and we could have played with them all game. You can't give Dallas four turnovers in 30 minutes and hope to win.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, I'm worried about my job, shouldn't I be?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, I guess you could say we turned it up at crunch time,&quot; said Dallas coach Barry Switzer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ORCHARD PARK, New York"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
