<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="279382" id="root" date="1996-12-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania doubles fuel prices ahead of visit by IMF.</title>
<headline>Romania doubles fuel prices ahead of visit by IMF.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-12-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's government said on Sunday it would double fuel prices in the New Year to help cover losses caused by the depreciating leu currency and to meet International Monetary Fund recommendations for the economy.</p>
<p>An official statement said that from Wednesday petrol would rise to 1,900 lei (46 cents) per litre of premium, up from 990, and 1,300 lei (31 cents) per litre of diesel, up from 680.</p>
<p>The increases were in line with suggestions made by the IMF, which suspended a $460 million accord on the grounds that Romania's former leftist government, had failed to meet targets agreed with the Fund. The leftists lost power in a general election last month.</p>
<p>Bringing fuel prices gradually up to world levels was part of the package agreed with the IMF for this year.</p>
<p>Romania annually produces around 6.7 million tonnes of crude oil but needs to import about double that amount -- a huge financial burden for the cash-strapped ex-communist country -- to meet demand and keep its big refining sector running.</p>
<p>The leu has fallen steadily in value over the past year. Its reference rate was 3,030 to the dollar in July, when energy prices were last increased. It now stands at 4,035 to the dollar after being 2,580 in January.</p>
<p>An IMF mission is expected to arrive in Bucharest next month to discuss a new loan accord with the reformist government headed by Prime Minister Victor Ciorbea.</p>
<p>The government statement said the increase of fuel prices was expected to solve many problems of Romania's economy and to &quot;offer a favourable basis for future talks with the IMF&quot;.</p>
<p>July's fuel price increase triggered a blip in inflation.</p>
<p>The government would take steps to compensate the population for the new energy prices, the official statement said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
