<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="279485" id="root" date="1996-12-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: YEARENDER-Asian bonds, a free lunch for investors?.</title>
<headline>YEARENDER-Asian bonds, a free lunch for investors?.</headline>
<byline>Christopher Pizzey</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian bonds are so attractive nowadays that they should continue to draw in funds from around the world for the next few years, analysts say.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the financial equivalent of a free lunch,&quot; Greg Batey, head of market research at Peregrine Fixed Income Ltd, told a recent conference in Singapore.</p>
<p>Fund managers agree that the market provides investors with big potential profits.</p>
<p>&quot;The Asian bond market is at the threshold of being discovered by both international and regional investors. It represents a great opportunity,&quot; Julia Ho, assistant director at Rothschild Asset Management (Singapore), told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Asian debt markets only make up a small part of the world bond market. Deutsche Morgan Grenfell (DMG) in Singapore estimates the Asian share to be some two percent.</p>
<p>Until now, many governments have had no real need to issue bonds since they were running fiscal surpluses. Singapore is a prime example -- a country of some three million people, it has amassed foreign exchange reserves of over US$60 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Yet despite the infancy of the markets, the rate of growth has comfortably outpaced nominal gross domestic product growth over the last six years,&quot; DMG said in a recent report.</p>
<p>The report also noted that growth was set to accelerate because of increasing long-term capital requirements of the rapidly industrialising Asian nations.</p>
<p>The World Bank has estimated that -- driven in part by the need to fund massive infrastructure projects in the region -- the size of Asia's bond markets could triple to some US$1.5 trillion by early the next century.</p>
<p>&quot;Consequently, the development of local currency debt markets is now a common goal for most governments in Asia,&quot; the DMG report said.</p>
<p>POSITIVE OUTLOOK</p>
<p>One thing that makes Asian bond markets attractive is the fact that Asian borrowers, both corporate and sovereign, are improving credits and risk remains low, Rothchild's Ho said.</p>
<p>&quot;You have a very high reward/risk ratio... your risk is not as high as it is perceived to be, mainly because they (the borrowers) are too conservatively rated,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She noted Malaysia, Hong Kong, China, Indonesia and India all had positive outlooks from Standard and Poor's Corp and Moody's Investors Service Inc.</p>
<p>Rothschild Asset Management has just launched The Five Arrows Asian Bond Trust which will invest exclusively within Asian debt markets, Ho said.</p>
<p>She noted that even at the shorter end of the maturity spectrum there were big gains to be made. Indonesian three month commercial paper offers potential returns of some 15 to 20 percent per annum.</p>
<p>For investors unwilling to take on too much currency risk, simple hedging facilities are abundant.</p>
<p>The DMG report also looked at the shorter, three month, end of the curve. &quot;A comparison of returns in the money markets since 1990 shows that returns comfortably outperform U.S. investments in all regional markets,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The highest cumulative U.S. dollar return since 1990 would have been achieved in the Philippines (143 percent) and Indonesia (106 percent), DMG's calculations showed. An investment in the U.S. market would have yielded 42 percent.</p>
<p>UNDER-DEVELOPED SECONDARY MARKET</p>
<p>The arguments are sound and the figures look great, so what are the drawbacks that should be pointed out to potential investors? One that most analysts mention is liquidity.</p>
<p>Because bond issuance is still relatively slow, there is an under-developed secondary market.</p>
<p>In many Asian countries bonds are snapped up at launch by large investors, often state-run pension funds such as the Employees Provident Fund in Malaysia. These investors lock the bonds up until maturity.</p>
<p>This lack of liquidity can lead to wide dealing spreads, or worse-still, &quot;offer-only&quot; quotes.</p>
<p>However, Rothschild's Ho said that the higher yields paid in the Asian bond market was one compensating factor for lack of liquidity.</p>
<p>&quot;The liquidity problem is one that will be corrected over time,&quot; she said. &quot;As the size of the market grows, you're going to see more liquidity.&quot;</p>
<p>Another problem concerning the issue of new bonds is that many countries lack a meaningful benchmark yield curve -- an important factor in setting a new issue price. If a government has no need to issue bonds, the yield curve is missing.</p>
<p>&quot;Benchmarks have long been identified as an important missing element in Asia,&quot; Peregrine's Batey said. &quot;The (foreign exchange) swap yield curve is clearly becoming the benchmark.&quot;</p>
<p>Some countries are addressing this problem. Hong Kong, for example, has issued more government bonds down the maturity curve -- as far as 10 years -- in a systematic effort to help create a benchmark yield curve.</p>
<p>Also, Malaysia announced in October that in 1997 it would start issuing zero coupon bonds in small amounts with maturities ranging from one to 10 years. The government said it was issuing the bonds to help provide a meaningful benchmark yield curve.</p>
<p>Despite these problems, analysts still contend that Asia's bond markets are worth investing in.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors anywhere should find these markets attractive,&quot; Batey said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
