<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="279428" id="root" date="1996-12-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Four dead, one missing in NZ harbour collision.</title>
<headline>Four dead, one missing in NZ harbour collision.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four people were killed and one was missing after a fishing boat and a container ship collided during the night near the entrance to Wellington Harbour, New Zealand officials said on Monday.</p>
<p>The accident overshadowed the arrival of the first yachts in a round-the-world race, which were expected to reach New Zealand's capital later in the day.</p>
<p>The Maritime Safety Authority said it was opening an investigation into the collision, which occurred in calm conditions at around 10:40 p.m. (0940 GMT) on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;The first step is to establish the cause of the accident. We'll attempt to do that by talking with all those involved and any witnesses,&quot; MSA deputy director Tony Martin said.</p>
<p>The New Zealand-owned container ship, the 7,000-tonne Sydney Express, with an all-New Zealand crew of 15, was heading out of the harbour and the fishing boat with six men on board was on its way in, he said.</p>
<p>Police said the four dead men were believed to have been trapped in the upturned hull of the fishing boat. Their bodies had been recovered by divers.</p>
<p>One person from the fishing boat was winched to safety, and the remaining crewman was still missing.</p>
<p>The Sydney Express is registered in the Isle of Man, a self-governing crown dependency off Britain's west coast, and is owned by the Auckland-based Tasman Express Line Ltd.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the BT Global Challenge yacht race said he did not expect the accident to affect the welcome for the leading yachts, which have been sailing for 40 days from Rio de Janeiro on the second leg of their round-the-world voyage.</p>
<p>Organisers bill the Global Challenge as the world's toughest yacht race because the 14 boats are sailing &quot;the wrong way&quot; around the world, against prevailing winds and currents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
