<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="279593" id="root" date="1996-12-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Algerian rebels kill 28 in village - security forces.</title>
<headline>Algerian rebels kill 28 in village - security forces.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Moslem fundamentalists killed 28 people in an attack in the early hours of Sunday in the village of Dhamnia in Ain Defla province, some 120 km (75 miles) southwest of Algiers, security forces said.</p>
<p>The overnight raid was the fifth such mass killing this month in which the authorities say a total of 82 people have died, many with their throats slit.</p>
<p>The security forces said in a statement on the official Algerian news agency APS that the 28 were killed by a &quot;group of terrorists&quot;, Algeria's official term for Moslem fundamentalists.</p>
<p>They gave no other details.</p>
<p>News of the killing coincided with that of a bomb attack early on Sunday in the Algerian capital where hospital sources and witnesses said 53 people had been wounded. The official toll by the security forces was 20 wounded.</p>
<p>Thousands of people have fled isolated villages to take refuge with relatives in bigger towns and cities since their communities became targets of mass killings in darkness in November.</p>
<p>Early that month 31 people were slaughtered in Sidi El Kebir near the garrison town of Blida, 50 km (30 miles) south of Algiers. All had their throats cut and many were mutilated.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm leaving Sidi El Kebir for anywhere, provided there is more mercy there,&quot; said one boy as villagers prepared to bury their friends and relatives.</p>
<p>Three nights earlier, 10 women and three children were killed in a similar night of bloodshed, which Interior Minister Mustapha Ben Mansour called &quot;ignoble savagery&quot;.</p>
<p>Shortly afterwards, Algerian newspapers reported hundreds of people leaving scattered communities, with some people sleeping in the streets of Blida, headquarters of Algeria's No. One military region.</p>
<p>One newspaper, Liberte, called November the &quot;month of all horrors&quot;. The killings continued.</p>
<p>Ten people died on an isolated farm near Blida on December 5. A further 19 were found dead the following day in a nearby village.</p>
<p>Twenty more were killed in mid-December, dragged from a bus stopped at a fake roadblock in Blida province.</p>
<p>On December 24, Algerian security forces said &quot;a group of terrorists&quot; had killed six civilians overnight in the Algiers suburb of Baraki.</p>
<p>The bombings too have continued, refocusing violence on the overcrowded capital and defying the authorities' claims to have wiped out most of those responsible, leaving only &quot;residual terrorism&quot;.</p>
<p>A bomb exploded on Sunday inside a cafe in the working class suburb of el Harrach, in the southern edge of Algiers, wounding 53 people, hospital sources said.</p>
<p>It was the fourth blast within one week in which 18 people were reported to have been killed and 210 wounded in Algiers.</p>
<p>About 60,000 people have been killed since violence erupted in the North African country after the authorities in January 1992 cancelled a general election in which the Moslem fundamentalist Islamic Salvation Front (FIS) had taken an overwhelming first-round lead.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
