<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="279596" id="root" date="1996-12-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Wealthy Germans dash for expiring east tax break.</title>
<headline>Wealthy Germans dash for expiring east tax break.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>With generous tax inducements for property investors in eastern Germany expiring at midnight on Tuesday, wealthy westerners are racing the clock to buy even though thousands have already been burned by dubious deals.</p>
<p>Lured by an immediate 50-percent tax write-off that will disappear at the stroke of midnight on December 31, high-income Germans have for years been handing over small fortunes for &quot;can't-miss&quot; investments in office buildings, apartment blocks, hotels and property funds in the east.</p>
<p>&quot;In Germany, the instinct to save taxes is stronger than the instinct to reproduce,&quot; according to Bavarian Finance Minister Ervin Huber.</p>
<p>Motivated by the desire to save taxes, investors often signed up without having seen the property and only later discovered that their money went on buildings that offered almost no chance of financial success.</p>
<p>Some new projects were often built with lofty projections on rental income that have fallen far short of expectations. Office space in Dresden has slumped from 60 marks ($40) per square metre three years ago to 30 marks ($20).</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly a lot of construction in eastern Germany was done without the slightest regard for demand,&quot; said Hartwig Hamm, director of the Landesbausparkassen (LBS) building society.</p>
<p>&quot;Thousands of projects are the result of an extreme obsession to save taxes rather than meet demand,&quot; he added. &quot;There is doubtlessly going to be panic buying in the final hours of the year.&quot;</p>
<p>Newspapers are filled with advertisements for property in the east, promising with the time-honoured &quot;last-minute&quot; sales pitch that would-be investors can save taxes without risk.</p>
<p>&quot;Invest in a sensible tax-savings scheme,&quot; read a recent ad in a national daily for a 10-family apartment house in Leipzig.</p>
<p>&quot;Save 4.8 million marks ($3 million) in taxes&quot; claimed another for two multi-unit apartment buildings outside Berlin.</p>
<p>&quot;Grab it now before the finance ministry grabs you!&quot; said another more direct listing for apartment buildings in Dresden.</p>
<p>The immediate 50-percent tax break on property investments in the east was introduced shortly after German unity in 1990 as a way to stimulate investment in the former East Germany, where the condition of housing had deteriorated badly during the 40-year communist reign.</p>
<p>As intended, the tax incentive spurred a building boom in the east. But the tax break, which many industry experts say was left in place too long, had an unintended side effect: too much building done blindly without regard to the needs.</p>
<p>Many of the office buildings, hotels and luxury apartment blocks now stand empty or half-empty because supply outstripped demand. Yet in many eastern cities there is still a shortage of low-cost housing.</p>
<p>The billions of marks pumped into eastern investment projects and funds pushed the prices to unsustainable levels. Blinded by the &quot;too-good-to-be-true&quot; temptation to cut tax and invest in property at the same time, many investors signed up without a clue to what they were buying.</p>
<p>In Leizpig, one out of three office buildings is unoccupied and in Berlin rents for offices have fallen from an average of 67 marks ($43.10) per square metre to 45 marks ($28.95) in the last three years because of overcapacity.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was dramatically influenced by the tax write-off,&quot; said Sascha Hettrich, a director at Jones Lang Wootton property managers in Berlin.</p>
<p>&quot;It led private investors to make decisions that under rational circumstances would not have been made.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
