<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="279587" id="root" date="1996-12-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Dehaene admits clumsy in Belgian child sex scandal.</title>
<headline>Dehaene admits clumsy in Belgian child sex scandal.</headline>
<byline>Janet McEvoy</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene said on Sunday he reacted clumsily to a child murder and sex scandal which erupted in August shaking the nation.</p>
<p>He told the VTM television station there was a turning point in Belgium two months later when 250,000 people took to the streets of Brussels for a peaceful &quot;White March&quot; to protest at what they said was an inefficient political and legal system.</p>
<p>&quot;I reacted awkwardly. The turning point was the white march,&quot; he told the commercial television station.</p>
<p>&quot;The forces of the white march should be used to make things better in 1997,&quot; he said, vowing to continue with reforms he promised at the time to the parents of children who died or are still missing in the paedophile scandal.</p>
<p>&quot;1996 was a turning point for Belgium,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dehaene said it would have been wrong to call elections at the time of the uproar over bungling surrounding the investigation into convicted paedophile rapist Marc Dutroux as it would have inflamed the situation.</p>
<p>On Sunday Belgian police braved the freezing cold and snow in a fruitless search of a disused coal-mine complex in the southern town of Jumet for clues in the investigation.</p>
<p>Hopeful at the start of the day of a breakthrough on their 14th day of searching the mine, they ended up disappointed.</p>
<p>The team broke through a suspicious bricked-over entrance to find it revealed only earth, gendermerie spokesman Guy Soumoy told reporters.</p>
<p>The police, visibly disappointed, had hoped the entrance, discovered on Saturday, would lead to a hideaway used by Dutroux to hold children kidnapped for a paedophile network.</p>
<p>In August police rescued two sexually-abused young women from a makeshift dungeon in a house owned by Dutroux and later unearthed the bodies of four more. Dutroux and four others are still in jail.</p>
<p>Two months later more than 250,000 people marched through Brussels in a demonstration both of support for the victims and their families.</p>
<p>Dehaene vowed on Sunday to push on in 1997 with reforms he had promised at the time of the march in a bid to restore public confidence in the Belgian establishment.</p>
<p>Dehaene also praised Deputy Prime Minister Elio Di Rupo for &quot;combativeness&quot; and for carrying on with his duties while facing allegations of having had sex with boys under the legal age of consent of 16. Di Rupo was recently cleared by parliament of the allegations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
