<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="279840" id="root" date="1996-12-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee reverses to close narrowly mixed.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee reverses to close narrowly mixed.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee ended narrowly mixed on Monday, after persistent selling by both speculators and producing countries wiped out the market's early gains, trading sources said.</p>
<p>Prices rallied early in the session, as commodity funds, encouraged by Friday's strong technical finish, continued to bid the market higher.</p>
<p>But buying interest faltered as nearby March approached the previous day's high of 117.50 cents, and pressure from the origin sector increased. Mexico and several Central American countries were steady sellers, traders said, while top growers Brazil and Colombia were largely quiet.</p>
<p>Traders also cited figures released at midday data showing a sharp rise in open positions as of last Friday. Open interest rose 2,035 lots through last Friday, to 30,415, with the March contract posting the bulk of the increase.</p>
<p>&quot;The market tried to go up, but we found some selling around 117.50,&quot; one trader said. &quot;The open interest was a negative factor.&quot;</p>
<p>Most-active March fell 0.25 cent per lb, to 115.95, having traded from 115.10 to 117.45. Second-position May inched up 0.10 cent, to 113.65, as the nearby switched narrowed to 2.30 cents from 2.65.</p>
<p>Having closed above 115 cents for two straight days, the market's technical outlook remained solid, dealers said. But March would need to hold above last Friday's low 113.20 cents to sustain its momentum. Overhead, March faced strong resistance toward 119-120 cents.</p>
<p>On the fundamental side, new developments have been scarce, but traders said tonight's weekly certified stock report could provide some direction.</p>
<p>Volume on Monday reached an estimated 6,642 lots.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, December 31, the CSCE will hold an abbreviated session before New Year's Eve. Trading on the &quot;C&quot; contract will close at 1135 EST/1635 GMT.</p>
<p>The CSCE will be closed on Wednesday, January 1, in observance of New Year's Day.</p>
<p>((-- W Pollack, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
