<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28024" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-OPINION-Louthean on Australian Mining: Hopes for diamonds.</title>
<headline>RTRS-OPINION-Louthean on Australian Mining: Hopes for diamonds.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Ross Louthean*</p>
<p>Diamond explorers are crossing their fingers that an ambitious quest by Damin Resources NL has picked up a target that may provide Australia with a new diamond discovery.</p>
<p>The remote prospect, named Mad Gap Yards, 150 km south of the Argyle diamond mine on the Kimberley Plateau of Western Australia, is the focal point.</p>
<p>The company drilled into a blind target in the hope of picking up signs of a kimberlite pipe.</p>
<p>Earlier drilling had proved negative. But in the waning days of August, exploration manager John Towie re-directed the drill and hit a bullseye that has shown the right indicators for a kimberlite -- the prime source of emplaced diamonds.</p>
<p>Damin said steam sediment sampling at Mad Gap Yards had discovered kimberlite indicator minerals though follow-up drilling had failed to find the source.</p>
<p>Studies have since showed drilling was incorrectly sited through confusion over the location of stream samples and inadequacies in aeromagnetic data of that time.</p>
<p>A bullseye feature was picked up with a new aeromagnetic survey in June 1996 and the first of a planned 50 hole reverse circulation and diamond drilling programme showed the presence of kimberlite at a depth of 80 metres.</p>
<p>Executive director Peter Streader said Diamin now proposes to drill step out holes over a spacing of 100 metres in all four directions of the first hole. Sampling results from a Perth laboratory would be released &quot;shortly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>NOT NECESSARILY PAYDIRT</p>
<p>While in diamond terms this is not necessarily paydirt -- for almost all kimberlite pipes fail to show up commercial grades of diamonds -- it is a feather in the cap of Diamin, which has become one of the pennydreadful stocks of the listed Australian diamond seekers.</p>
<p>It is also a plaudit of John Towie, the geologist whose father had run the company under its earlier name -- Triad Minerals.</p>
<p>Earlier this decade Towie had unearthed the Aries pipe in the Kimberleys as a kimberlite target and the company went to large-scale commercial bulk testing.</p>
<p>But the testing ended up somewhere between negative and inconclusive and the cash-limited company moved on.</p>
<p>The market, rather than recognising the company as having demonstrated a skill in the difficult task of finding good targets was unforgiving.</p>
<p>Towie is one of the specialist diamond prospectors in Australia, as are others in his clan.</p>
<p>His father, Rees Towie, was in on the ground floor of the famous Kalumburu Joint Venture through Northern Mining Corp, which pioneered diamond exploration in Western Australia, finding Ellendale and then Argyle.</p>
<p>Through playing corporate cards with Alan Bond, Rees Towie lost the company, which then became the catalyst for the West Australian Diamond Trust, an entity still in the Argyle structure, though now owned by the existing partners RTZ Corp Plc-CRA Ltd and Ashton Mining Ltd</p>
<p>One of the geologists to carve a name out of the Ellendale and Argyle discoveries was Maureen Muggeridge who was in the field teams that made both finds.</p>
<p>Muggeridge, niece of famous British media commentator, the late Malcolm Muggeridge, is married to John Towie and is a director of Moonstone Diamond Corp NL which listed in the early 1990s diamond boom and, while still prospecting in the Kimberleys, is now poised to mine diamonds in South Africa.</p>
<p>Australian diamond exploration certainly needs a spark, and the best means of momentum could come from a minnow-sized company.</p>
<p>There are other good projects, including the Ashton Mining-managed Merlin project in the Northern Territory, Striker Resouces NL's Upper Beta Creek project in the Kimberleys and Diamond Ventures NL-Clough Pacific Resources' Bingara project in New South Wales.</p>
<p>* Ross Louthean is editor of Paydirt magazine, publisher of Gold Mining Journal and The Australian Mines Handbook and convenor of Paydirt's Diamond Conference.</p>
<p>Qualification: A member of Ross Louthean's family holds shares in Diamin.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
