<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="280293" id="root" date="1996-12-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Official probe dispels concern for Poles in Libya.</title>
<headline>Official probe dispels concern for Poles in Libya.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Warsaw delegation, which visited Libya to probe allegations that Polish nurses working there were being badly treated, said on Monday most Poles were pleased with their jobs and had little reason to complain.</p>
<p>The team, from the labour ministry and the main nurses' and doctors' organisations, toured Libya this month, after a tabloid newspaper alleged in August that 100 of about 400 Polish nurses there were having trouble leaving, that many lived in appalling conditions and that the terms of some contracts had been broken.</p>
<p>A statement after the visit, issued at a news conference, said that in talks with about 200 nurses as well as doctors at hospitals around Libya, no evidence had emerged of harsh conditions, limits on freedom or any drastic failure by Libya to honour contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;During all meetings, nurses and doctors expressed general displeasure and indignation over the unjustified, generalised views recently expressed by the Polish press over the conditions of their work and stay in Libya,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The delegation, which included the head of Poland's nurses' chamber, recommended that more Poles could go to work in Libya, not just in medicine but in oil and other industries.</p>
<p>A senior Libyan delegation will visit Poland in the first quarter of 1997 to discuss such proposals, Andrzej Pilat, the head of the National Labour Office, told the news conference.</p>
<p>Polish medical staff have been taking posts in Libya since a 1980 agreement between the countries, although few Polish doctors now find it worthwhile to go there.</p>
<p>Poland suspended new departures to Libya by nurses after the August report in the Super Express tabloid aroused concern, even though 400 are registered as willing to go.</p>
<p>Since then new openings had been snapped up by staff from Belarus, Ukraine and the Philippines, Pilat said.</p>
<p>Pilat said there were cases of culture shock when Polish nurses first arrived, often badly prepared and unable to speak foreign languages, and their accommodation varied in quality.</p>
<p>He said those who wished were free to leave whenever they liked, but very few chose to end their contracts early.</p>
<p>While there were sometimes delays in paying staff, all the money owed to them was eventually paid and many highly valued the professional expertise they gained in Libya.</p>
<p>Polish nurses earn up to $450 a month in Libya and get around $120 for living expenses on the spot.</p>
<p>Pilat said that in all some 150,000 Poles had travelled to work in Libya and many had considerably improved their living standards as a result, while 1,600 were now employed there.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
