<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="280353" id="root" date="1996-12-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: FEATURE - Russian tycoon faces controversy in political role.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Russian tycoon faces controversy in political role.</headline>
<byline>Timothy Heritage</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian businessman Boris Berezovsky has courted controversy at almost every turn in his meteoric rise from car dealer to Kremlin politician, and his new role negotiating in Chechnya is no exception.</p>
<p>Loathed by communists and many business rivals alike, the 50-year-old entrepreneur who made a fortune under market reforms epitomises all that many Russians despise.</p>
<p>But, dismissing critics' jibes that he is using politics for personal gain, Berezovsky says he is one of a new breed of businessmen-turned-politicians whose role is to spread the word of market reforms and guarantee that they continue.</p>
<p>&quot;The way to continue peace in Russia is without doubt the economic way. We need political will but we also need to take very concrete economic steps,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;What I am trying to do is to protect the way of reform in the fight we have today in Russia.&quot;</p>
<p>Berezovsky says he has no long-term political ambitions. But he says businessmen with an understanding of what he calls the &quot;new reality&quot; in Russia can plan an important role in the transition period before democracy gets a firmer grip.</p>
<p>APPOINTMENT STIRRED CONTROVERSY</p>
<p>He was appointed deputy secretary of President Boris Yeltsin's advisory Security Council on October 29, a move which formalised his influence behind the scenes and made him part of Russia's negotiating team with Chechen separatists.</p>
<p>A fierce opponent of communism, Berezovsky made his name selling cars and now controls a vast financial empire based around the LogoVAZ industrial giant, which gives him a finger in many pies.</p>
<p>He also owns a major stake in a bank and is a director of the ORT television channel, which is usually pro-Yeltsin and reaches most of Russia's 150 million people.</p>
<p>Berezovsky says he played a role in helping Yeltsin defeat communist Gennady Zyuganov in last July's presidential election and that a small group of bankers and businesmen now has huge sway in Russia's political affairs.</p>
<p>His shock appointment to the Security Council, despite his lack of experience in politics, provoked a furore which the opposition communists have exploited to attack the Kremlin and further stain Yeltsin's image.</p>
<p>The scandal has also opened Berezovsky to attacks on his personal integrity, some based on a controversy over whether, as a Jew, he also has Israeli citizenship. He says he does not.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's ousted confidant and personal security chief, Alexander Korzhakov, even accused Berezovsky of asking him to kill a business rival. Berezovsky denies the charge.</p>
<p>LEARNING TO LIVE UNDER PRESSURE</p>
<p>Berezovsky, who survived an apparent assassination attempt when his car was blown up in 1994 and his driver killed, says he has taken the latest attacks in his stride.</p>
<p>&quot;I had big pressure in my business life...and as for the new part of my life, the political part, it is nearly the same,&quot; he said. &quot;I certainly do not enjoy this pressure but I enjoy the position I have and matching them (the critics).&quot;</p>
<p>Berezovksy's main role as a negotiator with separatists in Chechnya has been to dangle a financial carrot to persuade them that peace and staying in Russia will be to their advantage.</p>
<p>He is the lynchpin in a new strategy in which the Kremlin is using economic leverage to try to ensure peace and keep Chechnya in Russia after almost 21 months of fighting.</p>
<p>&quot;Chechnya has a lot of problems and we need to find a specific way to help the Chechen people be happy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In my mind it is part of Russia and I will do my best to find a way which will be acceptable for the Chechen people and where they will be happy to be part of Russia.&quot;</p>
<p>IS OIL BEING USED AS BAIT IN NEGOTIATIONS?</p>
<p>Many independent political analysts say Moscow hopes Berezovsky can persuade the separatists that he can attract investment to Chechnya. They say that oil is also at the heart of the new strategy.</p>
<p>Chechnya, an oil refining centre, already has a pipeline running through it and is a possible transit point for future pipelines carrying oil through that part of southern Russia.</p>
<p>Berezovsky denies he has been discussing oil, despite recent visits to oil-producing Azerbaijan and to Georgia, which could host an oil pipeline taking Azeri oil to Western markets.</p>
<p>He also says he has given up his business activities and has nothing to gain financially from the negotiations.</p>
<p>&quot;On the one hand, it would be hypocrisy if I said I do not have any intersection of political interests and business interests. But on the other hand I have stopped all my business activities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>FUTURE IS UNCERTAIN</p>
<p>Berezovsky gives away few details of his negotiations in Chechnya, which helps maintain the mystery around him.</p>
<p>His time in office may be limited. Some analysts say Yeltsin could sack him soon as a way of reprimanding chief of staff Anatoly Chubais, who is Berezovsky's sponsor and has amassed power in the president's absence with heart problems.</p>
<p>&quot;For sure, the president could change his understanding but, in any case, I am trying to to do my best to realise the presidential line the way I understand it,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
