<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28049" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - News may pay TNT up to A$75 mln.</title>
<headline>RTRS - News may pay TNT up to A$75 mln.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Global media company News Corp Ltd would pay transport firm TNT Ltd up to A$75 million if News sold its 50 percent stake in Australia's Ansett Airlines before June 2003, TNT said.</p>
<p>TNT also confirmed that it had signed a deed to sell its 50 percent stake in Ansett to Air New Zealand Ltd, which would generate cash receipts of A$325 million for TNT.  </p>
<p>&quot;TNT has also reached agreement with The News Corp Ltd to receive up to A$75 million from News if it disposes of its 50 percent interest in Ansett before June 2003 based on an agreed formula,&quot; TNT said.</p>
<p>&quot;If full disposal does not take place, TNT may receive a payment from News based on the future profitability of Ansett,&quot; TNT said.</p>
<p>TNT said the disposal of its interest in Ansett, comprising shares and loans, had now been formally documented.</p>
<p>&quot;The disposal will generate cash receipts of A$325 million for TNT,&quot; TNT said.  </p>
<p>TNT said the sale remained subject to Foreign Investment Review Board (FIRB) approval and approval by the shareholders of Air New Zealand (ANZ).</p>
<p>&quot;ANZ has advised that shareholder approval is to be sought at an extraordinary general meeting of the company planned for Friday September 27, enabling settlement of the transaction as early as 30 September 1996, if FIRB approval is received before that date,&quot; TNT said.</p>
<p>A FIRB official told Reuters the matter was still under consideration and a decision was legally required before September 26.  </p>
<p>Earlier Air New Zealand said it was buying the stake in Ansett for a total of A$475 million, including a purchase price of A$133 milion; loans of A$122 million by Air NZ to Ansett to repay TNT's subordinated debt in Ansett; subscription of A$70 million for redeemable preference shares in Ansett to replace those held by TNT and an additional capital contribution by Air NZ to Ansett of $150 million.</p>
<p>News would also provide a further A$50 million capital contribution to Ansett, Air New Zealand said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
