<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="280433" id="root" date="1996-12-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Menem says Argentina prepared to share Falklands.</title>
<headline>Menem says Argentina prepared to share Falklands.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina would be willing to share with Britain the sovereignty of the disputed Falkland Islands over which they fought in 1982, President Carlos Menem told reporters in comments published on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not lose hope of perhaps in the year 2000 seeing the Argentine flag flying in the islands, either alone or with other flags,&quot; Menem said in his native La Rioja province on Sunday.</p>
<p>Asked if that meant shared rule of the islands Argentina calls the Malvinas, Menem replied: &quot;Of course, I see that as a possibility: to have the Argentine flag flying in the islands for example with the English flag would be a step forward.&quot;</p>
<p>About 1,000 soldiers, mostly Argentine, died in the 10-week war when Britain sent a task force to oust Argentine troops trying to enforce Argentina's sovereignty claim.</p>
<p>Argentina lost the war, but maintains its claim. The two countries resumed diplomatic ties in 1989 and have reached an agreement on oil exploration in the South Atlantic, while putting the sovereignty issue aside.</p>
<p>Since coming to power in 1989, Menem has promoted a trade and diplomatic rapprochement with Britain and hosted visits by British royalty while insisting that Argentina will regain ownership of the islands by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Guido Di Tella has attracted criticism for a &quot;charm offensive&quot; that has included sending the islanders Christmas cards with photos of his family. But he recently acknowledged: &quot;I haven't had any results for six years.&quot;</p>
<p>Menem said in La Rioja that &quot;our strategies change with the times. We have never had such good relations with England as we do now. So our chances of recovering the islands are better.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FALK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
