<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28055" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Sydney storm leaves A$5-A$10 mln damages bill.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Sydney storm leaves A$5-A$10 mln damages bill.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian insurance companies on Monday said a storm that hit Sydney over the weekend, leaving 30,000 homes without power, unroofing houses and flooding streets, caused A$5-10 million (US$4-8 million) in damage.</p>
<p>However, the Insurance Council of Australia said the storm was not the worst to have hit Sydney in recent years and that insurance firms would be little affected.</p>
<p>&quot;Insurers estimate Sydney's weekend storm will generate claims of between five and 10 million dollars,&quot; Council spokesman Mark Sheehan said.  </p>
<p>&quot;At this stage we have had 10,000 claims, but most have been small,&quot; Sheehan said. &quot;Because it happened during the weekend people were at home and able to prevent further damage.&quot;</p>
<p>Insurance and motoring group NRMA Ltd said its claims alone would amount to A$6.0 million.</p>
<p>The NRMA said it had only received 100 claims for structural damage to houses, the rest had been for minor damage to buildings and motor vehicles.</p>
<p>&quot;Other storms have been worse, but they are usually localised. This one was widespread, but the damage has been less,&quot; said NRMA spokesman John Bowman.  </p>
<p>A low pressure storm off Sydney's coast hit the northern suburbs of the city on Friday night.</p>
<p>Winds gusting up to 60 knots uprooted trees, unroofed houses, and caused widespread electiricty blackouts with about 30,000 homes without power for part of the weekend.</p>
<p>Heavy rains and huge seas also caused localised flooding.</p>
<p>&quot;The majority of jobs we still have to do are a result of trees falling down,&quot; State Emergency Service duty officer Gary Grant said on Monday.</p>
<p>The storm lasted throughout Sunday as it moved south along Sydney's coastline.  </p>
<p>&quot;We usually only get one or two of these east coast low pressure systems a year,&quot; said Weather Bureau forecaster Philip Kinghe.</p>
<p>&quot;This one was particularly strong and close to the coast and that's why we got the storms and fierce winds,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
