<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="280594" id="root" date="1996-12-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</title>
<headline>Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain and oilseed exports reported by USDA and private export sources.</p>
<p>SOYBEAN MEAL SALE - Tunisia bought 13,000 tonnes of 44 percent soybean meal at $261.07 per tonne FOB and 13,000 of 48 percent at $313, C and F, traders said. Shipment is for January 29-February 6 for the 44 percent soybean meal and February 16-26 for the 48 percent.</p>
<p>CORN SALE - Cyprus on Monday bought from Toepfer Athens 18,000 tonnes of maize at $142.84 per tonne, a statement from the Grain Commission said. Prices include C and F free out of Limassol port in Cyprus. Shipment is expected in January 1997.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDERS - Sri Lanka's state buying arm the Co-operative Wholesale Establishment seeks 100,000 tonnes of soft and hard wheat, government officials said. The tender closes January 3 and is for 50,000 tonnes of soft wheat for delivery in the third week of January and 50,000 tonnes of hard wheat for delivery in the second week of February.</p>
<p>- The Commodity Credit Corp said it seeks up to 30,000 tonnes of U.S. No. 2 or better hard red winter wheat for donation to Bosnia. Shipment is for January 25-February 20. Offers are due January 7.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDERS - Bangladesh seeks 100,000 tonnes of U.S. No.2 wheat or Australian Standard or better Canadian winter red/spring wheat for shipment by February 21, food ministry officials said. Offers are to be opened January 18 and the results announced two to three days later.</p>
<p>- Yemen postponed until January 7 a soft wheat and soft wheat flour tender initially scheduled for December 26, European grain traders said. Yemen seeks 200,000 tonnes of optional soft wheat flour for shipment between February and June and 200,000 tonnes of new crop U.S. or Canadian or Australian soft white wheat for July-September, they said.  </p>
<p>SOYBEAN OIL TENDER - The CCC is to tender for 10,370 tonnes of U.S. bulk crude degummed soybean oil for donation to Peru. Delivery was for February 3-18. Offers were requested by January 7. Successful offerers will be notified January 8.</p>
<p>LENTIL TENDER - Syria's General Establishment for Cereal Processing and Trade has offered 10,000 tonnes of lentils from the 1996 crops for export, an official spokesman said. He said December 30 was the final date to receive bids, and results would be announced December 31.  </p>
<p>MARKET TALK - The Pakistani government decided on Sunday to import 600,000 more tonnes of wheat to stabilise domestic prices, an official statement said Sunday. Last week, the Food and Agriculture Ministry bought 270,000 tonnes of wheat from U.S. and Australian suppliers for shipment by January 31.  </p>
<p>MARKET TALK - Cargill Inc is waiting for a decision from the U.S. Treasury Department on an application to sell up to 2 million tonnes of grain to North Korea, a Cargill spokeswoman said Monday. The application, submitted in September, &quot;includes a broad authorization on what constitutes the business and does not specify rice, corn or other commodity. But it would be food,&quot; Cargill spokeswoman Laurie Johnson told Reuters.</p>
<p>((Doris Frankel 312-408-8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
