<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="280638" id="root" date="1996-12-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Storm-hit U.S. Northwest braces for flooding.</title>
<headline>Storm-hit U.S. Northwest braces for flooding.</headline>
<byline>Jeanne Sather</byline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The northwestern United States braced for flooding on Monday as powerful winter storms swelled rivers, disrupted travel and left tens of thousands of people without power.</p>
<p>Washington state Gov. Mike Lowry declared a state of emergency in 12 counties on Sunday after the second storm in a week dumped more snow and rain, creating havoc. The National Guard was mobilised in two counties to help residents.</p>
<p>Rain fell in Washington, Oregon and California on Monday but the whole area was waiting anxiously for the next in a series of powerful Pacific storms forecast to arrive on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Across the border in Canada, residents of British Columbia shoveled themselves out from the area's worst blizzard in decades. A rare snowstorm dumped up to 27 inches (70 cms) at the weekend, paralysing public transportation.</p>
<p>Vancouver International Airport operated at only 10 percent capacity on Sunday and was struggling to get ice-coated planes moving on Monday.</p>
<p>In Seattle, office workers struggled to work through streets buried under snow and slush and most government offices allowed employees to come in two hours late.</p>
<p>Three deaths were blamed on the storm in Washington state, according to Mark Clemens, a spokesman for Washington State Emergency Management. Two people were killed by falling trees and a third suffocated because of a faulty heater.</p>
<p>An Oregon bulldozer operator drowned when his machine flipped over, Oregon state police said.</p>
<p>Heavy snow brought roofs crashing down onto boats at the Edmonds marina, north of Seattle, sinking 300 boats and causing an estimated $8 million damage, Clemens said.</p>
<p>Drains could not handle the heavy runoff, flooding some streets and submerging vehicles.</p>
<p>Flood warnings were issued for about six rivers in western Washington state, and in Oregon a dozen rivers were at or near flood stage with water levels set to rise further.</p>
<p>Officials worried that the snow could quickly melt if the weather warmed up, swelling rivers and causing flooding. &quot;We're just hoping we get through the next few days before all this stuff melts,&quot; Clemens said.</p>
<p>Some 120,000 sandbags were being distributed to National Guard armouries throughout Oregon.</p>
<p>Authorities advised residents of low-lying areas near several rivers in Thurston County around the Washington state capital of Olympia to evacuate as a precaution.</p>
<p>&quot;We are advising people to evacuate now rather than later when it could be a panic situation,&quot; county spokesman Keith Eisner said. He estimated that 1,000 people had left.</p>
<p>The Red Cross said about 250 people spent the night at three shelters it set up in the Olympia area.</p>
<p>About 64,000 customers remained without power in nine counties in western Washington state, down from a peak of 248,000 on Friday, Betty Werblun, a spokeswoman for Puget Sound Power and Light Co., said.</p>
<p>About 7,000 customers in the Portland, Oregon area were without electricity and about 2,000 homes and businesses in northern California were also without power.</p>
<p>All major mountain routes connecting western and eastern Washington state remained closed due to avalanche danger. State transportation crews were working to clear the highways but they were not expected to reopen until later in the week. &quot;You cannot drive from the western to the eastern part of the state right now,&quot; Clemens said.</p>
<p>Driving conditions across the Pacific Northwest were generally treacherous.</p>
<p>In California, the National Weather Service issued a flood warning for the rain-swollen Napa and Russian rivers north of San Francisco and high wind warnings and flash flood watches for counties in the San Francisco Bay area.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
