<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="280825" id="root" date="1996-12-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: College enrollment rising, preliminary figures show.</title>
<headline>College enrollment rising, preliminary figures show.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>College enrollment is rising for the first time in four years in most states, according to preliminary data released on Monday by the American Council on Education.</p>
<p>The increase is modest and probably indicates that enrollment is stabilizing, according to complete data from 11 states, supplemented by surveys of education officials in 22 states.</p>
<p>The council said that trends vary by region. Enrollment increases are more likely in the South, Southwest and West.</p>
<p>Fewer states in 1996 saw a decline in enrollment at four-year public institutions. That is partly because as state economies have improved, more funding has become available for state colleges and universities so tuition has not risen as fast.</p>
<p>Enrollment at two-year community colleges also appeared to have stabilized. Some officials expect it to rise in coming years, partly because older workers will be seeing some work force training at these local schools.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Education has forecast that college enrollment nationwide will rise by 14 percent over the next 10 years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
