<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="280947" id="root" date="1996-12-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: At least 300 die in India train blast -- police.</title>
<headline>At least 300 die in India train blast -- police.</headline>
<dateline>GUWAHATI, India 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least 300 people were killed on Monday when a powerful bomb ripped through several carriages of a packed train in India's northeastern state of Assam, police said.</p>
<p>A senior police official told Reuters in Assam's biggest city of Guwahati that separatist Bodo militants had used a remote-controlled device packed with explosives to blow up the Delhi-bound train.  </p>
<p>&quot;Bodo guerrillas blew up three coaches of a passenger train killing at least 300 people at Sensapani railway station,&quot; a senior police official told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;They used RDX (research and development explosives) and a remote-controlled device,&quot; the official said. Sensapani is 200 km (125 miles) west of Guwahati, hub of the tea-rich state.</p>
<p>The blast came a day after tribal Bodo guerrillas blew up a road bridge that formed the main link between India's northeast regions and the rest of the country, injuring seven people.</p>
<p>Activists representing Bodo tribesmen living north of the Brahmaputra river want a homeland within India in the state of Assam, but an extremist fringe, the Bodoland Army, has been fighting for a separate nation since 1989.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUWAHATI, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
