<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="280972" id="root" date="1996-12-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian call money off day's high, gilts steady.</title>
<headline>Indian call money off day's high, gilts steady.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian call money ended Monday around 11 percent, off the day's high of 11.5 percent as demand for funds eased in the afternoon, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said rates which were firm during the morning and early afternoon eased off as demand for funds tapered off.</p>
<p>Dealers said most of the day's trade was between 10.90 and 11.25 percent with stray deals at 11.5 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The firmness in rates was a bit surprising,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;It appears that a number of borrowing banks do not have export refinance limits...otherwise rates would be below 11 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>Banks can avail refinance against their export credit disbursals from the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) at 11 percent per annum.</p>
<p>Prices of government securities were steady in moderate trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>The 13.40 percent 1999 government of India stock traded at a yield of 13.15 percent against its last traded yield of 13.18.</p>
<p>The 91-day treasury bill auctioned on December 27 at a yield of 8.19 percent was traded on Monday at 8.5 percent, a dealer said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
