<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="280984" id="root" date="1996-12-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: INDIAN IPOs - Few premium public issues in Dec - PRIME.</title>
<headline>INDIAN IPOs - Few premium public issues in Dec - PRIME.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Premium issues are now rapidly becoming extinct in the primary capital market, according PRIME, the country's leading data base on the primary capital market.</p>
<p>In a report by PRIME's Prithvi Haldea, substantial losses in earlier premium issues compounded by continuing dismal market conditions made investors wary of issues made at a premium.</p>
<p>Such issues have been declining over the past several months and in November had totally disappeared, he said.</p>
<p>December was also a month of par issues with the exception of the sole premium issue of Bank of Baroda. In the first nine months of the current year, only 82 issues were issued at a premium compared to 199 in 1993-94, 453 in 1994-95 and 302 in 1995-96, PRIME said.</p>
<p>Though from a low of 24 in November, the number of public issues in December increased to 41, the same was only because of a large number of finance and 'technical' issues. During April-September, as many as 577 public issues hit the market, -- an average of 96 issues per month. The first major fall came in the month of October which had only 41 issues.</p>
<p>Significantly, according to PRIME, of the total raised of 9,600 million rupees in the month, only 640 million rupees (seven percent) was mobilised by the manufacturing sector. The rest was raised by the finance sector which resurfaced in a major way with 21 of the 41 issues (51 percent) coming from this sector. This was higher than 33 percent in November, 39 percent in October, 37 percent in September, 40 percent in August and 26 to 29 percent in April-July, PRIME said.</p>
<p>Moreover, small issues continued to dominate the market in December too -- 29 of the 41 issues (71 percent) were below 30 million rupees.</p>
<p>Courtesy the Bank of Baroda's mega issue (8,500 million rupees), total mobilisation through public issues in December reached 9,600 million rupees, compared to 4,740 million rupees in November. The amounts in earlier months were 3,160 million rupees in October, 13,990 million rupees in September, 3,480 million rupees in August, 16,740 million rupees in July, 6,840 million in June, 12,750 million rupees in May and 3,830 million rupees in April.</p>
<p>The response to December issues, PRIME noted, continued to be poor. Of the 23 issues open till 18th December, several had to take their issues till the last closing dates. This included the issues of Skyline India, Pantex Geebee, Skeleton Pharma and Vijaylakshmi Syntex.</p>
<p>Worse, faced with poor market conditions, 16 issues of the month did not even provide for an earliest closing date -- these being Gwalior Tanks, Tridev Finance, Shubh International, Sai Moh Autolinks, Elite Capital, Ongoing Advertising, Goldedge Estate, Ankur International, Stenley Credit Capital, B.R. Cement, Sahyog Credits, SMC Credits, R.M. Mohite Textiles, Saraswati Capital, Man Mohak Fin-Invest-Lease as well as the mega issue of Bank of Baroda which also followed this route.</p>
<p>PRIME said that during the month, the issue of Mardia Global Finvest had to be withdrawn on the eve of the opening of subscription list. This brought the total to 24 issues since April of issues which were cancelled or withdrawn literally at the last moment.</p>
<p>The future, according to Haldea, appears extremely grim.</p>
<p>Not only fewer companies are qualifying under the new guidelines ... even the number of other companies willing to prepare themselves to face the market is going down rapidly.</p>
<p>PRIME said there has been a continuing slowdown in the number of issue documents submitted for clearance to SEBI. While a total of 837 documents had been filed in the four month January-April period (average of 209 per month), the same fell to only 227 in the May-August period (average of 57 per month) and has since fallen dramatically to 40 in September, 18 in October and 22 in November.</p>
<p>The issues from the private sector, in the present scenario, have literally gone into cold storage. Only the public sector is expected to dominate the immediate future.</p>
<p>To January's rescue is already the 7,500 million rupees debt issue of IDBI. The other mega offerings expected to hit the market in the near future, according to PRIME, are Canara Bank (10,000 million rupees), Bank of India (6,750 million rupees) and Corporation Bank (2,500 million rupees).</p>
<p>Incidentally, looking at the market conditions, Bank of India has already decided to pare down its premium while Canara Bank has put its premium issue on temporary hold, PRIME said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
