<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="281035" id="root" date="1996-12-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Brussels bourse set to await direction in New Year.</title>
<headline>Brussels bourse set to await direction in New Year.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brussels Bel-20 shares closed higher on the last trading day of the year but closed off their intraday highs. Dealers said the Bel-20 share index could meet stiff resistance around the 1,900 level in the coming months as the market lacked direction.</p>
<p>The Bel-20 closed up 0.12 percent to 1,895.49 after earlier touching an intraday high of 1,906.23.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors will need some new information, if the situation doesn't change I don't see the Bel-20 breaking the 1,900 level in the next couple of months,&quot; said trader Benoit Kint at brokerage Petercam.</p>
<p>He said that investors were now cautious and many were not taking profits because they didn't know where to invest their money as interest rates were low and share prices were high.</p>
<p>&quot;People don't know how to invest their money so they'll sit on their shares and wait for something to happen,&quot; a trader from a major Belgian bank said.</p>
<p>She expected little profit taking in the coming month as there was not much to buy on the Bel-20.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in a very dangerous period...it's the kind of situation you see before a major correction where the market is quiet and investors are cautious but want to take profits&quot;.</p>
<p>Another trader said the first half of 1997 would see more selective buying than this year, with people more cautious on their choice of stocks in the Bel-20. He expected interest in cement maker CBR to continue as it was still a cheap stock.</p>
<p>&quot;CBR will have a good 1997 as it is not an expensive stock compared to other European cement companies and it has the best margins&quot;. CBR closed up 1.76 percent to 2,885 francs.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be more selective buying on the Bel-20 next month with people more cautious on their choice of stocks,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>He said chemicals and drugs firm UCB would see further gains, particularly once the commercialisation of its Zyrtec drug in Japan was completed. UCB closed up 0.73 percent to 82,700 francs.</p>
<p>Steel cord and wire maker Bekaert finished 2.28 percent higher at 20,150 francs after recent falls due to 1996 profit warnings, but some dealers said the share was still too expensive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
