<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="281379" id="root" date="1996-12-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Colombo port faces unrest over expansion deal.</title>
<headline>Colombo port faces unrest over expansion deal.</headline>
<byline>Rohan Gunasekera</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lankan labour unions opposing plans to lease part of Colombo port to Peninsular and Oriental Steam Navigation Co. on Monday threatened more action similar to last week's strike that hobbled South Asia's trans-shipment hub.</p>
<p>&quot;We're totally opposed to P&amp;O getting any foothold in the country,&quot; said Bala Tampoe, head of the Ceylon Mercantile Union (CMU), the biggest union which took part in a strike last Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll go ahead with further action -- strikes or other forms of action,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;We will not stop with a one-day token strike. This is only the beginning. That was a warning to the government to lay off.&quot;</p>
<p>Labour unions which organised Friday's strike say they oppose plans to lease the Queen Elizabeth Quay to Britain's P&amp;O as they fear it would lead to retrenchment and losses to the Sri Lanka Ports Authority (SLPA), which runs the port.</p>
<p>The SLPA is currently holding talks with P&amp;O to turn Queen Elizabeth Quay into a new container terminal to expand capacity and later build a new port adjacent to the present one.</p>
<p>The project, estimated to cost up to $1 billion and take 10 years to finish, would see the development of the southern part of the port with a capacity of two million containers per year.</p>
<p>Shipping Ministry officials said the government would have to consider sterner measures to thwart labour union action which could damage the port's reputation.</p>
<p>Last Friday, the SLPA cancelled the leave of all workers to force them back to work.</p>
<p>Ports and Shipping Minister Mohamed Ashraff told labour union leaders last week he would go ahead with the deal only if it was profitable.</p>
<p>Ashraff urged workers not to damage the port's reputation by striking, saying a deal with P&amp;O was six months away.</p>
<p>The P&amp;O deal was required to urgently expand capacity to handle rising container volumes and bigger ships capable of carrying 5,000 containers and retain Colombo's position as a hub port, he said.</p>
<p>The port, with a capacity of 1.6 million containers, is expected to handle 1.3 million containers this year, up from just over a million last year, he said.</p>
<p>The CMU's Tampoe said his main concern was that P&amp;O, if allowed to come in, would take away income from the SLPA's main container terminal, the Jaye Container Terminal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
