<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="281394" id="root" date="1996-12-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai brokers threatened as stock exchange slides.</title>
<headline>Thai brokers threatened as stock exchange slides.</headline>
<byline>James Mclean</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some Thai brokers are taking security precautions following threats from disgruntled investors hit by a tumbling stock market, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Irate investors, who stood to lose fortunes if brokers force-sold their deteriorating portfolios, had tried to stave off such action by making threats, the sources said.</p>
<p>Under the forced-sales system, brokers compel clients to sell stocks bought on credit to cover portfolio losses.</p>
<p>A number of firms had received threats of varying degrees over the past few months, the sources said.</p>
<p>Thailand's stock market has plunged to 3-1/2-year lows on the back of blue-chip sales by mainly foreign investors. The market was down 7.08 points to 828.63 at midday on Monday.</p>
<p>The sales have also been sparked by worries about Thailand's economic fundamentals, especially the large 1996 current account deficit which is projected at 8.2 percent of gross domestic product.</p>
<p>Other investors' concerns were the deteriorating quality of bank loans given to firms in the depressed Thai property sector, official projections for a contraction in 1996 export growth and a slowing of the robust economy.</p>
<p>&quot;I think this problem may have happened to some brokers with margin accounts making big losses in the market, if the broker has forced clients to sell,&quot; said Sasitorn Withayaruksun, head of sales at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>Although intimidation against individuals is rare in Thailand, some serious business disputes are sometimes settled violently. So some executives are not taking chances.</p>
<p>&quot;One country manager has hired bodyguards after receiving threats,&quot; said George Morgan, head of the Foreign Brokers Association. &quot;Though I think this is an isolated case.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders at a Japanese brokerage said a package containing a severed dog's head had been sent to a company employee. But executives clarified that it was not market-related and was triggered by a personality clash between two employees.</p>
<p>Threats against brokers were widespread, but foreign securities companies had been targeted because they were generally less flexible in relaxing forced-sale rules than some local securities houses, brokers said.</p>
<p>The market has become more sensitive to negative reports and recommendations with the key SET Index having lost over 30 percent of its value since the start of the year.</p>
<p>A Hong Kong-Thai joint venture brokerage executive said his firm was among those targeted by losers for taking a bearish stance on the market this year.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the real issue is that some important people have been forced to sell and have lost money and they just don't like it,&quot; said the executive, who declined to be named.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
