<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="281671" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US mortgage-backeds whacked in pre-holiday trade.</title>
<headline>US mortgage-backeds whacked in pre-holiday trade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. mortgage-backed securities spent New Year's Eve in the doldrums, as pass-through prices skidded lower in line with Treasuries.</p>
<p>Treasuries and pass-through prices fell sharply following the release of much stronger-than-expected new home sales figures, traders said.</p>
<p>Also, the Conference Board released a report that showed consumer confidence rose to 113.8 in December from 109.5 in November.</p>
<p>Securities firms operated with skeleton crews as market players fled their posts early for the New Year holiday.  </p>
<p>The few traders at work said they couldn't find any inspiration amid Tuesday morning's economic data.</p>
<p>&quot;We're down with Treasuries,&quot; said one New York-based trader. &quot;That's the only thing going on today. No activity here,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>By early afternoon Tuesday, pass-throughs were 2/32 to 23/32 lower.</p>
<p>Specifically, Ginnie Mae 30-year 7.5 percent paper was down 19/32 at 100-00/32, yielding 115 basis points over the 10-year Treasury note.  </p>
<p>Comparable Fannie Mae 7.5 percent coupons dropped 15/32 to 100-00/32, and Freddie Mac 7.5 percent coupons were off 17/32 to 100-03/32.</p>
<p>The U.S. bond market and other debt markets will be closing early at 1400 EST/1900 GMT. Markets will be closed Wednesday for New Year's day.</p>
<p>Fresh cash in early 1997 may give mortgage-backeds a boost, traders said. &quot;Particularly in the first day, you are going to see things tighten up pretty good down here,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>((-- Jeff Coelho, N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1562))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
