<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="281689" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee ends firmer in abbreviated session.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee ends firmer in abbreviated session.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures closed out the year in quiet fashion Tuesday, scoring modest gains in an abbreviated pre-holiday session.</p>
<p>Light buying on the part of commission houses and the trade boosted prices early on, dealers said. But producers, led by Mexico and several Central American countries, were once again ready sellers at the highs, stopping the rally at a peak of 117.50 cents for the third straight day.</p>
<p>Key March delivery rose 0.95 cent a lb, to 116.90 cents, having ranged from 115.90 and 117.50. Second-position May gained 1.10 cent, while the rest finished 0.30 to 1.85 higher.</p>
<p>The day's volume was estimated at 4,659 lots.</p>
<p>The CSCE will be closed January 1 in observance of New Year's Day. Normal trading resumes on Thursday, January 2.</p>
<p>With this year's harvest well underway in the major Latin American producing countries and U.S. consumer stocks showing signs of rebuilding from historic lows, some traders said the arabica market ended the year in surprisingly strong form. Key to the bullish tone, they said, was last Friday's technical breakout above the widely-watched 115-cent level.</p>
<p>But unless the market is able to continue making new highs, a correction may be on the horizon as speculators seek to unload long positions.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we need a good shake-out again,&quot; said one trader, who estimated the funds' long position at an unusually large 10,000 lots. Total open interest on the &quot;C&quot; contract reached 30,507 lots as of Monday's close, up from some 23,000 in early December.</p>
<p>On the charts, March would need to clear 117.50, followed by 119 cents, to continue to attract buying interest. Support was seen at 115 cents, followed by 113-112 and 108.</p>
<p>((-- W Pollack, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
