<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="281665" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Conn. utility industry needs revamp -atty general.</title>
<headline>Conn. utility industry needs revamp -atty general.</headline>
<dateline>HARTFORD 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>A scathing state audit report on Northeast Utilities shows the need for a total restructuring of electric utilities in Connecticut, state attorney general Richard Blumenthal said Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This very scathing audit demonstrates the need for additional competition and restructuring at Northeast Utilities and in our electric industry in general,&quot; Blumenthal said in comments broadcast on local radio.</p>
<p>He was responding to a report issued earlier Tuesday by Connecticut's Department of Public Utility Control (DPUC), which concluded that Northeast and its subsidiary mismanaged the state's four nuclear units over the last decade.</p>
<p>Blumenthal said that increased competition would provide ratepayers with cheaper and more reliable service. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>&quot;This scathing audit of the management of Connecticut's four nuclear plants is further evidence that the troubles with Connecticut's nuclear plants are the result of massive mismanagement at Northeast Utilities,&quot; Blumenthal also said in a statement issued Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The costs associated with this nuclear mismanagement will be the responsibility of Northeast Utilities and not the citizens and businesses of Connecticut,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The DPUC report said, &quot;As NU has consistently misunderstood the nature of its problems over the past decade, it has consistently applied the wrong solutions.&quot;</p>
<p>Northeast and Connecticut Light and Power Co (CL&amp;P) co-own and operate the 582 megawatt (MW) Connecticut Yankee generating station in Haddam Neck and three units, with combined capacity of nearly 2,700 MW, at the Millstone complex in Waterford.</p>
<p>The latest criticism of Northeast and CL&amp;P followed a DPUC report earlier this month, which listed deficiencies and suggested technical improvements at each plant.</p>
<p>&quot;It (The first report) was more technical, and this is more historical with the management and the NRC (Nuclear Regulatory Commission),&quot; said DPUC spokeswoman Beryl Lyons.</p>
<p>--Matthew Lewis, Hartford newsroom (860-727-0224)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARTFORD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
