<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="281624" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Judge refuses to extradite German businessman.</title>
<headline>Judge refuses to extradite German businessman.</headline>
<byline>Rita Farrell</byline>
<dateline>WILMINGTON, Del 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>A federal magistrate has refused to order the extradition of a German businessman, saying German authorities failed to provide direct evidence linking him to charges of bankruptcy fraud, court papers say.</p>
<p>U.S. Magistrate Mary Pat Trostle of the Delaware district said papers filed by the Federal Republic of Germany &quot;do not contain sufficient factual information to support a criminal charge...The information submitted amounts to unsupported conclusory statements, which are insufficient to satisfy probable cause.&quot;  </p>
<p>A warrant for the arrest of Gunther Lehming, 70, was issued by a Saarbrucken court in November 1995 alleging he &quot;absconded with or transferred assets of&quot; Depro Keramische Buntdrucke GmbH when he was a director of the company.</p>
<p>His lawyer, Edmund Lyons Jr., told Reuters: &quot;What we have here is civil lawsuit, but not a criminal case. The transfer of assets was pursuant to a pre-existing contract&quot; which Lyons said gave Lehming the right to transfer assets from Depro to three other companies in which he has a proprietary interest: Elkap and Serico of France and Depro-Serical USA.  </p>
<p>In an affidavit, a German bankruptcy trustee said the transferred items included patent rights, semi-finished goods valued at 338,000 marks, a printing press, a repro-system, computer disk cabinets and color samples. Lyons did not know the total value of the transferred assets.</p>
<p>Lehming moved to the U.S. 10 years ago and about five years ago opened a Depro-Serical USA plant near Newark, Delaware where he now lives.</p>
<p>Lyons said Lehming has no plans ever to return to Germany even to face possible civil charges. The U.S. Attorney's Office, which serves as the agent for extradition requests for criminal charges, can restart the process if Germany provides direct evidence of criminal fraud to meet the standard of probable cause.</p>
<p>According to Lyons, the U.S. Secretary of State can countermand an extradition order by a U.S. court, but cannot order extradition without a warrant.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WILMINGTON, Del"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
