<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28179" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila steps further from debt restructuring.</title>
<headline>Manila steps further from debt restructuring.</headline>
<byline>Ramoncito dela Cruz</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippines took another step away from its debt restructuring status on Monday by retiring part of its Brady bonds in exchange for new, uncollateralised debt issues, finance officials said.</p>
<p>The Brady bonds are restructured Philippine government commercial paper issued in late 1992 when it was not in a position to pay its debts.</p>
<p>The government from Monday is offering two new uncollateralised bonds in exchange for $1.9 billion worth of U.S. Treasury note-backed Brady bonds, otherwise known as par bonds, through a series of auctions, finance secretary Roberto de Ocampo said.</p>
<p>The exchange of the 25- and 26-year Brady bonds will be made through a Dutch auction in which bondholders will submit a minimum rate they will accept for the new 15-year and 20-year bonds.</p>
<p>The government will peg acceptable rates at the end of the offer period, which runs until September 20, as coupon rates for the 15-year floating rate note and 20- year fixed rate note.</p>
<p>Secondary prices of Philippine par bonds inched up slightly on Monday to 81.75 from 81.50 posted last Friday, traders said.</p>
<p>De Ocampo said the effective retirement of the par bonds was part of the government's shift out of higher-yielding debt issues to commercial rated issues such as the Eurobond and Samurai bond issues.</p>
<p>Brady bonds are named after former U.S. Treasury Secretary Nicholas Brady who in 1989 proposed the concept of bonds backed by the U.S. Treasury but with repayments being made by a sovereign lesser developed country.</p>
<p>Eurobonds are issued in a specific currency outside the currency's domicile. Samurais are issued in Japan by a foreign borrower and denominated in yen.</p>
<p>&quot;All these initiatives distance us further from the era of debt restructuring,&quot; de Ocampo said during the launch of the bond exchange programme.</p>
<p>He said the new bonds, which have 100 percent Philippine risk exposure, would also set the benchmarks for local government and private firms as they tap the international debt market.</p>
<p>&quot;Offering investors a long-term bond with uncollateralised Philippine risk will allow a long-term pricing benchmark to be set, which in turn should help government agencies, corporates, and infrastructure projects access long-term maturities at attractive terms,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, this should reduce reliance on short-term foreign debt.&quot;</p>
<p>Central Bank governor Gabriel Singson said the new bonds, which are expected to yield lower rates, will make debt payment easier for the government.</p>
<p>The ratio of external debt servicing cost to current account receipts fell to only 13 percent last year from 36 percent in 1985 after a debt reduction and debt restructuring programme.</p>
<p>J.P. Morgan Securities, the arranger of the new debt issues, said the debt exchange was a &quot;win-win&quot; situation.</p>
<p>&quot;The bond holders (will) increase realisable spread on their investments, though with a commensurate increase in sovereign exposure,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Bond traders said the new programme might spur another round of credit upgrading for Philippine sovereign bonds.</p>
<p>In February, Moody's Investors Services upgraded the country's long-term foreign currency loan to Ba2 from Ba3, while the Standard and Poor's Ratings Group improved its rating to BB from BB minus.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
