<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="281838" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</title>
<headline>S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trade on South Africa's currency market ground to a halt on Tuesday, belying the events of the past 12 months which saw nearly 30 percent eroded from the rand's value against the dollar.</p>
<p>The rand finished the year at 4.6800/6850 against the greenback compared with a 4.6765/6815 finish on Monday in trade described by dealers as desperately quiet with absolutely no interest from anywhere.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a small bit of importer demand but that was about it,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;It has been very, very quiet.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected activity to pick up again next week when players returned from their Christmas breaks, with some predicting further weakness as January was traditionally a month in which the currency weakened.</p>
<p>Bond traders have also talked of rumours that the currency will come under renewed speculative attack in the new year with most European players having left for their Christmas vacations with square positions.</p>
<p>During 1996, repeated speculative attacks pummelled the currency more than 100 cents or 29 percent weaker against the dollar from 3.6450 at the start of the year.</p>
<p>Most economists expect the currency to weaken to 4.92 in the year ahead, according to a recent Reuters poll.</p>
<p>Against the crosses, the rand set yet another record low against sterling, finishing at 7.9349/9481 as cable continued its resurgence to levels last seen when the British pound was jettisoned from the European exchange rate mechanism in September 1992.</p>
<p>The rand was little changed against the German currency at 0.3317/3323 marks.</p>
<p>On the bond market, yields drifted sideways all morning in trade described by dealers as a non-event.</p>
<p>The key R150 was last at 16.095 percent from 16.09 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market would look to the release of November money supply and private sector credit extension data due out at 1500 GMT on Thursday for direction.</p>
<p>A Reuters consensus poll of economists forecast money supply growth would dip to 15.5 percent in November from a preliminary 15.96 percent in October, while the closely watched private sector credit extension growth was expected to slow to an 18.2 percent rise from 18.86 percent in the previous month.</p>
<p>&quot;Things may pick up on Thursday when the credit numbers come out but my feeling is that the market will only get going again next week when people start coming back from leave,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>On the money market three-month NCD rates were steady at between 17.40 and 17.75 percent while the 90-day BA rate was also unchanged at 16.70 to 17.00 percent.</p>
<p>The money market shortage stood at 10.737 billion rand on Monday from 11.117 billion rand on Saturday. On Friday it rose to a record high of 11.126 billion rand.</p>
<p>Bond Exchange statistics showed foreigners bought a net 128.06 million rand's worth of South African bonds on Monday after buying 12.70 million rand's worth last Tuesday.</p>
<p>Nominal cumulative turnover was 35.03 billion rand on Monday from 424 million rand last Tuesday. A Bond Exchange spokesman said that of Monday's trades it was estimated that 88 percent were repurchase transactions.</p>
<p>-- Paul Richardson, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
