<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="281844" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Dec 31.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Dec 31.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Kenyan press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY NATION</p>
<p>- Kenyans have until January 31, 1997 to acquire so-called second generation national identity cards.</p>
<p>- The latest oil exploration data on the potential of Kenya becoming a petroleum producing country indicates a positive outcome although commercially viable deposits that can be exploited remain elusive.</p>
<p>- 96 remand prisoners facing capital offences boycott Nairobi High Court proceedings for the third time on Monday, complaining that they are not fed whenever they attend court.</p>
<p>-EAST AFRICAN STANDARD</p>
<p>- In a major political about-turn, Opposition leaders Kenneth Matiba and Raila Odinga call for a government of national unity.</p>
<p>- C.A. Omollo becomes Kenya's first woman district commissioner.</p>
<p>- Kenya Posts and Telecommunications Corporation reduces its international telephone and fascimile tariffs by up to 33 percent from January 1, 1997.</p>
<p>KENYA TIMES</p>
<p>- Kipruto Kirwa, a member of parliament for Cherangani in the Rift Valley, apologises to President Daniel arap Moi for his past utterances which were disrespectful to the president.</p>
<p>- Kenyan police arrest a notorious gangster who they say has been terrorising motorists along the Nairobi-Mombasa highway.</p>
<p>- The government and non-governmetal organisations are urged to come to the rescue of drought-stricken residents in North Eastern province.</p>
<p>($1=55 shillings).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
