<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="281897" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Dec 31.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Dec 31.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Tuesday's Albanian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>KOHA JONE</p>
<p>- Newspaper editorial says pyramid schemes, Kosovo issue and presidential elections will be the main features of 1997.</p>
<p>- The year 1997 will be more expensive than 1996 for Albanians following an approximate price rise of 20 percent over the past year.</p>
<p>- Ibrahim Rugova, self-declared president of the ethnic Albanians of the Serbian province of Kosovo, is in conflict with Albanian authorities over many issues relating to the Kosovo question.</p>
<p>- Right-wing National Front party and the monarchic Legality Movement have formed an alliance.</p>
<p>- Albania's opposition Socialist Party rejected a pardon by conservative President Sali Berisha which reduced the jail term of their leader Fatos Nano by six months.</p>
<p>- Berisha issued a decree on Sunday pardoning or reducing the jail sentences of 102 prisoners.</p>
<p>- The appeals court turned down a request to change the detention conditions of Klement Kolaneci, son-in-law of the late communist leader Enver Hoxha, who was arrested last October in connection with a guerrilla group.</p>
<p>- Halit Shamata, interior minister, said on Sunday state- organised structures must fight organised crime, guerrilla activities, drug trafficking, illegal immigration, fraud, and smuggling.</p>
<p>GAZETA SHQIPTARE</p>
<p>- Gjallica, a pyramid scheme company, temporarily stopped giving returns and started investigating two of its staff for suspected embezzlement.</p>
<p>- Bledar Xhuli, an Albanian immigrant in Italy, was declared the man of the year in Milan by the Vatican newspaper Avvenire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
