<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="281956" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: &quot;Doors open&quot; for government mediator - Peru rebels.</title>
<headline>&quot;Doors open&quot; for government mediator - Peru rebels.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leader of Peruvian rebels holding 83 VIP hostages at the Japanese ambassador's residence told journalists on Tuesday the group was ready to receive government negotiator, Education Minister Domingo Palermo, for further talks.</p>
<p>&quot;The doors of the residence are open for them (Palermo and observer Bishop Juan Luis Cipriani) to come in,&quot; Nestor Cerpa Cartolini said on local radio from inside the building.  </p>
<p>In one of several meetings held with journalists inside the building on Tuesday, Cerpa said he wanted to reach an &quot;integrated solution&quot; to the crisis that began two weeks ago.</p>
<p>The leader of the 20 heavily-armed Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels made his statements on radio in a barely audible walkie-talkie communication.</p>
<p>After an agreement between the government and the rebels, the Red Cross, who had been mediating in the crisis, temporarily withdrew from the site to allow the approach of journalists to the compound. It was not clear if Cerpa's meetings with the world's media were part of the agreement.</p>
<p>Palermo has met Cerpa once during the crisis. Immeditaely following his conversation inside the residence on Saturday with the rebel leader, the MRTA freed 20 hostages.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
