<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="281954" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: MRTA leader says inflexible on original demand.</title>
<headline>MRTA leader says inflexible on original demand.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leader of Marxist guerrillas holding more than 80 hostages inside the Japanese ambassador's residence in Lima on Tuesday said the rebels were not prepared to relax their original demand for the release of roughly 400 rebels jailed in Peru.</p>
<p>&quot;We are inflexible in our original position,&quot; Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) leader Nestor Cerpa Cartolini said in a brief interview with Reuters via walkie-talkie from inside the residence.  </p>
<p>Cerpa added that the MRTA had already achieved its aim of drawing world attention to the bad conditions of Peruvian jails, and would now concentrate on pressuring for the release of its prisoners.</p>
<p>He said responsibility for resolving the crisis lay with the government. &quot;(President Alberto) Fujimori's speech is the only thing we have heard. There has been no opening up. This is now in the hands of the government. The government must reflect. This is not in our hands,&quot; Cerpa said.</p>
<p>In his only public speech since the crisis began two weeks ago, Fujimori said he would only rule out force if the rebels laid down their arms and released all hostages.</p>
<p>The guerrillas still held 83 hostages Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
