<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282058" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Panel to review Taiwan petrol price hike proposal.</title>
<headline>Panel to review Taiwan petrol price hike proposal.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's economic ministry said a special panel would review on Tuesday a request by state-owned monopoly Chinese Petroleum Corp to raise petrol prices by what local media said could be as much as 10 percent.</p>
<p>A ministry official reached by telephone said the committee would meet at 0600 GMT on Tuesday to review the inflationary effect of any increase.</p>
<p>A decision on whether the ministry should allow prices to rise and by how much could come before the end of the day, the official said without further comment. The economics ministry oversees the state monopoly's operations.  </p>
<p>Chinese Petroleum has refused to confirm Taiwan media reports that the monopoly had applied to boost petrol prices by 8-10 percent to alleviate its growing operating shortfalls.</p>
<p>Chinese Petroleum has reported a November pre-tax loss of T$1.29 billion (US$41 million) and a cumulative budget deficit of T$8.126 billion for the July-November period.</p>
<p>The state monopoly has blamed the deficit mainly on world oil prices that were far higher than expected.</p>
<p>Sources at the oil company said the &quot;most likely&quot; result would be a compromise eight percent increase that would boost revenues but with less inflationary impact than a larger rise.  </p>
<p>Government and private economists say a 10 percent rise in petrol prices would add 0.43 percentage points to the consumer price index in the month in which it takes effect. The wholesale price index would jump 0.53 percentage points, they estimate.</p>
<p>Taiwan consumer prices rose a year-on-year 3.19 percent in November, while wholesale prices fell an annual 3.02 percent, continuing a downward trend seen in recent months.</p>
<p>Chinese Petroleum needs state approval for monthly price adjustments that exceed three percent.</p>
<p>With the necessary approval, a price increase could take effect on January 1, a Chinese Petroleum official said.  </p>
<p>Chinese Petroleum's 95-octane petrol now sells for T$16.7 per litre (US$2.29 per gallon) at filling stations, including a T$0.2 per litre air-pollution surcharge.</p>
<p>Chinese Petroleum imported 12.8 million barrels of crude in November, bringing its cumulative total since the July 1 fiscal year start to 91.7 million barrels, company figures show.</p>
<p>Taiwan, almost totally dependent on foreign crude, imports more than 150 million barrels a year.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (2-508-0815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
