<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28207" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Korean prosecutors seek heavier punishment for Roh.</title>
<headline>Korean prosecutors seek heavier punishment for Roh.</headline>
<byline>Yeom Yoon-jeong</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean prosecutors on Monday challenged as too lenient a 22-1/2 year jail term on former President Roh Tae-woo, appealing instead for the life sentence they originally sought.</p>
<p>Roh was sentenced last Monday for his part in a 1979 coup and a 1980 army massacre in the southern city of Kwangju that crushed democratic resistance.</p>
<p>His predecessor, Chun Doo Hwan, was sentenced to death for masterminding the putsch and ordering the assault on Kwangju, in which 200 people were killed by official count.</p>
<p>Apart from appealing against Roh's sentence, prosecutors will fight to increase sentences imposed on 13 former generals and appeal against the acquittal of another general, an official at the Seoul prosecutors office said.</p>
<p>They also want to increase jail sentences handed to nine former presidential aides.</p>
<p>No challenge however will be made against sentences on nine businessmen. In passing judgement on the tycoons, the official said, &quot;our demands were met to some extent&quot;.</p>
<p>Prosecutors had seven days to appeal last Monday's court sentences.</p>
<p>The one-time generals were handed jail terms of between four and 10 years, whereas prosecutors asked for between 10 years and life. The maximum jail sentence handed the aides was 14 years for Roh's bodyguard Lee Hyon-woo.</p>
<p>Four of the tycoons received jail terms of up to 2-1/2 years. Daewoo Group chairman Kim Woo-choong got two years. Five others, including Samsung Group chairman Lee Kun-hee who decided on Monday not to appeal, were given suspended sentences.</p>
<p>On Saturday, lawyers for both Chun and Roh submitted appeals against their sentences.</p>
<p>Chun kept Koreans guessing for days about whether he intended to go meekly to the gallows. In the end, he said he had to defend the truth about his administration.</p>
<p>The three-judge panel said Roh was spared the death sentence because of his role in returning democracy to South Korea and in recognition of his diplomatic triumphs while in office.</p>
<p>Roh became the first democratically-elected president in more than three decades in 1988 after refusing to be rubber-stamped in office by Chun.</p>
<p>During his presidency, which lasted until 1993, Seoul scored a series of impressive diplomatic breakthroughs, gaining entry to the United Nations and reaching out to China and the former Soviet bloc countries.</p>
<p>The domestic Yonhap news agency quoted prosecutors as saying they were unappy with the outcome of what was dubbed the &quot;trial of the century&quot;. If they did not appeal, the defendents could end up with even lower sentences.</p>
<p>President Kim Young-sam is widely expected to offer his predecessors a pardon if their appeals fail. The cases could reach the Supreme Court and the whole legal process may drag out for up to eight months.</p>
<p>Death sentences are rarely carried out in South Korea. But if Chun were to hang, it could cost Kim the support of a large number of voters in his home province.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
