<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282021" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia storm caused $52 million in damage.</title>
<headline>Malaysia storm caused $52 million in damage.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>A tropical storm that lashed the eastern Malaysian state of Sabah over Christmas caused about 130 million ringgit ($52 million) damage to government property and infrastructure, the state chief minister said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The damaged government property belongs to the state and federal governments, such as buildings, roads, bridges, water treatment plants, schools and clinics,&quot; Yong Teck Lee was quoted as saying by the national Bernama news agency.</p>
<p>He said the damage caused by the storm would be far higher if the losses suffered by individuals and the private sector as well as economic losses were taken into account.</p>
<p>Eleven 11 bridges were either washed away or damaged in the logging town of Keningau, the worst affected area, Yong said.</p>
<p>Tropical storm Greg, which blew ashore into Sabah state from the South China Sea at 70 kph (44 mph) on Christmas Day, triggered heavy rains and floods which swelled rivers to overflowing, downed power lines and washed out roads and communications links.</p>
<p>The death toll from the storm rose to 170 on Tuesday with more than 100 believed to be still missing, Bernama quoted officials as saying.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
