<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282065" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>TUNISIA: Tunisian opposition leader gets out of prison.</title>
<headline>Tunisian opposition leader gets out of prison.</headline>
<dateline>TUNIS 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Tunisian opposition leader who was let out of prison said on Tuesday he was freed for health reasons and that his release was conditional.</p>
<p>Opposition leaders Khemais Chammari and Mohamed Moada were released on Monday, two weeks after a Tunisian human rights activist and a leftwing opponent of the government were freed.</p>
<p>Moada, former president of the main Tunisian opposition party Movement of Social Democrats (MDS), was arrested in October 1995 and later given a 11-year jail term on charges of having secret contacts with Libyan agents.</p>
<p>Chammari, 55, a vice-president of MDS and former member of parliament, was arrested in May 1996 and sentenced last July to five years in jail for disclosing secrets of judicial proceedings in Moada's case.</p>
<p>Speaking by telephone from his house, Chammari said he only learned of his impending freedom about an hour before he actually got home.</p>
<p>&quot;I was freed for health reasons...I was told that my release was conditional and lectured over what that means in the Tunisian law,&quot; he said without elaborating.</p>
<p>He said he felt well, however, and was a little tired.</p>
<p>Under Tunisian law a conditional release means political activities are not allowed.</p>
<p>Judicial sources had said the two men were released for &quot;humanitarian reasons&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;This is very positive, one can't end the year better than this way,&quot; a European diplomat commented.</p>
<p>The Tunisian League for the Defence of Human Rights (LTDH) welcomed the releases, saying they were &quot;highly positive&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;LTDH hopes that the decision added to the last political measures announced by the head of the state...were part of the (process of) realisation and strengthening of human rights and democracy in the country.&quot;</p>
<p>An opposition leader also welcomed the releases and a speech by President Zine al-Abidine Ben Ali on Saturday in which he promised to amend the electoral code to allow more seats to the opposition parties in parliament and municipalities, which are overwhemingly dominated by the ruling party.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a pretty gift for the end of the year. The gesture must be appreciated by all democrats. It will contribute to easing the political life,&quot; Mohamed Belhaj Amor, president of the opposition Parti de l'Unite Populaire (PUP) told Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TUNIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TUNIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TUNISIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
