<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282196" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</title>
<headline>Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain and oilseed exports reported by USDA and private export sources.</p>
<p>WHEAT SALE - Morocco has bought 20,000 tonnes of North American durum wheat for delivery in early February at around $229 a tonne, grain traders said on Tuesday. The durum is likely to come from Canada, they said.</p>
<p>RICE SALE - The state-run Rice Export Corporation of Pakistan said on Tuesday it had accepted the lowest bid at $238 per tonne CIF for the sale of 42,016 tonnes of IRRI-6 variety rice. The corporation had received 10 bids, including the lowest at $238 and the highest at $360 per tonne CIF.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDERS - Pakistan will tender in mid-January for 315,000 tonnes U.S. and/or Australian wheat for February shipment, U.S. exporters said. Several exporters said the shipment was slated for February and that Pakistan would be looking at both U.S. and Australian wheat. Bids will be opened on January 12, Pakistan's export agent said.  </p>
<p>- Sri Lanka's state buying arm the Co-operative Wholesale Establishment seeks 100,000 tonnes of soft and hard wheat, government officials said. The tender closes January 3 and is for 50,000 of soft wheat for delivery in the third week of January and 50,000 tonnes of hard wheat for delivery in the second week of February.</p>
<p>- The Commodity Credit Corp said it seeks  up to 30,000 tonnes of U.S. No. 2 or better hard red winter wheat for donation to Bosnia. Shipment is for January 25-February 20. Offers are due January 7.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDERS - Bangladesh seeks 100,000 tonnes of U.S. No.2 wheat or Australian Standard or better Canadian winter red/spring wheat for shipment by February 21, food ministry officials said. Offers are to be opened January 18 and the results announced two to three days later.  </p>
<p>- Yemen postponed until January 7 soft wheat and soft wheat flour tenders initially scheduled for December 26, European grain traders said. Yemen seeks 200,000 tonnes of optional soft wheat flour for shipment between February and June and 200,000 tonnes of new crop U.S. or Canadian or Australian soft white wheat for July-September, they said.</p>
<p>SOYBEAN OIL TENDER - The CCC is to tender for 10,370 tonnes of U.S. bulk crude degummed soybean oil for donation to Peru. Delivery was for February 3-18. Offers were requested by January 7. Successful offerers will be notified January 8.  </p>
<p>MARKET TALK - U.S. exporters could not confirm market talk that Brazil was seeking 500,000 tonnes of Argentine wheat for February/March delivery, although several exporters did not rule out the possibility of such a purchase.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be pretty hard to get any confirmation today (Tuesday) because of the (New Year's) holiday. But I would not be surprised if it gets done,&quot; one U.S. exporter said.</p>
<p>Wheat futures on the Chicago Board of Trade and the Kansas City Board of Trade firmed in abbreviated holiday sessions, supported partly by the Brazilian rumors.</p>
<p>((Doris Frankel 312-408-8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
