<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282245" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cotton meeting to stress technology, global market.</title>
<headline>Cotton meeting to stress technology, global market.</headline>
<byline>Suzanne Rostler</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>After a year in which U.S cotton producers saw export business stagger as output soared, the National Cotton Council will address the changing world market in its upcoming annual conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Competitive in Every Quarter,&quot; is the theme of this year's annual Beltwide Cotton Conferences, held Jan 7-10 in New Orleans.  </p>
<p>More than 5,000 industry members, including growers, exporters, textile manufacturers and agronomists, will hear speeches ranging from how to manage price risks to what is new in biotechnology.</p>
<p>On Tuesday next week, leading cotton merchant William B. Dunavant Jr., chairman of Memphis-based Dunavant Enterprises Inc, will give a price outlook and discuss exports and mill use for the coming year.  </p>
<p>National Cotton Council president Tom Smith will highlight some of the challenges facing the U.S. cotton industry in the coming year under new farm legislation, while NCC economist Mark Lange will discuss cotton and synthetic fibers.</p>
<p>The conference will also spotlight new technology, from genetically-engineered &quot;Bt&quot; cotton to an online network that will help producers manage price risk.</p>
<p>The network will give growers the latest information on crop prices and futures markets, including price charting software, in which farmers can run scenarios based on past prices and trends.</p>
<p>&quot;It has always been important for growers to incorporate the latest technology, but it will become more important to the industry as government support diminishes,&quot; Cotton Nelson, a spokesman with NCC, said in reference to the new farm legislation.</p>
<p>A cotton economics and marketing session will be held on Thursday, when the U.S. Department of Agriculture will give an outlook for U.S. and world cotton.</p>
<p>((-- New York Commodities Desk, 212-859-1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100138">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
