<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282482" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Israel president ill at India banquet but improves.</title>
<headline>Israel president ill at India banquet but improves.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-12-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Visiting Israeli President Ezer Weizman was taken ill during a state banquet in New Delhi on Monday and retired hurriedly to his room at the Presidential Palace, witnesses said.</p>
<p>A member of the Israeli media delegation present at the banquet hosted by Indian President Shankar Dayal Sharma quoted Israeli officials as saying later that the 72-year-old former air force chief had recovered well after the sudden illness.</p>
<p>&quot;The president vomited twice and was escorted quickly to his room,&quot; the media representative, who declined to be named, said.</p>
<p>Weizman looked cheerful and cracked jokes during a news conference earlier on Monday.</p>
<p>But he did show the odd memory lapse, on one occasion speaking of Lebanon when he meant to give his comments on Hebron.</p>
<p>Earlier on Monday, Weizman finished his walk past a guard of honour at the Presidential Palace but then walked back half the distance to resume the drill for a second time.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
