<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282574" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Sydney set to welcome 1997 with massive fireworks.</title>
<headline>Sydney set to welcome 1997 with massive fireworks.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sydney will explode into a kaleidoscope of colour on New Year's Eve when some 5,000 tonnes of fireworks explode over the city in what organisers say is a dress rehearsal for the year 2000 and the Sydney Olympics.</p>
<p>A total of 16,654 fireworks will be fired from 25 locations around the city, covering an area the size of 7,000 football fields, enabling the pyrotechnics to be seen as far away as the Blue Mountains, some 50 km (31 miles) west of the city.</p>
<p>The 40-minute lightshow will be the largest ever fireworks display over Sydney and will cost A$1.0 million (US$790,000).</p>
<p>Organisers expect more than one million people to crowd Sydney Harbour foreshores to watch the Sydney Harbour Bridge turn into a cascading waterfall and a harbour ballet involving 50 tugs and boats set to a musical symphony.</p>
<p>There will also be a masked party at the Sydney Opera House, with masks in the shape of the &quot;sails&quot; of the opera house supplied by local newspapers.</p>
<p>The &quot;Mask a Sydney Face&quot; theme party was introduced this year to give New Year's Eve in Sydney a unique characteristic for when the city celebrates the year 2000 and the Sydney Olympics, the city mayor Frank Sartor said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to show off the best face of Sydney as the first major world city to cross the dateline, especially in the lead-up to the Olympics Games in 2000,&quot; said Sartor. &quot;From now on, masks will be essential wear for New Year's Eve revellers.&quot;</p>
<p>Sydney 2000 Olympics opening and closing ceremonies director Ric Birch will produce the New Year's Eve show.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
