<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282504" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Circus Circus unveils plan for new resort.</title>
<headline>Circus Circus unveils plan for new resort.</headline>
<dateline>LAS VEGAS 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Circus Circus Enterprises Inc. unveiled plans Tuesday to build a 4,000-room resort casino modelled on a South Sea island in Las Vegas, starting with the planned destruction of the Hacienda Hotel on New Year's Eve.</p>
<p>The Hacienda, which is to be blown up on national television, sits on the site along Vegas' famed &quot;Strip&quot; where the resort for upscale tourists and high-rolling gamblers that is code-named Project Paradise will be built.</p>
<p>The resort will attempt to recreate a South Seas island and will include jungle foliage, waterfalls and terraced gardens, the Las Vegas-based company said in a statement.</p>
<p>At its centre will be a wave-washed beach, reef and tropical fish among which visitors can snorkle. Next to that will be a shark-filled tank they can swim by.</p>
<p>Construction is slated to start in February and end in fall of 1998, said Circus Circus, a major U.S. gambling company.</p>
<p>Circus Circus declined to give a cost estimate for the project, saying a final budget will be announced in the next few months.</p>
<p>Financial analysts and published reports have put the cost anywhere between $700 million and $1 billion. Company executives were not immediately available to comment.</p>
<p>The project will be financed through cash flow and bank lines of credit, the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>The company owns and operates 10 properties in Nevada, including the themed Circus Circus, Excalibur and Luxor hotels and casinos in Las Vegas.</p>
<p>Circus Circus stock dropped 37.5 cents to $34.375 in afternoon trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS VEGAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
