<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28258" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila peace pact seen ushering in new prosperity.</title>
<headline>Manila peace pact seen ushering in new prosperity.</headline>
<byline>Alistair McIntosh</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Moslem rebels and the Philippine government signed a peace pact on Monday ending 24 years of war in the south that killed 125,000 people and ushering in what President Fidel Ramos said could be unprecedented prosperity.</p>
<p>The president said the pact, which took four years to negotiate with the aid of Moslem nations led by Indonesia, was being signed two days after the Philippines announced its strongest economic growth figures in six years.</p>
<p>&quot;We can now strive for higher economic growth never heretofore anticipated or imagined by our economic planners,&quot; Ramos said in a speech at a glittering ceremony in the presidential palace.</p>
<p>Rebel leader Nur Misuari had earlier led a standing ovation for Ramos, praising his &quot;boldness and heroism&quot; in pushing ahead with the accord despite bitter opposition from Christian groups in the southern Philippines.</p>
<p>But he also warned that failure to translate the accord into genuine development could bring new fighting to the region that has known little else for 400 years.</p>
<p>&quot;Failure has the habit of instinctively unleashing the fury of war... How many times have we seen the monster get loose and unchained?&quot; said the former university professor who now leads the Moro National Liberation Front (MNLF).</p>
<p>He said the pact ended a war that began in 1972 when Moslems believed they faced a &quot;campaign of genocide and extermination&quot; by the government of then president Ferdinand Marcos.</p>
<p>Ramos has said he takes personal responsibility for the success of the Southern Philippines Council for Peace and Development, which will be set up under the pact as a prelude to an autonomous regional government covering almost all of the main southern island of Mindanao and nearby islands.</p>
<p>Moslem nations which helped broker the accord have also pledged investment funds to promote development of the region that, although fertile and rich in minerals, remains the country's poorest area.</p>
<p>The Philippines' five million Moslems regard the south as their ancestral homeland although they are outnumbered by some 15 million Christians.</p>
<p>Christian opponents of the pact staged protests in several parts of the south on Monday, with a noisy barrage in the city of Zamboanga and a Philippine flag being flown at halfmast in the city of Iligan.</p>
<p>&quot;Here there is only mourning, cries of sorrow not joy. Look at our flag, this is a symbol of mourning because democracy has died,&quot; city councillor Lawrence Cruz, one of the leaders of the Iligan protest, told reporters.</p>
<p>The pact was also signed by chief government negotiator Manuel Yan, Indonesian Foreign Minister Ali Alatas and Hamid Algabid, secretary general of the Organisation of the Islamic Conference.</p>
<p>&quot;This is indeed a historic moment for the Filipino nation. It is also a great day for all the peoples of Southeast Asia and for a world yearning for peace,&quot; Alatas said in a speech.</p>
<p>After the signing, Misuari told a news conference he would encourage other Moslem rebel groups to help make the pact work and had maintained contacts with the MNLF's main rival, the Moro Islamic Liberation front.</p>
<p>&quot;The only problem I have is with this Abu Sayyaf group,&quot; he said, referring to an extremist group blamed for a series of murders, bombings and kidnappings in the south in recent years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
