<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282573" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Traders see 97/98 Australia wheat price down.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Traders see 97/98 Australia wheat price down.</headline>
<byline>James Regan</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>A looming supply overhang of wheat due to Australia's 1996/97 bumper crop could result in a decline in the Australian Wheat Board's (AWB) first pool estimate price for 1997/98, grains traders said on Tuesday</p>
<p>The AWB's current pool price of A$185 a tonne is based on an estimated harvest of 21.5 million tonnes, the second largest ever for Australia.</p>
<p>An AWB spokesman said it will be early February before it announces its first pool estimate price for the 1997/98 harvest.  </p>
<p>&quot;At that time, we'll indicate what carry over we'll have, if any ... the sort of crop size we are anticipating,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The value of the Australian dollar agains the United States currency also will help determine the price, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We put all those factors together,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>However, traders said that despite continuing export business, the size of the current crop would weigh on prices.</p>
<p>&quot;We think the next pool that is opened up will be A$15 to A$20 (a tonne) lower for ASW (Australian Standard White) at around A$165,&quot; one said.  </p>
<p>The traders estimate that so far about 50 percent of 1996/97 exports have been sold.</p>
<p>The Australian Bureau of Agricultural and Resource Economics sees Australian wheat exports at 13.34 million tonnes in 1996/97 versus 12.06 million tonnes in 1995/96.</p>
<p>&quot;There are still a lot of exports going through,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>&quot;Shipments from Australia are very tight until the end of January.&quot;  </p>
<p>This is being underscored by a slight premium on wheat futures over physical shipments, delivered to the port of Newcastle in New South Wales State, another trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;If you want to deliver wheat to Newcastle, you'll have difficulty booking freight unless you drive it there yourself,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>Nearby January wheat futures on the Sydney Futures Exchange (SFE) overnight screen trading system, SYCOM, were quoted at A$162.50 a tonne. Floor trading of wheat futures is scheduled to resume at the SFE on January 2, 1997.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
