<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282558" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-AWF raises Australia wheat f'cast to 21.37 mt.</title>
<headline>RTRS-AWF raises Australia wheat f'cast to 21.37 mt.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Wheat Forecasters Pty Ltd (AWF) further raised its forecast for Australia's 1996/97 wheat crop by 90,000 tonnes to 21.37 million tonnes on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The private forecaster's estimate, its tenth for the April-March season, compared with its previous forecast, issued early this month, of 21.28 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The forecast is in line with the latest estimates of 21.5 million tonnes from the Australian Wheat Board (AWB) and 21.3 million tonnes from the Australian Bureau of Agricultural and Resource Economics.  </p>
<p>AWF said Australia's wheat harvest was not yet complete in the south but, with a continuation of fine weather, most of the harvest will be finished within the next two weeks</p>
<p>Given the size of the crop, the quality is exceptionally good. Where there are quality problems, they relate to small grain size or, in southern areas, low protein.</p>
<p>Despite these problems, the wheat is sound and will be readily saleable, it said.</p>
<p>Because of the high quality of the wheat and the depressed state of the cattle feedlot industry, growers have perceived little benefit from storing grain.  </p>
<p>As a result, a higher proportion of the harvest has been delivered to the AWB and less stored for domestic trading later in the year, AWF said.</p>
<p>&quot;This aspect is important because it is unlikely that the present harvest will exceed the record harvest of just over 22 million tonnes in season 1983/84,&quot; AWF said.</p>
<p>Growers generally deliver more to the AWB in large crop years and more so when the quality is good, it said.</p>
<p>AWF said the Queensland harvest finished some time ago. The early harvested grain had some weather damage but this has already been absorbed by the local stockfeed industry.  </p>
<p>In New South Wales (NSW), there were some quality problems in the northwest following late frosts but of the seven million tonnes-plus harvest, less than a million tonnes had been received into categories lower than Australian Standard White.</p>
<p>Yields in the southeast of NSW have been high, AWF said.</p>
<p>Victorian yields have been very favourable despite an early finish to the season. Grain protein was helped by generous applications of fertiliser both before and after sowing.</p>
<p>A rain on Christmas Eve was followed by drying conditions on Christmas Day and no weather damage was reported.  </p>
<p>South Australia had a season of exceptional quality. The strategy of South Australia lifting grain protein over a period of years was complemented by the hard finish that the crops received this season.</p>
<p>Western Australia had a good spread of qualities this season. Early northern deliveries had problems with high percentages of screenings.</p>
<p>But there were also some segregations of high protein.</p>
<p>A late season in the south meant high yields and some grain protein below nine percent, AWF said.  </p>
<p>AWF's state crop forecasts, in million tonnes, and area estimates, in million hectares, are as follows-</p>
<p>			    Crop			    Area</p>
<p>		 1996/97 Prev f'cast   1995/96     1996/97  1995/96</p>
<p>Queensland    2.13	2.20	  0.58	  0.95     0.73</p>
<p>NSW	     7.20	7.15	  4.73	  2.90     2.45</p>
<p>Victoria	2.52	2.46	  2.08	  1.08     0.95</p>
<p>S. Australia  2.72	2.72	  2.97	  1.55     1.63</p>
<p>W. Australia  6.80	6.75	  7.42	  4.25     4.17</p>
<p>TOTAL	  21.37     21.28	 17.78	 10.73     9.93</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
