<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282623" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Villagers clash with police over Hanoi golf course.</title>
<headline>Villagers clash with police over Hanoi golf course.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of villagers clashed with police on the northern edge of Hanoi this week as authorities moved to reclaim farmland earmarked for a luxury golf course, local residents said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said some 600 police officers, many carrying riot shields and wielding electric prods, fought a pitched battle with protesters on a dirt track in Kim No commune, near the Vietnamese capital's airport, on Monday.</p>
<p>The protesters, estimated to number 500, hurled stones at the police and set two bulldozers and another vehicle on fire.</p>
<p>It was not clear how many were hurt in the violence, though one resident said he saw at least five injured people being taken away.</p>
<p>An official at the Kim No People's Committee said authorities were still trying to persuade people to give up their land but denied that any violence had occurred.</p>
<p>A Reuters correspondent watched on Tuesday as about 60 people from the commune's Tho Da hamlet surrounded a truck on the same dirt track, hauled its driver and passenger out and torched the vehicle.</p>
<p>Two other trucks, which local residents said had come to erect fencing, turned around and raced back down the track as smoke billowed from the first.</p>
<p>Riots and demonstrations are rare in communist Vietnam and almost never reported by the state-controlled media.</p>
<p>However, this was not the first unrest at Kim No commune. One woman was killed and scores were injured there last May in violence which erupted when police began ripping up rice plants from a field being appropriated for the golf course.</p>
<p>Three men and one woman were sentenced last month to prison terms of between three and five years for their involvement in that incident.</p>
<p>The planned golf course is part of a $177 million joint-venture project involving South Korea's Daewoo Group, the biggest single foreign investor in Vietnam. A senior official from the joint venture declined to comment on the land dispute.</p>
<p>The official Hanoi Moi daily said the villagers had agreed to vacate their land by December 30 and praised them for demonstrating their district's traditional revolutionary fervour.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
