<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282792" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam booms again in 1996, but problems remain.</title>
<headline>Vietnam booms again in 1996, but problems remain.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam said on Tuesday that it enjoyed another year of rapid economic expansion, but tempered celebration with an assessment of problems that could stymie growth in the future.</p>
<p>The government's General Statistics Office said in a statement that gross domestic product (GDP) grew 9.34 percent from 1995, while industrial output increased 14.1 percent.</p>
<p>This year's GDP growth rate was just below last year's rate of 9.5 percent and compared with average growth of 8.2 percent during 1991-95, when market-style reforms began to bite.</p>
<p>However, the statistics office sounded a warning on the country's trade deficit, which this year widened to a record $4 billion from $2.2 billion in 1995 because of a surge in imports.</p>
<p>It said there had been mismanagement of imports, which had caused competition problems for local industry, and warned against moves to counter the trade imbalance by seeking to substitute imports rather than develop export-oriented industry.</p>
<p>&quot;If these things are not overcome in time, that will counter the open-door policy, slow down economic growth and cause greater pressure on the balance of payments,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>That was the view expressed in a United Nations report last month, which argued against restricting imports and in favour of more fundamental reform of the country's trade regime.</p>
<p>The statistics office said the budget deficit was still at a serious level despite an increase in revenues and said disbursement of aid from foreign donors was still slow.</p>
<p>It also gave a list of problems now plaguing the country's sprawling, often loss-making state sector, including competition from smuggled goods, imports paid for by letters of credit and foreign-invested companies.</p>
<p>According to local media reports, more than half of 4,000 local-level state-owned enterprises are unprofitable and thousands are short of cash.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
