<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282728" id="root" date="1996-12-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: PRESS DIGEST - Lebanon -  Dec 31.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Lebanon -  Dec 31.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-12-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Beirut press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AN-NAHAR</p>
<p>-The conspiracy on state security is reduced to charging a Lebanese journalist with having contacts with Israel and distributing leaflets that incite military disobedience.</p>
<p>AS-SAFIR</p>
<p>-Syrian Vice-President Khaddam: &quot;We are awaiting a commitment from the United States to the guarantees it gave us on the issue of an Israeli pullout to the June 4, 1967 borders&quot;.</p>
<p>-Authorities are interrogating four suspects in the case of the attack on a bus carrying Syrian passengers in Tabaraja earlier this month.</p>
<p>-The Beirut Stock Exchange delists 38 companies that have not met listing requirements by December 21.</p>
<p>AL-ANWAR</p>
<p>-Parliament Speaker Berri says Egyptian President Mubarak has informed him of his refusal to deploy Arab forces in south Lebanon.</p>
<p>-General Lahd, the commander of Israel's client South Lebanon Army militia, is in France on a long vacation.</p>
<p>AD-DIYAR</p>
<p>-The ministry for displaced people says that 40 percent of the hundreds of thousands of war displaced have already returned to their original homes.</p>
<p>NIDA'A AL-WATAN</p>
<p>-Sheikh Fadlallah, the spiritual leader of Lebanon's pro-Iranian Shi'ite Moslem fundamentalists, says that the United States is pressuring Lebanon and Syria.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
