<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282826" id="root" date="1997-01-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: CRICKET-SORRY ENGLAND CRASH TO SERIES DEFEAT.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-SORRY ENGLAND CRASH TO SERIES DEFEAT.</headline>
<byline>Andy Capostagno</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-01-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwe achieved their first one-day international series victory over any opposition on Wednesday as England again failed to deliver in front of a delirious crowd at the Harare Sports Club.</p>
<p>Chasing a revised victory target of 185 in 42 overs after rain delayed the start of their innings, England finished on 179 for seven to give the home side an unbeatable 2-0 lead in the best-of-three series.</p>
<p>Leg spinner Paul Strang was the architect of victory, dismissing top scorer John Crawley (73), England skipper Mike Atherton (25) and Ronnie Irani to finish with figures of three for 24.</p>
<p>England collapsed from a comfortable 137 for three in the 34th over to a position where Robert Croft and Darren Gough needed 16 off the last over bowled by John Rennie. Croft edged a boundary off the first ball, but they could only scramble a further six runs from the last five balls.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe won the first one day international in Bulawayo by two wickets and now lead England 4-1 in the history of one-day meetings between the teams. The final match of the series is at the same venue on Friday.</p>
<p>Put into bat, Zimbabwe collapsed to 38 for four and at the end of the innings lost their last three wickets for no runs.</p>
<p>But Andy Flower held the innings together in between with a composed 63 from 114 balls and there was some effective hitting from Craig Evans (32) and Heath Streak (43 not out).</p>
<p>Darren Gough took four for 43 and Alan Mullally three for 29 in an improved England bowling performance, although they conceded 24 extras which were to prove costly.</p>
<p>England got away to a flying start after Nick Knight had gone for a duck, Alec Stewart and Crawley putting on 66 at a rate of seven an over.</p>
<p>Stewart was caught behind for a fluent 41 off 37 balls and Nasser Hussain went for seven, but while Atherton and Crawley were adding 42 for the fourth wicket the game seemed to be England's for the taking.</p>
<p>Strang changed the complexion of the match when he had Atherton caught at long on by a juggling Guy Whittall. The crucial breakthrough came four overs later when Crawley charged and missed and was stumped via an inside edge.</p>
<p>Crawley has been England's most consistent batsman on tour and his 73 from 103 balls included a six and four fours. But his dismissal prompted panic in the England camp and Zimbabwe's fighting spirit was ultimately rewarded.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
