<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="282974" id="root" date="1997-01-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: The Chinese dragon breathes fire.</title>
<headline>The Chinese dragon breathes fire.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Browne</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-01-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>After stirring from a deep slumber, the Chinese dragon breathed fire in 1996, announcing itself as a rising Pacific superpower with military rumblings.</p>
<p>Missiles launched from Chinese shore batteries hurtled close by Taiwan as voters went to the polls. And the highly charged warnings to advocates of independence for the Chinese Nationalist-ruled island echoed through a region jittery about Beijing's ambitions.</p>
<p>The crisis in March was a bad omen for a year that was dominated by prickly national conflicts and that sapped some of the region's economic self-confidence.</p>
<p>Ancient territorial disputes flared again.</p>
<p>Asia's last Cold War-era flashpoint, the Korean peninsula, was brimming with military tension after a North Korean submarine ran aground off a South Korean beach after landing 26 agents.</p>
<p>Several &quot;Tiger&quot; economies, including South Korea and Thailand, ran out of steam. Vietnam turned back the clock on capitalist reforms, even ripping down signs with Western brand names. Japan's recovery proved maddeningly slow.</p>
<p>Famine loomed in North Korea. Its beggar economy shrank for the sixth straight year.</p>
<p>But it was not all bad news. Asia's economies still top world growth charts. Look forward to an upturn in 1997, say regional economists.</p>
<p>CHINESE COLOSSUS LOOMS OVER ASIA</p>
<p>China made the biggest headlines with wargames in the Taiwan Strait. Suddenly, a Chinese colossus loomed over Asia.</p>
<p>Beijing feared Taiwan's first direct presidential elections would lead towards independence for an island it regards as a breakaway province.</p>
<p>As two U.S. aircraft carriers steamed towards Taiwan offering protection, anxious Asians asked if an economically resurgent China would seek to revive its ancient political dominance in the region or opt for common peace and prosperity.</p>
<p>There was no denying China's historic claim to one territory -- Hong Kong, a glittering British-ruled city on its own southern coast.</p>
<p>While Governor Chris Patten prepared to pack his bags and leave Britain's last important colony, a billionaire shipping magnate was elected by a Beijing-appointed panel as the first post-colonial leader.</p>
<p>Tung Chee-hwa, 59, will deliver Hong Kong's six million plus people back to China's embrace at the stroke of midnight on June 30, 1997.</p>
<p>At the bidding of Hong Kong's new communist masters, one of Tung's first duties will be to preside over the scrapping of an elected legislature, which has enraged Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;Compromise is not a weakness,&quot; asserted Tung.</p>
<p>OVER REGIONAL DISPUTES</p>
<p>That message was lost in ugly disputes over rocky island outcrops, for centuries fought over only by nesting seagulls.</p>
<p>South Korean nationalists planted their country's flag on what Seoul calls the Tokto islands and what the Japanese refer to as Takeshima.</p>
<p>Tokyo sent warplanes circling over the specks of wind-swept land as a warning.</p>
<p>Japan also became embroiled in another island row, this time with both China and Taiwan, when a group of right-wingers twisted the dragon's tail by building a symbolic lighthouse on the Diaoyu Islands, known as the Senkakus in Japan.</p>
<p>The publicity was the last thing Tokyo needed as a wary China and nervous Asia looked on at its new willingness to give the United States military backup in the Pacific through an expanded defence treaty.</p>
<p>Domestic politics in Asia -- a bewildering hodge-podge ranging from Stalinism in North Korea to monarchy in Brunei -- were predictably turbulent.</p>
<p>The world's largest democracy, India, went through three prime ministers in three weeks after the corruption-tainted Congress Party of P.V. Narasimha Rao was booted out of office in peaceful elections.</p>
<p>At least 50 people were killed and many more were believed to have died when two bombs exploded on a crowded train in northeastern India in late December.</p>
<p>South Korea, one of Asia's youngest democracies, was turned upside down after President Kim Young-sam vowed to &quot;right the wrongs of history&quot; in a campaign that brought to trial ex-presidents Chun Doo Hwan and Roh Tae-woo.</p>
<p>It was a bad year for Asia's woman politicians. In Pakistan, Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto's government was sacked on disputed charges of corruption and misrule.</p>
<p>Bangladesh's first woman prime minister, Begum Khaleda Zia, was toppled. And Burmese opposition leader Aung San Suu Kyi was briefly under house arrest after another burst of pro-democracy student agitation.</p>
<p>In Sri Lanka, President Chandrika Kumaratunga, daughter of the country's first woman prime minister, Sirima Bandaranaike, failed miserably to quell civil war.</p>
<p>The year offered respite from great natural disasters. But there was tragedy in India when a Saudi Arabian jumbo collided with a Kazakh airliner near New Delhi, killing 349 people in the world's worst mid-air collision.</p>
<p>Australia lost its innocence through violence when Martin Bryant killed 35 people in a shooting rampage in the historic convict site of Port Arthur in Tasmania.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
