<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="283022" id="root" date="1997-01-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli Chamber chief blasts central bank.</title>
<headline>Israeli Chamber chief blasts central bank.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-01-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The high interest rates imposed by the Bank of Israel are responsible for the slowing economy, Danny Gillerman, chairman of the Federation of Israeli Chambers of Commerce, said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He described 1996 as a &quot;lost&quot; year for the economy because of its enormous growth potential at the end of 1995,</p>
<p>The Chamber said the slowdown in economic expansion in 1996 to an estimated 4.4 percent from 7.1 percent in 1995 equalled lost output of seven billion shekels.</p>
<p>But Gillerman said the actual cost was 10 billion shekels or more if the loss was measured against the economy's potential growth at the start of 1996.</p>
<p>Gillerman blamed the central bank's restrictive monetary policy for cutting into capital spending growth and increasing the government's budget deficit. &quot;There is a complete correlation between rising interest rates and a rising deficit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gillerman also blamed concerns about the future of Middle East peace for the economy's problems.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt part of the uncertainty comes from the political/security situation,&quot; he said. &quot;Multinational companies are here for the long run....I have not head of a single company that was already here that left, but I see in the field that companies deciding whether to come to Israel are worried.&quot;</p>
<p>Gillerman called for a social-economic compact between employers, the government and labour unions to agree on a package of reform measures. Over the past week strikes called by the country's Histadrut trade union crippled some sectors as workers protested proposed economic austerity measures.</p>
<p>While Gillerman said he was encouraged by the budget cuts for 1997 passed by parliament on Wednesday, he added that without a commensurate cut in interest rates 1997 &quot;will be a very bad year.&quot;</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
