<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="283292" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Roosevelt sees Q4 $52 mln charge.</title>
<headline>Roosevelt sees Q4 $52 mln charge.</headline>
<dateline>ST. LOUIS 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Roosevelt Financial Group Inc, holding company for Roosevelt Bank, said Thursday it will recognize a 1996 fourth-quarter charge of about $52 million of after-tax expenses that were previously deferred in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles (GAAP).</p>
<p>It said the expenses are related to historical activities with interest rate exchange agreements. Roosevelt also said it anticipates core operating earnings, excluding the charge, to be about $0.42 per diluted share in the fourth quarter, in line with the First Call consensus among analysts.  </p>
<p>The current charge results from the continuing balance sheet repositioning associated with the execution of the bank's retail strategy, Roosevelt Financial said.</p>
<p>The fourth quarter extinguishment of short-term borrowings, which had previously been synthetically altered by interest rate exchange agreements, dictates recognition of any previously deferred expenses, in accordance with GAAP, Roosevelt said.</p>
<p>While the charge will reduce reported stockholders' equity, Roosevelt said it has no impact on the company's previously disclosed &quot;net market value&quot; calculation.  </p>
<p>During the fourth quarter, the company reclassified its entire investment and mortgage-backed securities portfolios from held to maturity to available for sale.</p>
<p>Roosevelt also said it anticipates that year-end 1996 assets totaled about $7.8 billion, down from the $9 billion reported at September 30, 1996. The balance sheet shrinkage led to a comparable paydown of short-term borrowings. Net borrowings for the quarter of about $300 million led to a further pay down of short-term borrowings, it said. The magnitude of the total shrinkage in short-term borrowings triggered the recognition of the previously deferred expense.</p>
<p>Management said it expects net interest income for the fourth quarter will be slightly greater than reported in the third quarter. But the effective net spread (net interest income annualized as a percentage of average earnings assets) for the quarter should approximate 2.10 percent, a 15-basis point increase over the third quarter.</p>
<p>Roosevelt Financial on December 23 announced plans to merge with Mercantile Bancorp Inc in a transaction expected to be completed in mid-1997.</p>
<p>((Chicago newsdesk 312 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
