<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="283459" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AMERICAN FOOTBALL-TENESSEE BEATS NORTHWESTERN 48-28 IN CITRUS.</title>
<headline>AMERICAN FOOTBALL-TENESSEE BEATS NORTHWESTERN 48-28 IN CITRUS.</headline>
<dateline>ORLANDO, Florida 1997-01-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peyton Manning threw for 408 yards and four touchdowns as ninth-ranked Tennessee routed 11th-ranked Northwestern, 48-28 in the Citrus Bowl on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In what could have been his last college game, Manning completed 27-of-39 passes without an interception and also ran 10 yards for a score. The junior has not said if he will enter the NFL draft, and many people believe he could be the top pick if he left college.</p>
<p>Tennessee fans were chanting, &quot;One More Year!&quot; as he left the field.</p>
<p>&quot;It was extremely flattering,&quot; said Manning, who was 16-of-22 for 285 yards and three scores in the first half, while Schnur was 10-of-19 for 94 yards.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the fans I know will support me no matter what I decide to do. It was the most fun I've had in quite a while.&quot;</p>
<p>Working against a suspect secondary weakened by the suspension of Hudhaifa Ismaeli, Manning directed Tennessee (10-2) to a 21-0 lead in the first 13 minutes. Northwestern (9-3) stormed back to tie the game, but could not contain Manning and suffered its second New Year's Day bowl loss in a row.</p>
<p>&quot;We certainly didn't slow them down very much,&quot; Northwestern coach Gary Barnett said. &quot;I thought at one point, after it was 21-21, the game might turn around and we would regain our composure and take advantage of that surge in momentum.  We weren't able to do that.&quot;</p>
<p>Manning's receivers ran wild, as Joey Kent caught five passes for 122 yards and two TDs and Peerless Price added six catches for 110 yards and a score.  Dustin Moore caught a six-yard TD pass with 2:27 remaining.</p>
<p>Steve Schnur was 25-of-45 for 228 yards and two touchdowns for the Wildcats, who have won or shared the last two Big Ten titles but have allowed 89 combined points in the ensuing bowl games.</p>
<p>Schnur also threw three interceptions, including one early in the third quarter that was returned 30 yards for a touchdown by Tyrone Hines and gave the Vols a commanding 38-21 lead. Hines added 13 tackles and stepped up in the absence of defensive end Leonard Little, who was sidelined with a knee injury.</p>
<p>&quot;We felt if that we could make them throw the ball and stop their running game, we could have a good chance of stopping them,&quot; Hines said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ORLANDO, Florida"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
