<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28350" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Kurd group says Saddam troops kill Kurds in Arbil.</title>
<headline>Kurd group says Saddam troops kill Kurds in Arbil.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Iraqi Kurdish group said on Monday Baghdad's troops remained in the northern city of Arbil and were carrying out mass executions in the streets.</p>
<p>Asked to confirm U.N. reports that Iraqi troops had evacuated Arbil, Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK) Ankara representative Shazad Saib said: &quot;It is not true.</p>
<p>&quot;(Iraqi troops) have committed mass executions in Arbil itself of PUK members -- some of them have been executed in the streets. A few hundred have been killed. Many hundreds have been arrested,&quot; Saib told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said there were reports that those arrested, including members of the Iraqi Turkoman community and communists, were being taken to the town of Mosul, under Iraq's central control.</p>
<p>U.N. officials contacted in Arbil by telephone said they had not heard about any mass executions.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen the Iraqis leaving,&quot; one official said. &quot;It is quiet, almost.&quot;</p>
<p>Reuters reporters in northern Iraq said they had been prevented by KDP members from going near Arbil, which Iraqi troops captured on Saturday in a joint assault with the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP).</p>
<p>PUK officials in London said they had no information that the Iraqis were leaving. &quot;But in any case they will leave the &quot;Mukhabarat&quot; (secret service) and a lot of equipment behind -- like they did in Kuwait,&quot; a PUK spokeswoman said by telephone.</p>
<p>The umbrella opposition Iraqi National Congress (INC) said the secret service had made its headquarters in the Kurdish parliament building in Arbil, the administrative centre of the Kurdish-controlled north.</p>
<p>The KDP was guiding the Iraqi troops who went from door to door armed with lists and rooted out figures of opposition to President Saddam Hussein, INC officials said.</p>
<p>The INC and PUK leader Jalal Talabani said Saddam's troops had executed nearly 100 defectors from the Iraqi army in a camp near Arbil on Saturday.</p>
<p>Saib denied reports by the KDP that Iraninan troops had entered northern Iraq, and said this was a ploy to justify the KDP's involvement with Saddam.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
