<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28369" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: PRESS DIGEST - Turkey - Sept 2.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Turkey - Sept 2.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Turkish press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>SABAH</p>
<p>- Fourteen people are killed and thirty-five injured in a traffic accident caused by an insane person attacking the driver of a coach.</p>
<p>- The opening of the Kirkuk-Yumurtalik oil pipeline between Turkey and Iraq under a U.N. &quot;oil-for-food&quot; deal is at risk as Iraqi President Saddam Hussein joins fighting in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>MILLIYET</p>
<p>- Islamists in government menace university deans by narrowing their budget if they do not allow students with Islamic headscarves to get an education under school dress rules.</p>
<p>HURRIYET</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Tansu Ciller calls on Saddam to withdraw his troops from Arbil in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>- The energy minister's plans to build 13 new natural gas power plants found unrealistic as it contradicts current policy and regulations.</p>
<p>CUMHURIYET</p>
<p>- Markets are sick of price rises enforced by the Islamist-led government to combat the budget deficit.</p>
<p>YENI YUZYIL</p>
<p>- Islamists criticise the chief of general staff for likening the Islamist Welfare Party to Iranian Islamists.</p>
<p>DUNYA</p>
<p>- Islamist Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan is aiming to raise $10 billion in his second &quot;economic package&quot; since he came to power in June.</p>
<p>ZAMAN</p>
<p>- The United States is gearing up to include Turkey in the black list of countries that take a role in drug trafficking. This is supported by a mounting consumption of drugs in Turkey.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
