<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="283752" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Peronists seen losing majority in mid-term polls.</title>
<headline>Peronists seen losing majority in mid-term polls.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine President Carlos Menem's flagging popularity will rob his Peronists of their majority in October mid-term elections, but the party should still garner more legislative seats than any other, analysts say.</p>
<p>A survey of six top political analysts and pollsters by the business daily El Cronista, published Thursday, suggested the Peronists' 51.4 percent majority in the lower house of Congress and 52.8 percent of the Senate will be at risk.  </p>
<p>&quot;There's a chance the opposition will have a very good election and the ruling party will not repeat its successes of previous elections, though that doesn't mean it will lose,&quot; said political analyst Ricard Rouvier.</p>
<p>Rouvier and colleagues cited the high unemployment rate of 17.3 percent as one of the main causes for the unpopularity of Menem, who was re-elected to a second term in May 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;That would be impossible today,&quot; said pollster Rosendo Fraga, predicting the loss of Peronist power in Congress in sharp contrast to the last mid-term elections in 1993.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's unthinkable the Peronists will win 50 percent (of the vote) since not even in 1993, when they were in excellent shape, did they manage that. They got 40 percent of the vote with a 13-point lead over the Radical Party,&quot; said Fraga.</p>
<p>The analysts said that what was saving the Peronists from defeat was the failure of the Radicals and the center-left Frepaso coalition to team up for this year's polls -- a move opposed by Radical ex-President Raul Alfonsin.</p>
<p>&quot;The final result will be lost seats for the Peronists,&quot; said pollster Enrique Zuleta Puceiro. &quot;But if there is no alliance between the Radicals and Frepaso the ruling party will have no trouble winning the election.&quot;</p>
<p>((-- Patrick Adam, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 541 318-0654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
