<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="283782" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile industrial output seen up slightly in 1997.</title>
<headline>Chile industrial output seen up slightly in 1997.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chile's industrial production will grow by 2.4 percent in 1996 and is expected to rise by 3.6 percent this year, said trade group Sociedad de Fomento Fabril (Sofofa).</p>
<p>Industrial output growth in December is expected to be on a par with November when production expanded 2.2 percent. Output rose 2.4 percent in the first 11 months of the year.</p>
<p>In both years industrial output growth is seen lagging behind overall growth of the economy which expanded 6.8 percent last year and is forecast to grow five percent this year, said Sofofa president Pedro Lizana.  </p>
<p>The industrial sector has been hurt by the Central Bank's year-long credit squeeze and by the strengthening of the dollar against the Chilean peso which has made imports cheaper.</p>
<p>Chilean car and electrical goods manufacturers have also faced tough competition from Mexican producers following a free trade agreement which came into force last year, sweeping away tariffs on a wide range of products.</p>
<p>((-- Margaret Orgill, Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595x212))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
