<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="283779" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil BNDES backs weaker real, fiscal improvement.</title>
<headline>Brazil BNDES backs weaker real, fiscal improvement.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's National Development Bank (BNDES) has recommended a speedier devaluation of the real in 1997 if the federal government can take a bigger bite out of its fiscal deficit.</p>
<p>In a 60-page report released this week, BNDES economists recommended accelerating depreciation of the real at a faster rate than inflation to attain a real depreciation of the currency, which would help the export sector.  </p>
<p>&quot;But it's important to make clear that there has to be a strong improvement in fiscal accounts to allow this kind of depreciation or there could be a problem with inflation,&quot; Mauricio Mesquita, one of the authors of the report, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Last year, Brazil's Central Bank depreciated the real in small increments every week or two, resulting in a 6.9 percent devaluation over the year against the dollar, while annual inflation stood at about 10 percent.  </p>
<p>Before pushing the depreciation rate of the real above inflation, however, Brasilia must improve its shoddy fiscal performance, Mesquita said.</p>
<p>At the beginning of last year, policy-makers pledged to reduce the country's closely watched operational deficit -- which includes interest payments on government debt -- from 5.0 percent of GDP in 1995 to 2.5 percent in 1996. Now it appears the operational deficit will close 1996 at about 4.2 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>Mesquita said a weaker real would not only help Brazilian exports by making them more attractive in global markets, but would attract more investment to export industries, which the government is trying to strengthen.</p>
<p>&quot;Now, with a strong real, there is a disincentive to invest in export industries, so you are seeing a lot of investment in non-tradeable goods,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>((-- John Miller, Sao Paulo newsroom, 5511 248-5414))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
