<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="283824" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine peso closes higher on inflows.</title>
<headline>Philippine peso closes higher on inflows.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippine peso greeted the New Year on a strong note on Thursday, finishing at 26.286 to the dollar from the end-1996 level of 26.299 amid strong inflows of foreign funds, traders said.</p>
<p>The peso was also buoyed by dollar sales by some banks which wanted pesos to cover their reserve positons, they said.</p>
<p>The day's average was at 26.288 from 26.293.  </p>
<p>The peso traded in a range between 26.292 and 26.285.</p>
<p>&quot;Most banks expected a stronger dollar,&quot; a dealer from a large bank said, referring to the fact that interest rates are expected to ease with the one percentage-point cut in reserve requirements effective on Friday.</p>
<p>Moreover, the imposition of the 20 percent final tax on term reverse repos would have discourgaed investors to invest in those bills and instead shift to dollars, the same trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;The strong dollar did not materialise. Arbitrage money came in. They have a strong belief in the stability of the peso,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>As expected, the Central Bank intervened in the market. Traders said the Central Bank bought at least $25 million at rates ranging from 26.285 to 26.287.</p>
<p>A dealer, however, said the market may see a weaker peso on Friday as banks do their usual arbitrage play for the weekend.</p>
<p>The dealer said the peso may only weaken up to 26.315 since the Central Bank had been quoting an offer rate for the dollar at 26.318 pesos.</p>
<p>--LILIAN KARUNUNGAN (632) 841-8937</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
