<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28380" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Officials wrangle over Arafat-Netanyahu meeting.</title>
<headline>Officials wrangle over Arafat-Netanyahu meeting.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Burston</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli and Palestinian officials held marathon closed-door talks to try to nail down terms for a landmark meeting between Israeli Prime Benjamin Netanyahu and Palestinian President Yasser Arafat.</p>
<p>As the talks lasted into Monday morning, Foreign Minister David Levy told Israel's Channel One television that a first face-to-face encounter between the two leaders could &quot;very possibly&quot; take place by the end of this week.</p>
<p>But Palestinians said several issues remained unresolved and Arafat convened his senior officials for an pre-dawn meeting on Monday in Gaza to discuss them.</p>
<p>Levy met Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak on Sunday to discuss Israeli-Palestinian relations, which have plunged in the past week to their lowest point since Netanyahu was elected in May at the head of a right-religious government.</p>
<p>Netantahu, facing the threat of a rekindled Palestinian uprising should the peace process founder, gave his strongest indication yet that he would agree to meet Arafat soon.</p>
<p>But Arafat aide Nabil Abu Rdeineh said the Palestinian leader would withhold agreement until he was certain a meeting would be more than merely &quot;a show for the world, a handshake for the sake of world media on Netanyahu's part.&quot;</p>
<p>Abu Rdeineh, asked by Reuters what points must be settled before a Netanyahu-Arafat meeting, said the Israeli government must commit itself to carrying out all remaining elements of the interim peace agreement.</p>
<p>He said the Palestinians demanded &quot;a full Israeli commitment to implement the peace deal and, at the top of the list, the agreed-upon troop redeployment in Hebron and freeing of Palestinian woman prisoners.&quot;</p>
<p>Palestinians accuse Netanyahu of trying to shelve or back out of interim accords reached with the former government of Shimon Peres, who froze the planned Hebron pullback amid a wave of Islamic suicide bombings in Israel early this year.</p>
<p>One official said the negotiators, meeting in a Tel Aviv apartment under the auspices of U.N. special envoy Terje Larsen, were working on a joint communique which would pave the way for an Arafat-Netanyahu meeting &quot;directly thereafter.&quot;</p>
<p>Israeli negotiators, led by Netanyahu adviser Dore Gold, were pressing the Palestinians to agree to a rediscussion of elements of the Hebron withdrawal agreement, state-run Israel Radio said.</p>
<p>Netanyahu, asked about reports that he would meet Arafat this week, replied: &quot;I have said that when the developments allow, we would announce the meeting -- and indeed, there are all sorts of developments.&quot; He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Netanyahu, who opposes trading occupied land for peace, had said he was in no hurry to meet Arafat but softened his line a week ago after President Ezer Weizman signalled he would see the Palestinian leader if the prime minister refused.</p>
<p>Netanyahu has angered Palestinians by rejecting curbs on Jewish settlement construction declared by the the previous Israeli government.</p>
<p>Last week, in a move widely seen as a slap to Arafat, Israel demolished an Arab community centre it said was built illegally in East Jerusalem. Two days earlier Arafat had bowed to a Netanyahu demand to close two Palestinian offices in the city.</p>
<p>Israel regards Palestinian political activity in the city's Arab eastern half as a challenge to its claims of sovereignty over the sector it captured in the 1967 Middle East war. The Palestinians regard East Jerusalem as their future capital.</p>
<p>Arafat warned Israel last week that Palestinians had other options if it did not honour its peace agreements and he hinted they could resume the intifada, the Palestinian uprising that began in late 1987 against Israeli rule.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
