<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="283859" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>TUNISIA: Libya executes CIA-linked spies.</title>
<headline>Libya executes CIA-linked spies.</headline>
<byline>Abdelaziz Barrouhi</byline>
<dateline>TUNIS 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Libya executed on Thursday six senior officers and two civilians sentenced to death by a military court for spying using equipment supplied by the U.S. Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), Libyan state-run radio reported.</p>
<p>The six officers were executed by a firing squad while the two civilians were hanged, the radio said.</p>
<p>&quot;The sentence was issued by the Supreme Military Court on Wednesday,&quot; a Libyan official contacted earlier by telephone said.</p>
<p>The radio, monitored in Tunis, said earlier the men were convicted of belonging to &quot;a banned organisation linked to agents of foreign governments&quot; and of passing defence secrets to foreign states.</p>
<p>It did not name the governments but said the convicted men used CIA-supplied equipment and implied they were spying for the United States.</p>
<p>In Washington, U.S. officials dismissed the trial as a propaganda ploy.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a new case and the proceedings have a show trial flavor,&quot; one official said. &quot;They look like a propaganda ploy for internal consumption.&quot; The CIA declined comment.</p>
<p>&quot;The report is the first public admission of opposition within the military to the rule of Colonel Muammar Gaddafi,&quot; a Tripoli-based diplomat said.</p>
<p>Libya's state-run television on Wednesday night broadcast footage of the trial room in an unidentified place.</p>
<p>&quot;Have you forgotten or are you just playing down what those who recruited you as spies, have done to us? They killed our children, tore our bodies apart, raided our families as they were sleeping late in the night,&quot; the television showed a prosecutor as telling the men.</p>
<p>He was apparently refering to the U.S. bombing of Tripoli and Benghazi in 1986.</p>
<p>U.S. military aircraft bombed targets in Tripoli and Benghazi on April 15, 1986. Ten days earlier a bomb had exploded in a West Berlin disco, killing a U.S. soldier and a Turkish woman. The United States accused Libya of instigating that incident and other attacks against U.S. targets in the Middle East and Europe.</p>
<p>Six other officers and two civilians were acquitted by the court, showing that the &quot;revolution is able to be clement when there is lack of evidence&quot;, the radio said.</p>
<p>The convicted officers were identified as Colonel Muftah Muhammad Gharoum, Staff Colonel Mustafa Abu al-Qasim Massud, Flight Lieutenant-Colonel Saad Salah Faraj, Major Khalil Salim Muhammad, Major Ramadan al-Ihumi Muhammad Ali and Major Mustafa Hubayl al-Fudhil.</p>
<p>The two civilians were Misbah Saad Musbah and Sulayman Ghayth Muftah.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TUNIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TUNIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TUNISIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
