<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="283921" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TB-type vaccine might help stop asthma.</title>
<headline>TB-type vaccine might help stop asthma.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Scientists puzzling over why asthma rates are soaring in developed countries have a new suspected culprit -- good health.</p>
<p>British and Japanese researchers report in Friday's edition of the journal Science that they have found some evidence that early childhood respiratory infections, such as exposure to tuberculosis, might actually make people less likely to develop asthma and other allergies.</p>
<p>Asthma rates have been rising in developed nations, where sanitation and good medical systems have made childhood infections less common. Genetics plays a role, but cannot explain the rise seen in a relatively short time span.</p>
<p>Dr. Julian Hopkin of the Lung Research Laboratory at Churchill Hospital in Oxford, England and colleagues at the Wakayama Medical Centre in Wakayama, Japan studied nearly 1,000 children who had been immunised against tuberculosis.</p>
<p>They found that those who had the strongest immune response were less likely to get asthma, suggesting that the exposure to tuberculosis can modify the human immune system in a way that makes allergic responses less likely.</p>
<p>The experiments &quot;point to the possibility that immunisation with harmless bacteria, related to tuberculosis, might be helpful in preventing and treating allergy. Further studies to test this idea are planned,&quot; Hopkin said.</p>
<p>&quot;Childhood infections may, therefore, paradoxically protect against asthma,&quot; William Cookson and Miriam Moffatt of Oxford University wrote in an essay accompanying the research in the journal. They said that more work needs to be done to clarify the specific relationship with tuberculosis versus other childhood infections also on the decline.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
