<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="284039" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wall Street stocks dip seen short-lived.</title>
<headline>Wall Street stocks dip seen short-lived.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The sudden malaise afflicting U.S. stocks has likely been exaggerated by a holiday-thinned market, analysts said, and a rebound is generally expected to occur soon.</p>
<p>Stocks have suffered from a sudden rise in interest rates, set off by a series of surprisingly strong economic reports that have pummeled the bond market over the last two sessions.</p>
<p>Over that time, the Dow industrials have fallen more than 150 points, pulling global stock markets lower in the process.  </p>
<p>But analysts generally discounted the move, predicting a recovery could start as soon as Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think you'll see the stock market rebound in a big way,&quot; said Robert Froehlich, chief investment strategist at Van Kampen American Capital. &quot;You're sitting here in January, when a lot of 401(k) money is available. This is going to be viewed as a classic buying opportunity.&quot;</p>
<p>The broad sell-off in financial markets began on Tuesday after stronger than expected home sales and consumer confidence reports and gained new vigor today from a robust National Association of Purchasing Management (NAPM) report.  </p>
<p>The NAPM index, which measures manufacturing activity, spooked the bond market by jumping to a 54.0 reading in December from 52.7 in November, showing the economy had finished 1996 with surprising momentum.</p>
<p>The report sent the long bond tumbling 1-10/32, pushing the yield up to a key level of 6.75 percent. Prior to the NAPM release, the long bond had been 1/4 point higher.</p>
<p>&quot;Economists were looking for an abnormally low reading because they thought factories would close for more than a day with Christmas in the middle of the week,&quot; said Philip Orlando chief investment officer at Value Line Asset Management.  </p>
<p>Even after the report, analysts remained skeptical of arguments the economy was running too hot.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't consider it so strong that we're in an economy that's overheating,&quot; said Peter Canelo, chief investment strategist at Dean Witter, adding that with the key monthly employment report due January 10, &quot;We'll have much better numbers to look at next week.&quot;</p>
<p>Absent a clear signal of inflation, Canelo said he expected stocks would actually benefit from the NAPM surprise.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if bonds remain under pressure, it will eventually dawn on the stock market that this is good news because it improves the outlook for earnings,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Regardless of how the coming sessions unfold, the back-to-back economic surprises have touched off jitters for a market that only recently had dropped its guard on inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;Before this I think most of the market was looking at January as being mostly non-events,&quot; Froehlich said. &quot;Now I think you'll be seeing people sharpening their pencils and viewing January's economic releases as very, very important.&quot;</p>
<p>((-- Wall Street desk, 212-859-1730))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
