<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="284083" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Marseille under Tapie misused millions - Le Monde.</title>
<headline>Marseille under Tapie misused millions - Le Monde.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's former European soccer champions Marseille misspent 101 million francs ($19 million) on rigging matches and transfers under the presidency of bankrupt businessman Bernard Tapie, Le Monde reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>The influential French daily said the money was spent between 1987 and 1993 to fix matches by bribing players or referees and to lure star players to Marseille.</p>
<p>&quot;The most illegal tricks were used in player transfers to make sure that the best would join (Olympique Marseille),&quot; said the newspaper, citing the final investigative report on the club's accounts by magistrate Pierre Philipon.</p>
<p>Philipon's report has not been published. It was drawn up so that a court may decide whether the findings justify a trial.</p>
<p>Philipon could not be contacted on Thursday. Officials at the Marseille club declined to comment.</p>
<p>Le Monde, quoting the report, said Olympique had misused important sums in order to &quot;reduce or even suppress the hazards which inevitably exist in a football match&quot;.</p>
<p>According to the newspaper, fictitious loans, false invoices and inflated payments to agents were among the means Marseille used during the Tapie years.</p>
<p>Tapie, a parliamentary deputy who in the 1980s served briefly as minister in a Socialist cabinet, chaired Marseille from 1986 until 1994. He has already been placed under investigation for fraud in the affair.</p>
<p>The one-time high-flying businessman is also awaiting the result of an appeal against a two-year jail sentence handed to him in May for his part in a match-rigging case in 1993.</p>
<p>Under Tapie, Olympique Marseille dominated French and European soccer, winning four league titles in succession and playing two European Cup finals, the second of which they won by beating AC Milan 1-0 in May 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
