<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="284359" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Eat, drink and be merry, it's good for you.</title>
<headline>Eat, drink and be merry, it's good for you.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forget those New Year resolutions to count the calories and stop drinking alcohol.</p>
<p>And there's no need to feel too guilty the morning after if you wake up with a hangover.</p>
<p>Scientists have decided moderate drinking is good for you and strict calorie watching is not the best way to stay slim, while a hangover can be a useful warning to keep drinking within limits.</p>
<p>Writing in the British Medical Journal, U.S.-based researchers said a study of the lifestyle of thousands of Chinese men showed 19 percent lower mortality among men aged 45 to 64 who had up to 14 drinks a week than among teetotallers.</p>
<p>But the researchers from the University of South Carolina said the study of 18,244 men in Shanghai between 1986 and 1989 showed heavy drinking was risky. Those who had more than 43 drinks a week had a 30 percent higher risk of death.</p>
<p>&quot;Moderate drinkers had a reduced risk of death compared with non-drinkers or heavy drinkers,&quot; they wrote.</p>
<p>Danish scientists reported that a free and easy diet was more effective than a strict regime for keeping the pounds off.</p>
<p>The researchers from Copenhagen's Royal Veterinary and Agricultural University made 43 obese adults lose around 13.5 kg (30 pounds) each either via a strict diet lasting 17 weeks or an even harsher one lasting eight.</p>
<p>Then, some of the volunteers were put on an &quot;ad lib&quot; low fat programme while others began a traditional calorie-controlled diet. The results were measured after a year.</p>
<p>&quot;The ad lib groups had regained 5.4 kg of the 13.5 kg initially lost while the fixed energy intake groups had regained 11.3 kg of the initial 13.8 kg weight loss,&quot; they found.</p>
<p>After two years the overall weight loss among &quot;ad-libbers&quot; averaged eight kg, more than three times the &quot;calorie counters&quot;.</p>
<p>A signed editorial in the same edition of the BMJ suggests even the post-Christmas hangover may be a blessing in disguise.</p>
<p>Ian Calder, a consultant anaesthetist at Britain's National Hospital for Neurology and Neurosurgery, wrote there was probably no foolproof remedy for the morning-after headache.</p>
<p>But at least the fear of a hangover makes most people moderate their drinking. &quot;Even moderate amounts of ethanol (alcohol) can be damaging, so a penalty for consumption is in our interest.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
