<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="284390" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel asks whether Hebron shooting part of trend.</title>
<headline>Israel asks whether Hebron shooting part of trend.</headline>
<byline>Susan Sappir</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>An off-duty soldier's shooting of Arabs in Hebron has Israelis debating whether his Jewish religious upbringing bred violence and asking why the army failed to weed out a man thought to have emotional problems.</p>
<p>Settler leaders said Noam Friedman, who wounded seven Palestinians in the attack on Wednesday, was unstable.</p>
<p>They dismissed claims his action was the latest in a growing chronicle of killings by religious Jews opposed to Israel giving land to Arabs in peace deals.</p>
<p>But the former head of Israel's Shabak secret service, Yaacov Peri, drew a connection between Friedman and other gunmen.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a young man who took upon himself, as in previous cases unfortunately, to try to halt or disrupt or neutralise the (peace) process,&quot; he told Israel radio. &quot;It must not be explained only as some mental disorder.&quot;</p>
<p>Police said on Thursday they had arrested another soldier on suspicion he helped Friedman plan the attack.</p>
<p>Palestinian commentators noted peace talks were stalled for months over Israeli demands to increase their own security, while the Palestinians were exposed to settler violence.</p>
<p>&quot;If these claims that the settler is psychologically ill -- which is something that is repeated every time there is a criminal act against Palestinians -- are true, why do they insist on arming these psychological patients?&quot; asked Yasser Abed Rabbo, Palestinian minister of information and culture, in al-Ayyam newspaper.</p>
<p>Many Israelis were troubled that Friedman, a religious Jew who was carrying a gun as part of his army service, seemed to fit a pattern of rightist political violence.</p>
<p>He was preceeded by Yigal Amir, who assassinated prime minister Yitzhak Rabin, and Baruch Goldstein, who massacred 29 Moslems in Hebron's mosque.</p>
<p>But Education Minister Zevulun Hammer, head of the National Religious Party that is largely identified with the settler movement, was not worried about an apparent trend. In an interview with army radio Hammer referred to reports Friedman was mentally unstable.</p>
<p>&quot;If it turned out he was a regular student, I would say we have to do something. But since he is this kind of person and we know his background now, then we can't blame the system (of religious education),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Newspapers quoted neighbours of the Friedman family in the settlement of Maaleh Adumim as saying Noam was &quot;wierd&quot; and the religious Yom Hashishi weekly published an unsourced report saying that Friedman had sought mental counselling.</p>
<p>It said his therapists had warned the army it should not induct Friedman.</p>
<p>An army spokesman said Friedman's background was under investigation by military police.</p>
<p>Friedman's grandmother, Esther Reiss, was asked by army radio whether she considered her grandson insane. &quot;Absolutely not,&quot; she answered. She said she had &quot;no idea&quot; what caused him to go on the shooting spree.</p>
<p>The former head of the Israeli army's mental health department, Avi Bleich, told Israel radio all recruits undergo structured interviews and a series of psychotechnic tests at the army's draft offices.</p>
<p>Only if these tests detected signs of &quot;strangeness&quot; were further tests conducted by mental health experts, Bleich said.</p>
<p>But he noted the army could be fooled.</p>
<p>&quot;There are lots of young people that for various reasons conceal mental problems...so that they'll be drafted at all, some even to combat units. Sometimes behind that concealment is a fantasy that going to the army will solve lots of pre-existing problems,&quot; Bleich said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
