<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="284486" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS-French 96 car sales surge masks gloomy trend.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-French 96 car sales surge masks gloomy trend.</headline>
<byline>Christine Tierney</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Car sales in France surged 10.5 percent in 1996 to 2.13 million units, the best level since 1992, the French carmakers' association CCFA said on Thursday, but the headline figure masked some gloomy trends.</p>
<p>The sales rise was fuelled by a state-sponsored rebate incentive programme in effect until the end of September, analysts say, and the year as a whole was difficult for the French car industry, which lost market share at home.</p>
<p>The CCFA said new car sales in December rose 1.8 percent to 144,735 units from dismal year-earlier levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The December sales figures must be seen in the light of the prior-year month, December 1995, which showed a 15 percent drop in sales because of public sector strikes in France at the end of 1995,&quot; the CCFA said in a statement.</p>
<p>On a comparable-day basis -- there were 21 shopping days last month compared with 20 in December 1995 -- sales fell three percent, reflecting the weakness in demand since the end of the rebate programme.</p>
<p>On a comparable-day basis, full-year 1996 car sales rose 10 percent in France.</p>
<p>Foreign carmakers, led by Italy's Fiat, Volkswagen and General Motors' European subsidiary Opel, ran up far bigger sales gains than the domestic manufacturers after waging a fierce price war in the French market.</p>
<p>Sales by foreign manufacturers rose 19.9 percent in 1996, giving them 44 percent of the market, up from 40.6 percent.</p>
<p>The combined share held by Renault SA and the PSA Peugeot Citroen group fell to 56 percent from 59.4 percent a year ago.</p>
<p>The price war, which was exacerbated by the rebate plan, badly eroded carmakers' earnings in France as companies slashed prices, sacrificing their profit margins, to win customers.</p>
<p>While foreign companies tend to tolerate losses in markets outside their own with the long-term view of gaining market share, the French industry paid a high price for the fierce competition in its home market on which it is heavily dependent.</p>
<p>Renault Chairman Louis Schweitzer has said the group, which entered the private sector in 1996, will lose money this year and he predicted the price war would intensify. The Peugeot group's first-half 1996 profit shrank by more than half.</p>
<p>Although the CCFA has not issued its outlook for the French car market for this year, industry experts are gloomy.</p>
<p>Unless the state steps in with help, the Peugeot group expects a nine to 10 percent drop in French car sales in 1997. The car lending division of Compagnie Bancaire, Cofica, has forecast a 10 percent drop.</p>
<p>Shares in Renault closed down 3.59 percent at 107.50 francs, and Peugeot shares fell 4.97 percent to 555 francs, shedding recent gains generated in year-end window-dressing by big funds. The bourse's blue chip CAC-40 index closed down 2.54 percent.</p>
<p>Analyst John Lawson at Salomon Brothers said the December figures were &quot;not cause for new gloom&quot; but he said the French carmakers would have trouble clawing back market share.</p>
<p>&quot;Both manufacturers have fallen behind in terms of product renewal,&quot; he said. Although Renault is rolling out new versions of its Megane car and the Peugeot group is producing stationwagon and coupe versions of its 406 and refreshing its 306 and ZX models, the companies have not kept pace with the rapid product renewal rate of some of their rivals, he said.</p>
<p>Their efforts are hampered by the urgent need to pare expenses. &quot;The industry is carrying too many costs given the way the European car market has developed,&quot; Lawson said.</p>
<p>The two French companies have asked the government to help them cut and rejuvenate their staffs through early retirements. PSA Peugeot Citroen Chairman Jacques Calvet said in December his group may have to lay off workers if the government balks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
