<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="284479" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Jan 2.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Jan 2.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Washington Post carried the following stories on its front page on January 2:</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - The theory that many veterans of the Persian Gulf War are ill because they were unwittingly exposed to nerve gas more than five years ago contradicts most of what is known about the health effects of chemical weapons.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - The international campaign to ban antipersonnel landmines is at a crossroads and President Clinton is likely to determine which way it goes.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>HEBRON, West Bank - An off-duty Israeli soldier fired at least 10 rounds from his M-16 assault rifle into a crowded Arab marketplace intending, he said, to kill &quot;Israel haters&quot; and halt an impending accord to transfer most of this West Bank city to Palestinian self-rule.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>LEXINGTON, Texas - Scott and Lou Ann Mullen waged a successful two-year legal battle against the Texas Department of Protective and Regulatory Services to adopt two black youngsters in a case reflecting the national debate over interracial adoption.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>BEIJING - As incomes rise and industrial affluence begins to take hold, General Motors Corp. is poised to launch a daring $2 billion investment program aimed at drawing in millions of Chinese when they start shopping for their first cars.</p>
<p>---</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
