<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="284603" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Asian stocks end lower in slow trading.</title>
<headline>Asian stocks end lower in slow trading.</headline>
<byline>Kenneth Barry</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks in Asia fell Thursday, feeling the spillover effect of a sharp New Year's Eve drop in U.S. shares, but traders said they expected the pessimism to be short-lived.</p>
<p>Stock prices ended lower in Hong Kong, Sydney and Manila while Tokyo and Singapore remained closed for holidays.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average suffered its biggest fall in six months on Tuesday, losing 101 points. Dealers said investors were spooked by signs of a robust economy that might herald higher inflation and a rise in interest rates.</p>
<p>The U.S. index of 30 industrials rose 26 percent for all 1996.</p>
<p>After Asian markets closed Thursday, stocks in the United States fell again, with the Dow Jones industrial average off about 69 points to 6,379 in early trading.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's Hang Seng Index slumped 248.01 points to close at 13,203.44.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't read too much into this,&quot; said Julian Ings Chambers in institutional sales at BZW Securities. &quot;We will get a more sensible view on the market toward the end of next week when new money is readied for allocation.&quot;</p>
<p>Australian shares closed weaker but well off their lows in quiet trading.</p>
<p>Despite diving 27 points early after the Dow's dip on Tuesday, strong support below the 2,400 level helped prices recover some ground. The All Ordinaries index fell 13.4 points to 2,411.2.</p>
<p>&quot;The Dow fall went through and then people started to pick it up again,&quot; said a Melbourne-based dealer.</p>
<p>In Manila, stocks ended lower in thin trading.</p>
<p>&quot;Most people are still on vacation. There was no buying interest in the market,&quot; Caesar Tanquingcen, trader at Connell Securities, said.</p>
<p>The composite index fell 16.08 points, or 0.51 percent, to 3,154.48 points amid turnover of less than one billion pesos.</p>
<p>Thai stocks lost 3.42 percent on a sustained sell-off by investors following steep falls on Wall Street and in Hong Kong, brokers said. The SET index fell 28.44 points to 803.13.</p>
<p>Brokers said investors were concerned about Thailand's economic problems, especially a high current account deficit and weak export growth.</p>
<p>Fighting the trend, Jakarta share prices edged up at the close in slow trading. The Jakarta composite index rose 0.67 point to 638.10 points.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka stocks closed up on optimism among local investors that 1997 would be a good year, brokers said. The all-share index rose 3.77 points to 606.73.</p>
<p>Gold in Hong Kong edged higher, to US$367.70 an ounce from $367.45 in New York on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
