<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="284689" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia miners await Century zinc mine pact.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia miners await Century zinc mine pact.</headline>
<byline>James Regan</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's resources industry, already shaken by a court ruling last month giving Aboriginal tribes more say over land rights, faces another setback if the world's largest mining house, RTZ Corp Plc-CRA Ltd loses its battle to develop a A$1 billion zinc deposit.</p>
<p>So far, RTZ-CRA has been negotiating outside official channels with Aboriginal leaders, promising jobs, schools and community funds in an attempt to reach a deal for development of the Century zinc mine, potentially among the world's largest.  </p>
<p>But failure to broker a deal by a mid-February deadline with members and non-members of the Waanyi Aboriginal tribe will send the battle before a government tribunal and then possibly the Federal court, where any decision is open to appeal.</p>
<p>If this happens it could take years to resolve, Michael Pinnock, chief executive of the Queensland Mining Council told Reuters on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Overseas investors will say if a group like RTZ-CRA can't do it with a project as big as Century, what chance does anyone else have?&quot; Pinnock said.  </p>
<p>After a series of starts and stops to the talks, RTZ-CRA maintains it is confident it can reach an agreement on the northwest Queensland deposit at some stage.</p>
<p>&quot;Because there is now formal representation among the claimants, a fair degree of confidence exists that the issues will be resolved,&quot; an RTZ-CRA spokesman said.</p>
<p>That was not always the case.</p>
<p>After RTZ-CRA spent about A$200 million on pre-construction work, the working staff at the mine was reduced to a handful last year and capital spending on the project was suspended.  </p>
<p>At a low point in the talks last July a A$60 million compensation package tabled by the mining company was reportedly rejected by one Aboriginal negotiator as an amount that &quot;wouldn't feed my dogs&quot;.</p>
<p>More recently, a High Court ruling that pastoral leases did not automatically extinguish any Aboriginal land claims was a further setback for miners.</p>
<p>The question of who can claim ownership to vast tracts of mostly remote properties in Australia in the wake of the December 23 ruling and 1994 legislation opening up claims to Aboriginals under so-called &quot;Native Title&quot; rights has once more  </p>
<p>pitted miners against indigenous Australians.</p>
<p>Critics of the legislation, brought in by former Labor prime minister Paul Keating, charge that land ownership has been made too open to dispute and subsequent litigation.</p>
<p>Such exposure can paralyse new projects, miners say.</p>
<p>The legislation also affects other big land users, such as farmers and graziers, with far-reaching implications.</p>
<p>With a land mass nearly the size of the United States without Alaska but a population of only 18 million, Australia exports much of what it produces.  </p>
<p>In the current fiscal year to June 30, 1997, the value of Australian commodity exports is foreast to reach A$58.9 billion, figures from the Australian Bureau of Agricultural and Resource Economics show.</p>
<p>As a result, negotiations between Australian miners and Aboriginal tribes are being closely watched by world markets.</p>
<p>Anaconda Nickel NL has reached its own agreements with 16 parties so far to enable it to develop a A$900 million nickel mine in Western Australia and is confident it can come to terms with three outstanding claimants.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's the framework that will be adopted across Australia as time goes on,&quot; Mal James, company secretary for Anaconda said.</p>
<p>&quot;Within a region, all claimants will come together on one side and all mining companies will come together on another and there will be an agreed structure as to payments and native title issues,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Century mine would be capable of producing about 780,000 tonnes of zinc concentrates annually.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
