<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="284717" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila orders new bidding for Subic container port.</title>
<headline>Manila orders new bidding for Subic container port.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippines President Fidel Ramos has ordered that fresh bidding be held for a major project for a container port at Subic Bay, presidential palace officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Subic Bay Metropolitan Authority (SBMA) had awarded the project to a unit of Hong Kong's Hutchison Whampoa last year, but Ramos had ordered a review after a losing bidder, International Container Terminal Services (ICTSI), protested.  </p>
<p>Ramos told SBMA chairman Richard Gordon in a letter to &quot;conduct a re-bidding for the (project), giving all interested parties the opportunity to qualify and participate in the re-bid,&quot; the palace officials said.</p>
<p>A copy of the letter was later faxed to Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We have found the terms of reference provided in the tender document to have been disregarded by the SBMA Bids and Awards Committee in its determination of the winning bid,&quot; Ramos said.</p>
<p>&quot;Accordingly you are ordered to refrain from signing the contract with Hutchison Ports Philippines Limited,&quot; the letter said.  </p>
<p>Hutchison Ports Philippines is a unit of Hutchison Whampoa.</p>
<p>SBMA rejected ICTSI's original bid on the grounds that it would violate a law forbidding monopolies in the port industry. ICTSI operates the Manila International Container Terminal, which handles 70 percent of container traffic in the country.</p>
<p>Analysts have expressed concern in the past that the row over the bidding could taint the country's privatisation programme in the eyes of foreign investors, who have often complained that requirements were often changed after bids were opened.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the circumstances, a re-bid is the fairest, most acceptable (and legally defensible) solution to the current impasse,&quot; Executive Secretary Ruben Torres said in a separate statement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
