<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="284849" id="root" date="1997-01-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Saudi police say British nurses confess to killing.</title>
<headline>Saudi police say British nurses confess to killing.</headline>
<byline>Diana Abdallah</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi Arabian police have said that two British nurses charged with murdering an Australian colleague have confessed and re-enacted the crime at the scene at a hospital in Saudi Arabia's eastern province.</p>
<p>An official statement by the eastern province police said the two women &quot;made a full confession and proceeded with the reconstruction of the crime at the scene...Their confession was confirmed legally by three judges in al-Khobar supreme court.&quot;</p>
<p>It was issued by the official media and Saudi newspapers in the past two days and was the first official Saudi comment on the arrest of Deborah Kim Parry, 41, and Lucille McLauchlan, 31.</p>
<p>The two have been charged with murdering Australian nurse Yvonne Gilford, 55, at the hospital complex where they worked. They were arrested and jailed in the city of Dammam on December 20, nine days after Gilford was found stabbed to death.</p>
<p>If found guilty, the women could face public execution by the sword, according to Islamic sharia law.</p>
<p>Salah al-Hejailan, who is providing legal advice to the two Britons, told Reuters on Thursday that if either were found guilty he would make a public appeal to Gilford's family not to ask for the death sentence.</p>
<p>Under Islamic sharia law enforced in the kingdom, a victim's family in a murder case has the right to ask that the suspect be spared the death sentence.</p>
<p>The Saudi English-language Arab News, which published pictures of the two jailed nurses and Gilford, on Thursday quoted eastern province police chief Lieutenant Hameed al-Ghanimi as confirming that the confessions had been filed.</p>
<p>The police statement said Gilford was stabbed several times in different parts of her body.</p>
<p>&quot;Following the investigation carried out with them (the two suspects), it appeared that Lucille McLauchlan and Deborah Kim Parry were with the nurse on the night of the murder till very late. A quarrel over personal relationships broke out between the murdered nurse and Deborah.</p>
<p>&quot;This led Deborah to resort to violence against her (Gilford) and stab her to death. Lucille McLauchlan helped her (Deborah) by smothering her (Gilford),&quot; the statement added.</p>
<p>Saudi newspapers had said the two were arrested while using the victim's cash card at a shopping mall.</p>
<p>The British Foreign Office has refused to comment on Saudi newspaper reports that the two had confessed.</p>
<p>Hejailan said he would make his first visit to the jailed women on Saturday.</p>
<p>He said that if the death penalty were imposed, it would be the first time foreign women had been executed in the kingdom, home to two of Islam's holiest shrines. But he said that even if the women were found guilty, a death sentence was unlikely.</p>
<p>Hejailan's firm said under sharia law the victim's family, regardless of religion or nationality, could ask for the death sentence to be dropped in return for a financial settlement, called 'diah' or blood money.</p>
<p>The family could also waive the right to blood money, in which case the court would decide on a sentence, which in such cases is usually five years imprisonment, the firm said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
