<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="284959" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER SHOWCASE-TOTTENHAM HIT BY FRESH INJURIES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-TOTTENHAM HIT BY FRESH INJURIES.</headline>
<dateline>MANCHESTER, England 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tottenham, already the clear underdogs for their F.A. Cup third round tie with Manchester United at Old Trafford on Sunday, are reeling under a deepening injury crisis.</p>
<p>Teddy Sheringham is the latest casualty following a training ground collision with reserve goalkeeper Espen Baardsen. The England striker damaged an ankle and will be out for three weeks.</p>
<p>Also sidelined for Sunday's clash are defender John Scales, signed last month from Liverpool, striker Chris Armstrong and long-term injury victims Darren Anderton and Gary Mabbutt.</p>
<p>Steffen Iversen, signed from Norway's Rosenborg last month, has influenza and is a doubtful starter, as are centre-back Sol Campbell (ankle) and teenage striker Rory Allen (back).</p>
<p>Manager Gerry Francis has drafted in apprentices Danny Hill, James Clapham and Neil Fenn for the trip to Manchester.</p>
<p>In contrast, the premier league champions are close to full strength. Striker Andy Cole may start a first-team match for the first time this season after coming on as a substitute in United's last two league matches, three months after cracking both shin bones in a reserve game.</p>
<p>&quot;Andy is certainly in the running for a place in the starting line-up against Spurs,&quot; manager Alex Ferguson said. &quot;He has worked very hard to recover from injury and has done fantastically well to be pushing for a place.&quot;</p>
<p>If Cole starts on Sunday, Norwegian striker Ole Solskjaer could be relegated to the bench.</p>
<p>Midfielder Nicky Butt has responded well to an ankle injury and should play but Gary Pallister (back) and Philip Neville (glandular fever) are both out.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Manchester United (from) - Peter Schmeichel, Gary Neville, David May, Ronnie Johnsen, Denis Irwin, David Beckham, Nicky Butt, Eric Cantona, Ryan Giggs, Roy Keane, Andy Cole, Ole Solskjaer, Karel Poborsky, Paul Scholes, Brian McClair, Ben Thornley.</p>
<p>Tottenham (from) - Ian Walker, Stephen Carr, Colin Calderwood, Sol Campbell, Clive Wilson, Justin Edinburgh, Ruel Fox, Allan Neilsen, David Howells, Andy Sinton, Danny Hill, Jamie Clapham, Neale Fenn, Steffen Iversen, Rory Allen, Ronny Rosenthal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANCHESTER, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
