<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285031" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NHL ICE HOCKEY-DONATO'S SECOND GOAL TAKES BRUINS PAST WHALERS IN OVERTIME.</title>
<headline>NHL ICE HOCKEY-DONATO'S SECOND GOAL TAKES BRUINS PAST WHALERS IN OVERTIME.</headline>
<dateline>HARTFORD 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ted Donato's second goal of the game 2:21 into overtime lifted the Boston Bruins to a 5-4 victory over the Hartford Whalers on Thursday.</p>
<p>Adam Oates slid a pass from the top of the right faceoff circle down low to the right side of the net, where Donato flipped a shot over goaltender Jason Muzzatti for his 12th goal of the season.</p>
<p>&quot;I wish it was that easy, but we stayed with it, we needed a good start tonight and we got it,&quot; Donato said.</p>
<p>Don Sweeney and Oates each set up two goals for Boston, which snapped a four-game winless streak.</p>
<p>At New Jersey, Fredrik Olausson and Jaromir Jagr scored 42 seconds apart in the second period and Patrick Laline made 31 saves and the Pittsburgh Penguins routed the New Jersey Devils 6-1.</p>
<p>Mario Lemieux had four assists and Jason Wooley three for Pittsburgh, which improved to 6-0-1 in its last seven games.</p>
<p>First-period goals by Ron Francis and Stu Barnes staked the Penguins to a 2-0 lead.</p>
<p>In New York, Alexander Karpovtsev scored the tying goal with 6:48 remaining and Mark Messier's second goal of the game 3:18 later gave the New York Rangers a 4-3 victory over the New York Islanders.</p>
<p>The Islanders carried a 3-2 lead into the third period but Karpovtsev's fourth goal tied it.</p>
<p>Messier capped a pretty give-and-go with Brian Leetch, snapping a one-timer past Salo's left side from the right circle for a 4-3 lead on Messier's 22nd goal of the season.</p>
<p>In Chicago, Bob Corkum's third goal of the season midway through the third period broke a tie and Nikolai Khabibulan made 27 saves as the Phoenix Coyotes beat the Chicago Blackhawks 4-2.</p>
<p>Keith Tkachuk added an empty net tally with 1:09 remaining to ice the win, his 13th goal in his last 11 games. Tony Amonte scired both Chicago goals.</p>
<p>In St Louis, Brett Hull scored with 85 seconds left in the third period to lift the St. Louis Blues into a 2-2 tie with the Montreal Canadiens.</p>
<p>Chris Pronger also scored for the Blues. Vincent Damphousse scored both goals for the Canadiens.</p>
<p>At Colorado, Uwe Krupp scored with 2:15 remaining to snap a tie and lift the Colorado Avalanche to their fifth straight victory, 3-2 over the struggling Calgary Flames.</p>
<p>With the game tied 2-2, Joe Sakic won a faceoff in the right circle and drew the puck back off the boards to Krupp, who blasted a high slap shot over Trevor Kidd's left shoulder for his fourth goal of the season.</p>
<p>It was Sakic's also his 800th career point.</p>
<p>In Vancouver, Pavel Bure had two goals and an assist and Alexander Mogilny added a goal and two asssists as the Vancouver Canucks beat the reeling Los Angeles Kings 4-3.</p>
<p>Donald Brashear also scored and Adrian Aucoin had two assists for Vancouver, which snapped a four-game losing streak.</p>
<p>Jeff Shevalier, Kai Nurminen and Ed Olczyk scored for the Kings.</p>
<p>In San Jose, Ron Hextall made 26 saves and Daniel Lacroix and Eric Lindros scored second-period goals, helping the Philadelphia Flyers extend their unbeaten streak to 15 games with a 4-1 victory over the San Jose Sharks.</p>
<p>Dainius Zubrus and Rod Brind'Amour also scored for the Flyers, who improved to 13-0-2 in their last 15 games.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARTFORD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
