<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285158" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African shares eye Dow, see volatile week ahead.</title>
<headline>S.African shares eye Dow, see volatile week ahead.</headline>
<byline>Paul Harris</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African shares head into 1997 still shaking off a hangover from New Year's Eve's Wall Street fall and dealers said on Friday that next week may prove to be another rough ride.</p>
<p>A 101-point fall in New York was not the way most dealers wanted to ring out the old year and see in the new and South African stocks quickly lost their festive mood of earlier in the week and headed straight down.</p>
<p>Portfolio managers said all eyes next week would be fixed nervously on the Dow to see if the market is set for further gloom or may launch a recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;It is going to be a very volatile week. It is very difficult to call as the market will be swinging up and down,&quot; said Raymond Goss, a portfolio manager at Irish &amp; Co.</p>
<p>On Thursday Wall Street shares looked like they were set for another steep dip, but a late rally saw them retrace most of their losses by the close.</p>
<p>Some portfolio managers and dealers said this could mean that the Dow will become more stable and less of a factor next week.</p>
<p>If the Dow doesn't become an issue then South African stocks could be in for a rise. The end of the holiday season will see all major players return to the scene and should spur the market forward.</p>
<p>Gad Ariovich, SMK Securities Investment strategy manager, said the Johannesburg Stock Exchange (JSE) was prone to this seasonality as local institutions accumulated cash during the quiet holiday period and were ready to plough it back into investments.</p>
<p>Private investors were also set to return to the market with fresh capital and new investment plans.</p>
<p>&quot;Other things being equal there is a tendency towards seasonality in the JSE and if there are no offsetting developments there is a very good chance the market will zoom ahead in the next two weeks,&quot; Ariovich said.</p>
<p>The market could also get a boost from South Africa's year-on-year broadly defined M3 money supply, which Thursday preliminary Reserve Bank figures showed grew 15.32 percent in November -- much better than the market had expected.</p>
<p>Annual private sector credit growth was 17.10 percent, preliminary figures showed -- well below a Reuters consensus poll of 18.2 percent -- against an unchanged 18.86 percent in October.</p>
<p>But the investors next week will be wary of December gold and foreign exchange reserves data due at 1600 GMT on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The market is already worried about South Africa's low level of reserves. Bad news here could lure currency speculators in to trigger off a new run on the rand and spoil the delayed New Year's party investors are looking for.</p>
<p>Such outside factors mean that, despite the market generally being seen as undervalued, investors will continue to be tentative for fear of getting their fingers burned.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market is undervalued but there are other issues at work here, not just if the market is cheap or not,&quot; one portfolio manager said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
