<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285266" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech currency firms on move into crown paper.</title>
<headline>Czech currency firms on move into crown paper.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech crown gained more than 50 basis points in early Friday trading against the central bank's mark/dollar basket on renewed foreign interest in crown-backed paper, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are seeing more foreign interest for the ministry of finance bills,&quot; said Petr Korous, a dealer at Ceskoslovenska Obchodni Banka.</p>
<p>He said that GECC's Thursday issue of two-year crown Eurobonds at 10.5 percent also generated demand for the currency.</p>
<p>At 0830 gmt, the crown was at 27.058/dollar, 17.518/mark, or +3.43 percent above parity with central bank's mark/dollar basket.</p>
<p>The crown ended trading late Thursday at 2.95 percent above basket parity, up slightly from the cenbank fixing at +2.92 percent.</p>
<p>Interest in crown paper is also being boosted by changes in the taxation structure on Finance Ministry treasury bills.</p>
<p>Dealers said the combination could help push the currency above 3.5 percent versus parity with the basket in the medium term, but foreign trade fundametals were still ominous in the long term.</p>
<p>Korous said some local buyers might have been long on foreign currency because of negative year-end forecasts on the future of the Czech economy.</p>
<p>-- John Mastrini, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
