<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285277" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru replaces security chiefs held by guerrillas.</title>
<headline>Peru replaces security chiefs held by guerrillas.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-01-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Alberto Fujimori on Thursday replaced Peru's top security chiefs who are among 74 hostages still being held by Marxist guerrillas in the Japanese ambassador's residence in Lima.</p>
<p>The head of the anti-terrorist police DINCOTE, Gen. Maximo Rivera, was replaced by Gen. Marcel Nakamura, and the country's security chief, Gen. Guillermo Bobbio Zevallos, was replaced by Gen. Arturo Marquina.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear why he replaced the two men, but they have come under fire for lowering their guard and allowing guerrillas to storm a diplomatic cocktail party on December 17 and seize 500 hostages.</p>
<p>Fujimori also swore in a new president of the Supreme Court to replace Moises Pantoja, also a hostage of the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA). Pantoja's term as Peru's top judge ended Dec 31.</p>
<p>In a speech at the swearing-in, Fujimori attacked the rebels as &quot;terrorists&quot; bent on pointless violence and refuted their claim to be fighting for Peru's poverty-stricken masses.</p>
<p>But he gave no clue as to his next move in the crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an error to think that the violence that arises from discontent can end poverty,&quot; he said. &quot;Twelve years of violence by Shining Path (guerrillas) and the MRTA ...has, on the contrary, made us poorer.&quot; The guerrillas &quot;cannot say that by destroying factories, bridges and by chasing away investors and tourists, poverty is going to be reduced,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The rebels have released most of the hostages, holding onto VIPs as bargaining chips to press their main demand -- the release from jail of over 400 of their comrades.</p>
<p>The remaining hostages include Fujimori's brother Pedro, the ambassadors of Japan and Bolivia, high-ranking Peruvian officials and about two dozen Japanese diplomats and businessmen.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll hold them there as long as it takes,&quot; MRTA international spokesman Isaac Velazco said in an interview from Germany. &quot;The guerrillas can stand it -- they've been trained in the jungle. But can the hostages? If they suffer, the Peruvian government must accept all responsibility for not facilitating a solution to this situation.&quot;</p>
<p>Fujimori has flatly rejected the rebel demands.</p>
<p>In a quiet day at the residence on Thursday the only &quot;hostage&quot; to walk free was an alsatian called Emma.</p>
<p>Looking dejected and emaciated after 16 days without food, the sandy-coloured dog was enticed from the diplomatic compound by firemen who offered her Christmas cake. But Emma's puppy was not with her.</p>
<p>Firemen believe the pup stepped on a mine planted by the rebels, causing the loud explosion heard last week in the garden of the mansion.</p>
<p>The dogs were thought to belong to Japanese Ambassador Morihisa Aoki whose Dec. 17 reception in honour of Japanese Emperor Akihito's 63rd birthday was stormed by about 20 heavily armed MRTA rebels.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
