<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285337" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Copper--Gibraltar drills Chile deposit.</title>
<headline>Copper--Gibraltar drills Chile deposit.</headline>
<byline>Margaret Orgill</byline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's Gibraltar Mines has started drilling at its Lomas Bayas deposit in northern Chile as the first stage in a plan to expand the pit's copper output to 90,000 tonnes from 60,000 tonnes originally planned.</p>
<p>Although the mine will only come into production next year, Gibraltar is carrying out exploration to see if the deposit's reserves will be sufficent to support an expansion, Paul Blythe, president of Compania Minera Gibraltar, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;A drilling program started in late 1996. It is the first stage in a feasibility study which is underway to expand the mine to 90,000 tonnes,&quot; said Blythe.</p>
<p>But any expansion will not take place until the next century as the company is not planning to complete the final feasibility study until 1999, he said.</p>
<p>The mine, which will cost more than $200 million to build, has been designed to make any enlargement easy, he said.</p>
<p>Gibraltar expects to receive the results of the drilling mid-year and will then carry out metallurgy work on the samples, said Blythe.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope to be moving forward on the feasibility study by the middle of the year,&quot; he said,</p>
<p>Lomas Bayas, one of a crop of medium-sized copper mines being built in Chile's bleak Atacama Desert, will produce copper cathodes from oxide mineral ores using low-cost heap-leaching technology.</p>
<p>The project had been delayed last year after Gibraltar struggled to find funding for the mine as financiers ducked copper projects following sharp mid-year fall in international copper prices.</p>
<p>But it was brought back on track in September when Gibraltar was bought by another Canadian metals producer, Westmin Resources, for $224 million.</p>
<p>Initial exploration has shown Lomas Bayas has reserves of 169 million tonnes with an average grade of 0.37 percent copper.</p>
<p>Gibraltar expects cash costs of $0.47 a pound in the first years of the mine's life.</p>
<p>   (--Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595x212)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
