<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28545" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-ENGLAND PLAYERS TO BOYCOTT SQUAD TRAINING SESSION.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-ENGLAND PLAYERS TO BOYCOTT SQUAD TRAINING SESSION.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Several England rugby union players have indicated they will boycott a national squad training session on Wednesday in the continuing row between the Rugby Football Union (RFU) and its senior clubs.</p>
<p>Leicester, who have four forwards in the 43-man squad, were the first to announce their international players would not be attending and others are expected to follow their example.</p>
<p>The English Professional Rugby Union Clubs (EPRUC), who last week announced their intention to break away from the RFU, believe the majority of the squad will also side with the clubs, currently their sole employers.</p>
<p>The players' RFU contracts ran out at the weekend, and EPRUC are clearly keen to put extra pressure on Twickenham to grant the clubs more money and a bigger say in the new professional era.</p>
<p>Former England hooker and current Leicester chief executive Peter Wheeler said: &quot;We didn't say to them `You will not go'. We told them the position as we saw it and left it up to them. They decided not to go.&quot;</p>
<p>EPRUC chairman Donald Kerr commented: &quot;The players are the key to this dispute. They are being paid reasonable salaries by their clubs and we are asking them to support us in this dispute,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The RFU issued a statement saying the date of the session had been confirmed in July and that it would go ahead.</p>
<p>Don Rutherford, the RFU technical director said: &quot;It would be very sad, with international rugby having moved to a higher level as seen in the southern hemisphere, if England's preparations were impinged upon at this stage.&quot;</p>
<p>Wheeler said he hoped to have &quot;a meaningful meeting&quot; with the RFU before the end of the week.</p>
<p>British Lions tour manager Fran Cotton appealed for the warring factions to get together.</p>
<p>The former England forward said: &quot;I really do feel sorry for the players. They are becoming pig in the middle and all they want to do is play for their clubs and their country.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There are two issues here. The Rugby Union have to accept the need to restructure and change to cope with a new era and the clubs need to come to terms with the fact they are over-valuing their product.</p>
<p>&quot;The dispute is preventing the opportunity for the exciting development of rugby.&quot;</p>
<p>Welsh first division clubs are also threatening to break away from their union to negotiate their own television and sponsorship deals.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
