<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285498" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Southeast power rebounds ahead of cooler temps.</title>
<headline>US Southeast power rebounds ahead of cooler temps.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot bulk electricity prices in the U.S. Southeast rebounded Friday, in response to cooler weather forecasts and slightly stronger natural gas prices, market sources said.</p>
<p>Temperatures in the Southeast are expected to remain about 10-20 degrees above-normal through Saturday and then return to more seasonable levels Monday and Tuesday.</p>
<p>Firm, peak power prices in the northern part of the Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) territory for Monday were assessed sharply higher in the $18.00-19.00 per megawatt hour (MWh) range, as compared with Thursday's $9.50-10.50 trading range.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak electricity in northern TVA for Monday was assessed at $13.00 per MWh.</p>
<p>For Saturday and Sunday delivery, peak, firm prices into TVA were talked in the $15.00-16.00 range.</p>
<p>At the Georgia/Florida border, prices for firm, peak electricity in 16 hour blocks for Monday delivery were talked about $3 higher in the $22.00-23.00 range.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak power for Monday at the Ga./Fla. border was notionally around $16.00.</p>
<p>In Florida, where daytime temperatures are reaching highs of 70s and 80s and lows of 50s and 60s, firm, peak electricity prices on a 16-hour schedule for Monday were also higher around $25.00 per MWh.</p>
<p>Helping to lift electricity prices was the stronger natural gas market. Weekend prices along the Gulf Coast rose by about five cents to the $2.54-2.60 per million British thermal units range.</p>
<p>((--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
