<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28546" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-THREE MANAGERS CHARGED WITH BRINGING GAME INTO DISREPUTE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-THREE MANAGERS CHARGED WITH BRINGING GAME INTO DISREPUTE.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three English premier league soccer managers have been charged with bringing the game into disrepute, the national Football Association (FA) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Graeme Souness of Southampton, Bryan Robson of Middlesbrough and Ron Atkinson of Coventry were all involved in rows with referees.</p>
<p>Souness and Robson tangled in successive matches with referee Michael Riley in the official's first week in the premier league.</p>
<p>Atkinson and his assistant Gordon Strachan were in trouble with referee Tony Green after Strachan, who still plays for Coventry, refused to leave the pitch after being ordered off for foul language in a reserve match against West Bromwich Albion.</p>
<p>Referee Tony Green eventually restarted the match, without ex-Scotland international Strachan, after a 14-minute delay. Atkinson was charged for remarks he made to the referee in the dressing-room area after the incident.</p>
<p>New Southampton manager Souness, a former Scotland international, was incensed by the dismissal of captain Barry Venison and shouted at Riley both at halftime and at the end of his club's 2-1 defeat at Leicester on August 21.</p>
<p>Robson, former captain and assistant manager of England, lost his temper when Riley booked nine players and sent off Middlesbrough's Nigel Pearson in a 1-1 draw at Nottingham Forest on August 24.</p>
<p>All have 14 days to answer the charges.</p>
<p>The FA has also asked Atkinson and Strachan to explain incidents in a match at Chelsea on August 24 which Coventry lost 2-0.</p>
<p>The pair were involved in angry touchline scenes over Chelsea's first goal, scored by Frank Leboeuf after Dan Petrescu was alleged to have handled.</p>
<p>An FA spokesman said referee Paul Danson's report had raised the question of their conduct: &quot;As a result we have written to them, asking them for their observations.&quot;</p>
<p>Premier league newcomers Sunderland also face charges of contravening rules following allegations that they fielded a suspended player in a reserve team friendly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
