<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285537" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Midwest power rises on cooler weather forecast.</title>
<headline>US Midwest power rises on cooler weather forecast.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot bulk electricity prices in the midwestern U.S. for Monday delivery were mostly higher Friday, led by forecasts calling for cooler weather next week.</p>
<p>Temperatures throughout the Midwest are forecast to remain well above-normal through Saturday, but the arrival of a cool front late Saturday will push temperatures down to near-normal levels by early next week.</p>
<p>Contributing to the rise in prices, traders said, was the anticipated increase in industrial load following the holiday.</p>
<p>In the Mid-Continent Area Power Pool (MAPP), peak, non-firm power prices for Monday delivery were discussed mostly in the $16.00-$17.50 per megawatt hour (MWh) area, as compared with Thursday's trading range of $15.00-16.50.</p>
<p>Off-peak non-firm MAPP power for Monday was also higher in the $11.00-12.00.</p>
<p>In the Mid-American Interpool Network (MAIN), peak, non-firm power prices for Monday climbed into the $19.00-21.50 range, up from Thursday's trading range of $16.00-17.00 for Friday and from the $17.50-18.00 area for next week delivery.</p>
<p>MAIN off peak power for Monday was assessed at $11.00-12.00, but no deals were confirmed done.</p>
<p>Peak, non-firm electricity prices in the East Central Area Reliability Coordination Agreement (ECAR) for Monday were talked in the $14.00-20.00 range, with most deals reported done in the $16.00-17.00 area.</p>
<p>These prices compare with the $13.25-15.00 range on Thursday.</p>
<p>ECAR electricity prices for off-peak, non-firm delivery were quoted at $11.00-$12.00.</p>
<p>January ECAR prices were talked around $23.00, while February ECAR was assessed in the $23.00-24.00 range.</p>
<p>In the Southwest Power Pool (SPP), where temperatures are expected to dip to about five to 20 degrees above-normal this weekend, peak, non-firm power prices for Monday delivery rebounded into the $15.00-16.00 range, up from Thursday's $9.00-10.00 trading range.</p>
<p>Off-peak prices throughout SPP for Monday delivery were notionally assessed at $11.00-12.00.</p>
<p>Temperatures in the SPP region are expected to drop to normal levels Sunday and Monday.</p>
<p>January peak prices in SPP were still in the $20.00-22.00 area, while the July/August market was talked in the $27.75-28.50 range.</p>
<p>Separately, Detroit Edison's 1,116 megawatt (MW) Fermi 2 nuclear unit in Michigan is expected to return to the electricity grid &quot;in the next couple of days.&quot;</p>
<p>Also, American Electric Power Co's 1,090 MW Cook 2 nuclear unit in Michigan, which has been operating at 55 percent power, will likely begin ramping up later today, with full power expected on Sunday.</p>
<p>Omaha Public Power District's 478 MW Fort Calhoun nuclear unit returned to full power after shutting on December 31.</p>
<p>Furthermore, Commonwealth Edison's 794 MW Dresden 2 unit is expected to begin ramping up this weekend from its 40 percent power level, while Dresden 3, with the same generating capacity, is still slated to restart January 13.</p>
<p>ComEd's 1,105 MW Byron 2 is holding at 75 percent power after dipping to about half power late Thursday. The company said the unit will likely increase power later Friday or early Saturday.</p>
<p>Also, the 1,040 MW Zion 2 unit, is expected to be on-line early next week, ComEd said.</p>
<p>All of these ComEd units are in Illinois.</p>
<p>Natural gas prices in the Midwest were also higher in the $2.31-2.36 per million British thermal units (mmBtu) range, while south Texas values were up about four cents to the mid-$2.30s per mmBtu.</p>
<p>((--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
