<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285678" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NOTICE OF SALE - Washington Suburban Sanitary, Md..</title>
<headline>NOTICE OF SALE - Washington Suburban Sanitary, Md..</headline>
<text>
<p>SUMMARY NOTICE OF SALE</p>
<p>		  Washington Suburban Sanitary District</p>
<p>				   Maryland</p>
<p>	 $45,485,000* Water Supple Refunding Bonds of 1997</p>
<p>$36,610,000* Sewerage Disposal Refunding Bonds of 1997</p>
<p>$42,520,000* General Construction Refunding of1997 NOTICE  IS  HEREBY  GIVEN  that  the  Washington  Suburban  Sanitary  Commission   (the</p>
<p>					     Commission'')  will   rece</p>
<p>written  sealed  bids  for  the  $45,485,000*  Water  Supply Refunding Bonds of  1997, the  $36,610,000* Sewage  Disposal Refunding  Bonds  of  1997,  and  the  $42,520,000*  General Construction Refunding  Bonds  of  1997  (collectively,  the Bonds'') of  the  Washington  Suburban  Sanitary  District until 11:00 A.M. Eastern Standard Time on</p>
<p>				January 9, 1997</p>
<p>or at  such  later  date and  time  as  the  Commission  may determine, at 14501 Sweitzer  Lane, Laurel, Maryland  20707. The Bonds will be dated January 1, 1997, and will mature  on June 1 in the years and  amounts as more fully described  in the Notice of Sale. The aggregate principal amount of each series of the Bonds and the principal amount of each maturity of each series  of the Bonds are  subject to adjustment  both before and  after the submission  of  bids, as  more  fully described  in  the Notice of Sale. No bids of less than 99%  of par or more  than 100% of par plus accrued interest, no oral bid and no bid for less  than all of  the Bonds  will be  considered.  The Bonds  will  be awarded based on the lowest interest cost to the Commission, determined in accordance with  the true interest cost  (TIC)  method. All  bids must  be accompanied   by  a  good  faith</p>
<p> check  or  surety   bond  in  the   amount  of  $1 ,200,000,</p>
<p>payable unconditionally  to  the  order  of  the  Washington Suburban Sanitary Commission. The Bonds are not subject to redemption prior to maturity. In order to  assist the underwriters  purchasing the Bonds in complying with  Securities and  Exchange Commission  Rule 15c2-12(b)(5) (the  Rule''), the  Commission will  by bond order covenant, for the benefit of  the owners from time  to time of  the Bonds,  to comply  with the  provisions of  the Rule. The Preliminary  Official Statement  dated January  2, 1997 with respect to the Bonds includes a description of the Commission's undertaking. Copies of  the  Preliminary  Official  Statement  and  the Notice of Sale  and Bid Form  relating to the  Bonds may  be  obtained  from  the   undersigned  at  Washington   Suburban</p>
<p>Sanitary Commission, 14501  Sweitzer Lane, Laurel,  Maryland 20707 (301-206-7108)  or  H.  C.  Wainwright  &amp;  Co.,  Inc., Financial  Advisor,  Suite  2515,  100  East  Pratt  Street,  Baltimore,   Maryland   21202   (410-347-3900)   or   Pryor,</p>
<p>McClendon, Counts &amp;  Co., Inc., 3  Penn Center, 1515  Market Street, Suite  819, Philadelphia,  Pennsylvania 19102  (215- 569-0274).</p>
<p>			     WASHINGTON SUBURBAN SANITARY</p>
<p>				   COMMISSION</p>
<p>			   By: /s/ MARY J. KIRBY</p>
<p>				   Treasurer</p>
<p>*Preliminary, subject to change.</p>
<p>			  (From The Bond Buyer)</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
