<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28567" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-BRETT BUTLER SAYS HE WILL BE IN LINEUP FRIDAY.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-BRETT BUTLER SAYS HE WILL BE IN LINEUP FRIDAY.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Los Angeles Dodgers centre fielder Brett Butler, after months of hard work and radiation treatment to recover from cancer, said Tuesday he will be in the lineup Friday when the Dodgers host the Pittsburgh Pirates.</p>
<p>&quot;I know it hasn't been announced yet, but I will be in the lineup,&quot; Butler, 38, told ESPN Radio.</p>
<p>Butler, who underwent tonsil cancer surgery on May 21, has been in uniform and seated with the team in the dugout since it began an East Coast road trip at Montreal's Olympic Stadium August 26.</p>
<p>Butler's cancer, found during a tonsillectomy, was in just one of his 50 lymph nodes. It was extracted on May 1. Butler also received 32 radiation treatments, then had to undergo a rigorous training programme to regain his playing weight and conditioning.</p>
<p>Butler is hitting .265 with seven runs batted in and seven stolen bases in 29 games this season. He is on the disabled list for just the second time in his 16-year career.</p>
<p>In his absence, Los Angeles tried Roger Cedeno in centre field, then traded with the Detroit Tigers for Chad Curtis. Curtis and Todd Hollandsworth have manned Butler's customary leadoff spot in the batting order.</p>
<p>A career .291 hitter, Butler has 2,274 career hits and 542 stolen bases.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
