<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285633" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: No impact if Subic deal lost - Hutchison.</title>
<headline>No impact if Subic deal lost - Hutchison.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hutchison Whampoa Ltd said on Friday it had not yet decided whether to re-bid on a container terminal project at Subic Bay in the Philippines but that losing the deal would have no impact on the group.</p>
<p>&quot;We've exhausted all our time and resources for the project,&quot; said John Meredith, group managing director at Hutchison Port Holdings. &quot;There comes a point when you have to say enough is enough.&quot;</p>
<p>Meredith said the company would have to look at whether it had an interest in placing fresh bids for a project it won twice last year but was forced to reconsider on Thursday when Philippine President Fidel Ramos ordered fresh bidding.</p>
<p>But Meredith said the potential loss of the project would have no effect on Hutchison.</p>
<p>&quot;It has absolutely no impact on the company at all,&quot; Meredith said. &quot;It's a pretty insignificant port investment compared to some of the other ones we are looking at.&quot;</p>
<p>He declined to speculate on the chances of Hutchison winning back the deal but said re-bidding was technically difficult.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it would be very difficult to re-bid it because everybody knows everybody else's details,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hutchison unit Hutchison Ports Philippines Ltd was awarded the project last year to develop and operate a container port in Subic Bay.</p>
<p>But on Thursday, Ramos ordered the Subic Bay Metropolitan Authority (SBMA) not to enter into a contract with Hutchison after local competitor International Container Terminal Services (ICTSI) protested.</p>
<p>ICTSI operates the Manila International Container Terminal, which handles 70 percent of container traffic in the country.</p>
<p>&quot;It would look as if it's a situation where the government will continue re-tendering the project until it is won by a local company,&quot; Meredith said.</p>
<p>The bidding was marred by too much politics, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Too many politicians are involved,&quot; he said. &quot;There's no other country in the world where we've to explain our bids several times over.&quot;</p>
<p>Meredith also questioned the legality of Ramos's move, saying Hutchison had been granted the project by SBMA.</p>
<p>&quot;We are taking advice as to whether legally the president has the power to overthrow the SBMA because SBMA is an autonomous undertaking as far as we know,&quot; Meredith said.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6590</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020017">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
