<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285748" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PC-industry awaits Intel multimedia chip.</title>
<headline>PC-industry awaits Intel multimedia chip.</headline>
<byline>Therese Poletti</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Personal computer makers next week will simultaneously roll out flashy multimedia PCs designed around a new chip by Intel Corp, a move that is expected to give the consumer sector of the industry a much-needed boost.</p>
<p>On Wednesday Intel will officially launch its P55C microprocessor, with its so-called MMX (multimedia extension) technology. A slew of companies will roll out consumer PCs, notebooks and desktops using the new chip, which offers much faster performance than earlier designs.  </p>
<p>&quot;(The impact of MMX) will be significant in the second half,&quot; said David Wu, a Chicago Corp analyst. &quot;I should hope it helps -- the corporate world is strong and the retail world is very weak.&quot;</p>
<p>He said there was currently nothing new and sexy to drive sales in the consumer market other than better price performance.</p>
<p>CompUSA Inc on Thursday became the latest retailer to report disappointing sales of PCs during the holiday shopping season, normally the industry's strongest.  </p>
<p>To be sure, analysts said that PC makers with a strong presence in the corporate market would not be hurt very much by the disappointing consumer sales.  </p>
<p>Consumer anticipation of the new PCs was one reason that retailers were showing weaker-than-expected sales, as savvy computer buyers waited for next &quot;big thing&quot; to hit the market, analysts said.</p>
<p>In tandem with Intel's announcement, Compaq Computer Corp , Dell Computer Corp, Gateway 2000 Inc, Toshiba America Corp, Sony Corp, International Business Machines Corp and other companies are expected to unveil new high-end PCs, priced at more than $3,000.</p>
<p>On Friday, Intel shares jumped eight to 138-3/8 after two analysts made bullish comments about the company.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's a tremendous kickoff to 1997,&quot; said Rod Schrock, a vice president of Compaq's Presario division. &quot;We are so excited about the new MMX processor that we redesigned the entire line of Presarios from the ground up. Customers are going to get a pretty dazzling experience.&quot;</p>
<p>Schrock declined to give any product specifics, but he said that Compaq will launch its Presario consumer PCs with MMX at about the same time as Intel's announcement.</p>
<p>&quot;It should provide an added boost to the demand for the new generation of PCs,&quot; Schrock added. &quot;There was no major industry event in 1996. This year you have a new processor.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
