<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285844" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: OSCE tells Belgrade to accept Gonzalez report.</title>
<headline>OSCE tells Belgrade to accept Gonzalez report.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's security forum on Friday backed former Spanish premier Felipe Gonzalez's report on disputed November local polls in Serbia and called on Belgrade for prompt and full implementation of its recommendations.</p>
<p>Gonzalez concluded in his Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe report that the opposition fairly won polls in 13 key provincial centres and in the capital Belgrade and called on Serbian authorities to accept the result.  </p>
<p>The OSCE held a special session on Gonzalez's report and a reply received on Friday from Yugoslav Foreign Minister Milan Milutinovic which acknowledged the opposition had won a majority of votes in nine municipalities in Belgrade.</p>
<p>&quot;The OSCE endorses the recommendations of Mr. Gonzalez's report and calls for prompt and complete implementation,&quot; said Ambassador Lars Vissing of Denmark, whose country took over the chairmanship of the OSCE on January 1.</p>
<p>The OSCE chairman-in-office, Denmark, said it was ready to continue dialogue over improvements to the Serbian electoral system, in free media and an independent judiciary.</p>
<p>Milutinovic's letter said Belgrade wanted to study further details on the results in other towns including Serbia's second biggest city, Nis.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
