<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285842" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: EA-Generali consortium says may lose CA bid - paper.</title>
<headline>EA-Generali consortium says may lose CA bid - paper.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of bidders for Austria's Creditanstalt led by insurer EA-Generali acknowledged on Friday its chances of topping a rival bid by Bank Austria were small, Austrian daily Kurier said.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately, this has become a political deal,&quot; the paper quoted an unnamed member of the consortium as saying in its Saturday edition, made available late on Friday. &quot;We see our chances as being very, very slim.&quot;</p>
<p>EA-Generali representatives were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>The group has bid a total of 13.8 billion schillings for the state's 19.9 million shares in the bank and wants to sell about a quarter of those on the market at a premium, 60 percent of which would also go to the government's coffers.</p>
<p>&quot;We will top up our offer slightly, but we simply can't match the price offered by Bank Austria,&quot; another influential member of the group said, according to the paper.</p>
<p>Bank Austria has bid 16.8 billion schillings for the government's 70 percent voting stake in Creditanstalt. Both suitors have until January 10 to update their offers.</p>
<p>Bank Austria's bid is preferred by Austria's dominant Social Democrats, while their junior coalition partner, the conservative People's Party, prefers the consortium. The debate has caused a growing rift among the partners.</p>
<p>-- Knut Engelmann, Vienna newsroom +431 53112 274</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
