<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285913" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Congress set to tap new parliament leader.</title>
<headline>India's Congress set to tap new parliament leader.</headline>
<byline>Nelson Graves</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lawmakers from India's Congress party prepared on Friday to select a new leader to replace former prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao, whose supporters threatened to upset a rebuilding drive after electoral defeat.</p>
<p>The Congress Parliamentary Party (CPP), comprised of 225 legislators from the upper and lower houses of parliament, was set to meet at 4 p.m. (1130 GMT).</p>
<p>Congress, which has led India for all but four years since independence in 1947, suffered its worst ever defeat in general elections last April and May.</p>
<p>Rao, who was prime minister from 1991 until last May and spearheaded a drive to open India's economy, quit under pressure as CPP leader last month.</p>
<p>The taciturn, 75-year-old leader had stepped down as Congress party president in September after a judge upheld a summons ordering him to appear in court to face criminal cheating charges.</p>
<p>The case is one of three criminal proceedings involving Rao, who claims he is innocent of the charges which, in each of the three cases, carry a maximum penalty of seven years in jail.</p>
<p>Rao had clung to his CPP post, which gave him considerable political influence because Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's minority coalition depends on Congress's backing in the lower house of parliament to survive against the Hindu nationalist opposition.</p>
<p>But Rao bowed to the inevitable as supporters deserted him in the face of a campaign to overhaul the party's leadership.</p>
<p>Three candidates emerged to succeed Rao as CPP leader after he resigned on December 19 -- his successor as Congress party president, Sitaram Kesri, and former ministers Sharad Pawar and Rajesh Pilot.</p>
<p>Pawar bowed out earlier this week during a meeting of the party's top decision-making body, but Pilot, 51, resisted and threw up a youthful challenge to Kesri, an 80-year-old former disciple of Mahatma Gandhi.</p>
<p>On Thursday Rao's loyalists announced they would back Pilot, raising the spectre of a split in Congress, which by tradition prefers quiet backroom deals to outright votes when it comes to picking party leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;Right from the late Indira Gandhi's time, organisational elections do not form part of Congress functioning,&quot; The Asian Age newspaper said in an editorial.</p>
<p>A five-member team including former finance minister Manmohan Singh was polling CPP members ahead of the afternoon meeting on Friday to see if a consensus had formed behind either candidate.</p>
<p>Local news agencies said most CPP members had come out in favour of Kesri, whose supporters did not want a vote, saying it could unveil divisions and upset the party's reunification drive.</p>
<p>But Pilot insisted on a ballot, saying it was time Congress shunned its secretive ways and held elections.</p>
<p>&quot;I cannot perceive how election of a separate CPP leader will weaken the party or create a separate power centre,&quot; Pilot said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Deve Gowda's centre-left coalition was eagerly watching Congress's moves, knowing that a unified Congress would be better placed to challenge the government and demand a greater say in decison-making.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
