<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="285944" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Court denies stay in NationsBank merger.</title>
<headline>Court denies stay in NationsBank merger.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A federal appeals court panel Friday denied a stay requested by two community groups that would have temporarily blocked completion of the $9.8 billion acquisition of Boatmen's Bancshares Inc. by NationsBank Corp.</p>
<p>The transaction is slated to be completed Tuesday.</p>
<p>The director of one of the groups said it was considering an emergency appeal to the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>The groups -- Inner City Press/Community on the Move and the New Mexico Alliance -- had argued bank customers would be harmed by the merger of St. Louis-based Boatmen's with NationsBank, based in Charlotte, N.C.</p>
<p>Upon acquiring St. Louis-based Boatmen's, NationsBank would become the fourth-largest U.S. bank holding company with about $233 billion in assets.</p>
<p>In its ruling, the two-judge panel of the 10th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals wrote, &quot;We conclude that petitioners have failed to show that they satisfy the tests for granting the relief sought. Accordingly, the motion for stay is denied.&quot;</p>
<p>The order applied only to the request for an emergency stay blocking the closing of the merger until the court could decide the underlying issue of whether or not the Federal Reserve Board acted properly in approving the deal Dec. 16.</p>
<p>Inner City Press Executive Director Matthew Lee said his New York City group, which has opposed many U.S. bank mergers, was considering seeking an emergency order from the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>Inner City Press and New Mexico Alliance alleged NationsBank consumer finance units engaged in predatory loan practices. NationsBank strongly denied the accusation.</p>
<p>The community groups also argued the approval process was flawed. The groups said that during proceedings before the Fed, NationsBank failed to disclose planned branch closings. They also said lawsuits against the consumer finance units were not disclosed.</p>
<p>The central bank told the court in a filing that the groups lacked legal standing to challenge the approval.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
