<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28605" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: CRICKET-ARAVINDA POWERS SRI LANKA INTO FINAL.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-ARAVINDA POWERS SRI LANKA INTO FINAL.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aravinda de Silva hit a brilliant</p>
<p>unbeaten century, his sixth in one-day cricket, to steer Sri</p>
<p>Lanka to a comfortable six-wicket win over Zimbabwe in the</p>
<p>Singer world series tournament on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The win ensured the World Cup champions finished top of the</p>
<p>league standings in the four-nation limited-overs tournament</p>
<p>with a maximum six points from three wins and qualified for</p>
<p>Saturday's final.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka must wait until Thursday's clash between Australia</p>
<p>and India to find out who will meet them in the final. Both</p>
<p>teams have two points from two games.</p>
<p>De Silva, hero of Sri Lanka's World Cup triumph over</p>
<p>Australia in Lahore earlier this year, maintained his</p>
<p>outstanding form in this tournament and took his aggregate to</p>
<p>259 in three innings without being dismissed once.</p>
<p>De Silva's exceptional exploits with the bat have put him in</p>
<p>line for the player-of-the-series award, a choice between a</p>
<p>luxury car and a four-wheel-drive jeep.</p>
<p>Chasing Zimbabwe's total of 227 for five from 50 overs, Sri</p>
<p>Lanka were in difficulties at 129 for four in the 29th over.</p>
<p>But De Silva, displaying superb temperament and a wide range</p>
<p>of shots, shared an unfinished stand of 99 for the fifth wicket</p>
<p>with Hashan Tillekeratne to steer his side to victory with three</p>
<p>overs to spare and claim his second successive man-of-the-match</p>
<p>award, following his unbeaten 83 against Australia last Friday.</p>
<p>He hit one six and 13 fours off 123 balls.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe, put in to bat by Sri Lanka, reached their total</p>
<p>largely thanks to a career-best 96 not out by hard-hitting</p>
<p>right-hander Craig Evans.</p>
<p>He struck three sixes and six fours in an aggressive display</p>
<p>and was unfortunate to miss his maiden century when the overs</p>
<p>ran out.</p>
<p>Skipper Alistair Campbell also struck form with a stylish 54</p>
<p>off 96 balls and shared with Evans a fifth-wicket stand of 114</p>
<p>from 146 balls to lift Zimbabwe from 66 for four to a total </p>
<p>their bowlers had a chance of defending.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka wicket-keeper Romesh Kaluwitharana made four</p>
<p>dismissals but missed an equal number of chances during the</p>
<p>Campbell-Evans partnership.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe are now out of the tournament, having lost all</p>
<p>their three matches.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
