<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="286100" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Wet Brent trades at Feb +20, unmoved by weakness.</title>
<headline>Wet Brent trades at Feb +20, unmoved by weakness.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea wet crudes remained well supported by demand during the afternoon on Friday despite weaker intermonth spreads and lower outright values.</p>
<p>A Jan 17-19 Brent traded at 20 cents over February, compared to Thursday's trade at +21 cents for a Jan 15-17 cargo.</p>
<p>Feb Brent was still trading about 25 to 30 cents a barrel below Thursday's close after API data released late on Thursday revealed a surprise build in U.S. crude stocks and a bigger than expected rise in distillate inventories.</p>
<p>European gas oil was also weighing on Brent with crack spread swaps under pressure.</p>
<p>Falling outright Brent values undermined CFDs and intermonth paper spreads, Feb/March slipping to +55/+58 cents from trade at +62 and +60 late on Thursday.</p>
<p>But wet North Sea crudes stayed firm after several January cargoes found homes with European refiners, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There were quite a few deals done privately yesterday at higher numbers,&quot; said one. Another trader saw good demand and a strong chance of Oseberg or Urals trading on Friday.</p>
<p>A third decade Forties was heard sold for around Dated Brent +40/+42 cents on Thursday after a mid-month stem was offered for +35 cents. Details could not be immediately confirmed.</p>
<p>Four Brent cargoes, loading Jan 18-22, were due down the paper chains on Friday. It was unclear whether the holders of the two Jan 17-19 clocked cargoes had been granted deferrals.</p>
<p>In the Mediterranean, Urals talked a touch firmer helped by improved refinery margins but a prompt cargo was still offered by a trader at around Dated Brent -$1.10. &quot;There are several cargoes around in both the north and south for the mid-decade (10-20 January),&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Syria trimmed five cents off its offer for Jan Light crude but at Dated -30 cents it was still seen too high for most term customers. Syrian Light was fixed at Dated -5 cents in December.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
