<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="286340" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: SNB makes 3.6 billion Sfr book profit on currency.</title>
<headline>SNB makes 3.6 billion Sfr book profit on currency.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Swiss National Bank (SNB) said it has realised a book profit of 3.578 billion Swiss francs on its currency reserves due to the recent decline in the Swiss franc against the dollar.</p>
<p>The book profit contrasts with a book loss in 1995 of 3.5 billion due to the appreciation of the Swiss franc.</p>
<p>The SNB, which each year adjusts the value of its currency reserves to market rates, said in a statement the valuation was based on an average dollar/franc rate in December of 1.3271 francs, up from 1.1639 last year.</p>
<p>Last year the SNB had to record a book loss on its reserves as the rise in the franc slashed the value of the SNB's currency reserves by 3.5 billion. A write-down also took place in 1994.</p>
<p>The SNB holds almost 90 percent of its foreign currency reserves in dollar-based assets, such as Treasury bills.</p>
<p>Around 33 percent of these reserves are used for currency swaps with Swiss banks, one of the SNB's main methods for adjusting money supply. These funds are essentially hedged and not subject to revaluation.</p>
<p>The other 66 percent are unhedged and used to intervene in currency markets in times of turbulence. These funds are valued each year according to market rates.</p>
<p>However, the SNB is in the process of updating its accounting methods, including the valuation of domestic bonds.</p>
<p>The accompanying changes will first be reflected in the SNB's reserve statement when the annual accounts have been approved by the banking council and the Swiss government.</p>
<p>&quot;This will lead to a one-off increase in provisions and the distributable profit,&quot; the SNB said.</p>
<p>Last month a report from a joint SNB-Finance Ministry working group outlined plans to give the central bank more freedom to manage currency reserves to improve its financial performance.</p>
<p>Like other central banks, the SNB hands over some of its profits to the government.</p>
<p>Between 1991 and 1994 the SNB transferred around 605 million annually to federal and cantonal Swiss governments, but this plunged to 147 million in 1995 due to the fall in the dollar and yen, which necessitated higher writeoffs on currency reserves.</p>
<p>This drop in transfers was followed by criticism of the SNB's investment policy.</p>
<p>Among the proposed changes is that the SNB be permitted to use gold lending and to invest in longer-dated and higher yielding debt by foreign states, banks or international organisations.</p>
<p>-- Peter Nielsen, Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
