<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="286312" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German prosecutors to charge tycoon with fraud.</title>
<headline>German prosecutors to charge tycoon with fraud.</headline>
<byline>David Crossland</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Frankfurt state prosecutors are expected to announce on Monday that they have formally charged disgraced tycoon Juergen Schneider with fraud related to one of the most spectacular corporate collapses in German history.</p>
<p>The prosecutor's office said in a brief statement on Friday it had completed its investigation into Schneider and would announce details at a news conference on Monday.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the office declined to say whether Schneider had already been charged, but prosecutors announced last month that formal charges would be filed in early January.</p>
<p>Schneider's lawyer Christoph Rueckel has said his client, who is being held in a local prison, will be charged with fraud, credit fraud, falsifying documents and fraudulent bankruptcy.</p>
<p>Schneider, once one of Germany's most celebrated entrepreneurs, became one of its most wanted fugitives after he and his wife Claudia vanished in April 1994, leaving his empire to collapse under more than five billion marks ($3.2 billion) of debt.</p>
<p>His disappearance, and the bankruptcy of his group, exposed Schneider's creditor banks to public outrage at the apparent ease with which he obtained funding from them.</p>
<p>Deutsche Bank AG, the country's largest bank and Schneider's biggest creditor, bore the brunt of public criticism over a perceived lack of supervision.</p>
<p>Its chief executive Hilmar Kopper made matters worse by dismissing as &quot;peanuts&quot; the millions of marks Schneider owed to small tradesmen and builders.</p>
<p>Prosecutors allege Schneider obtained credit on the basis of falsified documents, for example by overstating his expected rental income.</p>
<p>Schneider specialised in buying and refurbishing historic hotels and stylish shopping malls, purchasing some of Germany's most prestigious real estate in the post-unification property boom.</p>
<p>But he slid towards bankruptcy because his rental income was too low to service the huge debts he took on to buy the properties.</p>
<p>The Schneiders were detained in Miami in 1995 after a year-long international manhunt. They returned voluntarily to Germany last February to face questioning.</p>
<p>Claudia Schneider, who has been freed from prison on conditional release amid concerns about her health, is expected to be charged with being an accessory to bankruptcy.</p>
<p>Two former associates, Mehdi Djawadi, alleged to have helped the Schneiders plan their getaway, and Karl-Heinrich Kuepferle are also expected to be charged.</p>
<p>Frankfurt prosecutors have said the trial is unlikely to begin before mid-1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
