<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="286348" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek yield curve collapses on fx inflows at close.</title>
<headline>Greek yield curve collapses on fx inflows at close.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek and foreign players rushed to open new ecu/drachma positions driving ecu/drachma sharply lower to 306 and pulling implied drachma rates down 10 to 30 basis points with the drop more pronounced in longer tenors, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Forex inflows have pushed the yield curve sharply lower,&quot; said a foreign bank dealer. &quot;The drop is about 10 basis points in short dates and 30 basis points in longer tenors.&quot;</p>
<p>A total of more than 200 million ecus and 75 million marks were sold at the fixing where ecu/drachma dropped to 305.75 when a major foreign bank came out selling 200 million ecus but recovered to close at 306 as the same bank bought back 130 million ecus.</p>
<p>Dealers said more forex inflows followed suit after the fixing.</p>
<p>Other dealers said the opening of new ecu/drachma positions and the roll-over of maturing ones accounted for the forex inflows that had sent one-year implied drachma rates down to 11.35 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;One-year implied drachma rates are trading at 11.35 percent from 11.75 percent on Thursday,&quot; said a money dealer at a private bank. &quot;There is plenty of liquidity from the forex as new ecu/drachma positions are opened and it weighs down on the yield curve.&quot;</p>
<p>The central bank's reputation in navigating ecu/drachma succesfully through stormy weather and the still high interest rate differentials favouring the drachma account for the willingness of market players to take the risk in ecu/drachma.</p>
<p>The central bank kept its overnight bid unchanged at 12.40 percent. Market participants have been expecting the central bank to slash its intervention bid soon.</p>
<p>Bond dealers said there was modest to thin buying interest for non-taxable bonds in the secondary market mainly fuelled by retailers who wanted to get higher net yields that those offered by the taxable 12-month T-bills.</p>
<p>The 12-month T-bills issued on January 2 offered a gross yield of 11.20 percent or a net yield of 10.36 percent after the 7.5 percent withholding tax.</p>
<p>The finance ministry said in a statement that T-bill sales amounted to about 400 billion drachmas exceeding expiries of 335 billion drachmas.</p>
<p>The mark was quoted at 157.95/05 drachmas from Friday's 158.390 fix, the dollar at 245.14/24 drachmas from 247.030 and the Ecu at 305.41/51 from 306.000 drachmas.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Greece, the domestic money market's biggest player, quoted the following late rates:</p>
<p>** Overnight at 11.90-12.40</p>
<p>** T/N at 12.00-12.50</p>
<p>** S/N at 12.00-12.50</p>
<p>** One week at 12.00-12.50</p>
<p>** Two weeks at 12.00-12.50</p>
<p>** Three weeks at 11.95-12.45</p>
<p>** One month at 11.95-12.45</p>
<p>** Two months at 11.90-12.40</p>
<p>** Three months at 11.85-12.35</p>
<p>** Six months at 11.80-12.30</p>
<p>** Nine months at 11.75-12.25</p>
<p>** Twelve months at 11.70-12.20</p>
<p>--Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
