<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="286381" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German equities end bourse in positive territory.</title>
<headline>German equities end bourse in positive territory.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's DAX share index ended bourse trade on Friday slightly higher, boosted by interest from German domestic fund managers and a strong performance from German Bunds.</p>
<p>At the end of the session the DAX-30 index of German blue-chip shares stood at 2,859.28 points, up 10.51 points. Dealers said that the strength of German bonds underpinned the equity market.</p>
<p>&quot;The German market seems to be in better shape than other markets. There seems to be German domestic funds committing cash -- they have been light on equities so far and now they seem to be putting some money in,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>German shares made a strong recovery in early trade. Shares on Thursday were hit by the initially weak performance of U.S. equities, but a late U.S. rally gave German shares a much-needed early boost.</p>
<p>The main data of the morning was German November industrial output data, which rose 1.6 percent month-on-month, compared to a fall of 0.7 percent in October.</p>
<p>The DAX index seemed underwhelmed by the data and did not move appreciably up or down. &quot;People weren't watching the output data. The market doesn't seem to be concentrating on the macroeconomic data,&quot; a trader said. Many market players were still enjoying the last days of their Christmas holidays. Dealers said that Monday would be the first meaningful day for the German share market, but that low volumes could lead to market volatility.</p>
<p>Commerzbank AG saw respectable volumes among the banks, ending up 1.05 marks at 39.80 marks, followed by Dresdner Bank AG, which ended bourse up 10 pfennigs at 45.40 marks.</p>
<p>There was also strong interest in the chemical sector, which suffered after the dollar fell sharply on Thursday, but recovered as the dollar moved back up towards the 1.55-mark level.</p>
<p>BASF AG ended up 68 pfennigs at 58.70 marks, Hoechst AG ended up 38 pfennigs at 70.46 marks and Bayer AG closed up 23 pfennigs at 62 marks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
