<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="286375" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Portugal shares seen rising up to 20 pct 1997.</title>
<headline>Portugal shares seen rising up to 20 pct 1997.</headline>
<byline>Paula Cordeiro</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lisbon shares are set to rise by up to 20 percent in 1997 because of a strengthening economy, relatively cheap share prices and an ambitious privatisation programme, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The market could rise by 15 to 20 percent in 1997. I think the first three of four months of the year will be good,&quot; said Jose Freire of Espirito Santo Research (ESR).</p>
<p>&quot;The fundamentals of the economy are sound and the market is not expensive when compared to others,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Nuno Thomaz of Lisbon broker Titulo said: &quot;I think the market will rise by between 10 and 15 percent in the first half of the year.&quot;</p>
<p>Joao Vermelho of Central Banco de Investimentos said the market had potential to grow by 20 percent in 1997 as investors anticipated falling interest rates and inflation and a reduction in the budget deficit.</p>
<p>However, he warned of a possible correction in the short term, especially if Wall Street tumbled.</p>
<p>The PSI20 index  .PSI20 of 20 leading stocks rose by some 32 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>Vermelho said of 1997: &quot;The growth of the economy will assist a recovery in corporate results.&quot;</p>
<p>Vermelho said he expected the earnings per share (EPS) of a sample of 32 Portuguese companies which represent about a third of the total market capitalisation of Lisbon bourse to rise by 25 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>The total market capitalisation of Lisbon bourse at end-1996 was 10,600 billion escudos ($67.9 billion).</p>
<p>A survey by Espirito Santo Research, which covered 90 percent of the market capitalisation of the Lisbon bourse, estimated that the price earnings ratio (PER) of the domestic market would stand at 15 in 1997, compared with 14 in both Spain and Britain, 18.5 in France, 19.5 in Germany and 16 in Italy.</p>
<p>Among a sample of 40 actively traded companies on Lisbon bourse, Titulo's Thomaz forecast average EPS growth of 30 percent in 1997 and an average PER of 12.5.</p>
<p>ESR's Freire forecast average EPS growth of 18 percent in 1997, compared with 33 percent growth in 1996.</p>
<p>ESR's forecast drop in Portuguese companies' EPS in 1997, compared with 1996, was partly due to an expected dilution in bank profits caused by several recent capital increases.</p>
<p>Another factor was the exclusion of an expected increase in profits of pulp companies from its study owing to the cyclical nature of the industry.</p>
<p>Analysts warned that it was difficult to make accurate forecasts for the share market in the second half of 1997.</p>
<p>Analysts said the continuing privatisation programme in 1997, notably the selloff of up to 30 percent of electricity group EDP-Electricidade de Portugal in the first half, would attract investors to the local market.</p>
<p>The success of recent privatisations and a climate of falling interest rates would stimulate investor interest, analysts said.</p>
<p>Privatisations will boost the liquidity of the Lisbon bourse and increase its market capitalisation, which will make Portuguese stocks a more attractive long term investment, they added.</p>
<p>The 1997 budget projects 410 billion escudos in revenues from privatisations this year.</p>
<p>-- Lisbon newsroom +351-1-3538254 ($ = 156.1 Portugese Escudos)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
