<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28647" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: MISSING POLISH JOURNALIST FOUND, MYSTERY CONTINUES.</title>
<headline>MISSING POLISH JOURNALIST FOUND, MYSTERY CONTINUES.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A prominent Polish investigative journalist, whose week-long disappearance prompted a nationwide search, has been found alive in Warsaw -- but mystery still surrounds the episode, private Radio Zet reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Jerzy Slawomir Mac, known for his probes into intelligence and crime issues for the weekly Wprost, was spotted sitting groggily on a bench at a Warsaw railway station early on Monday and later discharged himself from hospital.</p>
<p>He declined to speak with other reporters.</p>
<p>Mac vanished on Tuesday last week after telling office colleagues he was going for a stroll.</p>
<p>Wprost deputy editor Marek Zieleniewski told Radio Zet that Mac said he had been abducted from a nearby park by two men.</p>
<p>&quot;Suddenly he saw two men. He heard the word 'police', and lost consciousness,&quot; Zieleniewski said.</p>
<p>&quot;We can suppose that he was held against his will, in an unspecified place. He remembers little of the period -- laughter, darkness -- and regained consciousness not far from the station,&quot; Zieleniewski said.</p>
<p>A witness present when railway employees recognised Mac at the station said he was incoherent and looked drugged.</p>
<p>Police, who launched a major search for Mac, are investigating the episode.</p>
<p>In March arsonists set fire to Mac's apartment and he suggested the attack could be tied to his reports on political and intelligence issues, but police later said the attack was revenge for a complaint he made against local drug dealers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
