<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="286529" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian dollar struggles to reclaim losses.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian dollar struggles to reclaim losses.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar reclaimed some lost ground in a thin market on Friday, stabilising above US$0.7900 after fall of half a cent overnight.</p>
<p>Trade was again affected by the closure of Tokyo for New Year's holidays, but market liquidity should return to more normal levels next week with the reopening of Tokyo, and the first major data releases of the year, traders said.</p>
<p>By 4.30 p.m. (0530 GMT) the Australian dollar was at US$0.7915/20, untraded for almost 20 minutes, up on its opening US$0.7908/13 and overnight low of US$0.7895.  </p>
<p>However, it failed to recoup all off its overnight U.S. dollar-led losses, finishing down on Thursday's US$0.7941/46 close.</p>
<p>After a very quiet two weeks around Christmas and New Year, trade is expected to pick up next week.</p>
<p>Early on, local events will be the focus, before attention turns to U.S. PPI and payrolls data next Thursday and Friday.</p>
<p>Monday sees the release of the November current account deficit, which despite a 1.2 percent rise in imports, is expected to come in at A$1.75 billion, almost level with October.  </p>
<p>Tuesday sees the release of November retail trade and building approvals data.</p>
<p>While still important, economists said any weakness may be discounted by the fact that there had been rate cuts in both November and December that would not yet have made an impact on the series.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar had followed the U.S. dollar down overnight, when the U.S dollar was weakened by selling in U.S. asset markets following the release of a stronger-than-expected December NAPM index.  </p>
<p>However, with the stock market recovering in late New York to finish almost level on the day, the U.S. dollar recovered its losses. After a quiet morning in Asia it weakened slightly in the afternoon, but the local dollar was flat on the crosses.</p>
<p>In trade weighted terms the unit was unchanged through the day at 58.9, after opening down from Thursday's 59.1 close. It was the first close below 59.0 since December 19.</p>
<p>Against the yen, the Australian unit ended at 91.36/46, almost level with an opening 91.38/48 but, once again, down on Thursday's 91.96/92.06 finish.  </p>
<p>While the unit was under some pressure on Thursday night, and may weaken further if there is renewed U.S. dollar selling offshore, analysts said the unit remained well supported.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite a tentative start to the new year, there is little reason to expect support to fall away markedly over coming months,&quot; Commonwealth Bank economists said in a commentary.</p>
<p>Key support at US$0.7810 was not expected to be challenged in the near term, and while US$0.8000 was generally seen as a topside cap while speculation of further rate cuts remained, there are those who remain bullish on the Australian dollar's prospects in 1997.  </p>
<p>&quot;For 1997, there are sound reasons to expect the Australian dollar to move even higher, sustaining a break above US$0.80 and testing US$0.85 at some stage during the year,&quot; Citibank Australia chief economist Stephen Koukoulas said in a report.</p>
<p>His outlook were based on continued low inflation, further fiscal tightening, maintenance of favourable interest rate differentials at around current levels, further progess in micro-economic reform and the current account deficit remaining at around four percent of GDP.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
