<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="286585" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia late palm olein stable on good demand.</title>
<headline>Indonesia late palm olein stable on good demand.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian palm olein prices were mostly steady in late trading on Friday, after rising in the early session, on sustained buying interest, traders said.</p>
<p>They said olein was quoted at 1,455-60 rupiah/kg in Jakarta, unchanged from the opening but higher than Thursday's close of 1,450-55 rupiah. No crude palm oil deals were heard.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand was still there although it was not as active in the morning session,&quot; one trader said. &quot;Players are beginning to return to the market after the holiday season.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said they expected prices to trend steady next week on continued buying interest and talk of tight supply.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think prices will be steady next week, with more buyers returning to the market,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's also been talk of tight prompt-delivery olein supply because of good crude palm oil exports last month,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Earlier, a government official denied rumours that the state-run Joint Marketing Board, which markets all crude palm oil produced by state plantations, had suspended exports from January to March. &quot;This is not true. We are keeping to our schedule and there has been no suspension,&quot; he told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Traders said there had been rumours, emerging from Malaysia, the marketing board had suspended exports because it wanted to ensure there was sufficient oil in the local market during the Moslem fasting month of Ramadan which begins later this month.</p>
<p>&quot;We did suspend exports in October because we had oversold, but the situation has been rectified,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>-- K.T. Arasu, Jakarta newsroom + 6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
