<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="286799" id="root" date="1997-01-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks end lacklustre day lower.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks end lacklustre day lower.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-01-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian share market closed lower on Friday after a volatile Wall Street kept local investors nervous.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index dipped 11.7 points to 2,399.5.</p>
<p>The market muddled about within a six-point range for all but the first 30 minutes of trade in the last day of the Christmas-New Year hiatus. Volumes remained subdued with many players still away.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was a bit lower which was not altogether surprising on the back of what we got from overseas, but we won't have a return to normal trading until Monday,&quot; said Andrew Sekely, head of equities at brokerage Intersuisse, pointing to the dull day's lack of activity.</p>
<p>&quot;It really has been quite featureless.&quot;</p>
<p>Among the bigger stocks, retailers suffered late in the day after upmarket department store operator David Jones slashed its profit forecast, citing continued depressed conditions in the retail sector. David Jones shares closed five percent lower at A$1.67 (US$1.32). Shares in rival operator, Coles Myer, also softened after the David Jones announcement to end three percent lower at A$5.08.</p>
<p>Kingstream Resources sparked some activity early after the company said it planned to merge with An Feng Steel Co Ltd, its Taiwan-based partner in the proposed A$1.4 billion Midwest Iron and Steel project in Western Australia.</p>
<p>Kingstream shares climbed seven percent to close at A$1.02.</p>
<p>Falls outnumbered rises by a ratio of about nine to seven, while about 35 percent of stocks traded remained steady.</p>
<p>(A$1=US$0.7923)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
