<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="287124" id="root" date="1997-01-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FULL TEXT - Apple sees Q1 operating loss.</title>
<headline>FULL TEXT - Apple sees Q1 operating loss.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-01-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Apple Computer Inc Friday said it expects to report an operating loss for the three months ended in December. The following is a copy of Apple's statement.</p>
<p>----------------------- NEWS RELEASE ------------------</p>
<p>CUPERTINO, Calif., Jan. 3 /PRNewswire/ -- Apple Computer, Inc. (Nasdaq: AAPL) today said that it has completed a preliminary review of financial results for its first fiscal quarter which ended Dec. 27, 1996.  The Company reported that while unit sales of its Power Macintosh and PowerBook lines of products exceeded internal plans, it experienced overall weakness in U.S. demand for the Company's Performa line of consumer-oriented products. This, coupled with anticipated shortages of new PowerBook models, contributed to an overall sequential revenue decline of approximately 10 percent from the September quarter, for which the Company reported revenues of $2.3 billion.</p>
<p>The Company indicated that it expects to report an operating loss of between $100 million and $150 million for the quarter when actual results are announced on Jan. 15, 1997. These estimates are preliminary and based on partial information and management assumptions.</p>
<p>&quot;Though consumer demand for personal computers in the U.S. was soft for the industry in general last quarter, the weakness in demand for Performa products in the U.S. is an obvious disappointment,&quot; said Fred Anderson, Apple's executive vice president and Chief Financial Officer.  &quot;Nonetheless, the quarter delivered positive results in other areas: We are encouraged by the strength of demand for our Power Macintosh and PowerBook products.  We experienced nearly 40 percent year-over-year unit growth in server sales during the quarter. And our development efforts for an exciting new product year in 1997 remain on track.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Our previously-articulated three-year strategic plan remains sound, and we continue to lay the groundwork for the transformation of Apple,&quot; said Apple Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Dr. Gilbert F. Amelio.  &quot;Our pending acquisition of NeXT Software, Inc. gives Apple the industry's most innovative and powerful Internet and software technology portfolio.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very pleased with the success in the first quarter of our PowerBook product transition.  Our disappointing Performa sales, however, dictate that we develop additional restructuring plans during the second fiscal quarter,&quot; said Dr. Amelio.  &quot;These results suggest that we need to reduce Apple's cost infrastructure so that we can achieve break-even results at a revenue level of $8 billion.  We expect that the NeXT acquisition will contribute to this cost-reduction process by enabling us to bypass some costly internal R&amp;D activities.&quot;</p>
<p>The intended acquisition of NeXT Software, Inc., announced by Apple on Dec. 20, 1996, is expected to bring together Apple's and NeXT's innovative and complementary technology portfolios and strengthen Apple's position as a company advancing industry standards.  Apple's leadership in ease of use and multimedia solutions will be married to NeXT's strengths in development software and operating environments for both the enterprise and Internet markets.  NeXT's object oriented software development products are expected to contribute to Apple's goal of creating a differentiated and profitable software business, with a wide range of products for enterprise, business, education, and home markets.</p>
<p>Except for the historical information contained herein, the statements regarding establishing competitive leadership, effecting innovation, integration of NeXT Software, Inc.'s products and technologies, introducing new products, continuing focus on certain industry growth areas, reduction of the Company's breakeven point, and the timing of execution of the Company's business plans are forward-looking statements that involve risks and uncertainties. Potential risks and uncertainties include, without limitation, continued competitive pressures in the marketplace; the effect competitive factors and the Company's reaction to them may have on consumer and business buying decisions with respect to the Company's products; the consequences competitive factors and buying decisions may have on current inventory valuations; the Company's ability to consummate the acquisition of NeXT Software, Inc. and successfully integrate its personnel, products and operations; the ability of the Company to make timely delivery of successful technological innovations to the marketplace; the ability of the Company to successfully resolve its quality issues; the effect of any future losses on the Company's needs for liquidity; the effect of the announced business restructuring on the future performance of the Company, especially the performance of the Company's employees; and the need for any future restructuring, and the effect that it might have on the performance of the Company. More information on potential factors that could affect the Company's financial results is included in the Company's Form 10-K for the 1996 fiscal year and will also be included in the Company's Form 10-Q for the first fiscal quarter, to be filed with the SEC.</p>
<p>			 ------------------------</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
