<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="287385" id="root" date="1997-01-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CENTRAL AFRICAN REPUBLIC: French reprisals kill 10 Bangui army mutineers.</title>
<headline>French reprisals kill 10 Bangui army mutineers.</headline>
<byline>Raphael Kopessoua</byline>
<dateline>BANGUI 1997-01-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>French troops killed at least 10 Central African Republic army mutineers on Sunday in helicopter-led reprisal raids after the killing of two French officers on a multinational mediation mission.</p>
<p>The French Defence Ministry in Paris accused mutineers of shooting the two unarmed officers in cold blood on Saturday and said the raids, which also used tanks and armoured personnel carriers, were in self-defence.</p>
<p>Witnesses said French helicopter gunships fired on the mutineers' command posts in Kassai army camp and other areas of the capital Bangui under their control in the operation that began in the middle of the night.</p>
<p>A French defence ministry spokesman said 10 mutineers were killed and 30 were taken prisoner.</p>
<p>Spokesmen for the mutineers put the death toll among their ranks at 21 and said 11 civilians had also been killed around their headquarters in the populous southern district of Petevo.</p>
<p>Calm returned to the city later in the day but residents reported an exodus of civilians from rebel areas.</p>
<p>&quot;The aim of this French operation was solely an act of self-defence against two particularly cowardly murders,&quot; a French Foreign Ministry spokesman said in Paris.</p>
<p>&quot;Our aim is not to put down the mutineers, our aim is to ensure that the Central African republic can continue its democratic process,&quot; he told Radio France International.</p>
<p>A French military spokesman in Bangui told reporters French troops had wrested control from the mutineers of the port and its fuel supplies and a short-wave radio transmitter.</p>
<p>The Central African Republic is in the grip of its third army revolt within a year. French troops, in the former colony under a defence pact, intervened to keep President Ange-Felix Patasse in power during the second revolt in May.</p>
<p>Hundreds of people have been killed in violence associated with the revolts that were initially about pay but have turned into a campaign to oust Patasse, a civilian elected in 1993 during the impoverished nation's democratic transition.</p>
<p>The French defence ministry said AK-47 automatic rifles, machine-guns and rocket-propelled grenade launchers were seized in Sunday's operation in which two armed helicopters took part.</p>
<p>&quot;It was an operation in reaction to the deliberate killing by mutineers of a French officer and junior officer...and to new attacks and shooting which have targeted us in the city,&quot; the French military spokesman in Bangui said.</p>
<p>&quot;There were no dead among the French forces, who remain particularly determined and vigilant,&quot; the ministry said.</p>
<p>A rebel spokesman, giving his name as Lieutenant Mbeaye, condemned the killing of the two French soldiers but told Reuters that 11 civilians, including children, were killed in Sunday's French attack on rebel headquarters in Petevo. He said 21 mutineers were also killed.</p>
<p>&quot;France is killing the Central African people. It's open war but the solution cannot be a military one,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The defence ministry in Paris said the two soldiers were ambushed and murdered by mutineers on Saturday while with a mediating team led by officers from Chad and Burkina Faso.</p>
<p>Witnesses said three civilians were killed on Saturday when French troops and mutineers clashed in Bangui after civilians supporting the mutineers tried to move towards the city centre.</p>
<p>The latest revolt began on November 16. The first was in April.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGUI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CENTRAL AFRICAN REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
