<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="287386" id="root" date="1997-01-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Two white miners arrested after S.African blasts.</title>
<headline>Two white miners arrested after S.African blasts.</headline>
<byline>Juliette Saunders</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-01-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African police have arrested two white men in connection with Sunday's three bomb blasts near Johannesburg, the second incident in two weeks involving attacks by suspected white rightwingers.</p>
<p>The explosions at a mosque, post office and shop occurred around midnight at and around the conservative town of Rustenburg in North West region.</p>
<p>Two black men sleeping at the mosque were slightly hurt in the explosion, which stopped the mosque's clock at exactly 12 minutes past one on Sunday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;I woke up (and) thought it is an earthquake,&quot; said Moemin Isaac Ibrahim, speaking from his hospital bed where he was being treated for a leg wound. He said he was from the Sudan on a visit to South Africa.</p>
<p>Two white mineworkers were arrested in connection with the blasts at a roadblock outside the small platinum mining town of Mooi Nooi on Sunday morning.</p>
<p>Police Captain Belinda Kleynhans said Christiaan Harmse, 26, and Pierre Jacobs, 32, were taken to court after their arrests. Their case was postponed to January 10. They were refused bail by the court and would be kept in custody, she said.</p>
<p>Explosives materials were allegedly found in the car they were driving and at one of the men's homes, Kleynhans said. They were in a car similar to one seen outside the mosque before the bomb went off, and at the shop blast.</p>
<p>The country's Moslem Judicial Council president, Nazeem Mohammed, told state radio the council would meet later on Sunday to plan strong action in reply to the mosque attack.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have to retaliate in a manner that will make the country know that acts of such a nature are not only unwanted but are something that call for the condemnation of all the people of the country,&quot; Mohammed said.</p>
<p>Police said they were investigating ties between the North West blasts and a Christmas Eve bombing that killed four people in a town 90 km (55 miles) northeast of Cape Town.</p>
<p>An unknown white right-wing group called the Boere Attack Troop (BAT) has claimed resposibility for the twin pipe bomb attack at a supermarket and pharmacy in Worcester.</p>
<p>The resurgence of white right activity has prompted some political analysts to draw a link between the blasts and President Nelson Mandela's extension of the cut-off date for political crimes to be eligible for amnesty -- announced days before the Worcester blasts.</p>
<p>The date was originally set as December 1993, which would have excluded right-wingers who planted bombs that killed 20 people on the eve of South Africa's all-race election in 1994. The cut-off is now May 10, 1994, when Mandela was inaugurated.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that a previous group (of bombers) are being treated as eligible for amnesty might well have encouraged these people to use their bombs as a further pressure point,&quot; political analyst Tom Lodge told Reuters.</p>
<p>David Welsh, a professor of politics at University of Cape Town, disagreed that the extension had acted as a spur for the bombers.</p>
<p>&quot;My sense is that it is a last gasp effort by a small bunch of desperados. I frankly don't see these blasts as the beginning of any large-scale white right insurrection,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hardline right-wingers like Afrikaner Resistance Movement leader Eugene Terre Blanche issued frequent warnings of civil war ahead of the 1994 election, demanding self-rule for Afrikaners, but their potential to cause serious disruption had appeared to dissipate in the last three years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
