<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="287487" id="root" date="1997-01-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs to test downside, support seen at 123.35.</title>
<headline>JGBs to test downside, support seen at 123.35.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Key March Japanese government bond futures are likely to make a try for the downside on Monday, following a sharp fall in the yen versus the dollar overseas.</p>
<p>The yen's fall versus the dollar may continue to weaken Tokyo share prices, and such falls could have a negative impact on JGBs, a trader for a city bank's securities affiliate said.</p>
<p>The March, however, is likely to find solid support at 123.35, which would be the lowest level for a benchmark futures contract since November 11, the trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;JGBs are unlikely to fall below 123.35, especially since there will only be a half-day of trade today,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The Tokyo JGB market will be closed on Monday afternoon. Regular full-day trade will resume on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Investors are unlikely to move aggressively ahead of a 10-year JGB auction expected to take place on Thursday, traders said. The coupon rate is likely to be either 2.7 percent or 2.8 percent, they said.</p>
<p>Although investors would prefer a coupon rate of three percent or above, since a sudden rise in JGB yields to such levels is unlikely, a coupon rate of around 2.7 percent is likely to attract some investors, the trader for the city bank's securities affiliate said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
