<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="287410" id="root" date="1997-01-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELARUS: Opposition politician barred from leaving Belarus.</title>
<headline>Opposition politician barred from leaving Belarus.</headline>
<dateline>MINSK 1997-01-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Belarus leader Stanislav Shushkevich said on Sunday that border guards had prevented him from flying to Poland, in the second such action against an opposition politician in less than a month.</p>
<p>Shushkevich, who led Belarus to independence from the Soviet Union in 1991, said he was told his diplomatic passport was no longer valid when he tried to fly out from Minsk airport on Saturday.</p>
<p>He had been due to attend a political symposium at Warsaw University.</p>
<p>&quot;My diplomatic passport is valid until the year 2001 and there is no law cancelling it,&quot; Shushkevich told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;The border guards showed me a two-page list written by the foreign ministry. There were no names on it -- only passport numbers, including mine. It's obvious that in Belarus there is no law and justice at all.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the flight he had been due to take was delayed for 90 minutes because of the incident.</p>
<p>Shushkevich said he had asked the foreign ministry whether he had the right to a diplomatic passport or should receive another one, but received no answer.</p>
<p>President Alexander Lukashenko, who won a referendum last November which gave him sweeping powers, has taken a tough line against his opponents.</p>
<p>Semyon Sharetsky, speaker of the parliament which has been dissolved by Lukashenko and replaced by a new chamber, was prevented from going to Poland by border guards last month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINSK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELARUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
