<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="287442" id="root" date="1997-01-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru hostage takers seen scoring propaganda coup.</title>
<headline>Peru hostage takers seen scoring propaganda coup.</headline>
<byline>Paul Hughes</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-01-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>With its spectacular assault on the Japanese ambassador's residence in Lima, Peru's Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) has demonstrated that a small, marginalized group can make the world sit up and take notice.</p>
<p>Much to the distress of Peru's President Alberto Fujimori, the 20-odd rebels have dominated news broadcasts and gotten headlines around the world since storming the residence on Dec. 17 and seizing scores of hostages.</p>
<p>&quot;Really, for them it has been a stupendous image campaign,&quot; said Hugo Guerra, editor of local newspaper El Comercio.</p>
<p>Though they are heavily armed with grenade launchers, explosives and automatic rifles, the rebels have so far found publicity to be their most effective weapon.</p>
<p>The MRTA -- which according to local analysts, counts on less than 100 active members -- may have taken its lead from Mexico's Zapatista rebels, who have buffered their weak military capability by cultivating the public image of masked leader Subcommander Marcos as an intellectual and a poet.</p>
<p>From crude signs to the latest cyberspace technology -- like the Zapatistas, the MRTA has a World Wide Web home page maintained by supporters abroad -- the Marxist rebels have thwarted Fujimori's attempts to play down the crisis.</p>
<p>Furious and embarrassed after the stunning attack at the diplomatic mansion of one of Peru's most important trading partners, Fujimori tried to isolate the rebels by cutting off power and communications to the residence.</p>
<p>But the rebels have shown remarkable ingenuity in getting their message out, using statements read by hostages, messages placed in windows and even information placed on the Internet.</p>
<p>People all over the world have heard that they took the residence in a bid to effect the release of about 400 imprisoned comrades. They have also been told that the rebels are not mistreating their VIP hostages, that they reject the label &quot;terrorists&quot; and are open to talks with the government.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear that the MRTA want to appear as people who, instead of being victimisers, are victims and defenders of just causes,&quot; said Carlos Tapia, Peru's leading authority on guerrilla movements.</p>
<p>While Fujimori has spoken in public only twice since the crisis broke, the rebels last week gave a photo opportunity to journalists outside the compound and let them inside for an impromptu news conference.</p>
<p>Images of guerrilla leader Nestor Cerpa, dressed in military fatigues and with his face partially covered by a bandanna bearing the MRTA emblem, were broadcast worldwide.</p>
<p>Whenever media attention has shown any sign of flagging as the crisis drags on, the rebels have released a few more hostages.</p>
<p>The publicity around the siege has led to scrutiny of Fujimori's government at a particularly difficult time. Amid a faltering domestic economy, the president's popularity has fallen to its lowest level since he came to power in 1990.</p>
<p>The hostage crisis came just as Fujimori has been seeking support to run for a third term in 2000 -- and one of the cornerstones of his appeal has been a claim to have virtually wiped out insurgent activity after 16 years of violence.</p>
<p>The issues raised by the rebels have led to closer examination of Peru's economic policies and the conditions in which people imprisoned under emergency terrorist legislation are being kept.</p>
<p>Local media have tried to counteract the rebels' publicity gains by reminding viewers and readers that the MRTA is a guerrilla group, and referring to the hostage takers by the government's preferred term of &quot;terrorists.&quot;</p>
<p>But many Peruvians acknowledge that, so far, the MRTA is winning the war of words.</p>
<p>&quot;They clearly have a temporary advantage over the government,&quot; Guerra said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
