<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="287492" id="root" date="1997-01-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China capital calls for more Taiwan investment.</title>
<headline>China capital calls for more Taiwan investment.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-01-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's capital Beijing has called on muncipal departments to cut red tape in a bid to boost investment from Taiwan, the Xinhua news agency said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Beijing Municipal People's Political Consultative Conference, an advisory body, had issued a report urging the city government to set up a special office to handle investment from the island and reduce bureaucratic hurdles, Xinhua said.</p>
<p>Priority should be given to high technology firms.</p>
<p>China views Taiwan as a renegade province and has threatened to use force to reunify the island.</p>
<p>Taiwan bans direct trade and investment but it has allowed contacts made through third territories such as Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Taiwan President Lee Teng-hui said last year the island should curtail its investments in China to avoid economic reliance on the mainland.</p>
<p>Some 1,450 Taiwanese firms had invested a total of $1.8 billion in Beijing by the end of last September, with most of those funds going into electronics, clothing, food, petrochemicals and machine-building, Xinhua said.</p>
<p>But it said investment from each company was relatively small and Taiwanese firms with interests in the capital tended to seek short-term profits.</p>
<p>Beijing has in the past issued regulations -- which were later rescinded -- compelling children of Taiwan businessmen to go to Chinese rather than foreign-run schools. It also has been stricter on visas for some Taiwan citizens.</p>
<p>In a separate report by the official news agency, the eastern province of Fujian, which is closest to Taiwan, vowed to improve its laws to try to boost economic and social contacts with the island.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
