<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="287500" id="root" date="1997-01-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Peru kidnappers demanded $100 million - report.</title>
<headline>Peru kidnappers demanded $100 million - report.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The guerrillas holding hostages at the Japanese ambasador's home in Lima, Peru, had tried to get $100 million in ransom from Japanese companies but now seek up to $30 million, a Japanese newspaper reported on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Mainichi Shimbun said the Marxist guerrillas of the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement had demanded the cash in exchange for freeing senior Japanese executives who were among the more than 400 people taken hostage on December 17.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto told reporters on Sunday he was not aware of any ransom demands and the Japanese government had not been approached by the rebels.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Japanese Foreign Ministry asked about the report on Sunday said that government policy was to refuse to answer any such questions for the sake of the hostages.</p>
<p>Among the Japanese executives believed held in the compound are the presidents of the Peruvian operations of Mitsui Mining and Smelting Co., Mitsubishi Corp. and Toyota Motor Corp.</p>
<p>The paper, quoting &quot;informed sources,&quot; said the group demanded the money as a &quot;war tax&quot;.</p>
<p>It said the Japanese companies rejected the demand, prompting the group to lower the amount to $30 million &quot;or less&quot;.</p>
<p>It said the president of a Japanese company it contacted but did not identify had heard about the ransom demand but had rejected any idea of making a payment.</p>
<p>Officials from the three firms were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Britain's Independent on Sunday newspaper first published reports of ransom demands on December 22, quoting a European diplomat. Tokyo dismissed the reports at the time as baseless.</p>
<p>After a series of hostage releases, the group is still holding 74 people. Japanese officials say prospects for ending the standoff anytime soon are poor.</p>
<p>The guerrillas want the release of some 400 jailed comrades. Peru President Alberto Fujimori has refused the demand.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I11000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
