<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="287558" id="root" date="1997-01-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SYRIA: Syria says bus bombers will not escape punishment.</title>
<headline>Syria says bus bombers will not escape punishment.</headline>
<dateline>DAMASCUS 1997-01-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Syrian Prime Minister Mahmoud Zu'bi said on Sunday that bombers of a bus in central Damascus would not escape punishment.</p>
<p>Medical sources said on Sunday that two more people had died of their wounds, bringing the toll in the New Year's eve blast in the Syrian capital to 11 killed and 42 wounded.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who committed this terrorist, cowardly act will not escape punishment,&quot; Zu'bi told reporters while visiting the injured in hospital.</p>
<p>Syria's first report about the explosion, made on Thursday, said nine people were killed and 44 wounded.</p>
<p>The Syrian government accused agents of the Israeli intelligence Mossad service of being responsible for the attack. Israel denied the accusation.</p>
<p>The Syrian government has not released any details about the investigation six days after the explosion.</p>
<p>Zu'bi conveyed President Hafez al-Assad's sincere condolences to the families of those killed and expressed his best wishes for speedy recovery for the wounded, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;This ugly criminal act will not achieve its purposes and will not harm the independent will of our people or the stability which our nation is enjoying,&quot; Zu'bi said during the tour.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SYRIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAMASCUS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SYRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
