<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="287690" id="root" date="1997-01-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: FEATURE - Stockholm's clean water hook salmon, trout anglers.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Stockholm's clean water hook salmon, trout anglers.</headline>
<byline>Ed Stoddard</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-01-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standing near Sweden's Royal Palace on a cold wintry night, Franco cast his heavy baited line into the freezing waters that run through the centre of Stockholm.</p>
<p>&quot;I've caught around 500 salmon in Stockholm over the past 20 years,&quot; says Franco, an Italian who moved to Sweden more than 30 years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Here's my most recent catch,&quot; he said, proudly displaying the one that didn't get away -- a four kg (8.82 lb) beauty.</p>
<p>Shortly afterwards, another angler caught a 35 cm (13.7 inch) sea trout which he promptly released.</p>
<p>&quot;It's rather small,&quot; says Franco. &quot;Most fishermen release salmon or sea trout that are less than 50 cm (19.7 inches).&quot;</p>
<p>Every night throughout the year, anglers line the banks of the &quot;stream&quot; running through Stockholm's picturesque Old Town, in reality a body of fresh water called the Strommen which separates the Malaren lake on one side of the city from the Baltic Sea on the other side.</p>
<p>For most Europeans, it is hard to imagine schools of Atlantic salmon and sea trout swimming through the heart of a European capital.</p>
<p>Marine biologists say that salmon and trout require almost pristine conditions to survive. Their presence in Stockholm -- in encouraging numbers -- is a clear sign that the city's water is clean and the aquatic habitats beneath the surface healthy.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a point of pride for Stockholmers that their water is clean enough for Atlantic salmon,&quot; says Lennart Nyman, a conservation officer with the Swedish branch of the World Wide Fund for Nature. &quot;It shows that the quality of the water is very good.&quot;</p>
<p>POLLUTION EFFORTS INTRODUCED IN THE 50s</p>
<p>An effort to clean the city's waters was launched in the 1950s when industrial and sewage controls were introduced to cut polllution levels.</p>
<p>Residents and tourists alike are allowed to fish free of charge and without permits in Stockholm, making it about the only free activity in this Nordic capital where even &quot;happy hour&quot; prices in bars can quickly empty a wallet.</p>
<p>Feeless fishing is part of a tradition that goes back to 1436, when the City Council granted wealthy burghers the right to fish the Crown waters in and around the city.</p>
<p>These rights were given royal sanction in 1636 by Queen Christina and successive monarchs. In 1860, the privilege of angling in Crown waters was extended to all of Stockholm's inhabitants, including visitors.</p>
<p>Salmon and sea trout, however, were not caught in the city's waters until the 1970s.</p>
<p>&quot;Salmon are not native to the Stockholm Strommen,&quot; says Nyman. &quot;There is no place for them to spawn and the system is filled with predators.&quot;</p>
<p>Salmon and sea trout were first introduced in Strommen in 1973, when 500 hatchery-reared two-year-old smolt were released by the city's sports federation.</p>
<p>Two years later, the experiment proved a success when some returned from the Baltic Sea.</p>
<p>Since then, around 600,000 salmon and sea trout smolt have been released under a programme sponsored by the City Council, the National Board of Fisheries and the State Power Board (Vattenfall).</p>
<p>&quot;We release about 25,000 salmon and sea trout smolt each year, and estimate that around 25 percent return,&quot; says Kjell Winstrom, a fisheries biologist at Vattenfall. &quot;About 800 sea trout and over 100 salmon were taken in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;They usually come back in two to three years' time and grow quite quickly. They weigh around 100 grammes when they are released and average five kg to 10 kg (11-22 lb) when they come back.&quot;</p>
<p>FISH of RECORD SIZE</p>
<p>Some grow to be enormous. The record salmon taken from Stockholm's waters, just south of the parliament, weighed in at 19.4 kg (42.77 lb).</p>
<p>Trophies of that size are tempting bait which lure anglers to the city's Old Town on long, freezing Nordic nights.</p>
<p>The salmon introduction scheme in Stockholm is part of a larger national programme which has seen almost two million smolt released in more than 30 Swedish rivers. Around 90 percent of Sweden's salmon population has been domestically reared.</p>
<p>But the programme has not been a complete success.</p>
<p>&quot;The domestically-hatched salmon all over Sweden have been plagued by M-74 disease, a vitamin deficiency passed by mothers to their young. Newly-hatched smolt with the disease don't begin feeding and die,&quot; says Dr Lars Karlssonm, a fisheries biologist with the Swedish Salmon Research Institute.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been unable to detect the source of the disease in the food chain.&quot;</p>
<p>Karlsson said the country's off-shore commercial salmon catch fell in 1995 to 2,892 tonnes from 5,600 tonnes in 1990.</p>
<p>Still, the fishing in Stockholm is better than that found in any other European capital.</p>
<p>Franco, for one, is hooked.</p>
<p>&quot;I come here most nights,&quot; he said as he cast his line into the water once more.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
