<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="287728" id="root" date="1997-01-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: WALL ST WEEK AHEAD/Vital data in 1st full '97 week.</title>
<headline>WALL ST WEEK AHEAD/Vital data in 1st full '97 week.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Intindola</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investors in stocks and bonds will get a good look at the state of the economy this week with a series of monthly reports on employment, retail sales and producer prices in the first full week of the new year.</p>
<p>Altogether, the news will give market watchers a solid reading of how the U.S. economy finished 1996 and an early glimpse of how the new year may play out, analysts said.</p>
<p>Selected stocks, meanwhile, are expected to defend against what has become a market ritual before each quarterly earnings season, the pre-announcement of results below Wall Street's expectations.</p>
<p>The month-long earnings deluge begins Jan. 13 with reports from major U.S. banks including J.P. Morgan &amp; Co. Inc. and NationsBank Corp..</p>
<p>Before that, however, Thursday's release of the producer price index for December and Friday's December employment report will widely influence markets, analysts said.</p>
<p>The average forecast for the jobs number is 192,000 new non-farm payrolls, up from 118,000 in November, while the outlook for the widely-watched change in average hourly earnings is up 0.2 percent, versus November's sharp 0.8 rise.</p>
<p>The December Producer Price Index, excluding food and energy, is forecast to increase by 0.1 percent, matching the change in November.</p>
<p>With the volatile food and energy components included, the reading is expected to rise by 0.3 percent, compared with a 0.4 percent November increase.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking for about 180,000 (in new non-farm payrolls), but there is a lot uncertainty for that figure and it is critical because it is the end of the quarter,&quot; said Pierre Ellis, senior economist at Primark Decision Economics.</p>
<p>For December's jobs data, &quot;the seasonal adjustment will define what it will be. Last year, unadjusted employment was up 21,000 and up 237,000 after the adjustment. In the year before that it was up 7,000, and up 248,000 after the adjustment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Charlie Crane, director of research at Spears, Benzak, Salomon &amp; Farrell, said: &quot;The real important number is the employment report and the bond and stock markets will be a little edgy heading into this.</p>
<p>&quot;The financial stocks will amplify whatever happens in the bond market. If we get a weak employment number and bonds trade higher, financial stocks are poised to move up. If the bond market remains as sloppy as it has been for the past few weeks, financial stocks will fall,&quot; Crane said.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones Industrial average closed last week with a 101.6 gain at 6,544. But for the four-session week, which included a 101-point loss Tuesday, the Dow shed almost 17 points.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond finished Friday up 1/32 to 96.30, yielding 6.74 percent.</p>
<p>Crane said he expects the pace of job creation over the next several months to slow significantly &quot;because profits were so uninspiring in 1996.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If earnings are not growing from one year to the next, companies are not going to build their businesses. If anything, they will be prone to be cut. Given the pace of earnings growth in 1996, it will translate into more anaemic job growth this year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Regarding the earnings warnings, Crane said he believes it won't be as dire as the red flags sent up for the prior period, which included admissions from such blue chips as Motorola Inc. and Hewlett-Packard Co. that they would not match expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;The fourth quarter economy was definitely better than the the third quarter, and activity better than anticipated. So I am guessing the pace of disappointments will be diminished relative to the third quarter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Roy Blumberg, chief investment strategist at Josephthal Lyon &amp; Ross, said the U.S. stock market is in &quot;an interim correction in an ongoing bull market. There are a lot of good stocks at bad prices.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The employment data and PPI only have the potiuenal to add to the volatility&quot; that the markets experienced last week, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there will by any big surprise in PPI, close to the consensus. The employment data should, because of the seasonal adjustment, look stronger than reported. This has happended in the last two years.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Brendan Intindola, Wall Street Desk, 212-859-1734)).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
