<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="287717" id="root" date="1997-01-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Twelve killed in clashes in northeast Sri Lanka.</title>
<headline>Twelve killed in clashes in northeast Sri Lanka.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1997-01-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least 12 Tamil Tiger rebels and government soldiers were killed in separate clashes in Sri Lanka's northeast over the weekend, military officials said on Sunday.</p>
<p>An army foot patrol on Saturday afternoon ambushed a group of Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam rebels near Weli Oya, about 240 km (150 miles) from the capital Colombo, killing four rebels and recovering their weapons, they said.</p>
<p>But another group of rebels ambushed the patrol as it returned to base, killing three soldiers and wounding 13, they said.</p>
<p>In eastern Batticaloa district the same day, rebels blew up an army armoured vehicle with a rocket-propelled grenade, killing two soldiers, while 19 soldiers and a civilian were wounded when a landmine exploded near their convoy, officials said.</p>
<p>Two local home guard militiamen also were killed and two wounded when rebels attacked the Kantale police post, 200 km (125 miles) northeast of Colombo early on Sunday, they said.</p>
<p>One of the rebels, who are fighting for an independent homeland for minority Tamils in the north and east of this Indian Ocean island, died in the raid, they added.</p>
<p>Government troops hunting the Tigers in the Batticaloa jungles last week destroyed two abandoned rebel bases.</p>
<p>The Tigers were not immediately available for comment on the military's reports of the latest clashes.</p>
<p>The Tigers said in a statement last week that they had lost more than 9,000 cadres in their war for independence, now in its 14th year.</p>
<p>The government says more than 50,000 people have died in the war. The rebels say the toll is much higher.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
