<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="287937" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ATT estimate cuts highlight phone market worry.</title>
<headline>ATT estimate cuts highlight phone market worry.</headline>
<byline>Nick Louth</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>AT&amp;T Corp shares were savaged on Monday as growing worries about marketing and investment costs in the hyper-competitive U.S. telecom market were reflected in earnings estimate cuts by two brokerages.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T shares plunged 2-3/4 or 6.6 percent to 38-3/4 by late-afternoon, after Salomon Bros. and CS First Boston issued their research.  MCI Communications Corp fell 7/8 to 33 and Sprint Corp 1/2 to 39-1/2 in sympathy.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is in AT&amp;T's court,&quot; said analyst Barry Sine of SBC Warburg.  &quot;The more they spend on marketing their new services for the long term, the lower 1997's results will be,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The market was particularly spooked by a sharp cut in his estimate of AT&amp;T's 1997 earnings per share by Salomon analyst Jack Grubman to $3.00 from $3.60, and to $3.25 from $3.80 for 1998.  Grubman later said his estimates may still be too high.</p>
<p>Most analysts thought this too bearish a view.  Frank Governali of CS First Boston said he only cut his estimate of AT&amp;T's earnings to between $3.25 and $3.45 for 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Salomon's number is for a dire outcome,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I would be shocked if AT&amp;T diluted its 1997 earnings down to $3.00 per share,&quot; said Richard Klugman of PaineWebber.</p>
<p>First Call's analyst consensus for AT&amp;T earnings per share in 1997 is $3.68 and for 1998 $3.98 per share.  For the fourth quarter 1996 it is $0.80 and the 1996 year $3.48.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T declined to comment on the estimate cuts, but a source close to the company said no guidance had come out of the investor relations department to drive them.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not yet determined what 1997 will bring, but it is safe to say we do not agree with the more pessimistic comments,&quot; the source said, declining identification.  </p>
<p>Governali said that AT&amp;T had a choice to make: &quot;Either to run the business for 1997, in which case they could make $3.60 per share, or to position itself for the long-term, in which case there is no way they can.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts say the whole industry faces the same dilemma.</p>
<p>The Telecommunications Act of 1996 will release the regional Bells into the long distance market place this year, on top of a horde of tiny rivals that have been nibbling away at the customers of the big three.  </p>
<p>Though AT&amp;T, MCI and Sprint can enter the local phone market, they will have to stump up hundreds of millions of dollars to to advertise their services, push their brand names and build network facilities to key business customers.</p>
<p>Grubman's research note said that he believed AT&amp;T was losing hundreds of millions on its popular Worldnet Internet access service too, because of high costs.</p>
<p>Analysts say MCI and Sprint have already bitten the bullet by warning analysts of increased spending, but AT&amp;T had not done so.  </p>
<p>&quot;Sprint and MCI have already done it.  MCI's merger with British Telecommunications Plc is a tacit admission of that fact (that you need very deep pockets to succeed),&quot; Governali said.</p>
<p>SBC Warburg's Sine said MCI told analysts it would spend an extra $200 million to $300 million this year on marketing, but the stock was not hit because it is underwritten by the value of the planned British Telecom merger, announced in November. -- New York Newsroom 212 859 1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
