<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="287980" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Prudential filed $1 mln over document destruction.</title>
<headline>Prudential filed $1 mln over document destruction.</headline>
<dateline>NEWARK, N.J. 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The judge presiding over a policyholders' class-action suit against Prudential Insurance Co of America today fined the insurance giant $1 million for its role in destroying documents relevant to the case.</p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Alfred Wolin ordered the Newark-based insurer to prepare a plan to uncover any further document shredding and to prevent future misconduct.  He also ordered Prudential to pay attorneys for the class-action plaintiffs for their time in making their charges of evidence tampering.  </p>
<p>The suit charges Prudential with encouraging its sales agents to persuade policyholders to take out new, higher coverage -- paying the cost by cashing in existing policies -- without disclosing the full costs involved.  The practice is called &quot;churning&quot; and has led to other suits against other insurers.</p>
<p>But the Prudential suit involves as many as 10.7 million policyholders, and the company has agreed to pay a minimum of $410 million.  A settlement could cost the mutual insurer more than $1 billion, analysts say.</p>
<p>Prudential lawyers admitted to Judge Wolin that documents were destroyed in a Cambridge, Mass., office.  The judge also found cause for action in sales offices in Des Moines, Iowa; Jacksonville, Fla., and Syracuse, N.Y.</p>
<p>He gave Prudential 30 days to file its response.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEWARK, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
