<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288084" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: ALPINE SKIING-STANGASSINGER LEADS AFTER FIRST SLALOM LEG.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-STANGASSINGER LEADS AFTER FIRST SLALOM LEG.</headline>
<dateline>KRANJSKA GORA, Slovenia 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austria's Thomas Stangassinger edged out in-form compatriot Thomas Sykora to take the lead after the first run of a men's World Cup slalom on Monday.</p>
<p>Stangassinger, the 1994 Olympic slalom champion, posted a first-descent time of 50.81 seconds on the 60-gate Podkoren piste under falling snow. He was 0.10 seconds ahead of Sykora.</p>
<p>Sykora won two of the winter's three previous slaloms in Park City and Madonna di Campiglio and finished second in Breckenridge.</p>
<p>Frenchman Sebastien Amiez and Italian Alberto Tomba prevented an Austrian sweep of the top first-leg positions by finishing in third (51.20) and sixth (51.44) places respectively.</p>
<p>The Austrians placed five skiers in the top seven with Mario Reiter fourth (51.21), Christian Mayer fifth (51.30) and Siegfried Voglreiter seventh (51.74).</p>
<p>Both defending slalom World Cup title-holder Amiez and Tomba are chasing their first victories of the season. Amiez has made the podium only once this winter, when he was third in Madonna.</p>
<p>Olympic and world champion Tomba finished second in Madonna, in his first appearance on the circuit this winter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KRANJSKA GORA, Slovenia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
