<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28814" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar ends easier in U.S., stg takes center stage.</title>
<headline>Dollar ends easier in U.S., stg takes center stage.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar ended easier after an early sell-off in U.S. assets cut short a rally, while sterling finished higher, boosted by a spike up in oil prices and a rout in the yen, traders said.</p>
<p>The dollar had opened higher, touching seven-week highs against the yen, on news of U.S. military intervention in Iraq and talk of an imminent rise in offical U.S. interest rates.</p>
<p>The rally fizzled, however, as interest rate jitters pummelled U.S. stock and bond prices. U.S. asset prices recovered to end higher but by then gains by sterling had stolen much of the dollar's thunder, traders said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The initial move down by the U.S. asset markets certainly weighed on the dollar through most of the day,&quot; said Robert Fullem, assistant vice president at Natwest Bank Plc.</p>
<p>The dollar's inability to break above 1.4920 marks and sterlings huge rally also hurt the U.S. currency, he said.</p>
<p>The U.S. unit closed easier at 1.4846/54 marks and 109.24/31 yen after opening at 1.4860/70 and 109.35/40.</p>
<p>News that the United States had launched cruise missiles against Iraq in retaliation for Iraqi attacks on a Kurdish enclave spurred safe-haven dollar buying overnight in Asia, traders noted.  </p>
<p>The dollar also received a boost from growing expectations that interest rates in the United States are set to rise.</p>
<p>A recent string of strong economic indicators may convince the Federal Reserve to raise short-term interest rates to keep the economy from overheating at its Federal Open Market Committee meeting on September 24, dealers and analysts said.</p>
<p>Supporting that view and helping to undergird the dollar was an article in Tuesday's Wall Street Journal that said the Federal Reserve was mulling a bigger-than-expected increase in the federal funds rate.  </p>
<p>The dollar climbed to intraday highs of around 1.4875 marks and 109.45 yen before paring gains as fears of higher interest rates trounced U.S. bond and stock prices.</p>
<p>The 30-year benchmark Treasury bond at one stage dropped 23/32 to yield 7.18 percent in early trading, while the Dow industrials briefly fell 53 points to 5566.</p>
<p>U.S. bond and stock prices later recovered to finish higher but the dollar remained mired in narrow ranges.</p>
<p>Sterling, meanwhile, climbed to a high of $1.5695, ending up at $1.5662/69 against $1.5610/20, after the events in the Middle East pushed crude oil prices higher.  </p>
<p>Sterling was also well-bid against the yen, which in turn eased against the mark and other crosses, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sterling is perceived to be an oil sensitive currency, but in inverse to the yen in the sense that (Britain is) quite a large holder of North Sea brent crude,&quot; said Bill Marr, foreign exchange manager at Credit Commerciale de France.</p>
<p>&quot;Higher oil prices are positive for the UK and negative for Japan. Sterling/yen is quite a bit higher.&quot;</p>
<p>Sterling ended around 171.15 yen. The British currency also rose as high as 2.3293 marks, approaching a technical objective of 2.33, traders said.  </p>
<p>Mark/yen rose to a seven-week high of 73.67 before closing at 73.59.</p>
<p>In other trading, the dollar eased to 1.2085/95 Swiss francs against 1.2096/06.</p>
<p>It was Canadian $1.3698/03 versus C$1.3686/91.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar was $0.7917/22 against $0.7912.</p>
<p>-- Daniel Rosenblum, 212-8559-1662</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
