<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288270" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOMALIA: Somali faction blasts leaders' peace agreement.</title>
<headline>Somali faction blasts leaders' peace agreement.</headline>
<dateline>MOGADISHU 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>A powerful Somali faction led by Hussein Aideed blasted on Monday leaders who agreed last week to set up a National Salvation Council to establish a government in Somalia.</p>
<p>Mohamed Kanyare Afrah, interior minister in Aideed's self- styled government, said he would arrest all those who attended the weeks of talks in Ethiopia and charge them with treason.</p>
<p>Afrah, of the Murusade sub-clan, said the conference in Ethiopia between 26 Somali factions were designed to break up Somalia and the peace talks were no difference from the Berlin Conference of 1884 that divided Africa among colonial powers.</p>
<p>Most of the faction leaders who met in Ethiopia never travel through territory controlled by Aideed but some smaller groups such as a wing of the Murusade represented at the talks could be affected by the threat.</p>
<p>Aideed, a south Mogadishu faction leader and 34-year-old former U.S. marine, succeeded his father Mohamed Aideed at his death last August and was elected president of Somalia by supporters.</p>
<p>Aideed refused to attend the Ethiopian-backed peace talks as the other factions flatly refuse to recognise him as president of Somalia or the authority of his south Mogadishu government.</p>
<p>After eight weeks of talks, the 26 factions in Addis Ababa said on Friday they were setting up a National Salvation Council authorised to establish a provisional central government.</p>
<p>The 26 leaders appealed to Aideed and Mohamed Egal, leader of the self-declared Somaliland republic, to participate in the reconciliation process.</p>
<p>The National Salvation Council (NSC) would be composed of 41 members selected from the 26 political movements with an 11-member national executive committee led by five co-chairmen.</p>
<p>The factions said all groups would be invited to a national reconciliation conference in Somalia to discuss the approval of a charter for the provisional central government. No date was set.</p>
<p>Somalia has had no central government since 1991 when rebels ousted late president Mohammed Siad Barre but turned their guns against each other and divided the country into rival fiefdoms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SOMAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOGADISHU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOMALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
