<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288269" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Chevron Nigeria oil output hits 401,000 bpd in '96.</title>
<headline>Chevron Nigeria oil output hits 401,000 bpd in '96.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chief executive of Chevron Nigeria Ltd, a joint venture with Chevron Corp, said on Monday his company's crude oil production averaged 401,000 barrels per day (bpd) in 1996 compared to 384,000 bpd in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;In spite of the difficulties in the business environment, we were able to raise our average 1995 production from 384,000 bpd to a 1996 average of 410,000 bpd, achieving a daily increase of 17,000 bpd,&quot; George Kirkland said in an end of year message to Chevron staff in Nigeria.</p>
<p>He said 1996 was a good year in the company's core business area of exploration and production.</p>
<p>Nigeria's military government last year cut by 30 percent its initial budget provision of $2 billion for oil companies involved in joint ventures with state-owned Nigerian National Petroleum Corp (NNPC).</p>
<p>Chevron is one of the six multinational oil firms in joint venture partnership with NNPC.</p>
<p>Kirkland said the 1996 reserves increased significantly, adding that work was progressing on the development of four new fields in the midwest of Nigeria, while two new fields had been been discovered in the eastern operations.</p>
<p>Installation of facilities at the site of the Escravos gas project in the midwest was nearing completion, Kirkland said.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, we expect the Escravos Gas Project will start-up in May 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>The Escravos gas project involves the gathering and processing of gas now being flared in the NNPC/Chevron offshore Okan and Mefa fields in the Escravos area.</p>
<p>The first phase of the project estimated to cost $569 million involves the processing of about 150 million cubic feet of associated gas per day.</p>
<p>About 96 percent of associated gas produced by the NNPC-Chevron operation is currently flared.</p>
<p>Kirkland said the gas project, new oil field development projects and other existing operations would be the company's key areas of focus for this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We have met with our joint venture partner, NNPC, to discuss the programmes and challenges of 1997. Our plans are to continue to grow the company and to increase production to 600,000 bpd by the turn of this century,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>($1=80)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 263 03 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
