<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288206" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE coffee sags further, March nears $1,210.</title>
<headline>LIFFE coffee sags further, March nears $1,210.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>LIFFE robusta coffee futures sagged in the afternoon to end Monday near their lows on origin sales which drove benchmark March to a new contract low of $1,211 a tonne at one stage.</p>
<p>But light industry price-fixing and arbitrage buying against New York provided some support, traders said.</p>
<p>March sank to a new life-of-contract low of $1,211 but rebounded slightly to end at $1,213 a tonne, still $15 down.</p>
<p>The next key support is seen at $1,210-$1,205 based on second-month continuation chart. The March contract had earlier taken out the previous major support at $1,225, the low seen on December 20.</p>
<p>&quot;London was under pressure all day long,&quot; said one. &quot;We could some some scale-down buying all the way from here.&quot;</p>
<p>The day's volume at 5,675 lots was dominated by Jan/March switches. But the levels were somewhat fairly stable at $23.</p>
<p>New York prices were also lower on speculative selling ahead of key supply/market data due on Monday.</p>
<p>The latest CFTC Commitment of Traders Report, which will be a day late, is expected to show a substantial increase in non-commercial long positions.</p>
<p>The biweekly report for the weeks ended December 24 and 31 is due to be released today after 2030 GMT.</p>
<p>Traders also await U.S. certified coffee stock figures expected after the close of New York trading today.</p>
<p>News the coffee crop in Brazil's top-growing state of Minas Gerais was unaffected by recent heavy rains was within expectation and had little impact on the market.</p>
<p>The rains have left over 60 people dead and thousands homeless, affecting mainly the Belo Horizonte region, the historic town of Ouro Preto and the coffee area of Zona da Mata.</p>
<p>But the coffee areas are on higher ground and so far have not been hit by the flooding. -- Jalil Hamid, London newsroom +44 171 542 4985</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
