<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288260" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: New Zaire army chief says rebels will be defeated.</title>
<headline>New Zaire army chief says rebels will be defeated.</headline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's new army chief vowed on Monday to defeat Rwandan-backed rebels who have captured territory in the east of the country, national television said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our cause is just and legitimate. Those who have imposed the war on us...will pay a heavy price. We will fight it out. We will win,&quot; General Mahele Lieko Bokungu said in an address to soldiers.</p>
<p>Zaire's ill-disciplined, under-equipped and poorly paid troops have been so far routed by the rebels who are reported to have advanced to the town of Mangbalu in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>General Mahele said the army would fight the war according to internationally accepted rules.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been humiliated, but we will not harm innocent people. Children and women will not be harmed. We will not harm civilians, our target is known,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that Zaire had no choice but to launch a major counter-offensive to recapture the territory lost.</p>
<p>&quot;Our men have been retreating for a while. But Kinshasa cannot receive as many as 45 million people (Zaire's total population). So we have to hit back,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that the army was waiting for a green light from President Mobutu Sese Seko.</p>
<p>The government has ruled out negotiation with rebel leader Laurent Kabila, but analysts say Zaire is not in a position to inflict heavy losses on the better equipped rebels. Many politicians are increasingly in favour of a peaceful settlement.</p>
<p>&quot;I know that a group of soldiers have misbehaved, but I want to ask for forgiveness. Let's forget what has happened. Let's rely on our army. We need the backing of the population to carry out our duty,&quot; Mahele said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
