<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288392" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Tensions rise in Moslem village on Serb land - UN.</title>
<headline>Tensions rise in Moslem village on Serb land - UN.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.N. international police on Monday reported rising tension between Serb police and Moslem residents of a northeastern village in Bosnian Serb territory who have complained of insults and night-time explosions.</p>
<p>The pre-war Moslem residents of Dugi Dio reoccupied their village in September, sparking a standoff with Serb authorities which ended after both sides signed a refugee return procedure and Serb police were allowed to conduct patrols.</p>
<p>U.N. spokesman Alex Ivanko said villagers had complained about several explosions and a 10-minute shooting spree from a neighbouring village in Serb territory on  January 3.</p>
<p>Serb police confirmed the report but claimed it happened on the Moslem-Croat side of the line.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is very tense,&quot; said Ivanko, citing a report from an international police patrol.</p>
<p>Moslem residents told a visiting patrol of the International Police Task Force (IPTF) that they had been insulted by Serb police patrolling the village on Sunday. The police denied the claim, Ivanko said.</p>
<p>&quot;As a precautionary measure, IPTF and (NATO-led) Stabilisation Forces will increase their patrolling in the area in and around Dugi Dio,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The IPTF patrol also spotted Moslem villagers gathering on Sunday inside Dugi Dio and on high ground around it, and looking towards the Serb police station.</p>
<p>&quot;They said they wanted to strategically deploy as a protection against the Serb police,&quot; Ivanko said.</p>
<p>He said IPTF had no reports of casualties or damage as a result of the explosions and shooting.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
