<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288591" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: FORECAST - Petron '96 net seen lower.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Petron '96 net seen lower.</headline>
<byline>Katherine Espina</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine oil refiner Petron Corp is likely to register slightly lower net profits for 1996 because the government's automatic pricing formula for petroleum products has cut into its margins, analysts said.</p>
<p>The analysts, who were polled by Reuters last week, on average forecast that Petron's 1996 net income would be 3.97 billion pesos ($150.76 million), down slightly from 4.0 billion pesos in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;The margins of Petron for 1996 will likely shrink as a result of the automatic oil price formula which resulted in cost under-recoveries for the oil companies,&quot; said Michael Gotera, an analyst at Peregrine Securities (Phils) Inc.</p>
<p>Market analysts said the formula, which came into force last August, failed to speedily translate changes in world crude prices to domestic pump prices. Also, it does not take into account increases in other costs, they said.</p>
<p>The government uses Singapore Posted Prices of petroleum products as a benchmark for the formula. Earlier, the government set prices based on crude prices and the foreign exchange rate.</p>
<p>The country's three oil refiners -- Petron, Pilipinas Shell Petroleum Corp and Caltex Philippines Inc -- estimate the industry's margins have been pared by 500 million pesos monthly since the formula was enforced.</p>
<p>&quot;None of the increases went to their bottom line and they were unable to compensate for increases in costs due to inflation. The delay in the reimbursement of their OPSF claims will also contribute to an overall erosion of margins for 1996,&quot; said Philippine Asia Equity Securities analyst Gina Manzano.</p>
<p>The OPSF, the Oil Price Stabilisation Fund, is a fund set up by the government to cushion refiners from fluctuations in global crude prices. Of the 2.4 billion pesos claimed from the fund by the three refiners, Petron's share is the largest, at more than one billion pesos.</p>
<p>Some of the respondents predicted a slight increase in Petron's 1996 profits, on the basis of increased volumes.</p>
<p>&quot;Oil consumption continued to rise and Petron has more than 40 percent share of the market,&quot; said Helen Alvarez, research director at All Asia Securities.</p>
<p>Petron's profits would rise to about 4.59 billion pesos in 1997 with full deregulation of the industry, the survey showed.</p>
<p>&quot;Once there's full deregulation, market forces will dictate prices and the oil companies will have more flexibility,&quot; said Erwin Tan, research manager at Abacus Securities Corp.</p>
<p>A foreign brokerage house that asked not to be named said full deregulation would pave the way for an eight to 13 percent across-the-board rise in pump prices, allowing oil firms to fully reflect actual costs of crude and petroleum products.</p>
<p>&quot;Petron will be able to respond quicker to changes in crude prices and not rely on something as cumbersome as the automatic oil formula,&quot; an analyst at the foreign brokerage said.</p>
<p>Efforts by Petron to diversify into other segments may also pay off in 1997, the analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;They have been shifting their sales to higher-margin, lighter products like gasoline and liquefied petroleum gasoline and this will contribute to better margins in 1997,&quot; said.</p>
<p>The following were the brokerage houses covered by the random survey and their corresponding net income projections:</p>
<p>						 Net Income</p>
<p>					    (in billion pesos)</p>
<p>					     1996	    1997</p>
<p> Abacus Securities		     3.56	    4.2</p>
<p> All Asia Securities		   4.17	    5.14</p>
<p> BPI Capital Corp			4.2	     4.8</p>
<p> ING Barings			     3.98	    4.98</p>
<p> Peregrine				 3.611	   3.797</p>
<p> Pryce Securities			4.38	    4.8</p>
<p> Philippine Asia Equity		3.77	    4.02</p>
<p> Sun Hung Kai			    4.05	    4.97</p>
<p> AVERAGE NET INCOME		    3.965	   4.588</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
