<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28859" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Western U.S. spot power rises on end of fish flush.</title>
<headline>Western U.S. spot power rises on end of fish flush.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>West Coast spot power prices rose slightly Tuesday following the expiration of fish-related requirements at the end of August for extra water through the hydroelectric power dams in the U.S. Northwest.</p>
<p>The additional flows are aimed at aiding the seasonal migration of endangered species.</p>
<p>&quot;We are out of the period of having to push a certain amount of water down rivers,&quot; said a Bonneville Power Administration (BPA) trader.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we can control how much surplus we generate.&quot;  </p>
<p>BPA raised today its price for next-day peak sales by $2.00 to $20.00 per megawatt hour (MWh) for 1100-2200 PDT delivery. The federal power marketing agency's off-peak offer for Wednesday delivery was unchanged at $13.00.</p>
<p>Mid-Columbia (Mid-C) prices were bid early Tuesday at $19.50 during peak hours Wednesday, compared with $15.00 on Friday. Next-day, off-peak Mid-C electricity was discussed at $13.00.</p>
<p>Next-day California-Oregon border (COB) electricity was offered in the high $18.00s, with confirmed trades at $18.00. Off-peak COB prices were unchanged near $12.50.  </p>
<p>October COB prices were assessed at $15.75-$16.50, a wider and slightly firmer range than the $15.85-$16.00 seen Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Air-conditioning loads are down,&quot; noted another Northwest utility trader. &quot;Today's market has more to do with water than with weather.&quot;</p>
<p>The National Weather Service forecast below-normal temperatures through most of the Northwest and Northern California next week.</p>
<p>But some market sources noted the start of the school year could help mitigate some of the expected load drop-off.</p>
<p>Still, power demand in the Southwest is seen trending downward amid the onset of autumn.</p>
<p>&quot;Our peak is over. And temperatures in the Northwest are expected to be 5 to 10 degrees below normal for the next few days,&quot; said a utility trader in New Mexico.</p>
<p>At the Palo Verde (PV) switchyard in Arizona, next-day firm delivery electricity was quoted $24.00-25.00 for peak hours, up slightly from $24.00 on Friday. October PV was quoted at $16.45-!6.75.</p>
<p>-- D Beasley, Los Angeles News Bureau +1 213-380-2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
