<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288524" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru hostages, rebels sing about going home.</title>
<headline>Peru hostages, rebels sing about going home.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-01-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hostages and Marxist guerrillas inside the Japanese ambassador's home in Lima sang songs on Sunday about returning home but the 19-day-old standoff looked further than ever from resolution.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to return, return, return to my home once again,&quot; they sang by candlelight to the tune of a Mexican folk melody.</p>
<p>The words of this and other songs were clearly audible from an upper room of the residence where about 20 Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels held 74 VIP hostages.</p>
<p>Witnesses said female voices could be heard during the choruses, apparently the two teenage rebel girls who were the only women left inside the residence. They were also heard laughing.</p>
<p>Earlier Sunday Bishop Juan Luis Cipriani gave a mass inside the diplomatic mansion and Pope John Paul II, in an apparent appeal to the MRTA rebels, urged kidnappers to free their captives as a &quot;gesture of humanity.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The mercy of Christ, born of human weakness, urges hostage-takers to fulfil this gesture of humanity -- free these people,&quot; the pope told pilgrims in St. Peter's Square during his regular Sunday address.</p>
<p>But the songs and prayers came to naught. There have been no new hostage releases or talks for four days.</p>
<p>Other than Cipriani's visit, the only activity at the mined and booby-trapped residence was the routine shuttling to and fro of Red Cross officials with medicine, food and other supplies such as books, cleaning materials and cigarettes.</p>
<p>The guerrillas have not released any hostages since New Year's Day, and Fujimori's negotiator, Education Minister Domingo Palermo, has not entered the residence since a first face-to-face meeting eight days ago.</p>
<p>Neither side relaxed its uncompromising position, with the heavily armed MRTA rebels maintaining a demand for the release of some 400 jailed comrades and Fujimori flatly refusing.</p>
<p>&quot;Both the MRTA and the government through President Fujimori have shown irreconcilable positions,&quot; said opposition legislator Maximo San Roman Caceres, a former Peruvian vice president under Fujimori.</p>
<p>&quot;The process of dialogue ... has become bogged down, and there is no immediate solution,&quot; he said. &quot;It is putting at serious risk the life of many human beings.&quot;</p>
<p>Reflecting the growing desperation in Peru for a solution from any quarter, San Roman proposed that the pope mediate an end to the crisis.</p>
<p>Another legislator proposed that veteran crisis-broker and former U.S. President Jimmy Carter be called in, while the rebels said they would accept Cuban President Fidel Castro or Russian leader Boris Yeltsin.</p>
<p>Bolivian Foreign Minister Antonio Aranibar arrived in Lima on Sunday to try to help bring about a solution. Bolivian ambassador Jorge Gumucio is among the captives.</p>
<p>At a news conference, Aranibar backed Fujimori's uncompromising position and ruled out releasing four MRTA prisoners in Bolivia. But he appealed to the rebels to care for Gumucio who &quot;suffers from high blood pressure, is diabetic ... and also has in his medical history a heart attack.&quot;</p>
<p>Gumucio and Japanese envoy Morihisa Aoki are the only two ambassadors left in the residence. Their fellow hostages include Fujimori's brother, top Peruvian government officials and about two dozen Japanese diplomats and businessmen.</p>
<p>Red Cross spokesman Ronald Bigler said the organisation maintained its offer of being an intermediary for talks in the crisis. But he said the Red Cross could only be of limited help in reaching agreement over the main sticking points between the two sides.</p>
<p>&quot;Eventually it must come to face-to-face talks,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The standoff began Dec. 17 when a group of well-armed MRTA rebels burst in to a cocktail party honouring Japanese Emperor Akihito's birthday that was attended by more than 500 people.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
