<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288588" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan car sales may stall in '97 after strong '96.</title>
<headline>Japan car sales may stall in '97 after strong '96.</headline>
<byline>Mitsuo Suzuki</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's automakers chalked up a third consecutive year of domestic sales growth in 1996, an industry body said on Monday, but analysts warned that they will face flat domestic sales and stiff competition in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;This year will be a tough one for carmakers, with private spending likely to be tight due to the slow economic recovery,&quot; a Japan Automobile Dealers Association (JADA) official said. &quot;Domestic vehicle sales in 1997 may fall short of the 1996 level.&quot;</p>
<p>The industry body said on Monday that Japan's domestic vehicle sales in calendar 1996 rose 4.4 percent to 5.38 million vehicles, aided by a brisk 13.1 percent pick-up in December sales from a year earlier to 432,603 vehicles.</p>
<p>Industry analysts and executives have estimated that Japan's domestic vehicle sales in 1997, excluding 660cc mini vehicles, will be roughly flat at 5.35 to 5.41 million units.</p>
<p>Higher sales are expected in the January-March quarter, but a setback is likely in April when Japan will increase its consumption tax to five percent from three percent, the JADA official said.</p>
<p>The industry body is expected to give an estimate for 1997 domestic vehicle demand next month.</p>
<p>Sluggish economic growth is also expected to weigh on car sales. The Japanese government forecast gross domestic product growth of just 1.9 percent for the fiscal year beginning on April 1 of this year, its lowest prediction ever.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said carmakers will have to fight it out in the domestic market with price discounts and new models if they hope to boost sales.</p>
<p>They added that the result of the sales battle would be a widening of the gap between Japanese car makers in 1997, with top maker Toyota Motor Corp the likely winner after an erosion of its market share last year.</p>
<p>Toyota was expected to have a wider range of new models and the financial strength needed to provide sufficiently attractive sales incentives to dealers.</p>
<p>At the same time, 1997 was expected to be a tougher year for Honda Motor Co, after its spectacular rise in 1996 to third place in domestic auto sales, overtaking Mitsubishi Motors Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year was the year of Honda. Honda became the third biggest manufacturer in domestic sales volume for the first time in eight years. But this year will be tough for Honda after last year's success with several new models,&quot; the JADA official said.</p>
<p>Honda's domestic sales jumped 39.3 percent to 539,573 vehicles in 1996, helped by strong demand for its recreational vehicles. Honda's market share also rose to a record 10 percent, surpassing the previous record of 7.9 percent in 1989, a Honda spokesman said.</p>
<p>In contrast, Toyota's share of domestic sales fell to 39.1 percent last year, the first time it fell below 40 percent since 1982. This setback occurred despite a 3.7 percent rise in the automaker's domestic sales to 2.10 million vehicles.</p>
<p>&quot;There was strong demand for our new models but poor demand for existing models, particularly sedans. We will bring our share to over 40 percent this year,&quot; a Toyota spokesman said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
