<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288621" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Toys R Us tumbles after report of sluggish sales.</title>
<headline>Toys R Us tumbles after report of sluggish sales.</headline>
<byline>Jessica Hall</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toys R Us Inc. stock tumbled Monday after the company reported sluggish holiday sales that it said would hurt 1996 earnings.</p>
<p>Toys R Us slid $4.625 to $26.125 on the New York Stock Exchange, where it was the most active issue and one of the biggest losers of the session.</p>
<p>The world's largest toy retailer said domestic sales rose 4 percent in December but were flat for all of the holiday selling season on a comparable-store basis. Sales including new stores rose to $4.1 billion in the eight weeks ended Dec. 28 from $3.9 billion in the 1995 period, it said.</p>
<p>Despite strong sales of Nintendo 64 video game machines and Tickle Me Elmo dolls, results were hurt by a lack of software titles and the late Thanksgiving holiday, Chief Executive Officer Michael Goldstein said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although our margin trend continues to be stronger than last year, lower-than-expected holiday sales will naturally have an adverse impact on our anticipated 1996 earnings growth,&quot; Goldstein said in a statement.</p>
<p>The company's holiday sales were &quot;way lower than anyone expected,&quot; said Sean McGowan at the brokerage Gerard Klauer Mattison. Most analysts had expected comparable-store sales to be up about 5 percent, but they came in flat, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The entire toy industry and retailers were far less promotional this year, so consumers were waiting around for price cuts that never came,&quot; McGowan said.</p>
<p>In addition, the late Thanksgiving holiday meant five fewer shopping days in the traditional holiday sales period. &quot;That was no surprise, but it did play a role,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The holiday selling season is crucial for retailers, who generate half or more of their annual profits during the period.</p>
<p>Overall holiday sales rose from 1995 levels for many retailers but the results still fell short of expectations at many chains, industry analysts said last week. One analyst said the season was unspectacular but certainly better than the poor results during Christmas 1995.</p>
<p>McGowan said that while Toys R Us holiday results were disappointing, the outlook for 1997 was strong and he raised his rating on the stock to buy from hold.</p>
<p>Paramus, N.J.-based Toys R Us operates 900 toy and children's clothing stores in the United States and 396 toy stores in other countries.</p>
<p>It will add 78 stores when it completes its purchase of Baby Superstore Inc. on Feb. 3. The all-stock acquisition was valued at about $376 million when announced on Oct. 2, 1996.</p>
<p>Baby Superstore stock lost $3.50 to $21.125 on Nasdaq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6540030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
