<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288633" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dlr closes US slightly lower after overnight slump.</title>
<headline>Dlr closes US slightly lower after overnight slump.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar ended slightly lower against major currencies after a Japanese official warned his country would not tolerate &quot;excessive&quot; moves in the foreign exchange markets.</p>
<p>During overnight trade, Japan's first official session of 1997, the dollar posted a nearly four-year high just below 117 yen, continuing a sharp rally from the previous week.</p>
<p>But Japan's Vice Finance Minister Tadashi Ogawa subsequently prompted heavy sales of dollars for yen, saying the government would &quot;deal appropriately&quot; with excessive foreign exchange shifts.</p>
<p>That suggested Japanese monetary authorities might at some point enter the market to buy yen for dollars if the yen continues to slide, currency experts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar came off overnight following the Ogawa comment. He basically said excessive yen depreciation is not necessarily what they're looking for,&quot; said John McCarthy, senior vice president for foreign exchange at ING Barings.</p>
<p>The dollar ended at 115.72/82 yen, down from 115.86/91 at the open and a high of 116.95 in overnight trade. Against the mark, the dollar fell to 1.5635/45 from 1.5645/55.</p>
<p>The greenback also posted early gains versus the mark, breaching 1.57 and approaching December's two-year high at 1.5735. But the dollar's weakness against the yen eventually helped drag it lower versus European currencies, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We had to wait until U.S. trading got underway before the Ogawa news caught up to the dollar and it gave up some ground to the mark,&quot; said Elliott Dix, foreign exchange trader at Signet Bank in Richmond, Va.</p>
<p>The dollar briefly bounced higher after bargain-hunters entered the market, but a late session slump in U.S. stock prices helped keep the dollar down, traders added.</p>
<p>After rising more than 60 points early in the session, the Dow Jones industrial average fell into negative territory by late afternoon. Ultimately the Dow closed at a record high of 6567, up 23 points.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar tracked the stock market in the afternoon. It gave up some of its early afternoon gains due to the stock market's tumble,&quot; Dix said.</p>
<p>Yet most traders still see the dollar continuing its recent rally, moving gradually toward 120 yen and 1.57 marks in coming sessions.</p>
<p>&quot;Frankly, most people are bullish here. It's hard not to be,&quot; said James Powers, corporate foreign exchange vice president at Westdeutsche Landesbank Girozentrale in New York.</p>
<p>The British pound traded erratically, rising toward $1.70 in early trade before selling off sharply to below $1.68.</p>
<p>Traders cited hedge fund sales of sterling/yen and sterling/mark, as well as an early report that British Prime Minister John Major refused to rule out sterling's participation in European Economic and Monetary Union.</p>
<p>Sterling ultimately settled at $1.6930/40, up from $1.6880/90 at the open.</p>
<p>&quot;Sterling had a tricky kind of day. There was a lot of movement,&quot; Powers said.</p>
<p>In other trade, the dollar fell to 1.3535/45 Swiss francs from 1.3545/55 at the open and to Canadian $1.3650/55 from C$1.3706/11.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar rose to $0.7886/91 from $0.7880/85.</p>
<p>((--Chris Stetkiewicz, 212-859-1664))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
