<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288674" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYS Democrats weigh two responses to Gov address.</title>
<headline>NYS Democrats weigh two responses to Gov address.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York State Democrats are weighing whether to give two responses to Gov George Pataki's &quot;State of the State&quot; address, which the governor plans to deliver on Wednesday, legislative officials said on Monday.</p>
<p>Pat Lynch, the spokeswoman for the Assembly Speaker, Sheldon Silver (D-Manhattan), said that Judith Hope, Co-chairwoman of the state Democratic party, might give a response, in addition to Silver's.</p>
<p>&quot;One is partisan, one is institutional,&quot; she explained, when asked why there might be two reactions.</p>
<p>Lawmakers speculated that the Democrats might wish to give their own competing &quot;State of the State&quot; address either before or shortly after Pataki speaks, but Lynch said Michael Bragman, considered a potential challenger for the governership, would not fulfil this role.</p>
<p>Richard Brodsky (D-Westchester) told reporters in Albany that he did not think the format had been decided yet, but signaled the Assembly, which last year thwarted some of Gov George Pataki's key measures, including criminal justice and welfare, was prepared to press its views.</p>
<p>The Assemblyman couched the House's stand in terms of defending the middle-class from the Republican's governor's pro-business stand. &quot;There is a sort of Calvin Coolidge in an Armani suit. They, the Republicans, think if it's good for International Business Machines Corp and General Elecric Co, it's good for the state. That's not where the jobs are and we have to make our point, and I think we made it very successfully in the last election.&quot;</p>
<p>In his addresss, Pataki plans to propose a sweeping, multi-year reduction in property taxes, a measure that will save localities and cost the state &quot;at least&quot; hundreds of millions of dollars over the next four years, the New York Post said on Monday.</p>
<p>The governor also is expected to highlight proposals to abolish parole for violent criminals, urge targeted tax cuts, including a reduction in the state tax on electric utilities, and argue that his first two years in office have &quot;produced a monumental turnaround&quot; in the attitude of the state's private employers, which will help create more jobs and boost revenues.</p>
<p>The Pataki Administration says that it has boosted the state's economy by a variety of measures, including winning the legislature's agreement to overhaul the workers' compensation system.</p>
<p>((--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
