<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288643" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Broadway composer Burton Lane dies at 84.</title>
<headline>Broadway composer Burton Lane dies at 84.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burton Lane, a high school dropout who became one of Broadway and Hollywood's most respected composers thanks to an inspirational encounter with George Gershwin, has died at age 84, his family said on Monday.</p>
<p>Working with some of Broadway's best lyricists, Lane wrote the music for the hit shows &quot;Finian's Rainbow&quot; and &quot;On a Clear Day You Can See Forever&quot; and such classic songs as &quot;Too Late Now,&quot; &quot;Dancing on a Dime,&quot; &quot;How About You&quot; &quot;Old Devil Moon,&quot; &quot;How Are Things in Glocca Morra,&quot; &quot;Moments Like This,&quot; &quot;Applause, Applause,&quot; and &quot;Everything I Have Is Yours.&quot;</p>
<p>Lane died at his Manhattan home on Sunday night after a long battle with lung cancer, a family spokesman said.</p>
<p>Born Burton Levy on Manhattan's Upper West Side, he was a 15-year-old school dropout when Gershwin's mother, Rose, heard him playing a piano at a rooming house and told his father, &quot;Your son sounds just like George. In fact, he looks like George.&quot;</p>
<p>Soon, Lane was a guest at the Gershwin house, playing &quot;S' Wonderful&quot; at breakneck speed for the master. &quot;When I got finished, George paid me the ultimate compliment. He said, 'Boy, even I couldn't do that,'&quot; Lane recalled in an interview with the Chicago Tribune. He said he became a regular at the Gershwin house and Gershwin inspired him to start writing popular music.</p>
<p>In 1933 composer Irving Berlin helped him land a job in Hollywood writing movie musicals after years of writing for Broadway reviews.</p>
<p>Lane wrote the scores for more than 30 Hollywood musicals from the camp classic &quot;Jupiter's Darling,&quot; which starred elephants and Esther Williams, to &quot;Babes on Broadway,&quot; which starred Mickey Rooney and Judy Garland to &quot;Royal Wedding,&quot; with Fred Astaire and Jane Powell.</p>
<p>He worked frequently with lyricists Ira Gershwin, Alan Jay Lerner and E.Y. &quot;Yip&quot; Harburg, with whom he wrote his biggest hit, the 1947 Broadway musical &quot;Finian's Rainbow,&quot; a fantasy about an Irishman who steals a leprechaun's pot of gold and wants to bury it in a mythical U.S. Southern state, &quot;Missitucky.&quot;</p>
<p>Many of that show's songs became standards including &quot;How Are Things in Glocca Morra&quot; and &quot;Old Devil Moon.'</p>
<p>Lane was credited with starting Judy Garland's movie career by recommending the then 11-year-old Frances Gumm to the head of a Hollywood talent department after hearing her sing at a club.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
