<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28871" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: First Union deals opposed by Bronx activist group.</title>
<headline>First Union deals opposed by Bronx activist group.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Inner City Press/Community on the Move, a Bronx, N.Y.-based activist group, said it asked the Federal Reserve Board to deny approval of First Union Corp's acquisitions of Connecticut-based Center Financial Corp and Florida-based Home Financial Corp.</p>
<p>In a press release Tuesday, Inner City Press said its formal protest to the board was based in part on the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 (CRA), which requires banks to meet the credit and banking needs of low- and moderate-income neighborhoods in their service areas.  </p>
<p>Inner City Press said it expected the acquisitions to lead to extensive branch closings, which would limit credit availabilty to consumers and small businesses.</p>
<p>The activist group also cited a First Union practice of imposing a $1 surcharge on transactions at its automated teller machines by users who are not First Union customers.</p>
<p>A spokesman for North Carolina-based First Union said the claims by Innner City press were &quot;simply without merit.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We currently have $6 billion in loans to low- and moderate-income neighborhoods on our books,&quot; he said. &quot;That's the reality of the strong CRA commitment that we have in place today.&quot;</p>
<p>Inner City Press said it also filed a protest with the Connecticut Department of Banking.</p>
<p>First Union was off 1/4 to 63-5/8 by midafternoon Tuesday. Center Financial was down 1/4 to 24-5/8, and Home Financial was off 3/8 to 13-3/4.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
