<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288773" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton holds out olive branch to Republicans.</title>
<headline>Clinton holds out olive branch to Republicans.</headline>
<byline>Gene Gibbons</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton went back to work on Monday after a week-long New Year's holiday with an appeal to his political rivals for a &quot;spirit of reconciliation&quot; in tackling the country's problems.</p>
<p>Clinton, about to embark on his second term in a political climate soured by partisan backbiting between his Democratic administration and the Republican Congress, extended his olive branch at a prayer breakfast with 100 religious leaders, Vice President Al Gore and members of the Cabinet.</p>
<p>Reflecting on the work he faces over the next four years on issues ranging from welfare reform to keeping the economy perking, the president said: &quot;We're on the cusp here, maybe, of turning a lot of our social problems around.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We know what we ought to do. Can we do it in the right way, in a spirit of reconciliation?&quot;</p>
<p>The reconciliation call came amid signs he is unlikely to get any second-term relief from political warfare.</p>
<p>The cover story in the Newsweek magazine issue out Monday deals with the continuing controversy over Paula Jones, who has accused Clinton of making sexual advances in 1991 when he was Arkansas governor and she was a state employee. She has filed suit against Clinton and the Supreme Court has agreed to decide whether that suit may proceed while he is in office.</p>
<p>Clinton is already buffeted by an inquiry into improper re-election campaign fundraising among Asian donors and by a long-running special prosecutor probe of alleged financial and ethical misdeeds known collectively as Whitewater.</p>
<p>Adding to the acrid political atmosphere in Washington is the embattled status of Republican House Speaker Newt Gingrich, who has admitted breaking House rules and giving false information to an ethics committee.</p>
<p>Gingrich's allies have warned that if the Democrats continue to pound the Georgia Republican, they will renew and intensify character attacks on the president.</p>
<p>Clinton, who returned late Sunday night from a Caribbean holiday in the U.S. Virgin Islands, mentioned none of this in his talk to the clergy.</p>
<p>He did urge them to stress the need for national harmony in implementing a tough new welfare reform law -- one of his top second-term priorities -- and addressing other ticklish issues like immigration policy.</p>
<p>&quot;I ask for your help in creating a sense of reconciliation, the right sort of spirit in which we can deal with these issues,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>His appeal was echoed by White House spokesman Mike McCurry, who told reporters on Monday that the president will press for national unity and harmony.</p>
<p>&quot;The theme of the next few weeks, the next few months is (to) move head on the problems which the American people elected Congress and this president to address,&quot; McCurry said.</p>
<p>He said Clinton, the first Democrat to be re-elected since Franklin Roosevelt was returned to office for a fourth term in 1944, would offer &quot;a very specific vision for the future and a very specific road map of how to reach that destination&quot; in his Jan. 20 inaugural address and his State of the Union speech to Congress and the nation on Feb. 5.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
