<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288733" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs end mixed after posting contract highs.</title>
<headline>CME hogs end mixed after posting contract highs.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME hog futures slipped on profit taking late to close mixed after setting contract highs in April, July and August earlier. Pork bellies also ran into profit taking which clipped sharp gains and finished mixed.</p>
<p>April hogs posted a new high of 76.900 cents per lb with July setting a new high of 77.100 and August 73.700 cents before slipping. Hogs closed 0.800 cent higher to 0.350 lower with February up 0.425 at 78.875 cents.</p>
<p>Buying linked to weather concerns boosted futures early into fund demand and buy stops before profit taking developed late, traders said.</p>
<p>Forecasts for bitter cold weather moving into the Midwest offset early pressure from Monday's weak cash hog prices. However, cash indications were mostly steady for Tuesday as packers appear to currently have adequate live and pork supplies on hand. The recent bullish Hogs and Pigs report also lent support before profit taking prompted by the wide basis weighed on prices, traders said.</p>
<p>Refco, Rand Financials and R.J. O'Brien notably bought February while E.D.&amp;F. Man, Smith Barney and Prudential Securities bought April on the early rally, pit sources said.  </p>
<p>In hog options, Cargill Investor Services sold February 80 calls early which put February volatility under pressure. Scattered commission houses sold February 80 calls late with First Chicago selling June 78 calls, pit sources added.</p>
<p>Pork belly futures also ran into mixed profit taking after rallying sharply early on local short covering, commercial support and fund buying. Technical buy stops added to the early advance before resistance was met at highs set after the latest USDA hog report, traders said.</p>
<p>Futures strength came despite weakness posted in cash bellies at noon, they said.</p>
<p>A much-lighter-than-expected hog slaughter estimate from the USDA after the close could also lend support to futures early Tuesday. The kill, estimated by USDA at 306,000 head, was well under trade estimates and coupled with continued indications of light belly storings, should keep futures supported, they added.</p>
<p>The 306,000-head slaughter estimate was well under 341,000 a week ago but above 275,000 head a year ago.</p>
<p>Pork bellies closed 1.100 cent per lb higher to 0.825 lower with February up most at 82.475 cents.</p>
<p>ING was a notable buyer late after early demand from LFG, Rand Financials and Prudential Securities. The latter offset selling by R.J. O'Brien and Lind-Waldock, pit sources said.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
