<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288857" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Bombay stocks end with small losses, dull trade.</title>
<headline>Bombay stocks end with small losses, dull trade.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>**  Shares finish shade lower, poor volumes</p>
<p>**  Quiet day for markets, lack of major action</p>
<p>**  Local funds keen sellers, foreign funds still stay on</p>
<p>	  the sidelines-traders</p>
<p>**  Bombay's key index falls 9.54 pts to provisional</p>
<p>	  3,254.46</p>
<p>**  National Stock Exchange open till 1700 (1130 GMT) after</p>
<p>	  technical problem forced trade suspension at mid-session</p>
<p>**  Morgan Stanley sees Indian markets gaining from U.S.</p>
<p>	  stock correction in mid-1997</p>
<p>Bombay blue-chips finished an erratic Monday trading session with minor losses, as a lack of market-moving factors limited price movement in pivotal stocks, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was stuck in a sideways price movement..a day of subdued trading,&quot; said R. Ramakrishnan, chief dealer at ASK-Raymond James Securities India Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;Action is slowly shifting to the broader market.&quot;</p>
<p>The Bombay Stock Exchange's (BSE) top 30-share index ended 9.54 points, or 0.29 percent, down at 3,254.46 after fluctuating in a 50 point price band.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market appears to have bottomed out,&quot; ASK's Ramakrishnan said but added that concerns about an impending price hike in petroleum products and an uncertain political situation was likely to put pressure on prices.</p>
<p>Year-on-year Indian inflation, measured by the wholesale price index was at a 56-week high of 7.58 percent on December 21 against 7.08 percent the previous week, the Industry Ministry said on Sunday.</p>
<p>A sharp correction of U.S. stocks by mid-1997 would likely help revive interest in underperforming Asian bourses, said Barton Biggs, Morgan Stanley's chief global strategist.  </p>
<p>Biggs picked South Korea, India and Thailand as potential beneficiaries of 10-30 percent correction of the Dow Jones Industrial Index this year. The Index rose 27 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;...If things work out in Thailand, India and Korea, then those markets could be up 30-35 percent in 1997,&quot; he told an investment seminar in Bangkok on Monday.</p>
<p>Back home, Arvind Mills added 5.75 rupees to 137.25 on some foreign buying, dealers said. SBI however fell 2.25 rupees to 241.75, ACC 12.0 to 1,289.0 and Reliance 0.75 to 215.75.</p>
<p>TISCO rose 0.25 to 181.50 and Bajaj Auto 3.0 to 915.0.</p>
<p>-- ANSHUMAN DAGA, Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
