<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288933" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Indian PM Deve Gowda arrives in Bangladesh.</title>
<headline>Indian PM Deve Gowda arrives in Bangladesh.</headline>
<byline>Shakeel Anwar</byline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda arrived to a warm reception in Bangladesh on Monday, less than a month after the two countries signed a historic water-sharing accord that ended a decades-old dispute,</p>
<p>He was received at the Dhaka airport by Bangladeshi Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina and senior members of her cabinet.</p>
<p>Bangladeshi airforce jets escorted Deve Gowda's aircraft to Dhaka after it entered Bangladesh's air space. As he descended from the plane, a red carpet was rolled out and the artillery fired 19 gunshots in his honour.</p>
<p>The Indian leader also inspected a military guard.</p>
<p>Deve Gowda, on his first visit to Dhaka, was accompanied by a 17-member entourage, which includes External Affairs Minister Inder Kumar Gujral, Home Minister Indrajit Gupta and Foreign Secretary Salman Haider.</p>
<p>Thousands of people lined both sides of a 17-km (12-mile) highway, waving hands and flags, waiting for the two prime ministers to drive in a ceremonial motorcade from the airport to the state guest house &quot;Jamuna&quot; in the city centre.</p>
<p>Officials in Dhaka described the visit as a landmark that would help cement bilateral relations after Hasina and Deve Gowda signed a 30-year treaty in New Delhi last December on sharing water from the Ganges River, which flows through India and Bangladesh before emptying into the Bay of Bengal.</p>
<p>The treaty ended a dispute rankling the two neighbours since 1974, when India built a barrage on the Ganges to hold back water near its border with Bangladesh.</p>
<p>The treaty ensures that lower riparian Bangladesh gets at least 35,000 cusecs (cubic metres per second) of Ganges water during the dry season to facilitate irrigation and navigation.</p>
<p>Officials said the prime ministers would discuss the repatriation of Bangladeshi tribal refugees from India, trade and increasing cooperation among member-states of the South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation (SAARC), which comprises the two nations, Pakistan, Sri Lanka, Bhutan, Nepal and the Maldives.</p>
<p>&quot;The visit is a goodwill one but repatriation of the Chakma refugees, trade and SAARC matters will feature prominently in talks between the two premiers,&quot; an official told Reuters.</p>
<p>An official in Deve Gowda's office in New Delhi earlier said: &quot;The prime minister is not going to Dhaka with a bag of demands or concessions.&quot;</p>
<p>The main focus of his visit would be on reviewing the growing, friendly relations between the two neighbours, he said.</p>
<p>India helped Bangladesh win a 1971 independence war against Pakistan, but ties between Dhaka and New Delhi later entered a cold era, often soured by distrust and fear.</p>
<p>Relations started improving after Hasina, daughter of Bangladesh's slain independence leader Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, came to power following a general election last June.</p>
<p>The water accord put a &quot;seal of trust&quot; on warming ties, officials say.</p>
<p>A widening trade gap in favour of India remains a major Bangladeshi concern. In 1995/96 (July-June), Bangladesh imported goods worth $1.1 billion from India but its exports were a paltry $70 million, officials said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
