<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="288909" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan locks horns with mobile phone operators.</title>
<headline>Pakistan locks horns with mobile phone operators.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Lyon</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's cellular telephone and payphone operators are angry at the caretaker government's demand that they drop demands for compensation in return for an end to an 18-month-old ban on services in turbulent Karachi.</p>
<p>The ousted government of Benazir Bhutto switched off mobile telephone and payphone services in the busy southern port city in July 1995 in a bid to disrupt the communications of armed militants of the ethnic Mohajir National Movement (MQM).</p>
<p>The struggle between the MQM and the security forces has since subsided and the caretaker government led by Meraj Khalid has said it favours restoring the services in principle.</p>
<p>But the Ministry of Communications insists that the three mobile telephone operators and three payphone companies must waive their claims for compensation for lost revenue.</p>
<p>Industry sources say two payphone companies, including the partly state-owned Telecom Foundation, have accepted the demand and are in the process of reviving their services in Karachi, Pakistan's biggest city and commercial hub.</p>
<p>But the three mobile phone operators and a third telephone booth company say they will resist the demand and go to court if necessary, though they would prefer to settle in talks.</p>
<p>&quot;If national security is no longer a concern, there is no reason not to restore the services,&quot; said Javaid Firoz, a director of Telecard Ltd, which has filed a claim for 2.2 billion rupees ($54.7 million) in damages.</p>
<p>&quot;We have asked the government to separate the issues of restoration and compensation. We are willing to discuss the claim, but we are not willing to accept blackmail,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A similar line has been taken by the three cellular telephone companies -- Pakistan Mobile Telecommunications, a joint venture of U.S.-based Motorola Inc and local Saif Telecom; Pakcom Ltd, a subsidiary of Luxembourg's Millicom International Cellular Sa ; and Paktel Ltd, a subsidiary of Cable and Wireless Plc.</p>
<p>One industry executive, who asked not to be named, said other members of the caretaker government, including Finance and Economic Affairs Adviser Shahid Javed Burki, had agreed that restoration of services should not be linked to compensation.</p>
<p>But he said Communications Minister Abdul Ghaffar Jatoi had told industry representatives that it would be &quot;criminal and an act of high treason&quot; to reconnect the services on that basis.</p>
<p>&quot;The minister said that Pakistan was tired of being held to ransom by economic imperialists,&quot; the executive said.</p>
<p>Jatoi and officials at the ministry could not immediately be reached for comment.</p>
<p>The executive said the firms had worked with a technical committee led by an official of the Pakistan Telecommunication Authority, a regulatory body, in recent weeks to design a rescue package to address industry grievances. Such a deal, he said, could possibly be accepted in lieu of compensation.</p>
<p>But the committee's report had apparently been set aside in favour of a much weaker alternative set of proposals, he added.</p>
<p>The three cellular telephone companies argued their case in a joint document presented to the government in November, saying they were losing money due to low consumer tariffs and high taxes, as well as the loss of Karachi, their biggest market.</p>
<p>Firoz, whose Telecard Ltd is about 60 percent foreign-owned, said Pakistan's treatment of the industry could badly damage efforts to push ahead with the long-delayed privatisation of state-run Pakistan Telecommunication Company Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;Any international investor looking at telecom opportunities in Pakistan will definitely get a very wrong signal,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
