<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="289110" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Russia hardens line with NATO - diplomats.</title>
<headline>Russia hardens line with NATO - diplomats.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian President Boris Yeltsin stepped up his country's opposition to NATO expansion in weekend talks with German Chancellor Helmut Kohl, laying out a range of tough demands, Western diplomatic sources said on Monday.</p>
<p>The sources told Reuters Yeltsin wanted a legally-binding commitment from the Western alliance to involve Russia in formal consultations with NATO on any issue including enlargement, which would give Moscow huge influence over alliance decisions.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, in his first meeting with a foreign leader since his heart surgery, told Kohl that this mechanism for consultations had to be set up before Moscow could consider any change in its opposition to NATO enlargement, the sources said.</p>
<p>NATO is expected at a summit in July to invite some countries from Central and Eastern Europe to join the alliance, with Poland, Hungary and the Czech republic the frontrunners.</p>
<p>&quot;The Russians are playing for very high stakes,&quot; said one source, who asked not to be identified. &quot;Any hope that Yeltsin's return would mean a more reasonable approach seems not to be justified. We face a difficult time ahead.&quot;</p>
<p>Yeltsin also told Kohl there could be no expansion of NATO's military structures to new members. The alliance has already said it has no plans to station nuclear weapons on the territory of new members, but it may still want to station some troops, headquarters or other military installations there.</p>
<p>NATO allies have agreed to offer Russia a special relationship of some kind to ease Moscow's security concerns about the alliance's enlargement.</p>
<p>But the allies have not yet agreed among themselves on how this should work. Diplomats say most of them would oppose the latest Russian demands.</p>
<p>&quot;This approach by the Russians is to see how much further they can cause divisions within the alliance by taking a very hard line,&quot; said one diplomat.</p>
<p>It was significant that Yeltsin chose to give the message to Kohl. Germany is Russia's closest ally in Europe.</p>
<p>Kohl said in Moscow after the weekend talks that he was optimistic a solution to the problems could be found this year, even though differences between NATO and Russia remained.</p>
<p>Kohl said he had discussed some ideas with Yeltsin that he would now discuss with other Western leaders. He gave no details.</p>
<p>Yeltsin and other Russian leaders confirmed their opposition to NATO's plans to expand eastwards at a top-level meeting on Monday, the Kremlin said.</p>
<p>Yeltsin summoned Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin, presidential chief-of-staff Anatoly Chubais, Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov and security and defence leaders to discuss Russia's relations with the Western alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;The meeting...confirmed Russia's negative position on the plans to expand NATO eastwards,&quot; Interfax news agency said, quoting Yeltsin's press secretary, Sergei Yastrzhembsky.</p>
<p>It gave no other details.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
