<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="289400" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Georgia president regrets girl's death.</title>
<headline>Georgia president regrets girl's death.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Georgian President Eduard Shevardnadze sent condolences to the family of a 16-year-old girl killed Friday in a five-car collision caused by a Georgian diplomat, an embassy official said Sunday.</p>
<p>A 1987 Ford Taurus driven by Gueorgui Makharadze, 35, struck a car and went spinning into three other cars including one being driven by Joviane Waltrick, 16, of Kensington, Maryland, who was pronounced dead shortly after the accident.</p>
<p>Embassy counsellor David Soumbadze said Shevardnadze's letter was conveyed to Waltrick's family via diplomatic channels.</p>
<p>In the letter, Shevardnadze pledged his government's cooperation and said the diplomat &quot;must bear responsibility for the tragic incident in accordance with norms.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S. State Department asked Georgian authorities for their cooperation in the investigation.</p>
<p>Police were expected to turn their findings over to the district attorney's office for a decision on whether to file charges against Makharadze as early as on Monday, NBC-TV reported on Sunday.</p>
<p>As a diplomat Makharadze is immune from prosecution, but the State Department will request a waiver of diplomatic immunity if local prosecutors pursue criminal charges.</p>
<p>Makharadze also sent the Waltrick family a letter of condolence on Sunday, saying, &quot;I cannot express adequately in words my sorrow for having been part of this horrible tragedy or for the pain it causes and will continue to cause to the family and friends of Joviane Waltrick.&quot;</p>
<p>Makharadze suffered only minor injuries in the accident, but was &quot;depressed morally,&quot; Soumbadze said.</p>
<p>His letter to the family continued, &quot;I deeply regret this unspeakable loss and pray that God may comfort you in this trying time and help to heal these wounds.&quot;</p>
<p>NBC-TV quoted David Richin, the family's attorney, as saying he would meet with Georgian embassy officials this week to press them to waive Makharadze's immunity.</p>
<p>&quot;When you take the life of a very young, 16-year-old girl and don't pay for it, that's unacceptable,&quot; Richin told the network.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
