<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="289545" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary BUX index hits record high of 4,291.29 pts.</title>
<headline>Hungary BUX index hits record high of 4,291.29 pts.</headline>
<byline>Sandor Peto</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's BUX Index surprised traders by soaring to its eleventh successive daily record on Monday, boosted by positive sentiment on world share markets and strong demand from foreign investors.</p>
<p>The index of the Budapest Stock Exchange (BSE) rose 3.8 percent or 156.98 points to close at 4,291.29.</p>
<p>&quot;This is simply unbelievable,&quot; said Bank-Austria Girocredit's Geza Raner. &quot;The market posted strong gains, stronger than we expected.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said BSE was helped on the first trading day of this year by a stronger Dow and rising prices of Hungarian shares on London's SEAQ on last Thursday and Friday.</p>
<p>They added that news both of macroeconomic figures and of bourse companies have been positive since last year, helping the BSE to become one of the best-performing bourses in the world in 1996 and probably pushing the BUX even higher in 1997.</p>
<p>New York Broker's Attila Gazdik said that &quot;new money&quot; appeared on the market, referring to foreign investment funds which seemed to be holding on to their Hungarian shares and even adding to their portfolio on the hope of further gains.</p>
<p>Traders said sellers disappeared from the market in loght early trading and only returned when the prices gradually rose to what they considered high enough levels.</p>
<p>Monday's price rises were also driven by the gains of oil company MOL and the drug maker Richter, traders said.</p>
<p>MOL rose 180 forints to finish at 2,200. Richter closed at 10,200, up 750 forints.</p>
<p>The retail firm Fotex rose 16 percent, or 16 forints, to 116 in unusually high turnover of 147. 2 million forints.</p>
<p>&quot;The boom had a favourable impact on Fotex -- it woke up from a four-month depression,&quot; Gazdik said, adding, however, that there were large sellers of Fotex, not only strong buyers.</p>
<p>Hungarian traders said they had been expecting a downward correction on the BSE for weeks, but foreign interest always pushed the shares higher.</p>
<p>However, a correction may come any day, they said, adding that they expected corporate news to give a fresh impetus to the market from the end of this month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
