<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="289655" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-NatMutual says sees improved results.</title>
<headline>RTRS-NatMutual says sees improved results.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Listed insurer National Mutual Holdings Ltd said on Monday it expected continued improvement in its financial results with a particular focus on growth in the Asian region.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook is for continued improvement in the group's results with new business growth and expense reduction the key objectives. Our expansion in Asia will continue to be a high priority,&quot; the company said in its annual review.</p>
<p>In December the group, which listed in Australia and New Zealand three months ago, unveiled net profit growth of 82.6 percent to A$210.9 million for the year to September 30.  </p>
<p>National Mutual had forecast a bottom line 1995/96 profit of A$198.0 million in its prospectus.</p>
<p>Managing director Geoff Tomlinson said in the review the Asian region was underdeveloped in terms of savings and life insurance risk products and the group would continue to work on securing a life insurance licence in China during 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;We are working hard to improve our chances of getting a licence to operate in China, an application for entry into Thailand has been made and we have increased our research activity in India, the Philippines and Vietnam,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The group aimed to grow volumes and and lower expenses during the current year and planned to push further into the superannuation market, Tomlinson said.</p>
<p>&quot;The superannuation industry will continue to grow. It is predicted to reach A$300 billion by the year 2000. It is not surprising that we are actively seeking to increase our market share in this area,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>National Mutual Life, the groups' largest division, was well positioned to take advantage of opportunities in the Australian and New Zealand markets, the company said.  </p>
<p>The group said its funds management operation would continue to reposition itself as the Asia-Pacific funds management arm of French insurance giant Axa SA, which bought a 51 percent stake in National Mutual for A$1.1 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>National Mutual shares closed two cents lower at A$1.81.</p>
<p>-- Melbourne bureau 61-3 9286-1435</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
