<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="289742" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia property market seen firm in 97.</title>
<headline>Malaysia property market seen firm in 97.</headline>
<byline>K. Baranee Krishnaan</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>A strong economy along with speculation will sustain the bullishness in Malaysia's property market this year, industry experts said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not expect the property market to perform any better or worse in 1997 than in 1996. The existing positive tone of the market will continue...and so will the negative aspects,&quot; property valuers Rahim &amp; Co Research Sdn Bhd said in a report released on Monday.</p>
<p>Single- and double-storey homes and bungalows, whose prices jumped by up to 136 percent last year, are expected to remain the strongest component of the property market in 1997, Rahim and Co said.</p>
<p>But demand for space in high-rise structures in the home of the world's tallest building continues to soften due to oversupply, the industry experts said.</p>
<p>The world's tallest building, the 450-metre high Petronas twin towers, are in Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>Sales and rental value for shopping complex, hotel, factory and condominium space will be relatively less due to a growing glut of such facilities, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;The only reservation we have about the market is that the competition is getting greater,&quot; L.H. Lim, associate director of Raine &amp; Horne International-Zaki &amp; Partners, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Lim said man-made lakes and horse stables were becoming common in towns outside Kuala Lumpur, while within the capital, homes were being equipped with all sorts of business-friendly facilities.</p>
<p>&quot;Developers have to resort to something unusual to tickle our fancy these days,&quot; Aloysius Bernard Marbeck, managing director of Rahim and Co, said at a property market seminar on Monday.</p>
<p>A decade of spectacular economic growth, averaging above eight percent a year, has increased disposable income for Malaysians and the situation is not expected to change much in the next four years, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Growing affluence and traffic congestion in cities is making people go for low-density country homes priced at around $250,000 to 300,000 ringgit ($99,000 to $119,000) each,&quot; K.L. Chee, a property valuer with Kemayan Management Services Sdn Bhd, said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think these homes have the real growth potential now, as just two years ago, some of them were priced as low as 190,000 ringgit each,&quot; said Chee.</p>
<p>Demand for prime office space in urban suburbs like Damansara and Bangsar in Kuala Lumpur remained high. But analysts doubted prices here could rise much further.</p>
<p>&quot;A square foot in Damansara now fetches 260 ringgit, more than 100 percent than it did last year. The appreciation is a bit too high,&quot; said Michael Wee, agency manager for Knight Frank Baillieu.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a definite oversupply of condos in Damansara and Bangsar,&quot; said Edward Ong, an analyst at research firm Schroders. &quot;Prices here have come off five to 10 percent in the last year and don't bode too well for the condo market.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-2014813)</p>
<p>($1 =2.52 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
