<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="289739" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan suffers post-holiday economic blues.</title>
<headline>Japan suffers post-holiday economic blues.</headline>
<byline>Linda Sieg</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan suffered a case of the post-holiday blues on Monday as executives back from their New Year break bemoaned the economic outlook, an official worried aloud about the yen's slide and stocks managed only modest gains.</p>
<p>Behind the gloom -- which economists said would likely linger for several months -- are persistent worries about the impact of government belt-tightening aimed at cutting Japan's big budget deficit and doubts about how dedicated political leaders are to delivering promised economic reform.</p>
<p>&quot;After April, we are going to have a very difficult situation,&quot; Shoichiro Toyoda, chairman of business lobby Keidanren, told a news conference. &quot;The economy depends on how positively the government carries out fiscal reforms, deregulation and other reforms.&quot;</p>
<p>Worries about the economic future overshadowed the stock market on Monday, the first trading day of the new year.</p>
<p>Tokyo share prices ended modestly higher after a half-day trading session, as gains by big blue-chip companies -- recently dubbed the &quot;Nifty 50&quot; -- for the moment outweighed worries about sluggish economic growth overall.</p>
<p>The Japanese government last month predicted an economic growth rate of 1.9 percent in the business year from April 1, its lowest official growth forecast ever.</p>
<p>Many private economists fear even that forecast may be too optimistic, given a budget that emphasises cutting government debt rather than stimulating the economy, a planned rise in the three-percent sales tax to five percent from April, and a planned end to special income tax cuts this year.</p>
<p>The benchmark Nikkei 225-share average finished up 84.65 points, or 0.44 percent, at 19,446.00, after dipping as low as 19,203.53 earlier in the session.</p>
<p>&quot;By the middle of the year, we'll get a turnaround in sentiment (about the economy), but the first half will be gloom,&quot; said Ron Bevacqua, an economist at Merrill Lynch Japan.</p>
<p>Despite the general angst, however, market punters bought cash-rich multinational firms, whose global production bases can cushion the impact of sharp currency fluctuations.</p>
<p>&quot;These firms invested based on two premises. One, that they wanted domestic production to be profitable with the yen at 80 (to the dollar). Second, to have global production bases so they could shift production in four months to adjust to exchange rate swings,&quot; said Jesper Koll, a chief economist at JP Morgan in Tokyo. &quot;They can do that now.&quot;</p>
<p>Immunity to currency volatility would be no bad thing, given lurches like that which took the yen from a record high of 79.75 to the dollar in April 1995 to the 117 level touched briefly on Monday -- its lowest value since March 1993.</p>
<p>Economists cited Japan's rock-bottom interest rates as a key cause for the yen's weakness. The Bank of Japan has kept rates low to help the economy since slashing its key official discount rate to 0.5 percent in September 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not just interest rate differentials, its absolute yields,&quot; Koll said. &quot;The level of interest rates is so close to zero that everyone from Mrs Watanabe to Fortune 500 companies are putting their assets to work in another currency.&quot;</p>
<p>Keidanren's Toyoda said low interest rates might have to stay a while longer to keep Japan's recovery on track.</p>
<p>But prospects of an ever-weaker yen are making Japanese financial markets jittery, raising worries about a &quot;triple-weakness&quot; scenario in which the yen falls while capital flees Japan's stock and bond markets.</p>
<p>Vice Finance Minister Tadashi Ogawa told a news conference that excessive yen weakness -- like excessive strength -- was not good for the economy and that Tokyo would continue to deal appropriately with excessive fluctuations.</p>
<p>&quot;Excessive weakness of the yen, as with excessive yen strength, is certainly not favourable for the economy,&quot; he said. The early evening comments weakened the dollar against the yen, taking it below 116 yen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
