<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="289973" id="root" date="1997-01-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Jan 6.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Jan 6.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Jordanian press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-RAI</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Kabariti urges a national consenus on the election law; the government remains attached to &quot;one-man-one vote system&quot; while the opposition reject it.</p>
<p>- King Hussein in a telephone call to Syrian President Assad condemns the bombing of a bus in Damascus and extends condolences to victims and families.</p>
<p>- Legal committee in parliament rejects expanding the jurisdiction of the state security court requested by the government.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Kabariti meets a delegation from Israeli Arabs and expresses Jordan's &quot;firm stance of support to brotherly Palestinians&quot;.</p>
<p>- Municipalities minister says government looking into the plight of municpalities which are in financial crisis.</p>
<p>AD-DUSTOUR</p>
<p>- Kabariti to visit Oman on Tuesday to deliver a message from King Hussein to Sultan Qaboos.</p>
<p>AL-ASWAQ</p>
<p>- Supply Minister Sobar says most of the holy Moslem fasting month of Ramadan's basic foodstuffs are in ample supply with prices steady; says the ministry has stockpiled a large reserve of commodities to intervene in case of shortages and sharp price rises.</p>
<p>- 55 foreign funds entered the stock market last year and 44 million dinars ($62 million) of non-Jordanian transactions in share dealings in the last quarter.</p>
<p>JORDAN TIMES</p>
<p>- Jordan warns that violence could wreck the Middle East peace process.</p>
<p>- Arab League chief arrives.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
