<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="290279" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Morgan Stanley shrs off after Q4 disappoints.</title>
<headline>Morgan Stanley shrs off after Q4 disappoints.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Morgan Stanley Group Inc slipped 1-1/8 to 55-3/8 after the company reported lower than expected fourth quarter earnings.</p>
<p>Morgan Stanley's fourth quarter net income of $236 million, or $1.36 per fully diluted share, brought the firm's full year earnings to a record $1.03 billion for the fiscal year ended November 30, 1996.</p>
<p>Even so, the earnings fell short of Wall Street expectations, which averaged $1.51 per share, according to First Call's consensus estimate.  </p>
<p>&quot;Morgan Stanley came in light,&quot; said Raphael Soifer, a financial industry analyst at Brown Brothers Harriman. &quot;I think there's probably a bit of disappointment, particularly with respect to expenses.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The whole (financial) group is down, but Morgan is down even relative to the group,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Morgan Stanley said its total expenses excluding interest costs rose 29 percent in the fourth quarter, essentially matching the firm's revenue growth rate.  </p>
<p>In the fourth quarter, expenses rose to $1.15 billion from $892 million in the comparable 1995 period, while net revenues rose to $1.51 billion from $1.17 billion.</p>
<p>In contrast, earnings at Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc exceeded expectations, coming in at $0.96 per share for the fourth quarter, up from $0.49 a year ago and well above First Call's consensus estimate of $0.85.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything went right for Lehman in the quarter,&quot; Soifer said, noting that Lehman's fourth quarter results improved despite the inclusion $0.43 per share non-recurring severance charge. &quot;They had just a blockbuster of a quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>However, the news was not enough for Lehman to overcome a general decline in financial shares on Wall Street. Lehman shares, which rose early in the session, dipped 7/8 to 29-3/4 in mid-afternoon activity.</p>
<p>((-- R. Melville, Wall Street desk, 212-859-1731))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
