<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="290209" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Merrill says India economic fundamentals are solid.</title>
<headline>Merrill says India economic fundamentals are solid.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's economic fundamentals remain positive despite a host of short-term weaknesses, according to Merrill Lynch analyst William Belchere.</p>
<p>India's industrial growth rate will slip to 8.0 percent in the current fiscal year, ending March 1997, from about 12 percent in 1995/96, said Belchere, who heads Merrill's currency and fixed income analysis and forecasting for Asia.</p>
<p>But thanks to the good monsoon, a bumper harvest may mitigate the impact of falling industrial output, with the resulting gross domestic product growth close to the government's forecast of 6.6. percent for 1996/1997, he said.</p>
<p>In October 1996, Standard &amp; Poor's revised its outlook on India foreign currency rating, currently at BB-plus, to &quot;positive&quot; from &quot;stable,&quot; citing an improved economic performance, progress on reforms and stronger external accounts. &quot;The possibility of S&amp;P upgrading India's sovereign rating to investment grade has increased,&quot; Belchere said.</p>
<p>While calling India's economic fundamentals &quot;compelling,&quot; Belchere warned that export growth in the current fiscal year may end below target, and inflation may rise, leading to higher interest rates and a weaker currency.</p>
<p>On politics, Belchere said the United Front coalition is experiencing pressure and the possiblity of a reunited Congress Party regaining power is increasing.</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1660))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
