<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="290293" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. economist Fosler sees higher interest rates.</title>
<headline>U.S. economist Fosler sees higher interest rates.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>An influential U.S. economist said on Tuesday that she saw U.S. interest rates rising in the months ahead and warned of the possibility of a steep dollar drop against the yen.</p>
<p>Gail Fosler, chief economist at the New York-based Conference Board, told the National Economists Club that she expects the yield on the 30-year Treasury bond to rise to about 7.2 percent in the first quarter and to around 7.5 percent by the middle of the year.</p>
<p>The yield on the long bond is currently around 6.8 percent.  </p>
<p>Fosler argued that both U.S. economic growth and inflation were on the rise, putting pressure on the Federal Reserve to raise short-term interest rates and pushing up bond yields.</p>
<p>The United States has been a &quot;magnet&quot; for foreign capital over the last year, Fosler said, and that has helped hold down U.S. interest rates.</p>
<p>But she questioned how long that could last, especially given her view that the U.S. current account deficit is set to rise this year to an annual rate of about $200 billion.</p>
<p>Fosler argued that the dollar is significantly overvalued against the yen on the order of about 15 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;There is a substantial risk we're going to see the dollar down around 100 yen,&quot; Fosler said.</p>
<p>She said that the dollar was more fairly valued against the mark, adding she only sees a two-to-three-percent decline of the greenback against the German currency.</p>
<p>With interest rates rising and the dollar falling against the Japanese yen, Fosler saw the stock market having trouble maintaining its recent upward march.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to be very hard for the stock market to maintain positive returns,&quot; she said. That is partly because U.S. companies may find it hard to continue to rack up big increases in profits, she added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
