<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="290385" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NHL ICE HOCKEY-GRANATO, FETISOV SPECIAL SELECTIONS TO WEST ALL-STAR TEAM.</title>
<headline>NHL ICE HOCKEY-GRANATO, FETISOV SPECIAL SELECTIONS TO WEST ALL-STAR TEAM.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Left wing Tony Granato of San Jose and Detroit defenceman Viacheslav Fetisov were added to the Western Conference All-Star roster Tuesday as special selections by NHL Commissioner Gary Bettman.</p>
<p>The 32-year-old Granato will be making his All-Star debut at the January 18 game at San Jose, while Russian Fetisov, 38, adds the All-Star honour to a long list of achievements.</p>
<p>Granato has made an inspirational comeback to the NHL after undergoing brain surgery last February to remove an abnormal collection of blood vessels.</p>
<p>Granato, who missed the Los Angeles Kings' final 32 games of the 1995-96 season, signed as a free agent with the Sharks in August. The nine-year veteran recorded a hat trick in the second game of the season and ranks second on the Sharks with 12 goals in 38 games.</p>
<p>&quot;The dedication and perseverance shown by Tony Granato in his remarkable comeback is certainly of All-Star calibre,&quot; said Bettman. &quot;His addition to the Western Conference All-Star team is well deserved.&quot;</p>
<p>Fetisov is playing in his eighth NHL season. The Moscow native made his NHL debut with the New Jersey Devils in 1989-90 after a much-decorated 15-year career in Soviet hockey which included participation in 11 world championships and three Olympics. Fetisov joined the Red Wings in April 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Slava Fetisov's tremendous accomplishments in a career that spans over 20 years in Europe and North America make him a worthy addition to the Western Conference All-Star team,&quot; said Bettman. &quot;His talent and leadership abilities have made him one of the most respected figures in hockey.&quot;</p>
<p>Players named to the Eastern Conference All-Star team as Commissioner selections will be announced Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
