<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="290544" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GHANA: Ship reported sunk turns up in Ghana - agency.</title>
<headline>Ship reported sunk turns up in Ghana - agency.</headline>
<dateline>ACCRA 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A ship with 28 crew reported sunk in the south Atlantic in unexplained circumstances has turned up in Ghana where it has been impounded and the crew arrested, the Ghana News Agency reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Tema Port director Nestor Galley told the agency that the Belize-registered M V Jahan entered Ghanaian waters on Monday, over a week after rescuers called off their search for the crew and ship which was carrying sugar from Brazil to Iraq.</p>
<p>He said the Ghanaian captain and the Burmese, Indian and Bangladeshi crew had been arrested following investigations launched on the orders of the Panamanian owners.</p>
<p>The arrested men were likely to be charged with piracy, Galley said.</p>
<p>&quot;After 11 days the rescue teams failed to locate the ship because it was not sinking and was in a completely different location to what the captain relayed,&quot; Galley told the agency.</p>
<p>&quot;During the investigations it was learnt that the vessel had been renamed M V Zacosea Two and had diverted its original voyage plan and was in Ghanaian waters, heading towards Tema harbour,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>It was not clear at the time what could have caused the sinking of the 15,022-deadweight tonne Jahan, built in 1972, registered in Belize and operated by Seatimes Shipping of Singapore.</p>
<p>The weather in the region, midway between the South African coast and the remote island of Tristan da Cunha, was reported to be fine at the time.</p>
<p>South African state radio said on December 28 that a South African airforce Hercules searched the area of the presumed sinking for several hours without sighting any survivors.</p>
<p>Other reports then said all 28 crew members abandoned ship after the vessel began taking on water and were presumed to be in lifeboats.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the vessel operators said Jahan was on charter to a London company and carrying a cargo of 14,000 tonnes of sugar.</p>
<p>An accord between Iraq and the United Nations, concluded after months of wrangling, allows Iraq to sell a certain amount of oil twice a year to pay for food imports, alleviating the effect of U.N. economic sanctions on the Iraqi people.</p>
<p>It was not clear whether the cargo on Jahan was part of the oil-for-food deal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ACCRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GHANA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
