<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="290822" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Fujimori's ex warns against talks with Peru rebels.</title>
<headline>Fujimori's ex warns against talks with Peru rebels.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Susana Higuchi, ex-wife of Peru's President Alberto Fujimori, warned him in an interview published on Tuesday not to negotiate with the Marxist guerrillas holding 74 hostages at the Japanese ambassador's residence.</p>
<p>&quot;They are a bunch of criminals and killers involved in the drug trade and there is nothing to negotiate with them,&quot; the former first lady, who divorced Fujimori in 1995, told the Argentine newspaper La Nacion.</p>
<p>Higuchi, who shares the Peruvian president's Japanese ancestry, praised his handling of the 3-week-old siege at the Japanese residence in Lima but said she would have dealt with it in a more decisive and tough manner.</p>
<p>She sent Fujimori advice about how to handle the crisis via their four children -- and says she would have cut off electricity, food and water to the residence right after the siege began and kept them hungry and thirsty for two days.</p>
<p>&quot;Then on the third day I would have sent water cans with long-lasting sedatives, the kind that put you to sleep for 12 hours. They would have all been out pretty soon,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Urged to seek a peaceful outcome to the crisis which began when about 20 heavily armed Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels stormed a cocktail party and took more than 500 guests hostage, Fujimori refuses to rule out force until all hostages are released and the guerrillas lay down their arms.</p>
<p>&quot;I think he is doing fine. I presume he has a strategy and wants to capture them by wearing them out,&quot; said Higuchi, who does not believe the president will cede to MRTA demands for action on poverty and prison conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;Knowing the president as I do, I don't think so. He's not the kind of guy who goes for dialogue. But neither is an armed attack a civilised way to start a dialogue,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Higuchi, who has formed her own political party called 20th Century Harmony, confessed to feeling &quot;indifference&quot; for her ex-husband rather than hatred, and said they have not talked for a long time.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been 2 1/2 years without dialogue ... So in way, I'm worse off than the MRTA,&quot; she joked.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
