<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="290922" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China interbank market rates (CHIBOR) mixed.</title>
<headline>China interbank market rates (CHIBOR) mixed.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following is the China Interbank Offered Rate (CHIBOR) for Tuesday issued by the official Xinhua news agency on behalf of the People's Bank of China, the central bank.</p>
<p>The figures represent weighted averages and not closing prices and are annual percentage rates.</p>
<p>		 1DAY   7DAY  20DAY  30DAY  60DAY  90DAY  120DAY</p>
<p> TUESDAY    11.880 11.622 11.842   -    11.831 11.821 12.240</p>
<p> MONDAY     11.040 11.102 11.925 11.541 11.888 11.850 12.240</p>
<p>Turnover fell slightly to 1.8 billion yuan from 1.9 billion yuan on Monday with the 60-day contract the most active.  </p>
<p>Traders said the 60-day contract was once again the most active. There was little interest in selling early-maturing contracts ahead of the Chinese lunar new year holiday, and that drove those rates higher.</p>
<p>There was no trading in the 30-day contract which stood at 11.541 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>Big state-owned banks were cautious due to rumours that the People's Bank would cut deposit and lending rates in the first quarter this year, traders said.  </p>
<p>&quot;A cut in interest rates is possible in the first quarter and the market seems to be waiting for news of this after the national bank meeting next week,&quot; a local trader said.</p>
<p>Senior officials of the central bank and other financial institutions will meet in Beijing next week for a national policy conference, officials have said.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
