<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="290925" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai government spending cuts win plaudits.</title>
<headline>Thai government spending cuts win plaudits.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's plan to cut government spending this year was welcomed by economists and investors on Tuesday as a major initiative in curbing its current account deficit.</p>
<p>The deficit, estimated at a six-year high of 8.2 percent of gross domestic product in 1996 against 8.1 percent in 1995, has sparked an exodus from the Thai stock market and triggered sporadic attacks on the baht in the past several months.</p>
<p>Thailand's slowest economic growth in a decade and sluggish exports last year have prompted the government of Prime Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh to announce major spending cuts and austerity measures this week.</p>
<p>The Thai economy grew 6.7 percent in 1996 against 8.6 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>Chavalit said state carrier Thai Airways International Plc should delay its 68 billion baht ($2.75 billion) plan to order 21 new Boeing and Airbus planes during 1996-2000. He asked the airline to consider leasing aircraft for its service.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Amnuay Viravan also said he would slash at least 50 billion baht of planned government budget annually during the fiscal year 1997 and 1998 by holding back defence expenditure and low priority social and economic programmes.</p>
<p>He said measures aimed at curbing wasteful consumer spending were also on the government agenda.</p>
<p>&quot;We are tightening our belts and we have to make sure that every baht we spend counts,&quot; Amnuay told Reuters on Monday.</p>
<p>The battered Thai bourse, which lost 38 percent last year, rallied 3.78 percent on Tuesday as investors welcomed prospects of a narrower current account deficit.</p>
<p>&quot;The measures should have a fairly instant effect...we are trying to contain the current account deficit and they should certainly make it more manageable,&quot; said Viraphong Vacharath, economic advisor at Bangkok Bank Plc.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a good start and it is a politically astute move to cut defence spending. I think Chavalit has taken note of mistakes of his predecessor and he realises the magnitude of the problem,&quot; said Rob Sheridan, an economist at Thai Fuji Finance and Securities.</p>
<p>He said new civil servant pension schemes and other plans to boost public savings should make a government target of narrowing the 1997 current account deficit to 7.9 percent of GDP Some analysts, however, warned that the government might have to be cautious in its spending cuts as changing committed purchase agreements on military equipment could strain relations with Thailand's trading partners.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
