<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="290921" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan VP leaves for Nicaragua, transit in U.S..</title>
<headline>Taiwan VP leaves for Nicaragua, transit in U.S..</headline>
<byline>Alice Hung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Even before Taiwan Vice-President Lien Chan left for Nicaragua on Tuesday, his scheduled stopover in the United States had already triggered a diplomatic protest from communist rival China.</p>
<p>Lien's schedule called for him to pass through Los Angeles on Tuesday on his way to Managua for Friday's inauguration of President Arnoldo Aleman. His journey includes an overnight stop in New York on January 11 on his way back to Taiwan.</p>
<p>Lien made no public comment as he left Taipei's airport.</p>
<p>Beijing said on Tuesday it already had made representations to Washington for issuing a transit visa to Lien and warned the United States not to create new damage to Sino-U.S. ties.</p>
<p>Beijing-Washington ties have begun to thaw only recently after more than a year of strain -- much of it linked to shows of U.S. support for Nationalist-ruled Taiwan, seen by the communist government as a renegade province of China.</p>
<p>&quot;We have made representations with the U.S. side,&quot; Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Shen Guofang told a news briefing.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. side should strictly abide by its promises in this matter to avoid new damage to Sino-U.S. relations,&quot; Shen said.</p>
<p>China, Taiwan's arch-rival since a civil war split them in 1949, has tightened a diplomatic squeeze on Taipei in its quest to bring Taiwan under mainland rule.</p>
<p>The U.S. State Department has pledged that Lien would not meet U.S. officials and would not attend any public events while in the United States, which recognises Beijing, not Taipei.</p>
<p>The United States downgraded its ties with Taiwan after it established formal diplomatic relations with China in 1979, a move precluding normal government-to-government contacts.</p>
<p>Washington's decision to let Taiwan President Lee Teng-hui enter the United States to attend a college reunion in June 1995 caused a major crisis with Beijing, which condemned it as a show of support for what it sees as Lee's independence drive.</p>
<p>Beijing froze what had been unofficial but warming contacts with Taipei and began mounting menacing war games and missile tests in waters near Taiwan that reached peak in the runup to the island's historic March 23 presidential election.</p>
<p>Washington responded by dispatching two aircraft carrier groups to the region in a bold show of support for Taiwan's democratic development.</p>
<p>Despite the manoeuvres, which Beijing acknowledged were a bid to scare voters away from Lee, the previously appointed incumbent won a landslide victory in the first popular polling for a national leader in Chinese history.</p>
<p>Nicaragua is one of only 30 states -- mostly underdeveloped countries in Africa and central America -- that recognise Taiwan's exiled Republic of China government instead of the rival communist Chinese government in Beijing.</p>
<p>Taiwan media have said Lien set the Nicaragua visit for fear that Managua may be tempted to ditch Taipei after South Africa announced in November it would switch allegiance in 1997.</p>
<p>Pretoria has been Taiwan's biggest ally.</p>
<p>Taipei's United Evening News said Lien would fly from New York to &quot;important&quot; and &quot;powerful&quot; European nations to bolster the island's ties with the world's major democracies.</p>
<p>Taiwan officials declined to confirm or deny the report.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
