<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="29107" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Iraq crisis, Russian export delay boost Med crudes.</title>
<headline>Iraq crisis, Russian export delay boost Med crudes.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot crude prices in the Mediterranean were firmer Tuesday on news of an indefinite postponement of the resumption of Iraqi exports and loading delays at the Russian port of Novorossiisk, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;With the Novorossiisk programme delayed and the Iraqi news everything's looking a lot firmer,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Regional benchmark sour Russian Urals, which traded last Thursday at Dated Brent less $1.03 a barrel cif, was sold for 90 cents a barrel below the bell-wether crude on Monday.</p>
<p>Other Russian barrels loading in the first half of September were offered at Dated Brent less 80 cents Tuesday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of this market is sentiment driven and sellers are certainly feeling more bullish,&quot; said an oil company trader.</p>
<p>Early Tuesday, the U.S. launched a cruise missile attack against air defence installations in the south of Iraq in response to military action by Baghdad against Kurdish regions in the north of the country.</p>
<p>In the wake of the attack the U.S. envoy to the United Nations Edward Gnehm said the U.N.'s May 20 oil-for-food deal with Iraq, agreed after months of laborious negotiations, needed to be reopened.</p>
<p>Gnehm said it could be &quot;months and months&quot; before the deal could be implemented. Oil analysts and traders said Baghdad's latest military adventure has probably derailed plans for the resumption of Iraqi exports beyond the end of the year.</p>
<p>Over two-thirds of the planned Iraqi exports, or about 450,000 barrels per day (bpd) at last week's prices, were due to flow through pipelines to the Turkisk port of Ceyhan and then onto the Mediterranean spot market.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of people who are disappointed that there won't be a flood of cheap barrels around in the near future,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Mediterranean refiners were major customers of Iraqi crude before the U.N. imposed an oil export embargo in the wake of Baghdad's 1990 invasion of neighbour and fellow OPEC member Kuwait. Adding to sellers' confidence was a substantial revision to the September Urals loading programme at Russia's key Black Sea port of Novorossiisk due to a combination of reduced crude flows to the terminal and weather-related delays.</p>
<p>Crude loadings have been delayed by five to six days due to three planned pipeline shutdowns in September and port closures in late August caused by high winds.</p>
<p>Shipping sources said the smaller 147,000 bpd crude pipeline to the port was shut for repairs, leaving only the 660,000 bpd line open on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There are very few prompt barrels available,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Crudes from alternative sources also benefitted from a knock-on effect, with sellers of September Syrian Light barrels confident of finding buyers willing to pay the Official Selling Price (OSP) of Dated Brent less 40 cents a barrel.</p>
<p>&quot;Last Friday it was looking like we'd have to accept a discount but I can see two firm bids and I don't think we'll see a sub-OSP number,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>-- Mark Thompson, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7930</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
