<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="291091" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: N.Korea and KEDO to sign nuclear protocols.</title>
<headline>N.Korea and KEDO to sign nuclear protocols.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S.-led consortium and North Korea will sign two protocols on Wednesday under which Pyongyang will provide services and access at the site of two light water reactors to be built in the Stalinist state.</p>
<p>The consortium, called the Korean Peninsula Energy Development Organisation (KEDO), said in a statement on Tuesday that the protocols were negotiated in North Korea in July and in New York during August and September.</p>
<p>Under a $4.5 billion agreement signed in December 1995 after lengthy talks with the United States, North Korea agreed to freeze its nuclear programme, which Washington suspected was being used to develop nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>In return, the United States agreed to arrange the provision of two light-water nuclear reactors generating 1,000 megawatts of power each by approximately 2003. The light-water reactors produce less weapons-grade plutonium.</p>
<p>KEDO, which includes the United States, Japan and South Korea, has its headquarters in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;The first of the two protocols sets forth contracting and other arrangements under which the DPRK (Democratic Peoples Republic of North Korea) will make available services to KEDO and its contractors for the LWR (light water reactor) project,&quot; the KEDO statement said.</p>
<p>The second protocol to be signed in New York on Wednesday concerns the use of, access to and takeover of the project site in North Korea, the statement said.</p>
<p>KEDO and North Korea signed three protocol agreements on July 11 concerning the logistics of building the reactors.</p>
<p>In November, at a time when tensions were high on the divided Korean peninsula over the landing of a North Korean submarine in South Korea, Pyongyang's official Korean News Agency (KCNA) accused Washington of dragging its feet on implementing the nuclear accord.</p>
<p>The United States and South Korea said they were pressing ahead with the agreement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I1610109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
