<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="291154" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. West Coast diesel prices ease on weak demand.</title>
<headline>U.S. West Coast diesel prices ease on weak demand.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast spot diesel fuel prices on Tuesday continued to ease on weak demand as floodwaters began to recede in some areas of northern California, traders said.</p>
<p>Sellers refused to come off asking prices pushed higher by yesterday's futures rally, and buyers that fled to the sidelines during the run-up patiently waited for cash prices to ease, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sellers are not coming down, and buyers are looking for lower prices in line with the Merc,&quot; one trader said, referring to a nearly 1.50 cent a gallon drop in front-month heating oil and more than 0.50 cent a gallon drop in gasoline futures in afternoon NYMEX trade.</p>
<p>With vast areas of farmland and hundreds of homes still under water in northern and central California from recent rains, spot demand for refined products remained weak, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand in the Bay Area is dead,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Traders also were looking for trading signals from weekly inventory figures due out today. &quot;(The market is) fairly quiet, waiting for inventories,&quot; one trader said of the American Petroleum Institute report due late in the day.</p>
<p>-- Houston Bureau ((713 210-8508))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
