<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="291355" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: PRESS DIGEST - Sri Lanka Newspapers - January 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Sri Lanka Newspapers - January 7.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Sri Lankan press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>DAILY NEWS</p>
<p>Justice and Constitutional Affairs Minister G.L.Peiris says government will be compelled to hold a referendum on devolution if main opposition United National Party opposes it.</p>
<p>The time has come for all communities to think and act &quot;Sri Lankan&quot;, instead of along ethnic lines, says President Chandrika Kumaratunga.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE ISLAND</p>
<p>Criminal Investigation Department (CID) questions Deputy Defence Minister Anuruddha Ratwatte, following complaint made by UNP politician Anura Bandaranaike. Bandaranaike, President Kumaratunga's brother, alleged that Ratwatte made a criminally defamatory statement at a public rally in September, 1996.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>DIVAINA</p>
<p>Troops of 'Operation Rivijaya Two' move on rebel camps in eastern Batticaloa, say defence sources.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>DINAMINA</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry says there is no confirmation that there were Sri Lankans on board ship which went down in the Mediterranean over Christmas.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>LANKADEEPA</p>
<p>Local businessmen to finance film on the recent incident where helicopter carrying Ratwatte, Police chief W.B. Rajaguru and Army Commander Rohan Daluwatte, crash landed in rebel territory.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THINAKARAN</p>
<p>Chief priests of Asgiriya and Malwatte chapters say they want to resign from posts because Buddha Sasana Ministry failed to safeguard Sinhala Buddhist rights.</p>
<p>---Colombo newsroom (941) 434319</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
