<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="291306" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU restarts clock on Credit Lyonnais's future.</title>
<headline>EU restarts clock on Credit Lyonnais's future.</headline>
<byline>Amelia Torres</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The clock begun ticking again for the French bank Credit Lyonnais on Tuesday, as the European Commission warned it might be unable to rule on a new rescue plan before the bank's 1996 accounts are closed unless it knows A European Commission spokesman told reporters a letter would be sent, probably later on Tuesday, to French representatives in Brussels requesting urgent information on the latest measures to restore the bank's long-term profitability.</p>
<p>On September 26, the Commission approved emergency aid of 3.9 billion French francs ($739 million) for the troubled bank to avoid a half-year loss of some 1.1 billion francs ($208 million) that could have called into question its very viability.</p>
<p>But this measure, which consisted of softening the conditions attached by the Commission in July 1995 to a 45-billion-franc ($8.5 billion) restructuring plan, was approved only for the financial years 1995 and 1996.</p>
<p>The French government wants to extend the new conditions beyond 1996 and plans a capital injection into the state-controlled bank this year, the Commission said in a statement published in the European Union's Official Journal on December 24.</p>
<p>Unless the Commission rules on the new measures before the end of March, when the bank closes last year's accounts, its dire financial situation could again be exposed.</p>
<p>&quot;(European Competition Commissioner Karel) Van Miert had said that ideally the Commission would take a decision before the accounts are closed. We should have received the file before the end of the year and that's fine if we get it at the beginning of this year,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>But the French government has apparently showed little desire to keep the Commission informed of its new plans to restore the bank's good health before privatising it.</p>
<p>More than three months after the urgent aid was approved, and despite a letter requesting details particularly on the capital increase and the timing and arrangements for the privatisation, the Commission was still limited to reading the details in the press, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The French daily newspaper Liberation said on Tuesday that Paris may be ready to provide 12 billion francs ($2.3 billion) in recapitalisation being sought by the bank.</p>
<p>The spokesman declined to comment on the figure, but Van Miert acknowleged in September that a &quot;considerable&quot; injection would be needed to solve the bank's problems in a durable way.</p>
<p>Credit Lyonnais has been assisted by the French state for several years following losses incurred during a reckless expansion during the past decade which turned it briefly into Europe's largest bank.</p>
<p>In July 1995, the Commission approved with conditions a multiannual restructuring plan consisting mainly in ridding the bank of some 135 billion francs ($25.6 billion) in loss-making assets which where transferred to a state-backed vehicle for a future sell-off or liquidation.</p>
<p>The Commission forced the bank to share the costs of the new structure by granting it a loan of the same value below the money market rate. It was this condition that caused the bank's latest misfortunes.</p>
<p>The Commission, therefore, agreed in September to allow the bank to increase the interest rate on the loan to money market levels.</p>
<p>Without an extension of this aid and a more solid plan, the bank's solvency and the very stability of the French banking system could be in jeopardy.</p>
<p>The Commission said that if Lyonnais had been left to post losses of 1.1 billion francs in the first half of 1996 it would probably not have been in a position to comply with minimum solvency requirements and that the rating agencies would have downgraded its debt.</p>
<p>&quot;In view of CL's size and its financial links with many other financial institutions, its difficulties could spread to those institutions as well,&quot; it said in the December statement citing the French authorities. ($ = 5.275 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
