<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="291324" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MONACO: Monaco celebrates 700th year in upbeat mood.</title>
<headline>Monaco celebrates 700th year in upbeat mood.</headline>
<byline>Irwin Arieff</byline>
<dateline>MONTE CARLO 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Monaco, a sliver of prime Riviera real estate carved out of southeastern France, celebrates its 700th birthday on Wednesday in an upbeat mood about its economic future.</p>
<p>The principality has less than two square km (one square mile) of territory and no natural resources.</p>
<p>But its low business taxes and lack of income tax -- except for French citizens -- have enabled its prospering service-oriented economy to provide jobs for 30,000 people, many of them from neighbouring France and Italy.</p>
<p>With its low crime rate and sunny climate, residents boast it comes close to heaven on earth. Among those lured to the tiny enclave have been super-model Claudia Schiffer, former Beatle Ringo Starr, Beatle offspring Julian Lennon and numerous professional racing car drivers and tennis stars.</p>
<p>Though much of Europe is in a slump, the principality boasts that it can be picky about which businesses it lets in, inviting only environmentally clean industries.</p>
<p>Gross domestic product rose by 15 percent to four billion francs ($760 million) in 1995, the latest year for which statistics are available.</p>
<p>Though Monaco was once heavily dependent on its casinos, turnover from the 70-percent state-owned Societe des Bains de Mer has been shrinking in recent years.</p>
<p>The firm, which owns several luxury hotels, the golf club, the glitzy Jimmy's discotheque, the Opera and numerous restaurants in addition to the casinos, had 1.4 billion francs in sales in 1995, down from 1.6 billion in 1994 and 1.7 billion in 1993, according to state figures.</p>
<p>In any case, the figures show that fees from the Societe des Bains make up just five percent of state revenues these days.</p>
<p>At the same time Monaco's banking, tourism and telecommunications sectors have been thriving, the state says.</p>
<p>Monaco is a neat and trim Riviera resort town which tumbles down to the edge of the Mediterranean from steep mountains to the north.</p>
<p>Unimaginably large yachts are moored in its port, and the streets near the waterfront are lined with banks, jewellery shops and luxury clothing stores.</p>
<p>Following a recent building boom, Monaco's business and residential centre bristles with high-rise apartment blocks and office towers. Luxury villas look down on the urban centre from the cliffs above.</p>
<p>Monaco's royal family has given the principality a glamorous image, particularly after Prince Rainier III married American film star Grace Kelly in 1956.</p>
<p>Kelly died in a 1982 car crash but their children, Prince Albert, 38, Princess Caroline, 39, and Princess Stephanie, 31, still appear regularly on the covers of glossy photo magazines.</p>
<p>Yet on a visit to the casino or a stroll along the port on a cool January day, Monaco's beautiful people appear decidedly elderly, flaunting oversized luxury cars, fur coats and gold jewellery rather than golden youth.</p>
<p>Prince Albert, who is being groomed by his father to rule the tiny state, said in a recent interview that he hoped the anniversary celebrations would showcase Monaco's economic and environmental successes and shift attention away from the princely family's sometimes steamy private lives.</p>
<p>It was on January 8, 1297, that Francois Grimaldi, disguised as a monk, sneaked into a Genoese-controlled fortress, let in his own soldiers, and established the Grimaldi dynasty. Rainier is the 29th Grimaldi to rule Monaco.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MONAC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTE CARLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MONACO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
