<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="291689" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK Treasury may contract out economic forecasting.</title>
<headline>UK Treasury may contract out economic forecasting.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The UK Treasury said on Tuesday it is to appoint a consultant to advise on the feasibility of contracting out the forecasting of key economic indicators.</p>
<p>&quot;The consultant will look at the feasibility of contracting with a service provider to undertake the central economic forecast of macroeconomic aggregates, the forecasting and monitoring of public finances, the work underpinning recommendations about the economic assumptions for public expenditure planning, and the regular assessment of outturn economic data against the forecast,&quot; it said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The study is expected to last around three months.</p>
<p>The statement said if the consultant's report found a market test would be feasible, the Treasury expects to issue a formal contract specification in the late spring or early summer.</p>
<p>It would invite potential service providers to make their bids against this specification. Treasury staff would be able to mount an in-house bid.</p>
<p>&quot;The aim would be to complete negotiations with potential service providers in time for the successful bidder to take over responsibility for the contracted services from the end of 1997,&quot; the statement added.  </p>
<p>Major independent forecasting bodies, such as the National Institute of Economic and Social Research or the London Business School, could be the type of firm expected to submit bids if the contracting out goes ahead.</p>
<p>-- Rosemary Bennett +44 171 542 7715</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
