<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="291605" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: General Instrument sees Q4 charges up to $65 mln.</title>
<headline>General Instrument sees Q4 charges up to $65 mln.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Instrument Corp said Tuesday its board approved a restructuring plan to divide the company into three separate public companies to be leaders in distinct global growth markets.</p>
<p>The company said it will incur after-tax charges of $55 to $65 million, or $0.37 to $0.44 per fully diluted share, in the fourth quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>These charges, the company said, consist primarily of costs related to the transition to the next generation of digital products, restructuring costs incurred through December 31, 1996 and the write-down of certain assets.</p>
<p>The company expects fourth quarter earnings, which will be announced on February 10, to be in the range of $0.28 to $0.32 per fully-diluted share, excluding the charges.  </p>
<p>The company said it will incur additional after-tax charges in 1997 of $50 to $70 million, or $0.33 to $0.47 per fully diluted share, for costs related to the consummation of the restructuring, including the costs of dividing the company's Taiwan assets between NextLevel Systems and General Semiconductor.</p>
<p>The restructuring, expected to be completed this summer through a tax-free spin-off to shareholders, will create three independent companies.</p>
<p>One, the company said, will be NextLevel Systems Inc, a worldwide supplier of systems and components for high-performance networks delivering video, voice and Internet/data services, comprised of GI's cable, satellite and telephony businesses, with 1996 sales in excess of $1.7 billion.  </p>
<p>Another will be CommScope Inc, manufacturer of coaxial cable and supplier of high-performance electronic cables, with 1996 sales of more than $560 million.</p>
<p>The third will be General Semiconductor Inc, now the company's Power Semiconductor division, the world's leading supplier of low-to-medium power rectifiers and transient voltage suppressors, with 1996 sales of over $360 million.</p>
<p>Richard S. Friedland, Chairman and CEO of General Instrument, who will be Chairman and CEO of NextLevel Systems, said the company's three businesses wuld be best positioned as independent, public companies.</p>
<p>&quot;The businesses have different dynamics and business cycles, serve different markets and customers, are subject to different competitive forces and must be managed with different short- and long-term goals,&quot; Friedland said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
