<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="291791" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares surge 3.8 pct to new record.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares surge 3.8 pct to new record.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares on Istanbul's stock exchange soared an average 3.8 percent in a continued rally on Tuesday, with the market index hitting this year's fourth consequtive record, brokers said.</p>
<p>The IMKB National-100 closed at a new all-time high of 1,094, up 40 points from Monday's previous high of 1,054. It leapt 1.84 percent yesterday on top of a six percent surge last Thursday and Friday following the new year holiday from December 27 to January 2.</p>
<p>In dollar terms, the index equalled the April 8, 1996 record of $1 and was up from 96.3 cents on Monday.</p>
<p>Trade volume jumped to 20.18 trillion lira ($184.4 million) from Monday's 17.93 trillion ($163.7 million).</p>
<p>&quot;There was strong activity in shares having specific expectations, but bluechips were rather quiet,&quot; said Huseyin Istanbullu from Meksa securities.</p>
<p>Brokers said the uptrend prompted by downward money and bond market rates, subdued currency trade, 1996 profit prospects of companies in the New Year continued.</p>
<p>&quot;The major reason behind the current rally is quiet alternative markets which causes money to remain within the share market. But it is early to say that extra liquidity is diverted to the shares from other markets,&quot; Istanbullu said.</p>
<p>Brokers said Tuesday's bond auction was also seen positive. The Treasury sold a record 373.3 trillion lira of 399-day bonds at 112.45 percent yield, including 12 percent witholding tax, down sharply from 125.45 percent in the previous 392-day auction on December 24.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
