<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="29195" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian prime minister approves Chechnya deal.</title>
<headline>Russian prime minister approves Chechnya deal.</headline>
<byline>Dmitry Kuznets</byline>
<dateline>NALCHIK, Russia 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin on Tuesday publicly backed a peace deal signed by security chief Alexander Lebed and Chechen rebel leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;The agreements signed by Lebed cause some concern but on the whole we consider them right,&quot; Chernomyrdin, who discussed the issue with President Boris Yeltsin on Monday, told a meeting of top North Caucasus officials.</p>
<p>&quot;We should act within the framework of these agreements and keep to their thrust.&quot;</p>
<p>In Moscow, Lebed told a news conference that about 80,000 people had been killed in fighting in breakaway Chechnya since Russian troops entered the region in December 1994 to crush its bid for independence.</p>
<p>&quot;One may say that about 80,000 people have died, plus or minus 10,000,&quot; Lebed said. &quot;Accordingly there are three times as many injured.&quot;</p>
<p>Fighting in Chechnya died down last month after Lebed signed a ceasefire with the rebels, followed by a political agreement last weekend.</p>
<p>Lebed is secretary of Russia's policy-making Security Council, which was given sweeping powers by Yeltsin last month to tackle the Chechen crisis after rebels seized most of the capital Grozny in an offensive that humiliated Moscow.</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin told the meeting in the ethnic republic of Kabardino-Balkaria that the decision to defer by five years a final decision on Chechnya's status -- the most sensitive issue in talks -- was right.</p>
<p>&quot;We should calm down and this issue should be resolved in five years, maybe with the help of a referendum.&quot;</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin said the Kremlin's initial decision to send troops to Chechnya &quot;did not produce the required results, led to a dead end and to grave consequences&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We must sort out this disgrace and I would even say shame,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, on holiday at a country residence northwest of Moscow, has not yet commented publicly on Lebed's peace agreement. But Chernomyrdin's comments suggested that the Kremlin leader would also give a cautious nod of approval.</p>
<p>Lebed, who is Yeltsin's personal envoy to Chechnya, has still to report to the president after his talks with rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov.</p>
<p>A further apparent snub came to Lebed from the Kremlin late on Tuesday in the form of an announcement that Yeltsin had decorated his bitter rival, Interior Minister Anatoly Kulikov.</p>
<p>The award, &quot;for services to the fatherland&quot;, appeared designed to show Lebed that he was out of line when he called for Kulikov's dismissal earlier this month for alleged mishandling of the Chechen conflict.</p>
<p>In addition to postponing a decision on Chechnya's status, Lebed's accord also involves setting up a joint commission to oversee economic reconstruction and the withdrawal of troops.</p>
<p>Most Russian troops have been withdrawn from Grozny and southern mountain regions in the past week, but federal forces remain on Chechen soil, mainly at bases near Grozny.</p>
<p>Interfax news agency quoted Chernomyrdin's spokesman as saying on Monday that Russia's territorial integrity was paramount and that &quot;the political price of the deal&quot; had yet to be discussed.</p>
<p>Analysts have speculated that Lebed and Chernomyrdin have been wrangling over Chechnya to further their own careers should something happen to Yeltsin and elections be held early.</p>
<p>Lebed has made no secret of his presidential ambitions, and Chernomyrdin, who would take over for up to three months in the event of Yeltsin being incapacitated, is widely regarded as another possible successor.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, 65, who suffered two heart attacks last year, has rarely been seen in public since late June and his failure to meet Lebed has raised speculation about his health. But presidential aides say his health is no cause for concern.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NALCHIK, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
