<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="291940" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Another loss for Gingrich in re-election bid.</title>
<headline>Another loss for Gingrich in re-election bid.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>House Speaker Newt Gingrich lost a fourth Republican vote in his bid Monday for re-election when Rep Linda Smith of Washington said she would cast her vote Tuesday for another member.</p>
<p>Smith, who is entering her second congressional term, told reporters she had not decided whom to vote for in the speakership election Tuesday but said she would probably vote for James Leach of Iowa who announced earlier Monday he would vote against Gingrich.</p>
<p>Other defectors are Rep Tom Campbell of California and Rep Michael Forbes of New York.</p>
<p>Smith spoke as she emerged from a meeting of House Republicans at which Gingrich answered questions about ethics charges against him.</p>
<p>She recalled Gingrich had been in earlier trouble over a $4.5 million book deal and his complaint that he had not been invited to the front of Air Force One when he flew with President Clinton.</p>
<p>She said Gingrich's admission that he had signed a document sent to the House ethics committee containing false information was the &quot;the straw that broke the camel's back.&quot;</p>
<p>She said Republican leaders had promised they would have vote after vote on the speaker until they got a majority for Gingrich.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
