<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292028" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain's Telefonica seen rising further.</title>
<headline>Spain's Telefonica seen rising further.</headline>
<byline>Robert Hetz</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spanish telecoms operator Telefonica de Espana SA has not exhausted its potential for a higher price ahead of a share offer, despite having risen more than 80 percent last year, bourse analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Telefonica still has growth potential, but it will be in line with the market in general,&quot; said one analyst, who did not think the share price was a big factor in the state's forthcoming sale of its remaining 21.01 percent of the company.</p>
<p>Experts agreed that based on fundamental factors, they would continue to recommend the company.</p>
<p>&quot;We are maintaining our buy recommendation,&quot; an analyst with a foreign bank said in Madrid.</p>
<p>He listed four basic reasons for Telefonica's continued popularity with investors: strong growth in mobile telecoms, a competent plan of international expansion, good basic telephone service, and the lack of a strong competitor on the horizon.</p>
<p>Telefonica shares rose 100 pesetas (76 cents), 3.27 percent, to 3,155 pesetas at midday on Tuesday after briefly touching a record high at 3,170. Its shares began to trade in 1996 at 1,657.</p>
<p>Some experts warned, however, that an excessive rise could make it difficult to place the nearly 200 million shares of Telefonica that the state plans to sell next month.</p>
<p>&quot;A climb as strong as this is not interesting and, in principle, Telefonica should take a breather at the high levels reached,&quot; Ignacio Cornejo of Beta Capital said.</p>
<p>Cornejo said his brokerage was still recommending that clients participate in the placement.</p>
<p>Another analyst, Alberto Espalosin of Ibersecurities, said he also had doubts about how high the share price should go and said a retail price below 3,000 pesetas, including the four percent discount, would make it attractive.</p>
<p>The state holding company SEPPa presented the offer to the National Stock Market Commission on Friday, but did not specify the number of shares that would be reserved for each of the distinct tranches.</p>
<p>SEPPa said retail buyers -- spending from 50,000 to 10 million pesetas -- would get a four percent discount on the final share price.</p>
<p>The state did not set an exact calendar for the placement, but said there would be a publicity campaign from January 20 to February 14.</p>
<p>The analysts said they expected Telefonica's privatisation to be a success, but they did not see it taking off as much as Deutsche Telekom did when it was floated last November. Shares in the German telecoms operator rose 19 percent to 33.90 marks on the first day of trading.</p>
<p>&quot;In the case of companies that are already in the bourse, it is much more difficult for something like that to happen,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom + 34 1 585 2151 ($ = 131.3 Spanish Pesetas)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
