<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292079" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: White mercenaries assembling in Zaire - Le Monde.</title>
<headline>White mercenaries assembling in Zaire - Le Monde.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A force of several hundred European mercenaries, some recruited by a former chief of security at the French presidency, are assembling in eastern Zaire to help stem advances by Rwanda-backed rebels, the daily Le Monde said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Questioned about the report, the French Defence Ministry said it had no connection with the recruitment of such mercenaries which it described as a private initiative with no official backing.  </p>
<p>The report in the well-informed French daily followed statements made in Goma, eastern Zaire, on Monday by Laurent Kabila, head of the rebels, who said 1,000 French soldiers had arrived in Kisangani to help Zairean government forces.</p>
<p>French officials had denied that report, saying the only French military on Zairean soil were a handful of gendarmes (para-military police) guarding the French embassy in Kinshasa and the military attache in the same mission.</p>
<p>Tuesday's report in Le Monde put the number of members of what it called a &quot;White Legion&quot; at between 200 and 300.</p>
<p>It said some were recruited by retired Colonel Alain Le Carro, head of the presidential guard at the Elysee palace during the late president Francois Mitterrand's rule. The South African firm &quot;Executive Outcomes&quot; was also involved, Le Monde wrote.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
