<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292082" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain on alert following ETA attacks.</title>
<headline>Spain on alert following ETA attacks.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's Interior Minister Jaime Mayor Oreja said on Tuesday that security forces were on alert for attacks by Basque separatists ETA after the group planted bombs in apparent reply to recent arrests.</p>
<p>&quot;I have always said that ETA, especially when the police chalk up successes, tries to respond,&quot; Mayor Oreja said in an interview on a Spanish radio station.</p>
<p>Spanish police have broken up six groups of violent youths with ties to ETA (Basque Homeland and Freedom) in the past five months, making a series of arrests that Mayor Oreja said was bound to provoke a response from the separatists.</p>
<p>He said security forces were placed on heightened alert after five grenades were launched against Madrid's Barajas airport early on Monday in what he called a bid for publicity.</p>
<p>Three of the grenades exploded on land close to a security fence around the airport causing no damage and bomb disposal squads deactivated the other two grenades.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear that with what (weapons) they were carrying, this was not a frustrated attack but an attempt to make noise and it was a pretty botched job,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Early on Tuesday, the Civil Guard deactivated a small bomb that had been placed on an electricity tower in the northern region of Cantabria, where there had been three small explosions late on Monday.</p>
<p>ETA often sets off small bombs and grenades without injuring people to call attention to its drive for Basque independence and to retaliate against police actions. The group has killed some 800 people since 1968.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
