<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292264" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul awaits action after North Korean apology.</title>
<headline>Seoul awaits action after North Korean apology.</headline>
<byline>Moon Ihlwan</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean President Kim Young-sam on Tuesday welcomed North Korea's apology over a submarine incursion but warned against false hopes for peace, demanding &quot;action rather than words&quot; by Pyongyang.</p>
<p>In a New Year's news conference, Kim urged the communist North to abandon its bellicose stand against the South and join peace talks with South Korea, the United States and China.</p>
<p>Hours after he spoke, reports that a North Korean steel-hulled barge had been found washed ashore near the beach where the Shark-class submarine ran aground last September rattled nerves in Seoul.</p>
<p>Police said a notebook containing a message praising Pyongyang leader Kim Jong-il was found aboard the barge, but a defence ministry spokesman said the vessel was unlikely to have landed any infiltrators.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the boat drifted to the South. It doesn't look like an infiltration vessel,&quot; the spokesman said. &quot;It appears to have been pushed South by heavy seas.&quot;</p>
<p>Another report, that a stricken North Korean vessel waving a white distress flag had been spotted in crashing seas off the east coast, was later denied by marine police.</p>
<p>A police spokesman said the South Korean resident who raised the alarm was mistaken, and the object at sea was a buoy.</p>
<p>Kim did not offer any new diplomatic initiatives in the news conference, which has often been used to unveil major policies.</p>
<p>&quot;It is fortunate for peace and stability on the Korean peninsula that at the end of last year North Korea formally admitted and apologised for the incursion of a North Korean submarine into our waters and then pledged that no incursions will recur,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;However, it is action, rather than words, that counts.&quot;</p>
<p>Kim said the incursion showed North Korea had not abandoned its dream of unifying Korea under communism. The peninsula was divided at the end of World War Two.</p>
<p>He stressed the need to boost defences against the North, saying &quot;only when we our strong will it be possible for us to deter North Korea from making provocations&quot;.</p>
<p>Kim said North Korea had agreed to attend a preparatory briefing this month on the peace talks jointly proposed by him and U.S. President Bill Clinton last year. U.S. and South Korean officials would hold the briefing.</p>
<p>&quot;Within this month the three countries will meet for a briefing and we already have a promise from North Korea. But we don't know the time or the place yet,&quot; Kim said.</p>
<p>The session is designed to pave the way for talks aimed at replacing a truce that ended the 1950-53 Korean War with a permanent peace mechanism.</p>
<p>The move is part of growing contacts between North Korea and the West after Pyongyang apologised for the submarine incident.</p>
<p>The submarine landed 26 armed agents on a Southern beach. North Korea apologised on December 29 and South Korea returned the bodies of 24 infiltrators shot dead during a manhunt.</p>
<p>One intruder was captured and another is still at large.</p>
<p>On Monday, the U.S. Treasury said it had given a licence to giant grain company Gargill to export 500,000 tonnes of grain to famine-struck North Korea.</p>
<p>Kim said that while North Korea struggled with internal problems any North-South summit to discuss Korean unification would be premature.</p>
<p>&quot;The security situation on the Korean peninsula remains volatile and the instability of North Korea due to its increasing difficulties could threaten the peace,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>North Korea's energy shortage is so bad that three MiG fighters had crashed in the past month because of a lack of fuel, Kim said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
