<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292230" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Direct Capital sees growth from NZ air investment.</title>
<headline>Direct Capital sees growth from NZ air investment.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Direct Capital Partners Ltd said on Tuesday it saw growth opportunities in air freight and aircraft maintenance through its 44.5 percent stake in unlisted Airwork (NZ) Ltd.</p>
<p>Direct Capital said earlier it paid NZ$12 million for the stake. &quot;It...exposes us to the growth opportunities in air freight and increasing activity in Asia in the operation and overhaul of rotary aircraft,&quot; Direct Capital Chief Executive Ross George said.  </p>
<p>Airwork provides operation and maintenance services for both fixed wing aircraft and helicopters from its bases at Auckland, Wellington and Christchurch international airports and Ardmore.</p>
<p>Airwork also operates a 50-50 joint venture airline, AirPost, in which its partner is state-owned New Zealand Post.</p>
<p>AirPost had New Zealand's largest air freight contract, providing the air freight services for FastPost and CourierPost. Airwork operates, pilots and provides full maintenance and service for AirPost's seven aircraft.  </p>
<p>George said AirPost's fortunes were closely tied to the postal and courier industries which were growing strongly, both internationally and domestically.</p>
<p>&quot;While postal revenues in New Zealand are forecast to grow at a steady 4-5 percent per annum, courier market growth is forecast to be double that rate. The international air express and air cargo businesses in Asia/Pacific are forecasting 14 percent growth rates,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said international airlines were increasingly outsourcing maintenance work. Airwork had won rotary maintenance and overhaul contracts in Taiwan, Malaysia and Thailand.  </p>
<p>Airwork operates 10 small and medium-sized aircraft, offering maintenance, overhaul and leasing to end users. It has operational contracts with New Zealand police, Tourism Holdings Ltd (formerly Helicopter Line) and the Westpac emergency rescue helicopter. It employs 160 staff, mainly pilots and engineers.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
