<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292370" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai Kaikai likely to rise on Wednesday debut.</title>
<headline>Shanghai Kaikai likely to rise on Wednesday debut.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Clothes maker Shanghai Kaikai Industrial Co Ltd, which will list 80 million B shares on the Shanghai stock exchange on Wednesday, is expected to perform strongly on the first day of trading, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Kaikai is a well-managed company and its initial offering price is low, which will help to offset the present poor conditions on the B share market, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Kaikai's B share is likely to gain solidly on its first day with the price possibly hitting more than $0.300 per share against an issue price of $0.256,&quot; one stock analyst said.</p>
<p>The low issue price has given the share a price earnings ratio of only seven times, according to Shenyin and Wanguo Securities, the lead underwriter of Kaikai's B share issue.</p>
<p>Shenyin said in a research paper published in the Shanghai Securities News on Tuesday that the company was one of China's largest shirt and sweater makers with a 5.7 percent market share for shirts and 2.5 percent for sweaters.</p>
<p>Traders with Shenyin &amp; Wanguo Securities said the stock would rise on the listing day but cautioned the rise would not be great.</p>
<p>&quot;It must be remembered that market conditions are not very good at the moment,&quot; said one trader.  </p>
<p>The 80 million foreign currency shares were issued last month, raising $19.15 million excluding the issue cost. The company says proceeds will be used to expand the firm's clothing production and to open new sales outlets around China.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
