<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="29237" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: OSCE unhappy with Bosnian voter turnout in Serbia.</title>
<headline>OSCE unhappy with Bosnian voter turnout in Serbia.</headline>
<byline>Peter Greste</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Only hours before polls were due to close, organisers of Bosnian absentee elections held in Serbia said they were disappointed with the turnout of about 42 percent of registered voters.</p>
<p>&quot;We expected that the number of voters would be higher,&quot; said the OSCE's representative Antonos Tsakirs.</p>
<p>&quot;We did not expect that all (refugees) would vote, but the cancellation of elections for local municipalities may have influenced some voters.&quot;</p>
<p>The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) which is organising the Bosnia elections under a UN mandate, said some 85,000 refugees had registered to vote in Serbia ahead of the poll rather than return to Bosnia.</p>
<p>About 640,000 Bosnian refugees were registered to vote in 55 countries around the world in the week from last Wednesday. The election day for Bosnia itself is September 14.</p>
<p>&quot;Through the week we estimate about 1,500 went to vote in person at our 54 polling stations in Serbia,&quot; Tsakirs said. &quot;The situation for voting by mail is better. By noon (on Tuesday) we had received about 30,000 ballots through the post.&quot;</p>
<p>The polling stations were scheduled to close at 1900 local time (1700 gmt), although over the next week electoral officials will accept ballot papers through the post that have been stamped with a post-mark before midnight on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The OSCE has described the election process as the most complicated in history.</p>
<p>Bosnian voters are choosing representatives for the Presidency of Bosnia Hercegovina, the House of Representatives of Bosnia Hercegovina, the House of Representatives of the Federation, the National Assembly of the Serb Republic, the Presidency of the Serb Republic and cantonal assemblies.</p>
<p>Even before the voting began, reports of widespread manipulation of the registration process in Yugoslavia and Bosnian Serb territory cast a shadow over the election.</p>
<p>Citing irregularities that would have handed the Serbs unfair electoral victories in local elections and legalise results of ethnic cleansing, the OSCE mission postponed municipal polls.</p>
<p>Soon after the polls opened for absentee ballots, hundreds of refugees complained that they had not received their papers which should have been delivered through the post.</p>
<p>OSCE officials said they would be delivered within the following few days, although Tsakirs conceded that some refugees were complaining on Tuesday that their papers had still not arrived.</p>
<p>&quot;The figure is not significant,&quot; he said. &quot;What I can figure out is that some people changed address and did not go back to pick the papers up, or postmen were unable to deliver them for some reason.&quot;</p>
<p>Tsakirs said while he was concerned at the relatively low turnout, he said many people may have changed their minds and decided to vote in person on polling day in the villages where they used to live before the war.</p>
<p>Western powers including the United States concede that the vote in Bosnia may not be entirely free and fair, but they insist the elections should go ahead to put unified democratic institutions in place and seal the Dayton peace accord.</p>
<p>But human rights groups say the poll will only give a thin veneer of democratic legitimacy to ethnic conquests won in battle.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
