<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292385" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Marriott to manage Philippines hotel.</title>
<headline>Marriott to manage Philippines hotel.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Ayala Group said on Tuesday it had signed a contract with Marriott Lodging, a division of Marriott International Inc, to operate a hotel in the Cebu province in the central Philippines.</p>
<p>Called the Cebu City Marriott Hotel, the 303-room hotel is expected to open in early 1998 after a two-year construction period. It is being built at a cost of over 1.0 billion pesos inside the 50-hectare Cebu Business Park, Ayala officials told reporters.</p>
<p>The hotel is owned by Cebu Insular Hotel Co, a 63-37 joint venture between Ayala Hotels Inc and Cebu Holdings Inc, both members of the Ayala Group.</p>
<p>&quot;To date there are about 1,000 hotel rooms targeted available in Cebu city. Average occupancy rate has been estimated at 70 percent, a firm indication of the keen need for such accommodation,&quot; said Miriam Ramos, a director of Cebu Holdings.</p>
<p>Ed Fuller, executive vice president of Marriott International, said the project will help Marriott grow in the rapidly expanding Asian region. Marriott came to Asia only in 1991.</p>
<p>&quot;Asia is a growing market. The Philippines is indicative of that. We're very excited about starting in this market,&quot; Fuller said.</p>
<p>Cebu Holdings Inc is owned 44 percent by Ayala Land Inc, while Ayala Hotels is half-owned each by Ayala Land and Ayala Corp, the group's flagship company.</p>
<p>The Marriott Group manages and operates more than 210,000 hotel rooms and 1,200 properties in 50 states in the United States and in 33 other countries, including three in Asia-Pacific.</p>
<p>--Manila newsroom 63 2 841-8937 fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
