<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292354" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Nikkei futures plunge through 19,000.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Nikkei futures plunge through 19,000.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Nikkei futures closed at their lowest level in more than a year on Tuesday as depressed sentiment and a bearish technical outlook combined to drag the market down by almost 500 points.</p>
<p>The benchmark Nikkei 225 March contract finished at 18,960 against its previous settlement at 19,455, after hitting a low of 18,860.</p>
<p>Dealers said stop-loss sales were triggered below the psychologically important 19,000 points level pulling the March Nikkei sharply lower.  </p>
<p>The yen's recovery against the dollar was largely ignored by the market, which on Monday used the dollar's rise to a near 46-month high of 117 yen as a reason to sell the Nikkei.</p>
<p>The dollar was quoted at around 115.48/58 yen at 0830 GMT after a slew of comments by Japanese officials calling for more stability in forex rates.</p>
<p>&quot;We couldn't get above the small intra-day resistance of 19,550-19,590 so the market just tried the bottom and pushed through it,&quot; said a trader with a local institution.  </p>
<p>He said the March Nikkei could bounce back from the 18,550-18,750 support region but on the longer-term charts it looked set to test 17,550 eventually.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole downtrend will only be able to change if we can see 20,000 again. But that looks tough. There are so many (resistance) levels before that,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Sonali Desai (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
