<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292469" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: PRESS DIGEST - Vietnam - Jan 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Vietnam - Jan 7.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the official Vietnamese press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>VIETNAM NEWS</p>
<p>-- Prime Minister Vo Van Kiet on Monday urged the Vietnam News Agency to accelerate its own renovation to match the country's fast integration into the world community, and in particular the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN).</p>
<p>-- The Ministry of Maritime Products has established a National Humanitarian Fisheries Fund to support fishermen suffering economic hardship.</p>
<p>-- Prime Minister Vo Van Kiet is establishing a national executive board for Vietnam's Global Environment Fund.</p>
<p>-- The Vietnamese and Chinese Unions of Peace and Friendship Associations expressed their determination to boost bilateral cooperation in promoting peace and friendship between the two nations.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SAIGON TIMES DAILY</p>
<p>-- Vietnam Paper Corporation's subsidiaries suffered losses of up to 25 billion dong ($2.3 million) in 1996, according to a report released by the Industry Ministry.</p>
<p>-- The Mekong Delta province of An Giang has asked the government to open Tinh Bien Border Gate to trade to help boost commerce between Vietnam and Cambodia.</p>
<p>-- Vietnam will import only 300,000 tonnes of steel this year because the country's own output increased 226 percent last year over 1995, a source from Vietnam Steel Corporation said.</p>
<p>-- The Daewoo Group of South Korea is targetting total investment of $4 billion in the coming years, Daewoo Electronics Indochina's General Director, Hong Nam, said. So far, Hanoi has granted Daewoo licences for 19 projects capitalised at $1.027 billion.</p>
<p>-- Vietnam's industrial sector last year received 162 foreign direct investment projects with total registered capital of $2.19 billion, a Ministry of Planning and Investment source said. Sixty-three of the projects were in heavy industry, with total investment capital of over $1.0 billion, 67 worth $470 million were in light industry and 29 worth $612 million were in the food industry.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>NHAN DAN</p>
<p>-- Vietnam exported 1.37 million tonnes of aquatic products worth $670 million in 1996, 21.69 percent more than in the previous year.</p>
<p>-- Vice Foreign Minister, Nguyen Dy Nien, has called for more favourable conditions, including issuance of visas, for overseas Vietnamese intellectuals to return and give assistance to the country.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>HANOI MOI</p>
<p>-- Hanoi's chief architect is considering measures to simplify procedures for approval of construction licences.</p>
<p>-- The Ministry of Trade has set out the conditions under which companies may operate as exporters.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SAIGON GIAI PHONG</p>
<p>-- The country's biggest sugar factory, in the southern province of Long An, began operations after a trial period, with daily capacity of 3,500 tonnes of sugar cane.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
