<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292613" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch see chance of slight easing of UK BSE ban.</title>
<headline>Dutch see chance of slight easing of UK BSE ban.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Gaunt</byline>
<dateline>THE HAGUE 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Netherlands believes it may be possible to lift the worldwide ban on British beef for cattle from Northern Ireland during the next six months, the Dutch farm ministry's spokesman said on Monday.</p>
<p>Henri Kruithof told reporters at a briefing to mark the start of the Dutch European Union presidency that Northern Irish herds, generally free of mad cow disease, could be exempted from the ban if Britain made a formal proposal.</p>
<p>&quot;There might be a majority (of EU states) for lifting the ban on certified herds,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he said there was little likelihood of any widespread easing in the near future.</p>
<p>&quot;The implementation of a good traceable system in Britain will take two years at least,&quot; he said, referring to a method for certifying which cattle are most at risk from mad cow disease, or bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE).</p>
<p>The EU imposed a global ban on British beef exports in March last year after London disclosed that BSE, which has ravaged British herds, could be linked to a fatal human equivalent.</p>
<p>Britain has been seeking a step by step lifting of the ban, starting with so-called certified herds -- those with a clear record of being BSE-free.</p>
<p>Kruithof said Northern Ireland had a good system of monitoring its cattle that could open the way to a partial lifting.</p>
<p>British Agriculture Minister Douglas Hogg told EU ministers last month that he would present proposals early in 1997 to have certified herds exempted from the ban. London, however, has been reluctant so far to approach the EU for a regional lifting.</p>
<p>Kruithof said other regions of Britain posed greater problems than Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be a lot more difficult in Scotland,&quot; he said. The traceability is better in Northern Ireland than Scotland.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain's Conservative government, now in minority, relies on Northern Irish members of parliament to stay in power. It faces a general election by May at the latest.</p>
<p>Kruithof said Hogg would have to make a formal proposal for a lifting of the ban on certified herds this month if action was to be taken before the poll.</p>
<p>&quot;He will have to make this proposal in January or it won't come into effect before the elections,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="THE HAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
