<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292647" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>COTE D'IVOIRE: AT&amp;T to join Ivory Coast phone bid.</title>
<headline>AT&amp;T to join Ivory Coast phone bid.</headline>
<byline>John Chiahemen</byline>
<dateline>ABIDJAN 1997-01-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. telecomunications giant AT&amp;T has agreed to buy a 35 percent stake in an African consortium that is bidding to take over Ivory Coast's telephone company CI-TELCOM, a partner in the group said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been given the firm commitment of the world's biggest telecommunications company that it will take a 35 percent stake in Africa Bell,&quot; Ivorian investor Bergson Koffi told Reuters.</p>
<p>Bergson said AT&amp;T's Director for International Programmes in Sub-Sharan Africa was due in Ivory Coast on Tuesday ahead of another round of bidding on Thursday.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T's decision marked a dramatic change from its previous cautious policy on CI-TELCOM, which is heavily in debt and would need heavy investment in network and equipment upgrade by the eventual operator.</p>
<p>The American giant had previously been selected as management contractor in the event of the bid going to Africa Bell, a consortium until now dominated by Ivorian entities.</p>
<p>CI-TELCOM, with an estimated value of between $200 million to $350 million, is the most important company on Ivory Coast's privatisation programme.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T's involvement, if the Africa Bell bid succeeds, would represent a major breakthrough for an American company in a traditionally French domain. Ivory Coast is the most important economy in France's former colonies in West and Central Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a sign of things to come,&quot; said Koffi, who is president of Ivorian cellular network Loteny Telecel. &quot;If AT&amp;T goes ahead other American companies will also come here.&quot;</p>
<p>Africa Bell made the highest offer for 51 percent of CI-TELCOM's shares during a previous bidding on December 17. Its rivals are state-owned France Telecom and Telekom Malaysia.</p>
<p>A columnist for Ivory Coast's official daily, Fraternite-Matin, on Monday argued in favour of Africa Bell, saying that a France Telecom or Telekom Malaysia takeover of CI-TELCOM would be like handing over the phone company to the French or Malaysian state.</p>
<p>Africa Bell bid 106.6 billion CFA francs ($203 million) for 204,000 shares and also agreed to pay 100 percent of an 11 billion CFA capital increase envisaged for the privatised CI-TELCOM.</p>
<p>France Telecom threw in a sweetener by agreeing to pay off CI-TELCOM's debt of 40 billion CFA, the bulk of that, owed to itself as a major supplier and technical partner.</p>
<p>Telekom Malaysia, which took over Guinea's telephone company in 1995 and looks on track to clinch a similar deal in Ghana, made the lowest offer of 82.4 billion CFA for the shares.</p>
<p>Industry sources said Ivory Coast's government privatisation committee found none of the offers sufficient and had called for new bids, which will be opened publicly on Thursday.</p>
<p>The winner will take a 51 to 55 percent stake in CI-TELCOM, the state will retain 35 percent, eight to 10 percent will be sold to Ivorian shareholders on the Abidjan stock exchange and staff will be offered one to two percent.</p>
<p>($=524 CFA)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABIDJAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COTE D'IVOIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
