<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292636" id="root" date="1997-01-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: DIW cuts 1997 German growth forecast - paper.</title>
<headline>DIW cuts 1997 German growth forecast - paper.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-01-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German DIW economic research institute has cut its 1997 gross domestic product (GDP) growth forecast to &quot;about two percent&quot; from 2.5 percent made last autumn, Handelsblatt newspaper reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The institute said in a new report to be published Tuesday that the &quot;dramatic slowdown&quot; in economic activity in east Germany gives &quot;great cause for concern,&quot; Handelsblatt reported.</p>
<p>DIW is scheduled to release the report at a news conference in Berlin at 0900 GMT.  </p>
<p>DIW is one of Germany's six leading institutes which had predicted German GDP growth of 2.5 percent in 1997 in their autumn report published last October.</p>
<p>According to Handelsblatt, DIW said in its new report that the east German economy would have to expand at annual rates of four to five percent for many years in order to catch up with the west German economy.</p>
<p>But DIW expected east German GDP growth of just one percent in 1997, half the increase predicted in the six institutes' autumn report. It had also cut its forecast for west German GDP growth to two percent from 2.5 percent, the paper said.</p>
<p>&quot;The goal of appropriate growth will not be met,&quot; the Berlin-based institute said in a report released on Tuesday. Growth remains insufficient to create jobs and meet the challenges posed by German unification, it said.</p>
<p>The slowdown of growth in formerly communist east Germany is the biggest cause for concern, DIW said.</p>
<p>Growth rates of four to five percent would be needed for the next several years for the east to reach a comparable level of prosperity with the west, it said.</p>
<p>But developments in the west have also been disappointing, DIW said. Since the end of the recession in 1993, the German economy has grown only 5.5 percent, far weaker than in the recovery of the early 1980s, which had been the weakest in west German history.</p>
<p>-- Terence Gallagher, Bonn newsroom, 49 228 26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
