<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292746" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mass Electric Co's ratepayer choice test starts.</title>
<headline>Mass Electric Co's ratepayer choice test starts.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than 4,700 customers of Massachusetts Electric Company, a subsidiary of New England Electric System, will be switching to the power supplier of their choice this month as a year-long test of the competitive marketplace gets underway.</p>
<p>The customers represent an annual usage of approximately 80 million kWh (kilowatt hours), or 80 percent, of the 100 million kWh which were available for the pilot, said Shana Pyun, a spokeswoman for Enviornmental Futures Inc which is administering the pilot program for the Massachusetts Department of Public Utilities.</p>
<p>&quot;We had 50 million set aside for small businesses users and 50 million for residential customers. The small businesses are fully subscribed and we have been getting more applications from them than we can serve,&quot; said Pyun, who said that residential customers applied for a total of 30 million KWh.</p>
<p>About one-third of the residential customers chose so-called &quot;green suppliers&quot; who provide power made by renewable energy sources or offered energy conservation benefits.</p>
<p>During the pilot, which ends December 31, Massachusetts Electric will continue to deliver power to pilot participants and provide billing, metering, and repair services.</p>
<p>However, the utility will not be purchasing power for the volunteers. Instead, these customers have chosen to receive their power from an energy supplier other than Massachusetts Electric.</p>
<p>&quot;This year-long pilot, which was suggested by the DPU, is aimed at uncovering and resolving the issues related to creating a market for competing energy suppliers,&quot; said Lawrence Reilly, Massachusetts Electric Company president.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan to use this year wisely as we approach the goal of allowing retail competition for all customers in January, 1998.&quot;</p>
<p>Massachusetts Electric Company is the state's largest utility, serving 950,000 customers in 150 communities.</p>
<p>Environmental Futures, Inc. is a Boston-based management and communications consulting firm focusing on the energy and environmental sectors.</p>
<p>((--Boston bureau, 617-367-4106))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
