<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292887" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bond rally, earnings anticipation boosts banks.</title>
<headline>Bond rally, earnings anticipation boosts banks.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Major U.S. bank stocks rallied Wednesday following an increase in the bond market and high expectations for quarterly earnings, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's been a reprieve. The whole group had been depressed for the last couple days due to interest rates concerns. They had been knocked around pretty hard,&quot; said Lawrence Cohn, a bank analyst with PaineWebber.  </p>
<p>The long bond gained 4/32 to yield 6.78 percent at midday on Wednesday. Chase Manhattan Corp gained 1-1/4 to 88-1/8. NationsBank Corp surged 4-1/8 to 103. Wells Fargo and Co gained 6-1/8 to 279-3/4 and Citicorp increased 1-1/4 to 103-1/4.</p>
<p>The rally in the bond market drove large money center banks higher, since those companies tend to be more interest rate sensitive than regional banks, said Frank Anderson, an analyst with Stephens Inc.</p>
<p>Bank stocks also jumped in anticipation of strong earnings results. The major banks are expected to begin reporting quartely earnings next week.</p>
<p>Analysts expect banks to post 10-15 percent growth in earnings for the fourth quarter. That growth is expected to continue in 1997, with earnings increasing about 10 percent.</p>
<p>NationsBank's share price got an added boost from its announcement that it will repurchase about 37 million shares of common stock due to its $9.8 billion acquisition of Boatmen's Bancshares, analysts said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
