<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292956" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: TENNIS-CHAMPION BECKER SAYS &quot;NOTHING LEFT TO PROVE&quot;.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-CHAMPION BECKER SAYS &quot;NOTHING LEFT TO PROVE&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Six-times grand slam champion Boris Becker says he has nothing left to prove as he prepares to defend the Australian Open title that relaunched his career.</p>
<p>The seasoned German, who broke a five-year grand slam drought with last year's win over Michael Chang, told reporters on Wednesday he felt no pressure, except perhaps a yearning to again wear the world number one crown.</p>
<p>&quot;Coming back to a grand slam in the year after you won it is pure pleasure,&quot; Becker, 29, said after beating Ukrainian Andrei Medvedev in the Colonial Classic, a warm-up event for the Open which starts at Melbourne Park on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is something I don't experience after every grand slam. So coming back here brings back all the good moments and good memories I had in 1996 and I thrive on that.</p>
<p>&quot;So I only think positively, I don't feel any pressure,&quot; added Becker, who won his first grand slam at Wimbledon aged 17, then repeated the feat the following year. Some of his current opponents were then still learning how to play.</p>
<p>Becker has been consistently recorded end-year rankings in the world's top 10 since his first Wimbledon victory in 1985, but now concedes he is in the autumn of his career and gives the impression he is playing for his family rather than the crowd.</p>
<p>&quot;The most important thing, especially at my stage in my tennis career ... is most to enjoy every day of your life as a tennis professional,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Because after winning Wimbledon at 17 or 18 there was nothing really left to prove, so it was always important to enjoy the game.&quot;</p>
<p>Last Saturday, in a magazine interview published in Germany, the world number six said he hoped to reach the top again before retiring from the game in about three years' time, when his son, Noah, started school.</p>
<p>&quot;For as long as I play tennis, being number one will be the ultimate dream,&quot; Becker told Der Spiegel magazine.</p>
<p>Becker has been troubled by injury since winning his second Australian Open and was forced to pull out of last year's French Open and Wimbledon. But he finished the year strongly, winning the lucrative Grand Slam Cup last month.</p>
<p>He faces a formidable line-up for the year's first grand slam. Though out-of-form Andre Agassi has withdrawn from the event, world number one Pete Sampras will be keen to erase the memory of his shock third-round exit last year.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a huge event,&quot; Sampras told reporters in Melbourne on the eve of the Colonial Classic.</p>
<p>Last year's Australian Open was an emotional one for Sampras who cried on centre court after learning coach and close friend Tim Gullickson had fallen ill. Gullickson later died of a brain tumor.</p>
<p>World number two Michael Chang, outplayed by Becker here last year, hopes to go one better at Melbourne Park this month and bag an elusive second grand slam title.</p>
<p>&quot;Now is not the time for me to back down,&quot; said Chang, who is also playing the Colonial Classic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
