<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="292917" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-PGA TOUR'S NEW YEAR STARTS WITH MERCEDES CHAMPIONSHIPS.</title>
<headline>GOLF-PGA TOUR'S NEW YEAR STARTS WITH MERCEDES CHAMPIONSHIPS.</headline>
<dateline>CARLSBAD, California 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Whether 1997 will be the Year of the Tiger will begin to unfold this week when Tiger Woods and other 1996 U.S. PGA Tour tournament winners launch a new season at the Mercedes Championships.</p>
<p>The first full campaign for Woods, who took the tour by storm after winning his third straight U.S. Amateur title last summer, gets under way Thursday at the La Costa Resort and Spa.</p>
<p>Woods, 20, stunned the golf world when he captured a pair of tournament titles, had three other top-five finishes and banked $790,594 in earnings, the 24th-best total for 1996, after turning pro late in the season.</p>
<p>A top-notch, elite field, as usual, will be on hand for the $1.2 million tournament.</p>
<p>The defending champion is Mark O'Meara, who finished fifth on the 1996 money list with $1,255,749. At last year's event, O'Meara was the only player to shoot in the 60s in each round as he beat Nick Faldo and Scott Hoch by three strokes.</p>
<p>O'Meara had two wins in 1996 and has 12 for his career.</p>
<p>The tournament is limited to the 32 winners of PGA Tour events in 1996 and kicks off a season of 45 events.</p>
<p>Steve Elkington, who won this event in playoffs in 1995 and 1992, is not entered, but former champions Phil Mickelson (1994), Davis Love III (1993) and U.S. Open champion Steve Jones (1989) will play, as will 1979, 1980 and 1984 winner Tom Watson.</p>
<p>Watson finished one place behind Woods on the money list last year ($761,238). His win at the Memorial broke a nine-year drought and was the 33rd victory of his career. The 47-year-old Watson was sharp enough to lead the tour in eagles and rank fourth in scoring.</p>
<p>Mickelson was second on the money list ($1,697,799) to British Open champion Tom Lehman, who also is entered.</p>
<p>Mickelson, a left-hander, had four wins and four other top-10 finishes. Lehman earned $1,780,159 and led the tour in scoring at 69.32 despite only two wins. He led the tour with 13 top-10 finishes.</p>
<p>Love trailed only Lehman with 11 finishes in the top 10 and finished seventh in earnings at $1,211,139. He ranked in the top-10 in six different categories last season, including second in eagles.</p>
<p>The top-ranked golfer in the world, Greg Norman, is not entered.</p>
<p>Norman, who interrupted a break from golf to complete a million-dollar triumph in last week's Andersen Consulting world championship, is taking off until March to rest his sore back.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARLSBAD, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
