<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293085" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London freight - Atlantic looks less stable.</title>
<headline>London freight - Atlantic looks less stable.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dry cargo freight market in the Atlantic looked less stable on Wednesday, brokers said, apart from rates for Capers and modern Panamaxes.</p>
<p>Older Panamaxes and Handy-size vessels appeared to be picked off by charterers at weaker levels for transAtlantic business, especially from US Gulf, Brazil and Argentina. In the East brokers reported that conditions for Capers and Panamaxes were largely unchanged, although some said demand for geared tonnage was better from the North Pacific. Heavy weather in this area was reducing shipping to minimal speeds for the Pacific crossing. The BFI lost one point to 1510.</p>
<p>GRAIN</p>
<p>Bunge's fixture of Arctic for 61,250 heavy grain Mississippi/Holland for Jan 14/17 at a lumpsum equivalent of only $12.90 was regarded as very weak. This vessel is said to be prompt in the US Gulf and waiting to present. She was originally fixed on subjects and failed for similar business at $14.75 (Cargill), $14.25 (Cobelfret) and $13.75 (cArgill again) before finally going to Bunge at $12.90. Market reports suggested that there might be tonnage available to repeat this rate. Cargill still quote 2.9/3m cft Mississippi to Continent for Jan 16/21 and today had a fresh order of 75/85,000 tonnes Mississippi /Egypt for Jan 30/Feb 8.</p>
<p>Rates for Amiga's fixture of Regina for a similar quantity to Egypt for Jan 15/20 did not emerge (estimates ranged from $15.25 up to $16.5, nor for Geepee's timecharter fixture of Gamal Abdel Naser 108,000 dwt US Gulf/Saudi Arabia. Modern Panamaxes continued to attract firm rates to the Far East. Maratha Messenger 71,252 dwt was fixed a week ago to Paxicon delivery US Gulf mid-Jan trip Philippines at in excess of $16,250 daily plus $350,000 bonus, and Gortys 71,504 dwt was rumoured booked by Transfield delivery passing Skaw retro Jan 6 trip via US Gulf to China at $16,000 daily.</p>
<p>Reports also circulated that Pacific Paradise fixed delivery prompt Porto Vesme for a transatlantic round at $12,750 daily, but some brokers suggested this was possibly account Lalemant for ironore from Nouadhibou to the Continent. Other Panamax grain fixings included Gesuri covering NoPac/Iran on timecharter but details were lacking.</p>
<p>In the smaller sizes Shipmair were linked with Michalis V 39,891 dwt delivery prompt Gibraltar for a South American round at $6,000/6,250 daily, and Comshipco fixed and failed on dates with Wor Agamemnon 37,000 dwt Brazil/Germany for mid-Jan at $7,300 daily plus $120,000 bonus. Saroc were said to have booked a similar vessel ECSA/W Med at about $7,200 daily plus $120,000 bonus. Cereole were rumoured to have fixed Iguana 35,267 dwt US Gulf/W Med at close to $7,500 daily plus $65,000 bonus. CAM fixed 28,000 heavy grain US Gulf/Algeria for Jan 12/25 at $21.00 with 2000 discharge, and Toepfer were understood to have fixed Cargo Trader for about 20,000/10 heavy grain prompt Mississippi Belfast at $17.75. Dreyfus booked a prompt 20,000/5 wheat stem from Rouen to W Italy at $12.50.</p>
<p>MINERALS</p>
<p>Fears of the effects of flooding in the ironore mines in the area of Sepetiba Bay and Tubarao were receding according to some brokers. There were unconfirmed reports of Panamax period fixtures - Joyous Land 69,283 dwt, for example, delivery Porto Vesme for 12 option 12 months at $11,300 and 12,300 daily respectively, and/or a sister vessel Joyous Society delivery Richards Bayarly Feb for similar business, possibly for account of Interbulk and Keoyang. NSAC were linked with Rialto 70,000 dwt delivery S Korea/Japan Jan for 12 months at $11,200 daily. Sea Success 69,755 dwt was rumoured fixed in the Far East by S Koreans for 3-5 months in the low $11,000's daily.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
