<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293070" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Soft and palm oil close higher on Europe veg oils.</title>
<headline>Soft and palm oil close higher on Europe veg oils.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Soft and palm oil prices were fully steady at the close of the European vegetable oil market on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Active trading devolped in soft oils prior to the Chicago opening on forecasts of a lower market, but traders were disappointed when the U.S. failed to open as low as expected and prices soon rose on this and pressure from the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;Trade was active but there was not a lot of volume behind and it fizzled out after Chicago opened,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>&quot;Sellers were still keen this afternoon, but buyers pulled out when Chicago opened,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>Palm oil was steady, supported by bullish fundamentals and talk of possible increased demand from China if it lowers its import duty on palm oil.</p>
<p>However not all traders were convinced the bullish trend would last.</p>
<p>&quot;People are walking on egg shells in the palm oil market, it has a life of it's own and takes little notice of what is going on around it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It can change direction without warning and the unwary can easily get caught.&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Dutch soy oil closed 1.75 to two guilders up after Jan traded at 91 and 91.25 guilders, Feb at 92, Feb/Apr at 92.75 and May/Jul at 94 and 94.50 guilders a 100 kilos fob ex-mill.</p>
<p>Dutch rape oil closed 0.50 to one guilder up after Jan fetched 93.50, 93.75 and 94 guilders, Feb/Apr 95 and 95.25 and Aug/Oct 96 guilders a 100 kilos fob ex-mill.</p>
<p>Crude palm oil cif Europe finished $2.50 up to $2.50 down while products were $2.50 with no further business reported.</p>
<p>Coconut oil closed $2.50 to $5 with no outright business reported although Jan/Feb traded in switch with Feb/Mar with a $12.50 spread.</p>
<p>Palmkernel oil was $10 to $5 up and tradeless.</p>
<p>--Jim Ballantyne, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8062</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
