<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293180" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia presses NATO over special relationship.</title>
<headline>Russia presses NATO over special relationship.</headline>
<byline>Timothy Heritage</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov urged NATO on Wednesday to step up efforts to forge a special relationship with Russia, but demanded a say for Moscow in decision-making and a new conventional arms deal as the price.</p>
<p>In a wide-ranging interview with Itar-Tass news agency at the end of his first year in office, Primakov reiterated Moscow's firm opposition to the Western alliance's plans to take in new members from eastern and central Europe.</p>
<p>But he made clear there was room for manoeuvre in a dispute which is overshadowing relations with the West. He called on NATO to start formal negotiations on building a special relationship -- a move which might soften the blow of expansion.</p>
<p>He said Moscow wanted the right to joint decision-making on issues which concern its &quot;vital interests&quot; and revisions of the Conventional Forces in Europe (CFE) treaty, which sets levels on conventional weapons in Europe and limits where they can be placed.</p>
<p>&quot;The main indicator of the seriousness of our partners' intentions will be...first of all, NATO's willingness to take into account our concerns at the talks on adjustments to the CFE treaty,&quot; Primakov told Tass.</p>
<p>&quot;If we manage to reach agreement on the modernisation of CFE ...and to create a mechanism for making joint decisions with NATO concerning Russia's vital interests and other issues, we will sign the appropriate document (on a special relationship).&quot;</p>
<p>He welcomed efforts by NATO to address Russian fears over its expansion plans but demanded more urgency.</p>
<p>&quot;They are steps in the right direction, but they are partial and insufficient,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;NATO members have declared their readiness to work out a document on special relations between the alliance and Russia, but officially the talks on this issue have not started yet.&quot;</p>
<p>Russia says NATO's enlargement to take in former Soviet bloc countries would threaten its security and create new divisions in Europe.</p>
<p>It particularly opposes any movement of NATO weaponry closer to its borders.</p>
<p>NATO is expected to issue invitations to some countries in June. Diplomats say Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic will probably all be members by 1999 and that Russia is seeking as many concessions as possible before enlargement goes ahead.</p>
<p>Russia appears to have toughened its opposition to NATO enlargement since President Boris Yeltsin returned to the Kremlin on December 23 following heart surgery on November 5.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, 65, had talks in Moscow with German Chancellor Helmut Kohl on Saturday. Kohl said after the talks that he was optimistic a solution could be found this year to the disagreement over enlargement.</p>
<p>But diplomatic sources said Yeltsin used the talks to push an even harder line from Moscow. They said he had demanded a legally-binding commitment to involve Russia in formal consultations with NATO on any issue it felt affected its security -- including enlargement.</p>
<p>This would give Moscow influence over alliance decisions and worry eastern European states, which fear Russia could block NATO's further enlargement.</p>
<p>Primakov's comments on Wednesday made clear that a quick agreement on revising the CFE treaty was essential.</p>
<p>The CFE treaty was agreed before the Soviet Union collapsed and set limits on conventional weapons which Moscow says are out of date. Western governments have said they are ready to negotiate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
