<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293190" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbian protesters block Belgrade with car demo.</title>
<headline>Serbian protesters block Belgrade with car demo.</headline>
<byline>Thalia Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbian protesters streamed into central Belgrade in cars and on foot on Wednesday, hoping to outwit police imposing a march ban on the 52nd consecutive day of protests.</p>
<p>Police blocked some city centre streets but car drivers managed to jam others, stopping in the middle of the road and pretending to have broken down.</p>
<p>&quot;The police should declare themselves -- are they here to keep traffic moving or to block it? Milosevic sent tens of thousands of policemen to keep traffic moving, but instead they are blocking traffic,&quot; said Vuk Draskovic, one of the leaders of the Zajedno (Together) opposition coalition.</p>
<p>&quot;Since all streets in the centre are blocked by police, I urge all Belgraders to drive down to the motorway and to drive along it very slowly.&quot;</p>
<p>En route to Republic Square, the daily gathering point for protesters demanding reinstatement of cancelled local election results, Draskovic peered under car bonnets and pretended to help drivers restart their engines.</p>
<p>Zajedno came up with the idea of giant traffic jams to get round a ban on protest marches imposed after clashes between opposition and pro-government demonstrators on December 24.</p>
<p>Sunday's car protest created gridlock in the city centre for several hours.</p>
<p>Students at their daily demonstration played a good-natured game of cat and mouse with police deployed to prevent them from marching and at one point managed to pass through the police cordon and come up on them from behind.</p>
<p>Students and police laughed and waved at each other and local residents, delighted to see the students march even a short distance, hung out of apartment windows, whistling, applauding and throwing balloons.</p>
<p>On Thursday, the students plan to line up in front of the police cordon and refuse to leave until they are let through. Groups of about 100 will be replaced every hour.</p>
<p>Students distributed a leaflet calling on the people of Belgrade to turn out to support them. &quot;Our professors, bishops of our church and academicians will be together with us. We will stand quietly and with dignity in front of the police cordon until it moves away,&quot; the leaflet said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Orthodox Christmas Day, protesters kissed police and wished them a merry Christmas after Zajedno called for a charm offensive to woo security forces to their cause and avert any crackdown.</p>
<p>The opposition accuses the government of President Slobodan Milosevic of robbing it of victory by cancelling results of November local elections in 15 of Serbia's largest towns.</p>
<p>An inquiry by the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) confirmed the opposition claims.</p>
<p>Serbia's Socialist government grudgingly admitted last week that Zajedno had prevailed in a few of the smaller cities but insisted that in other districts no party gained a majority or that the results were inconclusive and needed further study.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
