<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293162" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe delayed export zones set to take off.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe delayed export zones set to take off.</headline>
<byline>Emelia Sithole</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwe's export processing zones (EPZs) programme is set to gain momentum this year with construction of one of three planned industrial parks scheduled to begin this month, a senior zone official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>EPZ Authority Deputy Chairman Herbert Nkala said building of the two other industrial parks would start later and all three would be completed in the last quarter of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;This is going to be a watershed year for export processing zones. The three approved industrial parks will be finished in the last quarter of the year. Construction of one of them will be starting this month,&quot; Nkala told Reuters.</p>
<p>He however declined to give further details.</p>
<p>Development of the three parks, all to be located in the capital Harare, is estimated to cost Z$1.7 billion (U.S.$157 million). One of the parks is a joint venture between Malaysian quarrying and property developers Sungwei and Zimbabwe's state-owned Industrial Development Corporation.</p>
<p>Nkala said while other countries' EPZ industrial parks had been put up by the state, the Zimbabwean government could not do so due to cash constraints so it was looking to the private sector to build the parks.</p>
<p>The southern African country has been talking of implementing EPZs to spearhead export-led growth for the past six years but work on them only started in earnest in 1996 with the setting up of the authority and the appointment of an EPZ chief executive.</p>
<p>&quot;We might have been slightly late in jumping onto the bandwagon but our performance so far indicates that the wagon did not completely leave us behind. We are going to fly this year,&quot; Nkala said.</p>
<p>He said since the authority was set up 10 months ago, it had approved 16 projects -- besides the parks -- worth Z$500 million (U.S.$46 million) with a potential to create 2,684 new jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;The average global rate of approval of export processing zone projects in six per year so we are approving at a much faster rate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nkala said some of the projects would operate outside the industrial parks, saying two of them -- a paprika growing project and a timber venture -- were already on stream.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe's EPZs will offer among other benefits, a five-year tax holiday to companies exporting more than 80 percent of their goods, 100-percent remittance of profits and dividends and no restrictions on foreign and domestic borrowings. $1 = 10.82</p>
<p>----Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
