<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293102" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Tennis-Injured Woodbridge pulls out of Sydney International.</title>
<headline>Tennis-Injured Woodbridge pulls out of Sydney International.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's Tood Woodbridge on Tuesday withdrew from the Sydney International tennis tournament with an injured hip, tournament officials said.</p>
<p>Doubles specialist Woodbridge, who captured his second career singles title in Adelaide on Sunday, injured his right hip during his upset win over sixth seed Marc Rosset of Switzerland on Tuesday, tournament director Barry Masters said.</p>
<p>Masters said Woodbridge expected to be fit for the start of the Australian Open in Melbourne next week and for Australia's first round Davis Cup tie against France next month.</p>
<p>&quot;I spoke to Todd this morning and I know he is hurting and I can appreciate that he has the Australian Open and Davis Cup around the corner and he wants to be careful,&quot; Masters said.</p>
<p>Woodbridge was to have played Byron Black of Zimbabwe on Tuesday. Black receives a walkover into the quarter-finals.</p>
<p>In an early match on Wednesday, Woodbridge's Davis Cup teammate Patrick Rafter upset eighth seed Paul Haarhuis of the Netherlands 6-7 (5-7) 7-5 7-6 (7-2).</p>
<p>Sandon Stolle of Australia also progressed to the quarter-finals with a 6-2 6-1 defeat of Romania's Adrian Voinea while third seed Albert Costa coasted past Bohdan Ulihrach of the Czech Republic in straight sets.</p>
<p>Top men's seed Goran Ivanisevic of Croatia was due to meet Javier Sanchez of Spain later on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Americans Mary Joe Fernandez and fourth seed Lindsay Davenport both won their second round women's singles matches in straight sets, Davenport beating Kimberly Po and Fernandez downing Lisa Raymond.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-23 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
