<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293117" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>zaire: Armed men attack vehicles in rebel-held east Zaire.</title>
<headline>Armed men attack vehicles in rebel-held east Zaire.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Tostevin</byline>
<dateline>GOMA, Zaire 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Armed men believed to be Rwandan Hutus attacked vehicles in rebel-held eastern Zaire on Wednesday, killing one person and wounding six, witnesses said.</p>
<p>The witnesses, who asked not to be identified, said the attack happened at 7.30 a.m. near Katale, site of a former refugee camp for Rwandan Hutus 70 km (45 miles) north of Goma.</p>
<p>The attack was the first reported in rebel-held eastern Zaire since Rwandan-backed rebels of the Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire (ADFL) captured the area three months ago.</p>
<p>&quot;There were about 30 of them (attackers) and they were robbing buses and cars,&quot; said a witness. &quot;We are sure they were Rwandan Hutus because they fled towards the bush at the far side of the refugee camp, where some groups of them seem to be still living.&quot;</p>
<p>An estimated 700,000 Rwandan Hutu refugees left camps around Goma in November and returned home after Zairean rebels backed by Rwanda's Tutsi-dominated army captured the area.</p>
<p>Among those who fled deeper into Zaire were elements of the former Rwandan army and Hutu militias who took part in the 1994 killings of hundreds of thousands of Tutsis and moderate Hutus.</p>
<p>The pockets of armed Rwandans still in the area north of Goma are terrifying local people and have made it harder for remaining Rwandan refugees to be returned home.</p>
<p>The appearance of armed groups at the weekend halted UNHCR operations which in two days brought 932 Rwandan refugees out of Tongo 60 km (40 miles) north of Goma for repatriation.</p>
<p>The camps where the refugees lived for more than two years are deserted but apart from a few hardy local people who try to scavage the area is still considered unsafe by most Zaireans.</p>
<p>&quot;Most farmers are scared even to go out to their fields with these groups of refugees still around,&quot; said the director of a Zairean NGO who would not be named.</p>
<p>&quot;They steal people's crops and come to their houses at night to demand food, they have even abducted people, although we do not have evidence that they have killed them.&quot;</p>
<p>A Zairean group in late December found the bodies of 15 young men who had been hacked to death in a style typical of the Rwandan militia groups.</p>
<p>Alliance rebels fighting to topple President Mobutu Sese Seko say soldiers of the former Rwandan army are helping the Zaire army to prepare a counterattack against the 600 km (400 miles) strip of territory they control.</p>
<p>Mobutu was close to former Rwandan Hutu president Juvenal Habyarimana, whose death was the trigger for the 1994 massacres.</p>
<p>Zaire attempted last year to expel the Banyamulenge -- an ethnic Tutsi group -- to Rwanda, a land they left up to 200 years ago. But the Banyamulenge instead started a rebellion that attracted other Zairean opposition groups.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GOMA, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
