<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293371" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: South American port conditions - Lloyds.</title>
<headline>South American port conditions - Lloyds.</headline>
<text>
<p>Port conditions from Lloyds Shipping Intelligence Service --</p>
<p>ARGENTINA Jan 7 - Santa Fe - No vessels berthed, none in roads, none due. Max. recommended draft 27 ft. 0 in. at access channel. Diamante - No vessels in port, none due. Max. draft 27 ft. 0 in. at passage KM.520. San Lorenzo - Six vessels berthed of which 3 loading sbmp, 3 loading wheat. 4 Vessels in roads. 13 Vessels due at 9 terminals during the week. Max. draft guided by Emilio Mitre channel. Not forecast to vary in the next week. Pasa berth draft 23 ft. 5 in. fw. Rosario - Four vessels berthed of which 1 awaiting orders, 2 loading wheat, 1 loading sbmp. 5 vessels in roads, 6 due during the week. Max. draft guided by Emilio Mitre channel. Forecast indicates that draft will rise approx. 0.1M in the next week.</p>
<p>Villa Constitucion - No vessels in port/elevator berths. Max. draft 22 ft. fw. Max. draft guided by emilio mitre channel. San Nicolas - Three vessels berthed of which 1 discharging iron ore, 2 loading wheat. No vessels in roads, 4 due. Max. draft guided by Emilio Mitre channel. San Pedro - No vessels. Draft guided by Emilio Mitre channel. Max. recommendable draft for Mitre channel at high tide, vessels up to 22 m. beam 3200 ft./fw. High tide, vessels over 22 m. beam 3106 ft/fw. Buenos Aires - 18 Vessels in port, 25 due during the week. Max draft 31 ft. 6 in. fw. High tide Naabsa (guided by entrance channel). Dock sud max. draft 29 ft. fw. High tide Naabsa (guided by entrance channel). Necochea - Three vessels berthed of which 1 loading euca logs, 2 loading fish. No vessels in roads, 13 due. Max. draft 40 ft. Bahia Blanca - Four vessels berthed of which 3 loading wheat, 1 loading fish. 1 Vessel in roads, 17 due during week. Draft depends on each berth.</p>
<p>BRAZIL, Jan 7 - Vitoria - Vessels berthed 1 bulk malt discharger, 1 cellulose loader, 1 vehicles discharger, 1 bulk pig iron loader, 1 container/general cargo loader/discharger. Tubarao - 2 Iron ore loaders, 1 petroleum discharger. Praia Mole - 1 steel products loaders, 1 coal discharger. Portocel - 1 Cellulose loader. Ubu - 1 Iron ore loader. 14 Vessels waiting in roads. Santos - Vessels berthed, 6 full container vessels, 5 general cargo/containers, 1 bulk cement discharger, 2 sugar loaders, 1 bulk chemical products discharger, 1 sulphur discharger, 1 diesel oil discharger, 1 salt discharger, 1 reefer loader, 1 bulk wheat loader, 1 pellets discharger. 10 Vessels waiting in roads, 77 due during the next 7 days.</p>
<p>Private terminals - Cosipa - 1 Iron ore discharger, steel products loader, 1 bulk coal discharger. Rio Grande - Vessels berthed, 1 full container, 1 soya discharger, 1 cellulose discharger, 12 due. Rio de Janeiro - Vessels berthed, 2 general cargo/container dischargers, 3 general cargo dischargers, 2 paper dischargers, 1 passenger, 1 wheat discharger, 1 oil discharger, 1 garlic discharger, 3 wheat dischargers, 3 steel products loaders. Tecon - 2 Vessels. 32 Vessels due during next 7 days. Sao Sebastiao - Tebar - 1 Vessel berthed. Commercial quay - 1 Vessel berthed. Two vessels waiting in roads, 9 due. Paranagua - Vessels berthed, 1 general cargo discharger, 1 pellets loader, 1 general cargo loader. 10 Vessels waiting in roads of which for loading, 1 reefer, 1 container vessel for discharging. 24 Vessels due.</p>
<p>CHILE, Jan 6 - Arica - Two vessels in terminal, 4 berths vacant, 7 vessels due during the week. Iquique - One vessel operating, 5 berths vacant, 9 vessels due during the week. Antofagasta - Four vessels berthed, 2 berths available, 10 vessels due during the week for loading and discharging concentrates, bulk copper, containers and general cargo. 1 Vessel in roads awaiting cargo. Valparaiso - Six vessels berthed working normally, 1 berth vacant, 1 berth out of service due to enlargement of pier 3 until April 1997. 16 Vessels due during the week. San Antonio - Seven vessels operating in port, 2 berths vacant, 16 vessels due during the week. Port busy but no waiting time.</p>
<p>Conception Bay ports - Talcahuano - No vessels in terminal, 3 vessels due during the week, none waiting in roads. San Vicente - Three vessels berthed working normally, none waiting in roads, 3 due during the week. Steel pier - No vessels in terminal. Coronel pier - 1 Vessel berthed working normally. Oil terminal - 1 Vessel berthed, 2 due during the week. Navy pier (Molo 500) - 1 Vessel due during the week. Lirquen - Three vessels berthed, 3 berths vacant. 3 Vessels due during the week. Penco - No vessels in port. Puerto Montt - Two vessels berthed of which 1 coaster, commercial vessel. No vessels in roads, 3 due during the week. Punta Arenas - Two vessels and 1 coaster berthed, 5 vessels due during the week.</p>
<p>PERU, Jan 6 - Callao - Two vessels in bay, 9 in pier (general cargo/containers), no berthing delays. Paita - One fishmeal vessel in pier, no berthing delays. Bayovar - No vessels in port. Talara - Seven vessels in bay, 1 in pier (oil), no berthing delays. Chimbote - One fishmeal vessel in bay, no berthing delays. Pisco - One copper vessel in pier, no delays. Ilo - One vehicles vessel in pier, no berthing delays.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
