<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="29337" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Sept 3.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Sept 3.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Tuesday morning's Albanian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>KOHA JONE</p>
<p>- The Pristina-Belgrade agreement on education appears to be a very important accord in the light of recent bombs and the boycott of the elections by Kosovo's Albanians.</p>
<p>- Italy creates commission to lead the government's fight against the Albanian mafia.</p>
<p>- Opposition Socialist Party is as modern as the other Albanian parties, new secretary general Rexhep Mejdani says.</p>
<p>- Social Democrat Party to strengthen the coalition with the Democratic Alliance Party for the local elections.</p>
<p>- Bosnian Vice President Ejup Ganic, on a one-day visit to Albania, pledges to increase ties with the Albanian authorities and continue to work for peace and stability in the region.</p>
<p>- After participating in the U.S. Democratic Convention Albanian Republican leader Sabri Godo says U.S.-Albania relations are tense and a high level dialogue should start between them.</p>
<p>- Another pregnant woman dies from polio. Three foreign experts to visit Tirana to try to discover its origin.</p>
<p>- Authorities begin rigid control of food products in four districts.</p>
<p>- Albanian Confederation of Trade Unions asks the government to give full compensation after liberalisation of some articles.</p>
<p>GAZETA SHQIPTARE</p>
<p>- One Albanian died last Saturday and three others were sent to hospital after Italian authorities discovered a speed boat near the shore illegally carrying 22 people.</p>
<p>- Bus tickets and post service prices hiked from September 1.</p>
<p>- Following a Council of Europe recommendation President Sali Berisha invites 14 parties to a round-table talk but opposition parties say they have not received it.</p>
<p>- A rain storm last Saturday in the eastern area of Prenjas causes more than $400,000 damage.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
