<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293405" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Nicaraguans angry as Aleman inauguration nears.</title>
<headline>Nicaraguans angry as Aleman inauguration nears.</headline>
<byline>David Koop</byline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Angered by a Supreme Court ruling wiping out dozens of their left-wing laws, Nicaragua's Sandinistas warned on Wednesday of social unrest as their bitter enemy, President-elect Arnoldo Aleman, prepared to take power.</p>
<p>The Sandinistas, strangely silent in the run-up to Aleman's inauguration on Friday, were angered by a Supreme Court decision late on Tuesday striking down dozens of Sandinista-sponsored laws passed in recent weeks.</p>
<p>They accused the court of bowing to pressure from Aleman's Liberal Alliance coalition in overturning the laws, which were passed by the National Assembly in sessions boycotted by pro-Aleman legislators.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision was a coup d'etat with the collusion of the current and incoming governments,&quot; Sandinista Congressman Rafael Solis told reporters. &quot;It puts the country in a crisis situation with unpredictable consequences.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The Supreme Court decision will not help Nicaragua's democratic transition,&quot; Sandinista leader Victor Tinoco said.</p>
<p>Aleman easily beat former Sandinista President Daniel Ortega in Oct. 20 presidential elections. Ortega, who governed Nicaragua from 1979-1990, charged electoral fraud, sparking fears of political instability.</p>
<p>The Sandinistas have a history of revolutionary militancy and often used their muscle to frustrate the early years of the outgoing government of President Violeta Chamorro.</p>
<p>The party leadership called an emergency meeting for late on Wednesday to discuss how it would react. So far it has announced no protest actions during the inauguration ceremony, Sandinista spokesman Silvio Moro told Reuters.</p>
<p>Jubilant Liberals congratulated the Supreme Court for striking down laws they said were illegally passed by the parliament to tie the hands of the incoming government and award cushy jobs to outgoing legislators.</p>
<p>Police dogs sniffed the vacant seats at the national stadium for bombs as Nicaragua prepared for the arrival of seven presidents and delegations from 61 countries to attend the ceremony. Police estimated 22,000 spectators, including 1,000 representatives of foreign delegations, would fill Managua's Rigoberto Lopez Perez Stadium for the inauguration.</p>
<p>With an eye on the spectacular pre-Christmas assault by Marxist rebels on the Japanese ambassador's residence in Peru, officials have redoubled security, deploying 2,300 police officers around the stadium and in key plazas and hotels.</p>
<p>Chamorro, 67, a gray-haired, motherly figure, leaves office with the kudos of the international community for having ended Nicaragua's eight-year civil war and returning the country to democracy and the free market.</p>
<p>She has said the transfer will be the first time in more than 100 years that a democratically elected civilian president handed over power to another in Nicaragua.</p>
<p>Aleman, the beefy former mayor of Managua, takes power amid high hopes and predictions of soaring economic growth. But tough challenges remain. He inherits the second-poorest country in Latin America, still haunted by a bitter right-left polarisation and chronic unemployment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
