<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293498" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-TIMELINES-Today in History - Jan 9.</title>
<headline>RTRS-TIMELINES-Today in History - Jan 9.</headline>
<text>
<p>** BIRTHDAYS **</p>
<p>Scottish painter and writer JOHN RAE was born in 1813. He was the first Sydney Town Clerk.</p>
<p>The American born mother of Sir WINSTON CHURCHILL, Lady RANDOLPH CHURCHILL, was born on this day in 1854.</p>
<p>Australian writer and politician PETER AIREY, who once said &quot;An essential preliminary to social reform is the extermination of two-thirds of the social reformers&quot;, was born in 1865.</p>
<p>Early feminist and French writer SIMONE DE BEAUVOIR was born in 1908.</p>
<p>RICHARD M. NIXON, the 37th president of the United States who resigned over the Watergate Affair, was born in 1913.</p>
<p>American strip-tease artist GYPSY ROSE LEE was born in 1914. Her biography &quot;Gypsy&quot; was the basis of the Broadway musical of the same name, and once during a New York auction, an admirer paid 500 dollars for her mink G-string.</p>
<p>JOAN BAEZ, the American folk singer famous for her protest songs, was born on this day in 1941. The daughter of a Mexican doctor and an Irish teacher her career began in the fifties. She is also remembered for introducing the new talent BOB DYLAN during one of her concerts. Her million bestseller was &quot;The Night They Drove Old Dixie Down&quot; (1971).</p>
<p>British guitarist and songwriter with 'Led Zeppelin', JIMMY PAGE, was born in 1944. Their best known title is probably &quot;Stairway To Heaven&quot;.</p>
<p>US country singer CRYSTAL GAYLE (BRENDA GAIL WEBB) was born in 1951. She is the youngest sister of LORETTA LYNN and PEGGY SUE. The sisters originally performed as the 'Loretta Lynn Sisters'. Her hits included &quot;Don't It Make My Brown Eyes Blue&quot; (1977), &quot;Talking In Your Sleep&quot; (1978) and with EDDIE RABBIT &quot;You And I&quot; (1982).</p>
<p>			   ** EVENTS **</p>
<p>    1799 :    WILLIAM PITT The Younger, Prime Minister at the</p>
<p>time, introduced income tax in Britain at 10 per cent (two shillings in the pound). The unpopular move was to pay for the war against Napoleon's France.</p>
<p>(BOY, HAS THIS GUY GOT A LOT TO ANSWER FOR !!!)</p>
<p>    1806 :    Lord NELSON, hero of the Battle Of Trafalgar, was</p>
<p>buried at ST PAUL's Cathederal in London.</p>
<p>    1811 :    The world's first womens' golf tournament was held</p>
<p>in Scotland.</p>
<p>    1909 :    ERNEST SHACKLETON's polar expedition was forced to</p>
<p>turn back just 17 kilometres from the SOUTH POLE.</p>
<p>    1920 :    ALEXANDER FLEMING pioneered the use of penicillin</p>
<p>at St Mary's Hospital in London.</p>
<p>    1943 :    In Sydney 77 people pleaded guilty to taking the</p>
<p>day off on January 1st without permission. They were placed on twenty pound good behaviour bonds to ensure they  abided by holiday regulations. New Years Day was not a public holiday. Yet it was estimated more than 40,000 workers throughout the country took the day off in defiance of a government directive that it was not a public holiday.</p>
<p>    1945 :    HMAS AUSTRALIA, an 8-inch-gun cruiser, was hit</p>
<p>five times by Japanese suicide planes during the landing of troops north of Manila on the main Philippines island. The Allies were plagued by the kamikaze attacks during their attempts to liberate Manila. This was achieved a month later and more than 5,000 prisoners of war were released.</p>
<p>    1955 :    More than 400 Jamaican immigrants arrived in</p>
<p>Britain in the latest influx of West Indians to help rebuild the war-ravaged country. Conservative politicians were pushing for legislation to control the number of such immigrants.</p>
<p>1972 : British miners strike for the first time since 1926.</p>
<p>    1972 :    The sister ship of the QUEEN MARY, QUEEN</p>
<p>ELIZABETH, was destroyed by fire in Hong Kong harbour.</p>
<p>    1980 :    Saudi Arabia announced the execution of 63 of the</p>
<p>Shi'ite extremists  who seized the Great Mosque in Mecca last November. This inflamed already tense relations with nearby Iran.</p>
<p>(Compiled from ABC ARCHIVES, ABC RADIO NATIONAL, &quot;On This Day&quot; published by REED INTERNATIONAL BOOKS LIMITED, &quot;The Chronicle Of The 20th Century&quot; published by PENGUIN BOOKS and &quot;Rock And Pop (Day By Day)&quot; published by BLANDFORD BOOKS.)</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
