<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="29358" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Major personalities shape Bosnian elections.</title>
<headline>Major personalities shape Bosnian elections.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bosnian elections scheduled for September 14 will be dominated by a handful of Moslem, Croat and Serb personalities who came to prominence during the 43-month war which ended in December.</p>
<p>A few international figures will also play important roles coordinating arrangements for the balloting.</p>
<p>		    BOSNIAN MOSLEMS</p>
<p>ALIJA IZETBEGOVIC - Candidate for the collective Presidency of Bosnia Hercegovina.</p>
<p>As current President of Bosnia Hercegovina and of the Moslem nationalist Party of Democratic Action (SDA), Izetbegovic is the country's most prominent Moslem leader.</p>
<p>Born in 1925 in Bosanski Samac, Izetbegovic spent virtually his entire life in Sarajevo except for two terms (totalling nine years) as a political prisoner under the former Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>Elected to the Yugoslav republic of Bosnia's pre-war collective Presidency in 1990, Izetbegovic won independence for his country in April or 1992, precipitating a 43-month war with Serb and Croat separatists who feared Moslem dominance.</p>
<p>Austere and reserved, Izetbegovic's critics say he has used the SDA party machine to harass and intimidate his opposition. Loyalists view him as the father of the country. Critics say he is a Moslem fundamentalist at heart or in the thrall of those who are.</p>
<p>HARIS SILAJDZIC - Candidate for the collective Presidency of Bosnia Hercegovina.</p>
<p>Silajdzic, 50, served as Bosnia's foreign minister before becoming Prime Minister in 1993. He resigned from his post and from the SDA in January of 1995 to form his own party and contest national elections.</p>
<p>Handsome, mercurial, intellectual and combative, Silajdzic is a solo artist rather than a team player. The 50-year-old rebelled against SDA party discipline and what he saw as its flirtation with Moslem fundamentalism.</p>
<p>Easily the second most popular Moslem in Bosnia after Izetbegovic, Silajdzic is campaigning for a united, multi-ethnic Bosnia. He appeals to those who want a change from the SDA, but change at the hands of someone tested and familiar.</p>
<p>FIKRET ABDIC - Candidate for the collective Presidency of Bosnia Hercegovina.</p>
<p>Fikret Abdic won the most votes in Bosnia's last election but traded the job of president of the Presidency to Izetbegovic in exchange for placing one of his men in charge at the Ministry of Interior.</p>
<p>As the prosperous director of a large food processing business in the northeast of the country, Abdic had an independent financial and political base which he took with him when the Bosnian war started.</p>
<p>Forming his own autonomous province, Abdic worked with separatist Serbs and Croats against the Bosnian government and its troops. The Abdic rebellion collapsed in 1995 and he and his people fled to Croatia where he still lives.</p>
<p>Abdic, viewed as a traitor by most Bosnians, is not expected to be a strong candidate. But he and Silajdzic will siphon votes away from Izetbegovic, possibly handing a Serb the Chairmanship of the Presidency as the top vote-getter.</p>
<p>		    BOSNIAN CROATS</p>
<p>KRESIMIR ZUBAK - Candidate for the collective Presidency of Bosnia Hercegovina.</p>
<p>Zubak, 49, is the current President of Bosnia's Moslem-Croat federation and virtually guaranteed to win the Croat seat on the new national collective Presidency.</p>
<p>He was wounded in 1992 while serving as a soldier in the Croat militia in Doboj. Separatist Serb forces burned his family home in the town that same year.</p>
<p>Formerly a judge, Zubak is regarded as a relative moderate within the Croat nationalist HDZ party but a man without much of a political base outside the party.  </p>
<p>RADOVAN KARADZIC - Former president of Bosnia's Serb republic and of its ruling Serb Democratic Party (SDS).</p>
<p>Karadzic, a former Sarajevo psychiatrist, helped to found the SDS in 1990.</p>
<p>He led separatist Bosnian Serbs through war and peace until being forced from public life in July of 1996 by international pressure on account of having been twice indicted by a U.N. tribunal for war crimes.</p>
<p>Karadzic was supposed to have been handed over to the tribunal but remains in seclusion in the Serb republic.</p>
<p>Although stripped of public and party office and denied the right to run in elections he almost certainly still wields influence on Bosnian Serb politics behind the scenes.</p>
<p>GENERAL RATKO MLADIC - Commander of the Bosnian Serb Army.</p>
<p>Mladic is also twice-indicted for war crimes but the international community has not been able to force him from power and NATO troops refuse to mount a manhunt for him.</p>
<p>A colonel in the Yugoslav National Army when the Bosnian war broke out, Mladic soon found himself in command of Bosnian Serb forces. He is wildly popular in the Serb republic but most Bosnian Moslems and Croats revile him because of the siege tactics and brutal human rights abuses for which his troops became known.</p>
<p>Mladic maintains a low profile and is not running for office, but he still controls the army, the strongest single institution in the Serb republic.</p>
<p>BILJANA PLAVSIC - Acting President of the Serb Republic and candidate for the Presidency of the Serb republic.</p>
<p>Plavsic, 66, was a charter member of the SDS and the hardliner chosen to replace Karadzic as acting president of the Serb republic when he was forced from office in July 1996.</p>
<p>Known as the &quot;Iron Lady&quot; for snubbing Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic, Plavsic is an ultra-nationalist with a record of fierce opposition to the Dayton peace accord.</p>
<p>She lacks practical authority within the government and support within the Army and some patriarchal Bosnian Serbs have a hard time accepting that a woman is running the country.</p>
<p>MOMCILO KRAJISNIK - President of the Serb republic's Assembly and SDS candidate for the new collective Presidency of Bosnia Hercegovina.</p>
<p>Krajisnik, 52, is the main powerbroker in the Serb republic, a man with more clout than even Karadzic as a result of his tight control over police and local authorities and alleged contacts with war profiteers.</p>
<p>He served as speaker of the assembly in the pre-war (Yugoslav) republic of Bosnia Hercegovina but resigned that position when the Bosnian war began in April of 1992 to become speaker of the Bosnian Serb assembly.</p>
<p>Krajisnik will almost certainly win the Serb seat on the new central government collective Presidency. If the Moslem vote is split among several candidates he could emerge as top vote-getter among all candidates and the body's new Chairman.</p>
<p>ALEKSA BUHA - Chairman of the ruling nationalist Serb Democratic Party (SDS) and candidate for Speaker of the new National Assembly of the Serb republic.</p>
<p>Buha, 56, was picked as SDS party chairman when Karadzic was forced from office in July. He is a loyal Karadzic supporter whose constant theme in speeches and writing has been the impossibility of co-existence among Bosnia's Orthodox Serbs, Catholic Croats and Moslems.</p>
<p>		    INTERNATIONAL OFFICIALS</p>
<p>ADMIRAL T. JOSPEH LOPEZ - Commander of NATO-led air, land and sea forces helping to implement the Dayton peace agreement in Bosnia.</p>
<p>Admiral Lopez, an American, will have been in the job for just six weeks when elections are held on September 14. The international community will be looking to his 53,000 ground troops to help provide general security on election day.</p>
<p>The possibility that substantial numbers of refugees and displaced persons might try to cross de facto ethnic boundary lines to cast ballots in home towns from which they were &quot;cleansed&quot; during the war has NATO worried.</p>
<p>NATO will be aided in its security duties by as many as 1,600 unarmed U.N. police monitors.</p>
<p>CARL BILDT - High Representative to Bosnia for the international community.</p>
<p>Bildt, a fomer prime minister of Sweden, is the top international mediator in Bosnia and the man charged with overall responsibility for implementing the Dayton peace agreement. Lacking any executive authority over Bosnia's formerly warring factions he is forced to rely on negotiation to move the process forward.</p>
<p>Bildt's deputy, Michael Steiner, a German, has spent much of his time trying to strengthen Bosnia's shaky Moslem-Croat federation which is generally viewed as the cornerstone of the Dayton agreement.</p>
<p>ROBERT FROWICK - Chief of Mission for Bosnia for the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE)</p>
<p>Frowick has needed all his experience as a seasoned U.S. diplomat to organise and supervise Bosnian elections, which is OSCE's primary role under the Dayton peace agreement.</p>
<p>Ambassador Frowick and OSCE Chairman Flavio Cotti decided in June to proceed with elections on September 14 despite the factions' failure then to create conditions which would permit a fair and free vote.</p>
<p>Frowick decided to postpone Bosnian municipal elections because of voter registration irregularities, among other problems.</p>
<p>The OSCE is gambling that the Bosnian people will seize the opportunity to cast a secret ballot to break the lock on power currently held by Bosnia's Moslem, Croat and Serb nationalist parties.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
