<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293529" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Jan 9.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Jan 9.</headline>
<text>
<p>NIHON KEIZAI SHIMBUN</p>
<p>Japan Tobacco Inc plans to raise domestic prices of cigarettes and cigars following the consumption tax increase from April. JT will raise the price of cigarettes by 10 yen per pack.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Shimano Inc is expected to have increased its current profit by 15 percent to 11.8 billion yen for the year ended in November, helped by robust sales of fishing tackle and the weaker yen. It also expects sales of 131 billion yen.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Four sash window makers, including TOSTEM Corp, are expected to increase profits in the business year to March, helped by strong demand for housing materials. TOSTEM will raise sales by 13 percent to 600 billion yen from the year before.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Suntory Ltd has set up a joint company to produce and sell bio-tech medicine for patients with acute pancreatitis and serious bronchial asthma, in cooperation with bio-tech venture ICOS Corp. Suntory hopes to start selling the drug in the United States in 2001, and in Japan in 2005.  </p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Daiichi Pharmaceutical Co Ltd has licensed rights to its synthetic antibiotic Kravit to foreign companies, hoping to introduce the medicine into overseas markets as early as possible. Johnson &amp; Johnson has obtained permission to produce the drug and sell it from this month.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
