<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293635" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Solidere will not face trial over 1996 deaths.</title>
<headline>Solidere will not face trial over 1996 deaths.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>An investigating judge ruled on Wednesday that Lebanon's biggest company Solidere will not face trial over the deaths of 14 people in a 1996 building collapse in central Beirut.</p>
<p>Investigating judge Sa'eed Mirza issued a ruling that Solidere was not directly responsible for the deaths.</p>
<p>Fourteen people were killed and 10 injured on February 15, 1996, when demolition workers brought down a building in the war-shattered district slated for reconstruction while a family of squatters was still inside.</p>
<p>However, Mirza charged six Lebanese men including Solidere employee Ousama Gharzeddine with causing accidental deaths through negligence by causing the collapse of the building. If convicted they face up to three years jail.</p>
<p>Gharzeddine is an employee of the Solidere department that allocates payments to squatters for eviction from buildings in the central area where the company is in overall charge of reconstruction works.</p>
<p>Mirza ruled that Solidere would only be financially responsible if Gharzeddine was found guilty of an offence.</p>
<p>Solidere, which has said the incident was due to &quot;bad luck&quot;, hired sub-contractors to demolish hundreds of buildings in the war-shattered city centre to make way for reconstruction.</p>
<p>The deaths included squatters, workers and passers-by and brought public accusations of murder against Solidere.</p>
<p>The company is the brainchild of billionaire Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri who has been leading Lebanon's revival from the 1975-90 civil war for more than four years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
