<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293854" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New World Book Encyclopedia - substance over style.</title>
<headline>New World Book Encyclopedia - substance over style.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>PROVIDENCE, R.I.</dateline>
<text>
<p>CD-ROM encyclopaedias are a mixture of style and substance.</p>
<p>Some emphasise flashy pictures and lots of videos, and seem to offer less in the way of depth. Others try to be authoritative, detailed and comprehensive, and usually seem to carry a smaller assortment of multimedia bells and whistles.</p>
<p>The &quot;1997 World Book Multimedia Encyclopaedia&quot; from IBM (Windows, $50) clearly values substance. It lacks the catchy, eye-pleasing graphics of a &quot;Microsoft Encarta,&quot; but it easily compensates by the quality of the information, which is of a higher calibre than any of the leading competitors.</p>
<p>Every word of the 22-volume print encyclopaedia is here. It's easy to use and allows you to make notations in the text. There are lots of photographs and sounds, 65 videos, 44 animations, excellent animated diagrams of important concepts and a virtual reality feature that gives you a 360-degree view of 23 landmarks and parts of the body.</p>
<p>&quot;World Book&quot; turns out to be better than its competitors when dealing with controversial topics on the fringes of science, such as astrology, dowsing, homeopathy, UFOs, and subliminal advertising.</p>
<p>The CD-ROM set consistently gave more reliable information on such topics than any of its competitors. &quot;The Grolier Multimedia Encyclopaedia&quot; ranked a close second, &quot;Microsoft Encarta,&quot; a distant third, with &quot;Compton's Interactive Encyclopaedia&quot; and &quot;Encyclopaedia Britannica&quot; nearly neck and neck for last place.</p>
<p>One drawback to &quot;World Book&quot; is that if you want to browse the multimedia offerings, you're going to have to do a lot of disk-switching. Many of the videos and virtual reality scenes are on the second disk. If you've watched something on disk two and want to choose another selection, you have to put disk one back in first. It quickly becomes annoying.</p>
<p>Another is that the disks, which carry such high-quality information, are packaged in a cheap fold-over cardboard case. &quot;World Book&quot; disks deserve better.</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>Some new and notable software in the stores this week:</p>
<p>&quot;The Complete History of the Boston Bruins&quot; (ReadySoft, Windows/Macintosh $40) is one of six products that give statistics, photos, trivia and a &quot;virtual&quot; visit to the arenas of NHL teams. Related products are for the New York Rangers, the Detroit Red Wings, the Toronto Maple Leafs, the Chicago Blackhawks and the Montreal Canadiens.</p>
<p>&quot;Hardline&quot; (Virgin Interactive, DOS/Windows95, $40) -- &quot;It's the thought that kills&quot; is the slogan for this action/adventure game where you must use an arsenal of seven weapons, plus your ability to blow apart people by thinking about them, to defeat a supervillain known as &quot;The Sect&quot; who is terrorising 5 million people in 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;Jetfighter III&quot; (Mission Studios, DOS, $50) -- A flight combat simulator. This one boasts more than 3.5 million square miles of varied, real-world terrain, 90 missions, unlimited views and a flying system that's easy to use.</p>
<p>&quot;Popular Photography&quot; (Windows, $35) a collection of 500 images selected by the editors of Popular Photography which can be used for on-screen presentations, Web pages or printed materials. SoftKey International is releasing them in conjunction with the latest versions of two other products, &quot;Calendar Creator 4.0&quot; (Windows, $40), which now lets you make calendar pages where the individual boxes can be expanded to list everything on particularly busy days, and &quot;PhotoFinish 4&quot; (Windows, $40) for editing images for newsletters, flyers, reports and greeting cards.</p>
<p>&quot;Science Blaster Jr.&quot; (Davidson, Windows/Macintosh, $35) -- A game that teaches science concepts such as sound waves, relative size, taxonomy and climate. It has three levels of difficulty for ages 4 to 7.</p>
<p>&quot;Super Radio Addition with Mike and Spike&quot; (Windows/Macintosh, $35) -- A math game for ages 5-7 that's part of the &quot;Learning Ladder&quot; series from Panasonic Interactive Media. It has 11 music videos and 14 sing-along &quot;tunes that teach.&quot; Other $35 titles in the series are &quot;Phonics Adventure with Sing-Along Sam&quot; (ages 4-6) and &quot;Reading Adventure with Kenny Kite&quot; (ages 6-8).</p>
<p>    -   -   -   -</p>
<p>(Gene Emery is a columnist who covers science and technology. His Internet address is gene.emery(at)prodigy.com. Any opinions in the column are his alone.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PROVIDENCE, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
