<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293872" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Report says Darwin suffered from panic disorder.</title>
<headline>Report says Darwin suffered from panic disorder.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Charles Darwin, whose theory of evolution altered the course of science, suffered from panic disorder and a phobia that often keeps people shut up at home, two U.S. physicians said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The diagnosis, based on Darwin's writings and other evidence, had not previously been suggested as a source of the ills that bedevilled the 19th-century Englishman, the report from the University of Iowa College of Medicine said.</p>
<p>Fears about the reception his theory of evolution would get from the British scientific establishment might have contributed to the onset of his symptoms, which were present during the 22 years he was writing his revolutionary &quot;On the Origin of Species,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;In descriptions of his illness, Darwin frequently referred to discrete attacks that began suddenly and left him drained,&quot; Thomas Barloon and Russell Noyes wrote in this week's Journal of the American Medical Association. &quot;These attacks consisted of palpitations, shortness of breath, lightheadedness, trembling, crying, dying sensations, abdominal distress and depersonalization.&quot;</p>
<p>The symptoms are consistent with panic disorder, which frequently hits around the age of 28 as did Darwin's problems, and with agorophobia, a fear of crowds, travel and other situations from which escape might be impossible, which can turn its victims into recluses.</p>
<p>Darwin, who lived from 1809 to 1882, suffered from abdominal distress as a young man and had heart palpitations and chest pain as he was preparing for his 1831-1836 round-the-world voyage aboard the HMS Beagle that produced the discoveries behind his theory of evolution by natural selection, the report said.</p>
<p>It was a year after his return from that trip that the symptoms became full-blown, the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;The natural history of Darwin's illness is consistent with panic disorder. He like many patients with this illness had a premorbid vulnerability described as a sensitivity to stress or criticism in his youth,&quot; the paper said.</p>
<p>&quot;Events, such as formulation of his evolutionary theory, which he feared would bring him into conflict with the British scientific estblishment, may have contributed to the onset of his symptoms,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Within two years of the onset of his full-blown illness Darwin was living the &quot;life of a hermit&quot; and had trouble leaving his home unless his wife went along, the study said. &quot;Darwin's illness had an enormous impact on his life and work. It significantly changed his lifestyle from that of a world-wide collector and traveller to a recluse,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;However, as a consequence ... he was able to narrow the focus of his energies ... had it not been for this illness, his theory of evolution might not have become the all-consuming passsion that produced 'On the Origin of Species'.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
