<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293948" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss leave door open for boosting Holocaust fund.</title>
<headline>Swiss leave door open for boosting Holocaust fund.</headline>
<byline>Marcus Kabel</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Swiss government may boost its proposed Holocaust memorial fund in a gesture of goodwill demanded by world Jewish organisations, an authoritative Berne political source said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A Swiss cabinet statement on Tuesday deliberately left open a door for adding government money to a planned fund drawing on some 40 million Swiss francs ($30 million) in dormant Swiss bank accounts, the source close to the issue said.</p>
<p>Jewish leaders, who have pressed Berne to make restitution for alleged Swiss profiteering from the Holocaust, had slammed the cabinet proposal for using other people's abandoned bank accounts rather than Swiss public funds.</p>
<p>But the Federal Council, or cabinet, included wording in its statement allowing a quick payout of federal funds if Berne's research confirms charges of Swiss wrongdoing towards Jews and other Nazi victims, the source told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;This sentence doesn't mean much to most people, but this is a very important sentence,&quot; said the source, who declined to be named. The sentence in question reads:</p>
<p>&quot;Should substantiated facts be found which require immediate action, even while the investigation process is under way, the Federal Council will immediately take the necessary steps.</p>
<p>Groups led by the World Jewish Congress (WJC) have suggested the Swiss make a good-faith financial gesture soon, before a report due in two to five years from historians probing Swiss financial dealings with Jews and Nazis during World War Two.</p>
<p>Separately, the head of Berne's task force on Jewish accounts, diplomat Thomas Borer, denied speculation that he had put forward a figure of $250 million in talks on a possible Swiss payment.</p>
<p>A Jewish source close to the talks said in New York that Berne had been receptive to a Jewish proposal for a financial gesture to Holocaust victims and that a Swiss representative had proposed the $250 million number.</p>
<p>&quot;This figure definitely did not come from the Swiss task force,&quot; said Borer, who did not have a mandate for negotiating any amounts in December discussions in New York with the WJC.</p>
<p>Borer also said he would contact world Jewish groups soon to try to ease tension over Berne's refusal to rebuke Economics Minister Jean-Pascal Delamuraz for calling demands for restitution &quot;blackmail&quot;.</p>
<p>The Swiss government refused to chastise Delamuraz on Tuesday, despite warnings the World Jewish Restitution Organisation might call for a boycott of Swiss banks if it did not.</p>
<p>An influential Swiss banker said lingering tension over the blackmail remark would not halt a joint commission of bankers and world Jewish groups tracking lost Holocaust accounts.</p>
<p>&quot;The work of the commission is not affected,&quot; Hans Baer, vice-chairman of the Swiss Bankers Association and the country's most prominent Jewish banker, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The commission's future was called into question when Jewish Agency president Avraham Burg, a member of the body, said he would not take part unless the Swiss members condemned Delamuraz's remarks.</p>
<p>Baer is an alternate member of the the commission, which was set up last May by Swiss banks, the WJC and the Jewish Agency and is headed by former U.S. central bank chief Paul Volcker.</p>
<p>The continued allegations that Swiss banks plundered unclaimed wealth of Holocaust victims have thrown a small but persistent degree of uncertainty into Swiss financial markets, economists and analysts said.</p>
<p>Markets have not sustained any lasting damage so far but they have been hit on a day-to-day basis by rumours and news.</p>
<p>Stocks of the big three banks, Credit Suisse -- Union Bank of Switzerland and Swiss Bank Corp -- fell temporarily on Monday after the Jewish boycott threat.</p>
<p>The Swiss franc, which is often volatile compared with more liquid currencies, has also suffered ups and downs on the issue.</p>
<p>It fell in December on the mistaken belief that Switzerland would abolish banking secrecy laws to let an independent panel search for unclaimed Holocaust-era bank accounts. Such a move would have stripped Switzerland of a big competitive advantage.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
