<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="293981" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian engineering unions agree to call strike.</title>
<headline>Italian engineering unions agree to call strike.</headline>
<byline>Crispian Balmer</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trades' unions representing Italy's 1.7 million metal and engineering workers agreed on Wednesday to unleash a fresh wave of strikes to press their pay claim.</p>
<p>Unions, who have been locked in dispute with employers since last July over the renewal of two year rolling contracts in the sector, said they would hold 10 hours of strikes between January 9 to 25 on a factory-by-factory basis.</p>
<p>&quot;In all likelihood we will decide on further strikes for the big companies,&quot; said Claudio Sabattini, leader of the Fiom union, adding that the main three metalworkers' unions would meet to discuss additional industrial action on January 15.</p>
<p>&quot;The strikes will only stop when we've got an agreement,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Metalworkers and engineering unions have so far held two eight-hour stoppages in their increasingly bitter showdown with the employers' federation Federmeccanica.</p>
<p>Federmeccanica head Michele Figurati told reporters on Wednesday that he saw no end in sight to the dispute. &quot;There is little hope,&quot; he said after a meeting with Labour Minister Tiziano Treu.</p>
<p>No further talks between the various parties are scheduled.</p>
<p>In a bid to break the stalemate, the government proposed last month that workers should be given a 200,000 lire ($129) a month pay rise to cover the 1996-98 contract period. Figurati said on Wednesday such an offer was &quot;not compatible with costs&quot;.</p>
<p>Unions, which had been seeking a 230,000 lire increase, accepted the government proposal but management is unwilling to pay out more than 139,000 lire a month unless the government offers companies big incentives in compensation.</p>
<p>&quot;By now we're at war with Federmeccanica,&quot; said Gianni Italia, leader of the Fim union. &quot;We want to block and snarl production,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The metalworker and engineering sector accounts for around 40 percent of total output in Italy and embraces some of the country's top companies like Fiat, Finmeccanica and Olivetti.</p>
<p>A number of other important sectors, including the construction and textile industries, are awaiting the outcome of the metalworkers' dispute before renewing their own contracts.</p>
<p>At the heart of the row lies a wrangle over how to interpret a landmark 1993 labour accord which scrapped the automatic index linking of salaries.</p>
<p>Unions argue that the deal allowed for any shortfall between forecast inflation, on which new contracts are based, and the eventual inflation, should be made up in full.</p>
<p>Management reject this.</p>
<p>Asked if the 1993 accord was now at risk, Fiom's Sabattini said: &quot;We are trying to be faithful to the deal, but if it isn't adhered to, there would be no more rules for union relations and we would be in rough seas.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists say that the 1993 labour accord has been key in keeping inflation in check.</p>
<p>&quot;The real risk of this dispute is that there is a breakdown between unions and managment marking the end of this accord,&quot; said Claudio Tosato, analyst with Deutsche Bank in Milan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
