<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="294021" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Maastricht Handling may take on cargo handling at Ostend airport.</title>
<headline>Maastricht Handling may take on cargo handling at Ostend airport.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Maastricht Handling is looking into the possibilities of taking on a cargo handling role at the Belgian airport of Ostend.</p>
<p>Marco van de Kreeke, joint managing director of the Dutch handling company, which is a 100 percent owned by Maastricht Aachen airport, said that Ostend airport's management team invited the Dutch handling company to investigate handling opportunities at the Belgian airport.</p>
<p>The investigation is in a very early stage and any conflict of interest that may arise between the two regional airports is also being considered, he added.</p>
<p>Currently, just a freight handling role is being looked into, although Maastricht Handling does handle both passenger and cargo aircraft at the southern Dutch airport.</p>
<p>Turkish Airlines, Royal Jordanian and Iberia are amongst its customers.</p>
<p>Commenting on why Ostend had asked a Dutch handling company he said: &quot;In spite of Maastricht's restrictions - only having a 2.5 km runway and a night curfew - we do have a good reputation for handling aircraft.&quot;</p>
<p>It is too early to say when a decision will be made but it could be in the next few months, he said.</p>
<p>Belgavia and Sabena carry out handling activities at the Belgian airport at present. But Ostend is experiencing a rapid growth in freight activities, with 1996 seeing a 12.6 percent growth in freight volumes on 1995 levels.</p>
<p>If the plans go ahead, this will be Maastricht Handling's first venture into third-party handling work. -Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax+44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
