<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="294004" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: EMI to unveil ECB policy tool blueprint on Friday.</title>
<headline>EMI to unveil ECB policy tool blueprint on Friday.</headline>
<byline>Janet Northcote</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe will get a glimpse of the shape of its future central bank on Friday, when the European Monetary Institute (EMI) unveils its blueprint for the new central bank's policy instruments.</p>
<p>While central bankers have already hinted at several key aspects of the bank's armoury, financial markets will be looking keenly to see whether the German Bundesbank has been successful in its call for the European central bank (ECB) to use minimum reserves.</p>
<p>They will also be seeking any signs on what guiding principles the central bank will use to steer monetary policy.</p>
<p>Eddie George, governor of the Bank of England, confirmed after a meeting of the EMI's policy-making council on Tuesday that the paper, due to be presented at Friday's news conference, had been approved by Europe's central bankers.</p>
<p>Asked to comment after the meeting in Frankfurt, George said the paper was &quot;a very solid piece of work&quot;.</p>
<p>He added, &quot;We will be able to see the real shape of the arrangement on Friday, but not the final details&quot;.</p>
<p>But the details are likely to remain elusive for some time to come, as the final decision on the instruments can only be taken by the European central bank itself, which will not be created until the first half of 1998.</p>
<p>The new central bank will then take over responsibility for the monetary policy behind the new single currency, the Euro, when it is created on January 1, 1999.</p>
<p>Markets already have a pretty good idea of most elements of the EMI paper, thanks to comments from various central bankers.</p>
<p>The ECB is expected to use a Lombard emergency borrowing facility, which will also form a ceiling for money market rates. There will also be a floor under the money market, although probably not in the form of a discount rate.</p>
<p>The central bank is also expected to follow open market policies, probably using a facility very close to that of the German Bundesbank's securities repurchase tenders, but possibly with a longer maturity and changed bidding rules.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank currently offers two-week funds to banks against securities, calling for bids at a fixed interest rate.</p>
<p>The main outstanding question regards the use of minimum reserves which the Bundesbank -- seen in many ways as the closest role model for the ECB due to its strong reputation and the mark's status as Europe's anchor currency -- insists must be part of part of the new bank's toolbox.</p>
<p>Yet analysts say it is unlikely that the German system of interest-free minimum reserves -- which is extremely unpopular with commercial banks -- will be adopted wholesale. Deposits earning a low rate of interest would be a possible compromise.</p>
<p>However markets are likely to be kept on tenterhooks on the question closest to their hearts -- what strategy the central bank will adopt to guide its monetary policy moves.</p>
<p>Two central models are already on the table for the ECB -- an inflation targeting strategy, as used by the Bank of England, or the monetary targeting beloved of the Bundesbank.</p>
<p>But other models such as careful observation of economic growth, or some combination strategy, are possible.</p>
<p>Economists at BHF Bank said they believed the EMI would leave this thorny decision -- which will be central to the credibility of European monetary policy -- to the ECB itself.</p>
<p>&quot;As the final decision on the monetary concept lies with the ECB council anyway, there is a lot to be said for the assumption that the EMI will present a comprehensive buffet rather than a set meal,&quot; BHF Bank said.</p>
<p>But BHF said the EMI should aim to be absolutely clear on one issue -- that the ECB will not fall in with calls from France in particular for targeting of the exchange rate.</p>
<p>&quot;Particularly against the background of fundamental Franco-German differences of view on the role of the exchange rate in economic policy...a word of clarity on exchange rate targeting would be helpful,&quot; BHF said.</p>
<p>&quot;It should be firmly rejected.&quot;</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
