<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="294142" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. brokers charged in largest test-cheat scheme.</title>
<headline>U.S. brokers charged in largest test-cheat scheme.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Gail Appleson, Law Correspondent</p>
<p>Fifty stockbrokers, some of whom paid up to $5,000 to imposters to take licensing exams for them, were indicted in the biggest securities test-cheating scheme ever uncovered, prosecutors said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Manhattan District Attorney Robert Morgenthau said there were 54 defendants in the scheme, including two &quot;ringers&quot; who took the tests, middlemen who helped carry out the scheme and 50 brokers who paid imposters to take the tests. Three of the latter became middlemen themselves.</p>
<p>Another defendant previously pleaded guilty for his role in the scheme and Morgenthau said the investigation was continuing with more arrests expected. The defendants arrested mostly worked for small brokerage firms throughout the country and many of them were employed by the same companies.</p>
<p>The scheme centred on a national six-hour exam that is offered daily at 56 sites across the country. About 200,000 tests are given annually.</p>
<p>The ringers were able to escape detection by taking the tests at a variety of locations in different states and by using fake photo identifications. The sites included Boston, Chicago, Cleveland, Milwaukee, Nashville and Philadelphia, and smaller cities such as Whitehall, N.Y., and Normal, Ill.</p>
<p>The test measures an applicant's knowledge of securities issues, markets, regulations and laws. It is the first hurdle that potential brokers must pass before they are authorised to sell securities to investors.</p>
<p>Mary Shapiro, president of the National Association of Securities Dealers Regulation, the enforcement arm of the National Association of Securities Dealers, told a news conference that the tests were &quot;critically important&quot; to determine someone's understanding of securities markets.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a serious violation of the law, and a breach of the public trust to cheat on the very examinations designed to ensure that only knowledgeable and qualified brokers deal with investors,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She said that because of the investigation the NASDR began fingerprinting test takers last year and this year will begin videotaping them as well.</p>
<p>Shapiro said it has not yet been determined if there were any customers who lost money due to the scheme.</p>
<p>Morgenthau said he was not prepared to say whether any of the firms that employed the defendants knew about the scheme. But he said there was no current evidence to show that they might be liable.</p>
<p>The 2-1/2 year probe began after proctors at test centres began noticing that one individual was apparently taking multiple tests under different names.</p>
<p>Shapiro said they had also received an anonymous tip about the scheme.</p>
<p>The alleged &quot;ringers&quot; arrested in the scheme were Igor Shekhtman of Encino, Calif., who was employed as a broker with M. Rimson &amp; Co., and who allegedly took at least 28 tests for 17 people, and Robert Idzi, of Pleasantville, N.Y., who allegedly took at least 22 tests for 17 people.</p>
<p>Rimson, which had offices in New York, was expelled by the NASD in March 1996. Idzi had previously worked for Sunpoint Securities Inc., based in Longview, Tex.</p>
<p>Two of the alleged middlemen worked for AS Goldmen &amp; Co., one worked for Gruntal &amp; Co. and the fourth for Associated Investors.</p>
<p>Morgenthau said the probe of exams held nationwide between 1993 and 1995 showed that the potential stockbrokers paid the ringers $2,000 to $5,000 or promised them future legitimate business and shares of commissions. The middlemen typically received a portion of the payments.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
