<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="29436" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Andean Pact to begin Mercosur talks next week.</title>
<headline>Andean Pact to begin Mercosur talks next week.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA, Colombia 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Andean Pact trade ministers will meet in Venezuela next week to discuss ways of forging a free-trade agreement with the Mercosur customs union, a senior Colombian official said Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to begin conversing about the mechanisims and criteria for negotiations with Mercosur,&quot; Foreign Trade Minister Morris Harf said.</p>
<p>He said the talks would be held on the sidelines of an Andean Development Corporation meeting in Caracas and help lay the groundwork for a formal meeting of Andean Pact and Mercosur countries to be held in the near future in Peru.  </p>
<p>Venezuelan Foreign Minister Miguel Angel Bureilli Rivas announced Monday in Cocbabamba, the Bolivian city where the so- called Rio Group of Latin American countries is holding its 10th presdiential summit, that the Andean Pact had agreed to negotiate a free-trade accord with Mercosur.</p>
<p>The Andean Pact groups Venezuela, Colombia, Ecuador, Peru and Bolivia  while Mercosur -- South America's biggest trade bloc -- is comprised by Brazil, Argentina, Uruguay and Paraguay.</p>
<p>According to Harf, no free-trade accord between the two groups is likely to be completed before 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't want to rush into negotiations,&quot; Harf said, noting that it took Chile about two years to negotiate its own free- trade agreement with Mercosur.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA, Colombia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
