<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="294396" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Blair claims British election race pole position.</title>
<headline>Blair claims British election race pole position.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>British opposition leader Tony Blair, radiating optimism about the imminent general election, said on Wednesday his Labour Party was in its best position for a generation to wrest power from the Conservatives.</p>
<p>Launching a New Year campaign to keep pressure on the unhappy ruling party, Blair condemned John Major as &quot;an uncertain prime minister&quot; who was finding it impossible effectively to lead his fractious troops.</p>
<p>But the event, like a similar effort by Major on Tuesday, failed to point up new themes for political debate, indicating that the election battle could be dominated by mudslinging.</p>
<p>Blair said Labour, which has been shorn of its traditional socialist policies and aspirations under his leadership, was now &quot;a party in the centre ground of British politics, that will govern in the centre ground too.</p>
<p>&quot;The Tories would love to be fighting the Labour Party of the late 70s ands early 80s. They are not,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Striving to keep the loyalty of the millions of middle-class Britons who now support the party, he repeatedly pledged that he would not raise their income taxes and would ensure that any new spending pledges were costed and funded.</p>
<p>&quot;Where we plan to spend money, we say where it comes from. There is no evasion, no double-dealing, no hidden agenda,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Speaking after the publication of a national opinion poll showing Labour 17 points ahead of the Conservatives, who have held power since 1979, Blair said he was not complacent.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;For the first time in a generation, Labour goes into a general election with real confidence that is borne of having a clear purpose for our nation.&quot;</p>
<p>Major, who must call a general election by May 22, said on Tuesday that buoyant economic growth and the public's fears of Labour plans to revamp Britain's constitution, could yet help his party win a fifth consecutive term in office.</p>
<p>Blair mocked Major for the problems he has had in holding his party together, particularly over the question of Britain's place in Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;In uncertain times Britain cannot afford an uncertain Prime Minister. And Britain cannot afford as its Government a party incapable of being led,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Blair repeated that education, designed to give Britain the skilled workforce needed for the 21st century, would be the key concern of his government.</p>
<p>But he said it also wanted to overhaul Britain's welfare state, make constitutional changes which would devolve power away from London and transform Britain's at present uneasy relations with its European Union partners.</p>
<p>The Conservatives claimed that Labour had still failed to spell out its plans for government in sufficient detail. &quot;Having policy statements on everything but detail on nothing is a recipe for disaster,&quot; Defence Secretary Michael Portillo said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
