<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="294323" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FINNISH EMPLOYERS, UNIONS DISLIKE NEW TRAINING PLAN.</title>
<headline>FINNISH EMPLOYERS, UNIONS DISLIKE NEW TRAINING PLAN.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish employers and trade unions on Wednesday criticised planned schemes offering active training opportunities for the long-term unemployed instead of passive pay-outs of jobless benefits.</p>
<p>Employers said the proposals would become too expensive while unions said the benefit to the unemployed would remain below current levels and that the terms to qualify for the schemes were too tight.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen, who received the proposed measures from two government-appointed investigators, said it would be possible to reach consensus.  </p>
<p>Based on the proposals by the investigators cosensus must be reached across the administrative branches and above various conflicts of interest between the labour market organisations, Lipponen said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is responsible for ensuring that there will be no undue delay in improving the training opportunities for the unemployed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The investigators' proposals offer the unemployed independent training possibilities (and) training support benefits equalling their unemployment benefits,&quot; the government said in a statement outlining the proposed schemes.  </p>
<p>Long-term unemployed with past working experience of at least 12 years would receive training support benefits equalling their unemployment benefits for an unlimited time of training, the government said.</p>
<p>Pay-outs of training support benefits at an unchanged level would continue also after the current fixed-term duration of his/her earnings-related unemployment benefits had expired, it said.</p>
<p>And an unemployed participating in the new training scheme would not &quot;lose&quot; any of his/her days of eligibility to receive earnings-related jobless benefits.  </p>
<p>The state pays 47.5 percent, employers 47 percent and employees 5.5 percent of earnings-related unemployment benefits.</p>
<p>The investigators also proposed a series of training support measures for other categories of unemployed.</p>
<p>They put the total costs of the training benefits at 2.2 billion markka, of which 960 million markka would come on top of unemployment security benefits projected for 1997 under the current systems.</p>
<p>In addition, the proposals would lead to 1.3 billion markka in new costs to provide training opportunities for the unemployed, the government statement said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Although the increase in training opportunities on offer and the training support benefits will cause additional expenditure, structural unemployment can be reduced and Finland's real competitiveness improved,&quot; the government said.</p>
<p>But employer confederations saw the proposals in a different light.</p>
<p>&quot;The annual cost to employers would rise significantly,&quot; Tapani Kahri, deputy managing director of the Confederation of Finnish Industry and Employers (TT), said in a statement.</p>
<p>TT called the entire set of new training support proposals &quot;unnecessary&quot;.  </p>
<p>&quot;For the service sectors, indirect labour costs would rise further, which will lead to weaker employment possibilities,&quot; the Confederation of Finnish Servcice Industry Employers said in its statement.</p>
<p>The 1.1-million mainly blue-collar member Central Organisation of Finnish Trade Unions (SAK) said the proposal was &quot;a failure&quot; and that &quot;benefits will in most cases remain below the current level&quot;. The terms for receiving benefits were also too tight, SAK said in its statement.</p>
<p>The central union for academic professionals (AKAVA) also said the proposals did not meet its targets.  </p>
<p>And the Labour Ministry issued a statement saying the proposals would require a lot of consideration. The ministry said it had found particular flaws in the planned financing of training support benefits.</p>
<p>--Helsinki Newsroom  +358 - 9 - 680 50 245</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
