<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="294312" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: SAMPO SEES '97 FINNISH PREMIUM INCOME UP 5-6 PCT.</title>
<headline>SAMPO SEES '97 FINNISH PREMIUM INCOME UP 5-6 PCT.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish insurance group Vakuutusosakeyhtio Sampo said on Wednesday it expects 5-6 percent growth this year in all Finnish non-life insurance premium income after three percent growth last year.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect 5-6 percent growth in premium income this year,&quot; Sampo Chief Executive Officer Jouko Leskinen told a news conference. He added he was referring to non-life insurance, and Sampo said it was referring to the whole sector.</p>
<p>According to preliminary 1996 data, non-life insurance premium income for the Finnish insurance business increased three percent to over 11 billion markka, Leskinen said. Life insurance premiums rose to over 10 billion markka from 7.2 billion in 1995, he said.  </p>
<p>Leskinen said the expected increase in non-life insurance premium income was largely based on brisk Finnish gross domestic growth forecasts for this year. The finance ministry is expecting 3.9 percent growth, most other forecasts are around 3.5 percent.</p>
<p>The quickest growth in Finnish insurance premiums would be seen in life insurance in the next fex years, Leskinen said.</p>
<p>By the turn of the decade, annual life insurance premium income is likely to be double that of the early 1990s, he said, again referring to the entire sector.</p>
<p>Sampo's pension insurance unit Elake-Sampo's 1996 earnings had improved clearly on 1995, Sampo executives said, but gave no figures.</p>
<p>&quot;The (1996) result looks clearly better than in 1995...the trend is very satisfying,&quot; Markku Hyvarinen, managing director of Elake-Sampo, told the news conference.</p>
<p>The changes governing employment pension funds approved by parliament before Christmas were seen increasing pension funds' stock market investments.</p>
<p>&quot;Investment in stocks will increase but moderately and in a controlled fashion,&quot; Hyvarinen said.</p>
<p>--Veera Heinonen, Helsinki newsroom +358 - 9 - 680 50 240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
