<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="294414" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bunds supported for now but dangers seen looming.</title>
<headline>Bunds supported for now but dangers seen looming.</headline>
<byline>Kate Kelland</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>High unemployment, low economic growth and subdued inflation will all help support German Bunds in the near term, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But the two sides in a German-U.S. battle for investor interest remain closely matched for now and Bunds will be playing second fiddle to Treasuries before the year is out, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Markets are anticipating a strong rise in German unemployment and a weak final quarter GDP, giving a very subdued reading for growth over 1996 as a whole,&quot; said Michael Burke, bond strategist at Citibank in London.</p>
<p>But the German market is being pulled both ways.</p>
<p>Latest production data show slightly more favourable developments in the economy but joblessness, due for release on Thursday, is expected to have ballooned in December.</p>
<p>Analysts forecast a rise of 35,000 to 60,000 from the November record of 4.1 million.</p>
<p>Gross domestic product (GDP) data for 1996 on Thursday is expected to depict a limping German economy -- a supportive factor for Bunds but around 36 billion marks ($23 billion) of new supply also threatens to drown the market in the first month of the year.</p>
<p>Holger Fahrinkrug, economist at UBS in Frankfurt, said the near-term outlook was good for Bunds in isolation.</p>
<p>Bund investors are hungry for fresh paper, especially in the 10-year area where the last benchmark was issued more than eight months ago, he said, and the sombre economic picture would keep prices up.</p>
<p>&quot;The current trend in Germany should be supportive,&quot; he said. &quot;The supply is going down well and all the signs we're going to get in the short term should point to a substantial economic slowdown.&quot;</p>
<p>But because expectations are so bearish, Bunds are already pricing in downward pressure on yields, analysts said, making it difficult to see the German market squeezing more outperformance over Treasuries in the near term.</p>
<p>Burke and Fahrinkrug said the 10-year T-note/Bund yield gap was likely to maintain the status quo for now, with Treasuries yielding around 70 to 75 basis points over Bunds.</p>
<p>The big shock could come on Friday when December non-farm payroll figures are released in the United States.</p>
<p>Analysts polled by Reuters predict that 192,000 jobs will have been addded to payrolls last month but say the figure may be distorted by Christmas hiring in the retail sector.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not as aggressive as some forecasters,&quot; said Burke, who was forecasting a 140,000 rise. &quot;The U.S. economy is at full employment, so the level of job creation should moderate.&quot;</p>
<p>If the U.S. jobs report is weaker than consensus expectations, relieving pressure for a rise in interest rates, Treasuries will begin to outclass Bunds, analysts said -- setting a trend for the medium term.</p>
<p>Mark Capleton, international bond strategist at BZW in London, said economic growth would slow to trend or below trend rates in the United States, while the German economic recovery would continue to crawl higher.</p>
<p>Against that background, Capleton said the Bund/T-note gap would start heading towards parity on a six-month horizon and should hit that goal before the year is out.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect Bund yields to be above Treasury yields by the end of the year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rallies in all debt markets into the end of last year had been overstretched, Burke said, and were due for a correction.</p>
<p>With the U.S. market having already achieved a substantial pull-back, a Bund price decline was next on the cards.</p>
<p>Fahrinkrug said fundamentals would be the key.</p>
<p>Market nerves about an overheating U.S. economy were misplaced, he said, adding that data further down the line was likely to depict a more subdued picture.</p>
<p>&quot;We are expecting more of a soft landing scenario in the economy, which is really not priced into the U.S. market yet,&quot; Fahrinkrug said. &quot;So over the longer term, we would expect outperformance in the U.S.&quot;</p>
<p>($1=1.5711 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
