<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="29456" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Che's daughter snipes back at France's Debray.</title>
<headline>Che's daughter snipes back at France's Debray.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES, Argentina 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The daughter of guerrilla Ernesto &quot;Che&quot; Guevara denied on Tuesday she was acting for communist Cuba in charging that a prominent French ex-Marxist was to blame for her father's death.</p>
<p>Aleida Guevara told the Argentine daily Clarin the charges she made in the newspaper last week against Regis Debray were her own opinion and were not fed to her by Cuba's leadership.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not interested in what Debray says and I'm not working for anyone because this has to do with my father, that and nothing else. No one has told me what to say,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Aleida, who works as a pediatrician in Havana, said Debray &quot;talked more than he should have&quot; when he was detained in Bolivia after visiting Guevara and his small band of leftist guerrillas in the Bolivian jungle in 1967.</p>
<p>Guevara, who was Fidel Castro's right-hand man and then tried to export Cuban-style revolution to mainland South America, was hunted down and shot by Bolivian troops.</p>
<p>Debray, once an advisor to late French President Francois Mitterrand and author of a recent book critical of Castro, said Cuba was hounding him because it thought he was encouraging resistance movements on the island.</p>
<p>Guevara stood by what she said: &quot;I don't have any proof. What I said last week is our opinion: that my father went out of his way to get Debray out of the jungle and that our impression is that when Debray was captured he spoke too much.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES, Argentina"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
