<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="294829" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: LVMH says not interested in Bulgari.</title>
<headline>LVMH says not interested in Bulgari.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>French luxury goods conglomerate LVMH denied a rumour circulating in the stock market that it was interested in buying or taking a stake in jeweller Bulgari.</p>
<p>&quot;We deny having any interest in Bulgari,&quot; an LVMH spokeswoman told Reuters.</p>
<p>LVMH shares were up 2.97 percent at 1,458 francs at 1205 GMT.</p>
<p>Brokers attributed the rise to rumours that the group was interested in Bulgari and to expectations that brokerage Cheuvreux de Virieu was about to issue a favourable study.</p>
<p>Portfolio managers said they had been advised that the study would examine the value of LVMH, taking into account the integration of the U.S. duty-free chain DFS.</p>
<p>An LVMH acquisition of majority control of DFS hinges on the approval of U.S. antitrust authorities, expected before the middle of the month.</p>
<p>Cheuvreux has maintained its high &quot;1&quot; rating on LVMH.</p>
<p>The Bulgari rumour was fuelled by the strong rise in Bulgari shares in the Milan bourse, a portfolio manager said. The firm, which originated as a manufacturer of luxury watches, has diversified into perfumes and silk scarves, and is growing fast.</p>
<p>One manager dismissed the Bulgari rumour, saying the purchase would be dilutive for LVMH.</p>
<p>LVMH has been on the acquisition trail, and one of its recent purchases has been that of jeweller Fred.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I49100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
