<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="294801" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU set to clear Coca-Cola buy of British bottler.</title>
<headline>EU set to clear Coca-Cola buy of British bottler.</headline>
<byline>Amelia Torres</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission appears set to clear Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc.'s full control of British bottler Coca-Cola &amp; Schweppes Beverages Ltd later this month despite strong initial competition concerns.</p>
<p>The deal, which will create a bottling and distribution giant, prompted fears that Atlanta-based Coca-Cola could dominate the British market.</p>
<p>But the Commission's competition services were unable to substantiate such fears and a panel of antitrust experts from the EU's 15 states recommended Tuesday that the proposed acquisition of CCSB be cleared, EU sources said.</p>
<p>At issue was mainly the question of whether the Coca-Cola brand and other cola drinks were a market of their own or whether they were interchangeable with orange-flavored fizzy brands and other carbonated soft drinks.</p>
<p>&quot;The question is 'does Coca-Cola compete with Orangina or is it competing only with Virgin Cola and other cola-flavored products?'&quot; an EU source said.</p>
<p>The Commission's competition directorate took the view that cola-flavored beverages did not compete with other carbonated soft drinks. But it stopped short of concluding that Coca-Cola would gain a dominant position.</p>
<p>&quot;The Commission was not satisfied there were sufficient grounds for believing there was creation of dominance,&quot; the EU source said.</p>
<p>Another EU official said: &quot;We knew that argument was shaky and the legal service had doubts of its own.&quot;</p>
<p>The Commission has until Jan. 29 to make a final decision. But the ruling may come as early as Jan. 22, the sources said. It must rule by a majority vote on a proposal by European Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert.</p>
<p>The expected outcome is a major defeat for British tycoon Richard Branson's Virgin Cola, which filed a complaint with the Commission against CCSB accusing it of anti-competitive practices in Britain. Coca-Cola's arch rival Pepsico is also reported to have voiced concerns about the acquisition.</p>
<p>Coca-Cola Enterprises is a major U.S. producer and bottler of beverages owned by the Coca-Cola company. It is acquiring control of CCSB from Cadbury Schweppes through its purchase of Amalgamated Beverages Great Britain Ltd.</p>
<p>Following the agreement with Coca-Cola, Cadbury will no longer bottle and distribute its own brands of soft drinks.</p>
<p>Coca-Cola's purchase of CCSB was submitted to the Commission for clearance in August under the bloc's merger rules. The Commission started a full probe in September, leading to fears that the transaction could be downsized.</p>
<p>The EU must approve all large mergers and acquisitions involving companies that have a European turnover of at least 250 million European currency units ($200 million) each.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
