<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="294927" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Race is on for round-the-world balloonist Branson.</title>
<headline>Race is on for round-the-world balloonist Branson.</headline>
<byline>Giles Elgood</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>British tycoon Richard Branson, soaring over North Africa's snow-capped Atlas mountains, on Wednesday begins in earnest his race to be the first man to fly round the world in a balloon.</p>
<p>Branson and his two co-pilots lifted off from an airbase near the Moroccan city of Marrakesh on Tuesday in what is believed to be the world's biggest balloon.</p>
<p>&quot;This is one of the most magnificent adventures that anyone could have in their lifetime,&quot; Branson said.</p>
<p>At his mission control centre in London, a spokeswoman said the team had spent their first few hours aloft getting to know how to handle their balloon, the Virgin Global Challenger.</p>
<p>They then headed up into the jetstream they hope will carry them across North Africa, Saudi Arabia and India, the South China Sea, the Pacific and the United States, to land in Britain in a 24,000-mile (38,600 km) trip expected to take between 14 and 21 days.</p>
<p>&quot;That's what they expected on the first day. Everything is going according to plan. From Wednesday, the race is on,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Their spirits are high and they are feeling good.&quot;</p>
<p>Speaking from aboard the the 1.1 million cubic feet (30,000 cubic metres) balloon, filled with hot air and helium, Branson said they had reached 38,000 feet (11,500 metres).</p>
<p>&quot;We're on our way,&quot; he said, heading over the Algerian border.</p>
<p>He said the flight had got off to a shaky start, but the team were back on course.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a little bit of a hairy launch. The balloon went up a little bit faster than we thought, about 2,000 feet a minute, and started spewing helium.</p>
<p>&quot;We seemed to head off in the wrong direction, but all was well in the end.&quot;</p>
<p>Branson is racing against American balloonist Steve Fosset who is planning a similar round-the-world attempt, launched from Switzerland.</p>
<p>With Branson are co-pilot Per Lindstrand and substitute Alex Ritchie who replaced Rory McCarthy at the last minute after he suffered a sudden attack of bronchitis which doctors feared could turn into pneumonia.</p>
<p>Branson, the flamboyant 46-year-old head of the Virgin group of companies, has launched an airline and products ranging from condoms to cola and pensions.</p>
<p>His planned dawn takeoff was delayed by the complexities of inflating the giant balloon, a task taking over 12 hours.</p>
<p>He had to cancel a previous attempt to fly round the globe from Marrakesh last January because of bad weather. He has already crossed the Atlantic and Pacific by balloon.</p>
<p>The record for the furthest flown by a manned balloon is 8,382 km (5,208 miles) from Japan to California, set by American Ben Abruzzo and three co-pilots in 1981.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
