<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="29491" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST - Australian Sports News - Sept 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Australian Sports News - Sept 4.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Caulfield Cup favourite Kenbelle will run in the A$121,460 Chelmsford Stakes (1600m) at Randwick on Saturday against four major spring candidates. Her opponents include Saintly, Filante, Nothin' Leica Dane and Dupain. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Despite being sacked by the Adelaide Crows yesterday, midfielder Andrew Jarman remains hopeful that he will be able to continue his 110-game AFL career, possibly with new team Port Power. Page 22.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Three former presidents, Ron Cook, Sandy Ferguson and Phil Ryan have threatened a Supreme Court injunction if the Hawthorn board continues its plans to consummate a merger with fellow AFL club Melbourne. Hawthorn has until tomorrow afternoon to cancel a merger vote on September 16. Page 22.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Assured of the New South Wales Rugby Union minor premiership last weekend, Warringah captain Mark Catchpole will miss the team's final-round game against Eastern Suburbs on Sunday after playing with a disc protruding on his spinal cord last week. Page 45.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>With no point guard winning the Women's National Basketball League's premier award since its inception in 1982, Michelle Timms will have to create history to take out the Most Valuable Player award. The Sydney Flames point guard is having the finest season of her career, featuring in the top four in points per game, assists, steals, free throws and three-point percentages. Page 45.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Manly chief executive Frank Stanton has accused the New Zealand Rugby League of trying to destabilise the Australian Rugby League series by selecting four ARL-contracted players in the New Zealand team to meet Great Britain next month.  Stanton said Manly centre Craig Innes would like to play for his country but is aware of his contract situation with the ARL. Page 46.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Tasmanian captain and former Australian test cricketer David Boon will captain English county side Durham next season.  After retiring from test cricket last year with 7422 runs, including 21 centuries in 107 Tests, Boon will take over the bottom placed team for two years. Page C14.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following meetings with new coach Malcolm Blight on Sunday and Monday, AFL veterans Andrew Jarman and Wayne Weidmann have been sacked from the Adelaide Crows. Fringe players Brendan Logan and Matthew Powell are also expected to receive their marching ordrs, with Tony McGuinness set to lose the captain's role.  Page C16.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Rather than hurt the AFL club's prospects of continuing beyond the first week of the finals, the Geelong board has decided to fine full-forward Gary Ablett his match payment, about A$10,000, instead of suspending him after the champion broke a club rule by turning up 20 minutes late for an early morning training session. Page C16.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>HERALD SUN</p>
<p>Leading the series with 40 points after thirds in the opening two events, Victorian Chris White is favourite to take out today's Australian King of the Mountains Classic between Wangaratta and Mt Buffalo. The 176km event is the last in the Tattersall's Cp series of selection races for the VicHealth Herald Sun Tour. Page 69.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In an end to the dispute with Soccer Australia, the Melbourne Knights have released a new logo which features a knight bursting through a shield, but still retains the club's traditional Croatian colours of blue, red and white.  Knights members adopted the logo by a 95 per cent majority at an extraordinary meeting. Page 70.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Failing to miss a senior match in three seasons, Carlton coach David Parkin is confident that defender Michael Sexton will make the cut for Saturday's AFL game at Subiaco against West Coast, despite rolling his ankle at a training session last night.  Page 72.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>Western Suburbs coach Tommy Raudonikis has replaced rookie halfback Willie Newton with the more experienced Steve Georgallis for Friday night's elimination quarter-final against Cronulla. Despite performing well since breaking into first grade three weeks ago, the club held fears that the 18-year-old might not be able to handle the pressure of the rugby league finals.  Page 68.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The brother and manager of jockey Wayne Harris admitted last night that the champion rider had major surgery last Friday, but refused to disclose details of his condition.  Greg Harris also refused to speculate on the likelihood of his brother returning to a racing career. Page 70.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After announcing prizemoney of A$2,100,000 will be paid to Australian Rugby League clubs in the eight-team playoff series starting this weekend, ARL chairman Ken Arthurson admitted the sporting organisation was under financial pressure but denied its was broke. Page 72.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
