<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="294949" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian property market to pick up - survey.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian property market to pick up - survey.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Activity in Australia's property markets will increase and broaden over the next few years, consultancy Access Economics said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Access' Property Investment Monitor, compiled in December, found the net value of projects listed rose for all sectors of the market, except for hotels, since the last survey was taken in September.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a rise in the net value of projects listed of A$24.1 billion, with the bulk in major residential projects and in culture and recreation,&quot; Access said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It suggests activity in property markets will pick up and broaden over the next few years,&quot; Access said.</p>
<p>Access said there were a large number of projects in planning in residential estates, hotels and offices, despite the currently depressed conditions in these sectors.</p>
<p>&quot;This reflects falling rental vacancy rates in housing, rising occupancy rates in hotels and falling office vacancy rates in Sydney and Perth,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Combined with continued growth in resource investment, this suggests the late 1990s will see strong growth in construction activity,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>The Property Investment Monitor lists details of 1,080 current projects, worth a total of A$72.5 billion, including those under consideration or in planning stages as well as those already under construction.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
