<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295025" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Security tight as Japan PM arrives in Malaysia.</title>
<headline>Security tight as Japan PM arrives in Malaysia.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto, into the second leg of his Southeast Asian tour, stopped here on Wednesday for a heavy schedule of discussions on enhancing bilateral relations.</p>
<p>Security measures were tightened for the Japanese leader's visit, which comes amid a three-week-old hostage crisis at the Japanese ambassador's residence in Lima, Peru.</p>
<p>Hashimoto arrived in the Malaysian capital after a short visit to Brunei on Tuesday night. He will depart on Thursday morning for Jakarta, in a continuation of a week-long tour of five Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) members.</p>
<p>The visit to Malaysia bears special significance as Malaysia currently chairs ASEAN, which is celebrating its 30th anniversary this year. Hashimoto was expected to discuss future relations between Japan and ASEAN during his visit.</p>
<p>After a brief welcoming ceremony at parliament on Wednesday, Hashimoto, who appeared to be wearing a bullet-proof vest under his suit jacket, led a 14-member delegation in bilateral talks with their Malaysian counterparts.</p>
<p>Malaysian police armed with M-16's lined the main highway leading from the international airport to the capital city. Hand-held metal detectors were used at Parliament Square, the site of the welcoming ceremony.</p>
<p>Hashimoto is also scheduled to meet with Malaysian Foreign Minister Abdullah Ahmad Badawi and to have an audience with King Tuanku Ja'afar on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A statement from the Japanese embassy said one aim of the visit was for Hashimoto &quot;to build stronger personal relations&quot; with Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad.</p>
<p>This is Hashimoto's first visit to Malaysia.</p>
<p>Japan is Malaysia's largest trading partner, accounting for 20 percent of its overall global trade. In 1995, Malaysia's trade with Japan stood at 76.5 billion ringgit ($30.35 billion), up from 31.6 billion ringgit in 1990.</p>
<p>The Japanese leader is due to also visit Singapore and Vietnam. He toured two other ASEAN members, Thailand and the Philippines, last year. ($1 = 2.52 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
