<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295098" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Shenzhen shares close lower on correction.</title>
<headline>Shenzhen shares close lower on correction.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shenzhen's A and B share indices closed Wednesday lower on a technical correction after strong rises in the previous session, brokers said.</p>
<p>The B share index dropped 1.88 points or 1.32 percent to end at 140.27 on volume of 18.54 million shares worth HK$96.51 million against Tuesday's HK$136 million.</p>
<p>The A share index slid 3.43 points or 1.03 percent to close at 329.73 on turnover of 3.43 billion yuan compared with 4.59 billion yuan on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Brokers said sentiment remained unstable, with the direction of the market unclear.  </p>
<p>&quot;The A and B stock markets are likely to continue to consolidate around current levels,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>Institutions are unlikely to engage in large-scale trading unless there is major market-moving news, brokers said.</p>
<p>Television maker Konka was the worst B share performer, losing HK$0.37 or 4.36 percent to HK$8.11 on thin volume of 77,481 shares due to speculative selling, brokers said.</p>
<p>Hotelier Dadonghai followed with a slide of HK$0.11 or 3.06 percent to HK$3.49 on trade of 931,900 shares on profit-taking, brokers said.  </p>
<p>Television tube producer SEG edged up HK$0.09 to HK$6.18 on the session's heaviest trade of 3.79 million shares, brokers said.</p>
<p>Building materials producer Fangda, the second biggest B share gainer, put on HK$0.11 or 1.43 percent to HK$7.78 after 482,440 shares changed hands.</p>
<p>On the A share market, Chongqing Real Estate tumbled 0.61 yuan or 4.81 percent to 12.07 yuan due to profit-taking. Beverage packaging materials supplier Zhuhai Zhongfu dipped 0.48 yuan or 3.68 percent to 12.55 yuan.  </p>
<p>Profit-taking sent market leader Shenzhen Development Bank down 0.53 yuan to 16.49 yuan after 12.5 million shares changed hands, brokers said.</p>
<p>Port facilities operator Beihai Xinli closed at its 10 percent limit-up of 8.32 yuan on speculative buying, they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
