<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295038" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Mycom shares fall on state gaming ruling.</title>
<headline>Mycom shares fall on state gaming ruling.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of Mycom Bhd slumped 16 cents to 3.58 after the government of the east Malaysia state of Sabah said Mycom's subsidiary Olympia Industries Bhd cannot resume its gaming operations in the state.</p>
<p>&quot;The gaming operations need the approval of both the federal and the state governments. Even though the finance ministry gave its approval for the licence, I have remained pessimistic over the the state government's approval,&quot; said an analyst at MBf Northern Securities in Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>Shares of Olympia remained suspended pending the company's announcement about an acquisition.  </p>
<p>Mycom shares had risen to a high of 4.00 ringgit earlier in the day after its 54.7 percent-owned subsidiary Olympia said on Tuesday that the Ministry of Finance had given its approval for the licence to be renewed.</p>
<p>&quot;Unlike the state of Kelantan where there is a total ban on gambling, Sabah has other (gaming) operators. So I don't see the reason for why the licence was not renewed,&quot; said a gaming analyst at brokers H.G. Asia in Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>Mycom officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
