<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295162" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: SE Asian Grain-Thais, Malaysia buy Argentine corn.</title>
<headline>SE Asian Grain-Thais, Malaysia buy Argentine corn.</headline>
<byline>Anchalee Koetsawang</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand and Malaysia bought about 100,000 tonnes of corn from Argentina as regional business picked up after the long Christmas holiday period, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Charoen Pokphand, Thailand's biggest agri-business group, bought 50,000 tonnes of Argentine corn for April shipment at US$130 per tonne C&amp;F.  </p>
<p>Nichimen Corp of Japan said on Tuesday it sold 50,000 tonnes of corn to Malaysia, also for April shipment. Singapore-based traders said on Wednesday the price for the corn reached about $135-$136 a tonne C&amp;f.</p>
<p>&quot;The cheapest corn one can find during this time is from Argentina for that shipment period. April shipment cargoes should arrive between May-June,&quot; a Thai trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some countries have apparently begun taking positions to cover their needs,&quot; a grains trader in Singapore said.  </p>
<p>There have been more inquiries for a few cargoes of Argentine corn, also for April shipment, but no new buying was heard, Bangkok-based traders said.</p>
<p>Millers bought corn to build up stocks as imported supplies are not expected to be available until May, trade sources said.</p>
<p>Thai domestic corn prices edged up to 4.20-4.30 baht a kg from 4.10-4.20 baht a kg.</p>
<p>Industry sources forecast that Thailand will need to import about 500,000-700,000 tonnes of corn this year.  </p>
<p>&quot;However, it all depends on the prices of traditional substitutes of corn such as tapioca and broken rice too,&quot; said the trader.</p>
<p>Thai soymeal prices firmed this week on rumours that soybean shipments from the United States could be delayed, traders said. Soymeal prices rose to 9.30-9.40 baht a kg from 9.20-9.30 baht a week ago, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The rumour that U.S. soybean imported by oil crushers might be delayed by a recent accident at one of the U.S. ports triggered fears of a shortage,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>The dealer was referring to an accident last month in New Orleans when a tanker on the Mississippi river lost its steering, collided with the embankment and blocked movement of ships in the area.</p>
<p>But some traders said a shortage was unlikely as the expected delay of the shipment will be offset by the arrival of 34,539 tonnes of U.S. soybean due to arrive this week.</p>
<p>Thai buyers have also started buying soymeal, mostly of Indian-origin, to cover February and March demand. Trade sources said at least three cargoes were bought at a price ranging between $301-$304 a tonne C&amp;F.  </p>
<p>In Malaysia, grain traders said some shortcovering may also be seen if China exports an estimated two million tonnes of corn this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We're now expecting the Chinese corn, which should come out in the next couple of weeks. But whether there'd be any buying depends seriously on the price,&quot; the purchasing manager of a flour mill in Kuala Lumpur said.</p>
<p>Price of bulk corn, ex-factories/godowns in Malaysia's central region, was quoted at 415 ringgit a tonne last week, compared to between 425 and 430 ringgit two weeks ago.  </p>
<p>&quot;A&quot; grade wheat in bags, ex-factories/godowns in the central region, was unchanged at 800 ringgit per tonne.</p>
<p>The price of low-grade wheat, also central-based, was also retained at 450 ringgit a tonne.</p>
<p>Local soymeal was at 820 ringgit a tonne, while the imported material was at 830 ringgit, both in the central region.</p>
<p>Indonesian corn prices, on the other hand, were generally stable on ample stocks and rising domestic supply, traders said.</p>
<p>They said corn was quoted at 370-375 rupiah/kg in Jakarta, unchanged from a week ago, while soybean meal was quoted the same as last week's 795-800 rupiah/kg.  </p>
<p>&quot;Feed mills seem to have sufficient stocks and are sourcing from domestic sources,&quot; one trader said. &quot;The harvest in Lampung (in South Sumatra) is proceeding well, and we expect the output to peak by mid-January.&quot;</p>
<p>Another trader said the corn import business seemed quiet, with feedmills having sufficient stocks and the Lampung harvest set to peak later this month.</p>
<p>&quot;Imports in January are likely to be relatively low because of the harvest,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Traders said players also seemed well covered on soymeal.  </p>
<p>Data from Belawan Port showed that the MV Feng Jin arrived at the North Sumatran port on December 31 with 3,000 tonnes of soybean meal from India.</p>
<p>    SOUTHEAST ASIAN GRAIN/MEAL PRICES:	Jan 8     Dec 18</p>
<p>Thailand - Corn/maize (baht/kg)	     4.20-4.30  4.05-4.16</p>
<p>Thailand - Soymeal, imported (baht/kg)    9.30-9.40   9.00</p>
<p>Malaysia - Corn (ringgit/tonne)		 415	425-430</p>
<p>Malaysia - Grade A wheat (ringgit/tonne)    800	  800</p>
<p>Malaysia - Low grade wheat (ringgit/tonne)  450	  450</p>
<p>Malaysia - Local soymeal (ringgit/tonne)    820	  820</p>
<p>Malaysia - Imported soymeal (ringgit/tonne) 830	  810</p>
<p>Indonesia - Corn (rupiah/kg)		  370-375    375-380</p>
<p>Indonesia - Soymeal (rupiah/kg)	     795-800    795-800</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
