<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295302" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Argentaria buys 2.12 pct of Telefonica.</title>
<headline>Argentaria buys 2.12 pct of Telefonica.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spanish bank Argentaria said it bought another 2.12 percent of Telefonica for 63.4 billion pesetas, bringing its total stake in the telecommunications group to 5.21 percent.  </p>
<p>In the operation, Argentaria bought 20 million shares at 3,170 pesetas a share.</p>
<p>Argentaria spokesman Manuel Bueno told Reuters on Tuesday that the purchase raised the group's stake ahead of Telefonica's upcoming privatisation.</p>
<p>The bank &quot;is betting on the group's future and does not rule out increasing its participation since Argentaria at the moment has a surplus of funds of more than 260 billion pesetas,&quot; Bueno said.  </p>
<p>Monday's purchase put Argentaria into the so-called hard core of Telefonica shareholders alongside Banco Bilbao Vizcaya and savings bank La Caixa, each of which holds a stake of just over five percent.</p>
<p>On Friday, state holding group Sociedad Estatal de Participaciones Patrimoniales S.A. (SEPPa) asked the Spanish Stock Market Commission (CNMV) to officially register the sale of the state's final 21.01 percent stake in Telefonica.</p>
<p>Of this stake, 20.9 percent is in the hands of SEPPa and 0.11 percent in another state holding group, Sociedad Estatal de Patrimonio II S.A.</p>
<p>Within the last year, the price of shares in Telefonica has risen more than 80 percent. On Monday, Telefonica shares cosed at 3,170 pesetas, up 115 pesetas or 3.76 percent.</p>
<p>--Madrid Newsroom +34 1 585 2167</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
