<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295390" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-ROBSON HAPPY TO STAY AT BARCELONA, SAYS OFFICIAL.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ROBSON HAPPY TO STAY AT BARCELONA, SAYS OFFICIAL.</headline>
<dateline>BARCELONA 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former England coach Bobby Robson wants to finish his contract with Barcelona rather than take over from Kevin Keegan at Newcastle United, Barcelona vice-president Joan Gaspart said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Robson, who is a complete gentleman, called me personally on Wednesday and said that they (two Newcastle representatives) had telephoned him and wanted to come and see him,&quot; said Gaspart.</p>
<p>According to Gaspart, Robson was prepared to listen to a possible offer, but would explain that he was very happy at Barcelona.</p>
<p>Gaspart added that Robson, 63,  had said he not only wanted to stay in Spain, but also wished to bring &quot;titles and victories&quot; to Barcelona.</p>
<p>Earlier, in London, a big bookmaking firm dramatically stopped taking bets on the next Newcastle manager after Robson's and midfielder Peter Beardsley odds dropped from 12-1 to 2-1 joint favourites.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically we are of the opinion that there are now certain people out there who know more than we do,&quot; explained William Hill spokesman Graham Sharpe.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears that the Newcastle board may have drawn up a short-list and from the betting patterns we have observed today, our original odds-on favourite, Kenny Dalglish, is not on it.</p>
<p>&quot;The vast majority of the cash we have been taking has been for two contenders, Bobby Robson and Peter Beardsley. We have a potential pay-out of almost 100,000 pounds on either Robson or Beardsley.&quot;</p>
<p>But Barcelona spokesman Jose Miguel Peres told Sky television earlier in the day: &quot;Mr Robson is manager of Barcelona and he will stay at the club for the next two years of his contract. We are not expecting any changes.&quot;</p>
<p>There has also been betting support for Robson's fellow exile in Spain, John Toshack, who is set to leave Deportivo at the end of the season and is reported to have had talks with Newcastle chairman Sir John Hall.</p>
<p>Toshack, who starred alongside Keegan in one of the great Liverpool sides in the 1970s, sought to play down speculation regarding a move to Newcastle, but, perhaps significantly, refused to rule himself out of the job.</p>
<p>&quot;At the weekend I announced I would probably not be renewing my contract at Deportivo,&quot; Toshack said on BBC Radio.</p>
<p>&quot;Then, with Keegan resigning a couple of days later, people may be think that our relationship is such that we speak more often than we do and are putting two and two together.</p>
<p>&quot;I have a contract till June 30, which in normal circumstances I would expect to fulfil. To be honest, I don't know where I'll be working after that.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BARCELONA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
