<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295322" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU declines comment on Coca-Cola report.</title>
<headline>EU declines comment on Coca-Cola report.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission declined to comment on a newspaper report on Wednesday saying the EU would approve Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc's acquisition of the whole of Coca-Cola &amp; Schweppes Beverages Ltd (CCSB), a British bottler and distributor of soft drinks.</p>
<p>&quot;We never comment on merger reviews,&quot; a Commission spokesman said. The decision is expected on January 22, an EU source said.</p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal Europe said that a panel of national government antitrust experts recommended on Tuesday that the deal under which Coca-Cola would buy Cadbury Schweppes's 51-percent stake in CCSB be cleared without conditions.  </p>
<p>CCSB produces a broad line of soft drinks, primarily Cadbury Schweppes and Coca-Cola products. If the deal goes through, Cadbury Schweppes will no longer bottle and distribute its products but will continue to own and promote them.</p>
<p>The EU started a full probe into the deal in September due to fears it would harm fair competition in Britain.</p>
<p>The assessment carried out by the EU's merger task-force, which prepares the decisions for the full Commission, seemed to indicate that this could be the case, the EU source said on condition of anonymity. He said this was based on a narrow definition of the market concerned.  </p>
<p>The MMC, after consulting the European Commission, concluded that the market for carbonated soft drinks should be considered as a whole and only recommended changes to CCSB's selling practices.</p>
<p>The merger task force usually follows the advice of the EU's consultative committee on concentrations, which is pledged to confidentiality.</p>
<p>The Commission has until January 29 to make a final decision. It has the power to vet all mergers and acquisitions involving firms which have a European turnover of more than 250 million European currency units each and can effectively block such deals that affect competition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
