<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295336" id="root" date="1997-01-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Branson balloon expected to land in Algeria.</title>
<headline>Branson balloon expected to land in Algeria.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Richard Branson's Virgin Global Challenger balloon was expected to land in Algeria early on Wednesday after his bid to circle the world had to be abandoned due to technical problems, a spokesman for Branson said.</p>
<p>&quot;They are going to try to land at first light if possible,&quot; project director Mike Kendrick told a hastily arranged news conference at a London hotel.</p>
<p>Earlier, officials had said the British tycoon's balloon would touch down in Algeria at about 0600 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no injuries involved, this is purely technical,&quot; said Kendrick.</p>
<p>&quot;The nature of the problem we are still trying to establish. I honestly can't tell you what it is, except that we know it's a ballast versus helium problem,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Kendrick said the balloon had been as low as 4,000 feet (1,200 metres) earlier on Wednesday and was now at 12,000 feet (3,650 metres). It would pass over mountains and then attempt to land on flat ground.</p>
<p>In an earlier statement, the Virgin Global Challenger control centre in London said the balloon would try to land in an area of Algeria about 50 to 70 miles (80 to 110 km) east of the border with Morocco.</p>
<p>Mission officials said Algerian rescue services had been alerted.</p>
<p>Political violence has rocked Algeria for the past five years. About 60,000 people have been killed since early 1992 when the authorities cancelled a general election in which radical Islamists had taken a commanding lead.</p>
<p>Branson and co-pilots Per Lindstrand and Alex Ritchie began their trip from an air base near the Moroccan city of Marrakesh on Tuesday in what is believed to be the world's biggest balloon.</p>
<p>They headed up into the jetstream they hoped would carry them across North Africa, Saudi Arabia, India, the South China Sea, the Pacific and the United States before landing in Britain after a record 24,000-mile (38,600 km) trip expected to take between 14 and 21 days.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
