<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295418" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-NEWCASTLE UNITED TO FLOAT DESPITE LOSS OF KEEGAN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-NEWCASTLE UNITED TO FLOAT DESPITE LOSS OF KEEGAN.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>English premier league soccer club Newcastle United will press ahead with its planned flotation despite the shock resignation of manager Kevin Keegan, a club spokesman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;This doesn't alter the float timetable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Newcastle last month confirmed plans to join the London Stock Exchange this spring and said further details of the listing would be made available in mid-January.</p>
<p>A further announcement is expected next week on the flotation of the club owned by property magnate Sir John Hall. Analysts say it is likely to be valued at over 150 million pounds ($253.8 million).</p>
<p>Newcastle, still in contention for the English premier league title and the F.A. and UEFA Cups, were rocked on Wednesday by the resignation of former England captain Keegan.</p>
<p>Keegan joined Newcastle five years ago when the club was languishing near the foot of the old Second Division but his drive, coupled with Hall's millions, have helped to restore the team's fortunes.</p>
<p>Share analysts said that the departure of Keegan from the club's management could unsettle potential investors but the damage could be repaired by the swift appointment of a high-profile replacement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
