<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295487" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: NSI SEES BULGARIA 1997 ANNUAL INFLATION AT 150 PCT.</title>
<headline>NSI SEES BULGARIA 1997 ANNUAL INFLATION AT 150 PCT.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's annual inflation this year is expected to slow to 150 percent from 311 percent in 1996, the National Statistics Institute said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the lev-dollar exchange rate averages around 700 levs, taking into account Bulgaria's strong dependence on imports, the 1997 annual inflation is expected to be around 150 percent,&quot; NSI director Zahari Karamfilov told a news conference.</p>
<p>Cumulative inflation for the first three months is expected to be higher at around 60 percent, he said.</p>
<p>The lev lost 33 percent of its value since the beginning of this year, slumping to 650 to the dollar from 70 a year ago. This year's budget draft, which has yet to pass parliamentary approval, assumed lev/dollar exchange rate of 500. The lev traded at around 650 per dollar on Thursday.</p>
<p>Major imports comprise fuel and other raw materials needed for the industry. Bulgaria will also need to import grain this year after excessive grain exports two years ago produced an acute bread shortage.</p>
<p>&quot;If the lev continues its freefall against the dollar, the 1997 annual inflation may reach or even top last year's inflation levels,&quot; Karamfilov said.</p>
<p>The NSI also estimated the 1997 gross domestic product (GDP) at around 3.9 trillion levs, lower than the government's budget assumptions of 4.5 trillion levs.</p>
<p>The NSI saw the economy this year declining between two and four percent. This year's budget assumes zero GDP growth.</p>
<p>Preliminary NSI estimates show 1996 output falling by up to seven percent on 1995.</p>
<p>Karamfilov said this year's estimates were not based on an implementation of a restrictive fixed exchange rate regime, due to be negotiated with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) in several weeks.</p>
<p>The IMF proposed the introduction of a currency board to halt the collapse of the lev.</p>
<p>&quot;We can not make such estimates as we have not yet seen any economic parameters of the future currency board system,&quot; said Karamfilov.</p>
<p>-- Anastas Petrov, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-876032</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
