<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295420" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: SOCCER-CANADA BID FOR WORLD CUP PLACE DESPITE PROBLEMS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-CANADA BID FOR WORLD CUP PLACE DESPITE PROBLEMS.</headline>
<byline>Paul Gains</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>While Canada's junior ice hockey team are the toast of the nation after winning a fifth successive world championship, another national team are preparing in virtual obscurity for a tilt at far greater glory -- the 1998 World Cup soccer finals.</p>
<p>Realistically Canada have no chance of winning the World Cup in France next year -- but that is not the point.</p>
<p>Just getting to the finals would represent a major sporting triumph in a country where, despite the fact that some one million people play soccer, the international squad is made up of largely anonymous characters playing either thousands of kilometres away or in obscure indoor matches.</p>
<p>The country no longer has a national league, thousands of talented youngsters give up the game every year because they have nowhere to play and coach Bob Lenarduzzi rarely gets to see his top players apart from when they appear in internationals.</p>
<p>More Canadians play soccer than ice hockey but at the top level the game is in a crisis which would appear to make World Cup qualification an impossible dream.</p>
<p>But Canada have qualified for the World Cup before, reaching the finals in Mexico in 1986. The fact that Mexico, traditionally the best team in the CONCACAF zone, qualified automatically as hosts played a significant part in Canada's participation.</p>
<p>This time Mexico are among Canada's opponents in the final pool which also contains the United States, Costa Rica, El Salvador and Jamaica. The top three qualify for France, one more team than in 1986 following the expansion of the finals to 32 teams.</p>
<p>It is a huge challenge for Lenarduzzi,  who, along with players Randy Samuel and goalkeeper Paul Dolan, was a member of the team that reached the 1986 World Cup.</p>
<p>Canada failed to score a goal and lost all three games to France, Hungary and the Soviet Union but were far from disgraced.</p>
<p>Today's team are scattered far and wide with seven of Lenarduzzi's usual starting line-up playing in Europe -- at Ipswich and West Bromwich Albion in England, Dunfermline in Scotland, Maritimo in Portugal and Germinal Ekeren in Belgium.</p>
<p>Lenarduzzi speaks with them on the telephone once or twice a month. By the time most of them return home for internationals they may have crossed nine time zones and are usually jet-lagged.</p>
<p>But there is little alternative. Since the collapse of the Canadian Soccer League (CSL) four years ago there is nowhere else for them to play -- apart from an indoor six-a-side league which is hardly the best way to prepare for a World Cup.</p>
<p>But though the situation is bleak, Lenarduzzi is optimistic, heartened by Canada having gone through the opening qualifying round without losing a match.</p>
<p>&quot;The problems are something I accepted when I took the job in 1992, &quot; he said this week.</p>
<p>&quot;If you are worried about that you'd be worried about something that is out of your control.</p>
<p>&quot;On the one hand it is negative because they are so spread out; on the other hand it is positive because presumably they are playing at a good level. The indoor soccer though is a toughie. But the players in that are better off playing indoor soccer than nothing at all.&quot;</p>
<p>Soccer in Canada dates from the 1860s but the sport never took root because of a famous match played in 1874 between Montreal's McGill University and Harvard University.</p>
<p>After much discussion the match was played under rugby, not soccer, rules and it made such a big impact that American and Canadian gridiron developed from it. Ever since then soccer has been a minor sport in North America even though it enjoys periods of popularity.</p>
<p>Lenarduzzi says: &quot;Canada is a very multicultural country. People support the country they came from, more so than they support Canadian soccer. I think they view Canadian soccer as second rate. That's a problem but you have to accept it.&quot;</p>
<p>Tony Taylor, a former youth development officer at Glasgow Celtic and Birmingham and now the coach of the Canadian Under-17 team has serious concerns about Canada's future at international level.</p>
<p>He says Canadian youngsters are as talented as their British and European peers but because there is no league at home they must travel abroad if they want a career in the game.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of the lads who are playing with the national side once played in the CSL. All the players who did so well and got to the World Cup in 1986 had done their stuff in the NASL,&quot; says Taylor.</p>
<p>But he warns: &quot;I think we are at a crossroads where something has to be done.</p>
<p>&quot;The talent is there but where do good young players develop ? Until we get an infrastructure in place to get them to a high level they have got to get out.&quot;</p>
<p>Canada's severe winter means they will not start playing their final qualifiers until March 2 when they visit Mexico and the Canadian Soccer Association have promised the 19-man squad shares of a $1.0 million bonus if they make it to the finals. It could be the best money they ever spend.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
