<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295452" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: RALLYING-MITSUBISHIS' CHIEF RIVAL CRASHES, ABANDONS RACE.</title>
<headline>RALLYING-MITSUBISHIS' CHIEF RIVAL CRASHES, ABANDONS RACE.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jean-Louis Schlesser's Buggy, the only realistic rival to the dominant Mitsubishis in the Dakar rally, crashed early in the sixth stage on Thursday and had to abandon the race.</p>
<p>Schlesser, who was fourth overall just over 15 minutes behind the leader at the start of the 404-km stage from Gao to Menaka in Niger, damaged his Buggy when he rolled it early in the morning.</p>
<p>His co-driver Philippe Monet suffered a fractured wrist.</p>
<p>Japan's Kenjiro Shinozuka, who lay second after the fifth stage, won Thursday's stage in three and a quarter hours and snatched the overall lead from Mitsubishi team mate Bruno Saby of France.</p>
<p>Saby, third in the stage placings, is now also third overall behind another French Mitsubishi driver Jean-Pierre Fontenay, who like Shinozuka has won two stages and is two and a half minutes behind the leader.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi drivers occupy the top four places although fourth-placed Japanese Hiroshi Masuoka is nearly an hour and a half behind his compatriot.</p>
<p>Nissan's Salvador Servia of Spain and Maurizio Traglio of Italy occupy the next places with Germany's Jutta Kleinschmidt, in another Schlesser Buggy, seventh overall after taking fourth place in the stage.</p>
<p>In the motorcycle section, four times winner Stephane Peterhansel of France stayed firmly in front on a Yamaha with his fifth stage win to open a lead of one hour and 15 minutes over Spain's Jordi Arcarons on a KTM.</p>
<p>The competitors later moved on to Tahoua, where Friday's 575-km seventh stage to Arlit starts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SENEG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
