<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295574" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Cold bolsters thin European grains market.</title>
<headline>Cold bolsters thin European grains market.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The winter has helped keep European grains prices steady in most markets, with a combination of transport problems caused by the freeze, and U.S. price rises triggered by winterkill fears.</p>
<p>Prices were were further underpinned by firm sterling which made British feed wheat less competitive.</p>
<p>Barley markets took some support from Saudi Arabia's purchase of 1.2 million tonnes.</p>
<p>French wheat was supported earlier this week by transport problems caused by frozen canals in the east. But prices have since eased slightly on thin export prospects, dealers said.</p>
<p>Today's EU grain tender is the first since December 19 following a two week recess.</p>
<p>But traders bidding in France failed to make any big cuts in their bids for wheat export subsidies, an indication business was slow, dealers said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday French barley prices hit a high of 885 francs for nearby delivery at Dunkirk, as traders scrambled to load cargoes destined to the Saudis under a previous contract.</p>
<p>German grains brokers reported little new trade in early 1997 but said prices were steadier on anticipated west and east European demand.</p>
<p>Transport problems were creating premiums for spot delivery, brokers said.</p>
<p>But they saw only limited upside potential in early 1997 prices because of German premiums over other west European origins and seller reluctance to pay for storage costs. The tone in the UK market is entirely set by the strength of sterling against other European currencies, traders said. That means the market is weak and looking likely to get weaker.</p>
<p>There is some farmer selling, but so far it is limited. &quot;We're struggling to pay 90 stg per tonne ex-farm and they haven't yet come to terms with it,&quot; one trader said. &quot;Last time they sold any it was at 90 stg,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sterling's strength has also put the UK at a disadvantage on export markets and traders bemoaned the disappearance of export customers. They noted that the Saudi business meant that UK barley was already trading at a premium to wheat for locations close to ports.</p>
<p>Spanish dealers said trade had been thin over the Christmas period and ex-farm prices had changed only marginally in the period between December 18 and January 9.</p>
<p>Ex-farm feed wheat prices inched slightly higher, but dealers said Spain now had very few farmers holding wheat of feed quality. Buyers were opting for other more competitive grains for feed, they added.</p>
<p>Milling wheat and barley prices were largely unchanged and durum wheat rose slightly although activity was subdued.</p>
<p>Maize prices were higher although demand was sporadic as suppliers awaited information on U.S. imports.</p>
<p>Traders said U.S. maize prices were expected to be more competitive than Spanish prices and buyers were holding off until they knew the details. The European Commission is expected to announce the details either Thursday or next week.</p>
<p>Dealers said another spate of torrential rains and heavy snow had affected the remaining harvest of maize mainly in the Castilla y Leon and Aragon regions. This was reflected in the higher prices. Existing stocks, however, remained untouched by the bad weather.</p>
<p>Latest benchmark European grains prices (French prices exclude carry, Italian prices based on Milan exchange closes) -</p>
<p>					   Jan 09		   Dec 18</p>
<p>Rouen dlvd wheat Jan	    860-865 Ffr ($162-$163)    855 Ffr</p>
<p>Rouen dlvd barley Jan		 870 Ffr ($164)	   850 Ffr</p>
<p>Bordeaux dlv maize Jan-March	845 Ffr ($159)     855-860 Ffr</p>
<p>German Hamburg Exch bread wheat   280 Dm ($178)	  277.50 Dm</p>
<p>(12.5 pct spot)</p>
<p>German Hamburg Exch feed wheat    275 Dm ($175)	  272.50 Dm</p>
<p>UK fd wheat E. Anglia Jan	94 Stg ($159)    100 Stg (Jan-Mar)</p>
<p>UK barley E.Anglia Jan	   94 Stg ($159)    100 Stg (Jan-Mar)</p>
<p>Spain feed wheat	     23,300 Pta ($176)	    23,000 Pta</p>
<p>Spain milling wheat	  24,000 Pta ($181)	    24,100 Pta</p>
<p>Spain durum wheat	    27,000 Pta ($204)	    26,500 Pta</p>
<p>Spain barley		   21,000 Pta ($159)	    21,000 Pta</p>
<p>Spain maize		    24,000 Pta ($181)	    23,000 Pta</p>
<p>Italy soft wheat Jan 8    309-310,000 ($201)	   305-306,000</p>
<p>Italy durum Jan 8	   360-365,000 ($234-$237)    340-345,000</p>
<p>Italy maize Jan 8	   277-279,000 ($180-$181)    267-269,000</p>
<p>--compiled by Christopher Lyddon in London (+44 171 542 7928) with contributions from Paris, Hamburg, Madrid and Milan</p>
<p>--Ffr/Dlr 5.31, Dm/Dlr 1.57, Dlr/Stg 1.69, Pta/Dlr 132.28, Lire/Dlr 1,539</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
