<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295630" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ETHIOPIA: Ethiopia resumes genocide trial, adjourns again.</title>
<headline>Ethiopia resumes genocide trial, adjourns again.</headline>
<byline>Tsegaye Tadesse</byline>
<dateline>ADDIS ABABA 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The trial of 71 former Ethiopian Marxist officials accused of genocide and crimes against humanity resumed briefly on Thursday after a 45-day break, court officials said.</p>
<p>But the trial was immediately adjourned until next Thursday after witnesses testified against former officials present in court.</p>
<p>Only 46 of the former officials were in court on Thursday. The others, including former leader Mengistu Haile Mariam, who lives in exile in Zimbabwe, are being tried in absentia.</p>
<p>All 46 have pleaded not guilty and face the death penalty if found guilty.</p>
<p>The former officials were members of the Dergue, the miltiary junta led by Mengistu which ruled the Horn of Africa nation from 1974, after ousting Emperor Haile Selassie, until 1991.</p>
<p>The prosecution presented five witnesses who said their relatives were arrested by Marxist authorities on suspicion of being members of opposition groups. They were later executed without trial.</p>
<p>A 44-year-old key prosecution witness told the court he was arrested by the miltiary in 1978 while working as head of the regional trade office at Makale in north Ethiopia on suspicion of being a member of a rebel group fighting to overthrow Mengistu.</p>
<p>Under Ethiopian law, witnesses in the trial cannot be identified.</p>
<p>The witness told how some 1,500 government officials belonging to the Tigrai ethnic group, a rebel stronghold in those days, were arrested in 1978 on grounds they backed the rebellion against Mengistu. They were repeatedly tortured.</p>
<p>&quot;Because of the unbearable repeated torture many of us had to sign a false statement admitting that we were members of the rebel group, the witness said.</p>
<p>Many of those arrested were never seen again and are presumed dead, he added.</p>
<p>The government says it holds 1,700 prisoners for alleged crimes under the Dergue. The only ones charged are those now on trial. The rest have been held for up to five years without charge.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ETHPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADDIS ABABA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ETHIOPIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
