<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295678" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin stable in clinic, political outlook cloudy.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin stable in clinic, political outlook cloudy.</headline>
<byline>Alastair Macdonald</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin was in stable condition a day after going into hospital with pneumonia but his illness, so soon after a long absence for heart surgery, has plunged Russia into a new bout of political anxiety.</p>
<p>The Kremlin has played down the trouble and insists it has nothing to do with last November's quintuple heart bypass operation. Doctors who examined the 65-year-old president on Thursday evening at Moscow's elite Central Clinical Hospital found no deterioration in his condition.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin, Yeltsin's constitutional deputy, felt confident enough to begin a planned week's holiday near Moscow. He spoke by telephone to Yeltsin, who is being treated with antibiotics after catching a heavy cold.</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin, who would take power for up to three months before elections if the president had to step down, spent six months effectively running the country after Yeltsin suffered a bout of heart trouble shortly before his re-election on July 3.</p>
<p>But the prime minister held formal power for just a day when Yeltsin had his operation on November 5. NTV television said arrangements had been made for the Kremlin leader, who returned to work only on December 23, to control Russia's nuclear arsenal from hospital.</p>
<p>General Alexander Lebed, whom Yeltsin sacked as national security adviser two weeks before his heart operation for too overtly pursuing his own ambitions during the president's last illness, immediately called on him to quit.</p>
<p>&quot;The president is badly ill,&quot; he said. &quot;No one is dealing with the economy...Someone has to rule.&quot;</p>
<p>The tough-talking Lebed, voted Man of the Year in a Russian opinion poll last month, would be a strong contender in any snap election. Chernomyrdin would probably be the choice of the Moscow establishment, but Lebed has much wider popular appeal.</p>
<p>It is not clear how long Yeltsin may be in hospital.</p>
<p>The heart surgeon who performed November's operation, Renat Akchurin, and U.S. specialist Michael DeBakey, who advised him, both stressed that the president's convalescence from surgery had gone well and saw no link to the pneumonia.</p>
<p>But some international heart experts said it was possible that Yeltsin -- who looked frail during a meeting on Saturday with German Chancellor Helmut Kohl -- could be seriously ill.</p>
<p>British Heart Foundation professor Brian Pentecost said: &quot;It seems likely that what he's got is a mixture of a chest infection and heart failure. He really looked a very sick man.&quot;</p>
<p>Izvestia columnist Stepan Kiselyov, in an editorial in Friday's edition of the liberal daily headlined &quot;President Sick, Premier On Holiday, Country All On Its Own&quot;, detected a similar pattern to last summer in the way the Kremlin press office's early optimism was later seen to belie a more serious illness.</p>
<p>Some political analysts say Russia has proved it can maintain a measure of stability without Yeltsin in the Kremlin. Chernomyrdin and the president's chief-of-staff Anatoly Chubais have ample powers to run the country.</p>
<p>But their in-fighting with Lebed and others last summer raised fears of instability and criticism that Russia's deep social and economic problems were not being properly addressed.</p>
<p>&quot;It means the country will once more live for at least a month without a fit president,&quot; Kiselyov said.</p>
<p>&quot;It means, ultimately, continuing that period of terrible stagnation, when not one senior official will be able to take a single decision of even minimal responsibility and which the Russian economy desperately needs today...</p>
<p>&quot;The chronic ailment of Russia's rulers is their persistent unfitness to rule.&quot;</p>
<p>On his return to the Kremlin, Yeltsin vowed to deal with problems which had built up in his absence, including tax evasion which has drained state coffers and led to long delays in wage and pension payments. But he has not had time to do so.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
