<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295670" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>poland: PRESS DIGEST - Poland - Jan 9.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Poland - Jan 9.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- The Kwidzyn-based International Paper plant's management and trade unions agreed on an average pay rise for workers of 312 zlotys a month. The lowest income workers will get the highest rise to balance out wage contrasts, the management said.</p>
<p>- Poland's Finace Minister Grzegorz Kolodko met India's Finance Minister P. Chidambaram during his visit to India and discussed the possibility of raising Poland's credit ratings by India's banks. Currently, the banks place Poland in the same group as Romania, Bulgaria and Cyprus.</p>
<p>- The economic climate index of Poland's manufacturing industry in December remained at the same level as in November last year. The result was worse than in the same period of 1995, although the corporate ratings and forecasts improved, the Central Statistical Office (GUS) said.</p>
<p>- The Mielec Special Economic Zone in eastern Poland allowed 19 companies to start operating in the zone. The investors promised to create 2,200 new jobs and invest 600 million zlotys in the zone, the Industrial Development Agency regional branch president Mariusz Bledowski said.</p>
<p>- The Raciborz-based Mieszko SA confectionery maker is considering a listing on the Warsaw bourse to obtain capital needed to increase market share from two to five percent, the management said.</p>
<p>- A banking consortium headed by the Polski Bank Rozwoju (PBR) Polish development bank has provided a $20.4 million vessel construction credit to the Gdynia shipyard. PBR's share in the credit is $3.35 million, the bank said.</p>
<p>- The listed Bank Slaski (BSK) bank has set up a BSK Konsulting subsidiary which will conduct managerial training, and provide advertising and financial consulting services.</p>
<p>NOWA EUROPA</p>
<p>- Construction of the HCRS soft commodity exchange in Gdansk-Barniewice, which was to be co-financed by the World Bank may not take place as the Gdansk municipality has not produced the facility's area development project on time, the HCRS president Jacek Austen said. The World Bank granted an up $17 million construction credit for the exchange.</p>
<p>- The Lublin-based PZZ grain processing firm, controlled by National Investment Fund (NFI) Victoria, has acquired a bankrupt pasta making plant in Gorzow Wielkopolski. PZZ will invest two million zlotys in facility development and environment protection equipment, PZZ said.</p>
<p>- The listed Bank Inicjatyw Gospodarczych (BIG) bank's consolidated annual net profit in 1996 was 110.03 million zlotys.</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>- The U.S.-based Vanstar Corporation has acquired a 7.5 percent stake in the listed ComputerLand computer firm.</p>
<p>- The London-based Salomon Brothers Ltd. will assist the listed Rafako boiler maker's search for an international strategic investor specialised in the energy sector.</p>
<p>ZYCIE</p>
<p>- The EU Integration Committee received Poland's national integration strategy yesterday.</p>
<p>- Poland's food prices inched up by 2.5 percent in December, the Central Statistical Office (GUS) said.</p>
<p>PARKIET</p>
<p>- The listed Mostostal Export construction firm's annual net profit this year will reach 30 million zlotys, the company's forecast said.</p>
<p>- The Rafamet machine tool maker's annual net profit in 1996 will be less than the previously forecast 900,000 zlotys as the tax office has not returned 169,000 zlotys plus accrued interests to the plant, Rafamet said.</p>
<p>- The net assets of the National Investment Fund (NFI)-10 grew by 0.2 zloty per share due to investment portfolio growth in the third quarter of 1996, the Fund said.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
