<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295716" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Milosevic seen defusing crisis with twin-track.</title>
<headline>Milosevic seen defusing crisis with twin-track.</headline>
<byline>Jovan Kovacic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Slobodan Milosevic is expected to make concessions to the opposition and then ban the street marches which have posed the biggest challenge to his 10 years in power, political sources and diplomats said.</p>
<p>&quot;Fifty-two straight days of consistent protests have now jeopardised Milosevic's rule in an increasingly isolated country,&quot; a senior political source told Reuters on Thursday. &quot;He must now bite the bullet and act before January 13.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The crisis will be resolved by January 12. The resolution will be positive,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The source did not elaborate, but indicated that Milosevic would finally acknowledge municipal election victories by the opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition in 15 of Serbia's 18 largest cities including the capital Belgrade.</p>
<p>In a big concession to the protesters, Milosevic conceded on Wednesday that Zajedno had won recent municipal elections in Serbia's second city Nis. But he gave it had only 37 of the 70 seats, four fewer than the 41 Zajedno says it won.</p>
<p>Cancellation of the November 17 election results triggered a wave of street protests, now in their eighth straight week, shaking the foundations of 52 years of leftist rule.</p>
<p>The political source said an announcement from Milosevic was now most likely at the weekend.</p>
<p>This would be &quot;perfect timing&quot; for the opposition to celebrate victory, the source said. &quot;It would be the last rally by the opposition and after that they will banned from the streets.&quot;</p>
<p>The fact that it was a public holiday -- January 13 is New Year's Eve in the Julian calendar followed by Serbian Orthodoxy -- would help Milosevic save face and not appear to be backing down under pressure from the street protests, the source said.</p>
<p>Conceding election victory would placate the West before it moved for possible sanctions against Belgrade and reduce the risk of civil war that authoritarian hardliners pray for, the source said.</p>
<p>The source, and Western diplomats in the capital, voiced fears that the longer the demonstrations went on, the higher the risk of major violence and casualties among protesters or the police.</p>
<p>&quot;That would transform the dimensions of this crisis entirely,&quot; a Western envoy said.</p>
<p>The longer the demonstrations last, the more Milosevic risks losing control over the last pillar of authority -- the feared police and security forces, the political source said, warning that hardliners might try to exploit that weak spot.</p>
<p>The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe has given Belgrade authorities until January 16 to act on the recommendations by its mission which last month investigated Zajedno's claims of election fraud by Milosevic's socialists.</p>
<p>The mission, led by former Spanish Prime Minister Felipe Gonzalez, endorsed all the opposition victories.</p>
<p>The United States has led unanimous Western condemnation of Milosevic's abuse of democracy in Serbia, cutting Belgrade off from desperately-needed foreign capital and raising the spectre that international sanctions would be reimposed.</p>
<p>The Council of Ministers of the European Union is expected to address the Serbian crisis at a meeting on January 20-21.</p>
<p>&quot;Yugoslavia's position in the international community has never been strong (since 1991) and will quickly turn disastrous unless the Serbian authorities address the concerns raised in the Gonzalez report,&quot; a senior Western envoy in Belgrade said.</p>
<p>&quot;That means, acknowledge in full the (verified) verdict of a popular vote,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Fresh sanctions would spell disaster in the country.</p>
<p>The local currency, the dinar, has already started sliding in relation to the German mark in reaction to reports that the government has caved in and started printing money to pay wage arrears of pensioners and workers.</p>
<p>As the usually well-informed Belgrade rumour mill has it, a series of cancellations of deals with the West has prompted some businessmen who were Milosevic's closest allies to contemplate selling their assets and moving abroad.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
