<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295701" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary improves deal with GE due to upturn - finmin.</title>
<headline>Hungary improves deal with GE due to upturn - finmin.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary was able to improve terms for selling a bank to GE General Electric Capital Corp because of the upturn in the country's economy, Finance Minister Peter Medgyessy told a news conference on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We were able to renegotiate the contract...partly due to the fact that uncertainties surrounding Hungary's economy have dissolved,&quot; Medgyessy said, referring to the sale of Budapest Bank (BB) to GE Capital and other investors.</p>
<p>Hungary sold a 27.4 percent stake in BB to GE Capital Services and gave it operational control over the bank in December 1995. The European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD) has a 32.4 percent stake and the Hungarian state 22.8 percent.</p>
<p>Medgyessy, speaking after a cabinet meeting, said Hungary's economic image was poor at the time of the sale and the contract contained unfavourable terms.</p>
<p>He renegotiated the contract in December, scrapping among others a state guarantee to buy back all BB shares if their value sank below 50 percent of the purchase price.</p>
<p>When putting the seal on the new contract on December 23, Hungary repurchased BB's loss-making Polgari Bank unit for 1.1 billion forints under an 8.25 billion forints buy-back guarantee.</p>
<p>BB's original privatisation was orchestrated by then finance minister Lajos Bokros, who resigned in February 1996 on the grounds that the prime minister did not support his social security reshuffle plans.</p>
<p>Medgyessy said the Finance Ministry's briefing on the sale presented to the government in January 1996 was &quot;biased and incomplete&quot;.</p>
<p>Opposition parties have called for a special parliamentary committee to look into the privatisation and the renegotiation of the contract.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
