<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="29571" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Eurodollars end down despite U.S.-Iraq news.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Eurodollars end down despite U.S.-Iraq news.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Eurodollar interest rate futures saw a volatile day on Tuesday, falling first on talk the U.S. Federal Reserve is mulling a bigger-than-expected rate hike and then recovering on news of the U.S. missile attack on Iraq.</p>
<p>The benchmark September contract finally finished sharply down at 94.26 against its previous IMM close at 94.34 and just off the day's low of 94.25.</p>
<p>&quot;The story of the day was the Eurodollars,&quot; said one dealer with a U.S. commission house. &quot;There was the Wall Street Journal report and then the U.S. launch of missiles and that made for quite a volatile day,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal reported in its Tuesday edition that U.S. Federal Reserve policy makers were mulling a bigger-than-expected interest rate increase unless clear signs of slower growth emerge in the next three weeks.</p>
<p>Dealers said the report sent the September Eurodollar contract crashing to the day's low but it rebounded slightly on news of the U.S. launch of missiles in Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;But at the end of the day, the market concluded that a launching of missiles isn't going to stop the Fed so the Eurodollars were sold back down,&quot; another dealer said.  </p>
<p>Elsewhere, Euroyen interest rate futures also finished weaker, partly due to sentiment that a U.S. rate hike would give the Bank Of Japan room to raise rates.</p>
<p>The sell-off was also exacerbated by market views that a further escalation of U.S.-Iraq tension would push the yen down against the dollar and drive U.S. short-term rates higher.</p>
<p>Japanese government bond futures ended at the day's low on news of the U.S. move against Iraq.</p>
<p>The September contract ended weaker at 122.05 against its opening levels at 122.54.  -- Valerie Lee (65 8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
