<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="295838" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru rebels say Fujimori &quot;lies&quot; on ransom demand.</title>
<headline>Peru rebels say Fujimori &quot;lies&quot; on ransom demand.</headline>
<byline>Saul Hudson</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The propaganda battle between Peru's government and Marxist rebels holding 74 hostages intensified on Thursday with the rebels accusing President Alberto Fujimori of lying by saying they want ransom money.</p>
<p>The rebels put a sign to a window at the besieged Japanese ambassador's residence that read: &quot;Do not lie Mr. Fujimori. Money does not interest us. The demand is freedom of our prisoners.&quot;</p>
<p>Fujimori's government had urged Japanese companies with employees being held hostage not to give in to rebel &quot;blackmail.&quot; Although the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) has in the past kidnapped businessmen and politicians to raise money, there was no evidence that was their aim in the 23-day-old siege.</p>
<p>In another sign at the window, the guerrillas said they had explained why they were still holding about two dozen Japanese captives to a reporter and a translator from Japan's TV Asahi.</p>
<p>Police arrested the two men on Tuesday after they sneaked past security officers for a two-hour meeting with the rebels. They have been held for interrogation at anti-terrorist police headquarters in Lima since then.</p>
<p>Journalists called on Thursday for the men, their notes and film of the interview to be freed.</p>
<p>&quot;We are waiting for the government to explain on what legal basis they are being held,&quot; said Sally Bowen, president of Peru's Foreign Press Association.</p>
<p>The MRTA's principal demand since they burst into an exclusive cocktail party and seized the residence Dec. 17, taking more than 500 guests hostage, has been the release of about 400 jailed comrades.</p>
<p>The rebels have freed most hostages, but say no more will be let out until the government's chief negotiator, Education Minister Domingo Palermo, meets them for a second time inside the compound.</p>
<p>Fujimori, who has vowed not to release the jailed rebels, said he was waiting for &quot;favorable conditions&quot; before sending Palermo to the mined and booby-trapped compound in answer to the rebels' &quot;open-door&quot; invitation more than a week ago.</p>
<p>Roman Catholic Bishop Juan Luis Cipriani, whose visits inside the compound helped win the release of hostages, has returned to his hometown of Ayacucho in central Peru.</p>
<p>&quot;An honest approach will move these mountains. Let's hope the problem ends soon and peacefully,&quot; Cipriani, a close friend of Fujimori, said after holding a Mass for the hostages.</p>
<p>Talks between the government and rebels stopped abruptly after a first face-to-face meeting 12 days ago between Palermo and MRTA leader Nestor Cerpa Cartolini inside the diplomatic residence. Fujimori blamed the stalled negotiations on an impromptu news conference by the guerrillas on New Year's Eve that derailed concessions the two sides had hammered out.</p>
<p>The MRTA responded to Palermo's first meeting by freeing 20 captives. A steady trickle of releases dried up on Jan. 1 with the rebels still holding top government and security force officials, Japanese businessmen and diplomats and Fujimori's brother Pedro.</p>
<p>Fujimori on Wednesday reiterated a promise he had made early in the siege to accept a &quot;commission of guarantors&quot; to oversee a peaceful solution to the crisis.</p>
<p>But while he publicly maintained his tough line against the guerrillas, lambasting them as &quot;terrorists&quot; bent on pointless violence, there was evidence of behind-the-scenes negotiations.</p>
<p>Fujimori said Palermo had been in contact with Cartolini by radio during earlier stages of the crisis and a local newspaper said key presidential adviser Vladimiro Montesinos -- believed by many to be the country's top power-broker -- had met with imprisoned MRTA leader Victor Polay.</p>
<p>Fujimori also soothed fears a false move could trigger a violent end to the standoff when he said in a Lima shantytown on Wednesday there would be &quot;no acts of blood&quot; in the siege.</p>
<p>The government was helped in its propaganda battle by the publication on Thursday of photographs in the country's leading weekly news magazine, Caretas, of child guerrillas being trained in the jungle. While denied by the MRTA, police sources have accused the guerrillas of coercing children into their ranks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
