<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="296055" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore shipyards to adapt to meet competition.</title>
<headline>Singapore shipyards to adapt to meet competition.</headline>
<byline>Ang Bee Lin</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore's marine industry is unlikely to grow in 1997 due to competition from Middle Eastern and Chinese shipyards and will diversify, upgrade, and expand in Asia to stay competitive, officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Economic Development Board (EDB) officials told reporters they expected growth to be flat in 1997 for the local marine industry, which includes ship repair, shipbuilding and maintenance.</p>
<p>The sector's 1996 output was projected at S$3.14 billion, a decline of 10.9 percent from 1995 output of S$3.52 billion.</p>
<p>The EDB said the decline resulted from a weak worldwide repair market, strong competition from shipyards in the Middle East and China, keen competition among local yards and the strength of the Singapore dollar.</p>
<p>It said high freight costs have dampened the outlook for ship repairs.</p>
<p>&quot;As freight cost rises, there would be greater demand to put ships in use and there would be a lag of between six and nine months before repairs are required,&quot; EDB deputy director John Tan said.</p>
<p>The EDB said daily tanker freight rates have risen to around US$22,000-$25,000 from $15,000 in 1995.</p>
<p>The EDB said Middle East shipyards were posing a &quot;strong challenge&quot; as they become more experienced while China's yards were 15 to 20 percent cheaper than those in Singapore.</p>
<p>It said shipowners point to higher costs in Singapore for such services as tank cleaning and anchoring as a factor in favour of Middle East yards.</p>
<p>The EDB said there was a need for an &quot;industry re-positioning&quot;.</p>
<p>Tan said Singapore yards were already poised to diversify into non-ship repair work, such as offshore rig-building and conversion jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;In response to the slow repair market in 1996, the yards have reviewed their competitive strategies for the future,&quot; said Andrew Khaw, another senior EDB official.</p>
<p>&quot;The yards are positioning to broaden their business scope to pursue jobs with more engineering content,&quot; he said. &quot;Such jobs include offshore oil rig-building, repairs and upgrading, and shipbuilding and turnkey conversions.&quot;</p>
<p>The EDB said other measures to improve business would include training to make workforces multiskilled and continued expansion in the Asia-Pacific region.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1996, the yards continued to expand into the region, to leverage on cheaper land and labour resources for ship repair jobs,&quot; its statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;This would complement higher value-added activities in Singapore. Regionalisation is a key initiative for our companies to position themselves for the future.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEAST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
