<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="296102" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Hebron economy a success story.</title>
<headline>Hebron economy a success story.</headline>
<byline>Wafa Amr</byline>
<dateline>HEBRON, West Bank 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian businessmen hope the West Bank town of Hebron will be better known one day as an economic powerhouse than a political powderkeg.</p>
<p>A PLO official said Hebron is home to at least 500 millionaires who spearhead a flourishing local economy and are at the forefront of business activity in other Palestinian areas and the Arab world.</p>
<p>&quot;Hebronites are known as very active workers, very intelligent. They help each other and are very attached to Hebron, so they collect money and invest it in Hebron and spread it abroad,&quot; said Khaled Oseily, a prominent Hebron businessman.</p>
<p>&quot;They are an economic power in Jordan, Egypt and in some Gulf states,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>The town, home to some 400 Jewish settlers and more than 100,000 Palestinians, is a flashpoint of Israeli-Arab violence and the focus of intense U.S.-brokered talks on self-rule.</p>
<p>Businessmen in the town say one of the reasons for their success is that their only entertainment in Hebron is work. They make money and spend very little.</p>
<p>According to Palestinian Finance Ministry statistics, there are 7,269 registered Hebronite businessmen who own factories, stores, workshops and companies. There are 3,000 commercial trucks.</p>
<p>Hebron is famous for its stone industry, glass products and shoes. Most enterprises in Hebron are family businesses and many home basements contain small factories and workshops.</p>
<p>Hebron's geographic location, situated between Jerusalem and Gaza Strip and bordering Israel, has helped townspeople spread their investments to all areas.</p>
<p>Hatem al-Halawani, a successful Hebron businessman and director of several key companies in Jordan and in other Arab states, said there were huge projects awaiting implementation in the town once Israel pulled back.</p>
<p>&quot;A stock market would start functioning in Hebron within four weeks and we are planning to build a huge industrial park to attract investors from all over the world,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very optimistic about the Hebron economy. Hebronites are an economic power in the region and they will continue to be.&quot;</p>
<p>Nasser Tahboub, director general of the Finance Ministry, said Hebronites import goods worth 55 million shekels ($17 million dollars) monthly from Israel, and export goods worth 35 million shekels (11 million dollars) monthly to Israel.</p>
<p>The biggest business in Hebron is quarrying and stone cutting. There are at least 300 stone-cutting workshops in Hebron, and many more owned by Hebronites in the rest of the West Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;We export 80 percent of our stone production to the Israeli market. Hebron supplies around 50 percent of Israel's needs of stones,&quot; Oseiley said.</p>
<p>Hebron has more than 250 shoe factories and workshops. But shoes made in the town, still under Israeli military occupation, are exported as &quot;Made in Israel&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Hebronites worked for Israeli shoe factories, and when they acquired the know-how they opened up their own workshops. They started manually, then they bought sophisticated European machinery and expanded to become the single suppliers of shoes in Palestine,&quot; Tahboub said.</p>
<p>Hebronites are also waiting for Israel to implement a long overdue troop redeployment and lift closures clamped on the West Bank and Gaza last February in the wake of suicide bombings in which Moslem militants killed 59 people in the Jewish state.</p>
<p>Hebron mayor Mustafa al-Natshe said the closure has obstructed economic growth and raised unemployment in the city to around 45 percent. Hebron has been one of the largest labour suppliers to the Israeli market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HEBRON, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
