<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="296307" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Snow, ice plague eastern United States.</title>
<headline>Snow, ice plague eastern United States.</headline>
<byline>Michael Conlon</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Winter struck with a vengeance on Thursday as a series of storms spinning over the eastern United States contributed to at least 11 deaths and spread snow and icy rain from the Great Plains to the Atlantic Coast.</p>
<p>White-out conditions closed roads in the Dakotas, blowing snow turned back school buses in northern Minnesota, and in Chicago snow made the morning rush hour a crawl.</p>
<p>Officials said at least 11 people died in weather-related incidents. Four died in Missouri, three in Kentucky and one in Oklahoma. Three people died at Kerrville, Texas when a pickup truck slammed into two Greyhound buses on an icy highway.</p>
<p>Snow in the nation's capital prompted schools to shut down and the federal government allowed employees to stay home.</p>
<p>Ice coated areas from Arkansas and Georgia through the Carolinas and northward, closing many schools. In Charlotte, North Carolina, freezing rain made city roads treacherous and mountain roads were covered with ice and blowing snow.</p>
<p>The coldest air of the season began pouring across the Canadian border and forecasters warned much of the region to expect a bitterly cold weekend. Four separate storm systems parked over the region dumped snow on a wide region.</p>
<p>Forecasters said eastern seaboard cities would see the snow change to rain but warned that the approaching polar air would cause icy conditions in the southeast again by Sunday.</p>
<p>In North Dakota, temperatures sank to zero Fahrenheit (minus 18 Celsius) and below. At Sisseton, South Daktoa, which has been paralysed for days by eight foot (2.5 metre) drifts, workers at a nursing home had to tunnel through drifts as high as the building to get inside.</p>
<p>Authorities blamed weather conditions for a 19-car pileup that occurred on Thursday morning outside of Sioux Falls and South Dakota Gov. Bill Janklow ordered Interstate 29 and most of Interstate 90 closed because of blizzard conditions.</p>
<p>The North Dakota Highway Patrol said it had closed Interstate 94, which crosses the state from east to west.</p>
<p>Air traffic delays were commonplace. Cancellations lit up flight boards at Chicago's O'Hare and Midway airports where heavy snow was falling. Some delays were also reported at Dulles and National airports in the Washington area.</p>
<p>In flood-ravaged California, some rivers were receding on Thursday but others remained high. Thousands of acres of farmland remained under water and hundreds of people were still evacuated from their homes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
