<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="296622" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed's Phillips sees some risk to inflation outlook.</title>
<headline>Fed's Phillips sees some risk to inflation outlook.</headline>
<dateline>GREENSBORO, N.C. 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite good news on U.S. inflation recently, there are some risks to the price picture and the Federal Reserve must remain on guard, Fed Governor Susan Phillips said Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Although I think the latest news on prices is pretty encouraging, there are I think some risks to the inflation outlook,&quot; Phillips said in a speech to the Piedmont-Triad Economic Conference here.</p>
<p>Specifically, she cited tight labor markets as one of the risks.  </p>
<p>Phillips said that rather moderate increases in benefit costs have helped restrain wage costs but she added that trend won't necessarily last, and higher unit-labor costs could eventually be passed along to consumers.</p>
<p>&quot;Tight labor markets will generate continued upward pressure on wages and salaries and it's not clear how much longer the increases in benefit costs will remain subdued,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Phillips also said that rises in food and energy prices could also pose some trouble if they continue.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's really quite reasonable to focus on the core rate of inflation, which shows improvements actually in inflation,&quot; Phillips said. The so-called &quot;core&quot; inflation rate excludes volatile food and energy prices.</p>
<p>However, she added: &quot;I do think we have to recognize that if food price increases and energy price increases persist at a high level, the current benign inflation outlook could be at risk.&quot;</p>
<p>Phillips stressed that the Fed must remain vigilant, as always.  </p>
<p>&quot;The bottom line is we at the central bank really can't yet declare victory on inflation,&quot; she said. &quot;We can't really let down our guard but I am very pleased with some of the recent reports in the inflation area.&quot;</p>
<p>Describing the overall health of the economy, Phillips said it was &quot;quite good&quot; and said that the indications for the quarter show fairly steady growth, which would be consistent with the long-run sustainable trend for the expansion.</p>
<p>The Fed governor pointed out the Fed's measure of capacity utilization, which stood at 83.3 percent in November, has been a bit above the long-run average.  </p>
<p>She said that was not indicative of bottlenecks, though.</p>
<p>Turning to the consumer sector, Phillips said spending may be constrained somewhat for some households carrying high debt burdens, while recent gains in the stock market may help to sustain spending for some households.</p>
<p>Phillips looked for more cautious lending on the part of banks, particularly toward more marginal customers. She said the situation &quot;could dampen consumer spending.&quot;</p>
<p>Her outlook for the housing sector was relatively upbeat.  </p>
<p>&quot;With the trends in income and financial conditions reasonably favorable, I think the odds are pretty good that strong housing activity could be maintained,&quot; Phillips said.</p>
<p>She was cautiously optimistic on the trade deficit. A likely improvement in the economies of the major U.S. trading partners would help exports but imports might also increase  as demand remains healthy, she said.</p>
<p>Noting that the trade deficit was a drag on the economy in 1996, Phillips said, &quot;I think the odds are that it will be better in '97 but it's hard to tell.&quot;  </p>
<p>On the fiscal front, Phillips said talk of a budget deal was encouraging. She expressed optimism that there would not be &quot;backsliding&quot; on deficit reduction undertaken so far.</p>
<p>Speaking broadly about the six-year-old economic expansion, Phillips said there were no signs of the kinds of supply shocks or imbalances that could derail it.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's safe to say that the fundamental laws of economics have not been repealed and that the current expansion will end at some point but I don't think that day is near,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She concluded her speech by highlighting what she saw as the &quot;primary risk&quot; the economy is facing: &quot;Resource utilization rates in labor and product markets are relatively high. We must continue to be watchful for signs that inflation is re-igniting.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GREENSBORO, N.C."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
