<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="296789" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: UK's Major presses for free trade in India.</title>
<headline>UK's Major presses for free trade in India.</headline>
<byline>Paul Mylrea</byline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Prime Minister John Major, on the first stop of a week-long tour to India, Pakistan and Bangladesh, said on Thursday that momentum towards free world trade had to be maintained to avoid economic disaster.</p>
<p>Shrugging of criticism at home that he was abandoning an election campaign with his ruling Conservatives trailing by some 20 points, Major said it was essential to keep up the pressure against protectionism.</p>
<p>&quot;The current opportunity to open world markets may not last,&quot; Major told around 10,000 businessmen at the Confederation of Indian Industries' annual conference.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be a tragedy of vast proportions if confidence were to falter and the momentum be lost. Even worse would be a turn up the blind alley of protectionism, with the disastrous economic consequences that followed a similar move in the 1930s.&quot;</p>
<p>Major, on the last scheduled foreign trip before elections less than four months away, praised a boom in trade with India.</p>
<p>Trade between India and Britan has doubled in the last four years to 3.5 billion pounds ($6.0 billion). Britain has set a target of 5.0 billion pounds a year by 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;I am determined that we should get there and then go further,&quot; Major said.</p>
<p>But he delivered a gentle warning to New Delhi, which he said was committed to tackling trade barriers but still losing foreign investment because of what he called &quot;bureaucratic inertia and the lack of transparency in the award of contracts&quot;.</p>
<p>Earlier on Thursday, Indian Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda repeated a promise that his seven-month-old government would soon take steps to attract more foreign investment and ensure transparency in policymaking.</p>
<p>Senior Conservative party sources say Major surprised them with his decision to go ahead with the India visit despite his poor poll showing.</p>
<p>Major shrugged off such charges telling journalists travelling with him: &quot;The election is important and will come in due course but it doesn't dominate or eliminate all other activities.&quot;</p>
<p>But the sources said that apart from the trade boost and the important political signal of an early visit in the year of India's 50th anniversary of independence from Britain, Major's trip could help boost support for the Conservatives among Indian and Pakistani communities in marginal seats at home.</p>
<p>In his speech Major praised the one-million-strong Indian community in Britain in what was interpreted as a clear bid to improve his image with Indian voters.</p>
<p>Praising the Indian community for its strong family values -- a key Conservative theme -- Major said: &quot;As an integral part of British society, they create an unbreakable bond between our countries.&quot;</p>
<p>The speech came after a hectic day of contract signings, talks with Deve Gowda and meetings with businessmen.</p>
<p>Major brought with him one of the largest trade delegations ever to travel with a prime minister including businessmen such as Robert Ayling, chief executive of British Airways, and Iain Vallance, chairman of British Telecom.</p>
<p>Major toured a Calcutta slum which has received British aid. The cricket-mad Major also took time to pop in at a game between the visiting Lancashire county side and a local team.</p>
<p>Major flies to Bangalore on Friday before continuing to Bangladesh and Pakistan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
