<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="296794" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Britain's Major begins visit to India.</title>
<headline>Britain's Major begins visit to India.</headline>
<byline>Paul Mylrea</byline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Prime Minister John Major, facing an election within four months, arrived in Calcutta on Thursday for a week-long tour of India, Pakistan and Bangladesh aimed at boosting British trade in the region.</p>
<p>Major visited a Calcutta slum and witnessed the signing of three agreements between British and Indian businesses before talks with Indian Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda scheduled for later on Thursday.</p>
<p>During the visit to the slum, Major announced Britain would be providing 41 million pounds sterling ($70 million) over the next seven years to help improve primary education in West Bengal state. Calcutta is the state capital.</p>
<p>&quot;Two and a half million children, including 650,000 who do not now go to school, will benefit directly from the British grant,&quot; Major said.</p>
<p>The money will be used to build new schools, pay for new teachers and buy books and equipment, officials accompanying Major said.</p>
<p>Major, on his last scheduled foreign trip before the general election, was accompanied by more than 50 top British businessmen.</p>
<p>British and Indian companies signed three joint venture agreements in the presence of Major.</p>
<p>In one joint venture, Britain's GPT, jointly owned by General Electric Co Plc (GEC) and Germany's Siemens AG, linked up with India's Mittal group to manufacture pay phone smart cards.</p>
<p>No financial details of the agreements were available.</p>
<p>Major said on arrival from London that the potential for growth in business between Britain and India was vast.</p>
<p>But the prime minister's decision to leave Britain in the midst of a bitter pre-election campaign surprised even senior ministers in his Conservative government.</p>
<p>Major's Conservatives are lagging 20 points behind in the polls, and ruling party members of parliament are growing increasingly nervous about the stubbornness of the opposition Labour Party's lead.</p>
<p>The British prime minister said he agreed to the visit when members of the Confederation of Indian Industry (CII) asked him last June to be the keynote speaker at their annual meeting in Calcutta. He was set to address the group later on Thursday.</p>
<p>Major said the visit &quot;could be no clearer demonstration of the confidence of British business in the potential of the Indian economy&quot;.</p>
<p>Among the businessmen representing a wide range of sectors including insurance, aerospace and merchant banking were British Airways Plc chief executive Robert Ayling and Iain Vallance, chairman of British Telecommunications Plc.</p>
<p>Major stressed the importance of his visit to India during the country's 50th year of independence from British rule. Queen Elizabeth was due to visit the region later in the year.</p>
<p>Major was set to leave Calcutta on Friday for the southern city of Bangalore, the capital of Deve Gowda's home state of Karnataka, before continuing to Bangladesh and Pakistan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
