<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="297144" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: GERMAN ECONOMIC DATA GIVES BONN EMU HEADACHE.</title>
<headline>GERMAN ECONOMIC DATA GIVES BONN EMU HEADACHE.</headline>
<dateline>WIESBADEN, Germany 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>German economic data released on Thursday showed a surge in unemployment during December to a post-war high as well as weaker-than-expected 1996 economic growth that widened the country's budget deficit.</p>
<p>The Federal Labour Office said German unemployment rose 48,000 to a seasonally-adjusted 4.156 million in December, a new post-war record that topped the prior level of 4.1 million in November. The rise was in line with economist expectations.</p>
<p>The unemployment rate, which is based on unadjusted data, rose to 10.8 percent from 10.3 percent in November, the Nuremberg-based office said.</p>
<p>The German economy also grew provisionally at a real 1.4 percent in 1996, marginally slower than economists' predictions for annual growth of at least 1.5 percent, the German statistics office in Wiesbaden said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The office said Germany's 1996 budget deficit, critical for membership in the single currency set to begin in 1999 under Economic and Monetary Union, was 3.9 percent of GDP compared with 3.5 percent of GDP in 1995.</p>
<p>The Maastricht Treaty, the blueprint for the new currency, sets as a requirement for membership that a country's budget deficit may not exceed three percent of GDP.</p>
<p>The jobless data was also critical for Bonn's currency union goals because it has based financial plans on the assumption that unemployment would average under four million in 1997 - the year whose data will be used to select members.</p>
<p>The German economy was expected to remain weak although conditions were favourable in 1997, the statistics office said. It also noted economic growth during 1996 was mainly driven by exports and capital as well as state spending.</p>
<p>But the office said 1996 growth was only moderate given the conditions and that they assumed there was zero growth on a seasonally-adjusted basis in the 1996 fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Economists have said the present cold weather gripping Germany could hamper construction so much that the economy might contract in the first quarter of 1997 -- as it did a year ago -- with little improvement likely before the spring.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WIESBADEN, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
