<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="297297" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: Cyprus plays down Turkish missile warning.</title>
<headline>Cyprus plays down Turkish missile warning.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cyprus on Thursday dismissed a warning by Turkey that it would attack the island if it needed to protect the Turkish Cypriot community in the north.</p>
<p>&quot;These threats from Turkey are nothing new,&quot; said Cypriot government spokesman Yiannakis Cassoulides. &quot;We have heard such threats before.&quot;</p>
<p>Turkey has accused the Cypriot government of trying to change the balance of forces on the divided island with a deal announced last weekend to buy Russian anti-aircraft missiles that could neutralise Turkish air superiority.</p>
<p>The Cypriot government says the S-300 missile system is purely defensive.</p>
<p>Turkey invaded Cyprus in 1974 in response to a Greek Cypriot coup inspired by the military then ruling Athens. Around 30,000 troops are based in north Cyprus, declared a breakaway Turkish Cypriot state in 1983 recognised only by Ankara.</p>
<p>&quot;What was needed in 1974 and what did we do? We will do the same again. If needed, we will strike,&quot; Turkey's Defence Minister Turhan Tayan told the state-run TRT television channel in an interview on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Cassoulides said there was no justification for a Turkish attack. &quot;If there is any danger of war right now it is a danger of a war of nerves,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The United States is to send an envoy to the island at the weekend to try to reduce tensions between Greeks and Turks.</p>
<p>Washington has criticised Cyprus, saying the missile purchase would introduce a destabilising new military element and complicate peace moves. Britain's deputy high commissioner to Cyprus expressed his concern at a meeting with the foreign minister on Thursday, a British spokesman said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
