<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="297303" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Istanbul bourse to seek brokerage rules annulment.</title>
<headline>Istanbul bourse to seek brokerage rules annulment.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Istanbul Stock Exchange (IMKB) chairman said the IMKB will seek the annulment of Capital Markets Board (SPK) rules limiting the volume of a brokerage's share transactions according to their equity basis.</p>
<p>&quot;We will secure the annulment of this decision by going to the administrative court as soon as possible,&quot; IMKB chairman Tuncay Artun said on the NTV television channel.</p>
<p>According to a new regulation signed by SPK chairman Ali Ihsan Karacan, a brokerage should have minimum equity of 50 billion lira in order to receive a licence for share trading.</p>
<p>Brokerages, most of which have capitals of around 10 billion lira, have until June 30, 1997 to fulfill the minimum equity requirement under the rules being retroactively enforced from January 2, 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Both theoretically and practically these (decisions) are devoid of support,&quot; Artun said earlier in a written statement.</p>
<p>He said there was no evidence in Turkey or internationally of a direct link between the quantity of a brokerages equity and its ability to sustain operations.</p>
<p>&quot;Either the SPK or the market, or both, will be burdened by these decisions which in my view are not valid from a legal point of view,&quot; Artun said.</p>
<p>Under the rules, additional equity of 20 billion lira is required for each agency set up by a brokerage and 10 billion lira for each branch or representative office.</p>
<p>A licence to deal in repos and reverse repos on the bond market will require an additional equity of 50 billion lira.</p>
<p>A licence to arrange public share offers will require additional 10 billion lira equity, another 10 billion lira for a portfolio management licence and five billion lira for a licence in investment consultancy.</p>
<p>Artun said he believed the market would give the best answer to the rules, which he said would have an impact contrary to intentions.</p>
<p>Brokerages will have to deposit four fifths of the minimum equity requirement in the form of state securities at the central depositary Takasbank, according to the SPK.</p>
<p>A single brokerage transaction will be limited to 25 percent of its equity and the total volume of share transactions in a day will be limited to four times its equity.</p>
<p>Share transactions of brokerages provided with comfort letters after being set up by banks will be excluded from the above limits.</p>
<p>Artun also criticised the SPK for excluding brokerages connected with banks from the limits imposed on share transactions.</p>
<p>&quot;The exclusion of brokerages connected to banks from this limitation is an unlawful privilage as well as an unfair practice in favour of a system whose liabilities are guaranteed by the state,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>To boost supervision in the market, the SPK had obliged banks last year to set up or buy separate brokerages with a minimum 125 billion lira capital to handle their share deals from the beginning of 1997. All banks complied.</p>
<p>The total share trading limit for merged brokerages will go up to eight times equity.</p>
<p>Istanbul Exchange had 162 brokerage members, including 62 bank-related ones.</p>
<p>-- Istanbul newsroom +90-212-275 0875</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
