<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="297499" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Commission will maintain beef export refund rates.</title>
<headline>Commission will maintain beef export refund rates.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission has lifted a suspension on applications for beef export licences introduced last week, and will not cut refund rates as expected, a Commission official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Licences were suspended some days ago because of the very high-level of applications, but a decision has been taken not to cut the refund rates,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>The Commission is relying on what it calls &quot;a measure of discipline among traders&quot; not to raise applications for licences above acceptable levels before next Tuesday when they close.</p>
<p>&quot;If the level of applications is again too high then they will have to be suspended again,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>Trade sources told Reuters that they were expecting refund rates to be cut at the next beef management committee meeting on January 17.</p>
<p>&quot;This is very good news for beef farmers at a time when beef exports are again coming under pressure because of BSE (Bovine Spongiform Encephalopathy),&quot; one farmers' organisation official said.</p>
<p>The Egyptian government this week announced a six month ban on imports of live beef cattle from Ireland, Portugal, France and Switzerland because of fears that they could be infected with mad cow disease.</p>
<p>The European Commission said that the ban was unjustified and it would ask Egypt to lift it.  REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
