<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="297510" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austrian shares close off, seen edgy on CA sale.</title>
<headline>Austrian shares close off, seen edgy on CA sale.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian shares tumbled on Thursday after a volatile day overshadowed by the looming sale of the state's stake in flagship bank Creditanstalt and traders said the outlook remained uncertain.</p>
<p>The ATX index of 21 blue chips ended 7.06 points or 0.62 points lower at 1,130.22. Among its constituents 16 ATX shares fell and five rose.</p>
<p>Traders said the index was well-supported at 1,130, but could test 1,120 points if it slipped below that level.</p>
<p>Creditanstalt preference shares fell one percent after the bank reported a 20 percent rise in its preliminary 1996 net profit.</p>
<p>&quot;The market slipped after the Creditanstalt results, which weighed heavily on the mood,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>EA-Generali, leading a consortium of bidders for Creditanstalt, whose chances of success are seen as increasingly slim, topped the day's decliners, falling 3.23 percent to 3,000 schillings.</p>
<p>But traders saw potential for a recovery due to a lack of sellers on the market and strong technical support at the current level.</p>
<p>The January ATX future dropped 6.8 points to 1,129.7.</p>
<p>The broad-based Vienna Bourse index shed 2.07 points or 0.48 percent to 425.56. -- Vienna newsroom +431 53112 257</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
