<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="297588" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Creditanstalt shares down despite 96 profit rise.</title>
<headline>Creditanstalt shares down despite 96 profit rise.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Creditanstalt were among the biggest decliners on the Vienna bourse on Thursday, in spite of a rise in 1996 earnings which analysts said were in line with expectations.</p>
<p>At 1215 GMT Creditanstalt ordinary shares were down 10 schillings at 714 on volume of 16,120 lots. Preferred shares of Creditanstalt were down 9.5 schillings at 478.5 on volume of 41,645 lots.</p>
<p>The ATX index of 21 blue chips was down 9.36 points or 0.82 percent at 1,127.92.</p>
<p>The flagship bank reported a net profit rise to 2.6 billion schillings from 2.17 in 1995 while operating profit climbed to 6.2 billion schillings from 6.14 a year ago.</p>
<p>Final bids for the sale of the state's 70 percent stake in the bank are due at 0800 GMT on Friday. Analysts said they did not think the results would have any effect on the sale.</p>
<p>&quot;The results have nothing to do with the sale of Creditanstalt. No one will improve their offer on the figures,&quot; said Roland Neuwirth, analyst at Deutsche Bank in Austria. -- Vienna newsroom, +431 531 12257</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
