<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="297665" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Continental Airlines demands squeeze on BA/American.</title>
<headline>Continental Airlines demands squeeze on BA/American.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Continental Airlines Inc. voiced strong objections Thursday to the British government's proposed conditions for allowing a controversial alliance between British Airways and American Airlines.</p>
<p>The British government proposal is that British Airways and American Airlines, a unit of AMR Corp., should be made to release to other airlines a total of 168 weekly takeoff and landing slots at London's giant Heathrow Airport.</p>
<p>Houston-based Continental said in comments to be submitted to Britain's competition advisory panel, the Office of Fair Trading, that it alone would need 140 extra takeoff and landing slots per week at Heathrow to be able to compete.</p>
<p>Last month the Office of Fair Trading asked other airlines participating in the trans-Atlantic market to submit their comments on the British government's proposals by Jan. 10.</p>
<p>Delta Air Lines also said this week that its general position would be that the planned constraints were not restrictive enough to allow rivals to establish &quot;meaningful competition&quot; at Heathrow.</p>
<p>The Atlanta-based carrier did not give any more details of its position, however.</p>
<p>Continental said in a statement that it would require enough runway slots and facilties at the airport to operate at least six daily round-trip flights between New York and Heathrow -- &quot;as well as the ability to add flights in response to competitive actions by the BA/American combine.&quot;</p>
<p>Chairman Gordon Bethune called the alliance between British Airways and American effectively the world's largest airline merger.</p>
<p>Without tighter curbs, Continental said, it believed the BA/American alliance would strangle competition by controlling more than 60 percent of all seats in the U.S.-Britain route market and more than 70 percent of seats from Heathrow to the United States.</p>
<p>Washington has linked approval of the competition aspects of the deal to getting a so-called &quot;open skies&quot; agreement with Britain that would entail giving all U.S. airlines access to Heathrow -- Europe's most popular and lucrative hub for transatlantic air traffic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
