<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="297687" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Tories' &quot;Demon Eyes&quot; poster wins UK ad award.</title>
<headline>Tories' &quot;Demon Eyes&quot; poster wins UK ad award.</headline>
<byline>Leslie Adler</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The controversial &quot;Demon Eyes&quot; poster advertisement unveiled by Britain's Conservative Party last summer on Thursday was named the top ad campaign for 1996 by a UK trade publication.</p>
<p>Campaign magazine said it named the Tories' poster ad -- which portrayed rival Labour leader Tony Blair with demonic red eyes and a manic grin peering through net curtains -- as Campaign of the Year.</p>
<p>Campaign editor Stefano Hatfield said the magazine's heavily pro-Labour Party staff itself found the decision quite controversial, but put personal prejudices aside in recognition of the ad's effectiveness.</p>
<p>&quot;Unquestionably this campaign worked,&quot; Hatfield told Reuters in a phone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Even the Labour Party privately admitted last year that the Conservatives had blown them out of the water,&quot; Hatfield said.</p>
<p>The ad, designed by long-time Conservative Party advertising gurus Maurice and Charles Saatchi, cost about 125,000 to 150,000 pounds, but generated about five million pounds in free publicity, Hatfield said.</p>
<p>In addition, not only did the media report on the ad itself, but opened the debate sparked by the ad's &quot;New Labour, New Danger&quot; theme of whether Labour can be trusted, he said.</p>
<p>The ad sparked a storm of criticism when it debuted in August, drawing fire from church leaders, newspaper writers and even some Conservative members of Parliament.</p>
<p>A survey published in October by a market research group found that the ad was more well-remembered than the Labour Party's &quot;Same Old Tories, Same Old Lies&quot; ad run in the same period, but that people liked the Labour Party ad better.</p>
<p>Campaign's Hatfield, however, said that the lack of recall for the Labour Party ad highlighted its weakness.</p>
<p>&quot;The great trick for the Saatchis for the Conservatives is people remember the ads,&quot; he said. &quot;You don't remember the Labour Party ads.&quot;</p>
<p>But Hatfield said the new advertising campaign  unveiled by the Conservatives earlier this week is disappointing. &quot;The new one is very disappointing. It's not based on any truths,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- London Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 2815</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
