<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="297722" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Scientists say brains may shrink in pregnancy.</title>
<headline>Scientists say brains may shrink in pregnancy.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Women who complain they lose their minds during pregnancy may be suffering from brain shrinkage and might not regain their full mental powers until six months after giving birth, British scientists said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;These are very early findings, but it may be that the two features are linked,&quot; Anita Holdcroft, an anaesthetist leading the team reporting the findings, wrote in New Scientist magazine.</p>
<p>Many women say their memories are impaired during pregnancy and complain of absent-mindedness, sometimes becoming the butt of male jokes. But Holdcroft, based at London's Royal Postgraduate Medical School, said there might be a tangible reason for the fuzziness.</p>
<p>Her team of radiologists and anaesthetists found that the brains of women they tested actually shrank in late pregnancy and took up to six months to regain their full size.</p>
<p>&quot;This unexpected observation could be linked to the cognitive problems experienced by some pregnant women and new mothers,&quot; said the journal.</p>
<p>Holdcroft said the team built up three sets of magnetic images to give three-dimensional pictures of the brains of healthy women. The first set were taken towards the end of pregnancy, the second six to eight weeks after delivery and the third up to six months later.</p>
<p>The team found that as the women's physiology returned to the non-pregnant state, their brains increased in size. The team said it was possible the women's brains were swelling from a normal size but believed it was &quot;much more likely&quot; the brains had shrunk during pregnancy.</p>
<p>The researchers believe the shift is more likely to result from changes in the volume of individual cells, rather than a change in the actual number of cells, said the journal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
