<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="297866" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: South Korean unions call biggest strike ever.</title>
<headline>South Korean unions call biggest strike ever.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Browne</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's largest union umbrella body, defying warnings by the government, called on Thursday for the biggest strike in the country's history in protest against a new labour law.</p>
<p>The President of the Federation of Korean Trade Unions, which claims 1.2 million members, said a two-ay strike would begin next Tuesday.</p>
<p>Ignoring threats against strikers by government ministers, Park In-sang urged electricity, port and railway workers to go on partial strike and all others to join a full stoppage.</p>
<p>&quot;The federation calls on all its members to join the largest strike ever, led especially by the public sector,&quot; Park told a news conference.</p>
<p>City buses around the nation would be halted along with subway lines in Seoul under the federation's control. Hospitals, banks, hotels, taxis, publishing companies and the tobacco monopoly would be affected, Park said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, a statement by the ministers of interior, justice and labour threatened &quot;stern measures&quot; against strikes that have been declared illegal.</p>
<p>State prosecutors said they they were seeking arrest warrants for seven leaders of the Korean Confederation of Trade Unions, which boasts half a million workers and is spearheading strikes now under way.</p>
<p>The confederation has ordered all-out stoppages from next Wednesday unless the government scraps the new law that allows companies to lay off workers.</p>
<p>Park said no decision had been made on whether to join forces with the confederation and coordinate action.</p>
<p>Strikes have crippled most major carmakers, although shipbuilders targeted earlier appeared to be working normally. Hospitals and broadcasters have been disrupted.</p>
<p>Unions claim around 200,000 workers are idle, but the labour ministry on Thursday put the figure at around 50,000.</p>
<p>The previous biggest industrial action was in 1989 when some 400,000 workers downed tools by official count. However, those strikes dragged on for months.</p>
<p>Confederation leader Kwon Young-kil said on Thursday all-out strikes would start immediately if police acted on arrest warrants being sought by prosecutors against himself and six colleagues sheltering in a tent pitched on the grounds of Seoul's Myongdong Cathedral.</p>
<p>He also called for international pressure on the South Korean government to repeal the law.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the global union grouping, the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU), strongly condemned the legislation that it said worsened existing violations of international labour law in the country.</p>
<p>The United Nations International Labour Organisation (ILO) in Geneva also said it was asking Seoul to respond to a formal complaint lodged by the Brussels-based ICFTU last month.</p>
<p>The ICFTU said an examination of the new law showed it &quot;failed to correct the wrongs of the old laws&quot;.</p>
<p>It listed five areas in which it said the legislation added to current violations of union rights.</p>
<p>These included provision for the replacement of strikers by outside workers &quot;as temporarily employed strike breakers&quot;, for dismissed workers to lose the right to belong to a union, and for a ban on companies paying strikers during a stoppage.</p>
<p>The others were a ban to be implemented by stages up to 2002 on employers paying full-time union officers and a ban on the occupation of workplaces during strikes.</p>
<p>The ICFTU said the ban on union membership for sacked employees &quot;is a particularly serious violation because it acts as an incentive to discriminatory dismissal of union activists&quot;.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the chairman of the ruling New Korea Party, Lee Hong-koo, rejected the union demand for the repeal of the new law, saying the legislation was &quot;the best solution&quot; to reform the labour market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
