<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="298037" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Yuan closes down slightly against US dollar.</title>
<headline>Yuan closes down slightly against US dollar.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chinese yuan closed down slightly at 8.2967 against the U.S. dollar on Thursday from Wednesday's 8.2966 on a technical correction, but pro-yuan sentiment remained strong, traders said.</p>
<p>The yuan opened unchanged at 8.2966 and moved steadily above 8.2970 for most of the session, hitting an intra-day high of 8.2963 and a low of 8.2973.</p>
<p>Trading was slow, with most done at 8.2967, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The sudden rises on Wednesday promoted more bids at lower levels,&quot; one dealer said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The trend indicated growing demand for the local unit ahead of the Spring Festival which gives the yuan more room for rises,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>A second dealer agreed, saying the yuan would remain strong in the near future.</p>
<p>He said that while the yuan's rise would be slow due to fear of central bank intervention, its upwards movement would not change in the short term.</p>
<p>Dealers expect the yuan to move in the range of 8.2960 and 8.2970 on Friday.  </p>
<p>The yuan closed up at 7.1410 from 7.2000 against 100 Japanese yen and down slightly at 1.0734 from 1.0730 against the Hong Kong dollar.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
