<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="29800" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Senate tentatively restores water funding.</title>
<headline>US Senate tentatively restores water funding.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Senate approved by voice vote on Tuesday an amendment to a fiscal year 1997 funding bill for the Department of Housing and Urban Development that rescues $725 million in funds earmarked to help states deal with pollution in local water systems.</p>
<p>The amendment, offered by Sen. Kit Bond, R-Mo., chairman of the Senate Appropriations Committee's subpanel on HUD and other agencies, was adopted pending final Senate passage of a Veterans Adminstration/HUD funding bill.</p>
<p>The Senate could take a formal vote on this and other amendments to the controversial bill as early as September 4.  </p>
<p>President Clinton on August 6 signed a bill to tighten U.S. safe drinking water standards that authorizes $7.6 billion over seven years for a revolving loan fund to deal with deteriorating water systems.</p>
<p>But because the bill was not cleared by Congress and signed into law by August 1, localities could lose $725 million that was to go to states for drinking water projects under a law that expired July 31.</p>
<p>House and Senate backers of the funding said, however, they would get around the problem by tacking the threatened funds onto the fiscal 1997 VA-HUD funding bill.  </p>
<p>&quot;We gave our assurances that this would be one of the first orders of business,&quot; Bond said of the move to restore the $725 million during a presentation on the Senate floor.</p>
<p>&quot;The members of the committee who worked so hard for passage of the safe drinking water measure were very anxious to have these funds available, and the funds will be available,&quot; Bond added.</p>
<p>Sen. Barbara Mikulski, D-Md., top Democrat on Bond's subcommittee, backed the move, saying the funds address a &quot;compelling need in a timely way.&quot;  </p>
<p>The $725 million in funds is not included in a fiscal '97 VA-HUD funding bill approved by the House earlier this summer. Thus, House and Senate negotiators will have to address the issue in a conference session shortly.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
