<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="298025" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Japanese PM arrives for three-day Indonesia visit.</title>
<headline>Japanese PM arrives for three-day Indonesia visit.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto arrived in Jakarta from Kuala Lumpur on Thursday for a three-day visit as part of a five-nation Southeast Asian tour.</p>
<p>He was greeted at Jakarta's Halim Perdanakusuma air base by Foreign Minister Ali Alatas and drove immediately to the state palace for a formal welcome by President Suharto.</p>
<p>The programme on Thursday was primarily ceremonial and included the official greeting, a courtesy call on Suharto, and an official dinner hosted by the Indonesian president in the evening.</p>
<p>Hashimoto, on his first official visit to Indonesia, was also scheduled to lay a wreath at the Kalibata cemetery where Indonesia's national heros are buried, and to plant a tree at a park in east Jakarta.</p>
<p>Hashimoto and Suharto, the region's elder statesman in power since the mid-1960s, will hold substantive talks on Friday, which diplomats said were expected to cover a range of domestic, regional and global issues.</p>
<p>However, Hashimoto had no plans to raise contentious issues such as Indonesia's controversial &quot;national car&quot; policy or human rights in East Timor in talks with Suharto, Japanese Ambassador Taizo Watanabe said in a pre-arrival briefing.</p>
<p>He said Hashimoto believed &quot;maintaining and cementing close cooperation and foreign relations with Indonesia is vitally important&quot;.</p>
<p>He noted Japan was Indonesia's biggest trading partner and biggest aid donor.</p>
<p>Japanese investment in Indonesia nearly doubled to about $7 billion in 1996 from $3.8 billion in 1995 and 53 percent of Japan's vital imports of raw materials moved through the sea lanes of the sprawling Indonesian archipelago.</p>
<p>Indonesia is also Japan's third-largest foreign source of oil and natural gas.</p>
<p>A special task force with high-powered communications equipment is accompanying Hashimoto to keep him in constant touch with Tokyo and Lima over the crisis in Peru, where Marxist rebels are holding hostages in the Japanese ambassador's residence.</p>
<p>Hashimoto will leave for Vietnam on Saturday and then proceed to Singapore. He has already visited Brunei and Malaysia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
