<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="298043" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: &quot;Red chip&quot; CITIC Pacific seen turning blue.</title>
<headline>&quot;Red chip&quot; CITIC Pacific seen turning blue.</headline>
<byline>Alison Leung</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong conglomerate CITIC Pacific Ltd is degenerating from a prime &quot;red chip&quot; highly prized for its China connections into just another &quot;blue chip&quot;, analysts say.</p>
<p>Once the &quot;reddest of red chips&quot; -- whose ultimate parent firm comes under China's State Council and was founded by one of China's vice presidents -- CITIC Pacific's shares have tumbled since management said it would buy a major stake in the company, disappointing fans of China-related stocks despite the company's sound fundamentals,</p>
<p>Analysts say red chips, Hong Kong firms with close China ties, are chased on hopes of generous injections of undervalued assets from Chinese parents. But punters now fear CITIC Pacific is becoming too independent to enjoy such largesse.</p>
<p>&quot;The market knows that its past perception was wrong, and the red chip factor that made the market willing to pay a high premium for the shares has begun to erode,&quot; said Carl Wong, an associate director of HSBC James Capel.  </p>
<p>On December 30, the company said a managment team led by chairman Larry Yung would buy a 15.47 percent stake in CITIC Pacific from its immediate parent, China International Trust and Investment Corp Hong Kong (Holdings) Ltd, or CITIC Hong Kong.</p>
<p>CITIC Hong Kong's interest in CITIC Pacific will be reduced to 26.45 percent from 41.92 after the share transfer.</p>
<p>CITIC Pacific's shares initially rose on the news, reaching a record high of HK$46.40 (US$5.99), but soon tumbled. They were down HK$0.30 at HK$39.40 in early Thursday trade, 15 percent off their peak.</p>
<p>Analysts said the stock was among the market's best performers last year and that would provide a profit-taking cushion for foreign fund managers who had accumulated holdings.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's perception is that its red chip concept would fade out, but I think selling is a bit overdone,&quot; said Herbert Lau, an anlayst at Vickers Ballas Hong Kong Ltd.</p>
<p>CITIC Hong Kong is the local arm of China International Trust and Investment Corp (CITIC Group) founded by Beijing's &quot;Red Capitalist&quot; Rong Yiren, now one of China's vice presidents and father of Larry Yung.</p>
<p>CITIC Group is now chaired by Wang Jun, a son of China's late vice president and Long March veteran Wang Zhen.  </p>
<p>One analyst said some market-watchers suspect an internal rift exists between the Wangs and Yung's family, which could result in CITIC Pacific being ignored by CITIC Group and moving away from the red chip category.</p>
<p>But some analysts said CITIC Pacific is already operating independently and receives no tangible benefits from its Chinese parent.</p>
<p>&quot;The share transfer itself did not change the fundamentals. We believe CITIC Pacific, or CITIC HK, has been working independently from China and that has not changed,&quot; Lau said.</p>
<p>CITIC Pacific still had strong earnings, a good balance sheet, the ability to source deals and strong connections in China through its chairman after the deal, said Mark Simpson, research director of ING Barings.</p>
<p>&quot;In the medium term, we still like the stock and we think that there is strong earnings momentum,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>CITIC Pacific management has stressed that the company is a Hong Kong company managed by Hong Kong people. It is mainly involved in property development and aviation through its 25 percent stake in Cathay Pacific Airways Ltd.  </p>
<p>The recent heavy selling of the stock also reflected the market's negative feeling about the massive share-price discount given to the management team, analysts said. The shares were bought at HK$33 each, against their last close of HK$43.60 before the announcement.</p>
<p>The silence of Yung and CITIC Pacific managing director Henry Fan, who together netted 97 percent of the 330 million shares, on the deal has fuelled uncertainty in the market, analysts added.</p>
<p>But they said the downside on CITIC Pacific shares was limited with net asset value seen at HK$33.6 a share.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
