<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="298140" id="root" date="1997-01-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Risk to oil supplies deterrent to U.S. attack - Iran.</title>
<headline>Risk to oil supplies deterrent to U.S. attack - Iran.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran does not expect the United States to seek a military confrontation with the Islamic republic because such a move would jeopardise oil exports from the region, an Iranian official was quoted on Thursday as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not think America would have, for the time being, any intention to start any confrontation, because it would not be in its interest to jeopardise the oil (shipping) route,&quot; Kuwait's al-Anba newspaper quoted visiting Iranian Deputy Foreign Minister Hossein Sheikholeslam as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;No one has an interest in threatening (regional) security and the security of the oil supplies in the Gulf,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The United States and its Gulf Arab allies have repeatedly said Iran's arms programme poses a threat to the region which sits on around 70 percent of the world's known oil reserves.</p>
<p>Iran's spiritual leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei last month said U.S. media reports alleging an Iranian role in a June bomb attack that killed 19 U.S. airmen in Saudi Arabia and a possible U.S. military retaliation for that indicated that Washington was preparing to launch an attack on Iran.</p>
<p>Iran, the region's non-Arab power, is strategically placed at the entrance to the Gulf, the narrow Strait of Hormuz, through which 15 million barrels of oil pass each day.</p>
<p>Asked if Iran would block the strait in case of a military clash, Sheikholeslam said: &quot;I do not foresee confrontation...if it happens I cannot envisage what we would do. Had we had such plans I do not believe we would disclose them.&quot;</p>
<p>He reiterated his country's stand that it did not pose any threat to the region's security.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
