<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="298531" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: ALPINE SKIING-WOMEN'S WORLD CUP DOWNHILL RESCHEDULED.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-WOMEN'S WORLD CUP DOWNHILL RESCHEDULED.</headline>
<byline>Adriana Pontieri</byline>
<dateline>BAD KLEINKIRCHHEIM, Austria 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A women's Alpine skiing World Cup downhill race had to be called off on Friday due to heavy fog and poor visibility at the Austrian resort.</p>
<p>Organisers were forced to halt the season's third downhill, which started one hour and 45 minutes late because of earlier heavy snowfalls, after only seven racers had come down the 3,010-metre Strohsack piste.</p>
<p>Friday's race was supposed to be the replacement for a downhill which was called off in Crans Montana, Switzerland, in December because of bad weather.</p>
<p>Organisers in Bad Kleinkirchheim decided to postpone Friday's race until Saturday, when another downhill is already scheduled.</p>
<p>They now plan to hold two downhills on Saturday, starting at 1100 and 1315 local time (1000 and 1215 GMT) respectively, marking the first time women will race two downhills on the same day.</p>
<p>Women's races in different disciplines have been held on the same day on numerous occasions, including this winter in Vail when a downhill and super-giant slalom took place on December 7.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't care if we have to race two downhills tomorrow. If we can do two training runs on the same day then why not also two races?&quot; said overall World Cup title-holder Katja Seizinger of Germany.</p>
<p>Christian Knauth, spokesman of the International Ski Federation (FIS), said: &quot;The piste was in good condition, the only problem today was the fog.&quot;</p>
<p>A downhill training run had to be called off on Wednesday because warm temperatures had softened the piste, which had to be mended with a chemical which hardens snow.</p>
<p>Friday's postponement was the fourth so far this season on the women's circuit. Two giant slaloms in Val D'Isere and Morzine were called off, as well as the downhill in Crans Montana.</p>
<p>France's Florence Masnada was leading with a time of one minute 44.78 seconds before Friday's interruption. Germany's Hilde Gerg was lying second in 1:45.29 and France's Regine Cavagnoud was in third place with 1:46.23.</p>
<p>The Austrian resort is also due to host a super-G on Sunday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAD KLEINKIRCHHEIM, Austria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
