<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="29853" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. reports sharp increase in Colombian heroin.</title>
<headline>U.S. reports sharp increase in Colombian heroin.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian heroin has become a major threat with 62 percent of all heroin seized in the United States last year originating in South America, the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Independent Colombian traffickers have moved into heroin and this is no accident. It's a shrewd marketing decision made to capitalise on the increased profits that can be derived from heroin trafficking,&quot; DEA chief Thomas Constantine said.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now they are positioning themselves to be central players in the Western Hemisphere heroin market by the year 2000. They control cocaine and they are looking to control heroin,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>In 1989, nearly all of the heroin seized in the United States came from Southeast or Southwest Asia, the agency said. But by 1993, heroin from South America, mainly Colombia, accounted for 15 percent of all domestic seizures, which increased to 32 percent in 1994 and kept surging in 1995.</p>
<p>The DEA said the availability of high-purity South American heroin had led to more overdoses and deaths in the northeast United States. It also said heroin consumption nationwide had been rising.</p>
<p>&quot;Heroin has become more affordable and more glamorous. We are seeing more people snorting heroin or using heroin coupled with crack or other forms of cocaine,&quot; Constantine said. &quot;Today we are seeing 11th and 12th graders turning to heroin.&quot;</p>
<p>DEA investigators have found a sharp rise in the number of Colombian couriers who have been arrested between 1991 and 1995 for attempting to smuggle heroin into the United States.</p>
<p>Constantine said the agency planned to spend more than $11 million over the next two years for domestic heroin enforcement and additional amounts internationally to fight heroin trafficking.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
