<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="298514" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Magnum horizontal test a success.</title>
<headline>Magnum horizontal test a success.</headline>
<dateline>IRVING, Texas 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Magnum Petroleum Inc said Friday the re-entry of the No. 1 Brown Morgan well in Fayette County, Texas, was successfully completed.</p>
<p>A lateral drilled from this wellbore averaged about 120 barrels of oil equivalent per day from the Austin Chalk formation over a 31 day producing period beginning December 1. Magnum owns a 25 percent working interest in the property.</p>
<p>This is the first well in a development program expected to involve about 15 wells over the next few years in an area where Magnum and its partner own over 12,000 gross mineral acres, the company said.</p>
<p>It said a second re-entry has been approved by the working interest owners and is scheduled to begin this month.</p>
<p>&quot;The new laterals from existing boreholes are designed to produce undeveloped reserves at less than half the cost of drilling new wells. The success of this recent lateral completion confirms our geological concept and enhances the potential to establish additional reserves and production.&quot;</p>
<p>Magnum also said it has agreed to participate in a new horizontal Austin Chalk well on a recently acquired exploratory prospect in Fayette County, Texas, where a discovery could result in six to eight development locations.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="IRVING, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
