<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="298556" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: CRICKET-BRILLIANT LARA LEADS WEST INDIES TO VICTORY.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-BRILLIANT LARA LEADS WEST INDIES TO VICTORY.</headline>
<byline>Bernard Hickey</byline>
<dateline>PERTH, Australia 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brian Lara hit a stylish century to lead West Indies to victory over Pakistan by five wickets in a run-laden limited overs international at the WACA ground on Friday.</p>
<p>West Indies batted strongly throughout their innings under lights in the day-night match, overhauling what should have been a daunting target of 257 with five wickets and eight balls to spare.</p>
<p>Lara, who exploded back into form with a century against Australia last Sunday, offered few chances as he cruised to his second consecutive century from 113 balls. He finished 103 not out.</p>
<p>The left-hander served up a delicate series of leg glances and gliding strokes through the slips, then laced his innings with several glorious drives off his legs.</p>
<p>Pakistan's spin-dominated attack failed to contain an increasingly confident Lara and his lieutenants, despite assistance from a bouncing and turning WACA pitch.</p>
<p>Only towards the end of his innings did Lara unleash all his shots, bringing up his century with a vicious pull shot through mid-wicket.</p>
<p>West Indies' win puts them on top of the table in the tri-nation World Series tournament and virtually assures them a place in the best-of-three match final series later this month.</p>
<p>Pakistan, with three wins from six games, are lying second while hosts Australia are languishing in last place and must win their game against West Indies at the WACA on Sunday to have any hope of reaching the final.</p>
<p>Opener and wicket-keeper Junior Murray blasted West Indies off to a rollicking start, crashing one six and seven fours in his 62 from 66 balls in the first 19 overs.</p>
<p>Lara, ably assisted by Shivnarine Chanderpaul with 35, then guided West Indies past the target easily. He was later named man of the match.</p>
<p>Earlier Pakistan had delighted the crowd of more than 13,000 with an explosion of runs in their last 15 overs, having struggled to score runs early on against some accurate bowling from West Indies' spinners Carl Hooper and Jimmy Adams.</p>
<p>Top order batsmen Ijaz Ahmed built the cornerstone of the innings, hitting three sixes and six fours in his innings of 94 before being run out in the final stages.</p>
<p>Most of Ijaz's runs were scored from a flurry of boundaries in the final 12 overs.</p>
<p>Pakistan scored just 45 runs in the first 15 overs when the fielding team are restricted to keeping just two in the outfield to stop boundaries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
