<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="298628" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: HUNGARY'S TV BIDDERS WARY OF HIGH FEES.</title>
<headline>HUNGARY'S TV BIDDERS WARY OF HIGH FEES.</headline>
<byline>Denes Albert</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The race for slices of Hungary's potentially lucrative TV market is approaching its final lap but high fees could compromise both profitability and programme quality, bidders said.</p>
<p>&quot;You don't invest in private TV for anything but return,&quot; James T. Cox, development director for US-based Central European Media Enterprises (CME) told Reuters. &quot;There is the concession, transmission and frequency fee and that's before you have invested a dime in the TV station&quot;.</p>
<p>CME is one of several foreign companies still interested in ten-year concessions for two national channels of the television market, which in the first half of 1996 attracted $100.8 million worth of advertising.</p>
<p>Other companies said to be lining up to bid include CLT-Bertelsmann, which owns RTL satellite television, a Hungarian-Swedish consortium MTM-SBS and a consortium of French channel TF1 and the German Westdeutsche Allgemeine Zeitung.</p>
<p>Hungary's media law, passed in December 1995 after four years of bitter political dispute opened the way for the privatisation of the two national channels but since the law was published the goalposts have been moved, the industry said.</p>
<p>&quot;The original idea was that there would be one general (TV) station and a slightly weaker one,&quot; said John Harrington of CLT. &quot;Now the two stations will be very equal and this makes the situation more competitive&quot;.</p>
<p>However, only one of the three state-imposed cost components, the concession fee, is known and the actual tender, to be published within the next days is not expected to define the other two, the transmission and frequency fees.</p>
<p>&quot;We would have liked to (define all three costs), but regulations are not yet in place,&quot; said media watchdog National Radio and Television Commission (ORTT) spokesman Gyorgy Lovas.</p>
<p>The first three annual concession fees, which will be eight billion forints per channel per year, are to be paid in advance to ORTT while the frequency usage fee is payable to the ministry of telecommunications (KHVM) and the broadcasting fee goes to to cash-strapped national broadcaster Antenna Hungaria.</p>
<p>The KHVM has proposed the same broadcasting fees for private and public TV alike.</p>
<p>&quot;This is our proposal but the government will have the final say on that,&quot; Imre Bolcskei, KHVM's deputy state secretary told Reuters.</p>
<p>Antenna Hungaria declined to give even a rough estimate of what the broadcasting fee would be if the government okays the KHVM proposal but foreign bidders still in the race said that excessive fees could result in lower-quality programmes.</p>
<p>&quot;If they make the fees too high, whoever does win this can't spend that much money on programming,&quot; Cox said. &quot;Maybe that's their goal&quot;.</p>
<p>Hungarian media analyst Attila Ledenyi said CME's suggestion that the state is fearful of too high a quality of commercial television may be based on their experience in the Czech Republic, where they opened a competely new private national channel in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;CME's Nova TV reached a 70 percent market share there almost overnight, bringing the state television to the brink of a disaster,&quot; Ledenyi said.</p>
<p>-- Denes Albert, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
