<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="298711" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Brent trims losses as NYMEX gasoline heads up.</title>
<headline>IPE Brent trims losses as NYMEX gasoline heads up.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE Brent trimmed earlier losses in mid-afternoon trade, pulled off lows by a recovery on NYMEX gasoline.</p>
<p>Feb Brent was trading 15 cents down at $24.42 a barrel at 1610 GMT, having dipped to a low of $24.18.</p>
<p>NYMEX gasoline recovered slightly in early trade from sharp falls on Thursday prompted by news that up to a million tonnes of January-loading gasoline will head to the U.S. from Europe this month. &quot;Gasoline is the one to watch and it's making some effort to break higher again,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>As expected, NYMEX crude and heating oil came under pressure at the open in spite of forecasts of colder weather having failed to break key technical resistance on Thursday, dealers said.</p>
<p>IPE Feb gas oil, the new front-month headed lower as temperatures in Europe started to climb back to normal levels after a long cold snap.</p>
<p>Feb gas oil was trading $2.50 a tonne down at $228.25 at 1614 GMT.</p>
<p>Deliveries into the Jan contract, which expired at midday will be 2,617 lots, or 261,700 tonnes, an IPE official said.</p>
<p>The delivery is higher than December's 87,900 tonnes but far off November's record 865,100 tonnes.</p>
<p>--Rosalind Russell, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5387</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
