<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="298753" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CENTRAL AFRICAN REPUBLIC: Mediators launch Bangui round table talks Saturday.</title>
<headline>Mediators launch Bangui round table talks Saturday.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Phythian</byline>
<dateline>BANGUI 1996-01-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>African mediators launch round-table talks in the Central African Republic on Saturday as a first step towards national reconciliation following ethnic bloodshed and three army revolts in a year.</p>
<p>Mali's former military leader, General Amadou Toumani Toure, and his mediating team, say they will at the same time, press ahead with efforts to associate the army mutineers more closely with the dialogue.</p>
<p>But they stress that at the end of the day, it is up to Central Africans themselves to find a lasting solution to the crisis, which has killed hundreds of people and which flared afresh with the latest revolt on November 15.</p>
<p>&quot;We have the feeling that people think that the situation is serious,&quot; Toumani Toure told Reuters on Friday. &quot;The will is there, we must find a way of channelling it.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Saturday's meeting would bring together a cross- section of political, social and religious leaders in the national assembly at 11 a.m. (1000 GMT) to launch the debate.</p>
<p>&quot;Confidence has been seriously undermined. Restoring a minimum of confidence is one of the aims,&quot; he said, but he added: &quot;It's up to the Central Africans themselves.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman for President Ange-Felix Patasse, whose resignation the mutineers and opposition politicians seek, said his representatives would join the talks at a later stage.</p>
<p>French troops, in the country under a defence pact, control key intersections in the capital's volatile southern suburbs, from which they ejected the mutineers after last Saturday's killing of two French officers on a mediation mission.</p>
<p>Life in the city has resumed the trappings of normality, with markets open and taxis and residents circulating in what were no-go areas, but tension is not far from the surface.</p>
<p>The mutineers, who are from the minority Yakoma tribe of former military leader Andre Kolingba, numbered about 750 but scattered after losing men and territory in Sunday's French raids. They want to regroup at pre-agreed assembly points.</p>
<p>&quot;We must regroup to take stock before we go to the negotiations,&quot; their French-trained spokesman Parfait Mbay told Reuters. He said mutineers had fled to the forest and across the broad Oubangui River into Zaire after the French raids.</p>
<p>Kassai camp in the east of the city remains in rebel hands.</p>
<p>The mutinies began in April over pay but turned into a campaign to oust Patasse, a civilian elected in 1993.</p>
<p>French intervention in May kept Patasse in power.</p>
<p>French commanders say their role is to protect symbols of state authority and foreign nationals, help life return to normal and act as a buffer between mutineers and presidential guard loyalists -- who are bitter rivals.</p>
<p>They say Sunday's retaliatory raids killed 10 mutineers but concede the toll could be higher. The mutineers put the death toll at 32, including 11 civilians.</p>
<p>The heads of state of Mali, Burkina Faso, Gabon and Chad launched the mediation effort with a visit to Bangui at the behest of a Franco-African summit in December.</p>
<p>They mandated Toumani Toure, who is widely respected for stepping back and ushering in civilian rule in his native Mali, to broker a lasting deal on their behalf.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGUI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CENTRAL AFRICAN REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
