<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="299022" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chilean shares end weaker but off day's lows.</title>
<headline>Chilean shares end weaker but off day's lows.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chilean stocks trimmed early losses to close a shade softer with the bourse bolstered by Wall Street's surge, said traders.</p>
<p>The market is expected to hold steady next week but much will depend on whether foreign investors continue the wave of bargain-hunting seen earlier this week, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market should hover at these levels but this will depend on the flow of orders from abroad,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The 40-share index, which had lost close to one percent midsession, ended down 0.24 percent at 107.82 points. The general index shed 0.1 percent to 5,135.16 points.  </p>
<p>Turnover dwindled to 12.6 billion pesos from 16 billion pesos Thursday and 22 billion pesos two days ago.</p>
<p>Traders noted that Chilean-issued American Depositary Receipts, which had opened sharply lower, recovered some ground on the rise in New York stocks following stronger-than-expected U.S. employment data.</p>
<p>Winners included Banco O'Higgins, up 2.42 percent at 1,690 pesos, pension fund manager Provida, up 2.22 percent at 9,200 pesos and winery Concha y Toro which firmed 1.5 percent to 203 pesos.  </p>
<p>Losers included paper-maker CMPC, down 2.08 percent at 4,700 pesos, bottler Andina, down 1.35 percent at 2,190 pesos and steel-maker Cap which shed 1.07 percent to 925 pesos.</p>
<p>((-- Margaret Orgill, Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595x212))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
