<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="299280" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. foreign crudes abound, pricing aggressive.</title>
<headline>U.S. foreign crudes abound, pricing aggressive.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Offerings of foreign crudes on the U.S. Gulf Coast abounded on Friday while pricing turned aggressive in response to continued weak demand, traders said.</p>
<p>North Sea and West African crudes are flocking to the Gulf Coast in response to the widening trans-Atlantic arbitrage rather than regional demand, traders said.</p>
<p>The spread between West Texas Intermediate and North Sea Brent for February gained more ground Friday to reach $1.85-90 a barrel, giving sellers further incentive to move cargoes westward.</p>
<p>Gulf Coast refiners, however, continue to show a weak appetite for foreign crudes amid slim margins and turnarounds. Moreover, comparable domestic grades have plunged in recent days in response to the foreign influx, tempting U.S. refiners back to the home front for their supply needs, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Domestics have come down a lot and that has dampened demand for Brent. I don't see much demand, though. Margins are poor,&quot; commented one Gulf Coast refiner.</p>
<p>A few foreign deals were heard done at prices considered aggressive. A Brent cargo for delivery February 18-20 was placed with a Gulf Coast refiner at February WTI minus 73 cents. A second cargo for delivery February 20-22 was placed separately at March WTI minus nine cents, traders said.</p>
<p>Oseberg for February 20-25 is on offer around February WTI minus 40 cents, they said.</p>
<p>West African barrels are also prominent. Cabinda was heard placed at March WTI minus 50 cents for February 20-25, while Forcados is looking for a home at an undisclosed price.</p>
<p>In the U.S. aftermarket, a full boat of February paper Brent changed hands at $24.48 a barrel, 12 cents higher than the London close. Partials traded at $24.45 and $24.47.</p>
<p>Brent Feb/Mar traded at 48 cents, three cents lower than the IPE settlement.</p>
<p>--Patricia Garip-Bertuol NY Energy Desk +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
