<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="299324" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mexico's monetary policy seen on track -- economist.</title>
<headline>Mexico's monetary policy seen on track -- economist.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite chatter that Mexico's monetary policy may spiral out of control, Morgan Stanley &amp; Co economist Ernest &quot;Chip&quot; Brown thinks quite the opposite.</p>
<p>&quot;The data thus far support the conclusion that monetary policy is roughly on track,&quot; Brown said in a report Friday.</p>
<p>Brown said Mexico's monetary policy is stable enough to support his economic forecast of 4.0 percent growth in 1997, 18 percent inflation (versus 15 percent estimated by the Mexican government) and a gradual decline in Mexican interest rates.  </p>
<p>He said the benchmark interbank rate could fall to 19 percent by year-end from about 27 percent at the end of 1996.</p>
<p>Brown asserted that rates have come down &quot;too fast too soon&quot; at the start of the new year and he expects to see the TIIE, a market-weighted average interbank rate, at 26 percent by the end of first-quarter 1997.</p>
<p>He noted the Christmas holiday usually generates a sharp spike in the demand for money balances and a sharp fall off post Christmas and even before New Year's day.  </p>
<p>&quot;On paper, the graph of the monetary base over many years has the appearance of a row of shark's teeth, with the sharp business end of each fang spaced at just before Christmas,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>This trend is due to the fact the Mexican central bank raises the monetary base at the end of the year, complying with market cues that it gets from money traders in Mexico.</p>
<p>&quot;This is rather like tailoring a suit to a moving and growing individual, but a suit where being too big is as lethal as one that's cut restrictively small,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>But this year, &quot;harried central bank traders&quot; raised the monetary base by 35 percent in the month before December 20, marking the monetary base at 88.6 billion pesos, nine percent over their own targeted end-year base level as the central bank money desk coped with end-year liquidity demand, said Brown.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the Morgan Stanley economic scenario is largely in line with Mexican authorities' expectations of total monetary base growth for the year, which is about 24.5 percent, according to Brown.  </p>
<p>That loosly translates into 15 percent inflation, four percent growth and a 3.8 percent rise in the demand for carry-around money if inflation falls, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't have a quibble with these numbers. We think inflation will be higher and the growth in money demand will be less, so their targets are a reasonable fit with our scenario,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Brown said the question in 1997 is whether or not there is a reversion to the shark tooth picture.</p>
<p>&quot;We will need both sides of the spike to keep inflation headed downwards,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>((--N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1660))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
