<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="299308" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX refined products send crude to lower end.</title>
<headline>NYMEX refined products send crude to lower end.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX oil prices ended lower Friday as refined products sagged under increasing gasoline supplies and lower cash prices, sending crude lower.</p>
<p>&quot;Gasoline has a cross to bear in the New York Harbor with a large amount of imports coming this way and distillate prices were off slightly in the (U.S.) Gulf,&quot; said Smith Barney analyst John Saucer.</p>
<p>February gasoline ended off 0.12 cent a gallon at 70.36 cents. February heating oil ended off 0.90 cent at 72.15 cents a gallon while February crude settled 28 cents a barrel lower at $26.09.  </p>
<p>&quot;It was just the general bearishness in heating oil which pushed down crude,&quot; said Nauman Barakat, dealer with Prudential Securities in New York.</p>
<p>Some said the options expiry in the February crude contract may have pulled prompt crude to the $26.00 strike price, but there were more positions held at the $27.00 strike, other dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the open interest in the $27.00 call compared to the $26.00, it is much higher for $27.00, so this time the options expiry may have had little do with it,&quot; said Barakat of crude's lower close.  </p>
<p>Gasoline prices eased on talk by traders that as many as 25 tankers have been fixed over the last week to carry about 8.5 million barrels from Europe to the New York Harbor where supplies were already deemed sufficient.</p>
<p>&quot;Gasoline is going to have a difficult time keeping its head above 70.00 cents (a gallon) next week,&quot; said Smith Barney's Saucer.</p>
<p>February gasoline settled at a 0.20 cent carry to March after those months slipped into contango Thursday.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, heating oil prices followed U.S. Gulf cash prices lower despite forecasts of below normal temperatures next week in the U.S. Northeast, the largest heating oil market in the world.</p>
<p>The brunt of next week's cold weather will be felt in the Midwest, however.</p>
<p>&quot;Temperatures are modifying after they leave the Midwest and go East, so this is more of a natural gas story than a heating oil one,&quot; said Saucer.</p>
<p>February natural gas rose as much as 14.9 cents to $3.63 per million British thermal units on ACCESS before a late session sell-off.</p>
<p>-- Harry Milling, New York Energy Desk, 212-859-1761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
