<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="299390" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: National carlot beef trade weekly review - USDA.</title>
<headline>National carlot beef trade weekly review - USDA.</headline>
<dateline>DES MOINES 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Boxed beef traded lower on good demand and heavy offerings, with most of the volume trading at the lower price levels, USDA said.</p>
<p>Retail demand improved, both for their immediate needs and good forward interest was also noted. Hotel, Restaurant and Institutional demand for immediate and forwarded interest continued rather slow.</p>
<p>Rib and loin cuts were under the most pressure this week, with Choice cuts suffering the heaviest losses. Chuck cuts traded lower at the beginning of the trading period, but regained some of the early losses as the week progressed.  </p>
<p>The round cuts, both Choice and Select experienced the most downward pressure at the end of the trading period.</p>
<p>Closely trimmed items also traded lower, even with the heavy retail demand, these cuts, both Select and Choice continued to trade lower through out the trading period. Beef trimmings also traded lower with fairly good demand both on the fresh and frozen product and offerings were moderate to heavy. Fed cattle and blended coarse ground items were generally steady on fairly good demand.</p>
<p>For the week - Select and Choice rib primal 5.50 to 10.00 lower; Select and Choice chuck primal 2.50 to 3.00 lower; Select and Choice round primal 3.00 lower; Select and Chouce loin primal 2.00 to 4.50 lower; Closely trimmed items 3.00 to 3.50 lower; Beef trimmings 4.00 lower; Fed cattle and blended coarse ground items generally steady. The Estimated Composite of Boxed Beef Cutout values of Choice 1-3 550/700 carcasses Dn 3.68 at 100.37; 700/850 Dn 3.51 at 99.60; Select 1-3 550/700 carcasses Dn 3.24 at 94.94; 700/850 Dn 3.11 at 94.41.</p>
<p>COW AND BULL CARCASS, BONELESS PROCESSING BEEF, CUTTER COW CUTOUT Slaughter cow receipts returned to seasonal levels as auction barns reopened and resumed business after the holidays. Moreover, offerings of boneless beef was mostly moderate. However, demand for lean boneless beef continues to be generally light to moderate, especially from the fast food grinders. This, coupled with lackluster post-holiday demand caused boneless beef to trade sharply lower.</p>
<p>Utility cow carcasses traded steady on moderate demand and offerings. In addition, cow cuts traded uneven, with the light weight tenderloins and 100% lean denuded insides moving at lower levels and 100% lean flats and eyes traded generally steady to weak as supplies continue to be light because of the government buying program. All other cuts seen some firmness.</p>
<p>Utility carcasses steady; Cutter no recent test for comparison; Fresh 90% boneless beef 4.00-10.00 lower in the Midwest, Texas mostly 13.00 lower; 85% 10.00 lower; 75% 3.00 lower; 65% 4.50-7.00 lower.</p>
<p>The Cutter cow carcass gross cut-out value for Thursday, January 9, 1996 was estimated at 65.03 per cwt., down 4.24 from a week ago Friday.</p>
<p>((Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DES MOINES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
