<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="299385" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: More cold temperatures seen for Iowa and Nebraska.</title>
<headline>More cold temperatures seen for Iowa and Nebraska.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Farmers in Iowa and Nebraska should be feeling bone-chilling temperatures through the weekend and Monday, which may further snarl livestock movement, weather forecasters said.</p>
<p>For Monday, highs are forecast at 10 to 15 degrees Fahrenheit in Nebraska and 5 to 10 degrees in Iowa, Weather Express Inc forecaster Brad Nesiba said.</p>
<p>But he noted wind chills are expected to moderate as winds begin to weaken in Nebraska and Iowa early next week.  </p>
<p>Farmers in the Texas Panhandle, Oklahoma and Kansas can also expect another dose of bitter temperatures with a chance of light snow in the next 48 hours.</p>
<p>&quot;The forecast (this weekend) calls for low temperatures in western Kansas of five to 15 degrees below zero, and minus five to plus five in western Oklahoma and the Texas Panhandle,&quot; Weather Services Corp meteorologist Mike Palmerino said.</p>
<p>Further aggravating the situation would be winds of 10 to 20 miles an hour, bringing wind chill temperatures down to 20 to 30 degrees below zero in those areas, he said.  </p>
<p>For late Monday and Tuesday, Weather Express's Nesiba predicted a potential two to four inches of snow for eastern Colorado and western Kansas with light amounts in the Texas and Oklahoma Panhandles.</p>
<p>Palmerino said the light snow should give some protection to the dormant winter wheat crop, likely sparing it from major damage in wheat areas of Kansas, Oklahoma and northwest Texas.</p>
<p>The cold should also prevail in Illinois, Indiana and Ohio although the lows were expected to be five below to five above in Illinois and Indiana and zero to 10 in Ohio.  </p>
<p>&quot;These temperatures will not damage the soft red winter wheat crop which is under several inches of snow,&quot; Palmerino said.</p>
<p>Early signs indicate a potential storm system for the Central Plains and Midwest starting Tuesday and Wednesday moving from west to east, bringing more snow, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Late Monday through early Wednesday of next week there could be a snowstorm, which definitely could be significant,&quot; said Craig Solberg, meteorologist for Freese-Notis Weather.</p>
<p>Solberg said the storm had the potential to produce up to eight inches of snow mainly for Kansas and Nebraska before marching into the Midwest by midweek.</p>
<p>He expected temperatures to remain below or well below normal next week for the Plains and Midwest.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the system) would have quite a bit of wind associated with it,&quot; he added, &quot;So, you might be talking about transportation problems once again during the middle of next week for the hogs.&quot;</p>
<p>((Doris Frankel 312-983-7305))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
