<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="299588" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Chidambaram meets Indian businessmen over budget.</title>
<headline>Chidambaram meets Indian businessmen over budget.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Minister P. Chidambaram met senior Indian businessmen on Friday for a pre-budget discussion, a government statement said.</p>
<p>It quoted the businessmen as seeking a string of measures to boost industrial growth in the 1997/98 (April-March) budget which Chidambaram is expected to present by late February.</p>
<p>The businessmen sought the following measures from Chidambaram:</p>
<p>* Reduction in customs duties and excise duties on capital goods</p>
<p>* Liberal depreciation rules to encourage investment</p>
<p>* Measures to improve performance by key infrastructure sectors</p>
<p>* Combined limits on pension, provident funds and gratuity for purpose of income tax concessions</p>
<p>* Special encouragement to foreign investments in infrastructure</p>
<p>* Fiscal concessions and duty rationalisations in the steel industry to encourage investments in steel-intensive infrastructure projects</p>
<p>* More liberal policy on external commercial borrowings</p>
<p>* Raising funds through American Depository Receipts (ADRs) should be facilitated</p>
<p>* Introduction of international accounting standards like GAP (General Accounting Practice)</p>
<p>* Reduction in interest rates</p>
<p>* Review MAT (Minimum Alternate Tax)</p>
<p>* Extension of MODVAT (modified value-added tax) to all capital goods, and also to small-scale and medium sized industries</p>
<p>* Allowing buy-back of shares by companies which result in their extinguishing</p>
<p>* Reduction of excise duties in general</p>
<p>* To allow telecom operators to amortise licence fees and to reduce customs duties on telephone instruments particularly cellular phones</p>
<p>* Reduction of excise duties on autmobiles and consumer durables</p>
<p>* Liberalisation of advance ruling for tax assessees and expedite litigation laws and enhancing the time limits for re-opening of old assessments</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
