<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="299530" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian bonds/futures closing report.</title>
<headline>Italian bonds/futures closing report.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian debt markets remained in positive territory on the last day of the week despite falls in U.S. and German bond markets.</p>
<p>One trader said buying Btps against Bunds was still a strategic play aiding Italy and he saw Btps performing reasonably well in coming weeks with the spread over Germany holding scope to close in from 162 basis points currently.</p>
<p>The March Btp future on LIFFE was 14 basis points higher at 128.87 with resistance above 129.00 at 129.25, the high of the day. The July 2006 Btp ended six basis points higher at 108.83 and was yielding 7.54 percent.  </p>
<p>Traders said the market was still awaiting, as it has for two months now, a cut in official Italian interest rates from the Bank of Italy. Dealers say however a long-running dispute over wage contracts between metal workers and employers is stopping the central bank from acting.</p>
<p>Little news came from Italy to stimulte the market although Prime Minister Romano Prodi said he would have no hesitation in drawing a supplementary budget for 1997 if additional measures were needed to keep Italy's public deficit under control.</p>
<p>The lira strengthened, reaching 972.00 per mark, its highest level since mid-June 1994.-C.Cooper, Milan +392 666129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
