<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="299535" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: ARA bunkers dive, then rise, Mediterranean stable.</title>
<headline>ARA bunkers dive, then rise, Mediterranean stable.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>ARA bunker prices responded to a rapid fall and partial recovery of fuel oil barges in a thin market, while Mediterranean prices were stable, dealers said.</p>
<p>Rotterdam 380 CST fell as low as $111.50 fob in early afternoon as a flood of selling from one major sent the high sulphur barge market crashing.</p>
<p>The major said problems affecting the flexi-coker of its Rotterdam refinery were solved after morning difficulties and the market recovered. Late 380 CST quotes were $114/$115 fob.</p>
<p>Enquiries in the whole of ARA were not plentiful, although there were a few large deals for the lucky sellers.</p>
<p>Hamburg prices barely responded to the ARA fluctuations, staying at around $126 fob. Buyers were again deterred by the ice surcharges levied by barge operators.</p>
<p>Mediterranean prices were broadly steady and demand low.</p>
<p>A number of enquiries came in for Gibraltar, but few actual trades materialised</p>
<p>The weak Singapore cargo market, the result of healthy stocks and additional Kuwaiti supplies, hit the Fujairah market which dropped $6 to around $106 for 380 CST bunkers.</p>
<p>-- Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
