<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="300033" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: Cyprus may cut interest rates next week.</title>
<headline>Cyprus may cut interest rates next week.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cyprus's central bank may decide to cut official interest rates when its board of directors meets on January 16, a senior bank official said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The matter is still being studied by the bank,&quot; said the official. &quot;Right now the economy is at a relative slowdown and a possible reduction will help the economy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Central Bank is considering a cut of 50 basis points to the borrowing rate, currently at 8.5 percent and the deposit rate, now set at 6.5 percent, commercial bankers said.</p>
<p>Interest rates in Cyprus are considered relatively high compared to European countries while a cut could also spur renewed investor interest in the Cyprus Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>More than 100 million pounds was injected into the market at the beginning of the year when the Central Bank released one seventh of a fund commercial banks were obliged to invest in treasury bills at the beginning of last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Lending also appears weak, weaker than a year ago,&quot; said an economist at a leading local bank. &quot;The economy is going for a slowdown.&quot;</p>
<p>A nine percent ceiling on interest rates has been in force since the 1940s. The government hopes to deregulate rates by the end of the year before accession talks start with the European Union.</p>
<p>-- Michele Kambas, Nicosia newsroom 357 2 365089</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
