<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="300025" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel court tells army to recognise same-sex spouse.</title>
<headline>Israel court tells army to recognise same-sex spouse.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Israeli district court in a landmark decision on Friday ordered the army to recognise a gay man as the spouse of a deceased male colonel and extend him the same benefits as military widows, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;The appeals committee decided it would recognise Adir Steiner as an army widower and grant him the according rights,&quot; court spokesman Moshe Gorali told Reuters.</p>
<p>Survivors of deceased army personnel are entitled to a monthly pension, tax deductions and other benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first time the state is required to recognise a man as the spouse of a man,&quot; Steiner told Reuters. &quot;It is the first time in my life I feel as an equal Israeli citizen.&quot;</p>
<p>Steiner, 30, had appealed against a 1995 court decision declaring him ineligible for survivor benefits after his longtime companion Colonel Doron Maisel died of cancer in 1991.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a historic and revolutionary decision,&quot; Steiner's lawyer Amnon Ben Dror said, adding &quot;It requires the state -- not only a private company -- to pay spousal benefits to a same-sex companion.&quot;</p>
<p>Israel's Supreme Court in 1994 ordered Israel's El Al airline to extend the same benefits to same-sex partners of gay employees as it did to heterosexuals.</p>
<p>Ben Dror said the decision could set a precedent not only for the army but also for the police force and other government bodies. &quot;It could end up costing the state millions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Steiner, a media consultant, said he petitioned for survivor benefits because the army had accepted him as Maisel's partner while he was alive. He said Maisel, a medical officer, was open about his homosexuality and was promoted over the years by officers who knew he was gay.</p>
<p>The decision comes on the heels of a public storm last month over Israeli President Ezer Weizman's derision of homosexuality as &quot;abnormal&quot;.</p>
<p>Weizman, whose presidential role is largely symbolic, later met with Steiner and other gay activists to express sorrow for the remarks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
