<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="300139" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chip barometer falls, but still strong.</title>
<headline>Chip barometer falls, but still strong.</headline>
<byline>Barbara Grady</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-01-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The semiconductor industry's key barometer fell last month but still indicated a solid recovery was under way for embattled chip makers, a trade group said Thursday in its last such report.</p>
<p>The industry's book-to-bill ratio was 1.10 in December, meaning chip makers received $110 in new orders for every $100 in sales shipped that month, the Semiconductor Industry Association said.</p>
<p>That number was lower than November's 1.16 reading, but the association said the drop came because sales rose while orders fell, sharpening the contrast between the two sides of the ratio.</p>
<p>&quot;We remain optimistic about prospects for growth in 1997,&quot; association President Thomas Armstrong said in a statement.</p>
<p>Analysts polled Wednesday said they were looking for a ratio of about 1.15, or the same as November's.</p>
<p>The association Thursday also revised its preliminary November ratio, reported a month ago as 1.15, to 1.16.</p>
<p>Analysts said the December number still shows a strong industry.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a pretty solid number, quite frankly, and indicates improving health for semiconductor companies overall,&quot; analyst Mark Edelstone of Prudential Securities said. &quot;Sales were higher than they were expected to be.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that will be good news for the stock market, since the report comes right before companies report fourth-quarter sales and earnings.</p>
<p>The association said industrywide sales rose 2.7 percent in December from November to $3.52 billion.</p>
<p>But orders fell 2.9 percent between the two months to $3.87 billion for December.</p>
<p>The widely watched report will no longer be available after the December data.</p>
<p>The association, citing the limited worth of a report on the domestic market in a global industry, is replacing the report with one on worldwide sales.</p>
<p>The new report will not have order data. Analysts said the lack of an industrywide order snapshot could add volatility to stock market trading of semiconductor stocks because the information indicates what future sales will be, opening a window on the health of the industry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
