<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="300216" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austrian shares close up, seen on firm uptrend.</title>
<headline>Austrian shares close up, seen on firm uptrend.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian shares powered higher on Friday, boosted primarily by strong demand in oil and chemicals group OMV, and traders said the uptrend was set to continue providing U.S. inflation data due today held no nasty shocks.</p>
<p>The next major goal of the 21 blue chip ATX index was seen at 1,200 points in the medium term, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are moving in areas we haven't seen since mid 1994,&quot; said one trader. Another confirmed the positive trend.</p>
<p>The ATX climbed 11.09 points or 0.98 percent to 1,141.31. Nine ATX shares rose, 10 fell and two remained unchanged.</p>
<p>OMV was the session's top gainer, taking the spotlight from privatisation candidate Creditanstalt.</p>
<p>OMV gained 6.3 percent to 1,249 schillings on turnover of 131,000 lots.</p>
<p>Creditanstalt ordinary shares rose 4.4 schillings to 720.5, while preferred shares of the bank ended 4.7 schillings down at 478.2.</p>
<p>The deadline for final bids for the government's 70 percent stake in the bank ended at 0800 GMT this morning.</p>
<p>Bank Austria and Italian-led insurer EA-Generali both improved their bids but the third bidder retail magnate Karl Wlaschek left his offer unchanged.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Viktor Klima said he intends to make a decision on the winner of the tender ahead of an emergency session of parliament on Tuesday. The government coalition partners are due to hold a special meeting on Saturday afternoon to resolve a bitter rift on the issue.</p>
<p>Papermaker Leykam was the leading decliner, shedding 1.44 percent to 273 schillings.</p>
<p>The January ATX future rose 8.8 points to 1,138.5.</p>
<p>The broad-based Vienna Bourse index added 2.92 points or 0.69 percent to 428.48.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
