<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="300354" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Bank Austria ups stakes in bank CA battle.</title>
<headline>Bank Austria ups stakes in bank CA battle.</headline>
<byline>Knut Engelmann</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA, Austria</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank Austria jumped in minutes before a final bid for privatisation candidate Creditanstalt closed Friday, raising its offer for Austria's flagship bank as political tensions over the sale intensified.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Viktor Klima had given the three existing bidders until 3 a.m. EST to improve their offers for the government's 70 percent voting stake in Austria's establishment bank.</p>
<p>Sources close to Klima said the minister was locked in his office with a gaggle of lawyers and financial advisers from investment bank J.P. Morgan, adding that a detailed evaluation of the three bids could take all weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't say anything. Klima is deliberating with his advisers,&quot; a source inside the finance ministry told Reuters.</p>
<p>A tight-lipped Klima told Austrian state television earlier Friday that he would announce the winner in Europe's longest-running privatisation battle before Tuesday, the day when parliament convenes for a special session on the sale.</p>
<p>Leaders of Austria's governing coalition of dominant Social Democrats and the conservative People's Party, deeply divided over the politically charged sale, will hold an emergency meeting Saturday in a last-minute attempt to hammer out their differences.</p>
<p>Bank Austria, the Social Democrat's candidate of choice, upped the stakes in the fight for control of the country's No. 2 bank when it said it had raised its existing offer of 16.8 billion schillings ($1.52 billion) for its competitor.</p>
<p>A Bank Austria spokesman declined to give details of the increased offer. &quot;We've handed our improved offer to Klima just before 9 a.m. (3 a.m. EST),&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;But I'm not allowed to say anything about its contents.&quot;</p>
<p>Its main rival, a conservative-backed international group led by insurer EA-Generali, Wednesday also raised its original 13.8 billion-schilling ($1.24 billion) offer, but declined to give details.</p>
<p>A maverick offer by former retail mogul Karl Wlaschek was the unknown third. No details of the multibillionaire's bid have been revealed. Austrian TV on Friday said Wlaschek had not made any changes to the original bid submitted last month. Media reports at the time put it at around 15.00 billion schillings ($1.35 billion).</p>
<p>Sources close to the talks have put their money on Bank Austria as the future owner of Creditanstalt, raising the prospect of a major restructuring in Austria's financial sector.</p>
<p>A merger of the two banks would create what for Austria would be a giant bank that would be among Europe's top 30 banks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA, Austria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
