<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="300471" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ANTARCTICA: FEATURE-What's in a name? In Antarctica, almost anything.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-What's in a name? In Antarctica, almost anything.</headline>
<byline>Roger Atwood</byline>
<dateline>PALMER STATION, Antarctica 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>There's a place called The Blob, another known as Blow-Me-Down Bluff and a prominent rock outcrop called Sore Thumb because it sticks out like one in the frozen wilderness.</p>
<p>No other spot in the world has such odd names as Antarctica, where a century of explorers, adventurers and researchers have let their imaginations run riot when it comes to putting a moniker to a mountain or a label to a glacier. Names range from whimsical to weird, from inspired to insipid.</p>
<p>There's Mt. Wyatt, named by an admirer after 1950s Hollywood actress Jane Wyatt, a conical peak known as The Pimple, and a pair of rocky pinnacles known as The Office Girls, named by appreciative U.S. surveyors in honour of the secretarial staff back home.</p>
<p>Other names seem to reflect the explorers' state of mind as they made their way through this vast, ice-bound continent -- Exasperation Inlet, Deception Island, Despair Rocks.</p>
<p>All these names appear in &quot;Geographic Names of the Antarctic,&quot; an 834-page catalogue published by the U.S. government and containing the definitive and internationally recognised list of Antarctic toponyms. The book gives all the rules and regulations for putting titles to as-yet unnamed geographical features, and experts say there are plenty left.</p>
<p>&quot;There was this frenzy to name things a few decades back but it's cooled off now,&quot; said Anthony Amos, a University of Texas meteorologist and Antarctic veteran. &quot;There are lots of places that have no name. Central Antarctica is nearly devoid of them.&quot;</p>
<p>NAMING A PEAK NOT EASY</p>
<p>In theory, anyone can submit an &quot;Antarctic Place Name Proposal,&quot; but applicants must supply detailed reasons for the choice, plus charts, surveys and other supporting documents. The process is not always easy or fast.</p>
<p>Amos and University of Hawaii oceanographer David Karl are still waiting for an answer to their proposal to give the name Santa Claus Island to a remote rock where they have studied the effects of sea ice on plankton populations. Not just whimsical, their proposal is an approximate acronym for Studies in Antarctic Coupled Linkages Among Micro-U Organisms.</p>
<p>They have already succeeded in dubbing another spot Racer Rock, an acronym for Research on Antarctic Coastal Ecosystems and Rates.</p>
<p>Some kinds of names are unacceptable -- no names of pets or of commercial sponsors, and you cannot name a feature after yourself. Someone else has to name it for you. Decisions on whether to accept a name are made by a seven-person committee including members from the U.S. National Science Foundation, the Library of Congress and the Defence Mapping Agency.</p>
<p>Other countries have their own committees, which apply more or less the same criteria. Every country with a presence in Antarctica has put its own distinctive stamp on the continent through the names it has given.</p>
<p>FRENCH LIKE FAMILY NAMES, AMERICANS ORDINARY FOLK</p>
<p>The French have a penchant for naming places after family members, like Marguerite Bay, which explorer Jean Charcot gallantly named for his wife in 1909.</p>
<p>The Americans like to name things after not just the powerful and famous but ordinary folk. Mount Smart is named for the cook on a 1965 expedition, and Mom Peak was named after Shirley Anderson of San Diego, widely known as the &quot;Antarctic Mom&quot; because her radio chats used to cheer up U.S. personnel during the long Antarctic winter, the book says.</p>
<p>For flights of pure fancy, no one beats the British. They named one group of islands after characters in Charles Dickens' novel &quot;Pickwick Papers&quot; and named features in another area after famous opera composers -- Mozart Ice Piedmont, Rossini Point, Verdi Inlet.</p>
<p>The New Zealanders named a spot after their famous rugby team, the All-Blacks Nunataks, while the Latin Americans have a preference for military figures. Sepulveda Point was named for a Chilean navy lieutenant and Lanusse Bay is a tribute to Argentina's first naval aviator on the continent.</p>
<p>Norwegian explorer L.A. Larsen is the champion of Antarctic tributes. He has 12 places named after him including an ice shelf and a glacier. U.S. explorer Nathaniel Palmer, often credited with being the first person to set foot on Antarctica, has six including scientific base Palmer Station.</p>
<p>Not all names stick. One peninsula was confused with another place and mistakenly carried its name for years until the error was discovered and the place rechristened. Its new name? Misnomer Point.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AARCT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALMER STATION, Antarctica"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ANTARCTICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
