<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="300499" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Costello says economy solid, inflation low.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Costello says economy solid, inflation low.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Treasurer Peter Costello said on Friday that the economy was showing solid, low inflation growth but he was concerned that inappropriate wage outcomes could jeopardise the current low inflation envirnoment.  </p>
<p>&quot;The economy is growing at a solid growth rate .... it is a low inflation growth economy,&quot; Costello told a Young Liberal convention in Melbourne. However, he said he was concerned about wages. &quot;The only foreseeable risk at present in relation to inflation is inappropriate wage outcomes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said wages would be significantly affected if the Australian Council of Trade Unions' (ACTU) proposed 'living wage claim' or a similar claim was to be granted.  </p>
<p>Costello told reporters after his speech that the composition of economic growth was changing, with investment strengthening and consumption weakening.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously we will have a look at the December quarter retail figures, but I think that the composition of growth in the economy is changing somewhat,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is stronger in relation to investment and off a little in relation to consumption, and we will have a look at the Christmas (retail) trading results when they come out,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
