<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="300482" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: New Zealand dollar ends firm, powers ahead on TWI.</title>
<headline>New Zealand dollar ends firm, powers ahead on TWI.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand dollar closed higher on Friday and powered ahead to fresh highs on its Trade-Weighted Index.</p>
<p>The currency ended at US$0.7085/92 and 68.34 on the TWI, from 0.7070/77 and 68.17 at the opening. The TWI was at its highest levels since late 1987, influenced by a strong U.S. dollar and a weak Australian unit.</p>
<p>&quot;The TWI's not necessarily seen as a big sell or anything (but) it is making people cautious about the currency going forward,&quot; a Wellington dealer said.  </p>
<p>Given that key December quarter inflation data were due next Friday, &quot;maybe the potential is for the Kiwi/U.S. to be a bit too high, given where the TWI is&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>The New Zealand/Australian dollar cross climbed to A$0.9089/04 from 0.9063/78 at the opening and dealers said the Aussie would continue to struggle under the burden of a weak gold price and rate cut fears.</p>
<p>&quot;The Aussie's shown no ability to bounce at all,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Phillip Lindberg at Bankers Trust said there still appeared to be eurokiwi and samurai-related buying.  </p>
<p>He said the Reserve Bank need not be overconcerned by the high-flying TWI. &quot;The 90-days are falling in line with the appreciating TWI. We're now under 7.5 percent -- when you think that two months ago we were at 10 percent, it's a huge fall.&quot;</p>
<p>Reserve Bank Governor Don Brash said at the time of last month's monetary policy statement that he was comfortable with 90-day rates around 8.5 percent and the TWI at 66.5. A dealer commented that despite the higher currency, the overall mix of monetary conditions was not much firmer than in December.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
