<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="300502" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian national coal strike averted.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian national coal strike averted.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A threatened national coal strike in Australia has been averted following a rescue package allowing for production to resume at the financially-shaken Metropolitan Colliery Ltd on the south coast of New South Wales.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Construction Forestry Mining and Energy Union (CFMEU) told Reuters that threats of a national strike had been dropped after the mine had been put back into production.</p>
<p>Work re-started at the mine this week. It was closed and put in the hands of an administrator in November last year after it was hit by a geologically-caused disruption to production.  </p>
<p>The national coal strike was threatened unless sacked mine workers were paid entitlements of A$4.9 million, which Metropolitan Colliery said it could not afford.</p>
<p>A solution was reached when the mine's 10 percent shareholder, Kanematsu Corp of Japan, assented to a plan brokered by mine administrator Price Waterhouse, the New South Wales state government and the CFMEU.</p>
<p>Kanematsu is a secured creditor for A$20 million.  </p>
<p>The plan involves the mine being operated on behalf of the administrator by contract miner Colrock Australia Pty Ltd, while the state government funded outstanding entitlements of more than A$1 million.</p>
<p>The mine's administrator has projected saleable coal production of about 850,000 tonnes in 1997, expected to be sold at a minimum average of A$45.00 a tonne.</p>
<p>Ian Ferres, chairman of Denehurst Ltd, which owns 90 percent of Metropolitan and is a second-ranking fixed charge holder, told Reuters that the deal and the resumption of mining had put his company in a better position because the mine could  </p>
<p>be sold for more as a going concern.</p>
<p>&quot;The administrator's next task is to attempt to sell the mine to someone else and obviously while it's working you're more likely to get a better price for it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Denehurst, meanwhile, continues with its other activities of copper and base metals mining, he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I11000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
