<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="300538" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore rubber futures close down in slow trade.</title>
<headline>Singapore rubber futures close down in slow trade.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rubber futures finished the week with a whimper on Friday as volume remained thin despite steady short-covering for prompt shipments of RSS3 rubber, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's so slow. What do you do if there are no buyers at all? The short-covering that we saw the last couple of days just ran out,&quot; a rubber trader for a Western rubber dealing firm said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was just very, very quiet. It's a weekend market as people decided to stay away,&quot; a dealer said. Dealers said the market will probably drift lower next week as people mark time ahead of the Chinese Lunar New Year holidays in February.  </p>
<p>&quot;People will also be taking their cue from the Japanese market although that may be quiet as well,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The most active month was the March RSS3 contract with 1,520 tonnes traded. The total traded for RSS3 reached 4,190 tonnes. Volume of trades for RSS1 and TSR20 rubber remained very thin.</p>
<p>At around 0945 GMT, February RSS3 was seen at 122.25 U.S. cents a kg from 122.75 cents. March RSS1 was seen at 174.75-176.75 Singapore cents (US$1.25-$1.26) a kg from the previous 176.75 cents. April TSR20 was seen at 169.50-171.50 Singapore cents (US$1.21-$1.22) a kg from the previous 171.75 cents. -- (US$1=S$1.40) - Rene Pastor (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
