<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="300779" id="root" date="1997-01-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: New BoF members not anti-European - Trichet.</title>
<headline>New BoF members not anti-European - Trichet.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of France head Jean-Claude Trichet praised the two new members of the central bank's monetary policy council as distinguished personalities and said neither was against European monetary union.</p>
<p>In an interview with French TF1 television late on Thursday, he also said that future euro single currency must be as solid as the franc.</p>
<p>The nomination earlier this month of Pierre Guillen and Jean-Rene Bernard to the nine-member council prompted some speculation about a softening in the Bank of France's defence of the franc-mark exchange rate, seen as the cornerstone of the future European single currency.</p>
<p>Newspapers suggested Guillen in particular might be opposed to the drive to monetary union, an accusation he himself has denied.</p>
<p>Trichet said the legal procedure for naming the two members had been &quot;scrupulously respected&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;These two people are distinguished people who have each had top responsabilities in their field and...contrary to what has sometimes been said, they are not anti-European and they did not vote 'no' to Maastricht (in a 1992 French referendum on the Maastricht treaty,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He declined to say what the Bank's own recommendation had been for the posts, though French newspapers have said he had sought the reappointment of ex-journalist Jean Boissonnat, a staunch supporter of Trichet.</p>
<p>Asked whether the Bank of France still had room to cut official short-term interest rates, he said that it had already reduced these significantly in the last year-and-a-half.</p>
<p>&quot;This was rigourously in line with an increase in confidence in our own currency and I would say also to a large extent, which is a good thing, in confidence in European monetary union. The three elements go together.&quot;</p>
<p>As regards the euro, Trichet said that he did not believe French people wanted to change their own currency for one which was less solid.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore you obviously have to show...that the future currency will be as solid as the one we have now,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
