<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="300977" id="root" date="1997-01-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: TENNIS-CHANG BEATS SAMPRAS IN OPEN REHEARSAL.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-CHANG BEATS SAMPRAS IN OPEN REHEARSAL.</headline>
<byline>Robert Galvin</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-01-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>American Michael Chang gave himself a psychological edge over world number one Pete Sampras on Saturday by winning a key warm-up event before the Australian Open for the third year in succession.</p>
<p>Chang, the world number two and second seed at the Open, starting on Monday, defeated compatriot Sampras 4-6 6-4 6-2 in one hour and 35 minutes in the Colonial Classic in Kooyong.</p>
<p>A losing finalist to Boris Becker in Melbourne last year, Chang is convinced he can finally take the extra step required to add a second grand slam title to his French Open success as a teenager in 1989.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is one word that sums up my career, it would be perseverance,&quot; said Chang, who also reached last year's U.S. Open final only to lose to Sampras.</p>
<p>&quot;Over the past couple of years I have got to a lot of finals and come up short. I have just had to pick myself up and try, try again,&quot; Chang said.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel physically and mentally ready -- now we'll have to see what the next two weeks have in store,&quot; said Chang, who produced a typically tenacious performance on Saturday, highlighting the qualities that have lifted him to his current ranking, the highest of his career.</p>
<p>After losing the first set in hot, blustery conditions, the 24-year-old Chang refused to yield to his great rival before eventually dominating the third and final set.</p>
<p>Chang will play Belgium's Kris Goossen, a lucky loser ranked 132 in the world, in the first round of the Open at the National Tennis Centre.</p>
<p>Sampras also declared himself satisfied with his preparations for the first grand slam tournament of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;This has been good preparation for me and I feel fit and fresh for next week,&quot; said Sampras, who is scheduled to meet Chang in the Open final on January 26 according to the seedings.</p>
<p>&quot;Michael is always difficult to play,&quot; Sampras told reporters. &quot;But it's a long time until the final and that is the last thing on my mind at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>Sampras will begin his challenge for a second Australian Open and ninth grand slam title in total against Romanian qualifier Dinu Pescariu, ranked 169 in the world.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
