<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="300986" id="root" date="1997-01-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NHL ICE HOCKEY-JAGR AND LEMIEUX LEAD PENGUINS PAST ISLANDERS.</title>
<headline>NHL ICE HOCKEY-JAGR AND LEMIEUX LEAD PENGUINS PAST ISLANDERS.</headline>
<dateline>PITTSBURGH 1997-01-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jaromir Jagr notched his league-leading 37th and 38th goals in the first period and Mario Lemeiux collected four assists as the Pittsburgh Penguins beat the New York Islanders 5-2 on Friday.</p>
<p>The streaking Penguins have won six in a row and are 9-0-1 in their last 10 and 17-2-3 since November 21.</p>
<p>Pittsburgh goalie Patrick Lalime stopped 37 shots to remain unbeaten at 11-0-1 since being called up.</p>
<p>Lemieux's third assist, coming on Jagr's second goal, moved him past Bobby Clark into 13th place on the all-time assist list. Lemieux, who has 854 career assists, has two goals and 14 assists in his last four games.</p>
<p>&quot;Our big guys just took over the game tonight,&quot; said Pittsburgh coach Ed Johnston. &quot;When they're playing like that, they're awful, awful tough to stop.</p>
<p>&quot;Jagr was a question mark,&quot; Johnston said. &quot;He put on a pretty good demonstration for a guy who was sick.&quot;</p>
<p>Bryan Smolinski and Zigmund Palffy tallied for the Isles, losers of six in a row.</p>
<p>In Anaheim, Paul Kariya recorded his first career hat trick and added an assist to lead the Mighty Ducks to a 5-2 victory over the Buffalo Sabres.</p>
<p>Kariya broke a 1-1 tie late in the second period with a short-handed goal and snapped a 2-2 deadlock with his second of the game at 4:36 of the third.</p>
<p>After assisting on Teemu Selanne's 24th goal just 71 seconds later, Kariya completed the scoring and his hat trick with a powerplay marker at 9:06 of the third.</p>
<p>Buffalo's Dominik Hasek made 47 saves in a losing effort as the Ducks outshot the Sabres by a wide 52-21 margin.</p>
<p>At New Jersey, Tony Amonte, skating on a bruised left knee, scored with 20 seconds left to lift the Chicago Blackhawks into a 3-3 tie with the Devils.</p>
<p>Denis Pederson had a powerplay goal and an assist for the Devils, who blew a 3-1 lead. Eric Weinrich scored to move Chicago within one with 6:43 left in the second period.</p>
<p>The Blackhawks pulled goaltender Jeff Hackett in the final minute for an extra attacker and Amonte streaked into the New Jersey zone and beat Martin Brodeur with a low wrist shot for his team-leading 27th goal.</p>
<p>In Dallas, Keith Tkachuk and Mike Gartner each had a goal and two assists to lead Phoenix Coyotes to a 4-3 victory over the Stars.</p>
<p>Gartner and Tkachuk scored just under six minutes apart in the second period to put the Coyotes up 3-2. Jeremy Roenick added a powerplay tally at 8:06 of the third, which proved to be the game winner as Phoenix snapped a three-game slide.</p>
<p>Tkachuk, who leads Phoenix with 26 goals, has 14 goals and 22 points in his last 13 games.</p>
<p>Nikolai Khabibulin made 31 saves for Phoenix.</p>
<p>In Vancouver, Pavel Bure had a goal and two assists and Kirk McLean made 20 saves as the Canucks handed the Hartford Whalers their eight straight road loss with a 5-3 victory.</p>
<p>Bure, back on track after a slow start, scored the game-winner in the third and assisted on earlier goals by Alexander Mogilny and David Roberts. He has a seven-game points streak with seven goals and six assits.</p>
<p>Glen Wesley and Kevin Dineen tallied goals for Hartford, which is 0-6-1 in its last seven games.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PITTSBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
