<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="30108" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraq to complete pullback from north today - Aziz.</title>
<headline>Iraq to complete pullback from north today - Aziz.</headline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq's Deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz said Baghdad would complete the withdrawal of its troops from the Kurdish north on Tuesday and denied reports that Iraq was massing troops close to Sulaimaniya.</p>
<p>&quot;Deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz ridiculed American claims on Iraqi troop movements towards Sulaimaniya,&quot; the official Iraqi News Agency (INA) said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our troops have started withdrawing to former positions and will complete their return today,&quot; it quoted Aziz as saying.</p>
<p>The United States fired 27 cruise missiles at what it said were military targets in southern Iraq on Tuesday, three days after Iraqi forces seized the Kurdish city of Arbil from the rebel Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK) after a rival group, the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP), asked for Baghdad's help.</p>
<p>INA issued Aziz's remarks shortly after President Saddam Hussein gave a defiant speech in which he urged his armed forces to resist the U.S. missile strikes and asked his pilots and anti-aircraft gunners to shoot down any allied plane violating Iraqi airspace.</p>
<p>Aziz said the U.S. missile attack would &quot;have no effect at all on the will of Iraq and its decision to protect its people and defend its sovereignty&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;This aggression will bring America nothing but added disgrace and shame,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry said on Monday there was evidence that some of the Iraqi forces were penetrating deeper into Kurdish-populated areas and were threatening Sulaymania, PUK's last major stronghold close to the Iranian border.</p>
<p>PUK leader Jalal Talabani, speaking from Sulaymaniya hours after the missile strikes, said the attacks had not deterred Baghdad and that the army had moved artillery pieces and 40 tanks towards other Kurdish positions.</p>
<p>Aziz said allegations of an Iraqi troop build-up close to Sulaimaniya were &quot;empty and groundless not supported by anyone. They are some of silly claims used by the United States, master of lies and deception in the world, to justify its cowardly aggression against Iraq today.&quot;</p>
<p>Saddam, in his brief address carried by state-run media, said damage and casualties from the U.S. attacks were minimal and that Iraqi forces had shot down many of the missiles.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
