<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301053" id="root" date="1997-01-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Opposition protests jam central Belgrade traffic.</title>
<headline>Opposition protests jam central Belgrade traffic.</headline>
<byline>Jovan Kovacic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of Serbian opposition supporters caused traffic chaos in central Belgrade for several hours on Friday on the 54th day of protests against poll fraud which they say cost them election victories in major cities.</p>
<p>Police fought a losing battle to divert traffic from the city centre to keep opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition supporters from using their vehicles to gridlock the area during the evening rush hour, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Hundreds of riot police were also present in the streets, heightening tension in the city, hours after persistent students had persuaded them to dismantle security cordons and let protesters march in defiance of a ban imposed last month.</p>
<p>Zajedno, protesting against annulment of their victory in local elections on November 17 in Belgrade and 13 other cities, have started using traffic jams to annoy the authorities.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no dispute with the police, they are also our police -- but we are in conflict with a regime which has stolen our votes,&quot; Vuk Draskovic, a Zajedno leader, told about 25,000 people assembled in a central square.</p>
<p>Protesters were joined by a delegation of U.S. congressmen who arrived in Belgrade on Friday to press home the message to President Slobodan Milosevic that he must respect democratic processes in Serbia. The crowd chanted &quot;U.S.A., U.S.A.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The major contribution that we can make is to continue to give encourangement to the opposition forces...to continue to insist that Serbia have free and open democracy and democratic institutions,&quot; said Rick Boucher, a Virginia Democrat.</p>
<p>Racheting up pressure on Milosevic, the Contact Group on ex-Yugoslavia meets in Brussels on Saturday amid expectations the five nations will seek to find a common stance on Serbia.</p>
<p>&quot;I have the impression that they are going to try to get a unified position,&quot; one NATO source said. &quot;They will probably come out with a fairly strong statement.&quot;</p>
<p>The European Union called on Milosevic to accept opposition victories and embrace democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>&quot;Only reform directed towards full democratisation and liberalisation of the political and economic system, in dialogue with the opposition, as well as respect for human rights...will allow for the full integration of Yugoslavia into the international community,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>After being thrown out for fomenting war in Bosnia in 1992, Yugoslavia, now comprising only Serbia and Montenegro, has yet to be readmitted to key financial institutions like the World Bank, blocking major foreign capital desperately needed by Belgrade to rebuild its wrecked economy.</p>
<p>It must improve its bad human rights record before rejoining those institutions, Western officials say.</p>
<p>Remaining so far deaf and mute to the calls, Milosevic, backed only by his police, stood alone in the apparent pursuit of total control of the country.</p>
<p>He has been abandoned by part of the army, the Orthodox Church and on Friday even by his normally staunch allies at the Serbian Academy of Arts and Sciences. Even his Socialist Party (SPS) was reportedly split into moderates and hardliners.</p>
<p>Senior officials from the SPS and the Yugoslav United Left led by Milosevic's wife Mirjana Markovic, who urges a crackdown on protesters, were reported to be meeting on Friday.</p>
<p>Political analysts believe the session will resolve a power struggle between options put forward by moderates and hardliners to end the crisis.</p>
<p>Milosevic conceded on Wednesday that Zajedno had won the election in Serbia's second largest city Nis but failed to appease Zajedno leaders who vowed to continue protests until all their claims were met.</p>
<p>The United States said that admission of Zajedno's victory in Nis did not go far enough and he could not win world applause by &quot;dribbling out minor concessions&quot;.</p>
<p>U.S. Assistant Secretary of State John Kornblum began a trip to The Hague, Brussels, Sarajevo and Zagreb to discuss issues pertaining to former Yugoslavia including the political crisis in Serbia. His itinerary deliberately excluded Belgrade.</p>
<p>Paul Poulade, a senior French Foreign Ministry official, was in Belgrade to urge Milosevic to heed confirmation by the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) of the opposition's victories.</p>
<p>Greek Foreign Minister Theodoros Pangalos was due on Sunday to try to ease tensions between Milosevic and the opposition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
