<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301063" id="root" date="1997-01-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Bosnia peace impossible without arrests - Portillo.</title>
<headline>Bosnia peace impossible without arrests - Portillo.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>BANJA LUKA, Bosnia 1997-01-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Defence Minister Michael Portillo said on Saturday permanent peace in Bosnia would be impossible until indicted war criminals had been arrested.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot expect an enduring settlement in Bosnia if those indicted of war crimes are allowed to go free,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Portillo was speaking on a flight to Bosnia which had to be diverted to Zagreb because of bad weather.</p>
<p>He was on his way to assess first-hand how British troops in the NATO-led Stabilisation Force (SFOR) were helping enforce peace after a 43-month-long war.</p>
<p>He praised political progress made since the Dayton peace agreement at the end of 1995 but said peace would not be anchored for good until suspects indicted by the U.N. tribunal on war crimes in former Yugoslavia had been apprehended.</p>
<p>NATO commanders say SFOR soldiers will arrest any of the more than 70 indicted war criminals if they encounter them during the course of their normal duties but have ruled out tracking down suspects because NATO is eager to avoid a violent backlash against its troops.</p>
<p>One of the most prominent war crime suspects, former Bosnian Serb president Radovan Karadzic, was spotted last month by U.N. police monitors in a motorcade in Pale, outside Sarajevo.</p>
<p>Critics say post-war reconciliation between Bosnia's Moslems, Croats and Serbs will be hard to achieve unless indicted war criminals are extradited to The Hague.</p>
<p>The British defence minister conceded there was a dilemma. &quot;We are between a rock and a hard place. We don't believe we can have a peace without their arrest but we recognise their arrest could be a flashpoint.&quot;</p>
<p>But he stressed: &quot;The importance of a lot of these people will reduce with time.&quot;</p>
<p>Portillo, who had to complete the last three hours of his journey by road to the British army headquarters in Banja Luka, said he hoped the 31,000-strong SFOR could complete its mandate within the next 18 months as envisaged.</p>
<p>&quot;But it's a bit like a forest fire,&quot; he added. &quot;The ashes could still be glowing in 18 months and they could be fanned back into flames.&quot;</p>
<p>Portillo was the first to concede what a tough battle it was converting the idealism of the Dayton agreement into a workable living arrangement in a land still scarred by war and divided into mono-ethnic sectors.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite political progress, I don't think there is much progress in reconciliation... There is precious little sign of the population wishing to tolerate each other,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the great challenges this year is if political progress continues. Will people want to go home in continuing numbers?&quot; he added. &quot;What is still very worrying is what is happening at village and town level.&quot;</p>
<p>At an international peace conference in London last month, Western powers warned Bosnia's leaders that further reconstruction aid depended on a stronger commitment to the reintegration principle of the Dayton accords.</p>
<p>Portillo hailed the decision of once-bitter foes to sit behind the same Bosnian flag at the conference and said:</p>
<p>&quot;Against our expectations, we have seen some genuine political progress. The elections gave us a set of leaders we can deal with. They are now beginning to enjoy their powers and see their successes.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANJA LUKA, Bosnia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
