<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301087" id="root" date="1997-01-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru government, rebels break stalemate in crisis.</title>
<headline>Peru government, rebels break stalemate in crisis.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-01-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peru's 25-day hostage crisis began a more hopeful phase on Saturday as the government and rebels broke a stalemate in talks since the New Year and an informal mediator renewed visits to the besieged embassy residence.</p>
<p>After nearly two weeks of stalled negotiations, government negotiator Domingo Palermo spoke on Friday with Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) leader Nestor Cerpa Cartolini by radio to arrange a face-to-face meeting this weekend.</p>
<p>As also agreed in that exchange, Roman Catholic bishop Juan Carlos Cipriani entered the Japanese ambassador's home to visit the remaining 74 VIP hostages.</p>
<p>The movements fuelled hopes of a negotiated end to the crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope these contacts will achieve developments which will lead to a peaceful resolution to the crisis,&quot; an official for the Japanese government's Task Force in Lima said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am optimistic that everything will turn out well,&quot; Cipriani told reporters before entering the residence.</p>
<p>The MRTA initially took more than 500 hostages when it stormed a cocktail party at the residence on Dec. 17, but has released most since then. It is holding the most valuable hostages as bargaining chips to obtain its principal demand: the release of about 400 jailed comrades.</p>
<p>Palermo, whose first face-to-face meeting with Cerpa on Dec. 28 brought the release of 20 hostages, had not entered the residence by late Saturday afternoon.</p>
<p>Red Cross officials continued to shuttle to and fro, taking in food and supplies. For the first time, books in Japanese were delivered for the Japanese captives.</p>
<p>The only sign of life from the MRTA was the brief appearance at a window of one young rebel dressed in black who watched photographers on a nearby rooftop with binoculars.</p>
<p>When asked by the photographers how the hostages were, the rebel first replied &quot;screwed up&quot; and then &quot;fine.&quot; When asked if there would be more releases, he waved his hands in a gesture intepreted by some reporters as meaning &quot;No.&quot;</p>
<p>Saturday's activity followed a week of heightened rhetoric between the government and the Marxist MRTA. Although both sides agreed to talk again, neither has made any concessions.</p>
<p>Fujimori has insisted he will not give in to &quot;terrorist blackmail&quot; and urged the rebels to lay down their arms and release all the captives. But the MRTA has reiterated it will not leave the residence until it obtains the release of some 400 imprisoned comrades.</p>
<p>The government has, however, floated the possibility of granting the rebels political exile abroad if they surrender.</p>
<p>Palermo insisted the government would accept nothing short of the release of all the remaining captives.</p>
<p>&quot;My goal is to free the 74 hostages in their entirety, in good health and as quickly as possible,&quot; he told a small group of foreign correspondents, including Reuters, who witnessed his radio conversation on Friday with the guerrilla leader.</p>
<p>Red Cross spokesman Steven Anderson said on Saturday that, as well as attending to the hostages' needs, the organisation &quot;served as a channel at the disposition of the government and the MRTA to facilitate a solution to the crisis.&quot;</p>
<p>Anderson told local CPN radio the Red Cross had exchanged more than 2,000 written messages between the hostages and their families. The notes were &quot;an important psychological support&quot; to help them through the long ordeal, he said.</p>
<p>About 20 MRTA rebels entered a small jungle village oto demand food and spread propaganda, local radio reported.</p>
<p>In the first such action in months, 13 men and seven women woke up residents of Palcazu in the central Pasco region at dawn, CPN radio said. The rebels collected food, spoke about the hostage stand-off and painted slogans on walls.</p>
<p>The MRTA's armed members, estimated to number 250 at most after several years of decline, are mainly based in Peru's central jungle area.</p>
<p>The daily La Republica reported on Saturday that Peru's secret military court had convicted an MRTA member for his involvement in the 1995 kidnapping of a former Bolivian planning minister. That kidnapping raised some of the money used for the MRTA's current hostage-taking operation in Lima.</p>
<p>Roque Gonzales La Rosa was sentenced on Dec. 12 to 20 years in a maximum security jail for his role in the Nov. 1995 abduction of Samuel Doria Medina in the Bolivian capital by nine MRTA members, the newspapers said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
