<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301129" id="root" date="1997-01-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. seeks WTO action on Brazil car import rules.</title>
<headline>U.S. seeks WTO action on Brazil car import rules.</headline>
<byline>Donna Smith</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States, worried about what it says are Brazilian car trade rules that hurt U.S. exports, moved on Friday to initiate a World Trade Organization (WTO) dispute settlement action.</p>
<p>The U.S. Trade Representative's Office said it formally asked the WTO for talks with Brazil to try to settle a U.S. complaint about a trade arrangement that gives preferential tariff treatment to car imports from Japan, South Korea and the European Union.</p>
<p>&quot;In our view that is inconsistent with the WTO,&quot; a U.S. trade official said.</p>
<p>The United States also wants to discuss concerns about a Brazilian program launched in December to attract car manufacturing investment in its poor northeast district.</p>
<p>&quot;The WTO requires that you consult on an issue before you can request a dispute settlement panel,&quot; the trade official said. The official, who asked not to be identified, said the &quot;best outcome&quot; would be for the two countries to resolve the disagreement without a formal WTO dispute proceeding.</p>
<p>The latest request for talks is in addition to an earlier complaint filed by the United States with the WTO against Brazil's car import regime.</p>
<p>That case remains open, but the United States has not yet requested a WTO dispute settlement panel ruling. The two sides had held some talks in October after the United States initiated a proceeding under U.S. trade laws, but they came to no resolution, the trade official said.</p>
<p>Brazil's import regime allows car firms with manufacturing facilities based in that South American country to import vehicles at a 35 percent tariff. Competitors without manufacturing in Brazil pay a hefty 70 percent duty.</p>
<p>The aim of the program was to spur investment in local production and exports. Car companies have pledged to invest at least $17 billion by the end of the decade.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue is the export of vehicle and parts out of the United States that have been diverted because of this regime,&quot; the U.S. official said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is fairly obvious that if everyone is pouring millions and millions of dollars into production facilities in Brazil and meeting local content requirements and trade balancing requirement that the chances for expanded U.S. exports are diminished,&quot; the U.S. official said.</p>
<p>Japan, South Korea, and the EU had filed complaints with the WTO, prompting Brazil to initiate the preferential program allowing a certain number of imports from those countries to be imported at a lower tariff.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
