<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301213" id="root" date="1997-01-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton vows to &quot;break the backs&quot; of gangs.</title>
<headline>Clinton vows to &quot;break the backs&quot; of gangs.</headline>
<byline>Steve Holland</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton said on Saturday he would propose legislation early in his second term aimed at stopping gang members from intimidating crime witnesses in a bid to &quot;break the backs&quot; of youth gangs.</p>
<p>&quot;Too many people will not testify about gang crimes because they are afraid of violent reprisal,&quot; he said in his weekly radio address. &quot;We must not allow the voice of justice to be frightened into silence by the violent threats of gangs.&quot;</p>
<p>In the Republican response to Clinton's radio address, Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott of Mississippi said Republicans would press for &quot;permanent tax relief&quot; for Americans in the new session of Congress. He gave no details.</p>
<p>Lott said Republicans would also act quickly on a constitutional amendment requiring Congress to pass a balanced federal budget each year. The amendment passed the House two years ago but failed by one vote in the Senate. Clinton opposes it but has said if it is enacted, it should include safeguards to protect the budget from recessions.</p>
<p>The president's radio address coincided with the release of a Justice Department report that said witness intimidation in gang- and drug-related cases was hampering the investigation and prosecution of crime throughout the United States.</p>
<p>The report said gang members and associates of defendants often appear in court to frighten witnesses into not testifying. This is hard to stop because the intimidation can be subtle and difficult to detect by the judge and prosecutors.</p>
<p>It said 88 percent of America's largest cities and 56 percent of smaller ones suffer from gang-related crime.</p>
<p>Clinton called the struggle against youth violence and drug abuse a top priority of his second term and said he would submit comprehensive legislation to the Republican-controlled Congress in coming weeks on ways to fight it.</p>
<p>&quot;As I begin my second term as president, the next stage in our fight must centre on keeping our children safe and attacking the scourge of juvenile crime and gangs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am determined to break the backs of criminal gangs that have ruined too many lives and stolen too many futures by bringing the full force of the law against them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said he had asked Attorney General Janet Reno to examine the &quot;growing threat&quot; of witness intimidation by gangs and to recommend strong measures to stop it that can be included in the legislation.</p>
<p>The White House said the legislation would include new tools for federal and state prosecutors to investigate and convict gang members and end witness intimidation.</p>
<p>The Justice Department report said prosecutors and police investigators recommend that communities develop comprehensive witness security programmes.</p>
<p>It also said a few jurisdictions, such as California, explicitly permit the removal from courtrooms of spectators who intimidate witnesses.</p>
<p>It said the practice of closing the court or restricting attendance to prevent intimidation has been upheld on appeal in some instances.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
