<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301262" id="root" date="1997-01-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austria leaders seek way out of crisis over bank.</title>
<headline>Austria leaders seek way out of crisis over bank.</headline>
<byline>Steve Pagani</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-01-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leaders of Austria's fractious coalition were locked in an emergency meeting on Saturday to try to solve a crisis threatening the year-old government, with little sign of a breakthrough in the offing.</p>
<p>Chancellor Franz Vranitzky's Social Democrats and the conservative People's Party led by Foreign Minister Wolfgang Schuessel are at daggers drawn over the privatisation of the country's second biggest bank, Creditanstalt-Bankverein.</p>
<p>The crisis meeting was called to try to settle differences over who should buy the 141-year-old flagship bank, long considered a conservative fiefdom.</p>
<p>In an atmosphere of mutual recrimination, there was little sign that the coalition was any closer patching up their row.</p>
<p>The two sides took a breather after four hours of talks at the chancellory and conservative party chiefs were seen heading for a separate room, Austrian television reported.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue the talks tonight, we will continue the talks tomorrow, we will continue day and night,&quot; a source close to the talks told reporters.</p>
<p>The discussions were focusing on some 10 points put forward by Schuessel's party over the Creditanstalt sale, he said.</p>
<p>Vranitzky had insisted before the talks that he would demand an explanation from the People's Party over a series of talks it has had with far right leader Joerg Haider.</p>
<p>&quot;You know what, the style that the chancellor has adopted over setting the agenda, makes me want to vomit,&quot; conservative chief whip Andrea Khol told reporters as he entered the talks in some of the strongest language yet used during the row.</p>
<p>Haider, whose nationalist Freedom Party scored nearly 28 percent in European elections last October, said final talks with the conservatives would take place on Monday, a day before parliament convenes in special session to debate the bank sale.</p>
<p>The conservatives and the far right can command a majority in parliament and if they decide to outvote the Social Democrats, the creaky coalition could collapse.</p>
<p>Vranitzky's party wants Creditanstalt to be sold to Bank Austria, which is effectively controlled by the Social Democrat-led City of Vienna.</p>
<p>The conservatives, together with Creditanstalt's management, favour an international consortium led by Italian-controlled insurer EA-Generali.</p>
<p>Conservative Education Minister Elisabeth Gehrer told a party meeting on Saturday that selling Creditanstalt to Bank Austria would not constitute privatisation but state control.</p>
<p>At the same meeting, Conservative Defence Minister Werner Fasslabend said thousands of jobs would be lost if Bank Austria won the bid and that Vranitzky and Social Democrat Finance Minister Viktor Klima would be held responsible.</p>
<p>&quot;You cannot conduct economic policy through power politics,&quot; Fasslabend said.</p>
<p>Klima, who has sole responsiblity for choosing the winning bid for Creditanstalt, said he would make a decision before Tuesday, a move sure to infuriate Schuessel's party which has warned him to hold his fire before parliament meets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
