<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301321" id="root" date="1997-01-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - Jan 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - Jan 11.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Bangladesh press on Saturday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE DAILY STAR</p>
<p>British Prime Minister John Major was accorded a warm welcome by Bangladesh counterpart Sheikh Hasina when he arrived in Dhaka last night. The two will hold official talks today.</p>
<p>British Prime Minister John Major has appreciated the recent water sharing agreement between Bangladesh and India, saying it was a tremendous achievement for both countries.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina yesterday warned the opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) that if it remained absent from parliament for 90 consecutive working days the seats would automatically fall vacant and there would be no other option than holding byelections.</p>
<p>Eight Moslem countries have resolved to form a new alliance of developing countries and hold a summit-level meeting in the first half of the year in Ankara. The summit will be attended by Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>BANGLADESH OBSERVER</p>
<p>Former president and Jatiya Party Chairman Hossain Mohammad Ershad passed his first day of freedom with family members and party leaders. Ershad was released on bail from jail on Thursday.</p>
<p>Begum Khaleda Zia, chairperson of main opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), said on Friday her party is the strongest political force to protest the activities of the present &quot;fascist&quot; government.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>FINANCIAL EXPRESS</p>
<p>The World Bank has expressed satisfaction at the improvement in project implementation during the current fiscal year and suggested a series of steps to further expedite the process.</p>
<p>-- Dhaka Newsroom 880-2-506363 REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
