<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301400" id="root" date="1997-01-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-TIGER WOODS SETS UP FINAL-ROUND SHOWDOWN WITH LEHMAN.</title>
<headline>GOLF-TIGER WOODS SETS UP FINAL-ROUND SHOWDOWN WITH LEHMAN.</headline>
<dateline>CARLSBAD, California 1997-01-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tiger Woods set up a final-round showdown between the 1996 Rookie of the Year and the 1996 Player of the Year by catching Tom Lehman at the season-opening Mercedes Championships on Saturday.</p>
<p>The sensational newcomer to the PGA Tour picked up where he left last season by firing a tournament-low seven-under 65 to grab a share of first place with Lehman, who had led after the first two rounds.</p>
<p>Woods, who began the day trailing Lehman by four strokes, birdied the daunting final four holes at La Costa to reach 14-under-par 202, along with British Open champion Lehman, who carded a third-round 69.</p>
<p>The pair stood five strokes clear of Guy Boros, who shot a two-under 70 to finish at nine under. Fred Couples and Paul Goydos were another stroke back after also recording 70s.</p>
<p>&quot;It could become matchplay on the back nine tomorrow, and everyone knows Tiger's matchplay record,&quot; Lehman said. &quot;But I'm no powder puff either, and I've never backed away from a challenge.&quot;</p>
<p>The 21-year-old Woods is already seeking his third tournament title since turning professional last August.</p>
<p>&quot;I may be player of the year,&quot; said Lehman, &quot;but Tiger's player of the next two decades.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not sure if I feel like the underdog or what. It's a unique situation, you feel like you're just trying to hold off the inevitable.&quot;</p>
<p>Woods set the tone for his challenge early with an eagle on the par-five second hole and added birdies on the fourth, eighth and 10th.</p>
<p>But he missed putts of four feet or less on the 12th, 13th and 14th holes, resulting in two bogeys and a par.</p>
<p>&quot;The two bogeys got me going,&quot; Woods said. &quot;They got me more focused.&quot;</p>
<p>The result of that heightened focus was his impressive four-birdie finish.</p>
<p>&quot;This is why we play, to get into position to win,&quot; Woods said. &quot;I'm thoroughly enjoying it.&quot;</p>
<p>If Woods picks up his third title in his ninth PGA event as a professional he will pass the $1 million mark in official earnings. The previous fast sprint the $1 million milestone was by David Duval, who reached the mark in 32 tournaments.</p>
<p>Lehman had led the tournament from the start, but came to the 18th a stroke behind Woods. He sank a 30-foot putt for birdie to regain a share of the lead.</p>
<p>&quot;I really wanted to make that putt. I heard four big roars coming in and it didn't take a rocket scientist to figure out that that meant I was behind.&quot;</p>
<p>Woods and Lehman will play together for the first time Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know just how good Tiger is because I've never seen him play,&quot; Lehman said.</p>
<p>&quot;If I play my best and lose, I'm going to know that there's a new kid on the block who's better than anyone else.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARLSBAD, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
