<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301598" id="root" date="1997-01-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Nicaragua's new president promises prosperity.</title>
<headline>Nicaragua's new president promises prosperity.</headline>
<byline>David Koop</byline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1997-01-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>When new right-wing President Arnoldo Aleman took power this weekend, he looked at world leaders gathered at his inauguration and promised a war -- a war against unemployment and poverty.</p>
<p>&quot;I shall never fail in the frontal fight against the plagues of unemployment and misery that make our hearts bleed. Let this be my most sacred promise,&quot; Aleman, an avowed supporter of the free market, said in his inauguration speech on Friday.</p>
<p>But the economic challenges awaiting the portly, 50-year-old lawyer and coffee grower are daunting.</p>
<p>The United Nations ranks Nicaragua as the second-poorest country in Latin America, still recovering from a bloody civil war and failed socialist economic experiment, both of which ended seven years ago.</p>
<p>More than 70 percent of Nicaraguans live below the poverty line, 52 percent are either unemployed and underemployed, and swarms of hungry street children clog Managua's street corners begging for change or cleaning windscreens.</p>
<p>Annual per capita income has fallen from $1,122 in 1978 to $469 in 1996, according to the Ministry of the Economy, and while the government of former President Violeta Chamorro halted the economic collapse, a lot of rebuilding remains to be done.</p>
<p>Nicaragua's economy has grown for three consecutive years, increasing to 5.5 percent growth in 1996, but the benefits have not trickled down to the poor majority, creating a powder keg of social unrest, politicians warned.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not enough that the economy grows and inflation falls. It has to be transferred to the great majority of the population for Nicaragua to have a future. The great challenge awaiting the next government will be social,&quot; outgoing Finance Minister Emilio Pereira said.</p>
<p>To do this, Aleman said he would focus on boosting agricultural production and tourism and promoting exports from its small but growing industrial free zone, new Economy Minister Francisco Lainez said.</p>
<p>&quot;During the campaign one of our central themes was the unpostponable need to attend to the agricultural sector and make Nicaragua once again the breadbasket of Central America. That is the master key,&quot; Aleman said.</p>
<p>Lainez said the government would do so by giving incentives to small- and medium-sized producers, improving the rural infrastructure, and guaranteeing financing for growers.</p>
<p>Aleman said he would attempt to attract more foreign investment and he repeated his offer for Nicaraguans living abroad to return.</p>
<p>&quot;Anyone who is or has been Nicaraguan can return whenever they want without paying taxes on their belongings, including working equipment, either for personal use or the establishment of a business or factory,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
