<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301593" id="root" date="1997-01-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico quake destroys town hospital, damages homes.</title>
<headline>Mexico quake destroys town hospital, damages homes.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-01-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A powerful earthquake on Saturday destroyed a hospital and damaged about 90 percent of homes in the western Mexican town of Arteaga, the town's mayor said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The earthquake that Mexican seismology officials measured at 7.3 on the Richter scale rumbled across western and central Mexico, causing panic in many areas but only minor damage in the capital and other major cities.</p>
<p>Arteaga Mayor Herminio Garcia Reuda told the government news agency Notimex that 90 percent of Arteaga's 2,000 homes were severely damaged by the quake.</p>
<p>&quot;The Health Ministry hospital is totally destroyed, so we are establishing a social centre to give medical attention to those who need it and to tend to births and first aid,&quot; Notimex quoted the mayor as saying.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the government of the western state of Michoacan confirmed that some houses fell and there were injuries, but he had no information about the hospital.</p>
<p>The earthquake, whose epicentre was under the Pacific Ocean 30 miles (50 km) west-northwest of Playa Azul, in Michoacan, was felt throughout western and central Mexico, causing panic in the major cities of Mexico City and Guadalajara.</p>
<p>A major bridge near Guadalajara was damaged and closed to traffic and power was lost in many communities and neighbourhoods of Mexico City.</p>
<p>Arteaga is an isolated town north of Playa Azul in the South Sierra Madre mountains. State authorities did not have reports of damage from there until Sunday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
