<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301512" id="root" date="1997-01-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Cricket-Victoria snatch last-over victory.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Cricket-Victoria snatch last-over victory.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Victoria shrugged off early setbacks to snatch a thrilling one-wicket victory over Tasmania in the last over of their Sheffield Shield match on Sunday.</p>
<p>Set 340 to win in 80 overs after two declarations by Tasmania, Victoria reached the target when wicketkeeper Darren Berry drove the third ball of the final over for a boundary.</p>
<p>Berry finished unbeaten on 50 after opener Graeme Vimpani set his side on course with 113, sharing a key fourth wicket stand of 79 with Rohan Larkin following the cheap dismissals of opener Warren Ayres, former Australia batsman Dean Jones and all-rounder Laurie Harper.</p>
<p>Victoria needed 37 from the final 10 overs but lost four wickets for 22 before Berry and tailender Damien Fleming saw their team home.</p>
<p>Tasmania captain David Boon had declared his side's second innings on 264 for four midway through the morning session, with axed Australia batsman Ricky Ponting 94 not out.</p>
<p>In Sydney, Western Australia moved into equal first with Queensland in the Shield standings after defeating New South Wales by nine wickets before lunch on the final day.</p>
<p>Opener Mike Hussey and test batsman Justin Langer made short work of their task as Western Australia, who resumed on 166 for one, reached their winning target of 220 without further loss.</p>
<p>Hussey was unbeaten on 81 and Langer was 70 not out.</p>
<p>In Adelaide, South Australia ended the third day on the verge of a comprehensive victory against Queensland, who were 220 for seven after following on exactly 300 behind.</p>
<p>Queensland, unbeaten in the competition this season, succumbed to spinners Bradley Young and Peter McIntyre, who shared six wickets.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
