<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301624" id="root" date="1997-01-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Pilot in fatal NZ air crash changes plea to guilty.</title>
<headline>Pilot in fatal NZ air crash changes plea to guilty.</headline>
<dateline>BLENHEIM 1996-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The pilot of a Soundsair plane which crashed on January 19 last year, killing five people, on Monday changed his plea to guilty when he appeared in the Blenheim District Court on a charge of dangerous operation of an aircraft.</p>
<p>The New Zealand Press Association reported that Aaron Tamblyn, who was charged following the crash on Mt Robertson, near Picton, has been remanded for sentencing in the Wellington District Court on February 14.</p>
<p>The 25-year-old from Roxburgh, central Otago, was the sole survivor of the crash and suffered serious injuries.  </p>
<p>A doctor who spoke to him shortly after the crash said that despite his injuries, Tamblyn had made a brave effort to rescue two people in the plane and tried to revive them.</p>
<p>Those who died were newlyweds Katrina Foster and Liam Benton of Seatoun, Wellington; Christopher Taylor, of Nelson; Martha Humston, of Ireland and Dorothy Egan, of Picton.</p>
<p>At his two earlier court appearances, Tamblyn, through his counsel Les Atkins QC, indicated he was pleading not guilty to the charge which carries a maximum penalty of one year's imprisonment or a NZ$10,000 fine, and one year's disqualification from flying.  </p>
<p>Tamblyn sobbed quietly in the dock as crown prosecutor Robert Lithgow read the summary of facts which revealed Tamblyn had been deceived by the shrouded landscape on the afternoon of the crash.</p>
<p>At the time he was completing his third return commercial flight for the day from Koromiko, near Picton, to Wellington Airport.</p>
<p>Between the earlier flights and the accident flight there was a marked build-up of localised cloud along the eastern slopes of the Mt Robertson range, more or less on the intended flight path of the aircraft.  </p>
<p>Although the cloud obscured visibility of the terrain and coastline, this was not immediately obvious to the pilot as he left Wellington and began flying across Cook Strait in clear skies, Lithgow said.</p>
<p>&quot;As he got closer to land, Mr Tamblyn changed an earlier decision to fly over the cloud and continued flying at the same height (2500 feet),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;He encountered progressively worsening conditions which he had not anticipated.  </p>
<p>&quot;The defendant did not recognise the gravity of the situation until it was too late and resulted in him crashing the aircraft into the side of the mountain at about 1,700 feet above sea level.&quot;</p>
<p>A number of casual factors were identified in the investigation as having adversely affected the safety of the flight, Lithgow said.</p>
<p>These included Tamblyn's misidentification of distant terrain features and the delayed decision to descend beneath the cloud layer which resulted in him being unable to maintain sufficient forward visibility.  </p>
<p>Further, the last 25-degree turn toward the north and high ground must have been made without an accurate assessment of his actual position, Lithgow told the court.</p>
<p>&quot;Although those factors in themselves may not have resulted in the accident, the increased speed of the descent along with worsening conditions, resulted in events overtaking the pilot and probably prevented any chance of avoiding the collision,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Atkins said for the defence that it was appropriate to mention that under pressure Tamblyn had made decisions which had been &quot;cleverly set by a unique set of conditions&quot;.  </p>
<p>In remanding Tamblyn for pre-sentence and reparation reports, Judge Pat Grace said he wanted to give the victim's families an opportunity to have a say in sentencing.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BLENHEIM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
