<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="30164" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares drop 1.13 pct on Iraqi tension.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares drop 1.13 pct on Iraqi tension.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Istanbul shares fell an average 1.13 percent in thin volume on Tuesday amid worries after the U.S. lauched missile attacks on military targets in southern Iraq, but recouped part of the early losses on selective buys.</p>
<p>Brokers said the index traded in narrow ranges in the second session with the help of support which surfaced at around 62,000 although the latest tension in Iraq continued to haunt the market which sank 2.2 percent at the opening.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is nervous because of the possibility that the crisis in Iraq may last longer,&quot; said Alp Tekince from Bumerang securities.</p>
<p>The IMKB-100 closed at 62,561.01, down 714.85 points from Monday when it shed 1.95 percent on worries following the weekend fighting in the Kurdish-held northern Iraq.</p>
<p>Daily trade volume firmed to 4.9 trillion lira ($56.3 million) after sinking to 4.3 trillion lira ($49.3 million) on Monday from previous 6.2 trillion ($72.3 million).</p>
<p>&quot;The market will remain tense because of the situation in Iraq, but the index is unlikely to fall below the 61,000-62,000 range,&quot; said Yalcin Arican from Hak securities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
