<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301605" id="root" date="1997-01-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru government prepares to meet hostage takers.</title>
<headline>Peru government prepares to meet hostage takers.</headline>
<byline>Paul Hughes</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-01-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peruvian authorities prepared on Sunday to send their chief negotiator to meet the leader of Marxist rebels holding 74 hostages inside the Japanese ambassador's residence to hammer out a peaceful solution to the 26-day crisis.</p>
<p>The long-awaited meeting between Education Minister Domingo Palermo and Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) leader Nestor Cerpa was expected to take place later on Sunday.</p>
<p>Palermo, the government's chief negotiator in the crisis, arranged the meeting in a brief radio conversation witnessed by a small group of foreign correspondents on Friday.</p>
<p>The two men have not met since their first face-to-face meeting on Dec. 28, although they have exchanged several written messages.</p>
<p>The MRTA took more than 500 hostages when it stormed a cocktail party at the residence Dec. 17, but has released most since then in what it has called &quot;goodwill gestures.&quot; The rebels are holding on to the most valuable hostages as bargaining chips to obtain its principal demand -- the release of about 400 jailed comrades.</p>
<p>Peru's President Alberto Fujimori has insisted he will not give in to &quot;terrorist blackmail&quot; and has urged the rebels to lay down their arms and release all the captives under the supervision of a &quot;guarantor committee.&quot;</p>
<p>The government has, however, floated the possibility of granting the rebels political exile abroad if they surrender.</p>
<p>In a sign that talks with the rebels had been revived, Roman Catholic bishop Juan Carlos Cipriani entered the residence on Saturday to visit the hostages.</p>
<p>&quot;I am optimistic that everything will turn out well,&quot; Cipriani, whose visits to the besieged diplomatic mansion have often been associated with hostage releases, told reporters before entering the residence.</p>
<p>News of renewed contact between the two sides was greeted warmly in Japan, where concern remained high about the two dozen Japanese diplomats and officials still trapped inside the ambassador's home.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope these contacts will achieve developments which will lead to a peaceful resolution to the crisis,&quot; an official for the Japanese government's task force in Lima said.</p>
<p>The rebels also hold dozens of Peru's top government and security force officials and the younger brother of Fujimori, Pedro Fujimori.</p>
<p>The only sign of life on Saturday from the roughly 15 MRTA members inside was the brief appearance at a window of one young rebel dressed in black who watched photographers on a nearby rooftop with binoculars.</p>
<p>When asked by the photographers how the hostages were, the rebel first replied &quot;screwed up&quot; and then said &quot;fine.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if there would be more hostage releases or if the rebels were still demanding that the government free all of their jailed comrades, he waved his hands in a gesture interpreted by some journalists as meaning &quot;No.&quot;</p>
<p>The rebels are armed with automatic rifles and grenades and have booby-trapped and mined the diplomatic compound against a surprise attack.</p>
<p>Peru's antiterrorist police DINCOTE released two employees of Japanese television station TV Asahi who were arrested after sneaking into the residence to interview Cerpa.</p>
<p>TV Asahi reporter Tsuyoshi Hitomi and his Peruvian interpreter Victor Borja had been held for four days and were heavily criticised by both Peruvian and Japanese authorities for jeopardising efforts to end the siege.</p>
<p>Hitomi left Peru under tight security early on Sunday on a flight to New York, where he is based, a TV Asahi official said. Hitomi's taped interview with Cerpa was in the hands of Japanese Foreign Ministry officials in Lima, his lawyer Augusto Linares told reporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
