<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301783" id="root" date="1997-01-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SYRIA: Syrian vice-president Khaddam to Iran for talks.</title>
<headline>Syrian vice-president Khaddam to Iran for talks.</headline>
<dateline>DAMASCUS 1997-01-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Syrian Vice-President Abdel-Halim Khaddam leaves for Tehran on Sunday for talks with Iranian leaders on regional developments and bilateral ties, officials said.</p>
<p>They said Khaddam would be accompanied by Foreign Minister Farouq al-Shara and several other ministers who would attend meetings of the joint Syrian-Iranian commission which is assigned to coordinate and promote bilateral cooperation.</p>
<p>Khaddam's visit follows harsh criticism by Iran's media of Syria's approval of a decision by Arab ministers backing the United Arab Emirates (UAE) in its dispute with Iran over ownership of three islands in the Gulf.</p>
<p>But several Iranian officials said in statetents later that ties with Syria, which backed Iran during its 1980-1988 war with Iraq, were strategic.</p>
<p>In a strongly worded statement after a meeting in Cairo on December 29, the Damascus Declaration states -- Syria, Egypt and the six members of the Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC) -- demanded that Iran withdraw from the islands in favour of the UAE which also claims them.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SYRIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAMASCUS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SYRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
