<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301703" id="root" date="1997-01-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korean union says no backing down over labour law.</title>
<headline>S.Korean union says no backing down over labour law.</headline>
<byline>Dean Yates</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-01-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean union leader Kwon Young-kil said on Sunday striking workers would not compromise even though the government appeared to be offering a peaceful solution to a three-week-old industrial crisis.</p>
<p>Speaking to Reuters in a makeshift tent pitched on the grounds of Seoul's Myongdong Cathedral where he and six other union leaders have sought sanctuary, Kwon said the spirits of striking workers were high.</p>
<p>Asked if strikers were ready to drop demands for the scrapping of a new labour law, the shaven-headed president of the outlawed Korean Confederation of Trade Unions said: &quot;No&quot;.</p>
<p>He said worker resolve and stamina were undiminished. &quot;There is no problem with that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>South Korea's ruling party chief Lee Hong-koo, in an apparent attempt to avoid more confrontation, challenged union leaders on Saturday to a televised debate over the law, which has sparked two weeks of nationwide strikes and growing international criticism.</p>
<p>Kwon later told a news conference: &quot;Without scrapping the new law we cannot accept the offer for a TV debate.&quot;</p>
<p>Leaders of the country's main union body, the Federation of Korean Trade Unions, have also brushed aside the offer.</p>
<p>Kwon said strikers would hold a rally in the grounds of the cathedral in central Seoul at 2.00 p.m. (0500 GMT).</p>
<p>He and other union leaders also met representatives of international labour groups to discuss the law, which allows companies to lay off workers and hire temporary staff to break strikes, shattering a jobs-for-life labour tradition.</p>
<p>Outside in freezing temperatures, strikers wielding iron bars and singing songs manned all entry points to the sacred grounds of the gothic cathederal to stop prosecutors from issuing arrest warrants to the seven unionists.</p>
<p>Unperturbed churchgoers picked their way through piles of rocks, firewood used by strikers to keep warm and other debris on their way to morning mass.</p>
<p>On Saturday night, thousands of riot police faced off against the workers near the cathedral but there were no incidents.</p>
<p>Earlier, about 20,000 workers calling for the resignation of President Kim Young-sam clashed with riot police in the most violent street protests since the labour bill was rammed through parliament on December 26.</p>
<p>John Evans, general secretary of the Trade Union Advisory Committee to the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), said he and other overseas labour leaders had not yet held talks with the government over the law.</p>
<p>They were due to meet Labour Minister Jin Nyum on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The OECD has said it would review the law on January 22. South Korea joined the Paris-based OECD last December.</p>
<p>Guy Ryder, who heads the Geneva office of the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions, said if the union leaders were arrested international pressure on Seoul would increase.</p>
<p>South Korean unions denounce the legislation as an &quot;evil law&quot;, and international labour organisations have said it is even harsher than the law it replaced. Seoul officials say the law is needed to rescue the economy from a worrying downturn.</p>
<p>Public opinion is seen as a make-or-break factor in the stoppages, which have closed car plants and disrupted hospitals. Unions have threatened the biggest strike in the nation's history next Tuesday and Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
