<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301887" id="root" date="1997-01-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French polemicist killed falling off bike.</title>
<headline>French polemicist killed falling off bike.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jean-Edern Hallier, 60, one of France's best-known and most controversial polemicists, was killed on Sunday falling off a bicycle in the chic Normandy resort of Deauville, police said.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear whether his death resulted from a blow to the head when he hit the ground or from a heart attack, police said.</p>
<p>Hallier, who was acclaimed as a talented novelist and who directed and featured in his own high-brow television literary show, also dabbled for over three decades in fields as separate as arts and politics.</p>
<p>Considered France's foremost provocateur, he was endlessly bogged down in libel trials directed against him or instituted by him as well as in occasional challenges to duels.</p>
<p>Alternately holding extreme rightist or, more often, extreme leftist positions, he tried to run for the French presidency in 1981 only to fail to garner the necessary number of sponsors' signatures. He ran, unsuccessfully, for the European Parliament in 1979.</p>
<p>The son of an army general, Hallier was best known recently for accusing the late Francois Mitterrand of seeking to have him murdered because he was first to reveal that the president was living with a woman other than his wife and had had an illegitimate daughter by her.</p>
<p>Since the revelation was published in Hallier's magazine &quot;The International Idiot&quot;, which specialised in outlandish reports, it went virtually unnoticed at the time.</p>
<p>Mitterrand later ceased to hide the special circumstances of his private life, and his widow and her rival attended his funeral side-by-side.</p>
<p>An inveterate attention-grabber, Hallier was once charged with staging his own kidnapping.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
