<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301894" id="root" date="1997-01-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss-Belgian round-the-world balloon takes off.</title>
<headline>Swiss-Belgian round-the-world balloon takes off.</headline>
<dateline>CHATEAU D'OEX, Switzerland 1997-01-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Swiss psychiatrist and a Belgian photographer took off from a snow-covered Alpine meadow on Sunday in a bid to become the first men to travel around the world in a hot air balloon.</p>
<p>As the silver-grey Breitling Orbiter balloon lifted skywards at 8.55 a.m. (0755 GMT), Bertrand Piccard and Wim Verstraeten were cheered by hundreds of onlookers including British tycoon Richard Branson, who failed in a similar bid last week.  </p>
<p>&quot;Pray for us, we'll need it,&quot; Piccard told the crowd from the top of the yellow, pressurised cabin under the balloon just minutes before the take-off as the sun rose over the surrounding mountains. Church bells rang as the balloon lifted off.</p>
<p>&quot;I wish I were going with them, but my wife won't let me,&quot; said a smiling Branson, whose own balloon crash landed in Algeria last week only a day after it took off from Morocco. &quot;But I wish them all the luck.&quot;</p>
<p>The 38-year-old Piccard, whose father and grandfather won world fame as explorers of the stratosphere and the ocean depths, and Verstraeten have already taken a balloon across the Atlantic together, in 1992.</p>
<p>If all goes well, their craft will rise to about 10,000 metres (30,000 feet) and head south before turning east and flying over Turkey, Afghanistan, China and Japan. They will then travel over the Pacific to the United States and finally across the Atlantic back to Europe. The voyage is expected to take about two weeks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHATEAU D'OEX, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
