<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301842" id="root" date="1997-01-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austrian leaders strike bank deal to end crisis.</title>
<headline>Austrian leaders strike bank deal to end crisis.</headline>
<byline>Steve Pagani</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-01-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austria's shaky coalition government stepped back from the brink of collapse on Sunday by settling a row over the privatisation of the most prestigious bank.</p>
<p>Social Democrat Chancellor Franz Vranitzky and conservative People's Party leader, Foreign Minister Wolfgang Schuessel, emerged from 11 hours of crisis talks clutching a piece of paper which ended the dispute that had threatened the survival of the year-old government.</p>
<p>&quot;As I said before the talks, there was no need to prepare a funeral dirge or compose a requiem (for the government),&quot; Vranitzky told reporters. &quot;We have shown...that the government is a unified body.&quot;</p>
<p>Vranitzky announced that the country's second biggest bank, Creditanstalt-Bankverein, long considered a power base of the People's Party, was to be sold to arch-rival Bank Austria.</p>
<p>The conservatives had opposed the winning bid for Creditanstalt going to Bank Austria, largely because it is indirectly controlled by the Social Democrats.</p>
<p>The prospect of the 141-year-old Creditanstalt, once the bank of the Habsburg emperors, falling under the control of &quot;leftists&quot; was too much for the conservatives to stomach.</p>
<p>But the Social Democrats accepted some key demands made by Schuessel, including the eventual privatisation of Bank Austria and the bank offering an attractive figure to buy out Creditanstalt's small shareholders.</p>
<p>Schuessel said he was satisfied with the outcome of the talks, but he cannot escape the fact that his party lost the main battle to stop Creditanstalt being sold to Bank Austria.</p>
<p>The seriousness of the government rift was palpable when the two parties began the day trading insults and calling for resignations.</p>
<p>Conservative chief whip Andreas Kohl said Vranitzky's style in setting the agenda for the talks &quot;made him want to vomit&quot; -- strong language for traditionally gentlemanly politicians.</p>
<p>Europe's longest privatisation, seven years in the making, was more than just selling off the state silver. It exposed cracks in a system of government that has prevailed in Austria since the Alpine republic returned to democracy at the end of World War Two.</p>
<p>Since 1945, the Social Democrats and the People's Party carved up the economy along party political lines in a system known as &quot;proporz&quot;, sharing control of banks and industry. There is even one motoring organisation for each party.</p>
<p>But as Austria began opening up its economy and with membership of the European Union two years ago, the old way of doing things had to change.</p>
<p>The emergency coalition committee was convened for the first time since a snap election in December 1995, called after the same two parties could not agree on big budget cuts to prepare Austria for European economic and monetary union.</p>
<p>With Joerg Haider's far right winning nearly the same number of votes as the two main parties in European elections last October, another early election could have handed him the power he has long craved.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
