<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301819" id="root" date="1997-01-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S., Caribbean at odds over drug war policy.</title>
<headline>U.S., Caribbean at odds over drug war policy.</headline>
<byline>Angus MacSwan</byline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1997-01-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>As Latin American drug gangs step up smuggling through the islands and sea lanes of the Caribbean, the United States and small countries of the region are at odds over measures to combat them.</p>
<p>Some Caribbean nations say Washington is using bullying tactics to push through accords that compromise their sovereignty and ignore their other problems.</p>
<p>The United States says fears it will ride roughshod over local sensibilities are a misunderstanding and the real threat comes from the narcotics traffickers.</p>
<p>But it wants more co-operation with Caribbean governments and has harshly criticised Jamaica in particular.</p>
<p>The matter has become more pressing for U.S. drug busters because traffickers are increasingly shipping their wares through the Caribbean.</p>
<p>&quot;All the action on the Mexican-U.S. border is putting a lot of pressure on the Colombian traffickers to use different routes,&quot; Felix Jimenez, the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) special agent for the Caribbean, told Reuters by telephone from Puerto Rico.</p>
<p>&quot;They are using the eastern Caribbean to bring drugs into Puerto Rico which is the gateway to the United States.&quot;</p>
<p>Narcotics agents are making large seizures every day in the eastern Caribbean, not only of cocaine but also heroin, which Colombian gangs are diversifying into, Jimenez said.</p>
<p>More than 100 gangs, mostly Colombian and several Dominican rings, are operating through the area, he said.</p>
<p>Smugglers in high-powered boats can dodge into a score of different territorial waters to evade capture and a key part of the anti-narcotics strategy is so-called &quot;ship-rider&quot; accords that would allow hot pursuit of suspected smugglers by U.S. agents into other states' territorial waters.</p>
<p>The United States has signed agreements with eight countries but Jamaica and Barbados have so far declined and it is still a touchy subject with the others.</p>
<p>Caribbean leaders met in Bridgetown, Barbados, last month and stressed they wanted to co-operate with the United States.</p>
<p>But in a blunt final communique they said: &quot;Unfounded allegations, innuendoes and the threat of punitive measures aimed at the economic welfare of Caribbean states would only weaken the collective effort against drug trafficking and undermine the foundations of good relations which the region has enjoyed and seeks to maintain with the United States.&quot;</p>
<p>They asked for a summit with U.S. President Bill Clinton early this year to discuss drug smuggling and related issues such as gun-running from the United States, which has led to an upsurge in violent crime, and other problems such as differences on trade quotas.</p>
<p>Joe Conroy, Coast Guard liaison officer with the U.S. State Department, said he believed there was a misperception in the Caribbean over the ship-rider agreements.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot feel we are infringing on their sovereignty. I think that's a misunderstanding,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>The agreements will allow hot pursuit of suspected vessels but do not mean random boarding of ships or patrolling of other countries' waters.</p>
<p>&quot;Frankly we see that as their job,&quot; Conroy said.</p>
<p>&quot;The drug smugglers are the real threat to their sovereignty. There really are a lot of ways for traffickers to evade us. It is not good for us. It is not good for those states. We are all the same side,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Treaties were still being negotiated with Jamaica and Barbados but &quot;we still have a way to go,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Patricia Hall, the State Department's director for Latin American and Caribbean drug enforcement programmes, raised hackles in Jamaica last month when she accused politicians there of having ties to traffickers.</p>
<p>She said Washington knew of at least one elected representative who had regular contacts with drug barons. The Jamaican government knew the people but refused to tackle them either out of fear or because &quot;the pool may be deeper than it appears,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>National Security Minister K.D. Knight told her to prove the allegations or shut up.</p>
<p>Jamaica is listed by the U.S. Narcotics Bureau as one of 30 major drugs producing and transit countries. It has been threatened with decertification as a drugs war ally, which could lead to cuts in aid, unless it makes more effort.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BARB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CARIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PURI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
