<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301867" id="root" date="1997-01-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Mixed bag of Euro allsorts loses CA.</title>
<headline>Mixed bag of Euro allsorts loses CA.</headline>
<byline>Elizabeth Fullerton</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-01-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A European hotchpotch of bidders for Austria's Creditanstalt made little effort to hide its disappointment on Sunday after Bank Austria pipped it to the post in the country's marathon privatisation.</p>
<p>The Austro-Italian-German consortium, initially established in early 1994 with the support of the conservative coalition government partner, was headed by insurer EA-Generali, the Austrian arm of Italy's insurance giant Assicurazioni Generali.</p>
<p>&quot;We regret the decision...We submitted the most attractive offer for the long-term good of Austria's economy,&quot; EA-Generali chief Dietrich Karner said in a tightly-worded statement.</p>
<p>The government finally struck a deal in the early hours of Sunday, ending seven years of wrangling over the sale, and awarded the country's most prestigious bank to the highest bidder Bank Austria, in line with European and Austrian law.</p>
<p>The consortium, which upped its final offer days before the final deadline to 14.3 billion schillings ($1.29 billion), still fell some three billion short of Bank Austria's bid.</p>
<p>However, EA-Generali may yet draw some crumbs of comfort from the reassurance on Sunday by Bank Austria chief Gerhard Randa that the insurer would remain &quot;a welcome partner&quot; following the takeover of Creditanstalt.</p>
<p>EA-Generali at present distributes its insurance products through Creditanstalt's branches.</p>
<p>EA-Generali is Austria's leading insurance company and has a strong presence in Germany and Eastern Europe. In 1995, group net premium income totalled 29.5 billion schillings.</p>
<p>The consortium's second frontline player was the Alpine republic's longest-serving credit institution -- Die Erste Oesterreichische Spar-Casse Bank, or First Austrian, set up in 1819.</p>
<p>The state had been trying to offload its 70 percent of Creditanstalt ordinary voting shares since 1990, making the sale Europe's longest to date. The consortium had submitted four bids in that period.</p>
<p>The rightist People's Party had threatened to leave the Social Democrat-led coalition if conservative stronghold Creditanstalt was sold to &quot;socialist&quot; Bank Austria.</p>
<p>Die Erste joined the group, whose Austrian interests also include beverage manufacturer Rauch, Europe's leading cardboard maker Mayr Melnhof, mortgage and insurance group Wuestenrot and Siemens Oesterreich, in May 1994.</p>
<p>Die Erste then left the consortium in September 1996 due to differences with the other members over what form the group's bid should take, only to join it again two months later.</p>
<p>The consortium also comprised Germany's third largest commercial bank Commerzbank.</p>
<p>The three remaining banks in the group were Mediobanca, Italy's leading merchant bank, Banca Commerciale Italiana, and Belgium's seventh largest bank Bacob.</p>
<p>The financial muscle of Union Bank of Switzerland strengthened EA-Generali's arm in the final round of bidding, allowing it to compete for the state's entire 70 percent voting stake with a view to placing a quarter over the stock market.</p>
<p>But EA-Generali saw its chances of winning slip away as the government stood by its resolution to award the tender to the highest bidder. ($1=11.09 Schilling)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
