<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="301915" id="root" date="1997-01-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Hindu party expects snap polls this year.</title>
<headline>India's Hindu party expects snap polls this year.</headline>
<byline>Clarence Fernandez</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-01-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's Hindu nationalists said on Sunday they were gearing up to strengthen the party organisation ahead of a general election they expect later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We have alerted all the party units to be prepared for polls in 1997,&quot; Lal Krishan Advani, president of the rightwing Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), told reporters.</p>
<p>BJP leaders who met in secret conclave near Bombay over the weekend said the measures included a school to train party workers and transparent new techniques to keep account of the donations that fund the party.</p>
<p>Advani said the 13-party United Front federal government led by Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda was very shaky.</p>
<p>&quot;They are squabbling with each other all the time,&quot; Advani said. &quot;It is tottering all the while. So our evaluation is that this may not last the whole year of 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>Deve Gowda's coalition comprises 13 political parties of all stripes, from free traders to communists.</p>
<p>It is propped up by India's oldest political party, the Congress, which suffered its worst defeat in inconclusive national polls last year, following numerous scandals. The polls returned the BJP as the single largest party but short of a majority.</p>
<p>&quot;In view of the fragmented Lok Sabha (lower house), and the fact that neither the largest party nor the second largest party are in the government, the government is shaky,&quot; Advani said.</p>
<p>The BJP, which has 161 seats in the 525-member lower house, held power for 13 days in 1996, but resigned after it was unable to prove a majority in parliament.</p>
<p>Many analysts say this forced it to face the fact that no major political party was willing to ally itself with the BJP, which avowedly has a fiercely nationalistic Hindu agenda.</p>
<p>At the end of a lengthy campaign by the BJP in 1992, Hindu zealots pulled down a 16th century Moslem mosque in northern Ayodhya, believed by many to be located at the birthplace of the Hindu god Ram. Thousands died in the fierce riots that followed.</p>
<p>Though Advani accused the BJP's enemies of banding together to keep it out of power, he said the party suffered from organisational weaknesses and needed to be strengthened.</p>
<p>&quot;The BJP is a tiger caged by itself,&quot; Advani said. &quot;The party suffers from weaknesses of organisation and behaviour.&quot;</p>
<p>The three-day conclave identified the directions and methods by which these deficiencies could be removed, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We see indiscipline as an organisational weakness,&quot; Advani said. &quot;We are in the process of putting into place a grievance redressal mechanism.&quot;</p>
<p>The BJP saw its state government in western Gujarat collapse in 1996, a victim of internal dissent, which also threatens the survival of its government in the desert state of Rajasthan.</p>
<p>The 33 senior leaders who attended the conclave tentatively decided to set up a school to train party activists. &quot;It will have a regular syllabus,&quot; Advani said, but gave no more details.</p>
<p>As part of what Advani called the BJP's commitment to probity in public life, the party plans to sign on a number of &quot;lifelong associates&quot; who will donate sums ranging from 1,000 rupees to 10,000 rupees annually.</p>
<p>&quot;Thus the entire process of raising funds for the party becomes transparent and above board,&quot; Advani said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
