<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="302022" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: H.B. Fuller seeks higher sales in 1997.</title>
<headline>H.B. Fuller seeks higher sales in 1997.</headline>
<dateline>ST. PAUL, Minn. 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>H.B. Fuller Co, a manufacturer and marketer of adhesives, sealants, coatings, paints and other specialty chemical products, said Monday that a key objective in 1997 is to improve sales.</p>
<p>&quot;This will be a challenge given the fact some economies around the world are experiencing various degrees of weakness. However, we have set aggressive goals for ourselves and are working hard to achieve them,&quot; Walter Kissling, president and chief executive officer, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Beginning in 1996, the company's international operations were shifted from a September 30 year-end to correspond with the company's fiscal November 30 year-end. Net sales for fourth quarter 1996 were $333.8 million, up 2.2 percent from restated fourth quarter l995 sales of $326.8 million.</p>
<p>Sales at North American operations in fourth quarter 1996 rose six percent compared to a restated fourth quarter 1995.</p>
<p>Sales at European operations fell one percent for the fourth quarter from a restated prior-year period. Latin American operations had a four percent decline in sales in the fourth quarter compared to the restated fourth quarter 1995.</p>
<p>Asia/Pacific sales were down one percent in the fourth quarter compared to restated fourth quarter 1995, primarily due to a 5 percentage point negative currency impact.</p>
<p>H.B. Fuller reported earnings for its fiscal 1996 fourth quarter ended November 30, 1996, rose 50 percent while per share earnings increased 47 percent. H.B. Fuller said results continue to benefit from actions taken to increase gross margins and reduce operating expenses.</p>
<p>Net earnings were $12.3 million or $0.87 a share for fourth quarter 1996 compared to restated fourth quarter 1995 earnings of $8.2 million or $0.59.</p>
<p>		  ((Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. PAUL, Minn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
