<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="302048" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hoechst says will fight withdrawal of allergy drug.</title>
<headline>Hoechst says will fight withdrawal of allergy drug.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo. 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hoechst Marion Roussel, a unit of Hoechst AG, said Monday it will not take Seldane, an antihistamine, off the market and will defend the drug against the U.S. Food and Drug Administration's proposal to withdraw approval of the allergy treatment.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not intend to withdraw Seldane from the marketplace and we will respond with the request to go into the hearing process,&quot; said Charles Rouse, director of communications for Hoechst's U.S. operations.  </p>
<p>Earlier today, the FDA said that due to the risk of serious cardiac effects when using Seldane (terfenadine) improperly, and the recent approval of Allegra, which contains fexofenadine that has the same benefits as terfenadine but not the risks, the agency has determined that drugs with terfenadine are no longer safe. Hoechst also markets Allegra.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to challenge that action. We intend to aggressively defend our product and continue to stand behind the safety of Seldane -- and the millions of patients who have found symptom relief from its use,&quot; he said in an interview.  </p>
<p>Seldane is safe and effective when used in accordance with the product labeling, he said.</p>
<p>Rouse said &quot;The FDA has put the ball in our court and has said we have 30 days to respond ... whether we intend to withdraw it from the market or whether we would request a hearing and we will respond with the request to go into the hearing process.&quot;</p>
<p>		((Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
