<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="302348" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - European stocks rally with Wall Street.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - European stocks rally with Wall Street.</headline>
<byline>Malcolm Davidson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>German and French shares climbed to record highs on Monday, bolstered by Wall Street's continued strength and a rebound in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Tokyo shares leapt 4.75 percent following sharp losses last week, while London's FTSE 100 index regained the 4,100 level as fears receded of an imminent rise in British interest rates.</p>
<p>Wall Street followed through on Friday's record close by rising further in early trade. The Dow Jones Industrial Average was up 12 points at 2,953 at 1500 GMT.</p>
<p>On foreign exchange markets, the dollar maintained its firm tone after the rally in Tokyo stocks lent some support.</p>
<p>The recovery in Tokyo's Nikkei 225 index helped stem worries that Japanese institutions could be forced to liquidate overseas bond and equity holdings to boost their capital ratios.</p>
<p>Wall Street's Friday performance provided the major early impetus to European stock markets, giving the Paris bourse the shove required for it join London and Frankfurt in the record territory where they have been for months.</p>
<p>France's CAC-40 index hit a high of 2,371.38 points, easily surpassing the previous trading peak of 2,360.98 set in February 1994 and underlining the recent strength of the French market, which has lagged its main European rivals.</p>
<p>Although the market later slipped off its highs, the blue chip CAC-40 index was still up nearly 1.5 percent at 2,361 points at 1500 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;The bourse is swept up by Wall Street, by the bond markets and by expectations of higher corporate results in France for 1997,&quot; said Jean-Pierre Filbien, director of sales at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in Paris.</p>
<p>Christian Mariais, a portfolio manager at Paris brokerage Oddo, said the Dow's performance had reassurred investors who feared Wall Street's bull run was faltering.</p>
<p>Among the big gainers was luxury goods group LVMH, which hit a high of 1,445 francs before slipping back to 1,433 for a rise on the day of 1.78 percent. The company announced on Saturday it had completed the acquisition of duty free chain DFS.</p>
<p>German shares also opened bourse trade at record highs before trading was disrupted by technical problems.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index ended floor trade firm, buoyed by Wall Street, the stronger dollar and German debt market. The DAX index of leading German shares ended up 21.56 points or 0.73 percent at 2,954.95, but off its trading high of 2,961.25.</p>
<p>Tame inflation data in Britain, which the market saw lessening the prospect of an early rate rise, helped push London stocks sharply higher.</p>
<p>The FTSE 100 index surged nearly 50 points to regain the 4,100 level before investors pegged it back a few points in the afternoon session.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets seem to have gone haywire,&quot; said the head of equity sales at one top investment bank. &quot;Whether this is the final topside blowoff we've been expecting I don't know.&quot;</p>
<p>British government securities remained strong in the wake of December producer price (PPI) data, which showed core factory gate prices up just 0.1 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Chancellor wants to keep interest rates steady...this morning's PPIs give him useful ammunition with which to argue his case,&quot; said Jeremy Hawkins, economist at Bank of America.</p>
<p>Chancellor Kenneth Clarke will meet Bank of England governor Eddie George on Wednesday to discuss monetary policy. The latest monthly Merrill Lynch survey found fund managers were taking a neutral view towards British shares, with a strong pound and fears of higher interest rates countering optimism for economic growth.</p>
<p>Interest rate concerns also looked set to keep the dollar firm. A rise of 262,000 in U.S. non-farm payrolls in December, reported on Friday, helped fire interest rate rise fever as earnings data set inflation alarm bells ringing.</p>
<p>Widening U.S.-German yield spreads and its resilience to credit market gyrations were buoying the U.S. unit, analysts said.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1500 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was trading at 116.17 yen and 1.5871 marks compared with 115.96 and 1.5855 late in Europe on Friday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1230 GMT</p>
<p>LONDON - The FTSE 100 index was up 45.9 points, or 1.13 percent, at 4,102.5.</p>
<p>PARIS - The CAC-40 share index was up 34.20 points, or 1.47 percent, at 2,361.70.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - The 30-share DAX index closed floor trade up 21.56 points, or 0.73 percent, at 2,954.95. In late electronic trade, the IBIS DAX was up 36.75 at 2.952.57.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold was fixed unchanged from the morning at $359.60. Silver was down two cents at $4.75.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
