<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="302419" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ SPORT - CRICKET - Atherton watches video to sort out woes.</title>
<headline>NZ SPORT - CRICKET - Atherton watches video to sort out woes.</headline>
<text>
<p>Palmerston North, Jan 14 - England cricket coach David Lloyd and skipper Mike Atherton will turn to video in a bid to find a solution to Atherton's batting woes, NZPA reports.</p>
<p>Atherton's miserable run of form in Zimbabwe carried into New Zealand yesterday when the opening batsman was dismissed for seven in England's first innings against the New Zealand Selection 11 at Fitzherbert Park.</p>
<p>It was the one disappointment on an otherwise highly satisfying day for the tourists.  </p>
<p>After dismissing the Selection 11 for 138 in their first innings, England had reached 106 for three by stumps, with Alec Stewart unbeaten on 40 and opener Nick Knight making a compact 46.</p>
<p>Atherton made 196 runs in 13 innings in Zimbabwe and has three innings left to find his touch before the first test against New Zealand in Auckland next week.</p>
<p>Yesterday a luckless Atherton received a fine delivery from New Zealand fast-medium bowler Robert Kennedy to be leg before wicket.  </p>
<p>Atherton lasted 14 balls, but Lloyd has had the video camera out and the pair will study what they see for an answer.</p>
<p>&quot;I did some video work which we've had a look at,&quot; Lloyd said.</p>
<p>&quot;When players get out of form you always look at two key areas, head position and foot position.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a little bit of work to do on both. If the feet and the head are in the wrong place you've got to be working very hard to get the bat coming down in a straight plane.&quot;</p>
<p>Lloyd has no doubts Atherton, who has scored 4661 runs in 64 tests including 10 centuries, will come good.  </p>
<p>The key issue is whether it will come in time for him to be a decisive figure in the test series.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got to be patient, we've got to give him every confidence that runs will come -- and they will,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The pick of the England batsmen yesterday was Stewart.</p>
<p>He looked in good form during his 105 minutes at the crease.</p>
<p>For Stewart it was the continuation of an outstanding 1996, during which he scored more test runs than any other player in the game.  </p>
<p>After starting the year with his test place in real danger -- then being overlooked for the first international of the summer against India -- Stewart scored 793 runs in eight tests.</p>
<p>Yesterday he was solid and assured and looked set to carry on where he left off in Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>The English bowlers gave Lloyd plenty of satisfaction yesterday, dismissing a good standard New Zealand Selection batting lineup in 58.4 overs.</p>
<p>Allrounder Craig White flew into Palmerston North on Sunday morning after a few days break in Australia, and immediately made an impact.  </p>
<p>He took four for 15 in 9.4 overs to put his hand up for a first test spot.</p>
<p>The other three fast-medium bowlers all had success, but Danny Morrison and Kennedy made sure it wasn't all one-way traffic.</p>
<p>Morrison got through 10 impressive overs taking two for 20 in what was effectively a personal fitness trial for the first test.</p>
<p>Kennedy, too, showed some of his best form of the season in taking one for 30 in eight encouraging overs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
