<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="302464" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ETHIOPIA: Somali group wants arms flow to Aideed stopped.</title>
<headline>Somali group wants arms flow to Aideed stopped.</headline>
<dateline>ADDIS ABABA 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Somalia's National Salvation Council (NSC) on Monday appealed to the U.N. Security Council to prevent the shipment of what it described as a large quantity of arms to leading faction leader Hussein Aideed.</p>
<p>In a statement issued from its Addis Ababa office, the NSC said it had received &quot;reliable information that a great quantity of arms and counterfeit Somali shilling banknotes shipped out of Hong Kong was heading towards the port of Merca, controlled by (the) Hussein Aideed faction.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If these goods fall in the hands of those who reject peace and pursue a course of war and destruction in Somalia, it is very clear that the Somali people will suffer more devastation,&quot; the statement added.</p>
<p>&quot;The introduction of counterfeit currency in Somalia will also no doubt wreck whatever little remains of the Somali economy,&quot; said the statement addressed to the Security Council.</p>
<p>The NSC repeated its appeal to Aideed to desist from all acts of violence and join the peace effort for Somalia.</p>
<p>The NSC was formed recently in Ethiopia by 26 Somali faction leaders with authority to form a provisional central government. Aideed boycotted the meeting and condemned those who attended it.</p>
<p>Aideed, a 34-year-old former U.S. Marine who succeeded his father Mohamed Farah Aideed on his death last August, was elected Somali president by his supporters. But he and his government are rejected by most other factions.</p>
<p>Somalia has been without central authority since 1991 when factions led by Mohamed Farah Aideed and his rival Ali Mahdi Mohamed ousted dictator Mohammed Siad Barre.</p>
<p>Guns of all kinds are easily available on Somalia streets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ETHPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SOMAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADDIS ABABA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ETHIOPIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
