<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="302482" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAfrica mulls power station sell-offs, unions wary.</title>
<headline>SAfrica mulls power station sell-offs, unions wary.</headline>
<byline>Vera von Lieres</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Power utility Eskom has moved into the limelight as South Africa's privatisation drive slowly gains momentum, with plans to sell mothballed stations at the centre of a clash with unions.</p>
<p>Eskom chief executive Allen Morgan believes government proposals to sell decommissioned stations could inject new competition into the South African market and bring foreign expertise on board.</p>
<p>But unions are concerned about jobs and the potential loss of state control in a vital sector of the economy.</p>
<p>Morgan said no decisions had been taken but benefits could flow to consumers.</p>
<p>&quot;We are busy developing options around the proposals. No decision has been made yet, but we are making progress...we are looking at different alternatives for the decommissioned stations,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Government, unions and Eskom will try to settle fundamental differences on the approach to restructuring the electricity giant once again on Tuesday after labour walked out of Eskom's Restructuring and Transformation Committee earlier this month.</p>
<p>The unions raised concerns about the possible sale of mothballed power stations or recommissioning of decommissioned plants; a planned outsourcing deal between Eskom and IBM; an internal regrouping of management within Eskom; and the structuring of the electricity distribution sector.</p>
<p>Morgan said the sale of the three decommissioned stations - Ingagane, Highveld and Taaibos - could benefit South Africa in providing the skills and know-how of a foreign partner.</p>
<p>A foreign company would hopefully be able to squeeze a dividend out of the operation and customers would benefit by the presence of more plants, producing power at a competitive rate.</p>
<p>He said the driving force in evaluating various options had to be whether South African consumers would gain.</p>
<p>&quot;The considerations that drive the initiative should be whether introducing a partner will benefit the South African consumer...not just introducing a private partner for privatisation sake,&quot; Morgan said.</p>
<p>Alternatives to an outright sale of the power stations could include a foreign party recommissioning the stations and obtaining a licence to operate them on a joint venture basis.</p>
<p>&quot;We wanted to see if, by bringing in new technology or by bringing in partners, we couldn't salvage the stations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Morgan said Eskom itself had no plans to bring the decommissioned power stations back into commission.</p>
<p>President Nelson Mandela's government has committed itself to the privatisation or restructuring of state corporations but progress so far has been slow.</p>
<p>However, government on Friday announced that investment bank BOE NatWest and law firm Moseneke and Partners had been appointed jointly to advise it on the privatisation of domestic airline Sun Air -- seen as an important step forward in the privatisation programme.</p>
<p>Sun Air is one of seven public sector corporations Public Enterprises Minister Stella Sigcau has said will be at least partly privatised by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>Strategic equity stakes are to be sold in telecommunications utility Telkom, the Airports Company which runs South Africa's major airports and forestry group Safcol.</p>
<p>The first major sale of state assets is expected in the next three months with the planned sale of up to 30 percent in Telkom.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
