<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="302408" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Shell picks options for Brent Spar disposal.</title>
<headline>Shell picks options for Brent Spar disposal.</headline>
<byline>Richard Mably</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anglo-Dutch oil giant Royal Dutch/Shell selected six engineering companies on Monday to produce plans for getting rid of the Brent Spar oil rig ranging from simple scrapping to using it for fish farming.</p>
<p>Shell has asked the contractors to make detailed proposals for a total of 11 different disposal ideas after a campaign led by the environmental group Greenpeace in 1995 scuppered its plans to ditch the platform in the Atlantic ocean.</p>
<p>&quot;The proposals now to be developed represent the best of those we were offered, while also maintaining a good range of potential solutions,&quot; said Eric Faulds, decommissioning manager for Shell Expro, which operates in the North Sea on behalf of Shell and Exxon.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an exciting competition and still wide open,&quot; he said. &quot;We genuinely do not know what the eventual solution will be.&quot;</p>
<p>Since the high-profile Greenpeace campaign and a consumer boycott of Shell, the company has staged a public relations blitz after admitting it failed to take into account the strength of public opinion on the issue.</p>
<p>Brent Spar is moored in a Norwegian fjord and Shell hopes that decommissioning can get underway in early 1998.</p>
<p>The contractors, whittled down from 19, have until the end of April to make bids for alternatives to the deep sea disposal which the British government approved almost two years ago.</p>
<p>Norway's Kvaerner Stolt Seaway Alliance (KSSA), Brown and Root of the United States, and a joint venture between Germany's Thyssen and Norway's Aker NC all proposed onshore disposal at yards in Britain or Norway.</p>
<p>KSSA and Britain's Alfred McAlpine, in a joint venture with France's Doris, suggested using Brent Spar for quay extension projects. Britain's AMEC proposed using sections of the rig in a coastal defence scheme planned for the east coast of England.</p>
<p>KSSA and a joint venture between Britain's John D. Wood and Norway's GMC identified potential clients interested in using the top of the platform for offshore training facilities.</p>
<p>KSSA also submitted late proposals for conversion into a floating dry dock gate and for a fish farm development.</p>
<p>Shell rejected a number of other possibilities from an original list of 30, including conversion to a wind and wave generating plant and use as a coastal tourist centre.</p>
<p>Shell must persuade the British government that any alternative solution -- balancing safety, technical feasibility, economics, environmental impact and public acceptability -- is better than deep sea disposal.</p>
<p>&quot;The focus of our effort is to find a solution which is at least as good or better than deep sea disposal,&quot; said Shell Expro Managing Director Heinz Rothermund. &quot;This remains the benchmark for comparison before we again make a recommendation to the government for approval.&quot;</p>
<p>Shell said any proposal other than deep sea disposal would require a difficult operation to lift the 14,500 tonnne platform from the water, either by replacing water in tanks with compressed gas or by placing a lifting cradle under the rig and jacking it out of the water from barges alongside.</p>
<p>Rothermund said independent specialists would be asked to review the detailed proposals and a final recommendation for the British government should be ready by the end of this year.</p>
<p>Faulds said the cost of preparing the 11 proposals would be about 1-1.5 million pounds ($1.7 million-$2.5 million).</p>
<p>Faulds estimated Shell would have spent almost 20 million pounds on Spar's disposal even before awarding a final contract.</p>
<p>The company has been paying 20,000 pounds a month in rent to keep the rig parked in the fjord. It had already spent 10 million pounds on disposal before the public outcry forced it to back down on the original plans for dumping at sea. ($1=.5974 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
