<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="302535" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbian student protestors win more backing.</title>
<headline>Serbian student protestors win more backing.</headline>
<byline>Jovan Kovacic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgrade students, protesting for eight weeks against election fraud, scored a victory on Monday when senior academics, led by a prominent ruling socialist, backed protests against election fraud.</p>
<p>The Belgrade University governing board &quot;supports the students' demands accepted by the Serbian deputy prime ministers and urges fulfillment of the commitments undertaken by them,&quot; Rector Dragutin Velickovic said.</p>
<p>He was speaking to reporters after a session of the board which comprises deans from all Belgrade University colleges.</p>
<p>The opposition Zajedno coalition claims it won 14 of Serbia's 18 largest cities, including the capital Belgrade, in November 17 local elections. International observors have backed their stand</p>
<p>The cancellation of the victories by the ruling Socialists, who claimed unspecified irregularities, triggered a continuing wave of daily street protests by Belgrade students and Zajedno supporters.</p>
<p>The highly imaginative, peaceful mass protests, echoed recently in neighbouring Bulgaria, have turned into the most serious challenge to leftist rule in Serbia since 1945.</p>
<p>Two Serbian deputy prime ministers agreed on Saturday to student demands for recognition of opposition election victories, access to state media, and Velickovic's dismissal.</p>
<p>Deputy prime ministers Ratko Markovic and Nedeljko Sipovac also told the students that those who rigged elections would be punished and they criticised state media as incompetent.</p>
<p>Velickovic, a Socialist Party (SPS) appointee, was against the student protest, pitting himself against most of the deans.</p>
<p>The board did not discuss Velickovic's sacking but referred a decision to the University Teachers Council which meets on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Political sources said his dismissal was highly likely, as the easiest student demand for the SPS to fulfil.</p>
<p>The board said &quot;students will not bear any consequences for taking part in the protests but must return to classes once their demands were fulfilled.&quot;</p>
<p>Senior political sources suggested President Slobodan Milosevic and his ruling SPS and allied neo-communist Yugoslav United Left party, under immense pressure from outside and inside the country, might accept all demands to save face.</p>
<p>&quot;The students are giving them a way out. They will not appear to be succumbing to the opposition which has identical demands except for the (sacking of the) rector,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
