<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="302696" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian deficit prompts economic emergency.</title>
<headline>Colombian deficit prompts economic emergency.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombia's President Ernesto Samper declared an economic emergency Monday to fight the central government's yawning fiscal deficit, national radio reported.</p>
<p>The emergency powers will last for an initial period of 30 days and can be extended for a maximum 90 days. The government deficit in 1996 was 4.0 percent of gross domestic product.  </p>
<p>The country's main radio stations said Samper declared the emergency after a four-hour meeting with his cabinet. It is not yet clear what precise measures Samper will announce.</p>
<p>He is due to give a televised speech at 8 pm (0100 GMT) in which he is expected to address the issue. Finance Minister Jos Antonio Ocampo has called a press conference for 8:30 pm (0130 GMT) in which he is expected to announce specific measures.</p>
<p>Colombia's economic emergency laws give the president powers that include firing public sector employees en masse and cutting out layers of bureaucracy without the previous approval of Congress.</p>
<p>It is the second time an economic emergency has been declared since a new constitution was ratified in 1991.</p>
<p>President Csar Gaviria called an emergency in 1992 when many of the country's dams dried up, sparking severe power shortages. Some 80 percent of  Colombia's electricity is generated by hydro-electric power.</p>
<p>((--Karl Penhaul, Bogota newsroom 571 610 7944))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
