<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="302713" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil shares pare losses, but still end weaker.</title>
<headline>Brazil shares pare losses, but still end weaker.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil stocks pared early losses, but still ended weaker as the PMDB party's vote against a bill allowing presidential re-election dashed market hopes for its quick passage in Congress, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Bovespa index of the 49 most traded shares fell 665 points or 0.89 percent to close at 74,118 points. Market volume was a moderate 439.7 million reais ($422.1 million).</p>
<p>President Fernando Henrique Cardoso suffered a blow in his campaign to stand for a second term after the PMDB decided on Sunday not to vote until February 15 on the re-election bill.  </p>
<p>The market reacted with disappointment, but analysts are still confident that re-election will be approved sooner or later.</p>
<p>&quot;I only see a delay in the process. The positive outlook for re-election has not changed,&quot; said Antonio Carlos Castrucci, president of Banco Paulista.</p>
<p>Analysts also said setbacks in the re-election debate should not catch investors by surprise.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's first reaction is negative. But we could not expect the re-election to be approved so easily,&quot; said Claudio Lellis, Banco Pontual's financial vice-president.  </p>
<p>Lellis said he never thought the re-election amendment would be approved in January, as the most optimistic analysts expected, adding that he does not see the voting process ending before April. He also said today's losses on the bolsa were natural after the market's recent rally.</p>
<p>Benchmark Telebras fell 1.62 percent to close at 85.10 reais, while its common stock dropped 1.51 percent, ending at 78.40 reais.</p>
<p>The Sao Paulo bourse's power sector index, comprising the nine most liquid stocks of the electrical sector, ended off 0.43 percent to 2,132 points.</p>
<p>((--Fatima Cristina, Sao Paulo Newsroom, 5511 2485412))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
