<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="302899" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel says Hebron accord can be signed Tuesday.</title>
<headline>Israel says Hebron accord can be signed Tuesday.</headline>
<byline>Wafa Amr</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai predicted on Monday the elusive Hebron deal with the PLO would be signed on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I predict this accord will be signed tomorrow,&quot; Mordechai told Israel Television on his way into a meeting between Israeli and Palestinian negotiators at a Jerusalem hotel.</p>
<p>An Israeli handover of 80 percent of Hebron has seemed within reach many times in recent months but concerns for the security of the West Bank town's 400 Jews and 100,000 Arabs -- along with other issues -- have delayed an agreement.</p>
<p>Palestinian negotiators attended an emergency cabinet meeting in Gaza during a recess in talks with the Israelis, then returned to Jerusalem. The cabinet said in a statement at the end of the meeting:</p>
<p>&quot;The Palestinian leadership will remain in constant meetings to follow up negotiations in the hope to conclude the drafting of the agreement as soon as possible.&quot;</p>
<p>A U.S. official said Middle East envoy Dennis Ross was considering returning to Washington on Tuesday after weeks of mediating between Israel and the PLO if the agreement was not finished by then.</p>
<p>Mediation on Sunday by Jordan's King Hussein removed a key negotiating block. Under the compromise -- proposed by both Egypt and Jordan -- Israel will complete three troop withdrawals from other, mostly rural occupied West Bank areas by mid-1998.</p>
<p>The PLO had been reluctant to sign an accord without a commitment from Israel to carry out the additional West Bank pullbacks agreed in previous peace deals.</p>
<p>An upbeat Mordechai said the army could redeploy quickly after the accord was signed.</p>
<p>&quot;The army is ready, all the plans have been completed and in a very very short time we can redeploy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked whether opposition to the deal within Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government would pose an obstacle, Mordechai said:</p>
<p>&quot;It will pass. I don't think there is a problem. We worked very hard during the last few months to conclude everything and fix it, and now we need to sign, especially since all the people in the area expect us to sign.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. Consul-General to Jerusalem Edward Abington said the talks late on Monday could lead to a summit meeting between Netanyahu and Palestinian President Yasser Arafat in which they would sign the accord.</p>
<p>&quot;We are continuing to work on issues,&quot; he said. &quot;We are resolving them little by little and hopefully by tonight we will be in a position to make arrangements for a meeting.&quot;</p>
<p>In Washington, White House spokesman Mike McCurry said President Bill Clinton had telephoned Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak on Sunday &quot;to exchange views with him on the status of the dialogue&quot; and get Mubarak's insights &quot;into the thinking of those who are negotiating&quot;.</p>
<p>Cautioning reporters against being over-optimistic, McCurry said: &quot;This is a process that requires hard work. Some progress has been made but there are differences that remain between the parties.&quot;</p>
<p>News of an imminent agreement angered members of Netanyahu's right-wing cabinet and Jewish settler leaders who want to hold on to the lands occupied since the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
<p>At least seven ministers in Netanyahu's 18-member cabinet were expected to oppose the deal. Jewish settlers warned the handover would lead to bloodshed in the town holy to Moslems and Jews as the burial place of the biblical Abraham.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
