<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="303076" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. analysts unfazed by Brazil vote delay.</title>
<headline>U.S. analysts unfazed by Brazil vote delay.</headline>
<byline>Nailene Chou Wiest</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The delay of the vote to amend Brazil's constitution so that President Fernando Henrique Cardoso could run for a second term has not rattled U.S. investors' confidence in prospects for Brazil's reform, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a temporary setback,&quot; said Paolo Leme, senior international economist at Goldman Sachs, who expected the amendment to pass sometime in the second quarter.  </p>
<p>The delay is not surprising for market watchers who are familiar with the protracted process of political bargaining in Brazil, and the large Brazilian Demcractic Movement Party (PMDB) is expected to extract the most advantage in the pivotal vote, he said.</p>
<p>The Lower House committee on Sunday delayed the vote on re-election reform until February 15.</p>
<p>Richard Segal, director of emerging market fixed income research at Santander Investments, was not surprised at the procrastination, saying: &quot;It's the same politics as usual.&quot;  </p>
<p>The delay is sobering to the investors who have been overly optimistic that the re-election vote would breeze through the Congress, he said, pointing out that the polls showed the government was far from mustering the required votes.</p>
<p>According to a local poll published on Sunday, the government was more than 100 votes short of the 308 lower house votes it needed to approve re-election.</p>
<p>Segal expected the re-election amendment to clear through Congress no earlier than in the coming second quarter.</p>
<p>Brazil Brady bond prices slipped on Monday but the overall losses were moderate, traders said.  </p>
<p>&quot;C bond is under pressure,&quot; said a trader, noting that the weekend news apparently inspired some traders to short the more liquid papers.</p>
<p>At 1300 EST/1800 GMT, Brazil C fell 3/4 to bid at 73-3/4, and Discount Z slipped 1/2 to 78.00 bid, while Brazil Pars was off 1/8 to 62-1/2 bid.</p>
<p>The trader expected continued volatility in Brazil debt until President Cardoso's bid for re-election becomes clearer.  </p>
<p>The intense bargaining ahead of the vote would focus on getting a higher profile for PMDB candidates in the coming election and more ministerial posts in Cardoso's second term, as well as allowing some of the future revenues of a soon-to-be privatized mining company to be reinvested locally, Leme said .</p>
<p>Leme admitted that fiscal reform had not proceeded as speedily as expected, and the uncertainty over Cardoso's re-election would further delay the process.</p>
<p>The re-election amendment, if passed in the second quarter, would allow the Congress to concentrate on the fiscal reform and privatization in the second half of the year, he said.</p>
<p>Privatization at both the federal and the state level would be a major theme. Leme estimated that some $12 billion worth of assets would be sold this year.</p>
<p>Brazil debts are likely to be under pressure in the near term due to the politically inspired jitters, Segal said.</p>
<p>But if the reform momentum resumes later, Brazil could do better than Argentina and Mexico, he said.</p>
<p>((-- 212-859-1674))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
