<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="303008" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX heat ends sharply lower on weather forecasts.</title>
<headline>NYMEX heat ends sharply lower on weather forecasts.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX oil prices went into a tailspin Monday after forecasts of warmer temperatures in the U.S. Northeast triggered a sell-off in heating oil.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices started to break down as soon as forecasts for warmer weather came out. Heating oil then led us down most of the day,&quot; said Ed Kevelson, director of refined products for Paribas Futures Inc in New York.</p>
<p>February heating oil settled off 2.45 cents a gallon at 69.70 cents. Pressured by heating oil's sharp declines, Feb crude settled off 90 cents a barrel at $25.19 while Feb gasoline settled off 2.27 cents a gallon at 68.09 cents.  </p>
<p>In the key heating oil market of the northeastern United States, temperatures are forecasted to warm to normal Tuesday through Thursday before a cold snap is expected to send temperatures eight to 10 degrees below normal during the weekend, said Charlie Notis, meteorologist with Freese-Notis Weather in Des Moines, Iowa.</p>
<p>But, temperatures are seen rising from lower levels again next week when they will fluctuate between normal and slightly below normal levels, Notis said.  </p>
<p>By late next week, a cold airmass will move across the Midwest into the Northeast, but the cold front will be weaker than the one experienced by the Northeast this past weekend, said meteorologist Jon Davis of Smith Barney in Chicago.</p>
<p>Traders said February crude's declines were steepened after prompt crude fell below key technical support of $26.00, igniting sell stops.</p>
<p>Despite Monday's price dive, dealers were not yet ready to say February crude has peaked after making a life-of-contract high of $26.74 on January 9.</p>
<p>&quot;One day does not make a trend,&quot; said William Brown, president of trading firm W.H. Brown &amp; Co in New York, adding crude's price was at a crossroads after not being able to stay above $26.00.</p>
<p>&quot;But, in the next couple of weeks, we should know whether crude has entered a higher trading range set in 1996 or if it's going back to $18.00,&quot; said Brown.</p>
<p>At last November's meeting of the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) in Vienna, Middle East Gulf sources said OPEC members, including Saudia Arabia, expected North Sea Brent crude, the world benchmark, to continue in a $20 to $25 a barrel range in 1997.</p>
<p>Apart from a spike in crude oil prices due to the 1990 Gulf War, Brent had been in a range of $15 to $20 for the last 10 years.</p>
<p>NYMEX light sweet crude usually trades at a $1.00 to $2.00 premium to Brent.</p>
<p>-- Harry Milling, New York Energy Desk, 212-859-1761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
