<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="303114" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton decorates black Second World War heroes.</title>
<headline>Clinton decorates black Second World War heroes.</headline>
<byline>Gene Gibbons</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seven Black American heroes of the Second World War received long-delayed recognition on Monday as U.S. President Bill Clinton presented them with the nation's highest award for bravery in combat, the Medal of Honour.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a great day. We've all been vindicated,&quot; said Vernon Baker, 77, of St. Maries, Idaho, the only one of the seven men still alive, after receiving a medal previously withheld from African-Americans who fought in the 1941-45 conflict.</p>
<p>Baker, an unassuming, soft-spoken man credited with killing nine German soldiers and knocking out several enemy positions in fierce fighting near Viareggio, Italy, in 1945, said of his valor: &quot;I was a soldier and I had a job to do.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;No African-American who deserved the Medal of Honour for his service in World War II received it,&quot; Clinton said at a crowded White House ceremony. &quot;Today we fill the gap in that picture and give a group of heroes who also loved peace, but adapted themselves to war, the tribute that has always been their due.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition to Baker, the men honoured were Edward Carter Jr., John Fox, Willy James Jr., Ruben Rivers and Charles Thomas, all of whom fought in Europe, and George Watson, who was killed in action in the Pacific.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we recognise seven men as being among the bravest of the brave,&quot; Clinton added. &quot;Today America is profoundly thankful for the patriotism and the nobility of these men and for the example they set, which helped us to find a way to become a more just, more free nation.&quot;</p>
<p>Among those at the East Room ceremony were retired Army Gen. Colin Powell, who as chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff became the highest-ranking African-American ever to serve in the U.S. military; Defence Secretary William Perry and a number of Medal of Honour winners.</p>
<p>The award of the nation's highest military decoration to Baker and his comrades-in-arms resulted from a study that started in 1993 when then-acting Army Secretary John Shannon asked about the conspicuous absence of any black Medal of Honour recipient in the Second World War.</p>
<p>Conducted by Shaw University, an historically black North Carolina institution, the study found no official documentation for racial prejudice in the awards process but concluded that the failure of blacks to win the highest U.S. military award lay in the racial climate and practice in the armed services of that period.</p>
<p>&quot;It was the atmosphere of the country at that time ... segregation was a way of life,&quot; Baker told reporters.</p>
<p>Mindful of his army buddies on a day that his country at last honoured his service &quot;above and beyond the call of duty,&quot; Baker said: &quot;Thank you, fellows. Well done. I'll always remember you.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
