<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="303202" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Telekom shares hit low as gag expires.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Telekom shares hit low as gag expires.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in German phone giant Deutsche Telekom AG fell on Monday to their lowest level since they were launched on stock exchanges two months ago as a regulatory gag on rating the stock expired.</p>
<p>Stock analysts released a string of recommendations to investors as underwriters were allowed to comment for the first time since the listing on November 18.</p>
<p>As the reports began to trickle into the market, analysts appeared to view the stock as fair value at its current level of around 30 marks ($18.90) and saw room for growth over the next six months, but few investors were aggressive buyers.</p>
<p>Telekom shares fell sharply in post-bourse electronic trade on profit-taking sparked by wary U.S. investors.</p>
<p>They closed at 29.86 marks on the IBIS computer system, down 45 pfennigs from Friday and the first time they have dipped below 30 marks. Telekom shares continued trading lower at mid-session in New York.</p>
<p>Earlier, the shares closed floor trade at 30.45 marks, down seven pfennigs from Friday, but still nearly seven percent above the initial offer price of 28.50 marks.</p>
<p>The issue's three main underwriters -- Deutsche Bank AG, Dresdner Bank AG and U.S. investment bank Goldman Sachs -- were divided with the German banks taking a much more positive view than their American counterpart.</p>
<p>Deutsche's investment arm Deutsche Morgan Grenfell (DMG) assigned Telekom a rating of &quot;overweight&quot;, saying it would outperform the DAX index of 30 blue-chip stocks. Dresdner's Kleinwort Benson unit recommended buying up to 35 marks.</p>
<p>&quot;We are initiating coverage with a recommendation of overweight,&quot; said James Golob, DMG telecommunications analyst. &quot;If they can deliver compound growth as predicted then there will surely be room for capital appreciation.&quot;</p>
<p>James Riddiough, a Frankfurt-based DMG analyst, added: &quot;By overweight, we mean that we believe it's going to outperform the DAX index.&quot; DMG predicted Telekom compounded net earnings would grow by 35 percent over the next five years.</p>
<p>But Goldman Sachs, reflecting earlier differences with its German partners over their valuation of Telekom shares, said it would initiate coverage of Deutsche Telekom with a rating of &quot;market performer&quot; and declined further comment.</p>
<p>Telekom shares have underperformed the DAX by around 16 percent since they were listed in Europe's largest share offer which saw Telekom sell more than 26 percent of its capital.</p>
<p>The highest level Telekom shares have reached since closing at 33.90 marks on their first day of trade was 33.45 marks on November 29. They have been falling ever since.</p>
<p>Lacking new information about the company's performance, analysts said there was nothing to boost the stock after it fell from 33 marks and above in November.</p>
<p>The shares are also under pressure as investors anticipate the flotation of new stock by France Telecom, Spain's Telefonica and Portugal Telecom later this year.</p>
<p>Commerzbank AG, Germany's third largest commercial bank, said it was keeping Telekom on &quot;hold&quot; and complained that the company had not made any recent comments on its business.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no new data on the company,&quot; said analyst Sabine Schauer. &quot;This is really astounding in the days of shareholder value and in light of the advertising hype ahead of the issue.&quot;</p>
<p>Telekom said it would make a general statement about its 1996 earnings and give an outlook for 1997 in March at the Cebit information technology trade fair. Its official 1996 results will be published on May 13. ($1=1.5865 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
