<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="303252" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Analysts see brewer Spendrup staying flat.</title>
<headline>Analysts see brewer Spendrup staying flat.</headline>
<byline>Kristina Zetterlund</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Swedish brewer Spendrups slumped on Monday, with market players unimpressed by company forecasts of better earnings and recovering beer sales.</p>
<p>Spendrups, a family brewing concern, lowered its forecast for calendar 1996 earnings on Friday but analysts said they were more concerned with other factors.</p>
<p>Analysts have a bearish view on the share because of factors such as the breaking up of its long-standing licensing agreement with Coca Cola on the Nordic market.</p>
<p>One analyst said: &quot;My expectations were already for a result of around 25-30 million crowns. If it is lower than that it would be a surprise.&quot;</p>
<p>Spendrups said on Friday that weak sales before the end of the year mean that the 1996 result will come in below earlier forecasts of around 40 million crowns.</p>
<p>Full-year results are due on February 20.</p>
<p>Spendrups B share was one of few losers on the Stockholm Stock Exchange on Monday. The share closed at 53.5 crowns, down 2.5 crowns, while the general index rose 1.81 percent to 2,442.93.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not the company I would buy right now. There has already been a profit improvement in the stock. Now I would like to see good earnings over a few quarters,&quot; said an analyst.</p>
<p>The lowering of tax on beer sales at the start of 1997 meant that Spendrups' sales were lower than normal at the end of 1996, following an inventory decrease.</p>
<p>Shops must now fill up their empty storerooms and the new lower tax on beer should lift sales in the longer term.</p>
<p>Spendrups had a 1.38 billion crown turnover in the first nine months of 1996 compared to 1.30 billion in January-September 1995.</p>
<p>The company said on Monday that beer sales had rocketed 180 percent in the first six days of this year as restocking took place. The company also said 1997 profits would be better than those of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;I am starting to doubt that the lowering of tax on beer will reduce private imports very much. There is still a big price difference in beer in Sweden and Denmark,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>Scandinavian countries charge prices for beer which astound visitors. In central Stockholm a half-litre glass can cost as much as 40 crowns.</p>
<p>The company could benefit from the Swedish beer tax being lower than equivalent taxes in Finland and Norway. This could possibly entice private beer exports from Sweden to Norway and Finland, analysts said.</p>
<p>Market players have large expectations for Spendrups' new beer, which has such a low alcohol content that it will not be burdened with a beer tax.</p>
<p>Some analysts forecast more positive events for Spendrups as Swedish state alcohol retailer Systembolaget is expected to lose its monopoly position and tax on beer is expected to be cut further following EU pressure.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1005</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
