<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="303535" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: First Chicago, Baird in finance alliance.</title>
<headline>First Chicago, Baird in finance alliance.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>First Chicago NBD Corp and Robert W. Baird &amp; Co Inc said they formed an alliance to be called the Baird/FCN Alliance that expands the corporate finance services of each firm.</p>
<p>First Chicago said it will offer clients mergers and acquisition advisory representation, as well as equity and preferred stock distribution services provided by Baird.</p>
<p>Baird will offer private placements, asset securitization, bank financing for acquisitions and high-yield securities provided by First Chicago NBD, the bank said.</p>
<p>The alliance is contractual and does not involve ownership interest of either firm in the other, the bank said.</p>
<p>First Chicago said it previously had an investment banking alliance with Chicago Dearborn Co that was discontinued after announcement of the purchase of a parent company of the firm, Chicago Corp, by ABN AMRO North America Inc, part of ABN AMRO Holding NV.</p>
<p>Baird is part of Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Co. First Chicago NBD is the ninth largest U.S. bank holding company with assets of $106.7 billion.</p>
<p>((--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
