<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="303513" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rubin--U.S. must meet commitments to loan agencies.</title>
<headline>Rubin--U.S. must meet commitments to loan agencies.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin Monday repeated his assertion that it was critical that the United States meet its commitments to the international financial institutions.</p>
<p>In remarks before an international development conference, Rubin conceded that it might be difficult since there is resistance to such assistance at a time of budget cutbacks.</p>
<p>&quot;It won't be easy,&quot; Rubin told the conference. &quot;There is growing resistance in this country, and elsewhere to engagement in the global economy.&quot;  </p>
<p>Rubin said that it would be difficult for the United States to exercise its leadership in the institutions such as the World Bank if it failed to made up its financing arrears.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot continue as the only major nation in the world with large-scale arrears to the World Bank, the Asian Bank, the Inter-American (Development) Bank and the Global Environmental Facility,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that the Clinton administration was committed to working with Congress to obtain the resources to fund key programs and institution, including the International Development Association, within balanced budget goals.  </p>
<p>Rubin, in his remarks, defended the institutions, which have been criticised for inefficiences and other problems, saying that they had made real progrsss in reforming their structure and policies.</p>
<p>&quot;Is the job finished? Far from it. But has real progress been made? Absolutely,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
