<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="303705" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Tomkins profit surge tops forecasts.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Tomkins profit surge tops forecasts.</headline>
<byline>Edna Fernandes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tomkins Plc, the British baking-to-engineering combine, reported a sharp surge in half year profits on Monday but snuffed out hopes of a share buyback this year by flagging possible acquisitions instead.</p>
<p>Pretax profits for the six months to November 2 rose 34 percent to 168.8 million pounds ($284 million). The dividend rose to 3.06 pence from 2.7 pence the preceding year.</p>
<p>Executive chairman Gregory Hutchings said the results marked &quot;another period of outperformance for Tomkins&quot; and forecast the the shares should continue to outperform the sector.</p>
<p>Hutchings ruled out the possibility of returning the company's 366 million pound cash-pile to shareholders this year, saying in an interview: &quot;We see sufficient (acquisition) opportunities to hold onto our cash for the time being.&quot;</p>
<p>Hutchings said the group was likely to make a number of smaller buys. &quot;It won't be one major deal, but it could be worth up to 200 million pounds,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rumours of a buyback in 1997 have helped push Tomkins shares ahead in recent weeks. Its shares on Monday reversed early gains, however, and were down four at 273-1/2p by 1115 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;The numbers were at the top end of what people were looking for and we've seen some early interest,&quot; one market-maker said. Analysts had expected profits of around 160 million pounds.</p>
<p>The outlook was also seen as promising.</p>
<p>&quot;Prospects for the second half look encouraging, with the majority of our operations having healthy order books and satisfactory market conditions,&quot; Hutchings said.</p>
<p>He said Tomkins was delighted with its purchase last year of U.S. automotive and industrial product firm Gates Corp for $1.1 billion.</p>
<p>Gates contributed 259.5 million in sales and 20 million in profit in its first 14 weeks under Tomkins control.</p>
<p>A divisional breakdown of the Tompkins figures showed fluid controls had sales of 189.2 million versus 165.7 million pounds, with profits of 19 million versus 15.8 million.</p>
<p>Industry services saw sales rise to 219 million from 194 million, with profits of 12.5 million versus 12.1 million. Professional garden and leisure products saw sales of 276 million versus 271 million and profits down to 8.5 million from 8.9 million.</p>
<p>Industrial products sales rose to 317.3 million from 267.9 million, with profits of 34.3 million versus 28.5 million.</p>
<p>Milling and baking, which includes the Hovis bread brand, saw sales up to 351.3 million versus 333.8 million, with profits at 15.4 million versus 13.7 million.</p>
<p>Food products, including Bisto gravy and Robertson's jam range, saw sales up to 543.5 million from 501.8 million, with profits at 42.6 million versus 38.5 million.</p>
<p>Excluding currency effects, organic growth in group operating profit was up more than 10 percent on sales, which in turn rose by seven percent.</p>
<p>Unlike other major export groups, Tomkins has so far been left unscathed by the pound powering ahead against the dollar and mark.</p>
<p>Against the dollar, Tomkins said it was locked at $1.52 to the pound for the rest of the year. The amount of mark-denominated business was minimal, it said.</p>
<p>On market conditions, Tomkins said the U.S. was seen remaining firm. Britain was described as mixed, while the French market was expected to continue to suffer due to economic problems. ($1=.5950 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
