<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="30378" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: In art, as in life, Fed seeks sustainable growth.</title>
<headline>In art, as in life, Fed seeks sustainable growth.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Reserve is a many-faceted institution. Assisting in the maintenance of a sound U.S. economy, its employees examine growth indicators, study aspects of monetary policy and ponder bank regulation.</p>
<p>So who would have imagined that for 20 years, the Fed has also been building a small art collection?</p>
<p>A special exhibition celebrating &quot;Twenty Years of Collecting by the Federal Reserve Board&quot; is on view on New York's Upper East Side at Beacon Hill Fine Art gallery until the middle of September.  </p>
<p>Another exhibition at the gallery, &quot;Dollars &amp; Cents, A Selection of Trompe l'Oeil by Major Painters of the Genre,&quot; also includes some work from the Fed's collection.</p>
<p>The impetus for the Fed's art collecting came from former Federal Reserve Board Chairman Arthur Burns, said Mary Anne Goley, the director of the Fed Board's Fine Arts Program.  </p>
<p>&quot;When Arthur Burns came over from the Council of Economic Advisors, there was a memorandum that had been sent around by (President) Nixon to cabinet members and departments, asking each department to do something for the arts,&quot; said Mary Anne Goley, director of the Fine Arts Program at the Fed. &quot;When (Burns) came here to be Chairman, that memo was on his desk.&quot;</p>
<p>The Fed then hired Goley, an art historian and authority on American painter John White Alexander (1856-1915), to give the visual arts a role at the central bank.  </p>
<p>&quot;Burns would see what central banks had in other countries and he concluded that this central bank ought to have something,&quot; said Goley. &quot;And we had nothing.&quot;</p>
<p>So the work began. After two decades, the Fed owns 220 pieces of art and it wants to sustain that growth.</p>
<p>In this respect at least, the bank has a conservative policy -- it doesn't buy art. Art is donated.</p>
<p>Goley's approach to collecting is accommodative.  </p>
<p>&quot;We collect American and international artists from the 19th century to the present,&quot; she said. &quot;We're interested in everything. We are an institution with an international reach so we do have some works by foreign artists.&quot;</p>
<p>But it is also restrictive. &quot;My restrictive policy is that I want good art,&quot; said Goley.</p>
<p>But the Fed collection does not restrict itself to monetary themes, though Goley would like some more examples of the money pictures popular in the late 19th century.  </p>
<p>&quot;But that's because they are part of a particular era of art history, not because the Fed conducts monetary policy,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Because they are very difficult to conserve, the Fed eschews photography and watercolors.</p>
<p>And restrictiveness does come into play with regard to who can donate art. &quot;We do not accept anything from anyone we regulate and we take a pro-active role in making sure that does not happen,&quot; said Goley. Some gifts come from the artists themselves or their estates, she added.  </p>
<p>To prepare for the Fine Arts Program's important anniversary, a special committee chaired by former Federal Reserve Chairman G. William Miller &quot;assumed an active role in identifying potential patrons for the Twentieth Anniversary,&quot; said Goley.</p>
<p>A few of the works on exhibit in New York are &quot;Shower on Lake&quot; by Eduard Jean Steichen (1879-1973), &quot;Landscape, Albany&quot; by James McDougal Hart (1828-1901), &quot;Mrs. Daniels with Two Children&quot; by John White Alexander (1856-1915), &quot;Abstraction-Verte&quot; by Jean Helion (1904-1987), &quot;Trees, Hudson at Newburgh,&quot; by Leon Dabo (1868-1960) and &quot;Study from the Locomotive Series, 1988&quot; by Lawrence Gipe (b. 1962).</p>
<p>On Goley's wish list for future acquisitions are &quot;more Trompe l'Oeil money pictures, some American impressionist pictures and some colonial portraiture.&quot;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, wouldn't you like to know which picture Fed Chairman Alan Greenspan chose to hang in his office?</p>
<p>&quot;The Fed Chairman has a wonderful landscape by an American Hudson River painter named Alexander Lawrie, an 1867 landscape called 'Pleasant Valley, Essex, New York,'&quot; Goley said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
