<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="303736" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Nordic currencies spearhead new onslaught vs mark.</title>
<headline>Nordic currencies spearhead new onslaught vs mark.</headline>
<byline>Abigail Levene</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nordic currencies spearheaded another European assault on the mark on Monday, and market watchers foresaw more grief ahead for the suffering German unit.</p>
<p>Dealers reported Bank of Finland intervention designed to restrain the markka against the mark, in a continuation of the vigorous European central bank activity seen on Friday.</p>
<p>Norway's crown leaped to fresh four-year highs, extending last week's rally, which accelerated when the Norwegian central bank cut rates twice in just two days and said it would stop intervening to rein in its currency for now.  </p>
<p>Traders spoke of strong interest from big investment houses and clearing banks to buy Finnish markka for marks.</p>
<p>&quot;Mark/Norway, having broken so far down, has prompted some follow-up on mark/Finny,&quot; said Peter Heath, senior dealer at Merita Bank in London. &quot;I don't know where it will end.&quot;</p>
<p>The Finnish markka touched 2.9745 per mark in early trade, its best level since December 1995. It settled at 2.9770/90 by 1029 GMT, up from late Friday's European level of 2.9800/20.</p>
<p>The Norwegian crown was quoted at 4.0040/70 after earlier racing to a four-year peak of 4.0015 to the mark from its previous close here of 4.0365/95.  </p>
<p>Traders said the market seemed set on lifting the markka through the upper end of notional 2.25-percent bands against the mark within the European exchange rate mechanism (ERM).</p>
<p>The markka joined the ERM in October at a central rate of 3.04 per mark, within 15-percent fluctuation limits. Bands of 2.25 percent -- as laid down in the Maastricht Treaty and within which most EMS units moved before 1993 -- would limit markka strength to 2.9716 per mark.</p>
<p>The Danish crown held at Friday's high of 3.8070/75 per mark -- its strongest since February 1993 -- while Sweden's crown firmed to 4.3390 in early trade from 4.3570/00 late Friday.  </p>
<p>The Swedish Riksbank was rumoured to have sold its currency for marks on Friday, as was the central bank of Portugal. Traders said the Bank of Spain had given up its strenuous efforts to keep the peseta below 84 per mark.</p>
<p>The peseta was trading at 83.39/41 to the mark by 1105 GMT versus 83.46/49 late Friday, while mark/lira hovered around Friday's 31-month low of 971.25.</p>
<p>&quot;The key thing is the market's got a much more realistic view of economic prospects this year in Germany, and hence there are increased expectations of a German rate cut,&quot; said Nick Stamenkovic, economist at DKB International here.  </p>
<p>Gloom over Germany's economic outlook grew last week when data showed unemployment rose by 48,000 in December to 4.156 million, or 10.8 percent of the workforce.</p>
<p>A slowdown in German GDP growth also fuelled expectations that the economy would remain in the doldrums, and that the Bundesbank would ease rates in the not-too-distant future.</p>
<p>German retail sales and wholesale prices are due out this week, but the Ifo survey on business sentiment will be key.</p>
<p>&quot;Much will depend upon the Ifo survey,&quot; said Stamenkovic. &quot;If that provides further signs of weakness in the German economy, the mark will come under some more downward pressure.&quot;</p>
<p>If the Ifo survey is upbeat, the mark should receive some relief, but in the longer term it is on a clear downward path, economists said.</p>
<p>While a weaker mark may be good news for Germany, it is not so welcome for its fellow European states, which are also desperate to boost growth and have little need of a stronger currency which makes exports less competitive, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The monetary tightening coming through the appreciation of currencies is to a large extent hitting economies which are also suffering from very tight fiscal policies,&quot; said Klaus Baader, senior currency economist at Deutche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
