<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="303988" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Italy's Fazio sees average 97 cpi below three pct.</title>
<headline>Italy's Fazio sees average 97 cpi below three pct.</headline>
<dateline>BASLE 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of Italy governor Antonio Fazio said on Monday that he believed average consumer price inflation would fall below three percent in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The improvement that we have seen has been very strong,&quot; Fazio told reporters while attending a meeting of central bank governors. &quot;We are counting on (average CPI in 1997) falling below three percent,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>&quot;But you know very well that there are risks for inflation,&quot; Fazio said, adding &quot;these come from public finance and labour costs and monetary policy has to reflect these things.&quot;</p>
<p>Italian inflation was 2.6 percent year-on-year last month, unchanged from the November level and in line with forecasts.</p>
<p>Average inflation was 3.9 percent, meeting the government target. Prime Minister Romano Prodi's government wants to get 1997 average inflation down to 2.5 percent. Milan newsroom +392-66102321  </p>
<p>Fazio also said it was important to look at monthly variations in inflation and not at the year-on-year data because with the latter &quot;you never know if the positive or negative variation is in the last month or in the month at the start (of the period).&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The 0.1 percent for January 1996 was linked to a revision of the index. We don't know how true that data is,&quot; he said. Asked what he expected the January 1997 figure to be like, he replied &quot;Let's hope it's good.&quot;</p>
<p>The January 1997 CPI figure will be the first not to incorporate a fall of 0.04 to 0.05 percent which was a direct result of the revision of the inflation basket introduced in January 1996. Milan newsroom +392-66102321</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BASLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
