<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="303907" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Unions say French pension funds bill unacceptable.</title>
<headline>Unions say French pension funds bill unacceptable.</headline>
<byline>Brian Love</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four French trade unions said on Monday that a bill to allow private pension funds in France was unacceptable because it would syphon large sums of money out of the state-backed pay-as-you earn retirement benefits system.</p>
<p>The CGT, CFTC, CGC and the Force Ouvriere (Workers Force) unions jointly condemned the bill -- mainly because of a clause on social security contribution exemptions for employers -- on the eve of the bill's second reading in the National Assembly.</p>
<p>The country's largest union, the Socialist CFDT, was absent from the news conference but, like the others, has written to Prime Minister Alain Juppe to protest against employer relief on tax and social security contributions for the same reason.</p>
<p>Marc Vilbenoit of the CGC union said the private pensions system envisaged would deprive the basic social security-funded retirement system of six billion francs ($1.1 billion) next year, drain seven billion from the obligatory ARRCO top-up system and another four billion from the twin AGIRC top-up system.</p>
<p>&quot;We've taken this step together,&quot; said Vilbenoit, whose white-collar union coordinated the news conference. &quot;Why, because the conditions for social security exemption are extremely dangerous for the collective regime.&quot;</p>
<p>The current bill amounted to &quot;tax evasion&quot; at the expense of the pay-as-you go scheme, he said.</p>
<p>Alain Deleu of the Christian CFTC union said that the very demographic issues threatening traditional pay-as-you-go systems were being ignored in any case in resorting to private pensions, because those best placed to subscribe to private systems would be those with less children in their charge.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not want a France a l'Anglo-Saxonne,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The two pillars of the current French pay-as-you-go system are the general regime funded by social security contributions and the twin, obligatory ARRCO and AGIRC topping-up schemes.</p>
<p>The government argues that the pension funds bill allowing for private, funded retirement schemes will amount to a third, complementary pillar, rather than a substitute.</p>
<p>The unions did not stipulate what action they might take if the bill was adopted despite their objections but said that they would not be dragged into lending their support to a bill which endangered the current system.</p>
<p>The would consult afterwards if this happened, they said.</p>
<p>Marc Blondel, the pugnacious leader of Force Ouvriere union, said the unions would not be fooled into sanctioning the private pensions bill and warned that &quot;these will be structures which will compete with the existing regimes&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a dangerous move,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Vilbenoit said a Senate amendment limiting exemptions for employers on social security contributions -- accepted by the government -- fell far short of what was needed because it only limited the exemption in the case of employer contributions on behalf of a small number of employees whose salary was in the top managerial rank of 900,000 francs or more.</p>
<p>He said the unions' calculations of the loss that would be incurred for the pay-as-you-go system has been calculated by actuaries and were as reliable as any actuarial estimations could be.</p>
<p>The bill has already been through the National Assembly once and also the Senate and is now back to the National Assembly for a second reading. Once the second reading in the National Assembly is finished, it must return to the Senate. ($1=5.350 French Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
