<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="303906" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French weekly fined over dead Mitterrand pictures.</title>
<headline>French weekly fined over dead Mitterrand pictures.</headline>
<byline>Thierry Leveque</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Paris court fined the weekly Paris-Match 100,000 francs ($20,000) on Monday for publishing two photographs of the late French president Francois Mitterrand, taken secretly as he lay on his deathbed.</p>
<p>It also ordered the weekly to pay each member of the Mitterrand family a symbolic one franc (20 cents) in damages for violating their privacy.</p>
<p>The photographs showed Mitterrand's body, dressed in a dark suit and tie and hands crossed on his stomach, in the Paris apartment where he died a year ago on January 8, after leaving office following two seven-year terms as head of state.</p>
<p>Mitterrand's widow Danielle, her two sons Jean-Christophe and Gilbert, and the late president's illegitimate daughter Mazarine Pingeot had filed suit against &quot;persons unknown&quot; in an effort to discover who took the photographs.</p>
<p>The court turned down their demand that the magazine publish an apology. The family had argued that publication of the photos was immoral and &quot;ran counter to the respect due to the dead&quot;.</p>
<p>Prosecutor Francois Cordier had asked the court to rule that publication of the clandestine pictures had &quot;gone over the limit&quot;, violating France's strict privacy laws.</p>
<p>Paris-Match has declined to name the photographer and said it was simply fulfilling its journalistic obligations.</p>
<p>The pictures had a historic value, and Mitterrand had while he was alive given an implicit green light for them to be taken, the magazine argued.</p>
<p>&quot;Public figures do not constitute a category of different beings, for whom the importance of their actions should lead to the absence of elementary rights valid for all individuals,&quot; the court said in its ruling.</p>
<p>Paris-Match's refusal to name the photographer &quot;clearly suggests the pictures were of fraudulent origin&quot;.</p>
<p>But the court did not order the weekly, as is usually the case in such affairs, to publish its findings as requested by the Mitterrand family.</p>
<p>&quot;The court notes that the prejudice caused by the publication of the photographs was of short duration,&quot; the findings said.</p>
<p>&quot;Only a few weeks after the publication of the photographs, several members of the Mitterrand family agreed to give Paris-Match interviews or to be featured in (the weekly),&quot; the court said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
