<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="304078" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch central bank sold 300 tonnes of gold.</title>
<headline>Dutch central bank sold 300 tonnes of gold.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dutch central bank said on Monday it had sold 300 tonnes of gold &quot;in the past period&quot; for about 6.4 billion guilders.  </p>
<p>The bank said the bullion sales, representing more than 20 percent of its total holdings, had brought the share of gold in its total holdings of gold and foreign exchange into line with with that of other gold-holding countries.  </p>
<p>The transactions would be settled in the course of February and March this year and be reflected in the bank's summary balance sheet.</p>
<p>The conversion of gold into foreign exchange would lead to a structural increase in the bank's annual profits of about 250 million guilders at present interest and exchange rates, the bank added in a brief statement.  </p>
<p>The gold price has fallen to 3-1/4 year lows this year amid talk of a central bank sale in the final quarter of 1996. It was quoted at $358.20/358.70 an ounce in early European trade on Monday.</p>
<p>The price has fallen about 3.25 percent since the start of the year, when a steady slide started to accelerate. Dealers said a major factor had been a report from research group Gold Fields Mineral Services (GFMS) that gold sales from the official sector had accelerated in the second half of 1996.</p>
<p>A report by the authoritative consultants Gold Fields Mineral Services last week estimated net central bank gold sales last year at 208 tonnes.</p>
<p>The market may be initially relieved that it had absorbed the volume of gold sold by the Dutch, Smith said.</p>
<p>&quot;But in the longer term, it's yet another central bank selling gold,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Dutch central bank said it had sold the gold &quot;in the past period&quot; for about 6.4 billion guilders.</p>
<p>The bank said the bullion sales, representing more than 20 percent of its total holdings, had brought the share of gold in its totaly holdings of gold and foreing exchange into line with that of other gold-holding countries.</p>
<p>In 1992/93 the Dutch and Belgian central banks between them sold more than 600 tonnes of gold. Since then the Belgian central bank has sold additional gold reserves.</p>
<p>--David Evans, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
