<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="304021" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Chirac rallies to defend French icon, la baguette.</title>
<headline>Chirac rallies to defend French icon, la baguette.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Jacques Chirac promised French bakers on Monday to push through a law to protect their crusty baguette loaves from cut-price rivals and supermarkets if a new decree to that effect failed.</p>
<p>Up to 5,000 shops selling bread in France have had to take down &quot;bakery&quot; signs under the decree in force since New Year's Day, the latest in a long series aimed at safeguarding artisans and village shops from the ravages of competition.</p>
<p>The decree states that bakers must select their flour, knead dough and bake bread on their premises. Supermarkets and shops which merely heat up factory-made frozen dough will have to use less attractive signs such as &quot;bread stop&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;If the procedure under way led to the decisions being called into question, it would naturally be very easy to affirm our political determination with a law,&quot; Chirac told the National Bakers' Federation at a New Year ceremony.</p>
<p>Federation president Jean Camus had expressed concern at judicial appeals against the decree lodged by bakeries' rivals.</p>
<p>&quot;It is unimaginable to compare the bread which comes out of a bakery...with this thing which looks like anything except bread, anything except Christian food,&quot; Chirac said, adding that bread was &quot;one of the great charms of our civilisation&quot;.</p>
<p>The new decree also outlaws selling bread at a loss -- sometimes baguettes can be bought for just 1.5 francs (29 cents) in a supermarket against about four francs (77 cents) in a bakery.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
