<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="304061" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch to invest gold money in dollars, marks, yen.</title>
<headline>Dutch to invest gold money in dollars, marks, yen.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dutch central bank said on Monday it would invest $3.8 billion raised from gold sales in bonds denominated in dollars, German marks and Japanese yen.</p>
<p>The bank said settlement of the recent sale of 300 tonnes of gold would be made in February and March, adding that the proceeds would not only be invested in dollar instruments.</p>
<p>&quot;It will go into our reserves, into dollars and maybe some other currencies,&quot; spokesman Bert Groothof told Reuters, specifying the other foreign currencies as marks and yen.</p>
<p>Asked how these funds would be invested, he said: &quot;Most of the time it goes into bonds and Treasury paper.&quot;  </p>
<p>Groothof declined to provide further details.</p>
<p>In early December, when speculation about central bank gold sales was rife, the Dutch central bank denied it had been selling gold in the preceding weeks.</p>
<p>The latest weekly return from the central bank showed it held total gold and foreign currency reserves of 61.6 billion guilders, of which 15.03 billion was gold.</p>
<p>The bank does not usually publish a breakdown of foreign currency reserves by currency, but the 1995 annual report showed marks was the largest component at 45 percent.</p>
<p>Then followed dollars at 32 percent, ECUs nine percent, SDRs nine percent and yen five percent.</p>
<p>This breakdown included forward transactions in foreign currencies and is not directly comparable to the figures published in the bank's weekly returns.</p>
<p>-- Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000, Fax +31 20 504 5040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
