<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="304101" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Big European monetary policy questions unanswered.</title>
<headline>Big European monetary policy questions unanswered.</headline>
<byline>Myra MacDonald</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's central bankers have begun to assemble the armoury they will use to defend the euro after its launch in 1999 but are leaving big questions unanswered about how monetary policy will be run under a single currency.</p>
<p>The European Monetary Institute (EMI), the forerunner of the European Central Bank (ECB), on Friday unveiled a policy blueprint in which the ECB will manage upper and lower interest rates to meet its primary aim of maintaining price stability.</p>
<p>But it is up to politicians to decide two questions which will set the tone -- on the relationship between governments and the ECB and on who will become first head of the central bank.</p>
<p>France has led a drive for an informal economic council among countries in the euro zone to counterbalance the central bank -- an idea gaining some acceptance among its European Union partners.</p>
<p>&quot;There were no major objections to the idea of having a kind of political body...giving some advice to the central bank,&quot; Luxembourg Prime Minister Jean-Claude Juncker said in an interview broadcast by Reuters Financial Television on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The French idea, in fact, was supported by Germany, by Belgium, by Luxembourg and by others,&quot; he said, stressing it must be an informal structure like the Group of Seven leading industrial nations to avoid formally excluding European countries outside the euro zone.</p>
<p>But the question is not so much the existence of such a council but its role in fixing exchange rate policy, which will be within the power of governments rather than the central bank.</p>
<p>French Prime Minister Alain Juppe has already warned that the euro currency must not be &quot;a plaything&quot; of central bank governors.</p>
<p>&quot;Our German friends say they do not want a &quot;soft euro'. Neither do I. Neither a soft euro, nor soft economic growth,&quot; he said in a book published last month. &quot;I insist that these questions must not be left to the judgment of central bank governors alone,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>France has said it wants Europe to fight any undervaluation in the dollar which gives U.S. exporters an unfair advantage.</p>
<p>So if governments decide they want a weaker euro, can they simply tell the central bank to lower rates?</p>
<p>The Maastricht treaty tried to prevent that scenario by making the ECB independent.</p>
<p>And, in an interview with Britain's Independent newspaper on Monday, EMI head Alexandre Lamfalussy said the ECB would be able to resist any political pressure. Though he added: &quot;That there will be political pressure is clear.&quot;</p>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac showed this month how central bank independence can be muddied by naming two allies to the nine-member Bank of France council, in a move that could allow the central bank to take a softer line on interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;What's happening today in France may happen tomorrow with the ECB,&quot; ABN Amro economist Philippe Brossard said.</p>
<p>France has already said it will not necessarily accept orthodox Dutch central bank head Wim Duisenberg, who takes over as EMI head this year, as the future president of the ECB.</p>
<p>And Bank of France monetary policy council member Paul Marchelli, seen as close to Chirac, suggested in an interview published last week that the ECB's first head should be French.</p>
<p>&quot;I would remind you that when Europe decided to put the headquarters of the European Central Bank in Frankfurt, there was an unspoken commitment on the part of the Germans that the first head would be French,&quot; he told weekly Investir.</p>
<p>EU leaders will name the president, vice-president and four executive members who will vote along with national central bank heads inside the euro-zone on an ECB governing council.</p>
<p>How hawkish this council will be will depend on those nominations and on which countries join a single currency.</p>
<p>Until recently, economists assumed that politicians would not jeopardise the ECB'S credibility by naming people who do not have a strong track record in national central banks.</p>
<p>Financial markets need to believe that the ECB will boost rates if necessary to defend the euro, just as national central banks in the past have pushed up rates in the face of recession to defend their currencies against the mark.</p>
<p>In return, the theory goes, investors will demand a lower risk premium on euro assets.</p>
<p>But looking at the new composition of the Bank of France's own council, it is far from clear that it would have raised rates quite as aggressively in the past to defend the franc, analysts said.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 42 21 53 81</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
