<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="304258" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-INTERVIEW-Australia's JeansWest bucks trend.</title>
<headline>RTRS-INTERVIEW-Australia's JeansWest bucks trend.</headline>
<byline>Justin McCamish</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Casual clothing retailer JeansWest Australia Ltd has bucked poor Australian retail trends and expected sales to rise more than 17 percent and stronger profits for the year to July 31, its managing director told Reuters on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Our sales...will pass through A$100 million during this year and that's going to happen earlier rather than later. Our sales are rising much faster than our overheads,&quot; JeansWest managing director David Lawn said in an interview.  </p>
<p>JeansWest, a subsidiary of listed Hong Kong clothing maker Glorious Sun Enterprises Ltd, posted a net profit of A$4.1 million on total sales of A$85 million in fiscal 1995/96.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be more profitable this year,&quot; Lawn said. He declined to speculate on by how much the bottom line would rise.</p>
<p>Lawn said sales from JeansWest's 160 stores in Australia and New Zealand for the five months to December 31 were about A$43 million, 25 percent higher than the corresponding period last year.  </p>
<p>The chain's ebullient outlook is in stark contrast to other Australian retailers which have predicted steep profit slides on the back of a torpid national economy and consumer thrift.</p>
<p>JeansWest's direct competitor Just Jeans Ltd, along with fellow clothing merchant Country Road Ltd and upmarket department store chain David Jones Ltd, all recently warned of 50 percent falls in half-year profits.</p>
<p>Lawn said JeansWest was growing sales despite flat retail conditions by winning market share through lower prices and better quality, as well as well-targetted marketing strategies.  </p>
<p>&quot;If you are not taking market share you are, by definition, losing it,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The chain's vertically integrated structure had allowed it to pass value directly to the consumer, Lawn said.</p>
<p>&quot;Glorious Sun...controls about 85 percent of the merchandise in our stores and controls it from ownership of cotton fields right through to retailing and that does deliver a startling competitive advantage.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We have transferred that into value within the stores that is progressively seen as stronger,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Lawn said competitor's efforts to claw back earnings during the next six months meant the Australian retail environment was likely to remain weak over the short term.</p>
<p>&quot;I think It'll continue to be tough...because of the reaction that clearly comes from the chains that have had poor first halves,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>JeansWest was started in Perth in 1972 and grew quickly before running into financial difficulties in the late 1980s.</p>
<p>The chain was eventually bought by Glorious Sun, which was one of several suppliers, in 1995.</p>
<p>-- Melbourne bureau 61-3 9286-1435</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
