<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="304264" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Rescued yachtsmen offer thanks for their lives.</title>
<headline>Rescued yachtsmen offer thanks for their lives.</headline>
<byline>Bernard Hickey</byline>
<dateline>FREMANTLE, Australia 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rescued yachtsmen Tony Bullimore and Thierry Dubois arrived back on dry land to heroes' welcomes on Monday, giving thanks for their lives as thousands of well-wishers cheered and waved banners.</p>
<p>&quot;It's absolutely astonishing,&quot; Briton Bullimore said after walking down the gangplank of the Australian navy frigate HMAS Adelaide at the Western Australian port of Fremantle.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm slightly emotional about this but I'm going to turn around and say this 'thank you guys',&quot; he said, raising his arms and pointing to the ship's crew at a dockside reception.</p>
<p>&quot;Thank you Australia for giving me back my life,&quot; he said to a huge cheer from the crowd of about 5,000, including Australian Defence Minister Ian McLachlan who told the rescued sailors they owed their lives to the professionalism of Australia's military.</p>
<p>Frenchman Dubois also thanked the crew of the Adelaide and the Australian airforce crews who rescued them from freezing Antarctic seas on Thursday 1,400 miles south-west of Perth.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't like a lot the word hero. We are not heroes. I think Australia have a lot of heroes on this ship and in the aircraft that saved us,&quot; Dubois said.</p>
<p>Bullimore and Dubois were competing in the Vendee Globe solo-handed round-the-world race.</p>
<p>The Adelaide was escorted into port by a flotilla of small craft as wellwishers on the dock waved British flags and sang along to the tune of Waltzing Matilda on a sunny morning.</p>
<p>Many people held up banners saying &quot;Welcome Home Heroes&quot;.</p>
<p>Family members were ushered on board the frigate to greet Bullimore and Dubois privately, before they emerged for an official welcome, arm-in-arm and wearing grey naval uniforms with the name tags &quot;Hon. 1&quot; and &quot;Hon. 2&quot;.</p>
<p>A smiling Bullimore was wearing a cap bearing the logo of an Australian TV channel which carried a live broadcast of the yachtmen's arrival.</p>
<p>The survival story of the 56-year-old former Royal Marine is expected to attract huge commercial interest from newspapers, television and movie studios.</p>
<p>Bullimore was picked up after surviving for four days in a dark air pocket in his upturned yacht, battered by Antarctic seas. His fate was unknown until he swam out from under his yacht and into the arms of rescuers.</p>
<p>Dubois, 29, was earlier plucked by helicopter from a tiny life-raft dropped by the Australian air force.</p>
<p>However, fears are held for another yachtsman in the race, Canadian Gerry Roufs, who has not been heard from since Tuesday.</p>
<p>A search for the Canadian, missing 2,500 miles from land between South America and the New Zealand, was suspended on Sunday.</p>
<p>Canadian authorities plan to use radar satellite photos to try to locate him.</p>
<p>Another race participant, Frenchman Raphael Dinelli, was rescued from his sinking yacht in the frigid seas south of Australia the day after Christmas.</p>
<p>Bullimore said he had been looked after like a baby during his time on the navy ship.</p>
<p>&quot;I was getting embarassed being tucked in at night, 'Wanna cuppa tea, mate?', you know and all that, breakfast in the morning - I've never had it so good in all me life,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked by one of the huge contingent of reporters on the dock how close he felt he had come to death, Bullimore said: &quot;Just moments maybe, not hours ... the sea conditions were atrocious ... I really thought, 'Well I've bought me ticket this time ... I'm not going to come out of this time',&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FREMANTLE, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
