<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="304272" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Market welcomes Packer's Sydney casino deal.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Market welcomes Packer's Sydney casino deal.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Morrison</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The surprise purchase by Australia's biggest gambler, Kerry Packer, of control at the Sydney casino was welcomed by investors and analysts on Monday.</p>
<p>Shares in Sydney Harbour Casino Holdings Ltd (SHC), which owns the Sydney casino and Packer's Publishing and Broadcasting Ltd (PBL), were both up after the deal.</p>
<p>Analysts said the deal was good for both companies as Packer's influence was likely to yield a tax-concession for the casino on the high-roller market, which is seen boosting cash flow for both the casino and PBL's coffers.  </p>
<p>Under the deal, PBL will buy 10 percent of SHC for A$1.85 per share from Showboat Inc and pay the U.S. casino operator A$240 million for management control of the casino.</p>
<p>The casino deal is likely to put any plans Packer has of controlling newspaper publisher John Fairfax Holdings Ltd on the back-burner, analysts said.</p>
<p>PBL has a 15 percent stake in Fairfax and Packer has said he would like to control Fairfax.  </p>
<p>SHC, which holds a 12-year monopoly to operate the only legal casino in Australia's largest city, has battled with the New South Wales (NSW) state government for the past 16 months to get a similar tax rate to other Australian casinos.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Packer will probably get the tax-break from the government,&quot; one Sydney-based casino analyst said. &quot;I expect there will be some tax-break announcement this month,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Sydney casino is seeking a 10 percent tax concession from the NSW government on big spending gamblers, mainly from Asia, compared with the present tax rate of 27 percent.  </p>
<p>SHC chief executive Neil Gamble told Reuters last month the tax-break could equate up to A$100 million in new revenue and about A$10 million to the casino's bottom line profit.</p>
<p>Analysts said PBL would improve the running of the casino, which has consistently failed to meet its profit forecasts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
