<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="304200" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Littlewoods Xmas sales up 10 pct on yr ago.</title>
<headline>Littlewoods Xmas sales up 10 pct on yr ago.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's privately-owned retail and leisure group Littlewoods Organisation said its UK retail sales in the six weeks to December 28 were up 10 percent on the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>It said in a statement that for the full 12 months to December 28, 1996 it recorded &quot;an encouraging increase in UK retail sales and this will contribute to operating profits significantly ahead of 1995.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier, Littlewoods announced that it had bought agency mail order business Freemans from British retailer Sears Plc for 395 million stg cash.  </p>
<p>Referring to sales growth in the Christmas 1996 period, Littlewoods said this was underpinned by strong sales in its home shopping business which rose by 12.6 percent, boosted by a significant increase in sales per agent in its agency business and growth in its new Index Extra direct catalogue sales.</p>
<p>It said sales at its high street Index stores were up 11.7 percent in total compared to a year ago, and by 6.6 percent on a like-for-like basis.</p>
<p>Sales at its Littlewoods stores were 5.4 percent higher in total in the six week period, but 3.4 percent on a like-for-like basis.  </p>
<p>&quot;The performance of Littlewoods stores has been below expectations and we will be reviewing the current strategy for this division,&quot; the group said in a statement.</p>
<p>It added that it was changing its accounting reference date from December to April.</p>
<p>It said it would issue a second set of interim results in March covering the 12 months to December 1996 and results for the 16 months to April 1997 would be announced in July.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 71 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
