<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="304326" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippines cautious after USDA wheat rally.</title>
<headline>Philippines cautious after USDA wheat rally.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine flour millers are expected to take a cautious buying stance this year on concerns that world wheat prices may jump further after a recent U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) report, traders said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will likely buy only on a need basis. We see lower wheat imports because of high prices. The local market looks bleak now,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The USDA reported on Friday that 1997 U.S. winter wheat crop seedings were estimated at 48.22 million acres, off seven percent from 1996 and the lowest planted acreage since 1978. The USDA estimate of 1996 U.S. corn production at 9.29 billion bushels was slightly below trade expectations of 9.38 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States is basically saying that there is less wheat acreage so that grain supply is tighter. It only means that U.S. wheat prices are about to go higher at least in the immediate period,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>In a knee-jerk reaction, traders said Philippine flour mills bought 40,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat for February shipment shortly after the USDA report was released.  </p>
<p>The Philippines buys its wheat requirements largely from the United States. But one trader said that prices of U.S. wheat may be tempered by increasing competition from wheat exporting countries such as Australia and Canada.</p>
<p>&quot;Moreover, the issue that potassium bromate used in making bread is carcinogenic in large doses is still unsettling. This may further dampen demand for wheat. Local buyers may not be consuming as much as they have,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Last year, fears that potassium bromate, used in local bakery products, may cause cancer hit domestic wheat demand.  </p>
<p>Traders said they expect local flour millers to buy between 1.8 million and 2.1 million tonnes of wheat this year.</p>
<p>In 1995, Philippine flour millers imported 2.4 million tonnes of wheat, mainly from the United States.</p>
<p>Philippine agriculture Secretary Salvador Escudero earlier said he expected the country to import up to 500,000 tonnes of corn due to a projected local production shortfall.</p>
<p>Agriculture officials were not immediately available for comment regarding the impact of the USDA report.  </p>
<p>The Department of Trade and Industry said the price of hard flour, which is used in making bread, was steady at 290 pesos per 25 kg bag, while the price of soft flour, used in making cakes and pastries, was also unchanged at 260 pesos.</p>
<p>Traders said the average retail price of white corn was at 11.93 pesos a kg from 11.88 pesos last week and yellow corn at 10.71 pesos per kg from 10.72 pesos.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
