<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="304340" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan signs nuclear waste pact with N.Korea.</title>
<headline>Taiwan signs nuclear waste pact with N.Korea.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>State utility Taiwan Power Co said on Monday it would ship 60,000 barrels of Taiwan's nuclear waste to Stalinist recluse North Korea and was seeking further deals with Russia and the Marshall Islands. The deal was signed on Saturday and the 60,000 barrels would be shipped to North Korea within two years, company president Hsi Shih-chi told reporters in Taipei.</p>
<p>&quot;We also are continuing to contact the Marshall Islands and Russia,&quot; Hsi said on state-funded television.</p>
<p>Under the contract, Taipower has an option to ship a total of up to 200,000 barrels of nuclear waste to North Korea.</p>
<p>Hsi would not disclose financial arrangements with impoverished North Korea, which presumably extracted a substantial cash payment in exchange for agreeing to take the waste.</p>
<p>&quot;We have an agreement with the North Korean side not to reveal the expenses for handling the nuclear waste,&quot; a Taipower spokesman said by telephone.</p>
<p>The utility offered in August 1996 to pay T$3.2 billion (US$116 million) to local governments and residents in Taiwan if they could offer a dump for the nuclear waste.</p>
<p>North Korea's domestic nuclear programme has fuelled a destabilising row with capitalist rival South Korea and the United States in recent years.</p>
<p>Pyongyang entered a landmark pact with Washington in 1995, agreeing to allow international inspections and replace its Soviet-era reactors with modern Seoul-financed light-water ones that produce less weapons-grade plutonium.</p>
<p>The deal has been threatened by renewed sabre-rattling and military provocations along the world's last Cold War frontier.</p>
<p>Taipei decided in July 1996 to stop dumping nuclear waste at its tiny Lanyu island, Taiwan's only nuclear waste dump, after strong protests by local aboriginals and growing numbers of anti-nuclear activists.</p>
<p>Since 1982, Taiwan has stored 97,672 barrels of nuclear waste at Lanyu, nearing its capacity of 98,112 barrels, according to official figures.</p>
<p>Taipower has promised to remove all nuclear waste from Lanyu by 2002 and has been seeking alternate sites overseas.</p>
<p>&quot;The North Korea contract will enable us to proceed ahead of schedule,&quot; the Taipower spokesman said.</p>
<p>Taiwan has three nuclear power plants and the government has authorised construction of a fourth in northern Taipei county.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I15000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
