<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="30432" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital markets closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital markets closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>French bond futures rose sharply from their lows and closed unchanged after weaker than expected U.S. economic data surprised markets.</p>
<p>The U.S. National Association of Purchasing Management's August index was reported at 52.6, up from 50.2 the month before and lower than the 52.9 reading analysts expected.</p>
<p>The report lifted debt markets around the world and France was no exception, but The market's gains were limited by worries about France's gross domestic product, due to be reported at 0645 GMT on Wednesday. Analysts expect French second quarter GDP to show a decline of between 0.2 percent and 0.4 percent.  </p>
<p>At 1515 GMT, the franc was trading at 3.4239 per mark.</p>
<p>Wyplosz said that the government had no other policy tools to boost growth, given restraints on public spending contained in the Maastricht treaty.</p>
<p>He suggested the Bank of France could manage a fall in the franc to 3.75 per mark without losing credibility, while maintaining the status quo would give the impression the central bank was locking itself into an indefensible position.</p>
<p>The drop would also tell markets that there would be no other change in the level of the franc between now and the end of 1998 when currency parities are due to be fixed ahead of EMU.  </p>
<p>The U.S. cruise missile attack on Iraq, launched in the early hours of the day, had little impact on French markets, dealers said.</p>
<p>Friday's U.S. unemployment report is likely to grab the focus of French markets after Wednesday's French GDP release, they said.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
