<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="304512" id="root" date="1997-01-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: FEATURE - Festivals bring buried Philippine towns back to life.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Festivals bring buried Philippine towns back to life.</headline>
<byline>Uday Khandeparkar</byline>
<dateline>ANGELES CITY, Philippines 1997-01-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A board advertising &quot;New Models Tonight&quot; still hangs outside a nightclub in this northern Philippine town even though the dancing girls, the sleaze and glitter have long since gone.</p>
<p>The party here, as in other night spots in Angeles City, ended in June 1991 when Mount Pinatubo erupted, shooting millions of tonnes of volcanic ash into the sky.</p>
<p>Angeles City, which used to be an entertainment centre for U.S. soldiers posted at the nearby Clark Air Base, was one of dozens of towns and villages smothered by Pinatubo's ash.</p>
<p>Soon after the eruption, the U.S. closed Clark Air Base. Angeles City has since got back to a quiet life but dozens of other villages have disappeared forever under tonnes of lahar, or mud-lava.</p>
<p>The eruption and its aftermath left more than 20,000 families homeless. About 800 people died in the wake of the eruption, many of illness in evacuation camps, and scores more perished in the lahar flows.</p>
<p>But the residents of the area, most of whom are now staying in temporary housing provided by the government, have not yet given up. At festival-time, they go back to where their towns once existed and celebrate atop the lahar which has buried their homes.</p>
<p>DISCO DANCING IN LAHAR LANDSCAPE</p>
<p>One of the worst hit towns, Bacolor, celebrated its annual La Naval feast last month during which youngsters stomped their feet and swivelled their hips to loud music in the middle of the bleak lahar-dominated landscape.</p>
<p>&quot;The town rises&quot;, said a welcome banner, in a reference to the original Bacolor now lying under 25 feet (seven metres) of lahar.</p>
<p>Erlinda Santos, 60, was among those who came for the festival and hopes to return home for good one day.</p>
<p>Santos will wait until she can build a new home on top of the lahar. &quot;We'll wait till when the lahar dries up,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The optimists include the town's mayor Ananas Canlas. &quot;I want to correct the impression that Bacolor is no more,&quot; he told the Philippine Daily Inquirer newspaper.</p>
<p>The people's attachment to their hometowns forced the Philippine government to build a $54 million concrete dike in a bid to staunch the lahar flow.</p>
<p>The 23-km (14-mile) long dike, which rises to 6.2 metres (20 feet) at its highest point, caused much controversy, particularly after an earthquake and floods caused a portion to collapse last July.</p>
<p>FUTILE FIGHTING NATURE</p>
<p>It was futile to pour millions of pesos into fighting the forces of nature, critics said. They buttressed their argument with opinions from vulcanologists who expect the lahar flow to continue for at least another 10 years.</p>
<p>A foreign engineer working as a consultant to a Pinatubo-related project agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no real engineering intervention possible,&quot; said the consultant, who did not want to be named.</p>
<p>Large sums of money were also spent on new roads and bridges after the eruption but they are now buried under lahar.</p>
<p>The Asian Development Bank (ADB), which set up rehabilitation projects soon after the eruption, was one of the agencies which had to change its plans after each monsoon.</p>
<p>The ADB is funding the construction of roads and bridges as an alternative to the main arteries that were washed away.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a problem as we have to reassess infrastructure needs as the lahar takes new twists and turns,&quot; Tom Walsh, ADB's senior programme officer for the Philippines, said.</p>
<p>WASTELAND BUT FERTILE FOR SUPERSTITIONS</p>
<p>On a recent visit to the lahar-stricken area, Bernie Bulman, a consultant to the ADB project, showed reporters the wasteland on which new roads and bridges had been constructed.</p>
<p>Pointing to a vast expanse of undulating greyish land shimmering in the heat, Bulman said: &quot;We rehabilitated this road in 1993 but now it is under 10 metres of ash.&quot;</p>
<p>A few hundred metres away, the endless expanse seemed punctuated by three stumps. A closer look revealed they were the steeples of a church buried under lahar.</p>
<p>The desolate ground has proved fertile for superstitions among the Aeta tribe, which lived on the slopes of Pinatubo.</p>
<p>&quot;For 600 years Pinatubo slept and suddenly it brought destruction. The Aetas say the Gods are angry because people are trekking up in the mountain,&quot; a government official in charge of relief operations for the Pinatubo victims said.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe they are right.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANGELES CITY, Philippines"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
