<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="30451" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: European allies split over U.S. strike on Iraq.</title>
<headline>European allies split over U.S. strike on Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Paul Taylor</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European allies were split over the United States' cruise missile strike on Iraq on Tuesday but united in their hope that the conflict would not escalate during the U.S. presidential election campaign.</p>
<p>Britain, Germany and NATO Secretary-General Javier Solana strongly supported President Bill Clinton's 27-missile blitz on air defence targets in southern Iraq in punishment for Baghdad's army offensive in Kurdish regions of northern Iraq.</p>
<p>But France and Spain refused to endorse the American strike, questioning its justification and timing, and several European officials suggested U.S. electoral politics was a key motive.</p>
<p>Despite its reservations, Paris, one of the Gulf War allies who fought to oust Iraqi invasion troops from Kuwait in 1991, went along with an extension of a no-fly zone over southern Iraq, policed by the U.S., British and French air forces.</p>
<p>As often, Britain was Washington's most vociferous supporter and apparently the only ally to provide logistical support.</p>
<p>&quot;We strongly support the action that has been taken by the U.S. against Iraq,&quot; British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind told a news conference in the Mongolian capital of Ulan Bator.</p>
<p>Defence Secretary Michael Portillo said Britain had been given unspecified logistics support for the raid, conducted from U.S. warships in the Gulf and B-52 bomber aircraft. He said more strikes should not be ruled out.</p>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel called the U.S. attacks an &quot;appropriate and justified&quot; response to Iraqi military attacks against Kurds in the north.</p>
<p>&quot;The Iraqi side violated the (Kurdish) safety zone in northern Iraq and caused a great amount of bloodshed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Denmark, Norway and Portugal also backed Washington.</p>
<p>But France, Germany's closest European partner, differed publicly, highlighting the absence of a common European Union foreign policy despite frequent attempts to forge one.</p>
<p>French Foreign Ministry spokesman Jacques Rummelhardt said Iraq had not violated any U.N. resolutions by taking action on its own soil at the request of one of the main Kurdish factions.</p>
<p>That implicitly challenged the legality of the U.S. strike.</p>
<p>&quot;France expresses its concern at the development of the situation in Iraq,&quot; a Foreign Ministry statement said, noting Paris was informed in advance of the U.S. strike but pointedly omitting any statement of French support.</p>
<p>French officials said Clinton telephoned French President Jacques Chirac on Monday night to inform him of the unilateral U.S. operation and the French leader voiced his differences.</p>
<p>Spanish Foreign Minister Abel Matutes said: &quot;(Our reaction) is one of understanding, although we would have wanted that armed intervention to be, at least, postponed.&quot;</p>
<p>Italy called the U.S. attack &quot;an inevitable response&quot; to Iraq's failure to respect U.N. resolutions but stopped short of expressing outright support and said it was consulting its partners on ways to prevent the situation escalating.</p>
<p>Several European officials said privately they were concerned that Clinton's action, under pressure from Republican challenger Bob Dole in the run-up to the November 5 U.S. election, should not lead to an escalation in the Gulf.</p>
<p>A French military analyst, retired colonel Jean-Louis Dufour, said publicly what several European officials whispered off the record: &quot;Politically, it is clear that Saddam Hussein and Bill Clinton are objective allies.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the U.S. strikes served the Iraqi leader at home and in the Arab world, by painting him as a victim of American imperialism, while they also served Clinton, pitting him as a &quot;war leader&quot; against America's most-hated foe.</p>
<p>&quot;A few weeks ago, I thought the Amerians were looking for any excuse to strike Iran militarily...They've struck Iraq instead. But the result is the same, the aim is to show that you are a war leader,&quot; Dufour said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
