<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="304952" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natl Health, Rural/Metro in pact.</title>
<headline>Natl Health, Rural/Metro in pact.</headline>
<dateline>PHOENIX 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>National Health Enhancement Systems Inc and Rural/Metro Corp Tuesday said they signed a joint business development and distribution agreement.</p>
<p>Rural/Metro will market National Health's Call Center Services and information, technology and software products to its managed care customers.</p>
<p>The companies will also collaborate to combine telephone triage and medical transportation services to improve the responsiveness and cost-effectiveness of healthcare services in a managed care environment.  </p>
<p>As part of the pact, National Health's second personal health management call center will be housed adjacent to Rural/Metro's &quot;911&quot; communications center in Rural/Metro's new Regional Operating Center in Scottsdale, Arizona.  National Health's new 11,000 square-foot call center will have capacity to handle calls for up to 5 million covered lives.  The new center is scheduled to open in the summer of 1997.</p>
<p>In a related transaction, Rural/Metro made an equity investment in National Health of $2.5 million, which represents less than 10 percent of National Health's outstanding stock. The equity investment will fund expansion of National Health's Call Center-based personal health management programs for managed care and assist National Health in meeting requirements for the company's stock to be traded on Nasdaq's National Market System.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHOENIX"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
