<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="305045" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-MANAGERS GET NASTY WITH REFEREES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MANAGERS GET NASTY WITH REFEREES.</headline>
<byline>Gideon Long</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>It is a truth universally acknowledged that English soccer referees are always wrong.</p>
<p>The poor fools are given two linesmen for each match, equipped with a whistle, a notebook and red and yellow cards, and yet this season, they appear more incompetent than ever before.</p>
<p>Anyone who doubts this truth should consult a premier league manager, preferably one whose side is slugging it out in the bottom half of the table.</p>
<p>The sight and sound of a disgruntled coach plodding into the compulsory post-match news conference and blaming referees and linesmen for the shortfalls of their sides has become tediously familiar this season as the pressure on top managers grows ever On Saturday it was the turn of Middlesbrough's Bryan Robson and Leeds' George Graham to put the boot in.</p>
<p>Robson's problem was a Southampton corner-kick which led to a penalty which led to a goal which led to a 1-0 defeat for Middlesbrough which left them bottom of the table.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no complaint about the penalty but there certainly is about the corner. Everybody in the ground saw it wasn't a corner,&quot; Robson said.</p>
<p>Had he consulted all 29,509 spectators at the Riverside stadium on Saturday? Had he not realised that the one man whose opinion mattered, referee Gerald Ashby, thought it was indeed a corner?</p>
<p>&quot;I thought the referee and his assistants had a very poor game,&quot; Robson said. &quot;The referee let a few early fouls on Emerson and Juninho go unpunished and that meant Southampton could keep on doing it for the rest of the first half.&quot;</p>
<p>Not suprisingly, Robson's opposite number Graeme Souness was all sweetness and light in comparison. His side had, after all, secured three valuable points which lifted them off the bottom.</p>
<p>Not so at Reading last week when Southampton crashed out of the F.A. Cup and had two players sent off in a match which Souness felt should never have been played owing to the rock-hard icy pitch.</p>
<p>&quot;(Referee) Mr Graham Poll has a reputation among the professionals in the game as somebody who is trying to make a name for himself,&quot; the Southampton boss said after the 3-1 defeat. &quot;It's the second time in a week that he's made teams play when the pitch wasn't playable.&quot;</p>
<p>Would Souness have been quite so vocal if Southampton had won? We will never know. More importantly, why did he feel the need to run onto the pitch within seconds of the final whistle to make his views known to the referee?</p>
<p>Mr Poll had to be shielded by a steward who, fortunately, was a good deal bigger than Souness.</p>
<p>Match officials cannot win. While Souness lambasted one referee for allowing a match to be played and Robson criticised another for allowing too many fouls to go unpunished, at Leeds, Graham chastised a third for being too strict.</p>
<p>Never before has there been quite such a clamour of managerial voices having a dig at match officials. As soccer grows in stature as a sport and sucks in more and more money, the pressures of management -- not just on Kevin Keegan at Newcastle -- are turning decent men into sour-pusses.</p>
<p>&quot;The referee had a very poor game,&quot; the normally genial Graham said after Saturday's 3-0 defeat of Leicester. &quot;It was played in a good spirit but he booked six players which I thought was very sad.&quot;</p>
<p>Even Aston Villa's Brian Little, respected in the premier league as a man who thinks before he speaks, was peevish on Saturday. He thought his goalkeeper Mark Bosnich was impeded as he geared up for a goal-kick which led directly to a Newcastle goal.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt Alan Shearer tugged at Bosnich,&quot; Little said. &quot;I talked to the referee at half time and he said he hadn't seen it. If it is a foul these are big decisions to get wrong at this level.&quot;</p>
<p>In fairness to Little, he accepted the referee's decision saying: &quot;He hadn't seen it and if he hasn't seen it, he can't give it I suppose.&quot; But even so, that begrudging &quot;I suppose&quot; tells a story of a manager who feels hard done by.</p>
<p>Football players have long been infamous for the abuse they dish out to referees.</p>
<p>But screaming at an official in the heat of the moment when your team is losing and the fans are on your back is one thing. Moaning about a decision in the cold light of a post-match news conference -- a decision on an incident you viewed from the dug-out -- is quite another.</p>
<p>What is to be gained by complaining about the inevitable mistakes made by referees, who are hardly likely to revoke their decisions simply because they are aired in the media?</p>
<p>If the aim is to improve the general standard of refereeing, how is it to be achieved by simply griping about isolated errors?</p>
<p>When it comes to referee's decisions, soccer falls victim of its own simplicity as well as its burgeoning popularity and financial clout.</p>
<p>One reason for the sport's worldwide appeal is its refreshing lack of laws compared to, for example, rugby union or American football.</p>
<p>But it is this aspect of the game which breeds an assumption it must be an easy sport to govern: The fewer laws there are, the easier a match is to control. Therefore a referee who makes mistakes is obviously a bad referee.</p>
<p>Maybe the premier league's irritable managers can learn from the foreigners in their midst.</p>
<p>Chelsea's Ruud Gullit refuses to get bogged down in disputes with officials and Arsenal's Arsene Wenger was a model of diplomacy on Saturday when his Dutch striker Dennis Bergkamp was sent off.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not sure yet how players are judged here,&quot; the Frenchman told reporters. &quot;That is something I am still coming to terms with.</p>
<p>&quot;But I won't make a judgement on the referee. I will leave it to you.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
