<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="305205" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GDR REPORT-Korea rallies on rate expectations.</title>
<headline>GDR REPORT-Korea rallies on rate expectations.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Korean global depositary receipts (GDRs) rallied sharply in London on the back of stronger local sentiment and the prospect of lower interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;Strikes have not been a major factor in the GDR market; what people are waiting for is a cabinet meeting, which is expected to announce more market boosting measures and the expectation of lower interest rates,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>The HSBC James Capel Korean GDR index JCEAI gained 3.03 points, or 4.62 percent, to 68.57 points, with the premium over the local market at 49.47 percent compared with yesterday's 52.89 percent.</p>
<p>The Korea Composite Index rallied 4.1 percent, or 27.05 points, to a provisional close at 686.59.</p>
<p>GDRs had been up over five percent earlier in the session.</p>
<p>Traders said that the fact that just 50,000 turned out for what had been billed as the biggest day of strike action was positive.</p>
<p>&quot;Although it has not been a major factor for the GDR market, there is a feeling that the government is determined to get its way,&quot; said the trader.</p>
<p>Many value fund managers have begun to trawl Korea for bargain stocks, one cited banks and domestically-oriented manufacturing companies as bargains.</p>
<p>&quot;We are expecting rationalisation in the banking sector and a lot of these stocks are trading below book value,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Activity in India was muted despite another rally in Bombay and after trading flat for most of the day, GDR prices were marked lower at the close of trade.</p>
<p>The Capel Indian GDR Index ended down 0.47 points, of 0.67 percent, at 70.03, a premium of 15.21 percent over the local market, compared with yesterday's 18.45 percent.</p>
<p>The Bombay Stock Exchange 30-share index gained 39.10 points to 3,492.26.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been some profit-taking in the GDRs and they are not expected to go anywhere ahead of the budget and VSNL's GDR issue,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Indian overseas telephone monopoly VSNL is planning a $800 million GDR issue.</p>
<p>Traders said that there had been some good two-way business in Larsen &amp; Toubro, off 18 cents at $16.00/$17.00, BSES, off 25 cents at $21.75/$22.75, Arvind Mills, off two cents at $4.40/$4.90, ICICI, off 10 cents at $9.87/$10.62, and State Bank of India, off 23 cents at $18.25/$18.75.</p>
<p>The Capel Taiwan GDR Index flat, up just 0.07 points at 68.57, a premium of 5.96 percent after the Taiwan Weighted Index fell 51.71 points or 0.72 percent to 7,137.76.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign investors have seen these levels before and I suspect this is a market which is not going to move much,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>-- David Chance London Newsroom +44 171 542 5887</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
