<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="305259" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: Trial opens of alleged Rwanda genocide ringleader.</title>
<headline>Trial opens of alleged Rwanda genocide ringleader.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Kotch</byline>
<dateline>KIGALI 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rwanda put on trial on Tuesday a prominent politician accused of being a ringleader of the 1994 genocide of minority Tutsis masterminded by Hutu extremists -- despite being an ethnic Tutsi himself.</p>
<p>Froduald Karamira was a vice-president of the extremist MDR-Power party under the ousted Hutu-led government and is the most senior suspect held in Rwanda on charges of taking part in the mass slaughter of some 800,000 people.</p>
<p>Karamira was born a Tutsi but using a Rwandan custom he converted to become a member of the Hutu tribe, the majority that ruled Rwanda until Tutsi rebels ousted them from power and put an end to the three months of killings in July 1994.</p>
<p>Karamira is accused of being a leader of the Interahamwe militia that led the attacks in the capital Kigali and was allegedly responsible for inciting genocide through broadcasts on state-run Radio Rwanda and Radio Mille Collines (RTLM).</p>
<p>His defence lawyer, Paul Atita from Benin, immediately applied for an adjournment of 15 days saying he had never met his client before and had not prepared himself for the case.</p>
<p>Presiding judge, Jariel Rutaremara, told the court he accepted the request and adjourned the trial until January 29.</p>
<p>After the adjournment of Karamira's trial, the special court dealt with four other cases of little-known Hutus.</p>
<p>The three judges rejected Atita's application to defend three of the other defendants, saying his organisation, Lawyers Without Borders, did not yet have official authorisation to do so.</p>
<p>The second defendant, Leonidas Ndikumwami, a Burundian, was left without a defence lawyer and refused to conduct his own defence, as Rwanda's 1996 Genocide Law provides.</p>
<p>His trial for acts of genocide in Kigali in 1994 went ahead nonetheless. The prosecutor gave his evidence, prosecution witnesses gave theirs and after Ndikumwami declined to take part the presiding judge, Jariel Rutaremara, said the verdict would be read on January 20.</p>
<p>The cases against the three other defendants were adjourned until February 11 after a Rwandan defence lawyer, Andre Bimenyimana, successfully argued that the accused had not seen the legal charges against them.</p>
<p>Bimenyimana said afterwards Rwandan lawyers were unwilling to defend the top or Category One genocide suspects who face death by firing squad.</p>
<p>&quot;Lawyers here do not dare defend them. There is a lot of pressure not to. But I know some of the people in prison are innocent and in any case everyone is entitled to a fair trial,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At the end of the hearings, the five defendants were led out of the courtroom and boarded a pick-up truck for the return to prison.</p>
<p>Bystanders jeered at them, derisively shouting &quot;Power&quot; at Karamira, recalling the nickname for his extremist party in 1994.</p>
<p>The international human rights group, Amnesty International, has expressed concern at the conduct of Rwanda's genocide trials. Some suspects have had no defence lawyers.</p>
<p>Defence witnesses laughed as they were called to the dock to identify themselves in Kigali on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Why do you think I am here?&quot; laughed Odette Mushashi, as she presented herself before the judges. &quot;I am here to testify him,&quot; she said pointing at Karamira.</p>
<p>Rwanda's prosecutor has assembled 23 witnesses to testify against Karamira, who was arrested at Ethiopia's Addis Ababa airport last June and extradited to Rwanda.</p>
<p>Rwanda holds about 90,000 people suspected of taking part in the genocide but has only just started putting them on trial. Two Hutu men were sentenced to death in Kibungo on January 3.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIGALI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
