<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="305286" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</title>
<headline>S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African bonds ended a nervous day steady, recovering from an earlier political shock as Pretoria rebuffed the U.S. over proposed arm sales to Syria, while the rand was strong against a firm dollar.</p>
<p>The debt market was also taking a surprise jump in the money market shortage in its stride with traders predicting the jump back above the 10 billion rand would prove a temporary blip.</p>
<p>Dealers in both markets said underlying sentiment remained generally positive, and they forecast further gains on Wednesday -- especially if the money market shortage fell back again as expected.</p>
<p>&quot;The rand is following the South African bond market which basically looks firm. We've strengthened from where we were in the morning and I see it (the rand) strengthening further with next resistance at 4.65,&quot; said one currency trader.  </p>
<p>Bond dealers said the diplomatic clash with Washington, which came after the U.S. threatened to cut aid to South Africa if the arms sale went ahead, had spooked the market.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not anything that will cause a bear market in itself, but it's a worry,&quot; said one fund manager in Cape Town.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if he U.S. government doesn't take any draconian steps, U.S. fund managers could give us a vote of no confidence which could do us a lot of damage.&quot;</p>
<p>One bond dealer said some weak holders of stock who had bought over the Christmas holiday period had been squeezed out in the morning, which could prove healthy.</p>
<p>&quot;There's been a bit of a clear-out. But I think these were weak holders and now the yields could carry on down,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On the money market, the daily shortage jumped to 10.370 billion rand on Monday from 9.556 billion rand on Saturday, disappointing those who had been expecting an improvement in liquidity.</p>
<p>However, money market traders said the increase was a temporary blip due to a lack of expected government expenditure flowing into the market, noting that there had been no major outflows.</p>
<p>Leading banks kept their short-term rates unchanged with three-month NCD rates between 17.30 and 17.50 percent and the 90-day BA rate between 16.65 and 16.85 percent.</p>
<p>At the long end of the market the R150 bond was yielding 15.77 percent, virtually unchanged from the 15.78 recorded at 1400 GMT on Monday. The stock had started the day at 15.73 percent, before kicking up above 15.80 on the Syria spat and the high money shortage.</p>
<p>The rand was at 4.6690/6740 on the dollar from 4.6790/6840 at the local close on Monday.</p>
<p>Against the crosses, it was last trading off at 7.8017/57 on sterling from 7.8002/8132 while on the mark it was back above 0.34 for the first time since early October, last trading at 0.3405/10 from 0.3390/3395.</p>
<p>Dealers noted the market had little data to look forward to this week, although December car sales are due at 1500 GMT.</p>
<p>News on progress in meeting budget targets this year will come with December exchequer figures, due on Friday, which are expected to underline that revenue overruns have kept the government on track for a deficit of 5.1 percent in 1996/97.</p>
<p>Foreigners bought a net 80.76 million rands worth of South African bonds on Monday after selling 180.58 million rands on Friday, the Bond Exchange said. Nominal cumulative turnover was 4.29 billion rand from 9.33 billion.</p>
<p>-- Ben Hirschler, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
