<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="305357" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: BPH shareholders approve $100 mln Eurobond.</title>
<headline>BPH shareholders approve $100 mln Eurobond.</headline>
<dateline>KRAKOW, Poland 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shareholders of Poland's Bank Przemyslowo-Handlowy SA (BPH) approved on Tuesday the management's plan to issue up to $100 million of convertible bonds to expand the bank's lending, BPH said in a statement.</p>
<p>It said its extraordinary shareholders meeting voted in favour of management's proposal to issue up to 100,000 fixed rate bonds with a par value of $1000 each with maturity of up to five years and exchangeable for up to 1,994,000 shares.</p>
<p>The shareholders also approved the plan to issue the shares ex-rights and seek their bourse listing. @</p>
<p>The BPH shareholders authorised the management board to set the due date of the bonds the conversion rate at a later date.</p>
<p>Henryka Pieronkiewicz told reporters after the meeting that the proceeds from the issue would be mainly used to finance the bank's credit expansion, especially the growth of foreign currency credits.</p>
<p>She also denied media speculation that BPH would use the funds raised from the issue to finance a planned purchase of a stake in Powszechny Bank Kredytowy (PBK) due for sale early in the second quarter of 1997. @</p>
<p>&quot;The funds raised from the bond issue will certainly not be used for a possible purchase of shares in privatised PBK. The bank (BPH) has enough money to buy a PBK stake it is interested in,&quot; Pieronkiewicz told reporters.</p>
<p>She said BPH had yet to decide whether the bonds would be issued through a public offering or in a private placement.</p>
<p>Pieronkiewicz, asked whether BPH planned to form a financial group with Kredyt Bank, PBK, Warta insurance firm and PBR bank said: @</p>
<p>&quot;I will not confirm or deny reports of a planned group of five Polish financial institutions. All I can say is that BPH is interested in taking part in the consolidation of the Polish financial market,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KRAKOW, Poland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
