<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="305308" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: PRESS DIGEST - Zambia - Jan 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Zambia - Jan 14.</headline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in Zambia's newspapers on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TIMES OF ZAMBIA</p>
<p>- President Frederick Chiluba has suspended a Lusaka high court judge and appointed a three-man tribunal headed by the anti-corruption commission chief to investigate him, state house said on Monday. No reasons were given for his supension.</p>
<p>- Chiluba has urged African universities to liberate themselves from foreign domination to reduce the number of &quot;flying consultants&quot; who depend on local expertise to prepare their reports.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ZAMBIA DAILY MAIL</p>
<p>-  Zambia's maize ouput in 1997 is likely to drop in spite of good rains because of the late arrival of fertilisers in the country, the agriculture ministry said on Monday.</p>
<p>- Council workers in the southern town of Livingstone went on strike on Monday for the second time in two weeks, disrupting normal social services in the tourist resort.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE POST</p>
<p>-  Former foreign affairs minister Vernon Mwaanga is a self-confessed drug trafficker, ministry of home affairs documents obtained by The Post have revealed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
