<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="305597" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Doctors' strike charged issue in Venezuelan reform.</title>
<headline>Doctors' strike charged issue in Venezuelan reform.</headline>
<byline>John Paul Rathbone</byline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unfolding wage talks between striking Venezuelan doctors and the government are increasingly viewed as a watershed event for Venezuela's hard-won fight against inflation and the place of its middle class in the aftermath.</p>
<p>&quot;Labour problems could well turn out to be the Achilles heel of the economic reform,&quot; said one New York-based analyst. &quot;It all depends on how quickly the government can deliver on its promises of economic growth.&quot;  </p>
<p>Although improving macroeconomic indicators may dazzle Wall Street, in Venezuela the doctors' strike crystallises the drama of a recession-battered middle class employed by, and increasingly dependent on, notoriously poor public services.</p>
<p>&quot;The strike is the beginning of the struggle of the middle class,&quot; the normally restrained El Nacional daily said in a recent editorial.  </p>
<p>After government-imposed privations last year, the administration is asking for more this year -- a tough political sell given the $5 billion bonanza of foreign reserves the government received last year from high oil prices and international confidence in the country's IMF-supported reform program, analysts say.</p>
<p>&quot;The economic program no doubt requires fiscal discipline ... But that should not stop the use of a substantial part of the gigantic revenues enjoyed last year for economic reactivation,&quot; El Nacional said.  </p>
<p>For many, the doctors' strike will show how far the government is prepared to stonewall or cede to union demands. Venezuelan ministers note that the outcome of the heated talks will set a benchmark for wider wage demands, and if the 300 percent increase sought by doctors were accepted, could set off waves of labour unrest.</p>
<p>&quot;The arrangement that is finally settled with the doctors will set a precedent for wider public sector pay settlements,&quot; Labour Minister Juan Nepomuceno Garrido said in a television interview this morning.  </p>
<p>Both government and doctors say they are sticking to their guns. So far offers of a 25 percent wage increase, in line with what's planned for the whole public sector, have been rejected by the Venezuelan Doctors Association.</p>
<p>A seven-day truce in the strike, which began December 27, expires Wednesday night. Authorities charge that 15 people died during the work stoppage, which left emergency wards unattended.</p>
<p>And pent-up wage demands are simmering, with Venezuela's one million public sector workers closely following the striking doctors' wage negotiations.  </p>
<p>University teachers have threatened to walk out Wednesday, leaving as many as 500,000 students out of class. Caracas judges are already striking over poor work conditions. And public sector engineers, architects, and dentists have said they might come out in sympathy with the doctors.</p>
<p>Venezuela's ministers acknowledge that inflation in 1996 of over 100 percent laid waste to real wages. And a tripartite commission that groups government, union officials and private sector leaders is currently struggling to find ways to improve social security payments and real wages.  </p>
<p>But in a second breath, the ministers are also urging public sector workers to show wage restraint and tighten belts further to help bring inflation down to 25 percent this year.</p>
<p>The government, which has repeatedly stressed fiscal prudence for 1997, is scheduled to meet with IMF officials this week to discuss macroeconomic targets for the coming year.</p>
<p>&quot;If we don't keep a firm hand, we'll lose the ground gained and everyone must understand this,&quot; President Rafael Caldera, 80, said in his traditional end-of-year message.</p>
<p>&quot;The hydra-headed monster of inflation, of which we've cut off a head, could come back,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>((-- Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
