<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="305579" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: FORECAST - Brazil eyes record trade gap in Dec.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Brazil eyes record trade gap in Dec.</headline>
<byline>John Miller</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil looks set to post a record $1.5 billion trade deficit in December, which would push the country's 1996 trade gap to an all-time high of $5.2 billion, economists said.</p>
<p>Larger-than-expected consumer and capital goods imports coupled with weak exports are being blamed for December's anticipated whopping gap, nearly double November's $853 million deficit.  </p>
<p>Also, many importers increased orders last month to avoid start-up problems with the government's new computerized import registry SISCOMEX, which came on line in January.</p>
<p>Brazil's Ministry of Commerce and Industry said last week that December exports totaled $3.78 billion, slightly lower than market expectations. The ministry was due to release the full trade balance for December and the year over the next two weeks.  </p>
<p>A recent Reuter survey of eight investment banks and research firms forecast a December trade gap of $1.4 billion. But some contributors have raised their estimates over the past few days.</p>
<p>&quot;There are rumors now that at the end of the month the ports were full of capital goods and commodities,&quot; said Nilson Teixeira, chief economist at Rio de Janeiro investment bank Fonte Cindam.</p>
<p>Fonte Cindam raised its December deficit forecast to $1.5 billion from $1.4 billion and MCM Consultores upped its estimate to $1.7 billion from $1.51 billion.  </p>
<p>&quot;The problem is not the deficit but the failure of exports,&quot; said Dany Rappaport, chief economist for MCM Consultores.</p>
<p>Capital goods have accounted for much of the rising import bill in recent months, reflecting a positive investment mood in the country, economists said.</p>
<p>But exports have underperformed and are not expected to pick up until March or April, when Brazil begins exporting its agricultural crops.  </p>
<p>Exports of manufactured goods, however, are not expected to take off for at least another year because Brazil's industrial sector is still retooling and being fitted to compete in the global market, economists said.</p>
<p>Brazil's trade accounts have shifted into the red over the past two years on a strong local currency and reduced import tariffs. A $10.4 billion trade surplus in 1994 turned into a $3.51 billion deficit in 1995.</p>
<p>Economists see the 1996 gap coming at about $5.2 billion and are forecasting a $7-8 billion shortfall for 1997.  </p>
<p>Although the markets have speculated the Central Bank will accelerate depreciation of the real currency to boost trade accounts, economists said political events this week point to continuity in exchange rate policy.</p>
<p>&quot;The big bet in the market is that they are going to speed up depreciation,&quot; Rappaport said. &quot;But the political environment is too fragile and the government will not change exchange rate policy untill it is in a stronger position.&quot;</p>
<p>President Fernando Henrique Cardoso was dealt a serious political blow on Sunday when the largest party in Congress agreed to delay voting on a bill that would allow the president to run for re-election.</p>
<p>((-- Sao Paulo newsroom, 5511 248-5414))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
