<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="305660" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: OPINION - New Zealand's dichotomous economy.</title>
<headline>OPINION - New Zealand's dichotomous economy.</headline>
<text>
<p>By Hamish Macalister, Economist at WestpacTrust</p>
<p>WELLINGTON, Jan 15 - 1997 looks to have the potential to be an interesting year for economists, not least because of the potential for volatility amongst a wide range of opposing sectors, and the resulting impact on the accuracy of forecasting.</p>
<p>It will be a year in which competing economic sectors appear to be more likely to move in opposite directions than in unison. A prime example is the relationship between fiscal policy and monetary policy.  </p>
<p>The year will see the evolution of a new coalition government, with all the uncertainty of coalition politics which that implies.</p>
<p>What is known at this stage is that spending will be considerably higher than the previous government had initially intended, although debt will continue to be repaid and surpluses will be maintained (ranged around 2.5-3.0 percent of GDP).</p>
<p>Despite the fact that these surpluses are considerably lower than those forecast by Treasury just prior to the election, they are substantially more attractive than the position in which most other OECD countries find themselves.  </p>
<p>European countries will be looking to cut budget deficits through 1997 as they strive to meet EMU requirements, Australia is following suit and so will the United States.</p>
<p>Increased government spending is likely to underpin economic growth over the next few years, but here is where the other half of the picture appears: monetary policy.</p>
<p>Although the Reserve Bank will now be operating with a little more room to move, in terms of a wider target band for underlying inflation, they will not want to see inflation quickly move to the upper end of this band, threatening future breaches of the target.  </p>
<p>However, looser fiscal policy is likely to stimulate growth, demand and consequently, prices. The more that the government looks to be increasing spending, the more the Reserve Bank will feel compelled to act to prevent spiralling inflationary pressures.</p>
<p>Two other factors which could be under pressure to move in opposite directions over 1997 are short term interest rates and the exchange rate.  </p>
<p>Although we expect short term interest rates to track lower through to the middle of 1997, with a similar trend for the Trade-Weighted Index, New Zealand's interest rates will still look very attractive on the world stage.</p>
<p>Much of the recent appreciation in the currency has been driven by interest rate considerations via dual currency bond issues, samurai bond issues, eurokiwi's etc. Continued demand for these could place further downward pressure on interest rates, but upward pressure on the currency.  </p>
<p>Similarly, although this will not be the mix of monetary conditions desired by the Reserve Bank, the fact that they have officially published their assumption for the trade-off between interest rates and the exchange rate (a 2.0 percent increase in the TWI is equivalent to a 100 basis point fall in 90 day bank bills) means that it is difficult for them to complain as long as overall monetary conditions are consistent with their desired settings.</p>
<p>A related issue is the performance of the tradeable and non-tradeable goods and services sectors.  </p>
<p>The latter has been an area of constant concern for the Reserve Bank (although recent inflation data suggest it should no longer be such a worry).</p>
<p>With inflation coming through the non-tradeables side the Reserve Bank would like a mix of monetary conditions biased towards higher interest rates.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, what they have had is the reverse: monetary tightening coming through the exchange rate which depresses prices in the tradeable goods sector, i.e. not where the inflation is.  </p>
<p>A prolonged period with a relatively high exchange rate will only aggravate the problem.</p>
<p>Similarly, while the domestic sector has been performing relatively strongly, and is expected to continue to do so (albeit with slightly lower growth through the first half of 1997 and slightly higher growth in the second half), the external sector is being severely hampered by a relatively high exchange rate, thus reducing the competitiveness of New Zealand's exports.  </p>
<p>Again, the mix of monetary conditions has meant that the external sector is being depressed, whereas the source of inflationary pressure has been the domestic sector.</p>
<p>While the domestic sector heads in one direction the external sector heads in the other.</p>
<p>The current mix of monetary conditions risks a sharp contraction in exports, a substantial increase in the current account deficit, rising debt burdens and a more pronounced slowing in economic growth.  </p>
<p>Yet another example of contradictory behaviour could well be the level of confidence amongst businesses compared with consumer confidence.</p>
<p>While we generally expect to see relatively high levels of consumer confidence over the course of 1997, significant volatility in business confidence numbers is possible.</p>
<p>If we see higher levels of volatility in exchange rates and interest rates over 1997, and any signs of political instability, business confidence could be significantly affected, resulting in volatility in business investments and profitability.  </p>
<p>This leads on to the final point of this brief comment, which is the likelihood of increased volatility (and therefore risk) throughout the economy, as a result of so many contradictory factors.</p>
<p>From 1994 through to 1996 we saw a gradually slowing pace of economic growth, but it is possible over the next few years that transitions will not be so smooth.</p>
<p>In that sense, 1997 has the potential to be an interesting year, but not an easy one, for economists.  </p>
<p>Note - The opinions expressed in this article represent the views of the author only. They should not be seen as reflecting the views of Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
