<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="305770" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Deputy Attorney General Gorelick resigns post.</title>
<headline>Deputy Attorney General Gorelick resigns post.</headline>
<byline>James Vicini</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deputy Attorney General Jamie Gorelick, who has served in the Justice Department's number two spot since early 1994, announced her resignation Tuesday, creating another senior vacancy at the agency.</p>
<p>Gorelick, who won a reputation as a tough, demanding manager in running the department's sprawling operations, said she was resigning &quot;to return to private life.&quot;</p>
<p>Justice Department officials said Gorelick, who has been responsible as a senior legal troubleshooter for a number of high-profile criminal cases, was undecided on her future plans.</p>
<p>The Justice Department said in a statement announcing the resignation that Gorelick will remain in office long enough to help Attorney General Janet Reno assemble a team to lead the agency during President Clinton's second term.</p>
<p>In picking his Cabinet for his second term, Clinton had considered Gorelick among the various candidates for the top jobs at the Defence Department and at the CIA. But he named Maine Sen. William Cohen as defence secretary and White House National Security Adviser Anthony Lake to run the CIA.</p>
<p>Gorelick also lost out on the possibility of getting the top job at the Justice Department when Clinton last month decided to keep Reno as the nation's top law enforcement and legal official.</p>
<p>Gorelick's departure creates yet another senior Justice Department position that must be filled.</p>
<p>Associate Attorney General John Schmidt, the department's third-highest ranking official, already has announced that he plans to return to Chicago and may run for political office.</p>
<p>Assistant Attorney General Deval Patrick, the head of the Civil Rights Division, also has announced his resignation, and the White House must make senior appointments to head up the Justice Department's Criminal and Antitrust Divisions.</p>
<p>Justice Department officials said a leading candidate for the number two post would be Eric Holder, the U.S. attorney in Washington, D.C. He formerly served in the Justice Department's public integrity unit handling corruption cases.</p>
<p>Clinton first nominated Gorelick in 1993 as the Defence Department's top lawyer. She played a key role in crafting the Pentagon's regulations on the &quot;don't ask, don't tell&quot; policy allowing gays to serve in the armed forces.</p>
<p>When the Justice Department appeared to be foundering due to personnel problems and management woes, Clinton selected Gorelick as the deputy attorney general in February 1994.</p>
<p>While Reno took a more public profile in giving speeches on crime, pushing pet projects and using her office as bully pulpit, Gorelick worked behind the scenes in charge of the department's day-to-day management.</p>
<p>In 1995, the White House briefly considered Gorelick for CIA director, but the job ended up going to then-Deputy Defence Secretary John Deutch, a close associate of Gorelick.</p>
<p>Gorelick, 46, is a former partner in a Washington, D.C. law firm known for its work on white-collar crime cases. She is married to Richard Waldhorn, a professor of pulmonary medicine at Georgetown University. They have two young children, Daniel and Dana.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
