<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="305768" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks hit new records; bonds, dollar rally on data.</title>
<headline>Stocks hit new records; bonds, dollar rally on data.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue-chip stocks set another record Tuesday as long-term bond interest rates fell on economic news that eased inflation fears.</p>
<p>The dollar rose to the highest level against the German mark since July 1994 and rose to a 45-month peak vs. the Japanese yen.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average ended up 53.11 points at 6,762.29, its fourth straight record finish and sixth high of the year.</p>
<p>In the broader market, advancing issues led declines 1,800 to 802 on heavy volume of 531 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite, Standard &amp; Poor's composite and the NYSE Composite indexes also set new highs.</p>
<p>Stocks got an early boost when key economic indicators for December confirmed inflation remained at bay.</p>
<p>The Consumer Price Index's &quot;core&quot; rate, which excludes food and energy costs, rose only 0.1 percent, triggering a big rally in bonds that sent interest rates falling and gave stock traders a green light to buy.</p>
<p>In the bond market, the benchmark 30-year Treasury bond gained a full point, cutting its yield to 6.77 percent from 6.85 percent at Monday's close.</p>
<p>&quot;We had lot of reports today but most traders were hanging their hats on the CPI,&quot; said Robert Froehlich, chief investment strategist at Van Kampen American Capital.</p>
<p>Technology stocks were clear favourites for the day.</p>
<p>&quot;We had an across-the-board run on technology stocks,&quot; said Arnie Owen, director of equities at Kaufman Brothers.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a personal computer upgrade cycle going on in the corporate world and everyone is looking for a very good number out of Intel,&quot; he said, referring to Intel Corp.'s plans to release its quarterly earnings after the close.</p>
<p>Intel, the world's largest semiconductor maker did not disappoint, saying its fourth quarter earnings more than doubled to $1.9 billion amid surging sales of its popular Pentium and Pentium Pro microprocessors.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index jumped 15.45 points to a record 1,346.36. The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks rose 9.35 to 768.86, also a record.</p>
<p>The dollar surged to 1.5973 marks, its highest level since July 1994, following the release of subdued U.S. consumer price and retail sales figures for December.</p>
<p>The dollar rose to 1.5941 marks in late trading from 1.5887 late Monday. Against the yen, the dollar made a late push to break its early 117.04 high, but closed just shy at 116.93 vs. 116.48 yen.</p>
<p>Coffee prices rose to eight-month highs as speculators bought heavily on worries that supplies were falling faster than expected.</p>
<p>At the Coffee Sugar and Cocoa Exchange, March coffee futures ended 3.75 cents per pound higher at 122.20 cents, its highest settlement since May 17.</p>
<p>Overseas, London's FTSE 100 finished 60.9 points higher at a record 4,168.2. In Tokyo, the key Nikkei average of 225 leading shares closed 25.66 points or 0.14 percent lower at 18,093.13.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
