<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="306080" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Investors to feast on new US corporate debt issues.</title>
<headline>Investors to feast on new US corporate debt issues.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungry investors are expected to feast on a bounty of new corporate debt offerings as the list of deals continues to grow, dealers said.</p>
<p>Philip Morris was expected to top Tuesday's menu with a $500 million A2/A rated 30-year debt offering via Merrill Lynch &amp; Co, expected to price, sources said.</p>
<p>Price talk on the issue was seen between 100 and 103 basis points over comparable U.S. Treasuries.  </p>
<p>High-grade syndicate sources said they heard talk on Tuesday that US West Inc unit, US West Capital Funding, would increase the size of its planned $2.0 billion four-part debt offering by adding another tranche.</p>
<p>&quot;Talk in the market is that the issuer added an additional tranche consisting of a century bond to the offering,&quot; said one syndicate source.</p>
<p>The A2/BBB-plus rated deal is now rumord to come in between $2.25 and $3.0 billion, syndicate sources added.  </p>
<p>Current price talk on US West Capital's offering is as follows, syndicate sources said.</p>
<p>-five-year, 55 to 60 basis points over Treasuries.</p>
<p>-10-year, 80 to 85 basis points over Treasuries.</p>
<p>-30-year, 110 basis points over Treasuries.</p>
<p>-40-year, put seven, 55 to 60 basis points over Treasuries.</p>
<p>*100-year bond is rumored to be added but the amount was not immediately available.</p>
<p>In addition, Quebecor Printing is expected to tap the market with its first-time ever debt offering, sources said.  </p>
<p>The $150 million BBB-plus/Baa1 rated 10-year issue is expected to be underwritten by Goldman Sachs &amp; Co may price as early as Thursday, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is Quebecor's first time in the market,&quot; said one high-grade source.</p>
<p>The issue is expected to be noncallable for life.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, with the improved tone in the Treasury market, dealers said, issuers are likely to tap the market now as the financing environment becomes cheaper.</p>
<p>Currently, the long bond is up 26/32 at 96-11/32 to yield 6.79 percent compared with 6.85 percent at Monday's close.  </p>
<p>Last Friday, a stronger-than-expected U.S. jobs report triggered about a two-point drop in the price of the benchmark 30-year Treasury bond, driving yields sharply higher and sending issuers to the sidelines.</p>
<p>Among other issues, Bank Nationale de Paris is expected to issue $350 million in either 10 or 12-year subordinated notes via Salomon Brothers. The deal is expected to be launched on Wednesday, syndicate sources said.</p>
<p>Leucadia National Corp is also expected tap the market with a $150 million 30-year capital securities deal with a ten-year call, dealers said.  </p>
<p>Also, BankAmerica Corp is expected to tap the market with $450 million in A1/A-minus rated trust preferred securities due 2026.</p>
<p>TCI Communications Inc is preparing a $500 million trust preferred securities deal for one day this week via Lehman Brothers, sources said.</p>
<p>Baxter International is expected to tap the market with a two-part $450 million A3/A rated debt offering via Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.</p>
<p>The deal is expected to consist of a $250 million 10-year issue and $200 million in 30-year debt, sources said.  </p>
<p>High-yield issuers are also expected to remain busy with offerings, dealers said.</p>
<p>CFP Holdings is expected to tap the 144A market with $110 million in seven-year guaranteed senior notes via NationsBank Capital Markets.</p>
<p>Imperial Credit Industries Inc is expected to issue $175 million in B1/B-plus rated 144A senior notes due 2007 via Lehman Brothers.</p>
<p>Vintage Petroleum is expected to set $100 million in 12-year senior subordinated notes via Salomon Brothers.</p>
<p>Electronic Retailing Systems International Inc is expected to bring $100 million (proceeds) in 144A senior discount notes ue 2004 via CS First Boston.</p>
<p>LDM Technologies Inc is expected to issue $100 million in 144A senior subordinated notes due 2007 via Smith Barney.</p>
<p>Tenet HealthCare is expected to bring a three-part debt offering consisting of $200 million in notes due 2003 and $600 million in notes due 2005 and $500 million in notes due 2007, sources said.</p>
<p>The deal is expected to be underwritten by Donaldson Lufkin &amp; Jenrette Securities.</p>
<p>--Nancy Leinfuss, 212-859-1675</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
