<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="306090" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. shuttle closes in on Russia's Mir.</title>
<headline>U.S. shuttle closes in on Russia's Mir.</headline>
<byline>Steven Young</byline>
<dateline>JOHNSON SPACE CENTRE, Texas 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. shuttle crew went for a run on a revolutionary space exercise machine on Tuesday as Atlantis raced toward a linkup with Russia's Mir space station.</p>
<p>The shuttle was due to dock with Mir on Tuesday night to pick up John Blaha, who has been in orbit since September, and drop off his replacement Jerry Linenger for a four-month stay.</p>
<p>As the shuttle closed in on Mir, three shuttle astronauts worked out on an experimental treadmill, which floats in mid-air like a magic carpet.</p>
<p>NASA wants to use the device aboard the international space station where delicate microgravity experiments can easily be upset by the vibration of exercise. The device uses gyroscopes to keep it steady during workouts.</p>
<p>It took astronauts Marsha Ivins, Jeff Wisoff, and Linenger longer than expected to assemble the device in the orbiter's cramped middeck area.</p>
<p>In anticipation of the orbital workout, the crew was woken on Monday evening to the sounds of &quot;It Keeps You Runnin,&quot; a popular 1970s song by the Doobie Brothers.</p>
<p>As the astronauts began their third day in space, Atlantis was trailing Mir at a distance of 6,300 miles (10,140 km) and was gaining on it at a rate of 570 miles (920 km) with each 90-minute orbit of the globe.</p>
<p>Shuttle commander Mike Baker fine-tuned the shuttle's approach to Mir with a rocket firing on Tuesday. The two craft were due to come together at 10:53 p.m. EST (0353 GMT) high above the China-Mongolia border. It will the shuttle's fifth visit to Mir.</p>
<p>In addition to the crew swap, Atlantis' was to deliver 3,600 pounds (1,630 kg) of food and other supplies. The cash-strapped Russian space agency has cutback its cargo deliveries to Mir and now relies on the U.S. shuttle for close to half of its resupply needs.</p>
<p>Linenger will be the fourth U.S. astronaut to live aboard Mir as NASA learns to work with Russia before embarking on the international space station project later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;It is incredible that once two great superpowers who were enemies with nuclear missiles aimed at each other are now holding hands,&quot; Blaha told NASA Administrator Daniel Goldin on Tuesday in a telephone call from Mir.</p>
<p>&quot;That's even way beyond, science, NASA and space flight as far as the impact that can have on world peace.&quot;</p>
<p>Blaha said he had not really missed anything while he was away from earth apart from his wife of 30 years, Brenda.</p>
<p>&quot;I missed my wife,&quot; he said. &quot;I hadn't realised how much the separation would hit me.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHNSON SPACE CENTRE, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
