<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="306017" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US money managers cut US debt exposure in week-MCM.</title>
<headline>US money managers cut US debt exposure in week-MCM.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. fixed-income managers shortened the durations of their U.S. debt portfolios in the past week, according to an MCM MoneyWatch Inc survey.</p>
<p>The weekly survey showed durations as a percentage of benchmark slipped to 107.5 percent--the lowest measure since November 4--in the week ended January 13, compared with 108.0 percent in the prior week.</p>
<p>A duration reading above 100 percent indicates the group of investors polled is mostly long on the market.</p>
<p>A portfolio's duration represents its average maturity and is used by portfolio managers to calculate exposure to risk.</p>
<p>In the &quot;next likely move&quot; category, portfolio managers representing 17 percent of total assets in the survey said they would &quot;buy,&quot; compared with 31 percent the prior week.</p>
<p>Strategists leaning toward &quot;sell&quot; dipped to 19 percent, down from 27 percent in the week ended January 6.</p>
<p>Sixty-four percent of managers said they were &quot;neutral&quot; on the market, up from 42 percent a week ago.</p>
<p>Cash as a percentage of assets rose to 2.48 percent, against 2.21 percent registered the previous week.  </p>
<p>The survey showed 29 percent of investors polled overweighted the 10-plus years duration sector, down from 30 percent the previous week, while 15 percent underweighted it. The remaining 56 percent were &quot;neutral.&quot;</p>
<p>In the five- to 10-year duration sector, 45 percent of investors polled said they overweighted the securities and 13 percent underweighted them.</p>
<p>The survey included 38 domestic participants, who manage about $110 billion in fixed-income assets. The poll is conducted weekly by MCM and usually is released on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Results of the survey follow:</p>
<p>   Category*					   Jan 13, 1996</p>
<p>   Duration percentage of benchmark		 107.5 pct</p>
<p>   Next Likely Move-Buy(B)/Sell(S)	17 pct B-19 pct S</p>
<p>Over(O)-Under(U) Weight Benchmark</p>
<p>   Governments				  19 pct O-59 pct U</p>
<p>   Corporates				   58 pct O-21 pct U</p>
<p>   Mortgages				    47 pct O-19 pct U</p>
<p>   Cash as a percentage of assets		    2.48 pct</p>
<p>Percentage experiencing cash</p>
<p>	In (I) - Out (O)			33 pct I-19 pct O</p>
<p>Over(O)-Under(U) weight Benchmark</p>
<p>   1- to 5-year duration sector	   29 pct O-35 pct U</p>
<p>   5- to 10-year duration sector	  45 pct O-13 pct U</p>
<p>   10+     year duration sector	   29 pct O-15 pct U</p>
<p>* Table provided by MCM MoneyWatch Inc consultants.</p>
<p>Results are dollar-weighted.</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1660 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
