<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="306146" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bonn refuses to give back East German land.</title>
<headline>Bonn refuses to give back East German land.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bonn government on Tuesday rejected mounting calls to reconsider its stand and return to former owners any of the land seized by Soviet authorities in East Germany right after the Second World War.</p>
<p>Chancellor Helmut Kohl's centre-right cabinet said it could not go back on the stand it took at German unification in 1990 that the 1945-1949 land reform could not be reversed, said Joachim Hoerster, a Christian Democrat CDU) parliamentary whip.</p>
<p>Former owners, ranging from one-time modest landholders to the remaining shareholders in the Nazi-era chemical concern IG Farben, have campaigned for years to get their property back, but Germany's supreme court has not supported their claim.</p>
<p>At issue are about 3.3 million hectares (8.2 million acres) or a third of East German farm land, mostly from estates of the Prussian nobility which was split up among peasants or turned into collective farms by Soviet occupation authorities.</p>
<p>The cabinet decision was a rebuff for Justice Minister Edzard Schmidt-Jortzig, who said this month the seizures were unjust and some confiscated land should be returned.</p>
<p>Politicians within Kohl's CDU have begun pressing for a policy change on East German property after learning that Russian military authorities had rehabilitated thousands of former property owners executed after the war as Nazis.</p>
<p>Redistributing land from former Nazis and Prussian gentry or Junkers to the people was the ideological rationale that East Berlin's communist rulers used to justify the land reform campaign called &quot;Junkers' lands in peasants' hands.&quot;</p>
<p>Der Spiegel magazine said Moscow had rehabilitated 6,000 victims of Soviet oppression in East Germany so far and another 10,000 appeals were still to be handled.</p>
<p>Many families who lost their property in the land reform have since brought the rehabilitation letters to state and local offices in eastern Germany demanding their property back.</p>
<p>The issue is highly political because Bonn inherited about a third of the confiscated property at unification.  Spiegel said this was worth about 13 billion marks ($8.19 billion) -- a sizable sum for federal coffers if Finance Minister Theo Waigel can sell it.</p>
<p>Bonn has always insisted that Moscow demanded the land reform be made irreversible as a condition to agreeing to German unification.</p>
<p>East Germany's democratic government backed this, fearing that any reversal of the radical land reform would only uproot the new owners and compound the injustice already done.</p>
<p>The former owners thought they had found a way around this when former Soviet President Mikhail Gorbachev denied that he had insisted a united Germany must respect the land seizures.</p>
<p>But the federal Constitutional Court ruled last May that Bonn had to accept this as part of unification.</p>
<p>Bonn has offered limited compensation to the victims and the opportunity to buy up to 500,000 hectares (1.2 million acres) of farm land at about 40 percent of market value. ($1=1.5867 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
