<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="306130" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French comments on ECB very worrying-Poehl.</title>
<headline>French comments on ECB very worrying-Poehl.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Bundesbank head Karl Otto Poehl said on Tuesday that French calls for a political authority to counterbalance the future European Central Bank (ECB) were &quot;extremely worrying.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The European Central Bank is the centrepiece, the cornerstone of Economic and Monetary Union,&quot; he told a conference on Europe's planned single currency, the euro.</p>
<p>&quot;For Germany, it was a basic condition to have an institution as independent as the Bundesbank,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>&quot;The fact that the highest French representatives, if I understood what I read, ask for control. That is something which puts the whole concept into question.&quot;</p>
<p>France wants a council to coordinate economic and exchange rate policies in the euro zone after the its launch in 1999 and counterbalance the ECB's role in fixing monetary policy.</p>
<p>It also says Europe should use the launch of the euro to fight against any competitive devaluation in the dollar.  </p>
<p>&quot;Our German friends say they do not want a 'soft euro'. Neither do I. Neither a soft euro, nor soft economic growth,&quot; French Prime Minister Alain Juppe wrote in a book published last month. &quot;I insist that these questions must not be left to the judgment of central bank governors alone.&quot;</p>
<p>Poehl, who left the Bundesbank in 1991 after nine years as president and is now a director of private bank Sal Oppenheim, was involved in talks on monetary union in the 1980s.</p>
<p>He said there had always been differences between France and Germany on monetary and exchange rate policies.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as exchange rate policy is concerned, I think there is a misunderstanding,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>During early talks, France wanted a clear exchange rate policy, while Germany had said this should be left to markets.</p>
<p>The compromise was that governments would decide on major changes to the exchange rate system -- for example a return to fixed exchange rates worldwide, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The day-to-day operation of the exchange rate system is the subject of the central bank, not the governments,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>If governments wanted the ECB to pursue a particular policy towards the dollar, it would ruin monetary policy and start a trade war with the Americans, who would never accept it, he added.</p>
<p>Moreover, the Maastricht treaty enshrined the independence of the central bank by forbidding its governors from taking instructions from politicians.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank is not allowed to accept instructions, neither from governments nor from parliaments, nor the councils of the central bank,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>The ECB governing council will comprise its president, vice-president and four executive members and the governors of national central banks.</p>
<p>Poehl also warned that calls by French officials for a appreciation of the dollar against the euro would undermine the credibility of the single currency from the start.</p>
<p>If you were an investor outside Europe with huge holdings in marks, knowing these would be swapped into euros in 1999 &quot;and you are told by high officials in France that this currency should be devalued, you would immediately start to sell.&quot; Such investors would sell marks even before the euro existed.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know whether the recent weakness of the mark is an indication this process is already underway. I don't think so, but it could easily happen,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Poehl, however, acknowledged a lack of democratic control on the ECB.</p>
<p>&quot;This institution will be very powerful. You can argue this is not very democratic, but as long as it is efficient, as long as it provides us with a strong and stable European currency, I would overlook that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Myra MacDonald  Paris Newsroom +33 1 42 21 53 81</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
