<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="306137" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Nestle, other firms breaching babymilk code - UNICEF.</title>
<headline>Nestle, other firms breaching babymilk code - UNICEF.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA, Switzerland</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations Children's Fund Tuesday said a number of multinational companies, including Nestle SA and Novartis, were putting infant lives at risk by aggressively promoting breast-milk substitutes.</p>
<p>The agency called on companies to disclose their marketing practices in each country and prove their compliance with a voluntary code adopted by the U.N.'s World Health Organisation (WHO).</p>
<p>Hind Khatib, coordinator of UNICEF's so-called baby-friendly hospital initiative, was asked which multinational firms violated the code. &quot;All of them,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>UNICEF backed a study released last week in London by an international group monitoring breast-feeding world-wide that found the code was being violated in Bangladesh, Poland, Thailand and South Africa.</p>
<p>The report, entitled &quot;Cracking the Code,&quot; was issued by a coalition of 27 churches, academic bodies, infant feeding experts and development groups.</p>
<p>It named Gerber, a subsidiary of Switzerland's Sandoz AG, Mead Johnson, Nestle SA, Nutricia and Wyeth as being among those violating the code in four countries.</p>
<p>Last year Sandoz merged with Ciba-Geigy to form Novartis. Wyeth is a division of American Home Products Corp.</p>
<p>The WHO argues that while mothers' milk is hygienic and passes on antibodies that enable babies to fight disease, substitutes involve adding water which is often contaminated in the developing world.</p>
<p>UNICEF appealed to manufacturers and distributors to uphold the provisions of the code, which itself calls on companies to monitor their own marketing practices and ensure they conform.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42390">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
