<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="306267" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Marxist ally flays India government's policies.</title>
<headline>Marxist ally flays India government's policies.</headline>
<byline>Narayanan Madhavan</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Communist Party of India-Marxist (CPI-M), part of India's ruling coalition, attacked Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's economic policies on Tuesday but said it had no plans to withdraw its support.</p>
<p>The CPI-M, which is in the 13-party United Front governing coalition but has no ministerial posts, said it would observe a week-long protest against rising prices next month and lambasted the government for welcoming foreign investors.</p>
<p>But it said it had no plans to cuts its ties to the centre-left government, which was formed last June after inconclusive general elections.</p>
<p>&quot;The sharp increase in the prices of wheat and atta (wheat flour) with stocks disappearing due to hoarding by big traders is creating immense hardships for the people,&quot; the CPI-M's politburo said in a statement following a two-day meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;Directly or indirectly, the government cannot absolve itself of the responsibility (for high inflation),&quot; CPI-M general secretary Harkishan Singh Surjeet told a news conference in the capital.</p>
<p>But asked if the party had considered withdrawing its support for the government, Surjeet said: &quot;There is no question of dissociating at all.&quot;</p>
<p>The CPI-M joined the other main communist party, the Communist Party of India, in speaking out against a possible rise in state-controlled petroleum prices.</p>
<p>Analysts have said the strain of oil subsidies will sooner or later force Deve Gowda's government to raise domestic prices for the second time. But the prime minister said on Monday that the government had no intention at present to do so.</p>
<p>The CPI-M asked the government to stop considering the export of foodgrains until adequate supplies were ensured for the domestic market, and demanded the government not raise the price of sugar supplied through government shops.</p>
<p>The communist party came out strongly against the government's recent decision to allow foreign investors to take stakes of up to 74 percent equity in Indian firms in certain areas, and reaffirmed its opposition to efforts to privatise the insurance sector.</p>
<p>&quot;Even the (domestic) industry has started opposing this,&quot; Surjeet said, referring to the move allowing 74 percent foreign stakes in some sectors. &quot;We want a reversal of the policy.&quot;</p>
<p>But Surjeet added that the government had also succeeded in smoothing relations between the federal and state governments, and improving relations with neighbours such as Bangladesh, with which India recently signed a landmark water-sharing treaty.</p>
<p>&quot;From that angle, there is a big achievement in the government to be taken note of,&quot; Surjeet said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
