<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="306475" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSTANT VIEW - U.S. Dec retail sales rose 0.6 pct.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - U.S. Dec retail sales rose 0.6 pct.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are comments from U.S. economists after the Commerce Department reported that December retail sales rose by 0.6 percent after a revised 0.2 percent decline in the prior month. Experts had expected retail sales to advance by 0.5 percent in December.</p>
<p>MICHAEL NIEMIRA, ECONOMIST, BANK OF TOKYO-MITSUBISHI LTD:</p>
<p>&quot;With revisions, retail sales now look stronger than anticipated,&quot; he said. &quot;That probably suggest something around (a) 3.0 percent fourth quarter consumption pace.</p>
<p>&quot;That seems to be the theme for the fourth quarter where consumption rebounded and (is) looking for growth.&quot;  </p>
<p>ANTHONY CHAN, CHIEF ECONOMIST, BANC ONE INVESTMENT</p>
<p>ADVISORS: &quot;Retail sales showed more strength than people anticipated, and point toward firmer growth in the fourth quarter. That is underscored by strong upward revisions of overall retail sales in the prior month.&quot;</p>
<p>He added, &quot;It is still questionable whether momentum will continue well into 1997. This is called into question by weakness in this month's eating and drinking sales. When consumers are optimistic, they tend to eat out more. It's a leading indicator of future retail activity.&quot;  </p>
<p>RAYMOND WORSECK, CHIEF ECONOMIST, A.G. EDWARDS &amp; SONS INC.:</p>
<p>&quot;The retail sales data are higher than expected but obviously the market isn't paying any attention to them.</p>
<p>&quot;The 0.6 percent sales gains are not a big deal. The holiday shopping season nationally was disappointing. It was not the boom that everyone thought it would be in September and October. Retail activity is not going to set the world on fire in 1997. There's no doubt about that.&quot;  </p>
<p>DAN SETO, SENIOR ECONOMIST, THE NIKKO SECURITIES CO</p>
<p>INTERNATIONAL INC: &quot;The retail report gives us a more upside risk for fourth-quarter GDP.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This month's performance is right in line with what we had forecast. We did see some upward revisions in the past two months -- up 0.2 percent in November and up 0.4 percent in October.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Take that together and plug it into your GDP equation and you are looking at even stronger growth.&quot;  </p>
<p>MARILYN SCHAJA, MONEY MARKET ECONOMIST, DLJ SECURITIES</p>
<p>CORP: &quot;The retail sales number, you had a tiny bit of disappointment (for the Treasury market), but the numbers were also very close to expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the increase in December was due to non-durable goods. Durables, excluding autos, was very weak.</p>
<p>&quot;The market probably didn't know what to do since the CPI number was so good.&quot;</p>
<p>((-- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1660))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
