<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="306465" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee futures called flat to 0.50 cent lower.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee futures called flat to 0.50 cent lower.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE arabica coffee futures were called to open unchanged to 0.50 cent lower Tuesday as traders expected some follow-through selling to Monday's losses.</p>
<p>New York arabica futures ended moderately lower in chart-driven dealings Monday, with March delivery falling 1.15 cents to close at 118.45 cents a lb after ranging from 119.30 to 117.00. Second-position May ended 1.00 cent lower at 116.40 cents, with the rest down 0.80 to 1.20 cents.</p>
<p>But some traders said a drop in U.S. certified coffee stocks could bolster the market and would at least provide underlying support.</p>
<p>Certified coffee stocks stowed in U.S. warehouses fell by 9,070 60-kg bags in the week ended January 10, to 23,388 bags, the Coffee, Sugar and Cocoa Exchange reported after the close Monday.</p>
<p>There were no bags pending grading or recertification, the CSCE said.</p>
<p>On the charts, traders pegged March near-term support at 116.50, followed by 115.25-115.00. Resistance was seen at 120.50-121.50, then 124.00.</p>
<p>Fundamentally, a Vietnamese official said Tuesday the country will produce 100,000 tonnes of arabica coffee by 2005 and plans to raise its output of robusta coffee to 300,000 tonnes by 2000.</p>
<p>Doan Trieu Nhan, vice-chairman of state coffee company Vinacafe, told an Asia coffee conference here that up to 100,000 hectares (247,100 acres) of land in the highlands of the country would be planted with arabica.</p>
<p>Vietnam currently produces only a small amount of arabica coffee.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Colombia's main public sector union could bring forward plans for an indefinite nationwide strike as early as next week in protest of the government's adoption of emergency economic powers, union leaders said Monday.</p>
<p>London robusta coffee futures were firmer early Tuesday. Most-active March delivery rose $5, to $1,294 a tonne at the midday break, while spot January was up $7, to $1,325. ((--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
