<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="306636" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GNI sees price rises in corn, wheat.</title>
<headline>GNI sees price rises in corn, wheat.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Commodity brokers GNI predicted price rises for wheat and corn later this year on higher imports.</p>
<p>In an annual update, GNI said wheat was likely to be broadly in balance in 1997/98 but imports could surge, creating a risk of a supply shortfall.</p>
<p>&quot;On this basis there is the potential for wheat to rally back to around the $4.50 level, even if there is no serious production problem in 1997/98.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Yield problems mean that a spike higher is possible over the next six months but the real gains in price will probably come in the autumn when countries assess their import requirements for the year ahead,&quot; said GNI.</p>
<p>Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) nearby wheat futures are at present just below $4 per bushel.</p>
<p>But GNI said the outlook was not entirely clear and prices later this year would determine the spring wheat acreage.</p>
<p>Prospects were less certain for corn and soybeans with farmers unsure about the level of acreage they will seed.</p>
<p>GNI forecast corn prices to rally above $3 per bushel by the summer as supplies were pointing to a deficit situation.</p>
<p>The outlook for soybeans was bearish with imports expected to fall.</p>
<p>GNI put world wheat production at 584,392 tonnes for 1997 and ending stocks at 109,861. Corn output was estimated at 567,636 tonnes and ending stocks 73,867.</p>
<p>-- Clelia Oziel, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8072</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
