<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="306713" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Koor to sell off Israel Edible Products.</title>
<headline>Koor to sell off Israel Edible Products.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Koor Industries Ltd intends to sell its 24.5 percent stake in Israel Edible Products, a food maker, to the U.S. company CPC International, a Koor source said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;In a few weeks Koor will complete the sale of its 24.5 percent holding in Israel Edible to CPC,&quot; the source told Reuters. He gave no sale price.</p>
<p>Israel Edible, also known as Tami, is majority-owned by CPC, which makes such products as Hellman's mayonnaise and Knorr brand soups.</p>
<p>Israel Edible produces about 90 percent of all retail margarine sold in Israel and also produces soups, mayonnaise, breakfast cereals and chocolate, many of the products under CPC brand names.</p>
<p>Koor, Israel's largest holding company, announced on Tuesday it had signed a memorandum of understanding with Greenfield Industries Inc to sell its wholly owned Hanita Metal Works to the U.S. firm.</p>
<p>Hanita and Greenfield both make cutting tools and related products. Greenfield is based in Augusta, Georgia.</p>
<p>A Koor spokesman said the sale was part of chief executive officer Benjamin Gaon's strategy to focus on Koor's core businesses: telecommunications, electronics, agrochemicals, building materials and energy distribution.</p>
<p>The Israeli Edible sale is part of the same streamlining strategy. Koor's other food companies include Shemen Industries, canneries and a meat processor.</p>
<p>The spokesman said no sale price for Hanita would be announced until due diligence was completed.</p>
<p>- Jeffrey Heller, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
