<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="30678" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Fate of sheep aboard fire ship still unclear.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Fate of sheep aboard fire ship still unclear.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The fate of 67,000 sheep on board a cargo vessel that caught fire on Monday bound for the Jordanian port of Aqaba from Fremantle, was uncertain, the Australian Meat and Live-stock Corp (AMLC) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Fifty-four crew members were rescued and one was killed, Lloyds shipping service said earlier from London.</p>
<p>Livestock vessels must meet Australian maritime safety standards, which stipulate animal welfare requirements  such as height, ventilation light, feed and water regulations, AMLC managing director Bruce Standen said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Standen said that Australia was at the forefront of animal welfare practices yet &quot;accidents such as this cannot be foreseen.&quot;</p>
<p>Jordan is Australia's single largest market for live sheep exports. In 1995 it imported 1.57 million head, worth an estimated A$58.2 million, the AMLC said.</p>
<p>Lloyds, quoting a radio report from Stavanger in Norway, said the ship's engineer fell overboard and was lost as the crew abandoned ship in the Indian Ocean near the Tanzanian coast.  </p>
<p>The blaze, aboard the 14,990 ton Uniceb, had begun in the engine room and spread to the crew accommodation. The crew of 22 Filipinos, 17 Chileans and 15 Indians were picked up by another cargo ship. None was injured.</p>
<p>The ship left Fremantle on August 23 for what was predicted to be a 16 day journey, the AMLC said.</p>
<p>Lloyds said the Uniceb, owned by Lugano-based Sistrin Services, was now unmanned and adrift in the Indian Ocean and constituted a danger.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100124">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
