<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="306874" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France drops toughening of anti-racism law.</title>
<headline>France drops toughening of anti-racism law.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The French government appeared on Tuesday to have shelved a bill to stiffen anti-racism laws as a response to far-right leader Jean-Marie Le Pen's public espousal of racial inequality.</p>
<p>The bill drafted by Justice Minister Jacques Toubon was conspicuously left out of the government-arranged agenda of the National Assembly (lower house) for the next six months as parliament reconvened after the New Year break.</p>
<p>&quot;As you can see, there is no hurry,&quot; Michel Pericard, head of the ruling Gaullist RPR party in the assembly, told reporters.</p>
<p>The bill, widening the grounds for prosecution of racist statements and stiffening punishment, has been criticised as double-edged and opening the way to restriction of freedom of expression.</p>
<p>Toubon had tabled the bill last October to plug a loophole in laws punishing statements seen as inciting racial hatred.</p>
<p>He had said Le Pen, leader of the anti-immigrant National Front, could not be prosecuted for saying that racial inequality was a fact of life as the law only prohibits statements directed against a particular race group and does not cover general verbal attacks.</p>
<p>Under the proposed reform, an individual would no longer have to cite a particular religion or national or ethnic group to be prosecuted for a racist statement.</p>
<p>The measure would punish a racist statement by up to a year in prison and a fine of up to 300,000 francs ($60,000). Sanctions would increase to two years in jail and a 500,000 franc ($100,000) fine if the remark were judged an incitement to discrimination, hatred or violence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
