<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="306987" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALTA: Malta fights tax evasion.</title>
<headline>Malta fights tax evasion.</headline>
<byline>Chris Scicluna</byline>
<dateline>VALLETTA 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malta's new Labour government wants the private sector to power the economy but is determined to get tough on tax evasion and will introduce new taxes to offset a larger-than-expected government deficit.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Lino Spiteri, presenting the government's first budget on Monday night, promised increased penalties and additional random audits of individuals and firms to deter tax evasion.</p>
<p>The government wanted to instil a &quot;culture of fiscal morality&quot; where everyone paid due taxes, he said.</p>
<p>Income tax would remain unchanged, he told parliament, but the government would increase a range of other levies.</p>
<p>&quot;The new taxes have been drawn up in a way not to harm industry and the economy. This government wants the private sector to be the motor of the economy,&quot; Spiteri told reporters.</p>
<p>The Labour government, elected on October 26, inherited a deficit of 112 million pounds ($309 million). He said this was three times the figure projected by the former Nationalist government a year ago.</p>
<p>The deficit amounted to 9.3 percent of GDP, with ordinary revenue totalling 446.1 million pounds compared with a projected 515.4 million pounds.</p>
<p>Most of the shortfall was in value added tax and income tax, where projections had been optimistic, the minister said.</p>
<p>Recurrent expenditure rose by 23.1 million pounds more than planned to reach 475.4 million pounds, while capital expenditure dropped by 16 million pounds.</p>
<p>Spiteri announced no new capital projects, but said projects underway would be sustained so that the rhythm of the economy would not be harmed.</p>
<p>Taxes introduced in the budget, ranging from higher car licence fees and petrol prices to a new tax on foreign travel, would contribute some 12 million pounds to government revenue.</p>
<p>Spiteri said, however, the strongest effort for a reduction of the deficit would be made through more efficient tax collection and &quot;more responsible&quot; government spending, with a reduction in waste and insistence on value for money.</p>
<p>The government, he said, would stick to its electoral promise to remove value added tax (VAT), but the system was being retained for a short time pending the publication of a white paper for wide discussion of government plans.</p>
<p>Spiteri said VAT would be replaced by a new system of indirect taxation later in the year. Care would be taken to ensure the new system did not affect essential items. Imports from the European Union would continue to be taxed at 15 percent, as at present, so as not to jolt the economy.</p>
<p>The minister did not give details on estimated tax evasion but said the government was considering setting up a Fiscal Authority to coordinate government sectors which collect revenue. The authority would also fight the black economy and promote &quot;fiscal morality&quot;.</p>
<p>As a first step a Commission for Fiscal Morality was being formed to educate people on the need to pay their taxes.</p>
<p>&quot;While we seek to instil this new culture, the government will step up its direct efforts at  fighting tax evasion,&quot; the minister said. ($=36 cents)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALTA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VALLETTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALTA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
