<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="306904" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: U.S. envoy declares Cyprus missile crisis over.</title>
<headline>U.S. envoy declares Cyprus missile crisis over.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Weeks</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. envoy Carey Cavanaugh said on Tuesday the recent Cyprus missile crisis was over and that &quot;soaring tensions&quot; in the Eastern Mediterranean had been brought under control for the time being.</p>
<p>&quot;The purpose of my trip to the region was to as much as possible reduce tension that really soared this year,&quot; he said after meeting the Greek foreign ministry's general secretary, Alexandros Filon.</p>
<p>He said some positive steps had been taken to reduce tension between rival Greek and Turkish Cypriots during talks on Cyprus on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear that this issue of missiles is no longer a crisis issue,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Cavanaugh received assurances from Greek Cypriot President Clafcos Clerides that recently purchased Russian anti-aircraft missiles would not arrive on the island for at least 16 months.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there is time to work on a solution of the problem so that we don't face any potential conflict in the future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cavanaugh called the Cypriot government's decision to buy the missiles a setback for efforts to find a peaceful solution to the militarily divided island.</p>
<p>The United States has made no secret of its plans to try to make progress on the Cyprus problem this year in the hope that this would ease tensions between feuding NATO allies Greece and Turkey.</p>
<p>Turkey invaded Cyprus in 1974 in response to an attempted coup, inspired by a then-ruling Greek military junta in Athens. Turkey has kept about 30,000 troops on the northern third of the island since, ostensibly to protect the Turkish community.</p>
<p>Greece has a military defence pact with Cyprus and has been working to coordinate defence strategies, and material, with the internationally recognised Greek Cypriot government.</p>
<p>Cavanaugh said he had made progress during talks on Cyprus with Turkish Cypriot community leader Rauf Denktash and Clerides on U.N. measures to reduce incidents along a ceasefire line.</p>
<p>&quot;I received from both Mr Denktash and President Clerides full support for an immediate implementation of a package of measures proposed in the past months by the United Nations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In Nicosia, Cyprus played down Cavanaugh's optimism that the U.N. measures were about to be agreed and signed by both sides.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still talking about it,&quot; Cypriot government spokesman Yiannakis Cassoulides said. He denied the two sides were on the brink of signing an agreement.</p>
<p>The U.N. proposals cover the unloading of live ammunition among troops on either side of the 180-km (110-mile) ceasefire line and unmanning sentry posts. It imposes a code of conduct for soldiers to follow.</p>
<p>Four Greek Cypriots and one Turkish Cypriot soldier have been killed in incidents along the U.N.-patrolled buffer zone since June, greatly raising tension between the two sides.</p>
<p>Turkey threatened military action several times last week to stop deployment of the S-300 system which the Cypriot government says is purely defensive.</p>
<p>Installation of the S-300 would provide Cyprus with a strong weapon for striking Turkey's air superiority in the region.</p>
<p>Cavanaugh will leave for Ankara on Wednesday morning.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
