<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="30690" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FAI's Adler sees solid 96/97 growth.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FAI's Adler sees solid 96/97 growth.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chief executive of FAI Insurances Ltd Rodney Adler said on Tuesday he saw solid growth for the company in the year to June 30, 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Our budgets are for a solid increase. I'm not talking two or three percent, it looks much better than that at this stage,&quot; Adler told Reuters in a telephone interview.  </p>
<p>Adler said if the first half of 1996/97 was as encouraging as FAI thought it to be now, the company would be likely to pay higher dividends this financial year.</p>
<p>FAI earlier said its net result for the year to June 30 turned around to a profit of A$10.04 million from a loss of A$89.84 million in the previous year.</p>
<p>Adler said FAI, which has cash reserves of more than A$500 million, was continuing its search for acquisitions in Asia and Australia. &quot;At the moment we have two companies which we are looking quite seriously at in Asia and have been for several months and we are doing due diligence,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Adler said he did not think an announcement about either of these companies was imminent. He said the company was continuing its organic growth in Asia.</p>
<p>Adler said the company was happy to remain conservative with its investment policy of largely avoiding the equity market.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the (equity) market has to have a correction of 10 percent minimum before any real change takes place,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>FAI was still in negotiations with two parties over its investment in the St Moritz Hotel in New York, Adler said. He said negotiations had broken down with a third party who had previously been the most active participant.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's a very large asset, it's well over A$200 million in value. It may be taking a long time but it need to take time to get the right deal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At 3.20 p.m. (0520 GMT), FAI shares were one cent weaker at 71 cents.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
