<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="30707" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ long-run growth potential 3.3 pct - Treasury.</title>
<headline>NZ long-run growth potential 3.3 pct - Treasury.</headline>
<byline>Vernon Small</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand Treasury estimates New Zealand's growth potential until the year 2010 at 3.3 percent a year in papers released to Reuters under the Official Information Act.</p>
<p>The papers show that in March Treasury revised its previous medium-term (five year) estimate of 3.8 percent growth down to 3.3 percent over the longer timeframe.  </p>
<p>The major elements of the change were a more pessimistic view of long-term growth in the labour force (down from two percent to 1.4 percent a year) and growth in capital stock (down from four percent to 2.4 percent).</p>
<p>Treasury's director of medium term policy Kevin Cosgriff told Reuters that in the current round of forecasting &quot;we are continuing to develop our thinking on the productivity component of trend growth rates&quot;.</p>
<p>That would be incorporated in Treasury's economic and fiscal update on September 12, a month before New Zealand's general election.  </p>
<p>In its May 1996 budget the government forecast growth of 2.6 percent in the 1996/97 March year, four percent in 1997/98 and 3.5 percent in 1998/99, but recently Finance Minister Bill Birch has said the economic cycle would bottom out at growth rates of around two percent later this year.</p>
<p>Among the papers released to Reuters was criticism by Australian academic Wolfgang Kasper of Treasury's &quot;too pessimistic&quot; economic outlook.  </p>
<p>&quot;While caution is an endearing NZ character trait and the electoral uncertainties suggest fiscal caution for 1996-97, a genuine forecast of real GDP (what is most likely, not what seems politically 'correct') should not only be based on an adding-up of the demand aggregates, but also be checked against the likely growth of the supply potential,&quot; Kasper said.</p>
<p>He said with &quot;mild further reform&quot; a trend growth rate of 4.5 percent might be conservative, and warned against &quot;underselling the medium-term consequences of reform&quot;.  </p>
<p>The Treasury papers showed earlier assumptions of labour force growth of one percent from population increase, 0.5 percent from migration and 0.5 percent from increases in participation were considered too optimistic. The total of two percent labour force growth was revised down to 1.3-1.4 percent a year. Treasury's analysts believe participation rates in New Zealand are high by OECD standards, the papers reveal.</p>
<p>The analysts said the key sensitivity was the net migration figure which would have to be more than 20,000 a year until the year 2010 if the labour force was to grow by two percent a year.  </p>
<p>They said: &quot;To the extent we are close to our estimated non-accelerating inflation rate of unemployment, we should not expect much impact on potential growth rates from (lower unemployment).&quot; Unemployment is currently 6.1 percent.</p>
<p>Treasury's lower forecast of growth in capital stock changed Statistics New Zealand's methodology which Treasury believes increasingly exaggerates the level of real computer investment.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate a current capital stock growth rate of 2.4 percent based on a constant real investment to GDP ratio. The key judgement is whether the future real investment rate will rise or fall,&quot; the analysts said in the March paper.  </p>
<p>As part of their revised outlook, the analysts raised their estimate of total factor productivity, defined as the difference between the output growth rate and the weighted average input growth rate, from one percent to 1.5 percent.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
