<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="30700" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ housing activity likely to cool - ANZ Bank.</title>
<headline>NZ housing activity likely to cool - ANZ Bank.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Inflationary pressure from New Zealand's housing sector is likely to cool over the short to medium term, ANZ Bank economists say.</p>
<p>In their September monthly economic commentary &quot;Focus&quot;, ANZ said that although lending growth remained surprisingly strong, the number of house sales had declined in recent months from the record highs experienced earlier this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect inflation from the housing group to moderate,&quot; ANZ said.  </p>
<p>Real Estate Institute of New Zealand statistics indicated the number of house sales in June was down significantly on the same month of the previous two years.</p>
<p>&quot;Indeed, real estate agents in Auckland reported a considerable fall in activity over the June quarter. This moderation in activity has allowed median house prices to ease back recently.&quot;</p>
<p>ANZ said the slowdown in house price growth was reinforced by Valuation New Zealand's provisional house price index for the June quarter.  </p>
<p>Although growth over the quarter was still positive at 1.7 percent, it was substantially down on the March quarter's 5.2 percent quarterly increase.</p>
<p>&quot;This slower growth was very evident in the Auckland area where quarterly growth moderated from nine percent in March to 2.3 percent,&quot; ANZ said.</p>
<p>ANZ said the current level of interest rates was likely to be underpinned by firm monetary policy until early 1997 at the earliest, which would continue to make the cost of borrowing relatively high.  </p>
<p>ANZ said some households may be starting to face some gearing or financing restraints given the substantial rise in borrowing over the past two years.</p>
<p>&quot;This may also act as a brake on further activity.&quot;</p>
<p>Furthermore, the slowing in economic activity was impinging on confidence levels and could be expected to reduce employment growth, which would again dampen housing market activity &quot;to some extent&quot;.</p>
<p>However, ANZ said the moderating effect on inflation would probably occur with a lag.  </p>
<p>&quot;Hence, over the September and December quarters, the risk that the housing group will comprise a substantial portion of underlying inflation is very real.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010022">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8500031">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E61">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
