<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="307151" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - UK BUSINESS NEWS - Jan 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - UK BUSINESS NEWS - Jan 14.</headline>
<text>
<p>- Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>-- GO AHEAD SHARES' RISE PROMPTS PROBE</p>
<p>Labour MP Dale Campbell-Savours has told the House of Commons that Go Ahead Group, the bus operator, is being investigated by the Stock Exchange in the seven weeks since it was shortlisted for the Regional Railways North East franchise. Go Ahead's shares have risen 41 percent since North Star Transpennine, a consortium of Go Ahead, the North East management team and French group Via-GTI, was shortlisted for North East in November.</p>
<p>-- WATER GROUPS REJECT BYATT DROUGHT RULES</p>
<p>Ian Byatt, water industry regulator, has criticised 15 water companies for refusing to accept new rules covering compensation payments to customers during drought periods. The companies accepted the principle of compensation but would not accept a legal obligation or allow Byatt to arbitrate in dispute cases. Nine, including Southern Water, were singled out for the strongest criticism because they were unhappy at Byatt's role as judge and jury in arbitration or were still considering their position on compensation.</p>
<p>-- JOHN LEWIS PLANS AIM FLOAT</p>
<p>John Lewis has announced plans for flotation on the Alternative Investment Market. However, this is not the giant retailing group but John Lewis of Hungerford in Berkshire, a small furniture business that has registered its name as a trademark under the nose of its larger rival. Founder John Lewis has agreed to allow the department store to continue using the name.</p>
<p>THE TIMES</p>
<p>-- SEARS HOPES TO PACIFY INSTITUTIONS WITH BUYBACK</p>
<p>Chief executive of retailer Sears, Liam Strong, has sought to placate institutional shareholders by promising the group would return 410 million stg to them through a share buyback. Most of the money for the buyback would come from the sale of its Freemans mail order business to Littlewoods for 395 million stg, leading to a loss of 220 million stg. The rest will come from the sale of a Glasgow shopping centre.</p>
<p>-- EUROPEAN OPPOSITION TO BA LINK INTENSIFIES</p>
<p>British Airways has insisted its proposed alliance with American Airlines is on track, despite growing opposition from the European Commission. BA says the final word on the deal lies with the DTI. European Competition Commissioner Karel van Miert has expressed his concerns over the deal in a letter to Ian Lang, President of the Board of Trade, claiming it would constitute an abuse of a dominant position and questioning whether it met the conditions for granting of an exemption under European law.</p>
<p>-- SHARES SOAR AS FEARS OF INTEREST RISE RECEDES</p>
<p>Renewed hopes that interest rates may not have to rise after a meeting between Chancellor Kenneth Clarke and Bank of England governor Eddie George has led to a surge on the London stock market to near record levels. Shares were also boosted by a set of subdued industry price figures, and a survey from the British Retail Consortium found that the Christmas season had been a &quot;nail-biting time for retailers&quot; which fell far short of 1980s-style boom conditions.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>-- TAXMAN &quot;BRAVED ARMED HEAVIES&quot;</p>
<p>The Old Bailey has heard that Michael Allcock, former worker at the Inland Revenue who tracked down wealthy tax evaders, braved armed Lebanese heavies in his attempts to reclaim taxes owed to the Crown. He said the Special Office, for which he had worked, was outside other Revenue procedures. He denies corruption charges.</p>
<p>-- MIDLAND EASES OVERDRAFT PAIN</p>
<p>Midland Bank has slashed the cost of borrowing and scrapped its existing range of current accounts in a battle for high- street customers. More than 4.5 million Midland Orchard, Vector and Meridian account-holders will be switched to the new Midland Bank Account which charges no fee on agreed overdrafts, unlike other major banks, and has a new, low borrowing rate of 13.3 percent.</p>
<p>-- BUYERS DRIVEN OFF BY WELCOME BREAK'S PRICE TAG</p>
<p>Potential buyers of Granada Group's Welcome Break roadside service chain, including Gerald Robinson's Heron Group and Whitbread, have snubbed the 370 million stg asking price. They have accused Granada's financial advisers, Lazards, of driving too hard a bargain, and Granada of leaving the restaurants in a state little better than when they were acquired from Forte last January. This leaves the field clear for National Express and several venture capitalists, including CinVen.</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>-- CABLE AND WIRELESS PLANS TO PAY OFF SENIOR STAFF</p>
<p>Senior managers at Cable and Wireless are being asked to take voluntary redundancies if a five billion stg cable merger goes ahead. They will be offered substantial extra bonus payments of up to 60 percent of salary, on top of any contractual severance payments. The catch is that the bonuses are at the personal discretion of C&amp;W's American chief executive Dick Brown, who joined the group last summer with a plan to shake up the internal management culture.</p>
<p>-- CBI REPORTS BOOMING CONFIDENCE IN THE CITY</p>
<p>According to a CBI and Coopers and Lybrand survey of financial services firms, the City is more buoyant than at any time since 1989, the peak of the last boom. This is further evidence of a bonanza last year among securities houses and other financial services firms. The survey showed confidence in the last quarter of 1996 rose at its fastest rate since the survey began, in 1989, and that profitability among financial services firms rose at its fastest rate since September 1994.</p>
<p>BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
