<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="307392" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan investors will not cut shareholdings - poll.</title>
<headline>Japan investors will not cut shareholdings - poll.</headline>
<byline>Michiko Iwasaki</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese institutional investors expect Tokyo share prices to fluctuate wildly in the coming months, but they do not have any immediate plans to trim their shareholdings, a Reuters investment survey found on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The recent plunge in stock prices has not made Japanese investors alter their weighting of Japanese equities in their overall portfolios as they think their current weightings are already set at low levels, investors said.</p>
<p>In last month's investment survey, the weighting for Japanese shares was lowered for the fourth consecutive month to 24.94 percent, down 4.17 percentage points from the previous survey and the lowest weighting since June 1994, when Reuters started its equities portfolio investment survey.</p>
<p>Fund managers said it was not a good strategy now to raise the weightings of equities in other markets.</p>
<p>They remain cautious about the high-flying U.S. market in the belief that Wall Street could face a tumble of up to 10 percent in the near future.</p>
<p>In a survey, Reuters asked more than ten Japan-based financial institutions about their investment strategies following the Tokyo stock market's massive loss of over 2,000 points in the past week.</p>
<p>Japanese institutional investors generally think that uncertainty over the Japanese economy and doubts about efforts by the government to carry out various reforms are the reasons for the recent stock price deterioration.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto said on Tuesday that Japan plans to carry out reforms to its administrative, fiscal, economic, social welfare, financial and education systems.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to know how serious the government is about carrying out those reforms,&quot; said a fund manager at a major institutional investor.</p>
<p>The fund managers said the Tokyo stock market is likely to perform well only when market participants see specific steps being taken to carry out reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;Half-hearted measures to deal with stock prices could only prompt selling,&quot; another fund manager said.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka, when asked whether his ministry was considering any special steps to tackle the recent stock plunge, said that its first priority was to put in place an already planned extra budget as soon as possible.</p>
<p>The abolition of securities transactions taxes, a change in the taxation system regarding dividends and land tax reforms are other measures that could pull the stock market out of its doldrums, fund managers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Tokyo market is likely to fluctuate wildly until March, probably April. The market has not hit rock bottom yet,&quot; said a fund manager.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
