<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="307350" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: RESEARCH ALERT - Kim Eng says buy Chuan Soon Huat.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - Kim Eng says buy Chuan Soon Huat.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kim Eng Securities on Tuesday recommended that investors subscribe to shares offered by Singapore's Chuan Soon Huat Industrial Group Ltd (CSH).</p>
<p>CSH, a maker and distributor of doors, conservatories and joinery products, offered 45 million new shares and 6.25 million vendor shares at Singapore S$0.35 each in an initial public offer on January 7. The offer closes January 20.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on our forecasts, CSH will be trading at 13.3 times its fiscal year 1997 earnings, which compares favourably to an earnings growth of 17.8 percent. Its low absolute price is likely to attract much investor interest,&quot; Kim Eng said in its  </p>
<p>research report.</p>
<p>The research house said the contributing factor to CSH's strong growth was an increase in operating margins, which grew to 15.5 percent in financial year 1995 ending December 31 from 1.3 percent in 1992 due to the transfer of its factory to Indonesia from Singapore.</p>
<p>Kim Eng said it expected CSH's margins for 1996 and 1997 to stabilise at current levels as the Indonesian factory was producing at nearly full capacity, but added that profits could rise as additional capacity came on stream.  </p>
<p>CSH is due to complete a second factory in Indonesia in mid-1997, which would lift existing capacity by 50 percent. A third, in Jiangsu, China, is due to start production sooner.</p>
<p>CSH's over-reliance on one agent for the United Kingdom market, however, might have a negative impact on its earnings, Kim Eng said.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I46000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
