<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="307500" id="root" date="1997-01-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan stocks resume downward spiral.</title>
<headline>Japan stocks resume downward spiral.</headline>
<byline>Hiroko Nakata</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese stocks fell sharply on Tuesday morning, resuming a downward spiral fuelled by persistent jitters over the nation's fragile economic recovery.</p>
<p>The renewed gloom briefly pushed the market's key index down by more than 500 points at one stage. Brokers cited concern about the future course of the economy and said the banking and brokerage sectors were hardest hit.</p>
<p>The benchmark Nikkei average of 225 leading shares was down 446.50 points, or 2.46 percent, at 17,672.29 by Tokyo midday, having slipped as low as 17,545.52 early in the session.</p>
<p>The key index lost more than 2,000 points last week, hurt by uncertainty over Japan's economic outlook.</p>
<p>Brokers said that although calls by some Japanese officials for steps to support the market spurred a rebound of more than 800 points on Monday, doubts about whether the government would really propose swift measures to pull the economy out of its doldrums led to renewed selling on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think such measures will be proposed soon,&quot; said a senior broker at a second-tier Japanese securities house.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka said on Tuesday that Japan would steadily implement reforms, and seek swift passage of a proposed extra budget for this fiscal year and the full state budget for the next fiscal year.</p>
<p>Mitsuzuka also told economic ministers he was watching the stock market with great interest.</p>
<p>But Masaru Takagi, chief economist at Fuji Research Institute, said any temporary government measures would do little to jack up the battered stock market.</p>
<p>&quot;What the government needs to do is to take swift action to realise structural reforms in the economy,&quot; he said. It must do something like abolishing the securities transaction tax as early as April, and seek early implementation of Japan's planned &quot;Big Bang&quot; financial reforms, he added.</p>
<p>The government's Economic Planning Agency decided not modify its official assessment of the economy in its monthly economic report released on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Although stock prices are falling, the current state of the economy is that it is continuing to recover gradually and is more or less firm,&quot; an agency official said.</p>
<p>The official said falls in share prices may have some negative impact on business sentiment, but this would be limited if the drop were for only a short period.</p>
<p>Japanese banking shares were battered by a renewed wave of selling on Tuesday morning, after a round of buying back the day before, amid lingering worries over the sectors' bad debts.</p>
<p>Sakura Bank Ltd shares were down 25 yen at 715 yen after dipping as low as 690 yen in heavy trading. Nippon Credit Bank shares shed 8 yen to stand at 251 yen.</p>
<p>Despite the overall gloom in the market, some blue chips were well bidy.</p>
<p>Honda Motor Co Ltd rode a wave of buying of blue-chip shares, rising 90 yen to 3,170 yen, while Sony Corp was bid up 20 yen to 7,380 yen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
