<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="30753" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - Sept 3.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - Sept 3.</headline>
<text>
<p>DAY'S TOP STORIES</p>
<p>- The government signs a peace agreement with the Moslem Moro National Liberation Front (MNLF) amid expressions of support from several people. But Christians in the southern city of Zamboanga stage protests against the signing of the pact. (ALL PAPERS)</p>
<p>- The government has run out of funds to repair the 1.4 billion peso megadike in Pampanga, Budget Secretary Salvador Enriquez said. (THE PHILIPPINE STAR)</p>
<p>- MNLF chairman Nur Misuari said vice-president Jospeh Estrada had asked him to be his running mate in the 1998 presidential elections. (THE MANILA TIMES)</p>
<p>				 ++++</p>
<p>BUSINESS</p>
<p>- The Department of Finance on Monday launched a Brady bond exchange scheme to give the government better means of managing part of its $37 billion external debt. (PHILIPPINE DAILY INQUIRER)</p>
<p>- As part of a compromise formula recently threshed out with the finance department, the Central Bank has revised provisions in its reverse repurchase agreements requiring banks to pay taxes on interest income derived from these transactions. (THE BUSINESS DAILY)</p>
<p>- Socio-Economic Planning Secretary Cielito Habito said a higher 7.5 percent GNP growth was within reach although the inflation rate was expected to be at a higher 8.7 percent. (MANILA BULLETIN)</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8934</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
