<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="30783" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan can achieve recovery without help - govt.</title>
<headline>Japan can achieve recovery without help - govt.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan will be able to achieve self-sustainable recovery even if the government does not come up with new fiscal stimulus measures, a government official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if the government does not come up with new fiscal stimulus measures, moves toward self-sustainable recovery would still be in sight,&quot; the official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Although worrisome factors such as the sluggish semiconductor market remain, both the Bank of Japan's (BOJ) short-term &quot;tankan&quot; survey of corporate business sentiment and July industrial production figures confirmed that capital spending was still on a gradual upward trend.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the downward risks for the economy are decreasing,&quot; he said, adding that the current economic recovery will not be without setbacks.</p>
<p>Japan is now debating whether to come up with a large extra budget this fiscal year featuring new economic stimulus steps as a way to help current economic recovery.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto and Finance Minister Wataru Kubo agreed on Sunday that the final decision on the need for a supplementary budget will be made around September 20 after the release of April to June gross domestic product (GDP) figures in mid-September.  </p>
<p>The official said that April to June GDP figures would likely be lower than the previous quarter, in reaction to surprising annualised 12.7 percent growth in the January to March period.</p>
<p>If the GDP figures are to be averaged out, the first half of calendar 1996 would post positive growth, he added.</p>
<p>For the July to September period, the official said GDP may grow slightly from the previous quarter or move sideways.</p>
<p>Another government official also said that he sees no downward risks for the economy at the moment and that the gradual recovery trend was continuing.  </p>
<p>Government officials in charge of economic policy played down any urgent need for an extra budget, while some said that the possibility of such a budget should be closely tied with the question of when Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto will call general elections, which are not mandated till mid-1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
