<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="307929" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. stocks seen gaining support from Q4 earnings.</title>
<headline>U.S. stocks seen gaining support from Q4 earnings.</headline>
<byline>Richard Jacobsen</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street expects fourth quarter corporate profits to provide an underpinning for the stock market's advance into record ground, with earnings showing a solid improvement over the third quarter.</p>
<p>Higher oil prices and a stronger economy are keys to the improved profit picture, analysts said.</p>
<p>But with good news anticipated, sometimes in the form of unpublished &quot;whisper&quot; earnings estimates that are above the published consensus forecasts, analysts say investors will punish any company posting disappointing numbers.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think the market will be positive in its response (to fourth quarter earnings), but I don't think there'll be any explosion to the upside,&quot; said Joseph Battipaglia, chief investment officer at Gruntal.</p>
<p>&quot;But God forbid if you come in with the wrong number...they'll really hit you hard,&quot; he said</p>
<p>Industry analysts expect the operating earnings of the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 companies to show an year-over-year rise averaging 8.8 percent for the fourth quarter, after 5.6 percent in the third quarter, said First Call's director of research Chuck Hill.  </p>
<p>He said the fourth-quarter rise could be even stronger because traditionally analysts' estimates start the year overly optimistic and end it overly conservative.</p>
<p>&quot;If history repeats itself, we're looking at probably a 10-point-something&quot; percent rise, Hill said.</p>
<p>An example of the high expectations came with Intel Corp's fourth quarter report late Tuesday. The profit of $2.13 per share exceeded Wall Street's consensus estimate of $1.84, but traders said it was shy of the whispered expectation of $2.50.</p>
<p>Intel shares were down 1-3/4 at 145-3/8 near midsession.  </p>
<p>A string of recent economic reports, including last Friday's stronger-then-expected U.S. December employment data, points to an economy that has weathered an autumn slowdown and is picking up, said Peter Canelo, chief investment strategist at Dean Witter.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the good news is you're going to see some (positive) profit suprises,&quot; Canelo said.</p>
<p>One group that could surprise is the depressed basic industries sector, which includes paper, metals and chemical companies, he said.  </p>
<p>On Tuesday International Paper Co reported fourth quarter operating earnings of $0.33 a share, down from $0.37 a year ago but above the First Call consensus estimate of $0.31. The company indicated the fundamentals in its market were improving.</p>
<p>Fourth quarter operating profits for the forest products sector are expected to be down 50 percent from a year ago, said Joseph Abbott, assistant vice president at I/B/E/S. Aluminum company earnings are expected to be down 42 percent and steel company results are seen down 16 percent, he said.  </p>
<p>On the flip side, rising oil and natural gas prices are expected to result in earnings gains averaging 105 percent at natural gas companies and 39 percent at oil companies, Abbott said.</p>
<p>Hill noted another good sign for fourth quarter earnings: Fewer companies have issued negative profit warnings than in the previous three quarters.</p>
<p>Companies that have advised Wall Street to expect earnings shortfalls include Apple Computer Inc, retailer Limited Inc, and smokeless tobacco maker UST Inc.  </p>
<p>Some analysts who are cautious about stocks' current levels say that if fourth quarter earnings fail to shine, the overall stock market could be in for a rough ride.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the rather pricey valuations we see in the equity market at this time, there's every real danger that earnings, even if they match expectations, will not be strong enough for the liking of investors,&quot; said Jim Solloway, director of research at Argus Research.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Chips and Technologies Inc's share price sank 24 percent after the company's quarterly earnings failed to produce the kind of upside surprise that Wall Street has grown to expect from the company.</p>
<p>((-- Wall St Desk 212-859-1721))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
