<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="307958" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-COURT TOLD GROBBELAAR SAVES COST HIM CROOKED MONEY.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-COURT TOLD GROBBELAAR SAVES COST HIM CROOKED MONEY.</headline>
<byline>David Ljunggren</byline>
<dateline>WINCHESTER, England 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Goalkeeper Bruce Grobbelaar lost 125,000 pounds ($209,100) when he inadvertently made two &quot;blinding&quot; saves in a game he had pledged to lose for an Asian gambling syndicate, a court was told on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Grobbelaar and three other defendants deny charges of accepting or giving money to rig matches in the first case of its kind in Britain for more than 30 years. All four could be jailed for up to seven years if found guilty.</p>
<p>Chief prosecutor David Calvert Smith said Grobbelaar, recorded covertly by former friend Chris Vincent, had admitted trying to rig a total of four games, three while playing for Liverpool and another after his August 1994 move to Southampton.</p>
<p>But the goalkeeper said he found it very hard to let shots in because he was trained to keep them out, the court heard.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm my worst enemy on that. I don't like to lose. So it's instinct,&quot; he said on one of the tapes recorded during talks with chief prosecution witness Vincent.</p>
<p>Calvert Smith said Grobbelaar, his speech littered with expletives, could be heard on one tape seething about a game between Liverpool and Manchester United in January 1994. United led 3-1 at one stage but the final result was a 3-3 draw.</p>
<p>&quot;Do you know how much money I lost? 125,000 pounds in cash,&quot; Grobbelaar told Vincent.</p>
<p>Grobbelaar related how he had dived in an attempt to miss two shots, thereby allowing United to increase their lead, but the ball had hit his hand both times.</p>
<p>The court was shown a video of two incidents during the game, in which the keeper dived and used his hands to make what looked like good saves from Ryan Giggs and then Roy Keane.</p>
<p>&quot;I could have done something. In the second half I made two blinding saves. I was diving the wrong way. I just went and it hit my hand,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Grobbelaar, the most successful goalkeeper in English league history, is renowned as a brilliant but eccentric keeper. He now plays for Plymouth in the second division.</p>
<p>Former striker John Fashanu and Malaysian businessman Heng Suan Lim are accused of acting as the shadowy syndicate's middlemen. The other defendant is goalkeeper Hans Segers, accused with former Wimbledon teammate Fashanu and Lim of taking part in a separate match-rigging attempt.</p>
<p>Despite his &quot;failure&quot; in the Manchester United game, Grobbelaar was told to rig the away game against Norwich the following month.</p>
<p>The game ended in a 2-2 draw and Vincent said Grobbelaar told him he was worried that Lim -- whom the keeper referred to as the 'Short Man' -- would be unhappy Liverpool had not lost.</p>
<p>&quot;Grobbelaar said the Short Man would be as mad as a snake,&quot; Calvert Smith quoted Vincent as saying.</p>
<p>Grobbelaar told Vincent in one of the tape recordings that Liverpool would have lost had a close-range shot from striker Jeremy Goss not hit his leg by accident. A video clip of the game seen in court seemed to show him making a good save.</p>
<p>Calvert Smith said that after this second failure to deliver a result, there was virtually no contact between Lim and Grobbelaar, possibly because the keeper had been dropped and could not affect the results of matches.</p>
<p>But ties were resumed in August 1994 after Grobbelaar was transferred to Southampton and the syndicate told him to rig an away game against Coventry in late September, even though the keeper said this would be very hard to do.</p>
<p>&quot;So two minutes into the game I pushed the ball into the back of the net. And then we steamrollered them,&quot; said the keeper. Southampton won the game 3-1.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINCHESTER, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
