<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="307963" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NHL, AMERICAN FOOTBALL-DEVILS FINALLY GET BRODEUR HIS 100TH WIN.</title>
<headline>NHL, AMERICAN FOOTBALL-DEVILS FINALLY GET BRODEUR HIS 100TH WIN.</headline>
<dateline>EAST RUTHERFORD, New Jersey 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Jersey Devils finally scored some goals on Tuesday to help goaltender Martin Brodeur notch his 100th career victory.</p>
<p>Bobby Holik and Brian Rolston each had a goal and an assist as the Devils broke out of their scoring slump for a 4-2 triumph over the Boston Bruins.</p>
<p>Rolston and Randy McKay tallied 79 seconds apart early in the second period as the Devils built a 3-0 lead en route to only their third victory in their last 11 games.</p>
<p>Brodeur, who backstopped the Devils to the Stanley Cup in 1995, made 21 saves to snap his personal four-game winless string and reach the century milestone in career victories.</p>
<p>Adam Oates, on a powerplay, and Rob DiMaio scored for the Bruins as Boston pulled within 3-2. But John MacLean's empty netter with 21 seconds to go put the win in the record books.</p>
<p>&quot;I think for our team it was great to win this game,&quot; Devils coach Jacques Lemaire said. &quot;We got a couple of goals at the start that helped us with our confidence.</p>
<p>In Pittsburgh, Patrick Lalime tied an NHL record for the best start by a rookie goaltender and Jaromir Jagr notched his league-leading 39th and 40th goals as the Penguins extended their unbeaten streak to 12 games with a 3-1 victory over the Dallas Stars.</p>
<p>Lalime stopped 30 shots to improve to 12-0-2 since being recalled from the minors in early December. His start equals the mark set by the great Ken Dryden with the 1970-71 Montreal Canadiens, who went on to win the Stanley Cup.</p>
<p>Joe Nieuwendyk's powerplay goal was Lalime's lone blemish.</p>
<p>Jagr scored with 5:27 left in the second period to break a 1-1 deadlock and added an insurance tally early in the third.</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, Paul Coffey's goal with 45 seconds left lifted the red-hot Flyers to their league-leading 27th win, a 3-2 victory over the Montreal Canadiens.</p>
<p>Coffey took a pass from Dale Hawerchuk in the slot and blasted a one-timer past Pat Jablonski for the game winner.</p>
<p>John LeClair and John Druce also scored for the Flyers, who are 15-1-4 in their last 20 games. Brian Savage and Benoit Brunet tied the game for Montreal, which was outshot 35-18.</p>
<p>Coffey's assist on Druce's goal was the 1,049th of his career, moving him into a tie with Gordie Howe for second place on the all-time list.</p>
<p>Ron Hextall needed to make only 16 saves to record his 200th victory with the Flyers.</p>
<p>In Detroit, Kevin Stevens scored at 8:20 of the third period as the Los Angeles Kings rallied from a two-goal deficit for a 3-3 tie with the Red Wings.</p>
<p>Ray Ferraro, who scored the Kings' second goal at 3:36 of the third, nearly won it for Los Angeles. But Detroit goalie Chris Osgood made a blocker save on Ferraro's wrist shot from the top of the crease with one second left in regulation.</p>
<p>Osgood finished with 26 saves for the Wings, who are unbeaten in overtime contests this season at 2-0-8.</p>
<p>Brendan Shanahan's 25th goal, a powerplay tally at 18:28 of the second, had given Detroit a 3-1 lead.</p>
<p>In Vancouver, Alexander Mogilny's goal 8:43 into the third period lifted the Canucks into a 4-4 tie with the Florida Panthers.</p>
<p>Robert Svehla second goal of the game with 14:04 left in regulation gave the Panthers a 4-3 edge, but Mogilny answered with his 18th of the season, whipping a wrist shot past John Vanbiesbrouck's right pad.</p>
<p>Vancouver had a power play for the first 1:56 of overtime, but the Canucks were unable to test Vanbiesbrouck.</p>
<p>Mike Sillinger scored twice for Vancouver, the second on a penalty shot at 5:03 of the third that tied the game at 3-3.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EAST RUTHERFORD, New Jersey"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
