<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="308013" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-CHIEFS EXTEND COACH SCHOTTENHEIMER, GM PETERSON CONTRACTS.</title>
<headline>NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-CHIEFS EXTEND COACH SCHOTTENHEIMER, GM PETERSON CONTRACTS.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite a late-season collapse that kept Kansas City out of the playoffs, the Chiefs said Tuesday that head coach Marty Schottenheimer and general manager Carl Peterson had been given contract extensions.</p>
<p>Peterson, whose contract was to expire at the end of the month, signed a four-year deal. Schottenheimer, with a year left on his contract, was given a four-year extension, the club announced.</p>
<p>Financial terms were not disclosed for either contract.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not accomplished the mission we set out to do and I have rededicated myself to accomplishing that goal,&quot; Peterson said of taking the Chiefs back to the Super Bowl.</p>
<p>The Chiefs, a pre-season favourite to contend for a Super Bowl berth, finished a disappointing 9-7 and failed to make the playoffs for the first time since 1989, the year Schottenheimer and Peterson took over.</p>
<p>The Chiefs appeared Super Bowl bound last season when the team went 13-3 and had home-field advantage throughout the playoffs. But Kansas City instead suffered a stunning 10-7 playoff upset to the Indianapolis Colts and seemed to take a step backward this season.</p>
<p>Schottenheimer has never suffered a losing season in his 13 years as an NFL head coach with the Cleveland Browns and Kansas City. This season marked just the third time that he failed to make the playoffs.</p>
<p>Schottenheimer thanked Chiefs longtime owner Lamar Hunt for the vote of confidence &quot;into the next century.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We know it's going to be a challenge, it always is. But we're excited about the opportunity to do it,&quot; Schottenheimer said.</p>
<p>Schottenheimer has a career mark of 130-83-1, including a 5-10 record in the playoffs, 3-6 with Kansas City. He has the second-longest current coaching tenure in the league behind Marv Levy of Buffalo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
