<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="30810" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia naphtha hits record high but demand dampened.</title>
<headline>Asia naphtha hits record high but demand dampened.</headline>
<byline>Marguerita Choy</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian naphtha prices have hit record highs on the back of crude hikes following mounting tension in the Gulf, but the firmer market was likely to dampen demand, traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Singapore's physical naphtha prices leapt 50 cents on Monday to just below $21.00 per barrel on a free-on-board (fob) basis, the highest level seen in at least two years.</p>
<p>Traders said overnight hikes in crude and market jitters over the Iraqi crisis were likely to push levels even higher.  </p>
<p>&quot;I cannot put a ceiling on prices,&quot; said a Japanese trader. &quot;Although naphtha's situation is quite tight, prices depend on what happens on crude.&quot;</p>
<p>Swaps in Singapore for September soared from Monday's close of $20.45/$20.75 to be bid at $20.70 on Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>Japan's forward naphtha contract, the open-specification contract for first-half November, the main trading period, was notionally quoted at $200/$201 per tonne on Tuesday morning, the highest since late April.  </p>
<p>Traders said petrochemical firms, which buy naphtha as feedstock, were expected to back off if prices stayed over $200 because it was almost impossible for them to make profits with naphtha costing more than that.</p>
<p>&quot;Once prices rise beyond $200, petrochemical buyers are most likely to stay away from the market,&quot; one trader said. &quot;In the petrochmeical industry, it is quite difficult to pass price hikes on to their customers.&quot;  </p>
<p>An official from Taiwan's state-owned Chinese Petroleum Corporation (CPC) said it might even cancel its tender to buy 30,000 tonnes of naphtha for September 21-31 delivery which closed on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;There were not too many offers,&quot; the official said. &quot;Offers were very high ... more than $200 per tonne.&quot; He said CPC would make a decision by late Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>Sellers were equally cautious. &quot;With the jump in crude, it is too risky to participate,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>(With contribution from Kiyoshi Takinaka in Tokyo)</p>
<p>--Singapore Newsroom (+65-8703086)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
