<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="308297" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian government, opposition inch toward talks.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian government, opposition inch toward talks.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Roche</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's ruling Socialists and opposition inched towards crisis talks on Wednesday, as protesters piled garbage before a parliament they accuse of reducing them to paupers.</p>
<p>Buffeted by 10 days of street protests and strike threats, the government of former communists gave some way to opposition calls for early elections by suggesting polls before the end of 1997 -- a year ahead of schedule.</p>
<p>&quot;We are prepared to hold elections by the end of the year and negotiations should start here and now,&quot; Socialist parliamentary group head Krassimir Premyanov told parliament.</p>
<p>A few hours later the opposition softened its previously uncompromising anti-government line.</p>
<p>&quot;From this moment we begin negotiations with the Socialists,&quot; Ivan Kostov, leader of the Union of Democratic Forces, said after discussions among opposition leaders.</p>
<p>But he attached conditions, including that no new Socialist government be formed under the present parliament -- implying parliamentary polls be held earlier than the government offer.</p>
<p>Demonstrators threw the contents of rubbish bags on the ground near the heavily-guarded parliament.</p>
<p>Some 10,000 people turned out later in the day, including the cast of Kanaleto, a hugely popular satirical TV show taken off the air on Sunday, singing protest songs dating from Bulgaria's uprising against Ottoman rule last century.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be here as long as it takes because we are not fighting a political party, we are fighting misery and starvation,&quot; said elderly demonstrator Kiril Georgiev. &quot;Pensioners like me have only one hope, and that's change.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I want those people out of power,&quot; said jobless Vladimir Velkov. &quot;We are not evil people and we are going to forgive but I want just once in history to hear them admit their guilt.&quot;</p>
<p>Sofia students marched earlier with &quot;wanted&quot; posters of outgoing prime minister Zhan Videnov, accusing him of &quot;crimes against the Bulgarian nation&quot;, and banners saying &quot;Game over&quot; and &quot;Death to communism&quot;.</p>
<p>Hundreds of taxi drivers made a noisy contribution to the unrest by driving in a slow cavalcade through the capital, leaning on car horns and waving opposition blue flags. Some ferried protesters to demonstrations free.</p>
<p>The opposition is boycotting parliament, but 123 deputies from the Socialists and small parties attended its first session since protesters ransacked the building on Friday.</p>
<p>Repaired and cleared of debris, it was surrounded by riot police who have cordoned it off since the clashes, which left at least 196 injured, triggered by the Socialists' refusal to vote on an opposition motion calling for early elections.</p>
<p>President-elect Petar Stoyanov, due to be sworn in on Sunday with the authority to invite leaders to form a new government, urged both sides to reach a solution in talks.</p>
<p>&quot;If a consensus is not reached, I will act according to my constitutional duties and I will hand the mandate to the (Socialist) BSP and its coalition partners,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But it is my duty to warn them that if that happens, the crisis is going to be even worse and the people are not going to go back to their homes.&quot;</p>
<p>Kostov repeated UDF demands for a new head of the central bank and the creation of an expert group to negotiate with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and World Bank on introducing a restrictive monetary regime.</p>
<p>Year-on-year inflation is running at more than 300 percent and living standards have plunged since the ex-communist Socialist party came to power in a general election in 1994.</p>
<p>Its failure to introduce market reforms is blamed for a flight of capital that has helped push the lev down to nearly 700 to the dollar from 70 a year ago. Most salaries are worth only a few dollars a month.</p>
<p>Quick formation of a new cabinet is seen as vital to secure a new funding agreement with the IMF and avert default on Bulgaria's $10 billion foreign debt.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
