<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="308266" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: De Beers welcomes S.Africa diamond inquiry.</title>
<headline>De Beers welcomes S.Africa diamond inquiry.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Diamond giant De Beers said on Wednesday that it welcomed a government Commission of Inquiry into the South African diamond industry.</p>
<p>The intention to set up the inquiry was announced in early 1996, but on Wednesday the government announced the Commission is to start sitting from February 19 this year.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the inquiry) will certainly help clarify certain issues,&quot; a De Beers spokesman said, adding De Beers was willing to help the inquiry in any way should it be requested to do so.</p>
<p>The commission, chaired by Justice Dennis Levy, has a broad mandate of issues for discussion and investigation.</p>
<p>These include diamond industry legislation, the role of the South African Diamond Board and the effectiveness of measures to stop illegal diamond purchases.</p>
<p>The commission will also look at the supply of rough diamonds to the local processing industry, the industry's contribution to state revenue and job creation, international models relevant to the local industry and the influence of foreign companies and international diamond combines.</p>
<p>Commission Secretary Bob Klaver said the inquiry was set to last about six months and after its conclusion would make recommendations on change to the Minister of Minerals and Energy.</p>
<p>&quot;The inquiry is friendly (towards the industry) but we will try to change things wherever necessary...it might suggest changes in tax, the way people get licenses, anything really,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The last such inquiry into the South African industry occurred in the early 1970s and Klaver said the African National Congress led-government, which came into power in the country's first democratic elections in 1994, felt another Commission was long overdue.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been about 25 years since there was an inquiry into the industry,&quot; Klaver said.</p>
<p>Klaver added the Commission had written to all sections of the diamond industry asking them to submit presentations on any of the issues to be looked at.</p>
<p>Requests had been sent to all producers, cutters, unions and dealers, including De Beers.</p>
<p>De Beers controls about three quarters of the world diamond market and is currently locked in a dispute with Russia over a new trade deal. Russia accounts for about 25 percent of all rough gems De Beers sells.</p>
<p>-- Paul Harris, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
