<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="308211" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Universe will end in 10 trillion years - scientists.</title>
<headline>Universe will end in 10 trillion years - scientists.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Zabarenko</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The end of the universe as humans know it will occur in about 10 trillion years, but certain physical processes will continue as far into the future as astronomers can imagine, scientists reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>For all practical purposes, what we think of as the universe will end when all the big stars like our Sun stop shining, said astrophysicist Fred Adams of the University of Michigan: &quot;At that time, a human eye on Earth would observe the universe to be dark and black.&quot;</p>
<p>But there would be no human eyes to observe it, Adams and his colleague Greg Laughlin said at a news conference, because by that point Earth's oceans would have boiled away in the Sun's dying flameout, reducing the planet to an uninhabitable cinder.</p>
<p>However, Adams stressed that these predictions have no effect on the details of current earthly life: &quot;As we approach the end of this millenium, I'd like to make the point that the end is not that near.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The universe will never end,&quot; Laughlin said. &quot;... The universe will always be here and interesting things will continue to occur.&quot;</p>
<p>Unlike many astronomers, whose studies have focused on the history of the universe, Adams and Laughlin peered into the distant future by applying &quot;fundamental physical laws,&quot; they told reporters at a meeting of the American Astronomical Society in Toronto.</p>
<p>To put their research into context, it is useful to remember that current estimates set the age of the universe at perhaps 10 billion to 15 billion years. To even discuss the far-off future they envisioned, the researchers had to make up a new measurement of time: the cosmological decade.</p>
<p>By this measurement, 10 trillion years would be described as 13 cosmological decades -- or a 1 with 13 zeroes in front of it.</p>
<p>In 14 cosmological decades -- 100 trillion years -- the very last stars, including smaller ones that will live longer than our Sun, will be dead, the scientists said.</p>
<p>After that will be a so-called Degenerate Era populated by burned-out stars and mysterious matter-sucking black holes. Galaxies like our Milky Way will &quot;relax&quot; with some star remnants moving toward the edge of the galaxy and others falling into the centre of it.</p>
<p>By about cosmological decade 37, the decay of sub-atomic particles called protons will begin, ringing &quot;the death knell for carbon-based life as we know it,&quot; Laughlin said.</p>
<p>In subsequent decades, dubbed the Black Hole Era, black holes will radiate away their mass and disappear.</p>
<p>By about the 100th cosmological decade the aptly-named Dark Era will begin, and about this era little is known. The universe will consist of a &quot;diffuse sea of electrons, positrons, neutrinos and radiation,&quot; Adams said.</p>
<p>Also presented at the astronomy meeting was the first three-dimensional map of the Milky Way galaxy. The map, put together using 20 years worth of data, was constructed by the Harvard-Smithsonian Centre for Astrophysics.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
