<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="308414" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: US favours awarding disputed town to Serbs - sources.</title>
<headline>US favours awarding disputed town to Serbs - sources.</headline>
<byline>Dan De Luce</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior United States envoy has proposed that an arbitration panel award the disputed Bosnian town of Brcko to the country's Serbs who seized the area four years ago, diplomats said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A policy statement written by U.S. Assistant Secretary of State John Kornblum this month lays out possible solutions to the dispute over Brcko but favours granting control of the strategic town to Bosnia's Serb republic, diplomatic sources who asked not to be named told Reuters.</p>
<p>The question of who controls Brcko is an explosive issue that nearly scuppered peace talks that ended Bosnia's war among Moslems, Serbs and Croats in November 1995.</p>
<p>The U.S.-brokered Dayton peace agreement failed to resolve the future status of Brcko and called for international arbitration to settle the disagreement.</p>
<p>Kornblum's policy paper, which is sure to enrage Bosnia's Moslem-Croat federation, coincides with arbitration hearings in Rome presided over by American lawyer Roberts Owen.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an elaboration of (U.S.) policy and it is policy guidance for Owen,&quot; said one Western diplomat.</p>
<p>The arbitration panel chaired by Owen must deliver a decision by February 15. A December deadline was postponed.</p>
<p>Some U.S. State Department officials disagreed with Kornblum's paper and it remained unclear if secretary of state-designate Madeleine Albright would back the proposal, according to diplomatic sources.</p>
<p>Under Kornblum's proposal, Brcko would lie inside the Serb republic but the Moslem-Croat federation would be given a transit route through the area which would be internationally monitored, the sources said.</p>
<p>The town's port on the Sava river would be placed under the control of Bosnia's joint inter-ethnic government that presides loosely over autonomous Serb and Moslem-Croat entities.</p>
<p>The Serbs would also have to agree to allowing the return of Moslems and Croats expelled from their homes in Brcko.</p>
<p>The proposal, if carried out, would be welcomed by the Serb leadership and accepted by Washington's European allies.</p>
<p>But it would almost certainly provoke an angry response from the Moslem-Croat federation.</p>
<p>Federation leaders in Sarajevo say Brcko should be placed inside the federation because Moslems and Croats formed a majority of the population before the 1992-95 war.</p>
<p>They argue that that giving Brcko to the Serb side would reward military aggression and &quot;ethnic cleansing&quot;.</p>
<p>Balkan political analysts have warned that hardliners on both sides are prepared to go to war over Brcko.</p>
<p>If the Brcko arbitration is perceived to favour the Serbs, those Moslem nationalists favouring military action will gain support, they say.</p>
<p>The narrow Brcko land corridor, which links Serb territory to the west and east, is considered vulnerable to attack especially now that the Serb army no longer enjoys military superiority over its Moslem-Croat foes.</p>
<p>Military analysts say that if NATO peace enforcement troops leave at the end of their 18-month mandate in mid-1998, war could easily erupt over the Brcko corridor barring a prior settlement.</p>
<p>Serb forces who opposed a Moslem-Croat vote for Bosnia's independence from Yugoslavia in 1992 swiftly seized Brcko and, backed by Yugoslav troops, brutally ejected Moslems and Croats as part of their goal of carving out a separate Serb state.</p>
<p>Under the Dayton accords, Bosnia is a union of autonomous Moslem-Croat and Serb territories governed by a weak central government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
