<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="308502" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico new accounting rules seen boon to big banks.</title>
<headline>Mexico new accounting rules seen boon to big banks.</headline>
<byline>Henry Tricks</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican banks are likely to take in their stride a tough new system of bank accounting, and the rule changes may even boost profits of the top banks, analysts said.</p>
<p>On Friday, the National Banking and Securities Commission announced new accounting rules that took Mexico's notoriously woolly bank reporting rules close to internationally accepted standards, known as U.S. GAAP.  </p>
<p>Banking officials said that in a single stroke the new rules would double the level of past-due loans in the banking system, because they increase the amount of the defaulted loan that must be recognized, and put a halt to interest accrual.</p>
<p>But analysts said the banks, after a year of preparing for the new rules, were unlikely to face stiff reserve-building requirements to cover their higher bad loan portfolios.  </p>
<p>&quot;The government has gone the extra mile to bail out the banking system and they were not going to let them go under because of the new accounting rules,&quot; said Laura Berdeja, chief Latin American banking analyst at Santander Investments.</p>
<p>As a result, several transition steps provided a cushion to banks, especially in the fragile area of mortgage loans and on the valuation of sovereign debt held by banks.  </p>
<p>&quot;These new (transition) measures will likely cause the increase in past-due loans to be considerably lower than we had originally estimated. Therefore, profitability should be higher,&quot; Salomon Brothers analyst Jose Garcia-Cantera wrote in a report this week.</p>
<p>Berdeja concurred. She said Santander was currently cutting its earnings estimates for Mexican banks, but the new rules meant the cuts would be less than anticipated.  </p>
<p>One of the major concessions, analysts said, was that banks need only make full reserve provisions against 35 percent of their mortgage portfolio. They must create reserves covering 10 percent of those mortgages immediately. They then have eight years to cover the other 25 percent.</p>
<p>Banks also do not need to classify mortages as past-due until six months after non payment, rather than three months as had been originally expected.  </p>
<p>Analysts said those provisions chiefly benefitted the biggest banks such as Banamex and Bancomer, who hold the largest proportion of mortgage loans and could have been throttled by tougher rules.</p>
<p>The Banking Commission also offered a breathing space to banks holding government bonds received as part of Mexico's 1989-1990 so-called Brady debt restructuring.  </p>
<p>While almost all other securities, according to the new rules, are required to be marked to market, Brady bonds could be accounted for at purchase cost, as could United Mexican States bonds received &quot;in lieu of restructurings or payment of private debt.&quot;</p>
<p>Salomon Brothers said that bonds in the latter category were given to some banks as payment for loans for toll roads. &quot;The impact on most banks will be negligible, although it will clearly benefit certain institutions such as Serfin and Bancomer,&quot; the investment bank said.  </p>
<p>Other analysts said the big three banks -- Banamex, Bancomer and Serfin -- would have no problem meeting a new rule stating they need a minimum 45 percent reserve coverage of past-due loans.</p>
<p>Serfin and Bancomer already had 100 percent reserve coverage under the old Mexican accounting system. Even if their bad loans double under the new rules, they would be comfortably above the new 45 percent lower limit, analysts said.</p>
<p>Banamex is also considered well covered. Banks short of the minimum requirement will have six months to raise the level of reserves, the Banking Commission said.</p>
<p>Banking officials and industry analysts said the main area of pressure on bank profits would come from lower margins, because banks can no longer accrue interest on past-due loans.</p>
<p>Rogelio Urrutia of Valores Finamex said margins could drop by an estimated 10 percent as a result of the new rules. That is expected to hurt Serfin, which already has low margins.</p>
<p>((-- Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9560))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
