<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="308745" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ADM informer Whitacre indicted on 45 counts.</title>
<headline>ADM informer Whitacre indicted on 45 counts.</headline>
<byline>Maggie McNeil</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A federal grand jury on Wednesday returned a sweeping 45-count criminal indictment against Mark Whitacre, a former vice president of Archer Daniels Midland and the chief informant in a major antitrust investigation of the giant agribusiness concern.</p>
<p>Whitacre was charged with wire fraud, interstate transportation of stolen property, money laundering, forfeiture, conspiracy, obstruction of justice and filing false income tax returns.</p>
<p>The indictment charges Whitacre with stealing more than $9 million from ADM from the spring of 1991 through November 1995. Whitacre served as president of ADM's Bioproducts division and as a vice president of the parent company until the summer of 1995.</p>
<p>Whitacre allegedly laundered the money through foreign and domestic companies and bank accounts, including accounts established in the Cayman Islands, Germany, Hong Kong and Switzerland.</p>
<p>The indictment was returned in U.S. District Court in Springfield, Illinois, the Justice Department announced.</p>
<p>ADM, whose slogan is &quot;Supermarket to the World,&quot; is one of the nation's largest agribusiness producers and is headquartered in Decatur, Illinois. Its chairman, Dwayne Andreas, has long been one of the most politically influential figures in the U.S. agricultural industry.</p>
<p>Whitacre acted as a government informant for three years in a federal probe of price-fixing in the global market of the feed additive lysine, and secretly taped company meetings in his cooperation with federal investigators. ADM pleaded guilty to price-fixing last fall and agreed to pay $100 million in fines, the largest criminal antitrust fine in history.</p>
<p>Whitacre and two other former senior ADM officials, including Michael Andreas, the former executive vice president and son of Dwayne, were indicted last December for their roles in the price fixing scheme. At that point, Whitacre announced he was no longer participating with the government.</p>
<p>Whitacre, 39, now lives in Chapel Hill, North Carolina, and earlier this week sued the FBI agent in charge of the government case of allegedly ordering the destruction of tapes that could have been beneficial to ADM.</p>
<p>Whitacre's latest indictment came on the same day that executives of two Japanese companies and one South Korean firm entered guilty pleas in U.S. District Court in Chicago to conspiring to fix lysine prices.</p>
<p>Kanji Mimoto of Ajinomoto Co Inc and Jhom Su Kim of the U.S. subsidiary of Sewon Co Ltd of Korea entered guilty pleas and agreed to pay a fine of $75,000. Masaru Yamamoto of Kyowa Hakko Kogyo Co Ltd also pleaded guilty and agreed to a $50,000 fine.</p>
<p>The executives also agreed to cooperate in the government's ongoing antitrust case against Whitacre and the other two indicted ADM executives.</p>
<p>Whitacre was also charged on Wednesday with conspiring with an unnamed individual of defrauding the United States and filing false income tax returns with the Internal Revenue Service from 1991 through 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
