<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="308774" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Simpson case plaintiffs attack defense evidence.</title>
<headline>Simpson case plaintiffs attack defense evidence.</headline>
<byline>Michael Miller</byline>
<dateline>SANTA MONICA, Calif. 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Plaintiffs in O.J. Simpson's civil trial called an expert on Wednesday who testified to the authenticity of a photo apparently showing Simpson wearing the same kind of shoes as his ex-wife's killer.</p>
<p>Former FBI photographic expert Gerald Richards also told the jury he examined a photo of the glove found at the scene where Nicole Brown Simpson and her friend Ronald Goldman were stabbed to death and concluded that what appeared to be a cut on one of the fingers was actually debris on the glove.</p>
<p>Los Angeles police criminalist Dennis Fung testified earlier that the left-hand glove he entered into evidence from the murder scene had a cut on the knuckle of one finger.</p>
<p>But the glove that was subsequently produced at the criminal trial and again in the civil trial had no cut. The defence has suggested that the glove, as well as the right glove found at Simpson's mansion, were planted by police.</p>
<p>Simpson was acquitted in October 1995 of the 1994 murders and is now battling a wrongful death lawsuit brought by the families of the victims.</p>
<p>Richards was asked about a photograph showing Simpson wearing Italian designer Bruno Magli shoes like those that experts say left bloody prints leading away from the murder scene. The photo was taken by freelance photographer Harry Scull at a Sept. 26, 1993, Buffalo Bills football game.</p>
<p>&quot;I am 100 percent certain that (the photo) is not a fake,&quot; Richards said.</p>
<p>Defence photographic expert Robert Groden had told jurors the photograph appeared to have been altered to add the Bruno Maglis. Simpson testified he had never owned a pair of the expensive shoes and said the photo must have been faked.</p>
<p>Under questioning by defence attorney Dan Leonard, Richards agreed that the examination of photographs to see if they had been doctored was not an exact science. &quot;Some sciences you have to use more experience, and this is one of them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Groden testified he had never before been asked to examine a photograph in a criminal case to see if it had been altered.</p>
<p>Richards said the white image on the left glove's finger was actually a piece of dirt or soil similar to other dirt and soil seen on the glove and not the glove's lining showing through a rip or tear. Under tough cross-examination by Leonard, however, he conceded that he could not tell whether the debris was embedded in a cut.</p>
<p>&quot;Do you have any reason to disbelieve Mr Fung when he said there was a damaged area underneath that rock?&quot; Leonard asked, referring to the debris.</p>
<p>&quot;No sir,&quot; Richard replied.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA MONICA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
