<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="308803" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Financial gurus have lesson for today's market.</title>
<headline>Financial gurus have lesson for today's market.</headline>
<byline>Linda Stern</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investment success is part science, part art and oodles of luck. If you've ever wondered why some money managers seem to have more luck than others, it probably has to do with the way they approach the art and science of investing.</p>
<p>&quot;Investment Gurus,&quot; a new book by Peter Tanous (1997, New York Institute of Finance, $24.95, 800-227-6943), does more to shed light on the methods behind the money mavens than any other finance book I've seen published in the recent past, and boy, have there been a lot of them.</p>
<p>In &quot;Investment Gurus,&quot; Tanous exposes modern market strategy and investment theory through chatty interviews with the thoughtful top of the investment world today: famous fund managers like Michael Price and Mario Gabelli; academicians like Nobel prize winner William Sharpe, who gave us the most widely used measures of stock market risk, and Rex Sinquefield, spiritual leader of the burgeoning you-can't-beat-the-market-so-just-buy-index funds movement.</p>
<p>What's funny about all the people chosen for this book is that they are all stock market winners with strategies that can be pretty incompatible with each other.</p>
<p>Michael Price talks of finding stocks by hunting through the yellow pages, uncovering hidden assets in warehouses, and making sure he pays less for those assets than they are worth.</p>
<p>MFS's John Ballen uses heavy doses of intuition and goes for well-managed companies in industries that are growing fast. He concedes that it's the rare (and probably great) stock that shows up in both his and Price's portfolios at once.</p>
<p>Richard Driehaus, a Chicago money manager, doesn't much care about sales formulas or warehouse holdings, but he watches the market like a maniac: If everyone else is buying something he wants it.</p>
<p>All three beat the market on a regular basis, yet Sinquefield makes a very convincing case for his argument that it isn't worth the bother: the biggest bang for the buck comes from buying the whole market at the lowest possible transaction costs with the fewest taxable transactions. It all sort of proves that old adage: Bulls make money, bears make money and pigs get slaughtered.</p>
<p>What conclusions does Tanous draw from all of this? His view seems to be that passive management (the Sinquefield approach) works pretty damn well, but stellar managers can buy you extra returns around the edges. And so he teaches readers to construct their own mostly passive -- with great funds around the edges -- portfolios. Tanous does a credible job of explaining modern portfolio theory with clarity; you come away understanding why asset allocation is so important and how to construct your own portfolio.</p>
<p>You also come away with some stories that are inspirational, educational, and entertaining. It's striking how many of these &quot;gurus&quot; were already into following the market before they were shaving on a regular basis.</p>
<p>Money manager Laura Sloate, credited with being one of the few who can regularly beat the market without taking extra risks, does so on a talking computer: She's blind and learned to tote up her father's portfolio in her head, as a child.</p>
<p>Money manager Bruce Sherman got 10 shares of stock for his bar mitzvah and sold them immediately -- he didn't like what he saw in the annual report. And so on and so on.</p>
<p>The stories are fun, the advice is solid, and this book is one of the very few I'm going to keep for my shelf.</p>
<p>You can Email Linda Stern at 72160.1546(at)compuserve.com or write to her in care of Reuters, Suite 410, 1333 H St., NW, Washington, DC 20005.  She regrets that she cannot answer each letter individually, but will cover your questions in upcoming columns.</p>
<p>(EDITORS: Linda Stern is a free-lance writer who covers personal finance issues for Reuters. Any opinions in the column are solely those of Ms. Stern.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
