<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="309069" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rising U.S. wages may hasten end of long expansion.</title>
<headline>Rising U.S. wages may hasten end of long expansion.</headline>
<byline>John P. Hughes</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The broad-based rise in wages for U.S. workers in the past two months could portend an end to the nation's seven-year economic expansion, analysts said.</p>
<p>Inflation pressures grow when businesses must pay more for a shrinking pool of skilled labor, said William Sullivan, director of money market research at Dean Witter Reynolds Inc. Rising wages also put more cash into consumers' pockets, which can also help push prices higher. This could force the Federal Reserve to hike interest rates to slow down an overheated economy.  </p>
<p>&quot;After nearly seven years of expansion, compensation pressures are building within the environment of a tight labor market,&quot; Sullivan said. &quot;This event is a typical late-cycle development.&quot;</p>
<p>Average weekly earnings of U.S. workers, after adjusting for inflation and seasonal factors, rose 1.1 percent in December. That followed a 1.0 percent rise in November real average earnings, the Labor Department said Tuesday.</p>
<p>That data followed last Friday's payrolls report showing back-to-back increases in hourly wages in November and December -- the largest in 11 years.  </p>
<p>Economists said wage gains in the last two months could not be explained entirely by October's minimum-wage increase. Sullivan said a breakdown showed gains concentrated in sectors that would not have a large number of minimum wage earners.</p>
<p>Jerry Zukowski, economist at PaineWebber Inc, said other factors could prevent the economy from overheating.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not going to try to repeal the rules of economics. Could it happen? Yes,&quot; Zukowski said of higher wages driving inflation. But he argued that commodities prices typically were a leading indicator on inflation, while wages were a lagging indicator.  </p>
<p>Inflation fears have not been evident in commodity prices lately. Oil prices have been strong recently while gold has been sliding for weeks and other major components of the Knight-Ridder Commodity Research Buearu Index have been mixed.</p>
<p>&quot;More importantly, if you look at producer prices at the crude and intermediate level you are beginning to see some hints of pipeline (inflation) pressures,&quot; said Christopher Low, economist at HSBC Markets Inc.</p>
<p>Those pressures probably will not cause significant problems in 1997, Low said.  </p>
<p>But toward the end of the year and early 1998 they could drive the &quot;core&quot; rate of the consumer price index toward 3.0 percent, Low said. The core excludes the volatile food and energy components. That growing inflation could perhaps signal the end of the current expansion, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;So far the Fed has been intolerant of that type of price pressure. The issue in 1997 is if the Fed does have to tighten, how much tightening can the economy take at this late stage of expansion,&quot; Low said.</p>
<p>Economists now await the release of the quarterly Employment Cost Index (ECI) on January 28 to better gauge just how rapidly wages grew in the fourth quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>While most economists downplayed the minimum wage increase, Doug Schindewolf, money market economist at Smith Barney Inc., noted that the retail sector -- home of many minimum wage jobs -- did show large increases after October.</p>
<p>&quot;But some of the higher-paying industries showed as much if not more increases,&quot; Schindewolf added. The only caveat, he said, was average earnings don't provide a &quot;clean&quot; reading because they don't take into account shifts within industries.  </p>
<p>Schindewolf said the preferred indicator was the ECI, which did account for shifts within industries and also counted the cost of providing benefits.</p>
<p>Despite real gains in wage pressures, however, Schindewolf said his firm is not forecasting a recession in 1997.</p>
<p>((--N.A. Treasury desk, 212-859-1663))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
