<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="309216" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: PRESS DIGEST - Pakistan - January 15.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Pakistan - January 15.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Pakistani press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAWN</p>
<p>- British Prime Minister John Major said Britain will continue to strengthen its economic ties with Pakistan despite its difficult political situation.</p>
<p>- The government has restored the licences of two firms to import gold, ending a monopoly that has lasted two years.</p>
<p>- London-based Lasmo Oil Ltd and Pakistan have signed an agreement for exploration of gas and oil in Pakistan.</p>
<p>- The government has decided to facilitate the export of cigarettes and tobacco to increase exports.</p>
<p>- Ginners urged the government to direct the state-run Cotton Export Corporation to buy unsold cotton stocks worth 20 billion rupees.</p>
<p>- Germany is pressing Pakistan to facilitate the early deportation of around 10,000 Pakistanis from Germany whose stay has been denied in that country.</p>
<p>- President Farooq Leghari said the formal inclusion of chiefs of the armed forces in the Council for Defence and National Security in an advisory capacity did not mean that the forces would get an upper hand in national affairs.</p>
<p>- A team of U.S. election observers from the National Democratic Institute, affiliated with the Democratic Party in the United States, will soon arrive to monitor the elections.</p>
<p>- Sita White, an English millionairess living in Los Angles, said that she may come to Pakistan on January 25 to tell the Pakistani people that Imran Khan is the father of her child.</p>
<p>BUSINESS RECORDER</p>
<p>- British Prime Minister John Major asked Pakistan government to attract long-term investment and trade by timely conclusion of international contracts and follow the policy of liberalisation and privatisation.</p>
<p>- The government assured the International Monetary Fund that collection of agricultural income tax would be around half percent of Gross Domestic Product, in line with IMF conditions.</p>
<p>- The President has issued an amending ordinance to exempt capital gain tax on sale of shares till June 1998.</p>
<p>FINANCIAL POST</p>
<p>- The IMF has still not received the macroeconomics data from Pakistan that will form the basis of the decision whether or not to release the $80 million tranche of the stand-by loan.</p>
<p>THE NEWS</p>
<p>- Commercial loans of about $250 million have raised Pakistan's external debt to more than $30 billion.</p>
<p>-- Karachi newsroom 9221-5685192</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
