<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="309282" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Profit growth expectations buoy Colombo stocks.</title>
<headline>Profit growth expectations buoy Colombo stocks.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lanka stocks closed stronger on strength in finance and manufacturing shares, which are expected to feature prominently in any 1997 economic recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a lot of buying by rich locals and institutions, in anticipation of good growth in the last quarter of 1996 and in 1997,&quot; said Gordon Nadesan, a trader at brokerage CT Smith.</p>
<p>The all share index closed 4.47 points higher at 622.40. Price gains outnumbered declines by 34 to 27. Commercial Bank rose nine rupees to 150, Dipped Products and Lanka Ceramic rose 2.25 each to 84.25 and 34.25 respectively.  </p>
<p>Buying was centred around banking and manufacturing stocks, which are seen the first to respond to any recovery in 1997 following a drought and power cuts last year, he said.</p>
<p>Turnover was 46.5 million rupees on trading of 1.2 million shares. Foreign buying totalled 8.7 million rupees and selling 19.4 million.</p>
<p>Brokers expect the index to move up towards the 630-point level before profit-taking sets in.</p>
<p>&quot;Potential sellers who see the index rising steadily will hold back to get the maximum possible,&quot; said Prasanna Chandrasekera, trader at broker John Keells. -Prithi Kodagoda</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
