<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="309677" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Brady bonds on the rise, good times seen staying.</title>
<headline>Brady bonds on the rise, good times seen staying.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>After a shaky start to the week, Brady bonds regained composure on Wednesday as traders generally found renewed confidence in financial markets and predicted more gains.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole screen is looking in very good shape this morning,&quot; ABN-AMRO trader Marcello Vasquez said.</p>
<p>By Tuesday's close, the West Merchant Bank Brady index had risen 0.8 percent to a new high, above the previous December peak.</p>
<p>Stripped spreads, which compare the value of Bradys without their collateral to U.S. Treasuries, fell below 500 basis points for the first time.</p>
<p>&quot;Country fundamentals are strong enough to support a continuation of the rally, as long as liquidity exists in search of high yield outlets,&quot; West Merchant Bank economic adviser Peter West said.</p>
<p>&quot;With measured inflation in the U.S. remaining low, there would not seem to be any compelling reason for the U.S. Fed to tighten policy just yet. The good times look set to roll on,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Both Russia and Bulgaria have recovered from their falls at the start of the week.</p>
<p>Traders have taken some heart from the willingness of Bulgaria's ruling Socialist Party to bring elections forward, albeit not until late in the year.</p>
<p>But most traders remain extremely wary of the bonds until the country implements a currency board and satisfies International Monetary Fund conditions for a loan.</p>
<p>Earlier fears over Russian President Boris Yeltsin's health appear to have dissipated for the moment, with the Kremlin continuing to insist that he is recovering well from pneumonia.</p>
<p>However, the debt price continues to stay at the lower end of its range over the past two months.</p>
<p>&quot;Yields are not yet generous enough to overwieght Russia,&quot; Bank of America analyst Richard Gray said.</p>
<p>Latin America is also recovering across the board.</p>
<p>West said he expected approval on Wednesday of an amendment in Brazil that would represent the first major step forward in President Fernando Enrique Cardoso's bid to be elected to a second term.</p>
<p>&quot;But in Brazil, things must very definitely be taken one step at a time, and today's vote will be a move in the right direction,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Gray said whichever way the vote goes, Cardoso has been weakened and with him, the prospects for significant economic reform and holding down states' spending.</p>
<p>Traders said Mexcio, Argentina and Venezuela all looked likely to continue to firm.</p>
<p>-- Jonathan Thatcher, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7770 (fax +44 171 583 7239)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
