<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="309737" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Rival Iraqi Kurds agree to help civilians.</title>
<headline>Rival Iraqi Kurds agree to help civilians.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two rival Iraqi Kurdish militias agreed at peace talks that ended in Turkey on Wednesday to improve the conditions of civilians harmed by their feud but the groups did not discuss key bones of contention.</p>
<p>&quot;The (Kurdistan Democratic Party) KDP and (Patriotic Union of Kurdistan) PUK also agreed...that previously displaced persons should be allowed to return to their homes,&quot; the participants said in a statement after two days of talks brokered by the United States, Turkey and Britain.</p>
<p>The Kurds agreed &quot;to end immediately the forced expulsion of each group's supporters from territories under their control&quot;, the statement said.</p>
<p>Western diplomats say tens of thousands of Kurdish civilians were displaced in several months of fighting between the groups in northern Iraq last year.</p>
<p>The KDP, led by Massoud Barzani, joined forces with Iraqi government troops to take the key city of Arbil in August, prompting retaliatory U.S. missile strikes on Iraqi targets.</p>
<p>The clashes gave Baghdad a foothold in the Western-protected north of Iraq for the first time since the end of the Gulf War in 1991.</p>
<p>Participants said the future status of Arbil and the thorny issue of revenue sharing was not brought up at the Ankara talks because the two sides wanted to build mutual confidence step by step.</p>
<p>The statement said Kurdish groups agreed to withdraw their forces from disputed areas along a ceasefire line and support a peace monitoring force of ethnic Turkomans and Assyrians that is to begin its task in February.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
