<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="309908" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bachelor party results in assault charges.</title>
<headline>Bachelor party results in assault charges.</headline>
<dateline>TROY, N.Y. 1997-01-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>A New York jailguard is accused of attacking a stripper at his own bachelor party, which spilled over to a local bar where he and his friends attacked other women as well, authorities said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Sgt. Mark Piche, a corrections officer at the Rensselaer County, New York, jail, is due to arrive home from his honeymoon in Aruba this week to face sexual abuse and harassment charges, said county Sheriff Daniel Keating.</p>
<p>The charges stem from Piche's late night bachelor party on Dec. 28 at a private club, where a friend of the groom's hired four nude dancers for $700 for a two-hour show, he said.</p>
<p>Police and witnesses said the party got out of hand when Piche allegedly held the women against their will and violently groped and fondled them and then sexually assaulted one stripper.</p>
<p>Piche is charged with harassment for allegedly harassing two brothers hired by the club owner to protect the women.</p>
<p>The party continued at another nightclub where witnesses said Piche and his friends groped the breasts and buttocks of female patrons, authorities said.</p>
<p>They also allegedly beat up the bouncer and punched and kicked other customers before police broke up the scene in the early hours of the following day, they said.</p>
<p>Police already arrested a friend of the groom's and charged him with assault, harassment and resisting arrest after he allegedly hit a Troy, New York, police oficer, fled the scene and was chased down by a police dog, authorities said.</p>
<p>If convicted on the sexual abuse charge, the guard faces a year in jail, authorities said. He is scheduled to appear in Troy Police Court on Wednesday, the sheriff said.</p>
<p>Authorities were investigating whether other county employees were at the party.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TROY, N.Y."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
