<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="30997" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Smurfit says all areas hit by lower pricing.</title>
<headline>Smurfit says all areas hit by lower pricing.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paper and packaging group Jefferson Smurfit Plc said on Tuesday that operations in all regions suffered from price reductions and over-capacity within the industry in the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>Smurfit said the group's U.S. subsidiaries had a difficult first six months but plastics performed well and its election printing business would benefit from the U.S. presidential poll in the second half of this year.</p>
<p>It said while packaging volumes had been flat in Ireland in the first half, it expected them to recover in the second half and on an overall basis they should be satisfactory for 1996.  </p>
<p>Smurfit said the UK corrugated market continued to be oversupplied and during the period volumes had remained flat.</p>
<p>&quot;While the region's first half results have been somewhat disappointing, it is anticipated that the performance will be stronger in the second half,&quot; Smurfit said in a results statement which showed a drop of 37 percent in pre-tax profit for the first half.</p>
<p>Smurfit reported pre-tax profit of 126 million punts for the six months to June 1996 and announced an increase of seven percent in its first half dividend to 1.5 pence per share.  </p>
<p>Smurfit finance director Ray Curran said Smurfit's U.S. associate Jefferson Smurfit Corporation (JSC) had experienced good volume growth in the first half but at a cost.</p>
<p>&quot;Pricing is poor and transaction prices are up to $200 off their peak. While from a business standpoint they are holding their own, obviously the bottom line suffers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said most analysts were disappointed with July growth figures which showed growth year-on-year of only 1.8 percent and again the jury was out on whether it was the end of a restocking phase or not.  </p>
<p>He said the group's French operation Cellulose du Pin continues to be earnings enhancing and was operationally doing well &quot;... but the big mills within the Cellulose companies are obviously feeling the pressure on the pricing side&quot;.</p>
<p>He said European pricing was obviously following the U.S. on the mill side &quot;but we are still making decent money on the (Cellulose) investment and it has been well integrated&quot;.</p>
<p>Curran addmitted that there was, however, scope for further cost cutting in the French operation but it would take time to achieve.  </p>
<p>&quot;Undoubletedy there is scope for further cost cutting in Cellulose but France and Europe are not the U.S. and you need a longer term view simply because of different labour practices.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;In the U.S. you can &quot;decruit&quot; 100-200 people but if you do that in France you can spend the next six months in dispute. We don't have any hang-ups with that, we always knew what we were getting into,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Carmel Linnane Dublin Newsroom + 353 1 676 9775</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
