<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="309964" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France urges more Serbian election concessions.</title>
<headline>France urges more Serbian election concessions.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>France, welcoming on Wednesday the Serbian government's acknowledgement that the opposition had won elections in the two main cities, said east European countries must respect democracy if they want to join the West.</p>
<p>&quot;The time when democratic process could be trampled over and popular votes annulled in Europe must be over,&quot; Foreign Minister Herve de Charette told the National Assembly.</p>
<p>&quot;Eastern and Central European countries must first respect democratic institutions and the people's vote if Europe is to be be united as we wish, and if they want to embark towards economic progress as their interest commands,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is what we are working for,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Foreign Ministry said it would monitor implementation of the Serbian government's concessions and insisted Belgrade authorities must recognise that they lost the elections in 14 cities, as the Organisation for Security and Coopereation in Europe (OSCE) said.</p>
<p>&quot;We remain vigilant and are awaiting confirmation and implementation of judicial rulings, as well as the recognition of the opposition's victory in all the cities named by (the OSCE's) Felipe Gonzalez,&quot; the ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>Electoral officials have voted to reinstate the opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition's victory in elections for the Belgrade municipal assembly and in Nis, Serbia's second biggest city. But the breakthrough looked vulnerable to challenges or sabotage by diehard Socialists.</p>
<p>De Charette has repeatedly put pressure on Serbian authorities to concede defeat in 14 cities. He received earlier this week Vesna Pesic, a leader of the opposition coalition which spearheaded eight-week-old peaceful demonstrations for democracy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
