<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="309988" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French police, troops stay on alert for bombs.</title>
<headline>French police, troops stay on alert for bombs.</headline>
<byline>John Follain</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre said on Wednesday police and troops taking part in a nationwide security operation would stay on alert as long as necessary after the bombing of a Paris train a month ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The fight against terrorism, which creates a permanent climate of tension, the search for the authors of the Port-Royal bombing, and break-up of networks is our absolute priority,&quot; Debre told reporters at a New Year reception.</p>
<p>Four people died and nearly 100 were injured in the December 3 rush-hour blast at the Port-Royal station in central Paris.</p>
<p>Debre said the so-called &quot;Vigipirate&quot; plan, involving security forces' patrols at stations, airports and other potential targets, would &quot;stay in force as long as necessary&quot;.</p>
<p>Police chiefs say their forces had been placed on alert, with plainclothes officers patrolling the Paris metro.</p>
<p>Intelligence sources have said French security services were also warned to be vigilant around Saturday's fifth anniversary of the military intervention in Algeria which put an end to elections which Islamic fundamentalists were poised to win.</p>
<p>In the capital alone, some 3,000 military and police, including 320 members of the Foreign Legion, have been deployed.</p>
<p>Late last month, Algeria's Armed Islamic Group (GIA) threatened attacks against France in a letter to President Jacques Chirac. The GIA has been blamed for a wave of bomb attacks which killed eight people in France in 1995.</p>
<p>Debre said the inquiry into the Port-Royal explosion, which investigators said initially was probably the work of Algerian Moslem fundamentalists who planted the previous series of bombs, was &quot;difficult&quot;.</p>
<p>He acknowledged there were many similarities with the investigation into the 1995 attacks, which led to the dismantling of several Algerian Moslem fundamentalist networks, but added that the devices used were technically different.</p>
<p>He said the bomb may have been manufactured by a different individual and &quot;could also be part of an internal settling of scores&quot; between factions at war in Algeria.</p>
<p>He confirmed a newspaper report that investigators had found a fingerprint on a piece of sticky tape which may have been used to attach a timer to the gas cannister containing the explosive.</p>
<p>&quot;But the fingerprint is of interest only if it is in our records,&quot; Debre said, refusing to elaborate. The daily Le Parisien reported that the tape was partially burnt and that the fingerprint was too incomplete for proper identification.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
