<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31003" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: PRESS DIGEST - France - Sept 3.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - France - Sept 3.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are leading stories in this morning's Paris newspapers.</p>
<p>-- New car registrations jumped 29.4 percent in August from August 1995, boosted by a governmental incentive measure for buyers of new cars, which comes to an end this month. (Les Echos, La Tribune, Le Figaro, Liberation).</p>
<p>-- Credit Foncier de France minority shareholders start legal action for a further auditing of the ailing bank's 1995 accounts which showed huge losses. Credit Foncier posted a 400-million-franc profit for the first half of 1996. (Les Echos, La Tribune, Le Figaro, Liberation).</p>
<p>LES ECHOS</p>
<p>-- Retail group Promodes sells its 36 Continent supermarkets in Germany to German group Spar AG.</p>
<p>LA TRIBUNE DESFOSSES</p>
<p>-- France Telecom telecommunications operator to pay 37.5 billion francs to the state as provision for civil servants' retirements, which the government will use to meet the Maastricht treaty deficit cut targets.</p>
<p>-- A tax on property transfers to rise 2 percent in January and government not ruling out raising taxes on tobacco again.</p>
<p>LE FIGARO-ECONOMIE</p>
<p>-- Labour Minister Jacques Barrot and Health Minister Herve Gaymard opened yesterday a conference on public health spending to prepare laws on social security finances.</p>
<p>LIBERATION Economic Section</p>
<p>-- European aircraft industry to unite, seeks to fend off U.S. competitors.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5381</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
