<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="310096" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: U.N. agencies warn Rwanda needs major food aid.</title>
<headline>U.N. agencies warn Rwanda needs major food aid.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rwanda will need substantial food aid this year following the return of more than one million refugees from neighbouring countries, two United Nations agencies said in a joint report on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Food and Agriculture Organisation (FAO) and World Food Programme (WFP) said that a joint mission to the central African country in December had found that food production there was still struggling to recover from the 1994 genocide.</p>
<p>&quot;The additional upsurge in food needs will undoubtedly strain the already fragile and unstable food supply situation in the country,&quot; the joint report said.</p>
<p>It said Rwanda would face a food deficit in the first half of 1997 of 30,000 tonnes of cereals, 45,000 tonnes of pulses, 124,000 tonnes of roots and tubers and 522,000 tonnes of bananas and plantains.</p>
<p>In cereal equivalent terms, it said the deficit was estimated at 141,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;Only a part of this can be met through commercial imports,&quot; the joint report said, adding that a &quot;significant level&quot; of additional aid was required above that already given.</p>
<p>It estimated food aid requirements for the first half of the year at 81,000 tonnes of cereals and 33,000 tonnes of pulses to cover the needs of more than 2.5 million people.</p>
<p>Rwanda's food output had also been affected by crop losses in regions hit by dry weather and low yields of beans.</p>
<p>Some 800,000 Tutsis and moderate Hutus are estimated to have been killed in 1994 genocide sparked by the assassination of Hutu president and military strongman Juvenal Habyarimana.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
