<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="310230" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Stanley ahead despite &quot;Dettori effect'.</title>
<headline>Stanley ahead despite &quot;Dettori effect'.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Betting shop and gaming company Stanley Leisure Organisation Plc said on Wednesday that half-year profits rose by 21 percent despite a hit of more than 2.0 million stg when jockey Frankie Dettori rode all seven winners at a race meeting at Asoct.</p>
<p>Chairman Leonard Steinberg said in the results statement that the company was confident for the future in both its betting and gaming divisions and looked forward to the second half of the financial year &quot;with eager anticipation&quot;.  </p>
<p>Stanley reported pre-tax profits 21 percent ahead at 7.04 million stg in the six months to October 27, 1996, and raised its interim dividend by 20 percent to 1.2p which Steinberg said reflected the board's optimism for the future.</p>
<p>&quot;Trading in the racing division since the half year has been good and we are pleased with the improvement in turnover and profitability, whilst the casino division traditionally has its best trading period between November and January in each year. Machine revenue in both divisions continues to improve,&quot; Steinberg said.  </p>
<p>&quot;At the time of our AGM I was confident and perhaps foolish enough to say that we expected our interim trading figures to beat the record profits made in the half year to October 1994,&quot; Steinberg said.</p>
<p>&quot;Little was I to know at that time that a jockey called Frankie Dettori would ride all seven winners at the main Ascot meeting on the following Saturday...In congratulating Mr Dettori on his remarkable and unique success, it resulted in the worst day ever in the UK bookmaking business.</p>
<p>&quot;Your company's pay-out on those results was over two million stg, of which the shops taken over in our most recent acquisition, Gus Carter, had a pay-out of 543,000 stg, with one bet alone of 235,000 stg.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This is what is affectionately known as the &quot;Dettori effect'. Had it not happened, we would have comfortably exceeded our record 1994 interim figures with profits in excess of 9.5 million stg,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the national lottery was still a major concern, particularly with the introduction of a mid-week draw next month. The company had hoped that in view of this, the government would allow betting on the lottery numbers.</p>
<p>This has not happened, but Steinberg said betting on numbers, known as the &quot;49s&quot;, betting on the Irish Lottery draw, which now accounts for some 2.5 percent of turnover, and deregulation of fruit machines &quot;gives us a reasonable shop window to fight the competition from the National Lottery and scratch cards.&quot;</p>
<p>He said a reduction in betting duty of one percentage point, tax changes which came into effect in April 1996 and the improved economy had also contributed to improved turnover.</p>
<p>Stanley said gaming margins in the casino division still give some cause for concern.</p>
<p>&quot;Members have, over a period of time, become more knowledgeable in playing the games, and are managing their money in a better way. We believe that further investment in the training and development of our staff will help improve margins and we are working on a detailed and rigorous campaign to ensure that the quality of our staff is enhanced,&quot; Steinberg said.</p>
<p>He said the future of the casino division was tied in to further deregulation which will allow three machines per gaming table in casinos, and with no limit on stake and pay-out.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that these machines will change the face of the casino business and result in considerably improved profitability,&quot; Steinberg said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
