<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="310456" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan stocks end higher, caution seen near 7,200.</title>
<headline>Taiwan stocks end higher, caution seen near 7,200.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan share prices closed higher on Wednesday, but brokers saw caution ahead of the six-year strong resistance at 7,200 points.</p>
<p>The index ended up 27.70 points or 0.39 percent at 7,165.46, off a 7,190.90 high. Turnover remained active at T$76.74 billion, but down from recent turnover of around T$100 billion.</p>
<p>Brokers attributed the rise to continuous bullish market sentiment despite a downward correction on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are still quite optimistic, grabbing every single bullish factor available,&quot; said Jardine Fleming Securities fund manger George Hou.  </p>
<p>Sentiment was helped by net buying by foreign funds and local securities trust funds on Tuesday despite overall profit-taking, brokers said.</p>
<p>Textiles rose most on rising prices for polyester drawn texturised yarn, with Lealea Enterprise up T$1 to T$23.7.</p>
<p>It would take time to see whether the drawn texturised yarn price hikes were caused by rising demand from China or a reflection of domestic economic recovery, said National Securities analyst Alex Yang.</p>
<p>Far Eastern Textile continued to rise after it won one of eight mobile phone licenses on Monday, up T$1.4 to T$32.5.  </p>
<p>Plastics and constructions were also strong while electronics fell slightly.</p>
<p>Brokers said liquidity remained quite loose to support the market. &quot;Recent rallies were liquidity-driven,&quot; Hou of Jardine Fleming said. &quot;And the recent successful fund raising by several securities trust funds showed that investors are waiting to jump into the market.&quot;</p>
<p>However, analysts said they did not expect the 7,200-point resistance to be easily broken through. A consolidation range of 7,100-7,200 was seen for Thursday.</p>
<p>-- James Peng (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
