<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="310486" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: History of South Korean labour unrest.</title>
<headline>History of South Korean labour unrest.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trade union calls for all-out strikes in South Korea on Wednesday to protest against a controversial new labour law were largely ignored.</p>
<p>This followed poor worker response to a similar plea by unions to down tools on Tuesday following three weeks of wildcat stoppages that have hit the export-led economy.</p>
<p>Industrial problems have plagued South Korea since democratic reforms in 1987.</p>
<p>Strikes are most common around May and June when annual pay negotiations, which typically last for several months, reach their climax.</p>
<p>The following is a chronology of major strike-related developments in recent years:</p>
<p>June 1987 - Strikes erupt after Roh Tae-woo, then ruling party presidential candidate, promises new democratic reforms, releasing worker fury suppressed under decades of military rule. Seven million work days lost over several months. Hyundai workers in southeast city of Ulsan torch cars, storm government offices and battle riot police.</p>
<p>March 16, 1989 - Police detain more than 2,000 Seoul subway workers who went on strike in defiance of a ban.</p>
<p>March 30, 1989 - Striking dockworkers battle riot police after massive police assault on Hyundai Heavy Industries Co at Ulsan. Police arrest 700 workers.</p>
<p>April 28, 1990 - Amphibious assault by 10,000 troops ends 109-day strike at Hyundai shipyard in Ulsan. Five months production lost during the year. At their peak, strikes involve more than 400,000 workers.</p>
<p>June 3, 1991 - Police arrest 33 strikers after storming firearms plant in southwestern town of Yangsan.</p>
<p>June 26, 1994 - More than 5,000 riot police crush anti-government protests in Seoul by striking subway workers and students.</p>
<p>July 1, 1994 - End of week-long strike by railway and subway workers that brought a virtual halt to nation's rail system.</p>
<p>May 1995 - Dismissed Hyundai Motor worker Yang Bong-soo sets himself on fire. He had stopped production of a new model car he said had not been cleared by the union.</p>
<p>June 6, 1995 - Police storm Seoul's Myongdong Roman Catholic Cathedral and Chogye Buddhist Temple to arrest 13 Korea Telecom union leaders who had led strikes over privatisation plans.</p>
<p>April 24, 1996 - President Kim Young-sam pledges labour law reform.</p>
<p>December 26, 1996 - New labour bill rammed through parliament in dawn session attended only by ruling New Korea Party deputies. Clauses include allowing worker layoffs and replacing strikers; Federation of Korean Trade Unions to retain its legal monopoly on union representation until 2000. Unions launch series of wildcat strikes.</p>
<p>Jan 11, 1997 - Riot police battle 20,000 strikers in central Seoul in biggest clash over the new law.</p>
<p>Jan 14, 1997 - Weak response to union calls for the biggest strike in the nation's history. The Federation of Korean Trade Unions had called its 1.2 million members out on Tuesday and Wednesday. They were to be joined on Wednesday by the Korean Confederation of Trade Unions with 500,000 members.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
