<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="310521" id="root" date="1997-01-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Netanyahu, Arafat meet to clinch Hebron deal.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu, Arafat meet to clinch Hebron deal.</headline>
<byline>Taher Shriteh</byline>
<dateline>EREZ CROSSING 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Palestinian President Yasser Arafat held a summit on Wednesday in an effort to clinch a long elusive Hebron deal.</p>
<p>The two men went into talks at the Erez crossing between Israel and the Gaza Strip for a meeting officials said could culminate in the initialling of an agreement to extend Palestinian rule to most of Hebron in the West Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The atmosphere is positive and upbeat,&quot; government spokesman Moshe Fogel told Reuters by phone from Erez.</p>
<p>U.S. Middle East envoy Dennis Ross, who hours earlier announced the summit, was mediating at Erez along with other American officials.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope there will be a signing tonight. There are still some minor issues which need to be resolved,&quot; PLO negotiator Mahmoud Abbas told reporters after efforts on Tuesday to clear final hurdles ahead of the summit.</p>
<p>&quot;The chance that we will finish this evening exists but it is not guaranteed,&quot; Netanyahu told reporters after the summit was announced on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Hebron, a West Bank flashpoint, is home to 400 militant Jewish settlers and 100,000 Arabs. It was due to be given self-rule 10 months ago but violence, security concerns and Israel's change of government in June delayed the pullback.</p>
<p>By sealing the Hebron deal Netanyahu will be doing what he and his right-wing Likud party said they would never do -- cede part of the biblical Land of Israel to Palestinians.</p>
<p>In Jerusalem, nearly 200 settler leaders who oppose the Hebron deal called on members of Netanyahu's cabinet to vote against it.</p>
<p>&quot;The agreement is a suicide pact,&quot; David Wilder, a spokesman for Hebron's settlers, told Reuters. &quot;It's like having somebody hold a gun to your head and having somebody else helping to pull the trigger.&quot;</p>
<p>At least seven of 18 cabinet members have said they will oppose the agreement when it comes up for government approval.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Netanyahu has a solid majority for the agreement,&quot; his communications chief David Bar-Illan told CNN television. &quot;Most ministers will vote for it.&quot;</p>
<p>Hebron is holy to Moslems and Jews who regard the Tomb of the Patriarchs as the burial place of the biblical Abraham. The tomb, the town's Jewish enclaves and about a fifth of Hebron's Arabs will remain under Israeli control.</p>
<p>Palestinian police will deploy in the rest of Hebron, the last of seven Palestinian towns that were to be turned over to Palestinian self-rule under a 1995 interim peace accord signed by the previous Israeli government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EREZ CROSSING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
