<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="310786" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries close down after Fed's Meyer speech.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries close down after Fed's Meyer speech.</headline>
<byline>John P. Hughes</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>An already jittery U.S. government securities market was further jolted by a Federal Reserve policymaker's remarks and fell sharply Thursday.</p>
<p>The 30-year bond ended down 15/32 at 95-25/32 to yield 6.83 percent.</p>
<p>The market had been struggling to cope with the largest investment grade debt offering ever, when Fed Governor Laurence Meyer delivered a series of remarks regarded as being hawkish on inflation -- implying the Fed was ready to tighten monetary policy at the first hint of rising prices.  </p>
<p>Meyer made his comments about midday just as the $4.1 billion US West deal was being priced. Its size had been increased for the third time and dealers were scrambling to contend with new supply.</p>
<p>Meyer said in North Carolina that wage increases bore scrutiny and the Fed must watch for signs of growing price pressures and act quickly if needed to contain them. He said risks to the economy were &quot;a little&quot; bit toward the upside.</p>
<p>&quot;Today it was all Meyer's comments on the risks being to the upside that upset the market,&quot; said Cary Leahey, senior economist at Lehman Government Securities Inc.  </p>
<p>Prior to Meyer's remarks the market had been up and down, but holding up fairly well after the release of initial jobless claims early in the session, Leahey said.</p>
<p>Claims for the January 11 week fell to 323,000 from a revised 355,000 in the prior week. Traders had expected claims to fall 6,000 to 355,000 from the original 361,000 in the previous week. Treasuries had been trading higher, but fell back slightly after the data, which did not shock market participants.</p>
<p>&quot;But the market held in real well until the Meyer comments,&quot; Leahey said, even with the US West debt deal.  </p>
<p>Leahey noted that Fed Governor Susan Phillips made comments similar to Meyer's later in the session on a news wire. &quot;She was saying the same kinds of things, but not as emphatically,&quot; he said. &quot;The tone of the market was very nervous anyway and Meyer's comments were just the thing to push it.&quot;</p>
<p>Meyer's comments kindled fears that the Fed might tighten monetary policy as soon as the next meeting of its policy-making Federal Open Market Committee on Febuary 4 and 5.  </p>
<p>David Orr, chief capital markets economist at First Union Corp., said &quot;I'm mystified at the market's reaction.&quot; to Meyer's speech, which he attended. He called it &quot;a 'round up the usual suspects' speech&quot; in which Meyer said &quot;the same things all the Fed people have been saying all along and made every effort to be balanced.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to me the market didn't react to the only new information we had today in initial claims,&quot; Orr said. &quot;Maybe it was a case of morning amnesia, but that's what it should have reacted to.&quot;  </p>
<p>Two-year notes ended at 99-18/32, down 2/32, yielding 5.99 percent. Five-year notes were 5/32 lower to finish at 99-4/32, yielding 6.33 percent. Ten-year notes lost 9/32 to end at 99-18/32, yielding 6.56 percent.</p>
<p>Three-month bill rates rose two basis points and ended at 5.03 percent. Six-month bill rates rose one basis point and finished at 5.07 percent. Year bill rates rose three basis points and ended at 5.30 percent.</p>
<p>((-- North American Treasury Desk 212-859-1663))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
