<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311024" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cephalon funding from Schering-Plough ends.</title>
<headline>Cephalon funding from Schering-Plough ends.</headline>
<dateline>WEST CHESTER, Pa. 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cephalon Inc said on Thursday that Schering-Plough Corp will discontinue its funding of the companies' research collaboration to develop compounds for the treatment of Alzheimer's disease.</p>
<p>According to company spokesman, Cephalon received $3 million from Schering-Plough from the collaboration in 1996.</p>
<p>The research collaboration has focused on the development of protease inhibitors that prevent the secretion of beta-amyloid peptide, a major component of the neuritic plaques that cause neuronal death in patients with Alzheimer's disease.  </p>
<p>In 1991, Schering-Plough and Cephalon entered into a five-year agreement worth $20 million.  The partnership was renewed in 1995.</p>
<p>A spokesman from Schering-Plough said that Schering is taking its preclinical central nervous system research in-house.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be developing new medications for the treatment of cognitive disorders and degenerative diseases, including Alzheimer's and schizophrenia,&quot; the Schering-Plough spokesman said.</p>
<p>Cephalon said that it remains committed to pursuing this therapeutic approach to treating Alzheimer's disease.</p>
<p>The company said that other provisions of the companies' agreement continue, including Cephalon's nonexclusive rights to use the technology developed in the program and the right to receive royalties on net sales of any products licensed exclusively to Schering-Plough under the agreement.  </p>
<p>In November, Cephalon reported a loss of $2.00 a share on revenues of $11.4 million for the nine months ended September 30, 1996.</p>
<p>Cephalon stock was down one point to 23 in late morning trade.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WEST CHESTER, Pa."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
