<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311062" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-&quot;I NEVER HAD A DRINK PROBLEM,&quot; CLOUGH SAYS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-&quot;I NEVER HAD A DRINK PROBLEM,&quot; CLOUGH SAYS.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brian Clough, the irrepressible former coach of Nottingham Forest and one of the all-time greats of English soccer management, has denied he was ever an alcoholic.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't have a problem with drink,&quot; he told British satellite TV station Sky News.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a social side to football as there is to most careers and I've been known to have the odd glass of champagne and with every good reason to have it.</p>
<p>&quot;I did go through a stage where possibly instead of having one glass of champagne I was having two and that inevitably became three, and all that, but it was all part and parcel of the job, an accepted part and parcel of every day life.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked about his earlier admission that his family had been concerned about the amount he drank, Clough said: &quot;That's perfectly true. I've cut it out totally.&quot;</p>
<p>He laughed off rumours he had been seriously ill, saying: &quot;I wasn't at death's door for a start.</p>
<p>&quot;I had a knee operation that set me back a bit but if people want to write about me at death's door, good luck to them. I hope everybody feels as good as I feel.&quot;</p>
<p>Clough is one of only three men, along with 1930s manager Herbert Chapman and new Newcastle boss Kenny Dalglish, to have won the English league title with two different clubs.</p>
<p>He guided Derby to championship success in 1972 and then repeated the feat with Forest six years later.</p>
<p>Clough, renowned for his straight-talking approach to life, began his managerial career at Hartlepool aged 29 after a serious knee injury ended his days as a player.</p>
<p>He then moved to Derby and had spells at Brighton and Leeds before arriving at Forest in 1975, guiding them to successive European Cup triumphs in 1979 and 1980.</p>
<p>He managed Forest for 18 years, stepping down in 1993 when they were relegated from the premier league.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
