<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311160" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: MERRILL LOWERS POLIFARBC 97 PROFIT OUTLOOK.</title>
<headline>MERRILL LOWERS POLIFARBC 97 PROFIT OUTLOOK.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Merrill Lynch in London has lowered its 1997 profit forecast for Polish paintmaker Polifarb Cieszyn SA by 10 percent because of the current competitive market environment, Merrill said in a report dated December 18.</p>
<p>&quot;Following a conversation with management we have lowered our 1997 earnings forecast for (Polifarb Cieszyn) by 10 percent to reflect the current competitive market environment,&quot; said the report which maintained the firm's accumulate rating.</p>
<p>Merrill did not give its forecasted profits for the firm but changed its 1997 earnings-per-share (EPS) forecast to 1.23 zlotys from the 1.37 zlotys earlier in the month.</p>
<p>The company currently has 19,125,000 shares outstanding.</p>
<p>Merrill said the prediction did not reflect the company's planned merger later in 1997 with Polifarb Wroclaw , which it saw as a good sign.</p>
<p>&quot;For current shareholders the merger should enhance value by eliminating inter-company competition, boosting purchasing power and focusing management on cost cutting,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Merrill said the merger should lead to EPS growth starting in 1998 as product lines were rationalised and manufacturing assets optimised.</p>
<p>Polifarb Cieszyn, which was at 14.5 zlotys at the time of the report, closed at 18 zlotys on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
