<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311213" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reuters historical calendar - January 23.</title>
<headline>Reuters historical calendar - January 23.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the major events to have occurred on January 23 in history.</p>
<p>1516 - Ferdinand II of Aragon died and was succeeded as King of Spain by his grandson Charles V.</p>
<p>1622 - William Baffin, British navigator and explorer who gave his name to Baffin Island, died.</p>
<p>1668 - Holland, Britain and Sweden signed the Alliance of the Hague, known as the Triple Alliance, under which they agreed to aid one another if attacked.</p>
<p>1719 - The Principality of Liechtenstein was formed by the amalgamation of Vaduz and Schellenberg.</p>
<p>1783 - Stendhal, French novelist, born as Marie Henri Beyle. His masterpieces, &quot;Le Rouge et le Noir&quot; and &quot;La Chartreuse de Parme&quot;, did not receive widespread recognition during his life.</p>
<p>1793 - Russia and Prussia agreed to a second partition of Poland.</p>
<p>1806 - William Pitt the younger, British prime minister, died. At the age of 24, he became Britain's youngest prime minister.</p>
<p>1832 - Edouard Manet, French painter, born. His &quot;Dejeuner sur l'herbe&quot; scandalised the critics but won him the enthusiasm of a group of young painters who became the forerunners of the Impressionists.</p>
<p>1883 - Gustave Dore, French artist and illustrator, died. One of the most successful book illustrators of the 19th century who was famed for his dream-like scenes.</p>
<p>1898 - Sergei Mikhailovich Eisenstein, Russian film director, born. His films include &quot;The Battleship Potemkin&quot; and &quot;Ten Days that Shook the World&quot;.</p>
<p>1900 - In the second British-Boer War, the British attempt to break through the Boer lines to relieve Ladysmith was thwarted at the Battle of Spion Kop.</p>
<p>1903 - Randolph Scott, U.S. film actor in numerous westerns, born as Randolph Crance.</p>
<p>1928 - Jeanne Moreau, French stage and screen actress, born. Her films include &quot;Les Liaisons Dangereuses&quot; and &quot;Jules et Jim&quot;.</p>
<p>1931 - Anna Pavlova, Russian dancer and one of the most celebrated prima ballerinas of her time, died.</p>
<p>1937 - The trial of seventeen leading Communists began in Moscow, after they were accused of involvement in a plot led by Leon Trotsky to overthrow the regime and assassinate its leaders.</p>
<p>1943 - In World War Two, the British under Field Marshal Montgomery captured Tripoli, Libya.</p>
<p>1943 - After nine days of talks in Casablanca, President Roosevelt and British Prime Minister Winston Churchill agree to put an invasion of Italy ahead of opening a second front in northwestern Europe.</p>
<p>1944 - Edvard Munch, Norwegian painter, died. His most notable work is &quot;The Scream&quot;.</p>
<p>1960 - The U.S. navy bathyscaphe Trieste dived to a record depth of 10,916 metres (35,810 feet) in the Pacific Ocean.</p>
<p>1961 - Venezuela's 26th constitution was promulgated by President Betancourt.</p>
<p>1963 - Harold &quot;Kim&quot; Philby, British journalist in Beirut, disappeared. Later in the year it was revealed that he was the third man in the Burgess-Maclean espionage affair and had been granted asylum in Moscow.</p>
<p>1968 - The North Koreans seized the American ship USS Pueblo, claiming it was spying. The crew were held until December.</p>
<p>1976 - Paul Robeson, U.S. singer and actor, died. Best known for the song &quot;Ole Man River.&quot; After the Second World War he turned increasingly to politics and his left-wing views led to him being ostracised at home. He left for Europe in 1958.</p>
<p>1978 - Baron Edouard-Jean Empain, one of Europe's most powerful industrialists, was kidnapped in Paris. He was freed on March 26.</p>
<p>1983 - Soviet satellite Cosmos 1402 entered Earth's atmosphere and crashed into the Indian Ocean.</p>
<p>1989 - Spanish surrealist painter Salvador Dali died. He was buried in a crypt under a glass dome in the Dali museum in Figueras, in Catalonia.</p>
<p>1995 - Jacques Delors formally stepped down as European Commission president, handing over to Jacques Santer after 10 years of steering Europe towards closer union.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
