<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311375" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Energy Africa seen low-cost Gabon oil firm.</title>
<headline>Energy Africa seen low-cost Gabon oil firm.</headline>
<byline>Nicole Mordant</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The relatively small size of South African firm Energy Africa Ltd would give it a cost advantage over global oil majors in the exploration and development of fields in Gabon, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>But they said Energy Africa's involvement in the African republic would have little impact on foreign oil giants there, including Shell and Elf, as they had plenty of potential production acreage elsewhere on the continent.</p>
<p>Their comments follow news late on Wednesday that Energy Africa, by entering into a partnership agreement with the Gabon government, had acquired minority rights in almost all of its oil acreage for an undisclosed sum.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the fields have been known for some time, but have not been developed because they have been considered uneconomic by the oil majors,&quot; said Themis Themistocleous, an analyst at brokerage SBC Warburg.</p>
<p>&quot;However, Energy Africa in association with other independents may be able to develop them successfully because they have lower overheads.&quot;</p>
<p>Under the deal a new company, Energy Africa Gabon SA (EAG SA), would get rights to a 40 percent stake in three satellites to the onshore Rabi Kounga field, and minority interests in three offshore discoveries, all undergoing development studies.</p>
<p>EAG SA would be owned 25 percent by the Gabon government and 75 percent jointly by Energy Africa and an African investment group.</p>
<p>It would also secure the option to acquire interests of differing sizes, in the event of a discovery being made, in 22 other contracts being undertaken by a number of international operators, including Shell Gabon and Elf Gabon.</p>
<p>Commenting on the 22 contracts, another analyst who asked not to be identified said: &quot;If you take any of those exploration areas in isolation, none of them are particularly big. It's not going to do the Elfs and the Shells of this world any damage.&quot;</p>
<p>He said both companies, especially Elf, were very heavily involved in African acreage generally. &quot;They have a number of alternative places they can go and drill at any point in time.&quot;</p>
<p>Energy Africa shares on the Johannesburg Stock Exchange jumped nearly 11 percent to a new high of 20.50 on news of the deal but analysts and dealers said interest was mainly speculative and players remained wary of exploration stocks.</p>
<p>Benefits from the deal were also seen slow to take off.</p>
<p>&quot;It does not mean a thing in the short term, in terms of earnings potential...I think you are talking 12 to 18 months before we see some oil production from some of these things,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>But others said once production started it would help to offset an expected fall in Energy Africa's output from a peak of 16,000 barrels per day in 1998 to around 10,000 in 2000.</p>
<p>The deal was a further illustration of the firm's ability to establish good relations with governments in Africa, where it is also active in projects in Angola, offshore Congo and Namibia.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GABON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
