<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311311" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Cricket-Stuart hat-trick key to Australian win.</title>
<headline>Cricket-Stuart hat-trick key to Australian win.</headline>
<byline>Robert Galvin</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fast bowler Anthony Stuart claimed a hat-trick as Australia salvaged some pride with a thrilling three-wicket victory over Pakistan in their World Series limited overs match on Thursday.</p>
<p>Stuart, playing in only his third one-day match for his country, dismissed Ijaz Ahmed, Mohammad Wasim and wicketkeeper Moin Khan in successive balls as part of a five-wicket haul.</p>
<p>Chasing Pakistan's total of 181 for nine in 50 overs, left-hander Michael Bevan helped steer Australia to 182 for seven with three balls to spare, ending a run of five straight losses in the triangular competition.</p>
<p>Bevan scored an unbeaten and highly controlled 79 from 142 balls to ensure that Stuart's outstanding figures of five for 26 from 10 overs were not wasted.</p>
<p>The lanky New South Wales paceman became only the second Australian bowler -- and the 12th in the world -- to take a hat-trick in a limited overs international.</p>
<p>But the victory came too late for Australia, who failed to qualify for the final as hosts in their worst performance in one-day cricket at home for 17 years in terms of results.</p>
<p>Pakistan and West Indies will face each other in the best-of-three final, starting in Sydney on Saturday.</p>
<p>Given his outstanding innings, it was fitting that Bevan should be responsible for the winning run, even if it came as a leg bye off his pads.</p>
<p>Man of the match Stuart, playing in only his third one-day match for his country, took the first five wickets to fall in the space of 14 deliveries at a miserly cost of just one run in a devastating early burst.</p>
<p>In his sixth over with the new ball, he lured Ijaz and Wasim to edge faint catches to wicketkeeper Ian Healy before Moin deflected a thicker edge to Australia captain Mark Taylor at first slip.</p>
<p>Opener Inzamam-ul-Haq smashed five fours on his way to a hard-hitting 64 to bolster Pakistan's total after they slumped to 29 for five.</p>
<p>Stuart's hat-trick was the first by an Australian in a one-day international since fast bowler Bruce Reid in Sydney in January 1986.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
