<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311556" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania cen.bank lifts one-week rate to 65 pct.</title>
<headline>Romania cen.bank lifts one-week rate to 65 pct.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's central bank (BNR) said on Thursday it jacked up the minimum permitted rate for its one-week refinancing funds by eight percentage points, to 65 percent, stepping up its drive to tighten monetary policy.</p>
<p>The move follows a four percentage point rise in the rate to 57 percent last week and a hike in the central bank's discount rate to 50 percent earlier this month from 35 percent.  </p>
<p>The BNR's tightened monetary policy is aimed at calming quickening inflation, also in line with International Monetary Fund recommendations.</p>
<p>Year-on-year inflation rose to 47.4 percent last November from October's 45.1 percent, sharply exceeding the 20 percent target agreed with the Fund for 1996.</p>
<p>Inflation is expected to climb after Romania's new centrist government doubled fuel prices earlier this month.</p>
<p>The Fund suspended a three-year standby credit of $460 million after criticising what were considered lax policies of the leftist government toppled in November's general election.</p>
<p>The central bank reduced its refinancing funds at Thursday's auction to 1.1 trillion lei from a previous 2.15 trillion lei.</p>
<p>An IMF mission is expected to start talks in Bucharest on Thursday on a new loan accord with the centrist coalition cabinet headed by Prime Minister Victor Ciorbea. -- Mirela Eremia, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
