<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311561" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech Radiomobil, Siemens sign DM 40mln supply deal.</title>
<headline>Czech Radiomobil, Siemens sign DM 40mln supply deal.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czech mobile phone company Radiomobil a.s., partly-owned by Germany's DeTeMobil, a unit of Deutsche Telekom AG, on Thursday said it signed a 40 million marks ($25.1 million) supply deal with Siemens Mobile Network Division.</p>
<p>Radiomobil said in a statement that the supplies, to be delivered and installed by Siemens by May, would include base stations and interchanges for the firm's Global System for Mobile (GSM) digital mobile phone network.</p>
<p>Radiomobil spokeswoman Tereza Kakosova told Reuters that Siemens should help the firm to speed up coverage of the hilly country, which currently reaches about 40 percent of the 10 million Czechs.</p>
<p>&quot;A deep understanding of the Czech environment...combined with Siemens' active participation in installation of the equipment should significantly contribute to an improved roll-out of Radiomobil's network,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>It added that Motorola would remain the main technology supplier for Radiomobil.</p>
<p>Radiomobil has atrracted &quot;close to 40,000&quot; customers for its &quot;Paegas&quot; service as of the end of last year, Kakosova said.</p>
<p>The company, 51 percent onwed by Ceske Radiokomunikace a.s., started service in September last year as a competitor to Eurotel s.r.o., owned by fixed line operator SPT Telecom a.s., U.S. West Media Group, and Bell Atlantic Corp International.</p>
<p>A consortium led by DeTeMobil, including STET SpA of Italy and several Czech firms holding marginal stakes, won a government tender to become a 49 percent partner in a joint venture with Radiokomunikace.</p>
<p>It has so far failed to keep up with promises regarding the speed of coverage of the country with its signal, citing red tape as a major reason for the delays.</p>
<p>-- Jan Lopatka, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003 ($ = 1.590 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
