<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311615" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Jan 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Jan 16.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Thursday's Albanian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>KOHA JONE</p>
<p>- The newspaper's editorial says Albanians' faith in pyramid schemes has placed President Sali Berisha in a dilemma and is causing social troubles.</p>
<p>- Thousands of protesters demanding their money back from the Sude pyramid scheme clashed with Albanian riot police and many were injured.</p>
<p>- Sude, a pyramid scheme manager, told the crowd she had gone bankrupt.</p>
<p>- Leaders of the opposition Socialist party and the Social Democrats met depositors with the failed pyramid scheme and expressed support for their protest.</p>
<p>- Vebi Alimucaj, president of Vefa Holding, one of Albania's biggest companies and of a pyramid scheme, told depositors banks were to blame for stopping payments to them.</p>
<p>- Gjallica, a pyramid scheme company which suspended payments to its depositors last December, said it had postponed the re-start for another two weeks.</p>
<p>- People's Democracy Xhaferri pyramid scheme continues to give returns to depositors.</p>
<p>- The moment to imitate the Belgrade protests has come, a newspaper commentary says.</p>
<p>- The prosecutor's office might investigate all pyramid scheme companies, an undisclosed source told the newspaper.</p>
<p>- The committee of the Interparlimentary Union will discuss the case of the Socialists' jailed leader Fatos Nano in Geneva.</p>
<p>GAZETA SHQIPTARE</p>
<p>- The state should not stand aside while Albanians suffer from the tragedy of the pyramid schemes, the newspaper editorial says.</p>
<p>- Albanian television reported on the events at the bankrupt pyramid scheme Sude after months of silence on the most debated theme in the country.</p>
<p>- Sude, manager of a bankrupt pyramid scheme company, was arrested at midnight after angry depositors left the area surrounding her flat.</p>
<p>- The ruling Democratic Party calls on Albanians to stay away from pyramid schemes and said the state will intervene to rectify the situation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
