<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311703" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine farming booms in wake of investments.</title>
<headline>Argentine farming booms in wake of investments.</headline>
<byline>Jason Webb</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's farms are reaping the fruits of economic liberalization and investment, and agronomists say rapidly rising output still leaves room for more growth.</p>
<p>The government said Wednesday that, barring climatic disaster, farmers are heading to harvest a crop of 56.2 million tonnes this season, 1996/97. This would be a massive 23 percent above the previous record of 45.8 million tonnes in 1994/95.</p>
<p>Officials think more growth is on the way.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be at 30 million hectares of sown area and 70 million tonnes very soon, in three or four years,&quot; Patricio Lamarca, advisor to the government's Agricultural Secretariat, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Pablo Vernengo, of the Argentine Agronomists Association, agreed that higher output may be on the way, but cautioned it will only come if the government continues to provide assistance including soft loans for sowing as it did this time round.</p>
<p>&quot;The agricultural sector can yield much more than this. But it has to be accompanied by clear policies to favor growth,&quot; he said, &quot;Otherwise production could fall as it has in the past.&quot;</p>
<p>Vernengo added that 30 million hectares was probably too optimistic a target for Argentine crop lands.</p>
<p>This season's leap in output will have been achieved with a climate which has largely favored the developing soybean and maize crops. However, a good run of wheat weather was marred by fierce storms in early December.</p>
<p>Food Under Secretary Felix Cirio argued that the real reason for the higher output and yields is less heavenly help with the weather than big investments by farmers in equipment and supplies to modernize long backward farms.</p>
<p>&quot;Saint Peter lent us a hand with the coarse crop but basically there has been a persistent effort by producers to adopt technology and expand sown area,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>With rising grain prices making marginal land more attractive, sown area was also record this season, at 25.5 million hectares, up from 23.1 million hectares last season and 20.9 million hectares in 1990/91.</p>
<p>But investment -- and therefore yields -- has risen even faster than area.</p>
<p>Annual tractor sales soared by 68 percent to 6,925 in the first 11 months of 1996. Harvester sales doubled. Fertilizer imports doubled in 1996 to around 1.9 million tonnes, and were 10 times higher than in 1990.</p>
<p>There is still plenty of room for improvement. Vernengo pointed out that despite the wave of investment, 60 percent of tractors in the country were more than 20 years old.</p>
<p>Argentine farmers were for years hobbled by an eccentric system of taxing farm exports, which coupled with big import tariffs on equipment to keep rural investment down.</p>
<p>But export taxes were abolished six years ago by the government of President Carlos Menem, which also slashed tariffs and ended state control of exports by dismantling the national grains board.</p>
<p>But while Argentine farmers are fairly happy to adopt new technology and use more fertilizer, another area of a modern agricultural sector has not grown as fast as the government would have liked.</p>
<p>Grains future sales totaled only 15 million tonnes last year, up from just two million tonnes four years ago, but still a fraction of total grain output.</p>
<p>But Cirio said that the volatile behaviour of grain prices last year could have opened many rural minds to the use of futures and options. &quot;As recently as May, a wheat producer could buy a put at $250 by paying $3. As recently as May. So, that is a very hard lesson which is going to speed up the use of these instruments.&quot;</p>
<p>Argentine farmers can now sell their wheat for about $138 a tonne in the Buenos Aires market.</p>
<p>((--Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0655))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
