<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311827" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: FOCUS - Telecoms deal market reaction mixed.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Telecoms deal market reaction mixed.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A deal to build the world's longest and largest-capacity submarine cable network that will usher in a new era for the telecommunications industry received a mixed reaction in Asian stock markets on Thursday.</p>
<p>Analysts hailed the deal as one that will satisfy in future years the ever-growing demand for phone lines, including the Internet and business needs such as tele-conferencing.</p>
<p>It will be built by 90 of the world's top telecommunications companies and create a network stretching from the South Pacific to the North Atlantic across Asia and the Middle East.</p>
<p>But on Thursday, investors failed to show much interest.</p>
<p>Shares of Singapore Telecommunications Ltd (SingTel), which announced the U.S.$1.3 billion deal on Wednesday, ended off S$0.04 at S$3.18 in light trading.</p>
<p>Japan's Kokusai Densin Denwa (KDD), ended 120 yen higher at 7,570 yen, while Indonesia's Indosat gained 150 rupiah to 6,975.</p>
<p>&quot;After the completion of investment plans on submarine fibre cables connecting Japan and the U.S., they've finally turned to Asia, where construction of trunk lines is relatively delayed,&quot; said Hironori Tanaka, an analyst at Yamaichi Research Institute in in Tokyo.</p>
<p>But in Malaysia, Telekom Malaysia fell 0.40 cents, to 20.60 ringgit as investors focused on an investigation by the government into a contract given to Sweden's LM Ericsson rather than the telecommunications deal.</p>
<p>&quot;There's not much positive sentiment over the cable deal, as it's very long term,&quot; said Phuah Lee Kerk, telecommunications analyst at Vickers Ballas in Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>&quot;Telekom will probably not see any profits from the deal for at least another three to four years,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Shares of India's Videsh Sanchar Nigam Ltd (VSNL) fell 47 rupees to 942 rupees on the National Stock exchange.</p>
<p>Analysts said there could be more interest in the stocks on Friday since some details on associated contracts, albeit brief, was released late on Thursday.</p>
<p>A SingTel spokesman said contracts to build the 23,000 km (14,300 miles) stretch of cable from Singapore to Europe via the Middle East and North Africa would be worth US$720 million.</p>
<p>This network would be built by a consortium of KDD-Submarine Cable Systems, a unit of Japan's KDD, AT&amp;T Submarine Cable Systems Inc, France's Alcatel and Maristel SpA of Italy.</p>
<p>A second stretch from Singapore to Australia, awarded to Japan's Fujitsu, would be worth US$80 million.</p>
<p>The SingTel spokesman said contracts to build a third part of the network, between Singapore and various Asian countries including China and Japan, had not yet been awarded.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
