<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311819" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai commodities unlikely to gain from weak baht.</title>
<headline>Thai commodities unlikely to gain from weak baht.</headline>
<byline>Anchalee Koetsawang</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's tumbling baht is unlikely to substantially boost the competitiveness of the country's commodity exports, at least not in the short term, economists and traders said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The baht, which is pegged to a basket of currencies dominated by the U.S. dollar, slid to a 56-month low against the surging U.S. currency on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Generally, the weakening of the baht against the dollar should boost our exports, but not every sector. For commodities, the benefit could be limited,&quot; said Arporn Chewakriengkai, chief economist of Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>&quot;Agricultural commodities usually have a low price elasticity...meaning lower prices might not necessarily spur demand. If you eat three meals with rice a day, cheaper rice won't make you eat more,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Most Thai trade contracts are denominated in the U.S. dollar.</p>
<p>Thailand expects farm commodity exports this year to grow 1.4 percent over last year and fetch 214.9 billion baht in foreign exchange, or 13.6 percent of total exports for Thailand in 1997.</p>
<p>Rice traders said the sliding baht would barely increase the competitiveness of Thai rice as its price was comparatively high compared with those elsewhere in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;In theory, we should benefit from the strong dollar. But in reality, I doubt the current (dollar/baht) level will be enough to help make our rice look attractive,&quot; said a trader from a major U.S. trading house.</p>
<p>&quot;The spread between Thai 100 percent grade rice and Vietnamese five percent grade has now widened to about $100 per tonne from around $40 normally. Buyers are mostly sidelined by the prices,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Thai rice prices soared in recent weeks with lower-than-expected supplies available and with demand to meet deliveries active.</p>
<p>For tapioca, the strengthening of the dollar against the mark or the yen, the two currencies in which it is traded, would mean that exporters would get less money in baht terms.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a good news for us. The easing of the mark against the dollar now makes our tapioca pellets about $10 per tonne lower,&quot; said Seree Denworalak, head of Thai Tapioca Trade Association.</p>
<p>&quot;But cheaper prices are unlikely to boost demand as grains prices in the European Union -- our major market -- are also very cheap,&quot; Seree said. Tapioca is mostly used by the animal feed industry.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
