<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311859" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Four-nation group/Fujitsu win $800 mln cable deals.</title>
<headline>Four-nation group/Fujitsu win $800 mln cable deals.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore Telecommunications Ltd (SingTel) gave brief details on Thursday of the breakdown of two giant submarine cable contracts worth a total of US$800 million.  </p>
<p>A SingTel spokesman said contracts to build a 23,000 km (14,300 miles) stretch of cable from Singapore to Europe via the Middle East and North Africa would be worth US$720 million.</p>
<p>This network would be built by a consortium of KDD-Submarine Cable Systems, a unit of Japan's Kokusai Densin Denwa (KDD), AT&amp;T Submarine Cable Systems Inc, France's Alcatel and Maristel SpA of Italy.</p>
<p>A second stretch from Singapore to Australia, awarded to Japan's Fujitsu, would be worth US$80 million.  </p>
<p>The SingTel spokesman said contracts to build a third part of the network, between Singapore and various Asian countries including China and Japan, had not yet been awarded.</p>
<p>Construction of the first two portions of the network were due to begin in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>When completed, the 38,000-km (23,600-mile) network will serve half the world's population and span the globe from the South Pacific to the North Atlantic.</p>
<p>It will be the world's longest and highest capacity submarine cable network.  </p>
<p>The SingTel spokesman said the contracts to build the first two sections of the network were awarded at a private ceremony in Singapore on Thursday. He declined to give further details.</p>
<p>SingTel is one of 90 investors in the cable project.</p>
<p>Other members of the consortium include British Telecom, Deutsche Telekom, Indonesia's Indosat, France Telecom, Australia's Telstra and China Telecom.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703199)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020043">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
