<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311971" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Midwest gets brunt of winter, more deaths in Calif..</title>
<headline>Midwest gets brunt of winter, more deaths in Calif..</headline>
<byline>Andrew Stern</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cold, blustery weather shuttered schools and blocked roads with towering snowdrifts across the hard-hit Midwest on Thursday, triggering scores of traffic accidents and creating dangerously frigid conditions.</p>
<p>Stinging winds and forecasts for sub-zero cold convinced Chicago authorities to close schools for the day.</p>
<p>In Minnesota, windchills down to minus 70 degrees led Gov. Arne Carlson to tell schoolchildren and many government workers to stay home. Officials worried that children could freeze waiting for buses on snow-clogged roads.</p>
<p>Three suburban Chicago teenagers died on a snowy highway late Wednesday when their car slid into oncoming lanes and was hit head-on. In Clarissa, Minnesota, a 79-year-old man died when he fell through a skylight while clearing snow off the roof of a shed.</p>
<p>National Guard troops in Minnesota piloting specially equipped snowcat vehicles rescued several motorists stranded by the latest storm.</p>
<p>Although skies had cleared, winds of up to 60 miles per hour blew snow into towering drifts and blinded drivers. Many sections of highways in North and South Dakota were closed as snowdrifts piled up in underpasses and froze rock-hard.</p>
<p>Officials across the Great Plains feared thousands of cattle have frozen or starved to death in one of the worst winters in memory. The federal government promised to release emergency feed to livestock ranchers and supplement snow-removal budgets for cities and towns that have already exhausted their funds.</p>
<p>&quot;We've had more than double the normal snow for this time of year and had a lot of blowing and drifting that needed ploughing,&quot; Minnesota Emergency Management Agency spokeswoman Sherrill Neudahl said.</p>
<p>The gusty winds were preceded by a storm that dropped up to 10 inches of snow on Chicago's suburbs, snarling traffic for the morning commute. Temperatures fell through the day.</p>
<p>As the storm moved east, it whipped up snow squalls in Michigan and dumped snow, ice and rain on the mid-Atlantic states and the Northeast. Maine was expected to get half a foot of snow and register 60 mile per hour winds, according to the National Weather Service's Hazardous Storm Centre.</p>
<p>Thunderstorms along the Eastern Seaboard may have produced a tornado Wednesday in northern Florida, causing one injury, the Storm Center's Hugh Crowther said. He said frigid weather will maintain its grip on the central part of the country and seep eastward, but winds should abate gradually and temperatures should climb modestly.</p>
<p>In California, illegal immigrants have been among the hardest hit by the cold. Officials in San Diego said five more who were trying to cross into California from Mexico had died of exposure to the cold, bringing the death toll to at least 10 this week.</p>
<p>Dozens of illegal immigrants have recently surrendered to Border Patrol agents to escape sub-freezing temperatures after trying to shield themselves with large plastic bags.</p>
<p>The latest discovery was early on Thursday when Border Patrol agents found three bodies along a hiking trail in the Laguna Mountains, 70 miles (112.7 km) northeast of San Diego.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, agents found the body of a male in the Otay Mesa area near the border, south of San Diego and U.S. Department of Forestry Service officers found the body of a male east of Buckman Springs, also in the Laguna mountains.</p>
<p>The U.S. Weather Service reported that temperatures were expected to get warmer on Friday and through the weekend in the San Diego region.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
