<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="311977" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pfizer says earnings rose 23 percent.</title>
<headline>Pfizer says earnings rose 23 percent.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pfizer Inc. said Thursday its earnings jumped 23 percent in last year's fourth quarter and it forecast double-digit growth in sales and profits in 1997.</p>
<p>The drug maker reported earnings of $504 million, or 77 cents a share compared with earnings of $411 million, or 65 cents a share, in the fourth quarter of 1995.</p>
<p>Sales increased 15 percent to $3.16 billion from $2.74 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a really good report,&quot; said David Maris, an analyst at Aros Securities. &quot;Expectations are so high on the company but they're meeting them.&quot;</p>
<p>Despite the higher earnings, Pfizer's stock was off $1.50 at $85.375 on the New York Stock Exchange in early afternoon trading.</p>
<p>Pfizer said it would launch two major new human pharmaceutical products early this year -- Aricept, a treatment for Alzheimer's disease, and Lipitor, for the treatment of elevated blood-cholesterol levels.</p>
<p>&quot;Heightened levels of investments are needed to participate in the launches of these major new products and support the necessary post-launch clinical research and development,&quot; Chairman William Steere Jr. said in a statement. &quot;However, we believe the commercial opportunity these products present is compelling.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the company expected to increase its spending on research and development by 20 percent this year to about $2 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;In spite of this substantial investment to support the near-, mid- and long-term success of Pfizer, we expect to achieve double-digit growth in both sales and net income this year,&quot; Steere said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
