<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="312068" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Southeast power rises ahead of cold weather.</title>
<headline>U.S. Southeast power rises ahead of cold weather.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot bulk electricity prices in the U.S. Southeast were boosted by forecasts for freezing night time temperatures throughout much of the region Friday and into this weekend, market sources said.</p>
<p>A cold front is moving into the Southeast, expected to drag temperatures to about 10-20 degrees below-normal Friday through Sunday. Lows in the 20s and even teens are expected to blanket parts of the region, mostly inland areas.</p>
<p>Firm, peak power prices into the Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) territory for Friday gained about $8 to about $35.00-36.00 per megawatt hour (MWh), as compared with Wednesday's range of $26.00-28.00.</p>
<p>As buyers scrambled for supplies late, prices were talked in the low-$40s per MWh.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak electricity prices into TVA for Friday were assessed higher around $22.00.</p>
<p>At the Georgia/Florida border, firm, peak electricity prices in 16 hour blocks for Friday delivery rose gradually throughout the day as supplies became more scarce. Traders said most deals were done in the $32.00-37.00 range, up from Wednesday's $26.00-27.00 range.</p>
<p>By the afternoon, suppliers in the Southeastern Electric Reliability Council (SERC) were offering firm, peak power at the border around $44.00.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak power for Friday at the Ga./Fla. border was notionally in a range of $22.00-23.00.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not doing any pre-scheduling. We're going to take our chances in the hourly market,&quot; one Florida source said.</p>
<p>Like electricity, spot natural gas prices along the Gulf Coast were up about 40 cents to about $4.70 per million British thermal units.</p>
<p>Separately, Florida Power and Light Co's 666 megawatt (MW) Turkey Point 3 nuclear unit, shut Wednesday for unscheduled repairs, will likely be back on line Thursday afternoon.</p>
<p>Also, Orlando Utilities said its 324 MW Indian River 3 power unit, operating at half power since late last year, will likely be available for full service late Thursday or early Friday. The unit, near Titusville, Fla., is fueled by natural gas or fuel oil.</p>
<p>The City of Lakeland, Fla., reported Wednesday that a 90 MW power unit, fueled by natural gas and fuel oil, would restart sometime Thursday and be back on-line this weekend after shutting down in October.</p>
<p>In its six- to 10-day outlook, the National Weather Service is calling for near-normal temperatures in the Southeast. In February, temperatures are expected to be above-normal in a large portion of the southern tier states, extending as far north as southern Pennsylvania and Delaware.</p>
<p>((--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
