<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="312123" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX natgas down late on weather, holds support.</title>
<headline>NYMEX natgas down late on weather, holds support.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX natgas futures, pressured by forecasts for more moderate weather next week, remained sharply lower late Thursday in moderate trade, but chartists noted prices were still holding above support.</p>
<p>At 1500 EST, February was still down by 25.1 cents at $3.36 per million British thermal units, while March was 20.5 cents lower at $2.94. Most others also were down.</p>
<p>&quot;We held support at $3.30 (basis February) twice today. Risk-reward says up from here,&quot; said one Midwest trader, noting any sign of cold weather should boost prices again.  </p>
<p>Despite some bearish sentiment from the near-term weather forecasts, some noted another Arctic wave was due to descend into the Midwest later next week, bringing more well-below normal temperatures to the eastern half of the nation.</p>
<p>Technically, traders pegged February support in the $3.30 area and then in the gap between $3.11 and $3.185. Resistance was seen at $3.64 and then in the $3.80-3.84 area.</p>
<p>In the cash, prices at the Gulf Coast jumped almost 40 cents Thursday to near $4.70. Midcon pipes tumbled almost 40 cents to the $4.80 area on forecasts for more moderate temperatures this weekend. Gas at the New York city gate was talked in the $6.00-6.50 area, up more than $1 on the day.</p>
<p>--((J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
