<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="312160" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chronology of U.S. abortion clinic attacks.</title>
<headline>Chronology of U.S. abortion clinic attacks.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Acts of violence against abortion clinics and their employees have been carried out across the United States throughout the 1980s and 1990s.</p>
<p>There were 1,700 acts of violence against abortion providers between 1977 and 1994, with four people being killed in 1994 and one in 1993, according to statistics from the National Abortion Federation.</p>
<p>In 1984 there were 18 bombings against abortion clinics.</p>
<p>In 1993 there were 78 death threats aimed at clinic employees.</p>
<p>In 1996, bombings, threats and harassment affected about one-third of U.S. abortion clinics.</p>
<p>Following is a list of violent incidents against abortion clinics in the past few years:</p>
<p>December 30, 1994 -- Two receptionists, Lee Ann Nichols, 38, and Shannon Lowney, 25, were murdered and five people were injured in a shooting spree at two health clinics in Brookline, Massachusetts.</p>
<p>Anti-abortion crusader John Salvi, 24, was convicted of the deaths and later committed suicide in his cell at a maximum security prison on Nov. 29, 1996.</p>
<p>August 10, 1994 -- A Planned Parenthood clinic in Brainerd, Minnesota, was firedbombed. The clinic did not perform abortions.</p>
<p>July 29, 1994 -- Dr. John Britton, 69, and his volunteer security escort, Jim Barrett, were shot and killed outside The Ladies Centre in Pensacola, Flordia.</p>
<p>On the same day, the Commonwealth Women's Clinic in Falls Church, Virginia, was also firebombed.</p>
<p>September 29, 1993 -- A family planning clinic in Lancaster, Pennsylvania, was firebombed causing damage estimated at $130,000 and forcing it to close.</p>
<p>August 19, 1993 -- Dr. George Tiller, 52, was shot once in each arm by an anti-abortion activist outside the Women's Health Care Services in Wichita, Kansas.</p>
<p>March 10, 1993 -- Dr. David Gunn, 47, was shot in the back and killed outside a medical services clinic in Pensacola, Flordia, as he arrived for work.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
