<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="312212" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX electricity front months down slightly.</title>
<headline>NYMEX electricity front months down slightly.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX electricity futures were trading down slightly Thursday as the market looked for some direction from physical power prices in the U.S. West, industry sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;People seem to be waiting to see what is going to happen next week, how far (physical) prices are going to come off,&quot; said one Houston-based electricity trader, adding &quot;the market is searching for some directions.&quot;</p>
<p>As of 1215 EST, February California Oregon Border (COB) was down 21 cents at $15.00 per megawatt hour (MWh) after trade as high as $15.25 per MWh.</p>
<p>March COB was bid at $12.25 and offered at $12.65 from Wednesday's settle at $12.60 per MWh.</p>
<p>August COB had traded down 10 cents at $19.15, while September had traded steady at $18.70 per MWh.</p>
<p>February Palo Verde (PV) had traded down 35 cents at $17.00 after trade as high as $17.15, while March PV was offered at $14.80 from Wednesday's settle at $14.50 per MWh.</p>
<p>June PV had traded down 10 cents at $18.00 per MWh.</p>
<p>Traders said the downward movement may have been influenced by talk of cheaper physical power prices in the U.S. West, where above normal and normal temperatures were expected through to Jan 25.</p>
<p>Some downward pressure was also seen from expectations of abundant hydroelectric availability in the Pacific Northwest this spring, the sources said.</p>
<p>Natural gas futures were also trading lower, with NYMEX February Henry Hub gas down 26.6 cents at $3.345 per million British thermal units as of 1220 EST.</p>
<p>NYMEX said as of 1150 EST an estimated total of 141 COB and six PV contracts had traded.</p>
<p>((--Chris Reese, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1627))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
