<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="312358" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Commission says it is against flexibility veto.</title>
<headline>Commission says it is against flexibility veto.</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission said on Thursday it did not want member states to be able to veto so-called &quot;flexibility&quot;, the degree to which individual countries embrace new legislation.</p>
<p>&quot;Flexibility is something that should be used as a last resort but not something that should be denied,&quot; said Nicolaus van der Pas, spokesman for European Commission President Jacques Santer.</p>
<p>Van der Pas was speaking after the Commission continued its internal debate on how it viewed flexibility in light of the inter-governmental conference (IGC), the ongoing rewrite of the EU treaties.</p>
<p>The idea of flexibility was born out of frustration by some EU states which felt that other members were not prepared to embrace fully the idea of European unity.</p>
<p>It has been given impetus by plans to enlarge the EU to take in scores of applicants -- mainly from Eastern Europe -- and knowledge that an expanded bloc will require a major treaty overhaul.</p>
<p>The idea of flexibility was devised by France and Germany who, worried by increasingly eurosceptical signals from Britain, wanted a formula whereby member states could in exceptional circumstances decide whether to go along with new legislation.</p>
<p>The decision by some states not to join in economic and monetary union (EMU) has been held up as an example of how this could be done.</p>
<p>However, Britain and some other countries say that they should still have the power to stop other European nations from &quot;going it alone&quot;, something the Commission strongly resists.</p>
<p>&quot;There must be a substantial number of states that want to go down a path before flexibility should be considered,&quot; said Van der Pas. &quot;Should decisions on flexibility be unanimous? The Commission feels it should be a majority,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The question of flexibility has opened up a can of worms for EU governments and institutions and problems are unlikely to be resolved before the scheduled end of the IGC later this year.</p>
<p>For example, Van der Pas said, if some action proceeds under flexibility with the blessing but not participation of all nations, should the &quot;opt outs&quot; still have a vote on the issue?</p>
<p>Again, Britain has insisted that it still has a say in matters regardless of whether it is participating and particularly if the issue is one using EU resources.</p>
<p>In Strasbourg, France on Thursday the European Parliament broadly endorsed a draft text submitted by Ireland -- the previous EU president under the bloc's rotating system -- on the IGC and the EU's future.</p>
<p>The parliament said it was in favour of the new idea but there were limits. Flexibility should be the exception rather than the rule, should be a transitional arrangement and be accompanied by support measures for those not taking part to make it possible for them to join in a reasonable time.</p>
<p>The Commission has dubbed the approach &quot;catching the later train&quot; in response to critics' suggestions that countries not fully embracing European unity would &quot;miss the train&quot;.</p>
<p>The EU's foreign ministers are to take up the issue at a meeting in Brussels on Monday where the Netherlands -- the current EU presidency -- will outline how it aims to speed up the IGC process.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
