<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="312329" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy 96 PSBR overrun may hurt 97 accounts - Ciampi.</title>
<headline>Italy 96 PSBR overrun may hurt 97 accounts - Ciampi.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Treasury Minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi said the overshoot in the 1996 public sector borrowing requirement (PSBR) might hurt 1997 accounts, but the impact would not be fully known until the second half of February.</p>
<p>Italy ran up a public sector deficit of 138.5 trillion lire last year compared with an original target of 109.4 trillion.</p>
<p>Ciampi said the overshoot was caused by lower tax revenues, larger-than-expected withdrawals by local authorities from government funds and higher-than-expected spending on both pensions and contributions to the European Union.</p>
<p>He said the large withdrawals by the local authorities at the end of 1996 might actually help 1997 accounts, with less money now needed by the regions.</p>
<p>However the other causes for the overshoot might have a knock-on effect this year. &quot;I can't make any guesses for how much. I'm waiting for figures in the second half of February,&quot; Ciampi said.</p>
<p>However an eventual knock-on might be partially covered by lower-than-expected interest payments on debt, he said.</p>
<p>Most analysts say the overshoot has created a hole in state accounts and say the government will have to push through a supplementary budget of up to 25 trillion lire as early as next month to plug the gap. ((  -- Rome newsroom +396 6782501))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
