<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="312501" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Bombay index off highs, down 193 pts at 3,453.61.</title>
<headline>Bombay index off highs, down 193 pts at 3,453.61.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share prices finished sharply lower on Thursday at the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) after a huge rally triggered widespread selling, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been a crazy ride. We're still recovering from it,&quot; said Neeraj Roy, head of institutional sales at Prime Broking.</p>
<p>&quot;This kind of movement is absolutely bizzare.&quot;</p>
<p>The 30-share BSE index ended 193.12 points, or 5.30 percent, lower at a provisional 3,453.61 -- after zooming to 3,812.31 in morning trade.</p>
<p>Traders attributed the early upsurge to wild speculative bidding for no apparent reason.</p>
<p>Local investment institutions and foreign funds sold heavily at the day's high levels to cool the market, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We recommend a total suspension of buying and a phased disinvestment programme,&quot; said analyst Praween Napate at brokerage ING Barings.</p>
<p>In a daily note on Thursday headlined, &quot;Red alert: Market has entered the danger zone,&quot; he said he did not see a revival of fundamentals in the near future.</p>
<p>The 50-share National Stock Exchange index dropped 46.40 points, or 4.45 percent, to a provisional 995.40 -- after soaring to 1,085.50.</p>
<p>The 500-stock CRISIL index shed 29.78 points, or 4.27 percent, to a provisional 666.64, off day's 718.63 peak.</p>
<p>Traders said they were confused by the market's volatile price movements and advised caution.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very difficult to talk about the market outlook at this time,&quot; said Prashant Purker, head of sales at securities firm Peregrine Capital.</p>
<p>SBI fell 22.25 rupees to 269, Reliance 19.50 to 235, TISCO 15.50 to 190, ITC 16.25 to 400, MTNL 16.50 to 246.50, TELCO 24 to 345, BSES 23 to 233.25 and L&amp;T 17.50 to 245.50.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
