<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="312800" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Green groups sue to block Cook Inlet permits.</title>
<headline>Green groups sue to block Cook Inlet permits.</headline>
<byline>Yereth Rosen</byline>
<dateline>ANCHORAGE, Alaska 1997-01-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Several environmental groups filed a lawsuit in federal court Wednesday to block what they claim are overly lax wastewater-discharge permits for oil and gas operators in southcentral Alaska's Cook Inlet.</p>
<p>The lawsuit was filed against the Environmental Protection Agency in the 9th Circuit Court of Appeals in San Francisco by Anchorage-based Trustees for Alaska and nine other Alaska and national groups.</p>
<p>It challenges the EPA's decision last fall to issue new wastewater-discharge permits for Cook Inlet, site of 15 oil and gas platforms.</p>
<p>Trustees for Alaska attorney Steve Koteff said the EPA erred in deciding to allow continued discharge of drilling muds and other wastes into the fish-rich inlet.</p>
<p>Instead, the agency should have mandated zero discharge of pollutants in its pending permits, which are revised every few years to keep pace with improved technology, they said.</p>
<p>Koteff said the EPA has required zero discharge for offshore oil operators elsewhere, and should have mandated that producers either reinject their wastes deep into the earth or barge it ashore for disposal.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no basis for separate treatment in Cook Inlet,&quot; Koteff said in a news release. &quot;This decision says to polluters, Come on up to Alaska! We'll take care of you here.&quot;</p>
<p>The disparate treatment violates the Clean Water Act, he said.</p>
<p>Koteff also said EPA was wrong when it determined that the cost of totally eliminating waste discharge would be prohibitive.</p>
<p>&quot;EPA accepted the industry's estimate or approximation, which to me calls into question the objectivity of those assessments,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A spokesman for one company operating in Cook Inlet disputed Koteff's claim that the new permits would increase pollution in Cook Inlet.</p>
<p>&quot;That is totally false. EPA has dictated a decrease in our allowable discharge -- in fact, they've cut our allowable discharge in half,&quot; said Kevin Tabler, a manager of Unocal's Alaska operations.</p>
<p>Trustees for Alaska and the other groups were confusing water volumes with pollutant volumes, Tabler said.</p>
<p>He also contradicted Koteff's claim that costs of eliminating marine discharge of wastes could be borne by oil and gas operators.</p>
<p>With production declining from the aged Cook Inlet fields, a zero-discharge requirement would shut down some operations permaturely, he said.</p>
<p>He also disputed claims that offshore platforms outside of Alaska are prohibited from discharging wastewater. &quot;There's hundreds of platforms in the Gulf of Mexico that have discharges,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Besides Unocal, Cook Inlet oil and gas operators include Marathon, Phillips Petroleum and Cook Inlet Region Inc.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANCHORAGE, Alaska"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
