<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="312862" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Eurobourses in new records,gold and oil slip.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Eurobourses in new records,gold and oil slip.</headline>
<byline>Roger Jeal</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The London stock market scaled new heights on Thursday after fears of higher interest rates receded and Frankfurt also registered a new record.</p>
<p>Recovering from a shaky opening, the London market, Europe's busiest, climbed on news of slower inflation followed by confirmation that official British interest rates would be held at six percent for now. Bonds also gained.</p>
<p>&quot;It's all about the no change in rates and the weaker (inflation) numbers,&quot; said one trader. &quot;We were all over the place this morning but sentiment is now very much improved.&quot;</p>
<p>The Paris bourse was also near its trading peak during the morning ahead of news that key French interest rates were to stay at current levels.</p>
<p>Gold, weakened recently by competition from a firmer dollar and booming stock markets plus concern over central bank gold sales, edged lower. Oil also declined after a weather-related leap upwards on Wednesday.</p>
<p>On the currency markets, the dollar was steady after what market analysts said was an expected correction following a move above 1.60 marks and a 46-month high against the yen.</p>
<p>&quot;We're seeing a correction after the dollar's rise to 1.60 marks but we don't see that progressing too much further. Similarly, the downside looks fairly limited on the yen,&quot; said Ian Gunner, senior economist at Chase Investment Bank.</p>
<p>European bourses had already taken their cue from Wall Street to book profits on Wednesday after hitting record levels.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average eventually ended 35.41 lower at 6,726.88 and U.S. shares in London were little changed from New York closing levels on Thursday morning.</p>
<p>On balance, economists had not expected a British interest rate rise yet despite the Bank of England's known desire for higher rates to contain inflationary risks.</p>
<p>But surprisingly strong British jobless data on Wednesday, with unemployment falling to a six-year low, had raised a few doubts and sent shares lower after earlier record levels.</p>
<p>The London stock market, Europe's busiest, opened a little easier on Thursday. But it was then reassured by news that inflation slowed to 2.5 percent last month from November's 2.7 percent and the decision to keep interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>French stocks, also on interest rate watch, gained ahead of the Bank of France policy-setting meeting at which dealers and economists said its intervention rate could be trimmed to 3.10 percent from 3.15 -- but wasn't.</p>
<p>The central bank's monetary council meeting, which left rates unchanged, was the first since the appointment of two new members seen to lean more towards faster rate cuts.</p>
<p>Frankfurt, meanwhile, joined London in rewriting the record books, with the IBIS DAX index for computerised trade up around 0.7 percent, in line with gains in Paris and London.</p>
<p>In Asia, Hong Kong's Hang Seng Index soared above 14,000 for the first time, hitting another record high of 14,004.93 before closing up 64.03 at 13,830.68. Tokyo stocks ended slightly higher, with the Nikkei 225 average up 51.21 at 18,144.34.</p>
<p>Gold slipped a little from the previous London close on continued concern that other central banks might follow the Dutch and sell more of their gold reserves, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the coming months and years, European central banks will gradually reduce their gold reserves,&quot; one Zurich trader said.</p>
<p>World oil prices, which had recovered in late trade on Wednesday amid concern over cold U.S. weather, also eased.</p>
<p>London February futures for international benchmark North Sea Brent blend were down 39 cents at $23.45 a barrel.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the Bank of Spain made a cut of a quarter point to six percent in its key money rate, surprising markets despite the peseta's strength and benign inflation. The peseta responded by strengthening to 83.56 to the mark from 83.70 overnight.</p>
<p>The dollar received support after Bundesbank council member Hans-Juergen Krupp, seen as a dove, said the German economy was in a grave position and the bank could not ignore this.</p>
<p>Thursday's diary of statistics, meanwhile, includes U.S. weekly jobless claims at 1330 GMT and the Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia's business survey at 1500 GMT.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1230 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was quoted around 117.09 yen and 1.5908 marks, compared with 117.17 and 1.5912 late on Wednesday. Sterling was only slightly weaker at 2.6677 marks from 2.6701 overnight.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1230 GMT</p>
<p>The FTSE 100 index of top British shares was up 33.0 at a new all-time high 4,191.9, topping Wednesday's 4,191.5 peak.</p>
<p>Frankfurt's 30-share DAX index for floor trade was up 6.72 at 2,995.17 after a record 2,998.61. The IBIS DAX for electronic trade was up 17.54 at 2,994.10 after a record 2,998.44 earlier.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 index was up 16.71 at 2,404.69 versus Wednesday's intra-day record of 2,418.93.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold slipped to $353.65 after a fix of $354 and previous close of $354.15. Silver was a fraction easier at $4.69.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
