<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="313059" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BAHRAIN: Gulf Air sells six Boeing 767s.</title>
<headline>Gulf Air sells six Boeing 767s.</headline>
<dateline>MANAMA 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Regional carrier Gulf Air said on Thursday it has sold six Boeing 767 aircraft as part of a restructuring programme to help it return to profit.</p>
<p>&quot;The sale comes in line with a decision taken at the recent Gulf Air board meeting to continue the process of returning the airline to profitability,&quot; a Gulf Air statement said.</p>
<p>It said the six aircraft would gradually be released from February to July this year to coincide with the return of the aircraft Gulf Air had leased out in 1996.</p>
<p>It did not say who it was selling the aircraft to.</p>
<p>The sale cuts Gulf Air's fleet to 30 aircraft. They include five Airbus A340s and 14 A320s and 11 Boeing 767s.</p>
<p>Airbus Industrie said on Wednesday that Gulf Air had opted to take delivery of six A330 passenger jets from 1999 instead of 1998 as originally announced.</p>
<p>Debt-ridden Gulf Air is owned by the governments of Bahrain, Qatar, Oman and Abu Dhabi emirate in the United Arab Emirates.</p>
<p>&quot;The measures taken are part of Gulf Air's strategic plan to return to profitability,&quot; president and chief executive Sheikh Ahmed bin Saif al-Nahayan said in the statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The rationalisation programme, which commenced last year, has begun to show very positive results and we are optimistic that Gulf Air can rise to the challenge and make it back to the road of success,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Bahrain-based Gulf Air also said it would terminate flights to New York, Geneva, Durban and Johannesburg.</p>
<p>The last flight from New York through Geneva would be on February 13 and the last flight from Durban through Johannesburg would be on February 4.</p>
<p>Gulf Air suffered losses of $159 million in 1995. It is facing debts of around $2 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BAHRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BAHRAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
