<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="313176" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Helsinki resumes assault on records, doubts mount.</title>
<headline>Helsinki resumes assault on records, doubts mount.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares resumed their assault on record territory on Thursday with volumes once again heavy after a dip on Wednesday, but anticipation of a correction continued to spread and forestry shares failed to hold early gains.</p>
<p>&quot;It would almost do us good to have a few days with a minus sign in front of the index, otherwise this rise will be killed,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Nonetheless some bulls remained, with one broker citing Wednesday's Moody's upgrade of Finland's credit ratings as supporting stocks and another saying market downturns have tended to come on smaller volumes than upswings.  </p>
<p>Dollar strength and stock-picking by international investors backed gains also continued to lend support and for domestic investors, more upbeat signals in construction helped.</p>
<p>Polar rose 0.61 markka or nearly eight percent to 8.30 and Lemminkainen 2.50 or nearly five percent to 54.00 but volumes in both were light.</p>
<p>The forestries index fell with individual stocks mixed in quite thin trade after getting an initial boost when Sweden's Stora said it had lifted fine paper prices, brokers said.</p>
<p>But the sector later surrendered gains after MoDo said it was hard to see higher pulp prices in the first quarter.  </p>
<p>Overall it was bourse engine Nokia, which booked a 5.00 markka gain to 308.00 after renewed strength in New York overnight, that led the market higher. Nokia made up nearly 80 percent of total volume -- a much higher share than of late.</p>
<p>As one broker pointed out, any investor seeking a correction faced a number of bullish factors which have combined to keep shares gaining: portfolio building, low interest rates and intermittent talk of more cuts, and ample cash for stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got the January effect on top of the interest rate effect on top of the liquidity effect,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +35 89 6805 0247</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
