<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="313251" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Thyssen Stahl profit down, but sees upturn.</title>
<headline>Thyssen Stahl profit down, but sees upturn.</headline>
<byline>Terence Gallagher</byline>
<dateline>DUISBURG, Germany 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thyssen Stahl AG, Germany's largest steel maker, said on Thursday 1995-96 group profits dropped sharply, but chief executive Ekkehard Schulz said a cyclical trough is over and the outlook has improved.</p>
<p>Group net profit at the steel unit of Thyssen AG fell to 174 million marks ($109 million) in the year ended September 30, 1996 from a record 651 million marks the year before. Sales fell to 10.623 billion marks from 11.937 billion marks.</p>
<p>A cyclical fall in steel demand, with a consequent 10 percent decline in steel prices, was the main reason for the weak results, Schulz told reporters.</p>
<p>Sales in the first quarter of 1996-97 were 2.1 billion marks, down 19 percent even after accounting for divisions that were spun off last October. Crude steel production in the quarter was up 11 percent, however.</p>
<p>Schulz, speaking against a backdrop of smoke-belching furnaces, said the steel business was back on an uptrend. He said he shared the view of the German steel association that national crude steel output would rise five percent to nearly 42 million tonnes in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The negative portion of the inventory cycle has been overcome,&quot; he said. &quot;We regard these projections as realistic.&quot;</p>
<p>Schulz declined to make a specific forecast for Thyssen Stahl's net profit in the current year.</p>
<p>&quot;It will not be as good as in 1994/95, but I do not want to say now if it will be as good as 1995/96,&quot; Schulz said.</p>
<p>The company's annual report said: &quot;In the course of the market rebound, it is expected that the profit situation, which remained depressed at the start of the business year, will recover.&quot;</p>
<p>Still, price increases announced for January 1 have not yet been fully implemented due to slack demand, but the company hoped to correct the situation by the start of the second quarter of 1997, Schulz said.</p>
<p>Thyssen Stahl is in the midst of a restructuring in which it will shed non-core activities and concentrate on hot-rolled flat steel products.</p>
<p>The company plans to sell off non-core &quot;long-steel&quot; activities with total sales of one billion marks that showed a net loss of 100 million marks last year, Schulz said.</p>
<p>Thyssen said it aims to eliminate entirely its loss carryover, which totalled 968 million marks in 1995-96, down from 1.55 billion marks the year before.</p>
<p>Schulz declined to give a specific timeframe for cutting the loss carryover, but said it would have a significant impact on the company's net profitability.</p>
<p>Thyssen aims to reduce its parent workforce to 13,600 by the end of 1998 from 16,900 on September 30, 1996. It wants to cut its workforce in flat-steel products to slightly above 10,000 by the year 2000 from 12,800 currently.</p>
<p>The group's overall workforce was 35,990 in September 1996, down from 39,572 a year earlier. It was 58,000 in 1992.</p>
<p>The company plans further international downstream tie-ups in fields like &quot;tailored blanks&quot; for the auto industry which will build its sales to 12 billion marks by the year 2000 from 10.62 billion in 1995-96.</p>
<p>Thyssen has recently started such ventures in Italy, Indonesia, China and Brazil.</p>
<p>The company was now among the most efficient of European steel makers, Schulz said. Thyssen Stahl needs only three man-hours to produce a tonne of crude steel, compared with an average of 3.5 hours in France and 3.9 hours in Britain.</p>
<p>But high German labour costs mean that tonne of crude steel costs 160 marks to produce in Germany, compared to 155 marks in France and only 120 marks in Britain, he said.</p>
<p>The company is building a 550 million mark casting plant in Bruckhausen which will open in April 1999. ($1=1.5978 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUISBURG, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
