<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="313391" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil prices slump but bull run intact.</title>
<headline>Oil prices slump but bull run intact.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>World oil prices fell up to 30 cents a barrel on Thursday in a retracement of Wednesday's late weather-driven gains.</p>
<p>But traders and analysts still see buying interest as the prolonged bull run looks sets to continue for now.</p>
<p>&quot;Traders still see this as a 'buy the dip' market. They do not see an imminent collapse,&quot; said Vahan Zanoyan, a director at the Washington-based Petroleum Finance Corp (PFC).</p>
<p>London February futures for international benchmark North Sea Brent blend traded as low as $23.44 but by 1639 GMT had recovered to $23.71, down 13 cents from Wednesday's close.</p>
<p>Zanoyan and others see the market as rangebound and well-supported at least until mid-February or early March when demand takes a seasonal downturn.</p>
<p>&quot;Traders just do not see at this time what  could happen to be more bearish than Iraq's return,&quot; Zanoyan said.</p>
<p>Since they hit a post-Gulf War high of $25,06 last October, Brent oil prices have not been far from that level despite the onslaught of about 500,000 barrels daily of Iraqi oil now that Baghdad is permitted by the United Nations to sell some oil again.</p>
<p>Buoyant demand because of the cold weather and the need to replenish very low heating oil stocks has kept a floor under prices all winter.</p>
<p>But there are bearish warning signals ahead, analysts say.</p>
<p>Extensive refinery maintenance work, which will cut demand for crude oil and other feedstocks, at a time of increasing oil flows from the North Sea and other producers, will give the market a bearish one-two punch, analysts say.</p>
<p>&quot;We see a steady surplus of supply building up, rising to about one million barrels a day of extra oil that will pressure this market,&quot; Zanoyan said.</p>
<p>A senior executive at the Royal/Dutch Shell Group said on Thursday &quot;unpredictable factors&quot; like politics and weather are holding sway over the oil price and not supply-demand fundamentals.</p>
<p>&quot;If I look at fundamentals, just on that basis, doesn't justify the prices we have got at the moment,&quot; Shell Managing Director Cor Herkstroter said.</p>
<p>But for now forecasts for colder weather in the United States should be enough to keep the bears at bay, traders said.</p>
<p>Private forecaster Weather Services Corp (WSC) said on Thursday energy demand in the U.S. northeast, the world's largest heating oil market, will rise to well above normal levels over the next few days as temperatures will fall to as much as 10 degrees Fahrenheit below normal by Saturday.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>						   Jan 16     Jan 15</p>
<p>						  (1639 GMT) (close)</p>
<p> Dated Brent				   23.50	23.64</p>
<p> IPE London Brent futures (Feb)	  23.71	23.84</p>
<p> NYMEX light crude futures (Feb)	 25.88	25.95</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
