<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="313384" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Spanish prime minister confident on EMU.</title>
<headline>Spanish prime minister confident on EMU.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spanish Prime Minister Jose Maria Aznar, who last year ruled out any joint Italo-Spanish push for flexibility on the EMU criteria, said in an interview published on Thursday he was sure Spain would qualify on its own merits.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want a tandem with Rome,&quot; Italian newspaper La Repubblica quoted Aznar as saying in an interview from Madrid.</p>
<p>&quot;Spain has to make it on its own.&quot;</p>
<p>Italian officials said on Thursday that Aznar was due to meet Prime Minister Romano Prodi in the northern lagoon city of Venice this weekend, but stressed it would be a private visit and had no further details.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to improve the political relations between Madrid and Rome,&quot; La Repubblica quoted him as saying. &quot;That's why I want to meet Prodi, to be able to have a long chat with him about matters that interest both our governments.&quot;</p>
<p>Spain and Italy fell out last year after Prodi sought assurances from Aznar that he would support a joint bid to have the tough criteria for Economic and Monetary Union relaxed.</p>
<p>Aznar refused and both have since redoubled efforts to be in shape by EMU's planned 1999 start.</p>
<p>As a result of the meeting, Prodi drew up a tougher-than-expected austerity budget to slash 62.5 trillion lire ($40.27 billion) off the 1997 deficit and has repeatedly said Italy is determined to be a founder member of EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;I have no doubt that we will make it,&quot; Aznar said. ($1=1552 Lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
