<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="313489" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BA,American hope for grand finale.</title>
<headline>BA,American hope for grand finale.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Airways Plc said on Thursday it expects the regulatory issues confronting its planned alliance with American Airlines will all come together in one big endgame towards the end of March.</p>
<p>The alliance is now being judged by regulatory authorities in Britain, the European Commission and the United States.</p>
<p>In a parallel process, &quot;open skies&quot; trade talks between Britain and the U.S. aimed at opening up their restrictive transatlantic market, resume in Washington on February 4.</p>
<p>&quot;That would essentially mean all the trains (regulatory approvals and open skies negotiations) coming into the station at pretty well the same time, around the end of March or early April, enabling us to start implementing our alliance from early in our summer season,&quot; a spokesman for British Airways said.</p>
<p>Airline industry sources said the next open skies meeting in Washington on February 4 is designed to keep the negotiating process ticking over.</p>
<p>It is expected to focus on settling the least contentious issues, clearing the way for the bigger cards, featuring access to London's Heathrow airport and to the domestic U.S. market, to be played out in the weeks ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;Our understanding is the next round of bilaterals is not going to discuss the substantive issues...There are going to be at least two more meetings,&quot; said one industry source.</p>
<p>&quot;They are clearing the decks of the smaller issues so that they can really concentrate on the beefier ones once the regulatory pots start approaching boiling point,&quot; said another.</p>
<p>BA declined to comment but said it was confident an open skies deal is now within reach.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the two sides are pretty close to agreement and that the outstanding issues can be resolved in a matter of weeks rather than months,&quot; a company spokesman said.</p>
<p>He said BA also expects it to be &quot;a matter of weeks&quot; before British trade and industry minister Ian Lang rules on the deal under British and European competition law.</p>
<p>Britain's Office of Fair Trading (OFT) and Lang's Department of Trade and Industry both routinely declined to comment on media reports that the OFT is due to make its final recommendations to Lang at the end of this month.</p>
<p>Meanwhile BA and American submitted their joint application requesting approval under U.S. anti-trust laws with the Department of Transportation in Washington last Friday.</p>
<p>BA has said it expects the U.S. regulatory process to take about three months but notes that approval will only be granted if Britain and the United States can agree open skies.</p>
<p>Conversely, Britain has said approval of the alliance is the key to getting an open skies deal, since it would allow BA to compete for transatlantic transfer traffic in the huge U.S. domestic market where only U.S. airlines are allowed to operate.</p>
<p>BA's chief executive Robert Ayling said in response to criticism from the European competition commissioner this week that the alliance would lead to more competition because it would bring with it an Anglo-U.S. open skies agreement.</p>
<p>Under the proposed alliance, BA intends to coordinate its 244 flights a week to 22 U.S. destinations with American's 238 flights from seven U.S. airports to 12 European destinations.</p>
<p>BA and American say their deal will lead to greater competition because an open skies deal would allow all U.S. airlines access to compete at Heathrow, the most popular of Europe's transatlantic landfalls.</p>
<p>Under the current bilateral aviation treaty, only four airlines are allowed to operate services out of Heathrow -- BA, Virgin Atlantic, United Airlines and American -- and frequencies and routes are restricted.</p>
<p>British trade minister Lang proposed in December  conditions for allowing the alliance through, with a core demand that BA release 168 weekly runway slots at Heathrow -- enough to operate 12 daily return flights -- to make room for competitors.</p>
<p>But other airlines have told the OFT in a review of Lang's proposals that more concessions need to be made if BA and American are to be prevented from dominating the British transatlantic market with 62 percent of all current capacity.</p>
<p>Critics of the deal, which include United, Delta Air Lines, Virgin, Continental Airlines and TWA say more than the 168 slots need to be given up, at competitive times of the day, as well as ground facilities.</p>
<p>&quot;At the end of the day this deal will probably still get done but I think they are going to have to bite on a few tougher undertakings,&quot; said an executive at another major airline.</p>
<p>-- Greg Mahlich, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
