<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="313412" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Superhighway tough challenge to papers - consultant.</title>
<headline>Superhighway tough challenge to papers - consultant.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Media linked to the &quot;electronic superhighway&quot; will account for about six percent of U.S. advertising spending, collecting just over $13 billion by 2010, a leading pulp and paper consultancy said.</p>
<p>&quot;This amounts to an average annual growth rate of 22.4 percent per year for these new media compared to the next-highest rate for Direct Mail/Catalogues of 2.99 percent,&quot; Finland-based Jaakko Poyry said in a client magazine.</p>
<p>Poyry, an advisor to pulp and paper companies worldwide, said its studies in the United States suggested newspapers and newsprint would be the grade hardest hit by new media.</p>
<p>The article by two U.S.-based executives, received on Thursday, did not define the new electronic media closely. It discussed the Electronic Superhighway in a broad sense.</p>
<p>It said the potential negative impact of new electronic media on the U.S. newsprint market could reach 900,000 short tons (816,466 metric tonnes) by 2010 of a 10.3 million short ton (9.3 million tonnes) market in 1996.</p>
<p>Newspaper inserts, fliers and circulars -- a 2.3 million short ton (two million metric tonne) market in 1996 -- would continue to play an active role, Poyry said.</p>
<p>However, &quot;some displacement of advertising dollars toward electronic media is expected as the number of U.S. households with mass media interactive linkages (TV-linked as opposed to PC-linked) starts to reach critical mass after the year 2005.&quot;</p>
<p>Coupons would come under considerable pressure, but magazines were likely to continue in demand, Poyry said.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically, some paper tonnage will be lost to electronic media, but at the same time, new magazines will come onto the market to meet the specific informational needs of the new types of target readers,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Electronic media would also start to take market share from direct mail, Poyry added.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +35 89 6805 0247</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
