<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="313793" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: PRESS DIGEST - Singapore - January 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Singapore - January 16.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the top stories from selected Singapore newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE STRAITS TIMES:</p>
<p>- President Bill Clinton and his new foreign policy team intend to pay &quot;very strong, sustained attention&quot; to Asia, said outgoing Assistant Secretary of State for East Asia and Pacific Affairs Winston Lord.</p>
<p>- Meeting in the middle of the night at a military base between Israel and the Gaza Strip, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat concluded a long-elusive accord on Hebron.</p>
<p>- Property tycoon Ng Teng Fong's Far East Organisation outbid DBS Land for Scotts Tower, offering a higher than expected S$96.8 million to the building's 32 apartment owners.</p>
<p>- Singapore Telecom has invested US$51 million in a new submarine cable network that will link the Pacific Rim, Southeast Asia, the Middle East and Europe.</p>
<p>- Singapore is reviewing its legislation to further strengthen the protection of intellectual property rights, Senior Parliamentary Secretary for Law Ho Peng Kee said.</p>
<p>THE BUSINESS TIMES:</p>
<p>- Compared to the OECD and East Asian economies, Singapore has become more cometitive since the mid-80s, but it has lost ground against its ASEAN neighbours, according to a new index of export competitiveness.</p>
<p>- Hong Kong announced a series of measures to crack down on rising speculation in the luxury property sector, but property observers say the widely expected move is unlikely to affect the bullish market sentiment.</p>
<p>- Developers turned up in force for Hong Kong's first public land auction of the year, chasing two plots of residential land to prices well above market expectations.</p>
<p>- Ng Teng Fong's Far East Organisation staved off stiff competition from DBS Land to clinch Scotts Tower, which was being sold collectivbely by auction.</p>
<p>- One answer to local retailers' woes may be to try and lure back some of the shopping money Singaporeans have been spluring abroad, DBS Bank's head of economic research Friedrich Wu said.</p>
<p>- Singapore Telecom joined more than 80 telecommunications administrations to sign an agreement finalising a US$1.3 billion investment in an undersea cable network.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom 65-8703080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
