<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="313932" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Ford's UK plans to benefit German plant - source.</title>
<headline>Ford's UK plans to benefit German plant - source.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Restructuring measures to be discussed today at Ford Motor Co's Halewood plant in England will benefit the group's German factory in Saarlouis, a German industry source said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be positive for Saarlouis,&quot; the source, who spoke on condition of anonymity, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Ford's German subsidiary Ford-Werke AG declined official comment on a report by the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) news service that Ford was set to announce the elimination of 1,500 jobs at Halewood at a management meeting with unions.</p>
<p>&quot;A statement will be released in England in the course of today,&quot; a Ford-Werke spokesman said.</p>
<p>Industry observers believe manufacturing of the next version of the Escort car, due in 1999, could be switched to Ford plants in Spain or Germany. Halewood is seen by some analysts to be one of the least productive Ford plants in Europe.</p>
<p>Ford's Saarlouis plant, located in the southwestern state of Saarland, employs about 6,000 people and has capacity to build 1,480 Escorts per day in two shifts.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
