<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="313958" id="root" date="1997-01-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German bourse opens lower, bank shares support DAX.</title>
<headline>German bourse opens lower, bank shares support DAX.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-01-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares started bourse trade lower on Thursday, weakened slightly by Wall Street's overnight decline, but a switch of interest in favour of banking shares limited losses on the blue-chip DAX index.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX was down 16.16 points at 2,972.29 in early trade. However the IBIS DAX index, which tracks electronic trade over the full day, was down only 3.51 points at 2,973.05.</p>
<p>March DTB DAX futures were up 0.5 points at 2,990.5.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see us taking any heavy knocks this morning,&quot; said one Frankfurt dealer. &quot;Nothing has changed in that we all still want to see 3,000 (the next key threshold level for the DAX). We are not far off.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers noted a sharp shift in sector preferences, with bank shares now firmly in demand, replacing the clear favourites of recent weeks -- chemical stocks.</p>
<p>Deutsche Bank was up 1.30 marks at 78.10 marks, while Dresdner Bank rose 70 pfennigs to 51.20.</p>
<p>Dealers said bank shares had not kept up with chemical stocks' recent rally and were now starting to make up lost ground.</p>
<p>At the same time, BASF AG slipped 1.44 marks to 59.15 marks while Hoechst AG was down 1.55 marks at 68.20 marks.</p>
<p>Dealers said the overall market was likely to remain in a reasonably narrow range.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, attention would be on the U.S. jobless claims report due at 1330 GMT, amid hopes it will reinforce the benign interest rate message from Tuesday's U.S. CPI report.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
