<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314063" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Northeast plant outages soften power price fall.</title>
<headline>US Northeast plant outages soften power price fall.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Outages at two big New York power plants helped break a hard price fall for Monday bulk electricity in the Northeast, but forecasts for milder weather kept downward pressure on the market, traders said.</p>
<p>Niagara Mohawk Power Corp planned to take its 610 megawatt (MW) Nine Mile Point unit 1 in Scriba, N.Y., later today to repair a leak in the dry well, a Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) spokesman said.</p>
<p>The 650 MW Kintigh coal-fired station, owned and operated by New York State Electric and Gas Co (NYSE&amp;G), remained shut after tripping off line Thursday, market sources said, adding the Barker, N.Y., power plant could resume operation as early as Saturday. NYSE&amp;G declined to comment on the plant's outage.</p>
<p>Although power demand was expected to ease next week after the passage of the arctic cold front, the two plant outages also tightened supply availability, market sources said.</p>
<p>The outages also dried up spot activity with very few trades, especially in the New York market, they said.</p>
<p>Peak, non-firm electricity prices (including transmission costs) for Monday delivery in the eastern New York Power Pool (NYPP) slipped to $30.00-$40.00 a megawatt hour (MWh) from Thursday's $38.00-$44.00.</p>
<p>Off-peak, non-firm power for Monday in eastern NYPP was quoted near $23.00, compared with $22.00-$24.00 Thursday.</p>
<p>Heavy snow squalls was expected to continue to extend through western New York, with wind chills of -15 to -45 degrees Fahrenheit across the region through early Sunday. The Northeast would continue to moderate through the weekend into early next week.</p>
<p>In western NYPP, peak, non-firm power for Monday was pegged at a $35.00-$40.00 versus Thursday's quote near $38.00.</p>
<p>Western NYPP electricity for off-peak, non-firm delivery Monday firmed to $20.00 from Thursday's $16.00-$17.00 range.</p>
<p>In the New England Power Pool (NEPOOL), peak, non-firm electricity for Monday delivery at Northeast Utilities' (NU) border was quoted near $36.00, the lower end of Thursday's $36.00-$41.00 range.</p>
<p>Non-firm, off-peak NEPOOL power for Monday at the NU border was assessed near $25.00, compared with Monday's $22.00-$26.00.</p>
<p>Swing natural gas prices remained strong on this weekend's deep freeze. Spot gas values at the New York City gate held at $6.00-$6.50 per million British thermal units.</p>
<p>((--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
