<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314175" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Remington Hotel, Nomura &amp; Promus Hotels in deal.</title>
<headline>Remington Hotel, Nomura &amp; Promus Hotels in deal.</headline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Remington Hotel Corp said Friday it made an agreement with Nomura Asset Capital Corp and Promus Hotel Corp to develop 10 Embassy Suites hotels.</p>
<p>Groundbreaking will occur for the Dallas Galleria hotel within 30 days with all 10 hotels to be under construction within 18 months.  </p>
<p>Other market areas targeted for development are: the Arboretum in Austin; Dulles Airport in the greater Washington, D.C. area; Princeton, New Jersey; and the Boston suburbs. Other sites are under consideration as well.</p>
<p>Nomura Asset Capital Corp will provide construction financing that will convert to permanent financing once hotel operations have stabilized. Promus Hotels, will provide mezzanine financing as part of the overall agreement, with the remaining equity provided by a joint venture composed of the Bennett family, owners of Remington Hotel, and Nomura.</p>
<p>Since April 1, 1993, Nomura has provided more than $15 billion of capital to real estate owners and operators on a principal basis.  about one- fourth of such financing has involved hotel properties of all types -- full service, limited service, extended stay and resorts.</p>
<p>The newly constructed hotels will contain between 150 and 200 suites each, together with all the standard features of Embassy Suites hotels.  These features include a large atrium, a free cooked-to-order breakfast and a manager's evening cocktail reception.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
