<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314211" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: ALPINE SKIING-DUVILLARD &quot;SERIOUS BUT STABLE&quot; AFTER CRASH.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-DUVILLARD &quot;SERIOUS BUT STABLE&quot; AFTER CRASH.</headline>
<byline>Steve Keating</byline>
<dateline>WENGEN, Switzerland 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>French ski officals said Adrien Duvillard was in serious but stable condition after crashing heavily on Friday in training for a World Cup downhill.</p>
<p>Duvillard lost control on the final turn of the Lauberhorn course, at 4,260 metres the longest on the World Cup circuit, and crashed at the same spot where Austrian skier Gernot Reinstadler was killed six years ago.</p>
<p>The 27-year-old Frenchman was still unconscious 30 minutes later when he was put into a helicopter for the flight to a hospital at Interlaken where he was examined by chief doctor Paul Guenter.</p>
<p>Shortly after his arrival at the hospital doctors said Duvillard had started to regain consciousness but was placed in drug induced coma in order to undergo a brain scan.</p>
<p>He was then immediately taken to a hospital in Berne, because of what a press release described as possible complications related to the head injury.</p>
<p>Duvillard also sustained a punctured lung and broken ribs in the crash.</p>
<p>&quot;He has very serious head trauma,&quot; said Didier Bonvin, head of the French ski team. &quot;They are also checking his spine and lower limbs because of the magnitude of the impact at over 90 kilometres an hour.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very serious accident but apparently his life is not in danger.&quot;</p>
<p>Bonvin also said the team would race in Saturday's downhill, &quot;unless something terrible happens overnight.&quot;</p>
<p>The Lauberhorn course, site of one of the five classic downhills on the World Cup circuit, has a difficult final turn, combined with a jump.</p>
<p>&quot;This part of the course has always been tricky,&quot; said Canada's Olympic downhill bronze medallist Ed Podivinsky. &quot;You are tired when you come off that jump. You get a little air and your tips come up a bit. It's so steep you just lose it.&quot;</p>
<p>The 20-year-old Reinstadler broke his pelvis and suffered massive internal injuries when he crashed at the spot during training in 1991.</p>
<p>He never regained consciousness and died in hospital several hours later.</p>
<p>Duvillard, who had returned to form with fifth place in December's downhill in Val Gardena after two seasons beset by injury, is the nephew of Henri Duvillard who won six World Cup races between 1969 and 1973, including the Wengen downhill in 1971.</p>
<p>He had also posted the second quickest time in Thursday's training behind Italian Kristian Ghedina.</p>
<p>Along with room mate Luc Alphand, the reigning World Cup downhill champion, he had been expected to do well for France at the world championships in Sestiere, Italy, in February.</p>
<p>Bonvin said Alphand, who rushed to his team mate's aid in the finish area, was still extremely shaken by the accident.&quot;</p>
<p>When training resumed at Wengen about 45 minutes after Duvillard's accident, American Chad Fleischer, the first skier onto the course, crashed at the same place. He was not seriously hurt.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WENGEN, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
