<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314294" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-PSG SEEK REHABILITATION AT THIRD DIVISION GROUND.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-PSG SEEK REHABILITATION AT THIRD DIVISION GROUND.</headline>
<byline>Rex Gowar</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crisis club Paris Saint-Germain will not be dwelling on the romantic aspect of the French Cup that pits holders Auxerre against the amateurs of a tiny village in northern France in the first round this weekend.</p>
<p>A trip to third division Besancon on Sunday which PSG might have regarded as a leisurely country stroll is now, their confidence in tatters after their European Super Cup humiliation by Juventus, a hard-nosed search for rehabilitation.</p>
<p>&quot;The revolution has to happen on the pitch, from Sunday against Besancon in the French Cup and in the (first division) championship at Monaco (a week later),&quot; PSG chief executive Michel Denisot said.</p>
<p>Underdogs Besancon will try to take advantage of the doubts afflicting PSG's players, but could find themselves the victims of a backlash from a side who above all else will be looking to restore their pride.</p>
<p>&quot;We're having a hard time coming out of the nightmare of Wednesday against Juventus,&quot; Denisot said. &quot;But we're going there concentrated. It will be difficult and we're going to prepare for this match very seriously.&quot;</p>
<p>Veteran defender Paul Le Guen said: &quot;We'll be a little bit afraid at Besancon.&quot;</p>
<p>Panama striker Julio Cesar Dely Valdes has been dropped from Wednesday's side in favour of the newly-signed Cyrille Pouget.</p>
<p>Auxerre face a minor league team whose 64-year-old coach Serge Durand does a paper round on his bicycle in Vervins, a village of 3,000, and whose striker admires the French league and Cup double winners' goalkeeper Lionel Charbonnier.</p>
<p>&quot;For me, at the end of my days on the bench, I could not have dreamt of a more beautiful story,&quot; Durand said as he contemplated playing against European Cup contenders Auxerre in front of 10,000 people at the nearby town of Saint-Quentin.</p>
<p>The match was switched from the village close to the Belgian border where Vervins, whose pitch is frozen, normally play in front of 150 spectators.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no tactic, other than to delay as long as possible the moment when we concede the first (goal),&quot; Durand said.</p>
<p>Striker Philippe Bod</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
