<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314268" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: CRICKET-SOHAIL BAN HANDS WEST INDIES FAVOURITISM.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-SOHAIL BAN HANDS WEST INDIES FAVOURITISM.</headline>
<byline>Bernard Hickey</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan captain Wasim Akram conceded on Friday that the loss of suspended opener Aamir Sohail would be a severe blow to his side's chances in the first match of the World Series limited overs final on Saturday.</p>
<p>The dashing left-handed opener was suspended on Friday for one game by match referee Raman Subba Row after questioning an umpire's decision in Pakistan's loss to Australia on Thursday.</p>
<p>West Indies in contrast have been bolstered ahead of the best-of-three finals series by the return to form of star batsman Brian Lara.</p>
<p>&quot;He's our main player, it's tough news,&quot; Akram said of Sohail's suspension after the team arrived in Sydney on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are definitely going to miss Aamir tomorrow. We can't play with our proper combination tomorrow, but we've got good back-up and I think we will be okay,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>West Indies, after a bad start to the series, have beaten Pakistan three times in four games and have won five of their last six games.</p>
<p>Australia were eliminated from the annual competition last week by a rampant Lara, who blasted 192 runs in two innings against the host nation, capping a remarkable form turn-around.</p>
<p>Lara began his tour of Australia with a wretched series of low scores in both one-day matches and tests, hitting just 139 runs in nine innings over November and December.</p>
<p>But a stunning 102 against Australia on January 5 sparked a purple patch where he scored 295 runs in three games over a one-week period.</p>
<p>The left-hander also plundered Pakistan's attack in scoring 103 not out to lead West Indies to victory last Friday in Perth.</p>
<p>Fast-bowling spearheads Curtly Ambrose and captain Walsh were also rested for that match, devaluing any confidence Pakistan could have taken from the victory.</p>
<p>Walsh told reporters the return of Ambrose after a rest to cure a nagging hamstring injury could be vital.</p>
<p>&quot;He's a class player. When the chips are down, he knows how to get himself back into it. He wasn't having a successful tour, he wasn't taking wickets but now he's Back,&quot; Walsh said.</p>
<p>West Indies were also bolstered by the arrival of Phil Simmons early on Friday as a back-up for fellow all-rounders Jimmy Adams, Carl Hooper and Shivnarine Chanderpaul.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WEIND">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
