<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314375" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIAN UNREST CONTINUES, DIVISIONS REMAIN DEEP.</title>
<headline>BULGARIAN UNREST CONTINUES, DIVISIONS REMAIN DEEP.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Roche</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria faces a 12th day of unrest with government and opposition calling for talks to break a political and economic impasse but still far apart on details.</p>
<p>The opposition, led by deputies of the Union of Democratic Forces (UDF) boycotting parliament, and sympathetic students planned Friday afternoon marches in Sofia to demand general elections soon. Other protests were expected nationwide.</p>
<p>The Socialist government, blamed for economic mayhem, says it wants negotiations with the opposition but hopes to delay until the end of this year polls likely to sweep it from power if held sooner.</p>
<p>An opinion poll on Thursday gave the former communist Socialists just eight percent support. Millions have been plunged into poverty by inflation of over 300 percent and a currency collapse blamed on their failure to implement reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;We have the legal, economic and political arguments to hold elections at the end of the year,&quot; Socialist party chairman Georgi Parvanov told reporters on Thursday.</p>
<p>Negotiations with the opposition should begin by January 19, after talks on a draft anti-crisis programme introduced by the Socialists' prime minister-designate Nikolai Dobrev, he said.</p>
<p>The Socialists want a government of technocrats led by Dobrev to rule until elections. The opposition says it opposes any new cabinet being formed under the present parliament.</p>
<p>Dobrev's predecessor, outgoing prime minister Zhan Videnov, said Bulgaria faced collapse unless the government and opposition agreed on forming a new cabinet.</p>
<p>&quot;Without urgent measures and concrete solutions, the country is on the brink of financial collapse,&quot; said Videnov, who resigned on December 21.</p>
<p>He is himself blamed by the opposition for the country's economic crisis. Students marched this week carrying posters of his face with the legend: &quot;Wanted for crimes against Bulgaria&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Without a parliamentary mandate to negotiate with international lending institutions, Bulgaria will squander its last foreign exchange reserves and further isolate itself from the world,&quot; Videnov said.</p>
<p>U.S. Ambassador Avis Bolen said: &quot;Bulgaria must urgently reach consensus through dialogue&quot;. The International Monetary Fund and World Bank want Sofia to introduce tough monetary policies as a condition for financial aid to save the economy.</p>
<p>Schools, hospitals and factories on Thursday held protests ranging from one-hour warning strikes and rallies to staff wearing blue opposition ribbons.</p>
<p>Some workers at the Stomana steelworks in Pernik near Sofia held a rally and stopped work for an hour but a rally in the pro-government stronghold of Kozloduy won scant support from well-paid workers at the town's nuclear plant.</p>
<p>Some 15,000 people, more than on Wednesday, attended a rally and concert outside Sofia's gold-domed cathedral.</p>
<p>&quot;I can promise you that we will never again allow another Socialist government to rule this country because we do not want chaos to prevail over democracy any more,&quot; Nadezhda Mihailova, UDF spokeswoman, told the rally.</p>
<p>An opinion poll by the MBMD polling agency showed that while the Socialists' support had fallen drastically, UDF support had not grown since November's presidential elections.</p>
<p>&quot;This supports the thesis that the people are on the streets not for political motives but for purely economic ones,&quot; said MBMD director Mira Yanova.</p>
<p>The Socialists won parliamentary elections in December 1994 but last November's presidential election was won by opposition lawyer Petar Stoyanov, who will be sworn in on Sunday and formally takes office on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Outgoing President Zhelyu Zhelev, also a staunch critic of the Socialists, has refused to ask them to form a new government in the present atmosphere. The responsibility is likely to be handed on to Stoyanov next week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
