<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314570" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria needs stability to avoid economy collapse.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria needs stability to avoid economy collapse.</headline>
<byline>Elisaveta Konstantinova</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria needs to resolve its political crisis as soon as possible to permit the introduction of a strict monetary regime and avert economic collapse, political and financial analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>Vital talks with the IMF and preparations for a currency board to halt the slump in the lev were halted after Socialist Prime Minister Zhan Videnov resigned on December 21. A week ago the opposition walked out of parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;Bulgaria is in a state of weightlessness. There is no government, no budget, the finance minister is outgoing and the legitimacy of the central bank is becoming dubious,&quot; co-manager of Adlon-Discont brokerage house Andrei Pramov told Reuters.</p>
<p>An International Monetary Fund (IMF) representative said the IMF was set to send a mission to Sofia on January 22, but had cancelled the trip.</p>
<p>&quot;The IMF is prepared to complete negotiations on the implementation of a currency board with a new government as soon as it is appointed,&quot; said another IMF official.</p>
<p>The IMF last November proposed the introduction of a currency board system, which severely curbs the financial power of the government and the central bank, to boost confidence in the crumbling financial system.</p>
<p>Preparations for the currency board, due to be completed by February, included restructuring the central bank, passing in parliament a viable 1997 budget and approving amendments to banking laws.</p>
<p>After 12 days of massive protests the opposition and the Socialist government, composed largely of ex-communists, are calling for talks to break a political and economic deadlock but remain far apart on details.</p>
<p>The Socialists, blamed for mismanaging the economy, say they want negotiations. Political opponents say the Socialists hope to delay changes until the end of the year as polls are likely to sweep them from power if held sooner.</p>
<p>Millions have been plunged into poverty by inflation of over 300 percent and a lev collapse blamed on the government's failure to implement reforms.</p>
<p>The opposition, which is demanding elections soon, wants to appoint a government of technocrats which would complete negotiations with the IMF and the World Bank and appoint new managers at the central bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the circumstances the introduction of the currency board is very much on a when and if basis,&quot; said Pramov.</p>
<p>Central bank foreign exchange reserves stood at $518 million in December.</p>
<p>Bulgaria has pledged to pay a $135 million coupon on Brady bonds issued two years ago to restructure an $8.16 billion foreign commercial debt due on January 28.</p>
<p>Foreign payments of more than $300 million are due in the first quarter of this year alone.</p>
<p>The outgoing government pledged to boost revenue through speedy sell-offs of major local state enterprises, but economists say investors would be deterred by the unstable situation in Bulgaria.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's grain supplies, depleted by excessive exports in 1995 and a bad harvest last year, will last until end-January and grain imports are inevitable. Seasonal fuel imports would also demand funding.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's domestic debt topped one trillion levs in December, and payments due in January alone are around 100 billion levs. The finance ministry hopes to cover such payments through roll-over issues, but buyers on the shrinking interbank market are fading away.</p>
<p>President-elect Petar Stoyanov, due to take office on January 22, had said he would hand the Socialists a mandate to form a government which his predecessor Zhelyu Zhelev has so far refused.</p>
<p>&quot;There are only questions and no answers on Bulgaria's short and long-term prospects,&quot; said Pramov.</p>
<p>$=682.12 levs</p>
<p>--  Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
