<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314631" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Rumeli ups stake in Polish cement plant.</title>
<headline>Rumeli ups stake in Polish cement plant.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's Rumeli concern has finalised a 1996 agreement to buy a 33 percent stake in the Polish Cementownia Nowa Huta SA cement plant and has bought back shares from the firm's employees, Rumeli said on Friday.</p>
<p>By the end of the month Rumeli will also finalise an already agreed purchase of 27 percent of Nowa Huta for $21 million from 14 National Investment funds which have 1.9 percent of the cement plant each, Rumeli said in a statement.</p>
<p>In July last year Rumeli agreed to pay $20 million for 33 percent of Nowa Huta held by National Investment Fund No. 4 but had to wait to finalise the deal for an interior ministry clearance, necessary in all foreign majority takeovers.</p>
<p>The statement said Rumeli has also bought 15 percent of Nowa Huta's stock held by its 446 employees for $9 million. It will raise wages by 15 percent, pay out a one-off bonus of 8,000 zlotys and keep the company's jobs for five years.</p>
<p>Nowa Huta has about five percent of the Polish cement market. Rumeli said it planned to raise Nowa Huta's output to one million tonnes of cement a year from the current 600,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Engin Saydam, Rumeli's representative in Poland said in the statement the higher output would be possible thanks to a modernisation of the plant in which Rumeli wants to invest $58 million over the next five years.</p>
<p>&quot;We have already made a modernisation plan and picked the company whcih will do it. The work will begin in February,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nowa Huta had a net profit of 2.3 million zlotys in 1995 on sales of 40.6 million zlotys, down from 7.7 million and 55.3 million zlotys respectively in 1994.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
