<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314650" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenia PM offers coalition to all parties.</title>
<headline>Slovenia PM offers coalition to all parties.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Janez Drnovsek, putting together a new government after Slovenia's inconclusive election in November, said on Friday that he had offered cabinet posts to all parties in parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;Today I sent a proposal of cooperation in coalition to presidents of all parliamentary parties,&quot; Drnovsek, a centre-left Liberal Democrat, told a news conference. &quot;The proposal includes programme goals and a possible division of ministerial posts.&quot;</p>
<p>Drnovsek, who has a week to present his government lineup to parliament, said he had asked for relies by noon on Monday and hoped to form a coalition on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The advantage of a very large coalition would be that we could reduce the tension and polarisation that developed after the election,&quot; Drnovsek said, but added that the work of the government would be simplified if not all parties decided to join the coalition.</p>
<p>Drnovsek's party took 25 out of 90 parliamentary seats in the general election on November 10. He won a mandate from parliament to form a new government by a single vote last week with support from smaller parties, including former communists.</p>
<p>The three rightwing parties of the so-called &quot;Spring Alliance&quot; which hold 44 seats and did not support Drnovsek's nomination, said they would only participate in a government in which all of them were included.</p>
<p>The alliance comprises the conservative People's Party, the centre-right Socical Democrats and the rightist Christian Democrats.</p>
<p>Drnovsek said the Christian Democrats and former communists of the United List of Social Democrats looked the least likely to participate in the deal since they had so far shown the strongest scepticism towards a government with no opposition.</p>
<p>According to the proposed agreement, the Liberal Democrats would have five ministers, the People's Party four and the Social Democrats three in the new government.</p>
<p>The Christian Democrats and the United List of Social Democrats would each get two posts, while the Nationalist Party and Desus, a party representing pensioners, would get one each.</p>
<p>Drnovsek said his party would provide the foreign minister and minister for economic affairs.</p>
<p>The new government would be Slovenia's third since independence from Yugoslavia in 1991.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
