<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314729" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico Cetes rate moderates gains at close.</title>
<headline>Mexico Cetes rate moderates gains at close.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican overnight Cetes rates reined in their earlier upward trend towards the close to end up 65 basis points at 23.50 percent during a session driven mainly by speculation, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some dealers wanted to jack rates up but then others stepped in to keep increases under control,&quot; one trader said. &quot;The whole session was hallmarked by dealers giving and taking.&quot;</p>
<p>The overnight Cetes rate ranged between 22.80 and 24.35 percent during the session.  </p>
<p>Overnight rates on bank paper meanwhile closed up 25 basis points at 24.75 percent.</p>
<p>Traders said that secondary rates had weakened earlier on fallout from the peso, which had opened weak.</p>
<p>&quot;The peso has been somewhat unsteady, and rates are just following in step,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The benchmark 48-hour peso opened 0.65 of a centavo weaker, but recovered to close 2.8 centavos firmer at 7.8020/7.8080 per dollar.</p>
<p>Banco de Mexico drained 1.556 billion pesos in liquidity from the market by purchasing paper through two auctions. The central bank normally injects liquidity into the market, but so far this year has often had to drain a daily surplus.</p>
<p>Dealers said that recent upside pressure on secondary rates and zigzagging exchange rates could augur an increase in primary rates at next week's central bank auction. &quot;I don't think it would be a good idea for rates to fall again, especially as the peso has been wobbly recently,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Liquidity of 2.541 billion pesos was scheduled to return to the system on Monday.</p>
<p>((--Patricia Lezama, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9554))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
