<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314739" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil shares end firm, Petrobras jumps.</title>
<headline>Brazil shares end firm, Petrobras jumps.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian shares ended strong on continued foreign buying, with state oil firm Petrobras spearheading the rise, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Bovespa index of the 49 most active shares closed up 2.1 percent at 78,163 points.</p>
<p>Trade remained heavy, with the bolsa's turnover totalling 599.6 million reais ($576.5 million).</p>
<p>Some traders said they were surprised with the market's strength throughout the session as the bolsa resisted an expected profit-taking after consecutive days of rises.  </p>
<p>Petrobras  PETp.SA jumped 4.02 percent to 194 reais on news that Brazil may allow foreigners to buy a minority voting stake in the company when Congress approves legislation regarding the opening up of the sector to private capital.</p>
<p>&quot;We had expected some selling pressure but the market absorbed all profit-taking,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Traders also said foreign investment should be behind the market's rally because, despite optimism that the re-election amendment will pass Congress, market players are not that sure President Fernando Henrique Cardoso will succeed in having the issue approved in lower house floor next week.  </p>
<p>State power utility Eletrobras closed up 2.66 percent at 424 reais.</p>
<p>Benchmark Telebras rose 2.4 percent, ending at 89.50 reais.</p>
<p>Analysts also said shares are seen firming next week although the market may see some gains-taking as the bolsa failed to weaken as expected.</p>
<p>((--Fatima Cristina, Sao Paulo Newsroom 5511 2485412))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
