<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314835" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong, China mark border before '97 handover.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong, China mark border before '97 handover.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong and China's southern province of Guangdong signed a preliminary agreement on Friday marking the territory's border with the mainland after 150 years as a British colony.</p>
<p>The memorandum of understanding was signed by Hong Kong deputy political adviser John Ashton and Xiao Jinzhe from the province's foreign affairs department.</p>
<p>Ashton told a news conference Hong Kong expected the border to be adopted as the legal boundary after the territory becomes a Special Administrative Region (SAR) of China on July 1.</p>
<p>&quot;We would hope that (China's) State Council follows the same course when it publishes the map of the SAR. We hope it will become the legal boundary,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Small parts of the border between China and Hong Kong had never been clearly defined. The uncertain areas have long been exploited by smugglers and have laid the territory open to frequent incursions both on land and by sea.</p>
<p>The agreement made no big changes to the existing boundary, but the new border would facilitate better administrative and police control, Ashton said.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be a very good thing to get this question resolved and agreed before the handover this year and (it) removes one particular set of uncertainty and ambiguity,&quot; he said, adding the agreement would be endorsed within the next four months.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
