<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314981" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. agents say they have leads in Atlanta bombings.</title>
<headline>U.S. agents say they have leads in Atlanta bombings.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Federal officials said Friday that they had received a number of leads in their investigation into this week's double bomb blasts outside an Atlanta abortion clinic.</p>
<p>U.S. Attorney Kent Alexander said information involving a range of possibilities, from anti-abortion activists to citizens' milita groups, had come from more than 200 telephone calls to a special federal hotline set up as an appeal for public assistance.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, he said, bomb sweeps were being conducted at other Atlanta-area abortion clinics and would continue through next week's 24th anniversary of the U.S. Supreme Court's Roe vs. Wade ruling that recognised a woman's right to an abortion.</p>
<p>&quot;So far, we've received over 200 calls,&quot; Alexander told reporters. &quot;From those calls a number of good leads are developing.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked to elaborate further, the federal prosecutor described &quot;a myriad of leads. Much of what you'd expect, ranging from people who are anti-abortion to militia.&quot;</p>
<p>He also revealed for the first time that investigators discovered shrapnel and bomb fragments some distance from the blast site, including some on the roof of a seven-story office building near the clinic.</p>
<p>&quot;These were two very powerful bombs. The most remarkable thing about this case thus far is that no one was killed,&quot; Alexander said.</p>
<p>The first bomb exploded about 9:30 a.m. EST (1430 GMT) Thursday outside the Atlanta Northside Family Planning Services centre. An hour later, as law enforcement officials and local firefighters sifted through debris, a second bomb detonated near a garbage container in the building's parking lot, injuring six people including agents from the FBI and the U.S. Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms.</p>
<p>Police said there was no warning of the attack and no one claimed responsibility.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
