<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314918" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Conrail says no sale to Norfolk Southern.</title>
<headline>Conrail says no sale to Norfolk Southern.</headline>
<dateline>PHILADELPHIA 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Conrail Inc. insisted Friday it would not be sold to hostile bidder Norfolk Southern Corp., and Conrail Chairman David LeVan said the railroad was committed to its proposed $9.3 billion merger with CSX Corp.</p>
<p>In remarks prepared for delivery to a Conrail shareholders meeting slated to start at noon EST, LeVan urged investors to back the CSX deal.</p>
<p>&quot;The Conrail board has determined that a sale to Norfolk Southern is not in the best interests of Conrail, and the Conrail board will not agree to a sale to Norfolk Southern,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>LeVan also said Conrail's board would not be swayed by a proposal by Norfolk Southern to buy 9.9 percent of the company if shareholders defeated a measure that is critical to the CSX union.</p>
<p>&quot;This promise is a stop-gap effort designed to entice shareholders to vote 'no' today and to shake the resolve of the Conrail board. That resolve will not be shaken,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Conrail has repeatedly rejected Norfolk Southern's $10.3 billion bid, saying that CSX's offer provides more benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope you all understand the Conrail board is fully committed to the CSX-Conrail merger and, regardless of speculation to the contrary, there can be no transaction with Norfolk Southern until 1999 at the earliest,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The proposed merger pact between Conrail and CSX prohibits either party, should their pact fail, from merging with another company until 1999.</p>
<p>The vote was expected to be very close.</p>
<p>Conrail's stock gained 25 cents to $103.75, CSX was up $1.75 to $46.75, and Norfolk Southern was unchanged at $88.125 in midday trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHILADELPHIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
