<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="314987" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. wheat export market at risk, food expert says.</title>
<headline>U.S. wheat export market at risk, food expert says.</headline>
<byline>Greg Frost</byline>
<dateline>ORLANDO, Fla. 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of a prominent baking school warned Friday that foreign markets for U.S. wheat were being lost to more agressive exporters, and he called for the U.S. government to rebuild its stockpile of grain and reinstate the Export Enhancement Program (EEP).</p>
<p>Dr. Virgil Smail, president of the American Institute of Baking, told attendees of the annual convention of the National Association of Wheat Growers that the U.S. share of the world wheat market was under threat from the influence of large subsidized wheat marketing boards.  </p>
<p>But he also criticized the inability of U.S. suppliers to meet the increasingly stringent needs of end-users.</p>
<p>&quot;Our share of international trade is, in my opinion very seriously jeopardized in the future. Part of the reason... is that the playing field is still not level,&quot; Smail said. &quot;GATT and NAFTA have been passed, but in passing those, the state trading enterprises were overlooked and pretty much ignored.&quot;</p>
<p>Smail said U.S. efforts to sell wheat overseas were competing with monopolies in such countries as Canada and Australia and in the European Union.  </p>
<p>He said the marketing boards for those countries promoted their wheat based on quality, but often made the sale based on prices that were negotiated behind closed doors.</p>
<p>&quot;A state trading association therefore can always underbid a U.S. supplier because of our bidding process, which is open,&quot; Smail told the growers in the keynote address. &quot;The only tool that you have to counterbalance this trade practice is your Export Enhancement Program.&quot;</p>
<p>Smail said the U.S. would have to &quot;repurchase&quot; lost markets in the near term by using EEP, but that EEP would only work if the United States had a big enough stockpile of grain.  </p>
<p>But Smail also said that long term, U.S. suppliers must work at meeting the quality demands of foreign buyer.</p>
<p>&quot;Bakers see variation within a type of wheat for a specific purpose as poor quality. What they really want is uniform quality and consistency,&quot; Smail said. &quot;Our grain industry tends to blend for an average quality but it does not take advantage of the best quality wheats available in a class for our export customers unless, of course, the export customer asks for it.&quot;</p>
<p>Smail said foreign customers have become so sophisticated that in many cases their processing needs were identical, if not more complex, than those of domestic customers. As a result, he recommended that U.S. suppliers develop more stringent tests for grading quality.</p>
<p>&quot;Our current grading system focuses on soundness and cleanliness but it really doesn't address any sort of quality factors,&quot; Smail said. He said U.S. quality grading measurements are limited to inaccurate estimates of end-user performance, such as test weight and protein.&quot;</p>
<p>Smail urged the adoption of quality tests, such as infra-red analysis of grain and measuring of the diameter of kernels so as to predict the flour yield.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ORLANDO, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
