<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="315087" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton gives Dole highest U.S. civilian award. [corrected 18:10 gmt]</title>
<headline>Clinton gives Dole highest U.S. civilian award. [corrected 18:10 gmt]</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton on Friday presented his electoral opponent Republican Bob Dole with the Presidential Medal of Freedom (corrects from &quot;Presidential Medal of Honour&quot;), the nation's highest civilian award.</p>
<p>&quot;I am pleased to be able to recognise Bob Dole's record of achievement with the highest honour our nation can bestow on a citizen,&quot; Clinton said at a White House ceremony. &quot;Through it we honour not just his individual achievement, but his clear embodiment of the common values and beliefs that join us as a people.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;Son of the soil, citizen, soldier and legislator, Bob Dole understands the American people, their struggles, their triumphs and their dreams,&quot; Clinton said before bestowing the medal on Dole, who was defeated by Clinton in last November's presidential election.</p>
<p>&quot;Through five decades of public service that took him from county attorney to Senate majority leader, and the longest serving leader of his party in history, he never forgot his roots in Russell, Kansas,&quot; Clinton added.</p>
<p>In addition to recalling Dole's record as a legislator, Clinton honoured him for his service in World War II, which left his right arm disabled, and for his wit.</p>
<p>Displaying that humour, Dole began his own remarks by pretending to take the presidential oath of office, saying: &quot;I Robert J. Dole...&quot; After the roar of laughter died down, he added, &quot;Sorry, wrong speech.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
