<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="315048" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: OPTIONS - U.S. debt vols pressured by time decay.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - U.S. debt vols pressured by time decay.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Implied volatilities for shorter-dated U.S. fixed-income options softened late in Friday's shortened session, under pressure from time decay over the long weekend, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going into the weekend mode now...so volatilities are obviously dropping,&quot; said a Treasury bond trader for a brokrage firm at the Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT).</p>
<p>He added, however, that T-bond volatilities had briefly popped higher in mid-morning when the underlying bond market started sliding from early highs.  </p>
<p>&quot;We had a little bit of action this morning when it looked as if we (bond futures) were going to stay down and break to the downside,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But before long, March T-bond futures found support in the mid-110 area and bounced back above Thursday's settlement, causing bids for options to back off, he said.</p>
<p>Implied volatility for February T-bond futures options on CBOT was off 0.2 point at 7.8 percent in late trade. March volatility was holding relatively well, virtually unchanged from Thursday's close at 9.5 percent.  </p>
<p>Traders said there were a number of 1,000-lot trades in the bond options pit but overall volume was moderate.</p>
<p>T-bond trade at the CBOT and Eurodollar contracts at the Chicago Mercantile Exchange will be closed on Monday due to the Martin Luther King Jr Day holiday.</p>
<p>At the shorter end of the yield curve, volatilities for CME Eurodollar futures options were generally easier.</p>
<p>Implied volatilities for June, September and December contracts were off 0.1-0.2 point each at 12.1, 15.0 and 16.4 percent respectively.  </p>
<p>Among the largest deals, a European firm was seen selling 2,000 lots of 93.75 March 1998 straddles and a commercial firm bought 2,000 of front-March 94.00/94.25 put spread.</p>
<p>An investment bank was said to have traded a total of 4,000 legs of June 94.00/94.25 squash -- buying 94.25 calls and selling 94.00 puts.</p>
<p>&quot;Volume is decent but volatilities are down because there's not that much activity really,&quot; a brokerage firm trader at the CME Eurodollar pit.</p>
<p>((Chicago Derivatives Desk 312-408-8750))</p>
<p>((E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
