<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="315184" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss stocks end at record highs.</title>
<headline>Swiss stocks end at record highs.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss shares again ended at a record closing highs on Friday as the dollar's gains propelled stocks to new peaks, dealers said.</p>
<p>The broad Swiss Performance Index (SPI) ended up 10.31 points at record high of 2,579.26.</p>
<p>The blue-chip Swiss Market Index (SMI) was up 12.8 at a record close of 4,019.9, just below its intra-day all-time high of 4,022.4. Dealers said the market expected analysts to raise their profit forecast for Swiss companies generally due to the dollar's gains versus the Swiss franc.</p>
<p>Dollar earners like Nestle and Holderbank were higher. Watchmaker SMH rose strongly.</p>
<p>Demand focused on industrials, which tend to benefit from a stronger dollar, while financial stocks were largely neglected.</p>
<p>Trade was seen as nervous on strong volume, traders said.</p>
<p>Expiry of futures and options on the Swiss Soffex exchange also supported cash prices.</p>
<p>Among pharmaceuticals, Roche was up 65 Swiss francs at 11,050, leading the actives list. The share was supported by new buy recommendations.</p>
<p>Novartis closed steady at 1,548 with dealers saying some investors swapped Novartis for Roche.</p>
<p>Banks were mixed. Union Bank of Switzerland fell six Swiss francs to 1,149, partially on technical factors. The bank was also downgraded by Standard &amp; Poor's on Thursday.</p>
<p>Credit Suisse Group rose 2.50 to 140.25 on buy recommendations. Dealers also said CS Group's new CEO Lukas Muehlemann held a roadshow which was favourably received.</p>
<p>Swiss Bank Corp added 0.75 francs to 249.75.</p>
<p>Insurers were lower, with Swiss Re seven francs lower at 1,391.</p>
<p>Winterthur lost eight to 779 after Moody's said on Thursday it had lowered its rating for the insurer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
