<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="315111" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Sony's German unit to return to profit in 96/97.</title>
<headline>Sony's German unit to return to profit in 96/97.</headline>
<dateline>COLOGNE, Germany 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German unit of Japanese electronics giant Sony will report a return to profitability in its 1996/97 business year, Josef Brauner, chairman of Sony Deutschland GmbH, said on Friday.</p>
<p>Turnover at Sony Deutschland increased by nine percent to around 1.6 billion marks ($997 million) between April and December 1996, Braunau said in an advance copy of an interview with the Koelner Stadt-Anzeiger newspaper to be published on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1996/97 we will see a clear return to the black,&quot; said Braunau.</p>
<p>Sony Deutschland would report single-digit-million-mark profits in the year to the end of March 1997, after notching up total losses in the previous three years of around 35 million marks, Braunau said.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to put these losses into context. Compared to the rest of the sector we got off very lightly. We have cut a lot of the fat that we put on in previous years and have reduced costs by 100 million marks in the last three years,&quot; said Braunau.</p>
<p>Braunau ruled out the possibility of a takeover of the troubled electronics group Grundig, which tipped into crisis after Dutch Philips NV said it was pulling out of management control over the company and would adopt a role as a passive shareholder.</p>
<p>The troubles at its rival Grundig were no cause for celebration, Braunau said. &quot;Grundig is a fantastic German brand,&quot; he said, but Sony had learnt from experience not to try to operate two brands in the same market.</p>
<p>Among Sony's main success stories in 1996 was its &quot;Play Station&quot; computer game product, which had risen to market leadership within two years, Braunau said.</p>
<p>The market for traditional home entertainment products in Germany was shrinking and the future lay in combining the audio, video, telecommunications and computer sectors, he said.</p>
<p>Braunau went on to say that the new Sony personal computer, recently launched in the United States, would probably hit the Japanese market in 1997 and arrive on German and other European markets in 1998. ($1=1.6040 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOGNE, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
