<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="315192" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian bonds/futures closing report.</title>
<headline>Italian bonds/futures closing report.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian debt futures set off into the blue in late trade, forging another all-time high on the March contract on LIFFE after a week of steady gains.</p>
<p>The March future hit a peak of 131.53 and by 1615 GMT was trading 33 basis points higher at 131.32.</p>
<p>The July 2006 Btp ended 19 basis points up on the day at 110.67, with the yield at 7.29 percent and the spread over the benchmark 10-year Bund 154 basis points.</p>
<p>The lira too had a buoyant day, breaking through 970 per mark and tearing up to 969.80 helped by the strength of the dollar against the mark.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the morning session had been fairly quiet but the acceleration of the afternoon led some to project the March future reaching 131.85 in the next few days and 132.47 later on.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is overbought at the moment. We're waiting for news like consumer prices data, an agreement on metalworkers' contracts and a rate cut,&quot; one broker in London said.</p>
<p>Preliminary CPI from 11 sample Italian cities is due to be released on Monday and Tuesday, with analysts forecasting a month on month increase of 0.2 percent and a year on year rate of 2.6 percent in January. This compares with a 0.1 percent monthly gain in December and a 2.6 percent yearly rise.  </p>
<p>The long-running debate between employers and unions over renewing contracts is still in stalemate and the Bank of Italy is not expected to shift rates until a solution is found.</p>
<p>One trader said a retracement of the market would be needed soon and he said an interest rate cut might be the trigger.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +392 66129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
