<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="315583" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK shares reach new peaks after U.S. record close.</title>
<headline>UK shares reach new peaks after U.S. record close.</headline>
<byline>Elaine Hardcastle</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The UK's blue chip FTSE 100 index leapt to an all-time high on Friday amid relief that British interest rates are being held steady and after U.S. shares put in another record-breaking performance overnight.</p>
<p>The FTSE 100 index was up 12.8 points at 4,210.3 by 1107 GMT, after breaching the psychologically important 4,200 level. Advancing stocks were in a two-to-one majority.</p>
<p>&quot;The FTSE is continuing to reflect relief that UK interest rates don't have to go up for a while, because the inflation news this week was very encouraging,&quot; said Andrew Bell, head of investment trust research at BZW.</p>
<p>The rally also spread to smaller stocks with the Mid-250 adding 6.3 points to a record 4,572.2.</p>
<p>&quot;We look to be in an arena of low inflation and low interest rates,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;Even though there's a little political uncertainty round the corner, the market will continue to reflect Wall Street, which is a raging bull at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>News that underlying inflation in Britain had slowed to 3.1 percent last month from 3.3 percent and Chancellor Kenneth Clarke's decision this week to leave base rates at 6.0 percent had underpinned market sentiment.</p>
<p>But the main impetus came from Wall Street, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Dow managed to shake off inflation jitters overnight to finish 38 points higher at a record 6,762 after being down 50 points at its worst. The U.S. stock market continues to defy those who believe it is ripe for a sharp correction.</p>
<p>&quot;How solidly-based it all is on Wall Street I'm not sure, but clearly the line of least resistance is upwards at the moment,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Wall Street is a huge bull, we have had several people trying to trip it up, including Mr Greenspan (Federal Reserve Chairman), but it has roared on again and still seems to have lots of momentum. We are on its tail,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the death of a Conservative member of parliament on Thursday which pushed Prime Minister John Major's government into a minority fuelled speculation about an early election.</p>
<p>&quot;It now seems inevitable that an election will be called early and the Chancellor will no doubt try to hold interest rates down if he can,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>But Bell said: &quot;The market will probably want to consolidate in the short term, because of the risk of rising sterling knocking down profit forecasts and political uncertainty. People are not really focussing on these issues.&quot;</p>
<p>But he added that the UK market still looked relatively cheap compared with other European markets.</p>
<p>&quot;I probably wouldn't want to be buying the market at these levels,&quot; he said. &quot;Though there is certainly value in the smaller company area, there's room for a good five percent outperformance over the next few months.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
