<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="315550" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Man arrested over suspected Belfast bomb.</title>
<headline>Man arrested over suspected Belfast bomb.</headline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A man was arrested on Friday after security forces found a suspected bomb on the pavement of a Roman Catholic area of Belfast.</p>
<p>Troops and police sealed off the area and searched for further devices. The man was taken away for questioning.</p>
<p>The device was found in an area called Rosebank gardens in the Ardoyne area of Belfast, which is inhabited by members of the Roman Catholic minority.</p>
<p>Police said troops and police made the arrest and discovery after &quot;suspicious activity&quot; in the area.</p>
<p>Some reports said they had found a bag containing home-made mortar bombs, a favoured weapon of IRA guerrillas.</p>
<p>Belfast has been on high alert this year after a wave of attacks by Irish Republican Army guerrillas fighting to end British rule of Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>Last week IRA activists fired a rocket a Belfast's High Court in a daylight attack which raised fears of reprisals by their Protestant Loyalist foes.</p>
<p>Loyalists, who want Northern Ireland to stay British, have maintained a ceasefire since October 1994 but say their activists want to avenge IRA violence.</p>
<p>Police blame two recent attacks on Loyalists but the British government says it believes the ceasefire is still in place.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
