<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="315633" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: PRESS DIGEST - Canada - January 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Canada - January 17.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are top headlines from selected Canadian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE GLOBE AND MAIL:</p>
<p>- Canada loses magazine case: World body rules against Ottawa, delivering blow to efforts to guard cultural sector.</p>
<p>- Quebec suicide rate reaches record: Demographers point to deaths of baby-boom men, links to economy, referendum.</p>
<p>- Teen dies in burning Toronto school bus: Appalled witnesses turn on firefighters.</p>
<p>- Military braces for more bad news: Reports due today on Bosnia incidents.</p>
<p>- Market-value assessment halts 'free ride,' Eves says: Property tax overhaul will hurt some, Ontario concedes.</p>
<p>- C$36,000 MBA tuition proposed: Western Ontario wants students to pay full cost of program.</p>
<p>Report on Business Section:</p>
<p>- Placer Dome prodded in Bre-X bid: Key Indonesian businessman encouraged company to get more bidders interested in huge gold play.</p>
<p>- Sportmart strikes out in Canada: U.S. sporting goods retailer shutting stores and leaving country as too many chains crowd market.</p>
<p>- Corel road show falls short: Software firm fails to steal thunder from Microsoft's launch.</p>
<p>- Plan to hide GST may be in jeopardy: Retailers reject Atlantic pricing scheme.</p>
<p>- Deal puts USA Waste on top of Canadian heap.</p>
<p>THE FINANCIAL POST:</p>
<p>- Canada loses magazine battle: WTO panel rules in favor of U.S. in trade dispute over 'split-run' edition of Sports Illustrated.</p>
<p>- Frame returns to mining, may make bid for Anvil Range.</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
