<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="315794" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Mercedes to up truck output slightly in 97.</title>
<headline>Mercedes to up truck output slightly in 97.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mercedes-Benz AG's commercial vehicles division will increase production slightly this year after posting a nine percent rise in worldwide unit sales, truck division director Kurt Lauk said on Friday.</p>
<p>Speaking at a truck fair in Brussels, Lauk said he expected production to exceed 350,000 units this year. Sales of vans, trucks, buses and Unimog utility vehicles rose by nine percent last year to 348,200 units.</p>
<p>&quot;We achieved record unit sales in 1996 for the second year running,&quot; Lauk said in extracts released from his speech. He added that Mercedes had kept its global lead in trucks over six tonnes and coaches over eight tonnes gross weight.</p>
<p>A copy of his speech was distributed to the media in Germany.</p>
<p>However, while unit sales hit a record, a disproportionate increase in demand for vans cause revenues to slip slightly in 1996 to 31.5 billion marks from 31.6 billion.</p>
<p>Looking forward, Lauk said the launch of a new range of light trucks in 1998 would complement recent gains in van sales and lay the basis for a return to profitability throughout the commercial vehicles business by the end of the decade.</p>
<p>&quot;The vans division has already shown what can be done with trucks. We aim to be every bit as successful on the trucks side,&quot; Lauk said.</p>
<p>He said Mercedes had profited last year from growth in the west European van market, with market share in the below six tonnes category rising to 15 percent from 13 percent, led by the new Sprinter van.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a clear turnaround in our van business,&quot; Lauk said.</p>
<p>Trucks over six tonnes won a west European market share of almost 23 percent in 1996, down from 24.8 percent, with competitors offering newer models. Lauk predicted good sales of the new Actros product, with its emphasis on safety and plans for it to run on clean fuels like electricity and natural gas.</p>
<p>European bus operations boosted sales of the Mercedes-Benz and Setra brands by 22 percent. Overseas markets accounted for 40 percent of bus revenues.</p>
<p>Lauk said that Mercedes-Benz would continue to boost its efficiency, even though a slide in foreign exchange rates had wiped out some cost savings already achieved.</p>
<p>He also said German labour costs were a problem: &quot;We need a steady improvement in our cost structures and an optimisation of our business processes. I pin my hopes on evolution and our ability to release still dormant potential in these plants.&quot;</p>
<p>Over half of planned investment for 1997 of 1.2 billion marks will go towards boosting efficiency at German plants.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, global planning and control will be sharpened to cope with increasing regionalisation of markets. Strict cash flow and a focus to operating profits will be the main elements of new controlling systems to be introduced this spring.</p>
<p>Lauk said overseas markets would increase in importance. He expected the Latin American market to grow by 60 percent in the next decade, while western Europe would grow by 20 percent.</p>
<p>The Asian commercial vehicle is set to double in the next decade, and Lauk said action was needed to increase regional penetration. Meanwhile, Turkey will be used as a bridgehead to eastern Europe and Russian markets.</p>
<p>Lauk's speech made no mention of the departure of Mercedes chief executive Helmut Werner resulting from the reintegration of the auto unit into parent Daimler-Benz AG.</p>
<p>-- Bonn newsroom, 49-228-26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
