<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="315822" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: British beef not on Council menu.</title>
<headline>British beef not on Council menu.</headline>
<byline>Peter Blackburn</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>For the first time in many months, a worldwide ban on British beef exports will not be on the agenda at a low-key meeting on Monday of European Union farm ministers, EU diplomats said.</p>
<p>But ministers will receive a progress report at the half-day meeting, their first in 1997, on proposals to introduce cattle passports and beef labels, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is nothing sufficiently important now to justify raising it (the ban) at (EU Farm) Council level,&quot; said one diplomat, noting that Britain submits fortnightly progress reports to the EU's executive European Commission.</p>
<p>The next step in Britain's campaign to lift the ban will be British farm minister Douglas Hogg's presentation, possibly at the end of January, of a plan to exempt certified herds from the embargo.</p>
<p>The EU imposed the export ban in March 1996 after the British government caused consumer panic by disclosing that the disease, known as Bovine Spongiform Encephalopathy (BSE), could be transmitted to humans as Creutzfeldt Jakob Disease CJD).</p>
<p>Most BSE cases, about 165,000, have been reported in Britain.</p>
<p>Northern Irish grass-fed herds, which are tracked from birth by a computerised system, are likely to be the first to be exempted from the ban, officials said.</p>
<p>But they said the British proposals would first have to be examined by various EU scientific and multidisciplinary committees before being sent to the European Commission for approval and this could take several months.</p>
<p>Diplomats said Dutch Farm Minister, Jozias Van Aartsen, whose country took over the EU presidency on January 1, is expected to tell ministers on Monday that the proposals for cattle passports and beef labels, aimed at restoring consumer confidence, needed more work.</p>
<p>&quot;Progress has been made but details, such as whether cattle passport and a computer data base are both needed, still have to be settled,&quot; said a Dutch official.</p>
<p>Several member states are pressing for EU financial aid in setting up computerised systems to identify cattle and track their movements and have complained that the January 1998 deadline is too early.</p>
<p>Under this plan it would be compulsory for all cattle to wear ear tags and have passports and for farmers to keep up-to- date registers.</p>
<p>On beef labelling, countries are split over whether this should be voluntary or compulsory and what details -- such as birthplace, feeding and slaughtering -- should be included.</p>
<p>Various countries, including Germany, France and Britain, are pressing for an early agreement, possibly in February, to reassure consumers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
