<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="315936" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: UN backs immunity of Malaysian rights investigator.</title>
<headline>UN backs immunity of Malaysian rights investigator.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations said on Friday it would insist on the immunity from prosecution of one of its human rights investigators who faces a libel suit in Malaysia.</p>
<p>The Geneva-based International Commission of Jurists (ICJ) said two Malaysian companies had filed a $25 million civil suit against Dato Param Cumaraswamy, a Malaysian, who serves as U.N. special rapporteur on the independence of judges and lawyers.</p>
<p>ICJ said the case began in November 1995 when Cumaraswamy was quoted in a London publication, International Commercial Litigation, as saying he was checking complaints that highly- placed businessmen were manipulating Malaysia's judicial system.</p>
<p>&quot;The United Nations has taken steps to assert the immunity of Mr. Cumaraswamy and is in the process of dealing with the matter,&quot; U.N. spokeswoman Therese Gastaut told a news briefing.</p>
<p>She declined to give further details.</p>
<p>But diplomats said that the United Nations in New York had reminded Malaysian officials that U.N. special rapporteurs were immune from legal action under the 1946 Convention on Privileges and Immunities of the United Nations.</p>
<p>The ICJ and the Centre for the Independence of Judges and Lawyers expressed deep concern last week that despite the immunity granted Cumaraswamy under the Convention, a suit had been filed by two companies before the High Court of Malaysia.</p>
<p>&quot;The Plaintiffs claim damages equivalent to approximately $25 million against the Special Rapporteur,&quot; according to the ICJ, a group of some 45 jurists.</p>
<p>Cumaraswamy is due to report to the U.N. Commission on Human Rights which opens its annual six-week session in March.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
