<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="315958" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek seamen extend strike to Tuesday.</title>
<headline>Greek seamen extend strike to Tuesday.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Striking Greek seamen, who have kept most cargo and passenger ships docked for the past five days, said on Friday they would extend their strike for another four days.</p>
<p>&quot;The strike was extended to Tuesday morning. Our struggle continues until the government satisfies our demands,&quot; a seamen's union representative told reporters.</p>
<p>The strike, which affects all ships with Greek crews, had been due to end early on Friday.</p>
<p>Police have reported minor clashes in ports around the country between passengers, lorry drivers and the striking seamen, who are pressing for better insurance, pension and tax benefits.</p>
<p>A telephone recording at the main port of Piraeus informed callers that no ships were sailing because of the strike.</p>
<p>Talks between the Panhellenic Seamen's Federation (PNO) and merchant marine ministry officials on Thursday were unsuccessful, union representatives said.</p>
<p>Owners of passenger ships have tried to declare the strike illegal and a court decision was expected later on Friday or on Saturday.</p>
<p>Civil aviation employees, pushing to maintain tax breaks which the government plans to abolish, also called for two four-hour stoppages on Friday and Sunday.</p>
<p>Airport officials said many local and international flights would be delayed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
