<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="315919" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: No cabinet action today on Italy's Stet.</title>
<headline>No cabinet action today on Italy's Stet.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A meeting of the Italian cabinet that was taking place on Friday will not discuss measures to transfer telecom holding Stet to the Treasury, a government source said.</p>
<p>Political sources said previously that the meeting, which began at 0900 GMT, could discuss relevant measures after the government suffered a surprise parliamentary defeat on the transfer plan on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing is being done about Stet&quot; at the cabinet meeting, the source said.</p>
<p>La Repubblica newspaper quoted cabinet undersecretary Enrico Micheli as saying measures would be considered at a forthcoming meeting of ministers.</p>
<p>&quot;The defeat of the plan leaves only some collateral aspects uncovered. These will be dealt with by an ad hoc provision...which could be approved at a forthcoming cabinet meeting,&quot; Micheli said.</p>
<p>The Treasury said last month it would pay at least 14.53 trillion lire to state holding IRI to take over its controlling stake in Stet ahead of its planned privatisation.</p>
<p>The government narrowly lost the vote in the lower house of parliament on the transfer by 230 to 234 with 26 abstentions.</p>
<p>The Treasury wants full control of Stet because it fears foot-dragging by IRI managers will hold up its privatisation. The move also allows the government to fulfil a commitment to slash IRI's huge debt.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi said on Thursday that the defeat would not affect the government's privatisation programme but acknowledged that it was a &quot;political alarm signal&quot;.</p>
<p>The hardline party Communist Refoundation, which ensures the government's majority in parliament, abstained on the vote, contributing to the defeat and raising strains in the alliance.</p>
<p>-- Rome newsroom +396 6782501</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
