<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="316190" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan mourns past disaster, juggles two new ones.</title>
<headline>Japan mourns past disaster, juggles two new ones.</headline>
<byline>Paul Eckert</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ghosts of crises past on Friday mingled with anxiety about present emergencies as Japan marked the second anniversary of the Kobe earthquake while juggling a hostage stalemate in Peru and its worst-ever oil spill.</p>
<p>If the solemn face of Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto as he mourned the 6,425 earthquake dead was a superficial link to the three natural and man-made events, a deeper connection was the poor marks Japanese have given their government in a series of crisis management tests.</p>
<p>From fishermen whose livelihood is threatened by oil slicks from a wrecked Russian tanker to former prime ministers critical of Hashimoto's performance in the Peru hostage crisis, the question is the same: Why does the government always appear overwhelmed by emergencies?</p>
<p>On the fateful morning of the earthquake, then prime minister Tomiichi Murayama was not awakened for the first two hours of the crisis and then squandered precious hours before calling in troops to help relief operations.</p>
<p>For appearing to fiddle while Kobe burned, the unassuming Murayama became an unwitting symbol of Japan's rudderlessness and institutional fatigue.</p>
<p>Hashimoto, who replaced Murayama in January 1996, was welcomed in Japan and around the world as a take-charge executive who would stop the paralysis.</p>
<p>But the two present back-to-back crises have exposed management deficiencies and left Hashimoto open to public criticism and media ridicule.</p>
<p>As the two incidents wear on, widespread sympathy for the prime minister in the face of the unpredictable events has given way to dismay at miscues and delayed responses.</p>
<p>&quot;Can we entrust matters to the bean bun prime minister?&quot; asked the Sunday Mainichi weekly magazine in a shot at Hashimoto's gesture of personally handing 130 Japanese sweets to the Foreign Ministry task force monitoring the Peru crisis.</p>
<p>The magazine quoted experts and former leaders as saying the widely televised gesture, while clearly well-meant, probably signalled to the hostage-takers that Hashimoto had no idea what to do.</p>
<p>&quot;The chief executive of state should not be doing things like personally buying and delivering sweets,&quot; former prime minister Tsutomu Hata was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;Ordinarily, it's nice for the prime minister to mix with the public, but in emergencies he should hunker down and take a more dignified stance.&quot;</p>
<p>As an oil spill covered ever wider areas of Japan's western coast, criticism emerged at a slow government reaction, including the Transport Ministry's waiting eight days after the Russian ship went down in early January before setting up a task force.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't see how authorities failed to take action earlier on the oil slick beyond monitoring the situation,&quot; grumbled a fisherman in Maizuru, a Sea of Japan port city at the centre of the country's worst-ever oil spill disaster.</p>
<p>In a parliamentary committee this week, Hashimoto, facing withering opposition attacks at the government response to the oil spill, said he would &quot;humbly accept criticism that the response was slow&quot;.</p>
<p>Analysts say the crisis management shortcomings stem from systemic factors, such as a prime minister's office that is weak by constitutional design, a parliament elected mainly on parochial issues and which fails to produce leaders with broad vision, and a consensus-based decision-making process geared for long-term solutions, not on-the-spot problem solving.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
