<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="316397" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan Dec money growth due to slow fund demand.</title>
<headline>Japan Dec money growth due to slow fund demand.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's money supply growth of 3.2 percent in December was largely a reflection of continued sluggishness in capital demand, economists said on Friday.</p>
<p>They said growth in money supply may stay below 4.0 percent unless bank lending increases significantly in line with a recovery in the economy.</p>
<p>The Bank of Japan (BOJ) said earlier on Friday that Japan's broadly defined money supply average of M2 plus certificates of deposit (M2+CDs) grew a preliminary 3.2 percent year-on-year in December, compared with growth of a revised 3.3 percent in November.  </p>
<p>The 3.2 percent growth was at the lower end of what economists had expected of between 3.2 and 3.5 percent.</p>
<p>A BOJ official said after the release of the data that money supply growth weakened in December from the previous month, mainly because of a decline in growth of bank CD issues. Another reason for the slower growth was that some funds had flown into money management funds, he said.</p>
<p>Commenting on M2+CDs growth of a preliminary 3.4 percent year-on-year in the October-December period, the BOJ official told reporters: &quot;That was within the BOJ's forecast of between 3.0 and 3.9 percent and was in line with the bank's view that the economy has been recovering gradually.&quot;  </p>
<p>Bank CD issues slowed in December despite seasonal year-end fund-raising demand because of the widespread view in the money market that Japanese interest rates will stay at their current low levels for the near future, economists said.</p>
<p>But they said slower money growth in December was not only because of special factors like CD issues but also because fund demand had remained inactive.</p>
<p>&quot;A decline in money growth in December from the previous month largely reflected a decrease in year-on-year growth in lending by banks,&quot; said Yasuhiko Ushikubo, an economist in the research division at the Industrial Bank of Japan.  </p>
<p>Capital investment will remain idle in the near future, keeping money growth at around 3.5 percent, Ushikubo said.</p>
<p>Other economists said slowness in private spending may also keep money supply growth below 4.0 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Money supply growth may stay between 3.0 and 3.4 percent for the time being due to lagging private spending. Another factor keeping money growth low is that activity in the stock markets is expected to remain dull,&quot; said Hiroshi Miyazaki, economist at Yamaichi Research Institute.</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-33432-8570</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
