<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="316432" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Gulf still tense on war's sixth anniversary.</title>
<headline>Gulf still tense on war's sixth anniversary.</headline>
<byline>Ashraf Fouad</byline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Six years ago the West's finest warplanes launched the Gulf War with punishing strikes on Iraq, now diplomats and analysts say Washington might next use its air superiority against Iran.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't believe a strike is imminent...But it remains a possibility in the medium term,&quot; said a well-placed Arab source. &quot;Many in the Gulf see a growing potential for a military clash between the United States and the region's 'superpower'.&quot;</p>
<p>Washington, as part of its &quot;dual containment&quot; policy on Iran and Iraq, has maintained a large military presence in the Gulf to deter potential threats to its Arab allies by Tehran and Baghdad since driving Iraqi troops from Kuwait in 1991.</p>
<p>Defence experts say a strike against Iran is one U.S. option if Tehran is accused of a direct role in a bombing in Saudi Arabia last June that killed 19 U.S. airmen.</p>
<p>&quot;If they accuse Iran and do nothing about it Saudi and America will look weak,&quot; said an Arab analyst.</p>
<p>Tehran has not been officially linked to the bombing but U.S. officials and Gulf Arab sources have hinted at a connection. Iran has always denied any role in the attack.</p>
<p>Washington says any decision on an air strike against Iran is premature because Riyadh has yet to make public the outcome of its investigation into the June bombing.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Saudi investigation says Iran was directly involved I do not think America will hesitate to retaliate,&quot; said an analyst.</p>
<p>U.S. HAS POWER TO ATTACK, BUT IRAN COULD STRIKE BACK</p>
<p>U.S. officials have emphasised Washington is prepared to go to war if its Gulf Arab allies are threatened. It sent extra troops and hardware, including eight radar-evading stealth bombers, to Kuwait last September during Washington's most recent confrontation with Iraq.</p>
<p>The war against Iraq was launched on January 17, 1991 -- two days after a U.N. deadline for Baghdad's withdrawal from Kuwait expired. Millions around the world watched on television as smart bombs destroyed key Iraqi targets.</p>
<p>&quot;Iran is not Iraq,&quot; cautioned one regional analyst. &quot;Washington has to consider many things like Iran's missile capability, terrorist retaliation, oil supplies, possible minority unrest in Gulf Arab states, international support and other matters.&quot;</p>
<p>One defence expert said any U.S. strike would probably avoid Iranian crude oil production and export terminals for fear of sharply raising world oil prices. But targets could include refinery facilities to force Tehran to import more of its strategic needs.</p>
<p>Iran has said it does not expect Washington to seek a confrontation that could jeopardise regional oil exports.</p>
<p>GULF SPECULATION ABOUT U.S. ATTACK ON IRAN</p>
<p>Talk of a possible strike against Iran has been circulating in the Gulf for several weeks. This month the chairman of the U.S. Joint Chiefs of Staff, General John Shalikashvili, toured the region.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't see what could be in common between these countries except the Iran situation...There is something on the front burner,&quot; said a Western diplomat of Shalikashvili's talks with the leaders of Washington's main regional allies Egypt, Saudi Arabia and Israel.</p>
<p>Diplomatic sources said Riyadh believed some suspects held in connection with the bombing were trained in Lebanon by the pro-Iranian Hizbollah and also went to Iran before the attack.</p>
<p>Some of the six Gulf Arab states -- Bahrain, Kuwait, Oman, Qatar, Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates -- see a potential threat from Iran and its brand of Islam. In recent months they have changed their often cautious tone when addressing Iran.</p>
<p>Even Iran's closest Arab ally Syria joined the six states and Egypt in December in accusing Tehran of threatening Gulf Arab countries by deploying missiles.</p>
<p>Although Iran and Saudi Arabia appear almost equal in amount of military hardware, the Islamic republic has 600,000 people on active duty, four times as many as Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>But Riyadh's high-tech weaponry is far superior to that of Iran. Although Iran has succeeded in recent years in buying arms from Russia, China and North Korea, much of its arsenal is antiquated equipment bought by the pro-Western Shah before the 1979 revolution.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
