<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="316514" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Lacroix turns 10, hopes for profits in 1999.</title>
<headline>Lacroix turns 10, hopes for profits in 1999.</headline>
<byline>Lee Yanowitch</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The house of Christian Lacroix turns 10 this year and although the flamboyant designer is immensely popular with the critics, he has yet to turn a profit.</p>
<p>Despite talk that Lacroix's boss Bernard Arnault, chairman of luxury goods giant LVMH, is about to pull the plug, Lacroix keeps on turning out his opulent, extravagant creations of chantilly, chiffon, taffeta and organza.</p>
<p>&quot;Making this house profitable would be the easiest thing in the world. We shut the faucet, stop investments, and in three years we're finished,&quot; Lacroix chairman Robert Bensoussan said.</p>
<p>He was brought in from Germany's Escada in 1993 to improve the balance sheet and set a strategy at Lacroix, reported to be losing as much as $5 million a year in the early 1990s.</p>
<p>Bensoussan said he expects the house to be profitable within two years. He said losses were narrowing, but declined to disclose the amount.</p>
<p>Sales rose 50 percent in 1995 from the previous year and grew another 20 percent in 1996 to 400 million francs ($80 million), he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The lack of profit is a constant worry, but it's not the only one. Our approach is that of a builder.  We want to last 20, 30, 50 years,&quot; he said. &quot;Arnault is the ideal shareholder. He is aware the company is growing and he recognises talent.&quot;</p>
<p>Bensoussan oversaw the launch of two down-market lines, Bazaar in 1994 and Jeans in 1996, which, with respective sales of 100 million francs ($20 million) and 60 million francs ($12 million), have given Lacroix's accounts a big boost.</p>
<p>Bazaar is manufactured by another LVMH house, Kenzo, as part of Arnault's strategy to wring out synergies from his many brands and lower costs.</p>
<p>A new team has also been hired to develop accessories, which along with Bazaar, are Lacroix's biggest profit-makers.</p>
<p>Dozens of in-store boutiques are opening in Europe and Asia -- 24 of them in Japan -- and the group is also pushing to expand in the United States.</p>
<p>A line of dinner ware, made in cooperation with Cristofle, will be in stores in the spring.</p>
<p>Once the disastrous 1989 launch of &quot;C'est la Vie&quot;, Lacroix's first and only scent, drifts out of the public consciousness, a new perfume is planned. It will be developed by another LVMH firm, and Bensoussan is aiming for a launch by early 1998.</p>
<p>Lacroix's clothes are dazzling to look at but hard to wear. Finding something that works with a persimmon jacket or fuschia and chartreuse plaid slacks is not easy.</p>
<p>A new concept in boutiques and department store corners in which sales people show customers how to put together an outfit seems to have had results.</p>
<p>The couture business has changed radically as houses fight over a shrinking customer base. An estimate by the Chambre Syndicale, fashion's governing body, of 2,500 couture customers is exaggerated, Bensoussan said. He said Lacroix has about 100.</p>
<p>Industry experts estimate the market is about 700 customers, down from several thousand when Christian Dior reigned in the 1950s.</p>
<p>&quot;There won't be any other real couture houses -- Christian Lacroix and Yves Saint Laurent are the only two left,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Hubert de Givenchy learned from Balenciaga, Saint Laurent from Christian Dior...but there's a lack of training, it's not following through to the next generation.&quot;</p>
<p>Spin-off products are the key to financing haute couture, whose primary role is to lend prestige to money-making items.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFAS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
