<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="316527" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FEATURE - Russia trade no aid for Finland's jobless.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Russia trade no aid for Finland's jobless.</headline>
<byline>Roland Moller</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unnoticed by many, fast growth in Russia's western neighbour Finland has in just five years helped restore its once-booming trade with the former Soviet Union to Communist-era levels.</p>
<p>But an already fragile economy has new bruises from that struggle. Joblessness, at one of Europe's highest rates, is a prime legacy of Finland's enforced change of focus, marring its achievement and rekindling political tensions.</p>
<p>Throughout the Cold War, Finland's barter deals with Moscow helped rank Finns among the world's richest peoples. The fall of the USSR was an economic body-blow.</p>
<p>As Finland scratched through years of punishing recession, gross domestic product fell by 12 percent and its exports to the area slumped by two thirds to just 4.4 billion markka ($1 billion) at their lowest point in 1992.</p>
<p>However in 1996, according to Finnish Foreign Trade Association estimates, annual exports to the former Soviet Union rose to 17.4 billion markka -- above the 15 billion average in the 1980s and not far from the 18.2 billion peak of 1983.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now back about where we were,&quot; said Esa Veijalainen, project manager at the association. Also allowing for inflation the value of exports is within the 1980s range.</p>
<p>Finland, which joined the European Union in 1995 in a decisive westward switch, has meanwhile boosted exports to the rest of the world by 70 percent.</p>
<p>The economy is this year expected to show a fourth straight year of growth, at about four percent.</p>
<p>UNEMPLOYMENT IS PERSISTENT</p>
<p>But statistics show the unemployment partly triggered by the collapse of Soviet trade persists, and nobody believes it can be solved as easily.</p>
<p>Joblessness -- a crucial problem across Europe which for some economists is already reducing the credibility of plans for a single currency -- is the second highest in the European Union at more than 15 percent, according to the Finnish statistics office.</p>
<p>Labour ministry data, which economists say is more accurate, shows almost one in four working-age Finns were unemployed or in special schemes at the end of November 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Unemployment is still a very difficult problem,&quot; President Martti Ahtisaari said in a New Year speech. &quot;Though the trend has turned for the better, we cannot be satisfied with the pace of improvement.&quot;</p>
<p>EASTERN EXPORTS GET COMPETITIVE</p>
<p>A key aspect of Finland's restoration of exports to the east is that it has come amid competition. Today's trade has a clearly different face from the barter deals with Moscow, but this has offered scant help to the jobless, economists say.</p>
<p>&quot;This trade is different,&quot; said Jukka Kero, economist at the Central Chamber of Commerce. &quot;It is competitive. The barter trade was for a few massive deals, machines, ice-breakers and building entire cities...and it all went through Moscow.&quot;</p>
<p>Finnish entrepreneurs have also found today's Russian customers more demanding in terms of quality than in the Cold War, when exports were delivered according to the &quot;Plan&quot;.</p>
<p>According to one Western diplomat, the barter system then promoted a lack of competitiveness by Western standards.</p>
<p>Today, Finland's exports to Russia are topped by things like food and fodder, electronics and mobile phones.</p>
<p>Paper and cardboard, which used to be significant, account for less than nine percent and another key Cold War item, industrial machinery, now accounts for just five percent.</p>
<p>Such products show Finland's export industry has adapted to survive by concentrating on less labour-intensive goods.</p>
<p>&quot;Although our eastern trade is staring to be restored to about normal, it has not brought back jobs. Manual labour has been replaced by machinery,&quot; Ahtisaari said.</p>
<p>He said only a sixth of almost half a million jobs lost had been restored.</p>
<p>NEED TO CURB LABOUR COSTS</p>
<p>Exactly how significant Russia was in building Finland's past wealth is often disputed here: contrary to a widely held view abroad, economists insist it is impossible to be sure if the net impact of past Soviet trade was positive or negative.</p>
<p>But they do see casual evidence that some companies depended fully on Soviet business.</p>
<p>One study in the mid-1980s showed an average of six percent of Finns in work had jobs related directly or indirectly to exports to the Soviet Union. And some economists say up to 40 percent of current joblessness is due to communism's collapse.</p>
<p>The former Soviet states today make up a clearly smaller slice of exports than their 1980s peak of around 26 percent, taking around 10 percent of Finland's total last year, according to a Foreign Trade Association estimate.</p>
<p>But Finland's leading export markets -- Germany, Britain and Sweden -- will continue to demand competitive prices.</p>
<p>POLITICAL TENSION MOUNTS</p>
<p>Despite a strong showing abroad, Finland's home markets stayed depressed until late last year and coalition governments have been forced to start scaling down the once-exemplary welfare state.</p>
<p>With cutbacks mounting and unemployment stubborn, political tension is rising. Splits have begun to emerge even in Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen's Social Democratic Party.</p>
<p>Among other worries, this could spell trouble for the government's plan to be among the first to join Europe's single currency in 1999, said Peter Bolt, economist at the influential Central Organisation of Finnish Trade Unions (SAK).</p>
<p>&quot;I think cabinet ministers agree fully on the EMU strategy but things are cracking within the coalition parties,&quot; he said. &quot;This could lead to problems when it comes to a decision in parliament on EMU participation.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
