<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="316529" id="root" date="1997-01-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Bombay shares end tad lower in volatile trade.</title>
<headline>Bombay shares end tad lower in volatile trade.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Speculative selling dragged stock prices lower at Bombay bourses on Friday, with caution ruling the markets after Thursday's wild gyrations, dealers said.</p>
<p>End-of-account trade at the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) put pressure on marketmen to offload huge positions build up in pivotal stocks, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Speculators are unwinding positions...,&quot; said chief dealer Sanjeev Choithani at brokerage Pashupati Advani.</p>
<p>The top 30-share BSE index closed 32.28 points, or 0.93 percent lower at 3,423.60, off 3,580.98 after tumbling 191 points or over five percent on Thursday.</p>
<p>The sharp price volatility prompted the Securities &amp; Exchange Board of India (SEBI) to convene a closed-door meeting with the chiefs of major exchanges on Friday to find ways to rein in excessive speculation.</p>
<p>The Economic Times newspaper quoted SEBI chairman D.R. Mehta as saying the regulator would not interfere with the market movements but would ensure all surveillance and monitoring systems were in order.</p>
<p>Optimism that the government was preparing moves to reverse slowing industrial growth and to jump-start markets ignited heavy speculative bidding in blue chip stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;Some sort of correction was necessary to make the market healthier. We are likely to see institutional interest at lower levels,&quot; said Maulik Sharedalal member-broker of the BSE.</p>
<p>&quot;By and large the market has been driven by huge trading volumes,&quot; he said. The 50-stock National Stock Exchange index fell 9.80 points, or 0.97 percent, at a provisional 999.60.</p>
<p>ACC dropped 154.75 rupees to 1,423.0, MTNL 12.20 to 234.0, ITC 4.75 to 395.0 and TELCO 8.25 to 336.75. Some stocks however ended in positive territory. SBI rose 9.0 rupees to 278.0, TISCO 1.0 to 190.0 and Reliance 3.50 to 238.50.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
