<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="316683" id="root" date="1997-01-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-MILAN DENY REPORTS OF ILLEGAL PAYMENTS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MILAN DENY REPORTS OF ILLEGAL PAYMENTS.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-01-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian club AC Milan denied media reports on Saturday that the club had made illegal payments to some of its star players in exchange for the rights to use their image for marketing purposes.</p>
<p>Italian media reported on Saturday that magistrates trying Milan owner and former prime minister Silvio Berlusconi for alleged graft had obtained documents which appeared to detail the payments to top players.</p>
<p>The reports said the documents were obtained by magistrates who are trying Berlusconi for his role in an alleged illegal payment of 10 billion lire ($6.5 million) to former premier Bettino Craxi through an off-shore company linked to his Fininvest business empire.</p>
<p>Milan managing director Adriano Galliani told reporters that the allegations were ridiculous.</p>
<p>&quot;The real problem is that a club like Milan is always in the news, whatever story is being told, and for the press this story is just too tasty,&quot; he said, adding: &quot;Milan have always made legal payments.&quot;</p>
<p>Most Italian newspapers said on Saturday that the documents detailed a list of leading Milan players, whose names were written in code, with a U.S. dollar figure written next to them.</p>
<p>The money was allegedly paid under the table to the players for the rights to use their images for marketing purposes.</p>
<p>The players named by the papers included captain Franco Baresi, Italy captain Paolo Maldini, Montenegrin Dejan Savicevic, former Milan player Jean-Pierre Papin of France, Italy's Stefano Eranio and former Milan winger Gianluigi Lentini, now with Atalanta.</p>
<p>Milan's former trio of Dutch stars, Ruud Gullit, Frank Rijkaard and Marco Van Basten, were also said to be on the list.</p>
<p>The reports said the players were not officially under investigation and it was not immediately clear whether the documents would be allowed to be part of the trial, which opened in Milan last November.</p>
<p>Letini's code name apparently had the biggest figure next to it -- $15 million -- while the other figures were between $300,000 and $3 million.</p>
<p>Both Baresi and Eranio were quoted by La Repubblica as denying the allegations.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't say anything about this because I know absolutely nothing about it,&quot; Baresi said.</p>
<p>&quot;I can safely say that I have never received anything under the table...I can only say that my pay is well-known and is registered at the professional league in Milan,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The reports said the documents also contained names of athletes belonging to other Milan sports teams owned by Berlusconi, including a volleyball and ice hockey squad.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
