<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="316755" id="root" date="1997-01-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian Socialist dissidents discuss rival party.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian Socialist dissidents discuss rival party.</headline>
<byline>Thalia Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-01-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dissidents from Bulgaria's Socialist party met to discuss forming a rival leftist coalition on Saturday as the ruling party insisted on forming a new government despite a 13th day of mass protests.</p>
<p>With the government and opposition as far apart as ever on the timing of a general election, opposition deputies said they were hoping that, if the Socialists formed a new cabinet, enough deputies would vote against it to force dissolution of parliament and a quick election.</p>
<p>National radio reported protests, rallies and concerts in a score of towns around the country to demonstrate against economic misery and for general elections not constitutionally required for almost another two years.</p>
<p>The New Left in Bulgaria coalition, proposed by the Bulgarian Socialist Party (BSP) reformist wing and a small, liberal Marxist party, would bring together prominent BSP reformers and representatives of other leftist organisations, as well as four deputies who left the BSP on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I am here because of an illusion and because of a dream,&quot; Socialist deputy Nikolai Kamov, head of parliament's foreign affairs committee, told the meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;The illusion is that the BSP is able to evolve to accept the values and political practices of the European Left...My dream was that children born around 1989 would be able to get European passports when they turned 18.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the next week will be decisive for the development of Bulgaria. I have heard many reasonable ideas here. If we can come together from the left and the right, we shall succeed.&quot;</p>
<p>The BSP is made up largely of former communists who renamed the party after the end of one-party rule in 1989.</p>
<p>Minority ethnic Turks rallied in the southeastern town of Kardzhali, Gypsies protested in Stara Zagora, and a cavalcade of taxis blocked the streets of the the Danube town of Rousse on Saturday.</p>
<p>Staff of state television said on Friday they were joining the unrest to protest at government censorship.</p>
<p>President-elect Petar Stoyanov, who will be sworn in on Sunday, says he might offer the Socialists the new ruling mandate denied them by his predecessor Zhelyu Zhelev.</p>
<p>The opposition Union of Democratic Forces (UDF) adamantly opposes any new mandate, demanding general elections which the Socialists, registering a mere eight percent support in one opinion poll, would be almost certain to lose.</p>
<p>Diplomats say delaying elections would aid the Socialists if polls were held after a new International Monetary Fund (IMF) accord and reforms began to bear fruit.</p>
<p>The IMF said it would complete talks on a tight monetary regime with a new government as soon as it was formed.</p>
<p>The collapsing lev currency fell to new lows below 700 to the dollar on the interbank market on Friday.</p>
<p>The UDF said on Friday it would give parliament a &quot;few more days&quot; to approve its &quot;Salvation Declaration&quot; calling for elections and a strict monetary regime approved by the IMF, before stepping up the pressure by calling a general strike.</p>
<p>Government officials appeared nervous that the president-elect's inauguration could be a flashpoint for a showdown like one a week ago when protesters ransacked parliament and clashes with police left 196 injured.</p>
<p>The Socialists said talks with the opposition could resume after Stoyanov becomes president. The opposition is boycotting parliament but says it will attend his inauguration.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
