<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="316717" id="root" date="1997-01-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Rugby union-Venditti hat-trick sinks Ireland.</title>
<headline>Rugby union-Venditti hat-trick sinks Ireland.</headline>
<byline>Damien Lynch</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-01-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three tries by left-wing David Venditti and another from centre Thomas Castaignede saw France come from behind and beat a determined Ireland 32-15 in their opening Five Nations Championship match at Lansdowne Road on Saturday.</p>
<p>The boot of recalled fly-half Eric Elwood, whose five penalties supplied all his side's points, enabled Ireland to be very much in contention for the first hour and, in fact, briefly hold a 15-12 lead.</p>
<p>But in the last 20 minutes, France's attacking flair told and the Irish defence wilted as Venditti ran in his second and third tries.</p>
<p>Coach Ian Ashton said Ireland were beaten because they had tried to be too adventurous over the final 20 minutes and the French had made them pay dearly for their errors.</p>
<p>&quot;For 60 minutes we competed remarkably well. Unfortunately, test rugby matches last 80 minutes and in the last 20 we lost our shape. We took our foot off the pedal and they came back at us,&quot; Ashton said.</p>
<p>French coach Jean-Claude Skrela said his side had given the ball away too often and he added that France had a lot of work to do with their overall game.</p>
<p>France took control of the game in the 61st minute after Venditti went over for his second try in the left corner, which Castaignede converted to make it 19-15.</p>
<p>Castaignede landed two late penalties before Venditti completed his hat-trick in the dying moments, with Castaignede again converting to maintain France's good record against the Irish.</p>
<p>The French last lost to France at Lansdowne Road in 1983.</p>
<p>Ireland had dominated play for a period after Elwood put them 15-12 ahead. The fly-half, who last played for Ireland a year ago, had kept his side in contention in the first half by landing four out of five penalties.</p>
<p>France had led 12-6 after 32 minutes through tries by scrum-half Fabien Galthie, which centre Thomas Castaignede converted, and Venditti.</p>
<p>France had both second-row forward Olivier Merle and number eight Fabien Pelous shown yellow cards just before the interval as the Irish, with their supporters roaring them on, pressurised their opponents line.</p>
<p>Ireland suffered a further blow to their Five Nations hopes when captain Keith Wood was forced to leave the field with a dislocated left shoulder shortly before the interval.</p>
<p>Wood, who was out of the game for over a year after dislocating his right shoulder during the 1995 World Cup in South Africa, is likely to miss Ireland's game against Wales on February 1.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not too bad an injury. I will be out for anything between two and six weeks,&quot; the Irish hooker said.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Ireland - 15-Conor O'Shea; 14-James Topping, 13-Jonathan Bell, 12-Maurice Field (16-Kurt McQuilkin, 50), 11-Dominic Crotty; 10-Eric Elwood, 9-Niall Hogan; 8-Eric Miller, 7-Denis McBride, 6-David Corkery, 5-Jeremy Davidson, 4-Paddy Johns, 3-Paul Wallace, 2-Keith Woods (Captain)(21-Allen Clarke, 38), 1-Nick Popplewell (20-Paul Flavin, 80).</p>
<p>France - 15-Jean-Luc Sadourny; 14-Emile Ntamack, 13-Stephane Glas, 12-Thomas Castaignede, 11-David Venditti; 10-Alain Penaud, 9-Fabien Galthie (18-Philippe Carbanneau, 43); 8-Fabien Pelous, 7-Philippe Benetton, 6-Abdel Benazzi (Captain), 5-Hugues Miorin (19-Richard Castel, 60), 4-Olivier Merle, 3-Franck Tournaire, 2-Marc Dal Maso, 1-Christian Califano.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
