<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="316853" id="root" date="1997-01-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China central banker urges loans to private firms.</title>
<headline>China central banker urges loans to private firms.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-01-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>China central bank governor Dai Xianglong has called on banks to give equal treatment to both state-owned enterprises and private companies when extending loans.</p>
<p>The emphasis for banks should be on giving high priority to the quality of loan granting, said Dai, head of the People's Bank of China.</p>
<p>&quot;I dislike such terms as 'state-owned' or 'private' while talking about giving loans,&quot; the Xinhua news agency quoted Dai as telling officials of the Agricultural Bank of China on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The top concern should not be the nature of an enterprise, but the quality of loaning,&quot; he was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>He urged state banks to give loans in line with regulations, but added that there were indeed bigger risks for banks when granting loans to smaller firms.</p>
<p>&quot;It is more safe for banks to give loans to private enterprises that are operating well, while banks should not lend to enterprises that are on the brink of bankruptcy, no matter whether they are state-owned or private,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
