<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="316934" id="root" date="1997-01-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. West Coast refiners start maintenance early.</title>
<headline>U.S. West Coast refiners start maintenance early.</headline>
<byline>David Brinkerhoff</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-01-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast refiners got an early start to a planned maintenance season expected to cut five percent of the nation's capacity this spring, trade sources and analysts said.</p>
<p>With the shutdown of Tosco's Avon, Calif., plant, this week, refiners in the West joined what analysts expect to become a heavy schedule of shutdowns in at least some parts of the country.</p>
<p>&quot;The level will be extremely high for this time of year,&quot; said Paul Ting, petroleum analyst for Salomon Brothers. &quot;The West Coast is starting earlier.&quot;  </p>
<p>A sharp year-on-year decline of heating oil stocks in the third and fourth quarters of 1996 and soaring prices for the product pushed back maintenance, leaving refiners around the country scrambling to shore up their plants before summer gasoline demand begins.</p>
<p>About half the 600,000 barrels-per-day (bpd) of lost capacity will come on the West Coast, Ting said.</p>
<p>Tosco, Chevron, and Mobil plan January shutdowns to conduct scheduled maintenance on key sections of their refineries.  </p>
<p>Refinery officials, citing policy, declined comment on maintenance or were not available.</p>
<p>Refineries are also taking downtime to cut losses sustained during an &quot;intense market competition,&quot; during the fourth quarter, Ting said.</p>
<p>California refining margins averaged $4.40 per barrel in the fourth quarter 1996 versus $7.01 in the third quarter.</p>
<p>Planned spring turnarounds include:</p>
<p>-- Chevron crude unit at its 225,000 bpd El Segundo, Calif., refinery for two weeks starting in January.  </p>
<p>-- Chevron rhenaformer, TKN, and A-train units at 225,000 bpd Richmond, Calif., refinery for two weeks starting February 10.</p>
<p>-- Tosco's 42,000 coker, at its 160,000 bpd Avon, Calif., refinery for three weeks starting January 14.</p>
<p>-- Tosco will shut most units at its 95,000 bpd Ferndale, Wash., refinery for three weeks starting in March.</p>
<p>-- Exxon will shut half its 130,000 bpd refinery in Benecia, Calif., from early February through mid-March.</p>
<p>-- Mobil 130,000 bpd crude unit at 130,000 bpd refinery in Torrance, Calif., for three weeks starting late January.  </p>
<p>-- Texaco's 136,000 bpd, Anacortes, Wash., refinery plans to shut its crude unit for a two week turnaround in February.</p>
<p>((David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles bureau +1 213 380 2014))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
