<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="317131" id="root" date="1997-01-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian dairy farmers block roads to Milan airport.</title>
<headline>Italian dairy farmers block roads to Milan airport.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-01-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian farmers blocked streets leading to Milan's Linate airport with tractors and cows on Saturday, protesting at a draft law they say does not compensate them enough for milk output cuts imposed by the European Union.</p>
<p>&quot;People are calling us from all over Italy, wanting to take part in the protest...people keep arriving,&quot; protest leader Aldo Bettinelli told reporters.</p>
<p>More than 1,000 farmers took part in the demonstrations, forcing air passengers coming from the centre of the city to walk three km (two miles) to reach the international airport.</p>
<p>It was the third day of protests in the northern Italian city and the second day running that Milan's main airport was blocked.</p>
<p>Dairy farmers are protesting at a government draft law drawn up to establish compensatiion in the wake of tough EU quotas.</p>
<p>They said the bill fell short of their demands for the state to help bear the burden of EU &quot;super levy&quot; fines for overproduction. The farmers were due to discuss the matter with Agriculture Ministry officials later on Saturday.</p>
<p>Media reports say Italian farmers face 420 billion lire ($270 million) in EU fines for overproduction. Estimates from member states place Italy as the worst offender for exceeding its national quota.</p>
<p>Late last year, an EU Commission official said milk production in the 15-member bloc was 1.1 million tonnes over quota, with Italy accounting for 470,000 tonnes, nearly half.</p>
<p>The fines hit individual farmers and not the state. Farmers want the government to ensure that they do not have to shoulder the full burden themselves.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
