<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="317282" id="root" date="1997-01-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Horlick met ABN AMRO friend for lunch -spokesman.</title>
<headline>Horlick met ABN AMRO friend for lunch -spokesman.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former top MGAM fund manager Nicola Horlick had lunch in December with a friend from ABN AMRO, her spokesman said on Sunday, but he declined to comment on whether business was discussed.</p>
<p>&quot;This was a personal lunch and I cannot confirm whether business was involved,&quot; the spokesman told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;There is absolutely nothing culpable about meeting a friend of yours for lunch. The friend in question had been known to Nicola and her family for many years,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Horlick, 35, was suspended last Tuesday from Deutsche Bank AG's London-based investment bank Deutsche Morgan Grenfell for allegedly trying to lure senior MGAM staff away with her to another bank in London.</p>
<p>ABN AMRO last week denied reports that it tried to poach a team of MGAM fund managers, but the Dutch bank declined to say if it had tried to hire Horlick herself.</p>
<p>Horlick, who resigned her newly-acquired position as Morgan Grenfell Asset Management's managing director on Thursday, alleging &quot;constructive dismissal&quot; by Deutsche Bank, is now seeking either reinstatement or compensation.</p>
<p>On Saturday, the mother-of-five said she wanted the case settled as quickly as possible, and was pinning her hopes on further talks with the senior Deutsche legal representative she met at the bank's Frankfurt headquarters on Friday, who she said had given her a fairer hearing than she had had in London.</p>
<p>Deutsche Morgan Grenfell, which described the Frankfurt meeting as a &quot;courtesy&quot; gesture, responded by insisting that there were no differences between it and its powerful German parent on Horlick's situation.</p>
<p>When contacted by Reuters on Sunday, Horlick directed all queries to her spokesman, saying she did not wish to comment directly at present.</p>
<p>Her spokesman distanced himself from suggestions in many British press reports that Horlick's December lunch meeting marked the start of negotiations with ABN AMRO on a possible move to the Dutch bank.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not believe there were any further talks (between Horlick and ABN AMRO officials after that lunch meeting),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The spokesman also said that the next move in the furore over the woman dubbed &quot;Superwoman&quot; in the City was up to Deutsche Bank itself.</p>
<p>&quot;It is now up to Deutsche to take the matter in hand and I think they will do so,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Horlick remained keen to be reinstated as managing director of Morgan Grenfell Asset Management, a post she was offered just days before her suspension, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nicola has said that her entire loyalty is to MGAM and the job as managing director is the one she always wanted.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
