<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="317341" id="root" date="1997-01-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania opposition wants more anti-govt protests.</title>
<headline>Albania opposition wants more anti-govt protests.</headline>
<byline>Benet Koleka</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-01-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanian opposition parties vowed on Sunday to hold fresh protests against President Sali Berisha's government after police dispersed about 3,000 demonstrators from Tirana's main square.</p>
<p>&quot;We shall continue protests for democracy until this fully anti-democratic regime is overthrown,&quot; Socialist secretary-general Rexhep Mejdani told Reuters.</p>
<p>Earlier a crowd, led by opposition party leaders including Mejdani, pierced police cordons to reach Skanderbeg Square, scene of a 1990 uprising that toppled the communist regime, shouting: &quot;The police are with us, the government is a thief&quot;.</p>
<p>Police officers beat shields with their batons to try to scare demonstrators away from the main boulevard but some struck out at protesters, witnesses said. Some were seen with bloodied faces being led away from square.</p>
<p>&quot;The Socialist Party and all the opposition will not only support these protests but be at the head of them up to the final solution of the political, institutional and economic crisis in the country,&quot; a Socialist Party statement said.</p>
<p>Berisha and his conservative Democratic Party government were severely criticised by foreign governments last May when police beat up opposition leaders, journalists and protesters around Skanderbeg Square in a demonstration against alleged vote rigging by the Democrats in a general election.</p>
<p>State-run television said demonstrators had daubed themselves with red ink to look as if they had been beaten.</p>
<p>&quot;Police have detained some citizens who used red ink in order to seem wounded by police in front of the television cameras,&quot; a television commentary said.</p>
<p>Mejdani said the police had been more restrained than at last year's protests.</p>
<p>&quot;Police forces were much more correct while some elements of special (police) forces were violent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Less than half an hour after Sunday's protest began, plainclothes police intervened as opposition leaders tried to address the throng, smashing their megaphones and holding them back from a platform in the centre of Skanderbeg Square.</p>
<p>Foreign diplomats watched the scene from the balcony of the Hotel Tirana International which overlooks the square.</p>
<p>Within an hour the main crowd had dispersed but hundreds continued to mill around streets fanning out from the square.</p>
<p>The Socialists said about 5,000 people had protested in the town of Fier, 110 km (70 miles) south of Tirana, demanding the resignation of the city mayor. They say he was elected with funds from controversial pyramid investment schemes.</p>
<p>The protest was called by three opposition parties -- the Socialists, centre-right Democratic Alliance and centre-left Social Democrats -- following a week of minor demonstrations against collapsing pyramid investment schemes in which hundreds of people have lost their life savings.</p>
<p>Pyramid schemes boomed in the Balkan nation after the fall of communism in 1990, luring thousands of Albanians into selling homes, land and livestock with promises of big returns.</p>
<p>Three dubious investment groups have collapsed in the past few weeks in Albania, Europe's poorest country. Infuriated investors clashed with police on Wednesday in a demonstration over the investment projects.</p>
<p>Berisha vowed on Saturday to crack down on pyramid investment schemes but warned the opposition against exploiting anger to try to destabilise the ex-communist state.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
