<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="317306" id="root" date="1997-01-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Taiwan, S.Africa start talks on future ties.</title>
<headline>Taiwan, S.Africa start talks on future ties.</headline>
<dateline>PRETORIA 1997-01-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwanese Foreign Minister John Chang said on Sunday patience would be needed in shaping a new relationship with South Africa which is breaking off diplomatic ties in favour of Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a very good meeting,&quot; Chang told a news conference after talks with his South African counterpart Alfred Nzo in Pretoria. &quot;These are the first negotiations on arrangements for our future relations.&quot;</p>
<p>President Nelson Mandela announced in November that South Africa would scrap diplomatic recognition of Taiwan, regarded by Beijing as a renegade province.</p>
<p>Chang said he was optimistic that the two countries would find a solution which would satisfy Taiwanese business leaders who have invested heavily in South Africa and which would enable Taiwan to resume suspended aid projects.</p>
<p>He said the three hours of talks with Nzo were candid, frank, constructive and useful, but added: &quot;We did not reach any concrete conclusions or reasonable consensus on many issues.&quot;</p>
<p>Chang said he had proposed that future relations take into account, among other things, reality, continuity, morality and legality.</p>
<p>&quot;We stated that the present negotiations would be long and both sides had better be patient,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nzo declined to speak to reporters after the meeting but Chang said he believed the South African minister was pleased with the talks.</p>
<p>About 280 Taiwanese factories in South Africa employing 35,000 people have begun a series of one-day stoppages to protest at Pretoria's decision to cut ties by the end of the year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRETORIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
