<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="317446" id="root" date="1997-01-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Lawmaker's fall seen boosting Manila justice image.</title>
<headline>Lawmaker's fall seen boosting Manila justice image.</headline>
<byline>Ruben Alabastro</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-01-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dramatic capture of a Philippine lawmaker facing rape charges has given President Fidel Ramos a big lift in his war on crime but analysts say much more is needed to restore confidence in the legal system.</p>
<p>Congressman Romeo Jalosjos, accused of the statutory rape of an 11-year-old schoolgirl, was arrested by Ramos's elite presidential guards on an island west of Manila on Friday, ending one of the biggest manhunts in the Philippines.</p>
<p>Manila's television networks cut their regular programming to show the congressman, in handcuffs, being led off by his captors.</p>
<p>A court had ordered the arrest of Jalosjos on December 26 but he had fled when police went to his house.</p>
<p>Jalosjos, a member of Ramos's ruling coalition in the House of Representatives, faces two counts of statutory rape and 12 counts of acts of lasciviousness for allegedly having sex with the girl several times in his Manila apartment last year.</p>
<p>He denies the charges and, in a radio interview on Sunday, accused politicians of riding on his case &quot;for the sake of their political ambitions&quot;. He did not name the politicians.</p>
<p>&quot;The arrest is the first important demonstration by the government of its capacity to enforce the law with an even hand,&quot; political analyst Amando Doronila wrote in the Philippine Daily Inquirer on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;After all, it's the first time in many years that we have seen a congressman in handcuffs - and we are sure the president will be applauded by his foremost constituency, the foreign business community,&quot; Doronila added.</p>
<p>Credited by businessmen with spurring the country's robust economic growth, Ramos has conceded Filipinos are losing faith in the legal system.</p>
<p>Analysts blamed low public respect for the judicial process on widespread perception of corruption in a police system where some officers have been linked to drugs, illegal gambling, robbery and kidnapping.</p>
<p>&quot;Civil society has been lacerated by crime these past years,&quot; Ramos said one week after Jalosjos disappeared.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is one area where the word 'war' is appropriate, it is in our fight against crime,&quot; Ramos said.</p>
<p>Despite police claims that the crime situation is under control, citizens groups said kidnapping for ransom had become a booming business, with 241 people abducted last year and the gangs collecting a total of 99 million pesos ($3.8 million) in ransom.</p>
<p>Government figures show 88 banks have been robbed in the past three years with the loot totalling more than 100 million pesos ($3.9 million).</p>
<p>One Filipina is raped every day but only 14 percent is reported to the police, according to the government statistics. Losses to the economy due to official corruption have been put at a total of $48 billion in the past 20 years.</p>
<p>Human rights lawyer Rene Saguisag said Jalosjos's arrest and the jailing in recent years of few other members of prominent families for crimes ranging from murder to rape and arms smuggling did not mean justice was finally working in the country.</p>
<p>&quot;A few swallows do not a summer make,&quot; he said. &quot;Name me any big-time crook in government who is in jail.&quot;</p>
<p>Raul Concepcion, chairman and chief executive officer of appliances maker Concepcion Industries, credited the arrest of Jalosjos to intense public pressure on government. He said the lingering perception among Filipinos was that justice remained tilted in favour of the rich.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the president realises that solving crime, improving the justice system, should be his main thrust now,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
