<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="317501" id="root" date="1997-01-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt shares surge in active trade.</title>
<headline>Egypt shares surge in active trade.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-01-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egypt's all-share index leaped almost six points on Sunday as share prices rose in resurgent trade focused on realty, milling and cement stocks.</p>
<p>The Capital Market Authority (CMA) overall index rose 5.93 points to 330.01 points in above average turnover of 85.37 million pounds ($25.1 million).</p>
<p>&quot;The market today was quite active. Last week was slower,&quot; said broker Neveen al-Tahry of Delta EAB.</p>
<p>Another broker, Elwy Taymour of EFG/Hermes, said that he believed prices rose across the board generally, but that cement, milling and two of the popular realty firms starred.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was quite active with high volume. Housing is again showing promising performance. Volume and price rose in Medinet Nasr and price went up in Heliopolis,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Family Foods was the most active share with 24 million changing hands. The firm, which closed unchanged at 285.6 pounds, is mostly owned by large investors who trade among themselves.</p>
<p>Fertiliser firm Egyptian Financial and Industrial also saw high interest, with 8.82 million pounds changing hands. Its share price closed one pound higher at 135.</p>
<p>Medinet Nasr Housing and Development, which was the day's third most active share, closed unchanged at 415 in 4.64 million pounds turnover.</p>
<p>Heliopolis Housing and Development surged 41 pounds to close at 512 pounds, the CMA figures showed.</p>
<p>Taymour said he saw more room for growth in the share price of Heliopolis, which along with Medinet Nasr has been generating market interest in recent weeks.</p>
<p>Three cement firms were next in the ranking of the day's ten most active shares, with Suez Cement the strongest among them, gaining 1.2 pounds to close at 65 after shares worth 3.04 million pounds exchanged hands.</p>
<p>The index for openly traded firms rose to 530.98 points from 518.77 on Thursday and the index for rarely traded &quot;closed&quot; firms also rose to 222.73 from 219.45.</p>
<p>Of the 73 shares traded, 30 gained, 13 lost and 30 ended the day unchanged.</p>
<p>$1 = 3.40 pounds</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +20 2 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
