<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="317740" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks end softer, snap seven-day rally.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks end softer, snap seven-day rally.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>CHANGE				    CHANGE</p>
<p>TSE	  6113.90    -24.90   HI 6126.41	    LO  6010.80</p>
<p>DJI	  6843.87    +10.77   GOLD (LONDON)   US$353.10 -2.65</p>
<p>FTSE100    4194.00    -13.70   GOLD (NY-COMEX) US$354.60 -1.50</p>
<p>NIKKEI    17480.34   -609.70   LME CASH NICKEL US$7245    +0.0</p>
<p>CANDLR	1.3385		 LME CASH ALUM   US$1580.5  -2.5</p>
<p>CAN 30-YR   108.20     -0.14   FEB BRENT CRUDE US$22.58  +0.04</p>
<p>--------------------MARKET COMMENT----------------------------</p>
<p>* Toronto stocks broke a seven-session winning streak, ending softer on weak golds and profit taking * All sectors except oil and gas lost ground in brisk trading.  </p>
<p>The Toronto Stock Exchange snapped a seven-session winning streak to end softer on Monday, depressed by weak gold stocks.</p>
<p>The TSE's key 300 Composite Index lost 24.90 points to end at 6113.90 points, in turnover of 104 million shares worth C$1.58 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a really nice seven-day rally,&quot; said MMS International analyst Katherine Beattie. &quot;You're bound to have some kind of correction.&quot; Gold bullion prices tumbled today in both London and New York, pushing Toronto's heavily weighted gold stocks into weaker territory.  </p>
<p>&quot;Actually we didn't have such a bad day today,&quot; said Maison Placements Canada president John Ing.</p>
<p>All of Toronto's 14 sub-indices tumbled except for oil and gas. The weak side was led by a 1.7 percent drop in golds, followed by media, transportation and forestry products.</p>
<p>Declining issues outnumbered advances 528 to 474, with 291 stocks unchanged.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Bre-X Mineral Ltd fell 1.40 to 23.00 on over 1.8 million shares. Indonesia's Mines and Energy Minister Ida Bagus Sudjana earlier today gave Bre-X and potential partner Barrick Gold Corp one month to settle with their local partners in the huge Busang gold find.</p>
<p>Barrick's shares dipped 0.75 to 36.10.</p>
<p>* Oil firm Canadian Occidental Petroleum Ltd rose 0.30 to 25.60, topping Toronto's most active list on volume of nearly four million shares.</p>
<p>* Golden Rule Resources Ltd closed up 0.95 to 9.35 after earlier hitting a 52-week high of 9.65.</p>
<p>((Lydia Zajc, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
