<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="317803" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Boston Scientific Target to merge.</title>
<headline>Boston Scientific Target to merge.</headline>
<dateline>NATICK, Mass. 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Boston Scientific Corp and Target Therapeutics Inc signed a definitive agreement to merge in a stock swap valued at $1.1 billion, the companies said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>Under terms of the transaction, Boston Scientific will swap 1.07 shares of its common shares for each Target common share.</p>
<p>The deal is expected to close during the second quarter of 1997, the companies said. It has been approved by the boards of both companies, but is subject to regulatory approval, as well as approval by Target shareholders.  </p>
<p>It is anticipated that the combination will be accounted for as a pooling-of- interests, the companies said.</p>
<p>Target Therapeutics, headquartered in Fremont, Calif., designs, develops, manufactures and markets catheter-based disposable and implantable medical devices used in minimally invasive procedures to treat neurovascular diseases and disorders.  </p>
<p>The company's products are used to treat diseased, ruptured or blocked blood vessels in the brain responsible for stroke. One of these products, the Guglielmi Detachable Coil system, is used to treat and prevent the rupture of cerebral aneurysms. The Guglielmi Detachable Coil is the only device today approved by the FDA for treatment of inoperable or high risk intracranial aneurysms.</p>
<p>Boston Scientific develops, manufactures and markets medical devices whose products are used in interventional medical specialties.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the acquisition gives Boston Scientific, a strong footing in the interventional neural radiology market, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Bottom line, it's a great move for Boston Scientific,&quot; said Sanjiv Arora, an analyst at Dain Bosworth. &quot;It's a lot of money to pay, but it gets them (Boston Scientific) an A-player in the INR market.&quot;  </p>
<p>He also said the acquisition would result in a &quot;substantial charge&quot; to Boston Scientific's earnings in 1997, although did not quantify the charge, which would include banking and legal fees, he said.</p>
<p>The company is expected to earn $2.12 per share in fiscal 1997 and $2.79 per share in fiscal 1998, according to the average estimate of analysts surveyed by First Call.</p>
<p>Best said the talks with Target turned &quot;serious&quot; last summer, when Target's stock traded in the 30s. It closed Monday up 12-3/4 at 59, while Boston Scientific's fell 4-5/8 to 66-7/8.  </p>
<p>Target has a 60 perrcent share of the worldwide interventional neural radiology market, compared with about four percent for Boston Scientific, Best said.</p>
<p>Best added that Target derives 30 percent of its international revenue from North America, 35 percent from Japan and 30 percent from Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;That's the kind of mix we're striving for,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The companies have set a break up fee &quot;upwards of $30 million,&quot; Best added.</p>
<p>He also said that the companies expect no plant closings or job cuts. If the acquisition is approved, Target will be an independent unit of Boston Scientific.</p>
<p>	  Best also said Boston Scientific would cut costs by</p>
<p>merging its neural business with Target's and by streamlining distribution and manufacturing. He said an Ireland-based Target manufacturing plant was likely.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NATICK, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
