<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="317985" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MONACO: RALLYING-SAINZ, MAKINEN IN MONTE CARLO DUEL.</title>
<headline>RALLYING-SAINZ, MAKINEN IN MONTE CARLO DUEL.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Vignal</byline>
<dateline>MONTE-CARLO 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spaniard Carlos Sainz and Finn Tommi Makinen slipped away from their Monte Carlo Rally rivals on the wet roads of the Ardeche mountains on Monday.</p>
<p>With two days of the world championship season-opener completed, Ford Escort driver Sainz held a narrow three seconds lead over world title-holder Makinen and his Mitsubishi Lancer.</p>
<p>Only Italian Piero Liatti, in a Subaru Impreza, matched the pace set by the leading pair on surfaces worsened by patches of snow and ice.</p>
<p>Liatti clocked the best time in two of the day's five stages to fill third place overall, 24 seconds behind Sainz.</p>
<p>Briton Colin McRae, also with Subaru, hit a snowdrift on the side of the road in the penultimate test from Burzet to St Martial. His new co-driver, Nicky Grist, formerly with Finnish world champion Juha Kankkunen, was needed to push the car clear.</p>
<p>McRae, 1995 world champion, restarted but lost more than a minute in the crash and was fourth overall, more than two minutes behind Sainz.</p>
<p>Sainz, twice a winner of the winter classic, was the first to figure on a rainy day, taking the 19.41 km section from Labatiere to Lalouvesc.</p>
<p>Makinen was four seconds slower but he fought back to clock the fastest time with near-reckless driving in the next stage of 25.74 km around St Bonnet le Froid.</p>
<p>Liatti was the fastest from St Piereville to Antraigues as the rain intensified and the thin layer of snow melted.</p>
<p>Then, young Belgian Freddy Loix, who had already clinched Sunday's single stage on part of the Monaco Grand Prix circuit in his Toyota Celica, surprised the favourites again with another fastest time.</p>
<p>The day's last section, over 27.52 km from Le Moulinon to the Moulin a Vent pass, went to Liatti with Sainz and Makinen still going strong and losing only a handful of seconds.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm happy to be in the lead but it looks like Tommi is going to make life difficult for me,&quot; said Sainz, driving a brand new Escort WRC.</p>
<p>The WRCs (world rally cars) are improved saloon cars with an exciting look introduced by the sport's rulers this year in a bid to make rallying more attractive.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi are still working on the WRC version of the Lancer and Makinen was using a group A car on the Monte.</p>
<p>&quot;The terrain is so changing and unpredictable that it's hard to say wether the WRCs are faster than the group A cars,&quot; said Sainz. &quot;All I can say is the car's fine but the race is far from over.&quot;</p>
<p>Six timed stages on narrow, twisting roads in the Vercors mountains await the drivers on Tuesday. The rally ends on Wednesday in Monte Carlo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MONAC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTE-CARLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MONACO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
