<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318035" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: TENNIS-BELGIAN FIGHTS OFF INJURIES TO SCORE UPSET.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-BELGIAN FIGHTS OFF INJURIES TO SCORE UPSET.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian surprise package Dominique van Roost overcame injury and extreme heat on Monday to score her second upset of the Australian Open in a day that belonged to the tournament's fighters.</p>
<p>Van Roost won a standing ovation from the centre court crowd, and a historic quarter-final berth for her nation, after playing through back cramps to beat 15th seed Chanda Rubin 7-5 6-4 in conditions she likened to being in an oven.</p>
<p>Her win followed a third-round victory over world number two Arantxa Sanchez Vicario on Saturday and sets up a quarter-final clash with Monday's other winner, 14th seed Mary Joe Fernandez.</p>
<p>Fernandez also proved her mettle in the extreme heat, which at over 50 degrees Celsius (122 Fahrenheit) turned Melbourne Park's Rebound Ace surface into fly paper and players' legs into lead.</p>
<p>Fernandez recovered from a tentative start to overhaul Patty Schnyder of Switzerland 4-6 6-4 6-1.</p>
<p>&quot;We are like in an oven and you feel the wind very warm and the ground is a little bit sticky,&quot; van Roost told reporters while still icing her back after the match.</p>
<p>&quot;You feel the heat coming into you and your legs are heavy and you really have to concentrate in these conditions.&quot;</p>
<p>Van Roost, ranked 43 in the world, joins 16th seeded compatriot Sabine Appelmans in the quarter-finals, the first time a Belgian has advanced so far in the women's singles of a grand slam event.</p>
<p>&quot;I think for Belgium -- because it's a very small country -- it's great for people to see that Belgian players are good fighters,&quot; said van Roost, who was fitted with a corset after she began suffering back cramps late in the first set.</p>
<p>Van Roost, wearing heavy strapping for a pulled abdominal muscle, received a back massage and manipulation beside the court early in the second set.</p>
<p>But neither injury appeared to trouble the Belgian as she used spanking ground strokes, deep serves and subtle drop shots to outplay Rubin, a semifinalist here last year. Van Roost took the match with an ace.</p>
<p>Romanian eighth seed Irina Spirlea disposed of ninth seeded Slovakian Karina Habsudova in straight sets, though had to save five tense break points along the way to a 6-4 6-4 win.</p>
<p>Spirlea now meets the winner of Monday night's game between fourth seed championship favourite Martina Hingis of Switzerland and another Romanian, Ruxandra Dragomir, in the quarter-finals.</p>
<p>Hingis is staring at the chance to become the youngest ever winner of a professional grand slam event, with the three top seeds falling out of the tournament at the weekend.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
