<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318094" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FEATURE-SAFRICA'S HOUSING PROMISES BALANCE ON A KNIFE-EDGE.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-SAFRICA'S HOUSING PROMISES BALANCE ON A KNIFE-EDGE.</headline>
<byline>Paul Harris</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tourist brochures tout South Africa as a land of contrasts, but few countries display such huge differences between rich and poor and nowhere is the yawning gap more visible than in the country's housing.</p>
<p>In Johannesburg the mansions of the well-off Hyde Park area nestle just a few kilometres (miles) away from the ramshackle hovels of the township of Alexandra.</p>
<p>The disparity is so great that while foreign professionals are tempted to the country by the promise of a high-quality lifestyle, more than a fifth of all South Africans live in a shack or a hut.</p>
<p>Nearly half have neither electricity nor a modern toilet.</p>
<p>&quot;There are still too many people who have to sleep out in the cold, on pavements, under bridges or in shacks,'' says Housing Minister Sankie Mthembi-Mahanyele.</p>
<p>A MILLION HOUSES PROMISED, PROGRESS AT SNAIL'S PACE</p>
<p>When it came to power in 1994 after decades of white minority rule, the African National Congress (ANC) was committed to providing a million houses in five years, aimed specifically at the poorest people.</p>
<p>But in the two and a half years since those heady election days, the plan has drawn criticism for the snail's pace of progress.</p>
<p>Statistics from the Department of Housing show that only 30,000 low-cost houses have actually been built so far.</p>
<p>One of the main problems has been a reluctance by banks to stump up cash to supplement subsidies from the government.</p>
<p>The largest subsidy of 15,000 rand ($3,200) is available to households that earn less than 800 rand a month. This drops to 5,000 rand for households bringing in between 2,501 and 3,500 rand.</p>
<p>But many banks see lending top-up sums to low-income households as a risk they are unwilling to take on.</p>
<p>This is heightened by a hangover of the &quot;culture of non-payment'' from the apartheid era when withholding rent and debt payments was used as a tool against the racist state.</p>
<p>&quot;Until a climate is fully established where contractual obligations are regarded as binding...it is always going to be a difficult market,'' said Duncan Reekie, divisional general manager for home loans at Standard Bank.</p>
<p>This means many of the lowest-income families are left with a mere 15,000 rand to buy a property, likely to be little more than a strip of land with a concrete base and a toilet -- a so-called serviced site.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who get 15,000 rand cannot get loans so they can only afford a serviced site and maybe a tiny top structure,'' said Sharon Lewis of housing consultancy Settlement Dynamics.</p>
<p>There have been disputes between government and the private sector. Mthembi-Mahanyele has slammed local business.</p>
<p>Without naming names, he told reporters that one European group wishing to set up a plant to make parts for low-cost homes was told by the managing director of a major South African building firm that they were &quot;wasting their time''.</p>
<p>Another problem has been the sometimes poor standard of construction. Land can be unsuitable, workmanship shoddy and some contractors will try to cut costs.</p>
<p>&quot;The low-cost housing sector has a lot of risk for the developers and so they try to minimise expenses,'' Lewis said.</p>
<p>SOME GROUNDS FOR OPTIMISM</p>
<p>But things are not all doom and gloom and many say there are grounds for optimism.</p>
<p>Aside from the 30,000 homes built, there are 139,000 more at some stage of production and a further 56,000 are in the planning phase. Also a total of 372,000 subsidies have been released so far.</p>
<p>Many say the million-home target -- vital to an ANC government desperate to provide concrete benefits for its black supporters -- will still be reached.</p>
<p>The nature of the construction industry is such that projects take a long time to feed through the pipeline. Settlement Dynamics estimates most housing developments take two to three years before homes open for their new owners.</p>
<p>This means projects begun in 1995 should start to come through this year. Mthembi-Mahanyele has confidently declared 1997 as the first year of delivery for mass low-cost housing.</p>
<p>&quot;We are on track to meet the commitment (of a million new homes) made during the election,'' a Department of Housing spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>There are also signs that the banks may become more willing to adopt a more relaxed approach.</p>
<p>Standard Bank, rare in being singled out by Mthembi-Mahanyele for praise, has adopted a policy of considering sympathetically loan applications from people who can show their payment records were adversely hit by the political situation before 1994 -- such as rent boycotts.</p>
<p>Reekie said there were opportunities for banks in low-cost housing, especially in tandem with government agencies that will provide cover for banks lending to the sector.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking at areas where new low-cost houses are being built and trying to find opportunities where lending can take place,'' Leekie said.</p>
<p>But he added that South Africa's interest rates -- raised to 20.25 percent in November -- needed to come down soon.</p>
<p>Economists add the government needs to muster the courage to act decisively to end the last vestiges of the culture of non-payment -- a policy they encouraged during the struggle.</p>
<p>&quot;This really tests their political will,'' said David Galloway, group economist at Investec bank.</p>
<p>Settlement Dynamics hopes that 1997 will see the start of a housing boom. This would start a virtuous circle of creating jobs that allow more people to afford houses and so cut risks to banks and free more capital to build houses.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a perception problem. People will hopefully see 1997 as the year when things take off,'' Lewis said.</p>
<p>($1=4.68 rand)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8500031">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
