<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318024" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: CRICKET-RHODES AND KALLIS NAMED IN ONE-DAY SQUAD.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-RHODES AND KALLIS NAMED IN ONE-DAY SQUAD.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jonty Rhodes and Jacques Kallis make a return to the international scene with their inclusion in South Africa's squad of 14 for the triangular limited overs series against India and Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>Rhodes has been out of favour since his early return from South Africa's recent tour to India because of injury.</p>
<p>However, he has been in fine form for Natal, scoring consecutive centuries in the Supersport Series matches against Free State and Eastern Province.</p>
<p>Western Province all-rounder Kallis has completed his rehabilitation from a back injury and will add an extra bowling option to Hansie Cronje's team.</p>
<p>The 11 playing in the final test against India here at the Wanderers have been selected, and the squad is completed by 37-year-old off-spinner Pat Symcox.</p>
<p>Symcox was an integral member of the test and one-day squad in India but has been surplus to requirements on the more seamer-friendly pitches in South Africa.</p>
<p>The first match of the series is between South Africa and India in Bloemfontein on Thursday.</p>
<p>South African squad: Hansie Cronje (captain), Gary Kirsten, Andrew Hudson, Adam Bacher, Daryll Cullinan, Jonty Rhodes, Jacques Kallis, Brian McMillan, Shaun Pollock, Lance Klusener, Dave Richardson, Pat Symcox, Allan Donald, Paul Adams.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
