<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318378" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Kwasniewski says Central Europe united on EU, NATO.</title>
<headline>Kwasniewski says Central Europe united on EU, NATO.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish president Aleksander Kwasniewski, starting a two-day working visit to Hungary, said on Monday Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic would form a close-knit group as they approach EU and NATO membership.</p>
<p>&quot;We agreed that Hungary and Poland should closely cooperate (in Euro-Atlantic integration) and that all countries of the region, particularly the Czech Republic, should be involved in this system of relations,&quot; Kwasniewski told reporters after meeting his Hungarian counterpart Arpad Goncz.</p>
<p>&quot;Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic should hold regular consultations on presidential, prime ministerial and ministerial level in the near future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The three states are now seen as favourites to form the first group of countries to open talks on joining both NATO and the European Union.</p>
<p>Goncz said there was no question of one country trying to outflank the others in accession talks to either organisation.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not competitors but strategic partners on the road leading towards NATO and the European Union,&quot; he said. @</p>
<p>Kwasniewski is in Hungary to open a retrospective exhibition of Polish art, and on Tuesday will deliver a lecture to the Hungarian Foreign Affairs Institute.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
