<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318375" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria ex-leader freed, protests continue.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria ex-leader freed, protests continue.</headline>
<byline>Liliana Semerdjieva</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's former communist leader Todor Zhivkov was freed from house arrest on Monday as thousands rallied for a 14th day of protests against his Socialist successors.</p>
<p>Sofia prosecutor Mikhail Doichev told Reuters he had issued an order for Zhivkov's release on the instructions of the chief prosecutor. &quot;He is an old man, and in view of his health he should be free to move round town,&quot; Doichev said.</p>
<p>The release of Zhivkov, 85, comes at the height of severe economic and political crisis and two days before anti-communist president Zhelyu Zhelev is due to hand over to his successor Petar Stoyanov.</p>
<p>Students marched through Sofia on Monday with alarm clocks ringing to symbolise time running out for the Balkan country's Socialist rulers.</p>
<p>The Bulgarian Socialist Party (BSP) has offered elections by December, a year ahead of schedule, but is insisting on forming an interim cabinet to replace that of Zhan Videnov, who resigned on December 21.</p>
<p>Opposition protests received a boost on Sunday when opposition lawyer Stoyanov was sworn in as president and said elections should be held as soon as possible.</p>
<p>&quot;The 14th day of our protests is different because now we have a new legitimate president and this new president is going to be our guarantee for a victory at the coming elections,&quot; opposition Union of Democratic Forces leader Ivan Kostov told the rally.</p>
<p>&quot;If they don't listen to us, they will have to oppose everybody, and this is a battle that they will never win. We shall never allow a second Socialist government to rule this country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Zhelev has refused to ask the Socialists to form a new government, a task likely to be inherited by Stoyanov when he takes office on Wednesday.</p>
<p>If the divided Socialists fail to do so, the president must ask the other parties in parliament, and if they fail or refuse, he appoints a caretaker government, dissolves parliament, and schedules elections within two months.</p>
<p>At his swearing-in on Sunday, Stoyanov urged all parties to work together on measures to bring the country out of crisis, including a tough IMF-backed fixed exchange rate regime, greater financial discipline and a crackdown on corruption.</p>
<p>He met bankers, finance officials and other economic experts on Monday and sources at the meeting said the majority backed elections as soon as March to give a government with a firm mandate to negotiate with international lenders.</p>
<p>A new government is urgently needed to resume negotiations with the International Monetary Fund and avert default on Bulgaria's $10 billion foreign debt.</p>
<p>Zhivkov was convicted in 1992 of embezzling 21.5 million levs (then about $24 million) of public funds, spent on luxury apartments and Western cars for his family and favoured aides.</p>
<p>Last February the Supreme Court overturned the sentence but he still needed permission to leave his granddaughter's villa in Sofia's wealthy Boyana suburb.</p>
<p>Doichev said Zhivkov had to inform the prosecutor's office if he wanted to leave Sofia or change his residence.</p>
<p>&quot;I haven't heard a report in the press,&quot; Zhivkov told the television. &quot;If he has signed something it is still on its way and it will probably take two years to reach me.&quot;</p>
<p>Zhivkov ruled Bulgaria for 35 years until the collapse of his hardline communist regime in 1989.</p>
<p>A one-time associate of late Soviet leader Leonid Brezhnev and Romania's Nicolae Ceausescu, he is one of Eastern Europe's last surviving communist leaders.</p>
<p>Despite allegations of corruption, Zhivkov remains popular among many Bulgarians nostalgic for the simpler days of one party rule when speech and movement wre restricted but basic needs were cheap.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
