<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318363" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Court suspends ruling on Socialists' election loss.</title>
<headline>Court suspends ruling on Socialists' election loss.</headline>
<byline>Mark Heinrich</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Serbian court on Monday suspended an electoral commission ruling that President Slobodan Milosevic's Socialist party had lost Belgrade municipal elections to an opposition coalition two months ago.</p>
<p>Municipal court president Dragoljub Jankovic, clarifying the effect of appeals against the electoral panel's decision, said it was put on ice pending a ruling by the Supreme Court on which court should decide the volatile issue.</p>
<p>The opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition has staged nine weeks of street protests against the annulment of its victories in countrywide municipal elections, generating pressure in the West for democratic reform in Serbia.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Socialist-influenced municipal court may have been browbeaten by party bosses into passing the buck to higher legal organs under no deadline for a ruling, giving hardliners more time for counter-moves.</p>
<p>Zajedno fears a new outbreak of political violence in Serbia's Albanian-majority province of Kosovo could allow Milosevic to divert attention from the election crisis and build a case for emergency measures to quell any dissent.</p>
<p>Belgrade's multi-party electoral commission reinstated Zajedno's triumph in the capital a week ago but said its judgment was preliminary and open to appeals.</p>
<p>Jankovic said two appeals were submitted -- one by the Socialists (SPS) and the other by the rightist Serbian Radical Party (SRS), which is not in the government but opposes Serbia's moderate opposition bloc.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision of the electoral commission is suspended until the Supreme Court decides (which court should rule on the matter),&quot; Jankovic told a news conference.</p>
<p>He said the Supreme Court had no deadline for a ruling.</p>
<p>Electoral officials in Nis, Serbia's second city, declared a Zajedno victory there too last week. The SPS lodged an appeal but it was thrown out by the Nis municipal court. Zajedno plans to convene the new regional assembly on January 27.</p>
<p>Zajedno wants election victories in 14 major Serbian towns recognised, as recommended by OSCE investigators, to start democratic and free-market reforms in Serbia after 52 years of authoritarian leftist rule.</p>
<p>Thousands of opposition demonstrators massed in central Belgrade again on Monday, the 64th day of protests across Serbia, and were addressed by Serbian Orthodox Patriarch Pavle.</p>
<p>His traditionally pro-government church has broken ranks with Milosevic over the election imbroglio.</p>
<p>Pavle blessed the crowd and said: &quot;On this day of St John the Baptist we pray to our God of truth, justice and peace ...</p>
<p>&quot;Your sentiment of truth and justice and respect for the freely-expressed will of the people is shown in peaceful ways worthy of you and our ancestors,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Western governments have called on Milosevic to respect Zajedno's electoral wins in full or forget about financial aid urgently needed for the moribund economy of federal Yugoslavia, which groups Serbia and tiny Montenegro.</p>
<p>But Zajedno's democracy campaigners have been jolted by the potential political fallout of an assassination attempt on a prominent SPS Serb in troubled Kosovo last week.</p>
<p>State-run mainstream media seized on allegations by the SPS mayor of Pristina, Kosovo's main city, that Serb oppositionists as well as ethnic Albanian separatists stood behind a car bombing that critically injured the local university rector.</p>
<p>Pristina Mayor Dusan Simic said &quot;Albanian terrorists&quot; behind the attack &quot;receive support in Belgrade from those who have been trying to destabilise Serbia for two months&quot;.</p>
<p>Zajedno leaders condemned the bombing and denied any involvement with it. They said the SPS hoped to use the university rector's misfortune to distract Serbs from the need to democratise Serbia.</p>
<p>Albanian media have published a claim of responsibility by the radical Liberation Army of Kosovo.</p>
<p>Kosovo, whose limited autonomy was revoked by Milosevic in 1989 to quell agitation by its 90 percent Albanian majority for more self-rule and to protect minority Serbs, has been shaken by renewed, sporadic anti-Serb violence in the past year.</p>
<p>Milosevic used attacks on Kosovo Serbs to help centralise and concentrate powers in his hands in the late 1980s and could dust off that strategy now to blunt pressures for democratic change, some analysts say.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
