<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318302" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa prepares for &quot;hard-nosed&quot; EU trade talks.</title>
<headline>S.Africa prepares for &quot;hard-nosed&quot; EU trade talks.</headline>
<byline>Marius Bosch</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African trade negotiators are preparing for hard-nosed talks with the European Union this week, accusing the EU of going back on promises to help the country's transition from apartheid to democracy.</p>
<p>The stalled negotiations, scheduled to begin in Pretoria on January 24, were put back on track last month when South Africa broke an impasse by outlining its mandate, or negotiating position.</p>
<p>The EU set out its mandate in March 1996 and has accused Pretoria of dragging its feet since then.</p>
<p>The European Commission produced a mandate which would exclude nearly 40 percent of South Africa's agricultural products from a future free trade deal, while calling on it to reduce tariffs to ensure easier access to its markets for European producers.</p>
<p>The EU has refused post-apartheid South Africa full accession to the Lome Convention which grants favourable access to its markets to developing countries in Africa, the Caribbean and the Pacific.</p>
<p>Pretoria has not made its mandate public but said the negotiating document was the culmination of extensive consultation with South African business, labour, parliamentary and public interests.</p>
<p>On Monday, South Africa accused the EU of backtracking on promises it made to assist the country in its transition to democratic government after decades of white rule.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to have to brace ourselves for the negotiation with the EU which is quite hard-nosed I think,&quot; Department of Trade and Industry trade relations director Bahle Sibisi said.</p>
<p>But Sibisi told Reuters recent local newspaper reports, saying that South Africa would reject the EU offer outright, were exaggerated.</p>
<p>Officials in Brussels said the Commission was forced into offering a swift trade deal with South Africa because of political pressure that greeted South Africa's return to the world stage -- particularly President Nelson Mandela's triumphant tours around European capitals.</p>
<p>The EU wanted a deal with South Africa, they said, but the exclusion of much of South Africa's agricultural produce and Pretoria's worries about the impact of any future deal on its smaller southern African neighbours were major stumbling blocks.</p>
<p>&quot;The initial offer to negotiate was made in terms of assisting South Africa in its transition to democracy, both economically and politically,&quot; Sibisi said.</p>
<p>&quot;The details which came out in the offer of the EU, suggests that that spirit, that commitment is not enmeshed (in the EU mandate). The European interest came out in the fore, for example the 40 percent exclusion.&quot;</p>
<p>The EU offer caused ructions within South Africa, including fierce criticism from parliamentarians who claimed the EU had failed to take into account the very different sizes and levels of development of the economies of the negotiating partners.</p>
<p>Sibisi said South Africa would approach Friday's talks in a serious manner.</p>
<p>&quot;It is quite a serious relation we have with the EU and we want therefore to structure the best arrangement we can with the EU which will take into account our economic needs and imperatives as well as the interests of southern Africa&quot;.</p>
<p>Other members of the five-nation Southern African Customs Union -- Botswana, Namibia, Lesotho and Swaziland -- fear they will lose millions in income from the joint customs revenue pool.</p>
<p>Some 40 percent of South Africa's exports go to EU member states and more than one third of its imports are of EU origin.</p>
<p>Sibisi said Pretoria was confident of presenting a viable framework within which a deal could be struck.</p>
<p>&quot;That doesn't suggest at all that we are not going to be negotiating seriously or there is a war or confrontation as has been alleged in some of the reports.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
