<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318568" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia must cut spending-US economist Dornbusch.</title>
<headline>Colombia must cut spending-US economist Dornbusch.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. economist Rudiger Dornbusch criticized Colombia's new tax on foreign loans and said the national government should cut spending to fight one of the highest fiscal deficits in Latin America.</p>
<p>&quot;In no other country in the region has the public sector been growing at a rate anything like it has in Colombia. It's truly scandalous,&quot; Dornbusch said in an interview with Bogota's El Tiempo newspaper.</p>
<p>Dornbusch, who teaches at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, said Colombia's fiscal deficit of about four percent of gross domestic product was &quot;unmanageable.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said the nation's central government sorely needed to cut spending, and criticized its decision to clamp a six percent tax on all new foreign loans.</p>
<p>The new tax, he said, threatened to hurt overall foreign trade and was &quot;definitely not the right response to poor fiscal policy.&quot;</p>
<p>Dornbusch visited Colombia last week for a conference on the economic outlook for Latin America.  </p>
<p>The Colombian government declared an economic emergency last Monday and vowed to take drastic steps, including moves to increase the tax base and crack down on tax evasion, to slash what President Ernesto Samper called its &quot;worrisome&quot; deficit.</p>
<p>Critics of the tax on loans have said it threatens to unleash an inflationary spiral, since many importers finance their purchases with credits abroad. Inflation last year totalled a higher-than-expected 21.6 percent.  </p>
<p>In the interview, Dornbusch said Colombians would face relatively steep cost of living increases -- for the foreseable future -- since &quot;it would be crazy&quot; to try to cut inflation to a single digit in a country with a fiscal deficit as large as Colombia's.</p>
<p>&quot;Lower inflation is desirable,&quot; he said. &quot;But the priority for you (Colombians) has to be cutting spending.&quot;</p>
<p>Dornbusch, who wields strong influence throughout Latin America, said the region holds solid economic promise to the extent that it enacts necessary reforms, increases overall education levels and boosts internal savings. &quot;If it does otherwise, it runs the risk of becoming the world's garbage can,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked which Latin American country he would recommend to foreign investors he said Argentina and Chile both looked attractive. Personally, however, he said he had put all his money in Brazil, a country he described as having &quot;great prospects&quot; and &quot;an enormous potential market.</p>
<p>((-- Tom Brown, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
