<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318564" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuelan union rejects social security offer.</title>
<headline>Venezuelan union rejects social security offer.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Venezuela's largest trade union rejected Monday recent government proposals to reform the country's outdated social security system and said it may not participate in the next round of tripartite talks, scheduled for Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not sure if we will go to the Thursday talks or not,&quot; Carlos Navarro, secretary general of the Confederation of Venezuelan Workers (CTV) told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;If the government doesn't change its position, we'll have to take concrete measures, such as strikes,&quot; Navarro said.  </p>
<p>On Friday ministers said the government could immediately pay off $3.5 billion in social security liabilities if the unions accepted the offer of one month's pay for each year worked.</p>
<p>But in talks with the government and private sector leaders, unions said they wanted double that to compensate for years of high inflation that have shrunk real wages to 30 percent of 1980 levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is bringing on social conflict if it doesn't agree to the double payment,&quot; Navarro said.</p>
<p>The tripartite talks are being held separately from ongoing negotiations between the government and the teachers' and doctors' unions over pay levels.</p>
<p>However both series of talks highlight the drama of workers, who have seen wages laid waste by 103 percent inflation last year, the highest in Latin America.</p>
<p>Navarro added he was also holding out at the tripartite talks for an increase in the minimum wage which currently only meets 42 percent of the 130,000 bolivar ($277) basic monthly food basket for a family of five.</p>
<p>((-- Omar Lugo, Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
