<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318606" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuela Cenbnk makes $78 million 2nd half loss.</title>
<headline>Venezuela Cenbnk makes $78 million 2nd half loss.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Venezuela's Central Bank reported a net loss for the second half of 1996 of 37 billion bolivars ($78 million), compared to a 45 billion bolivar ($96 million) loss over the first half of the year.</p>
<p>Total operating losses of 103 billion bolivars were partially covered by 65 billion bolivars from contingencies. Comparative figures for the second half of 1995 were not provided.</p>
<p>&quot;The losses ... are mainly because Central Bank assets earn less than its liabilities -- especially the Monetary Stabilization Notes (TEMs),&quot; the Bank said in a full page notice taken out in the national press Saturday.  </p>
<p>TEMs are the Central Bank's main instrument used to conduct monetary policy.</p>
<p>Total TEMs issued by year-end reached 1.659 trillion bolivars, compared to 1.067 trillion by the end of the first half. Interest payments stood at 227 billion bolivars, the bank added, compared to 169 billion bolivars over the first half.</p>
<p>Bank reliance on TEMs is due to be relieved by a 150 billion bolivar government mega-bond that will used to back Central Bank issuance of Treasury bills.  The T-bills will then slowly supplant TEMs in open market operations.</p>
<p>&quot;If there had been a mechanism already operating whereby the Bank could have issued T-bills, there would have been no loss for the year,&quot; said the Bank.</p>
<p>The government already approved a mega bond in early December, although the T-bills are yet to be defined.</p>
<p>&quot;This situation requires the urgent ... participation of the government, to establish the characteristics of the T-bills to be issued,&quot; the bank said.</p>
<p>(( -- John Paul Rathbone, Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
