<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318706" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan central bank says stock rally no concern.</title>
<headline>Taiwan central bank says stock rally no concern.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Central bank deputy governor Hsu Chia-tung said on Monday the bank would watch Taiwan's stock market rally but had no immediate plan to tighten up liquidity.</p>
<p>&quot;We will pay attention to the stock market movements, but there is no need to make any move at the moment,&quot; Hsu told reporters after the Taiwan index resumed a recent upsurge.</p>
<p>&quot;We may consider taking action if the stock index soars to 12,000 points,&quot; Hsu said, in effect reiterating the bank's hands-off policy since the index is nowhere near that level.</p>
<p>Taiwan's weighted index surged 1.40 percent on Monday to close at 7,254.32 points.  </p>
<p>That was its highest close since June 1990 but still far below a historic high of 12,495.34 on February 10, 1990.</p>
<p>Brokers and analysts attributed January's 320-point rally to increasingly speculative buying in advance of the February 7 Chinese lunar new year, fuelled by hopeful investors pouring their 1996 year-end bonuses into the stock market.</p>
<p>The central bank has consistently pledged to maintain a &quot;loose to stable&quot; monetary policy, hoping to liquidity levels high enough to add fire to a disappointingly slow recovery but not high enough to ignite inflation.  </p>
<p>Deputy governor Hsu said it was no longer likely that share prices could be pushed sharply higher merely by wild speculation as in the late 1980s before the market bubble burst in 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are more rational now,&quot; Hsu said.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (2-5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
