<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318753" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iran blames U.S., Israel for Pakistan arson attack.</title>
<headline>Iran blames U.S., Israel for Pakistan arson attack.</headline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran blamed on Monday the United States and Israel for an arson attack on an Iranian cultural centre in the Pakistani city of Lahore by Sunni Moslem militants, Tehran radio said.</p>
<p>&quot;What took place in Pakistan in recent days is the result of actions by America and the Zionist regime (Israel) which are provoking sectarianism...,&quot; Iranian Deputy Foreign Minister Alaeddin Boroujerdi was quoted by the radio as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;America's anti-Islamic move in Pakistan will in no way affect the level of ties between Iran and Pakistan,&quot; he said, without elaborating.</p>
<p>The Iranian foreign ministry on Sunday night summoned Pakistan's ambassador to Tehran to receive Iran's &quot;strong protest&quot; over the attack.</p>
<p>Witnesses in Lahore said activists of the Sipah-i-Sahaba Pakistan group, angered by a bomb blast on Saturday that killed their leader and 25 others, on Sunday attacked and burned the Iranian centre in central Lahore.</p>
<p>Sunni hardliners blamed the bombing on largely Shi'ite Iran and the local Shi'ite group Tehrik-i-Jafria Pakistan. Iran denied any involvement.</p>
<p>Pakistani police on Monday said a Shi'ite activist had confessed to the Saturday bombing.</p>
<p>No group has claimed responsibility for the attack. It appeared to be the latest in a long-running feud between militants in Pakistan's majority Sunni and minority Shi'ite communities, which claimed about 170 lives last year.</p>
<p>Iran last week urged Pakistan to crack down on what it called terrorist groups and prevent killings of Shi'ites.</p>
<p>On Sunday, Pakistani newspapers quoted a spokesman from the Sunni group as saying that Iran was providing Shi'ite groups with guns and money. Iran has denied similar charges earlier.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
