<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318848" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FCOJ futures end sharply up on cold Fla weather.</title>
<headline>FCOJ futures end sharply up on cold Fla weather.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>FCOJ futures closed sharply higher on weather-related damage to Florida's citrus crop, prompting prices to open the 5.00-cent daily limit higher and remain there throughout the session, dealers said.</p>
<p>Temperatures over the weekend dipped as low as 19 degrees Fahrenheit in the northern portion of the citrus belt and caused ice to form inside fruit. One Florida-based analyst said damage was most acute in a small area in the southeast section of the belt.</p>
<p>Citrus may be damaged when temperatures fall below 27 degrees Fahrenheit for at least four hours.</p>
<p>But while some yield and fruit loss is certain, it is too soon to gauge losses, growers said. As of January 12, about 67 percent of Florida's citrus crop remained on trees.</p>
<p>Some market sources said players may have overreacted to the cold weather. &quot;It's bad in a few confined areas but overall, the impact is negligible,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Agriculture pegged Florida's orange crop at a record 220 million 90-lb boxes.</p>
<p>Most-active March closed up 5.95 to 85.35 cents, traded 87.95 to 84.00 cents. The outer months ended up 5.00 to 4.00r.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at 6,000 lots.</p>
<p>Technically, nearby resistance was seen at 88.75 cents and then at 96.35 cents in March. Support was seen at 83.00 cents.</p>
<p>--((Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities 212-859-1646))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
