<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318937" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Duisenberg urges need for independent ECB - IHT.</title>
<headline>Duisenberg urges need for independent ECB - IHT.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The future European Central Bank (ECB) must be free of political interference, Dutch central bank chief Wim Duisenberg said in an interview to be published in the International Herald Tribune newspaper on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Maastricht treaty &quot;explicitly forbids the European Central Bank from either accepting or seeking political directions&quot;, the newspaper quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>It said Duisenberg recalled that the question of making the ECB independent had been settled by the European Union members nearly six years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The French lost that battle in 1991, but they have never given up,&quot; he said. &quot;At leat that's the way I see it.&quot;</p>
<p>Germany made an independent central bank, based on the model of its Bundesbank, a condition for accepting a single European Union currency, which due to be launched in January 1999 and come into general circulation in 2002, to ensure the new &quot;euro&quot; will be as strong as the mark.</p>
<p>But French calls for a stability council to coordinate economic policies inside monetary union has raised concern, notably from the Bundesbank, that it may try to use the forum to put pressure on the ECB.</p>
<p>French officials said on Monday that there was no question of undermining the ECB and that the proposed stability council would fully respect its independence.</p>
<p>The Herald Tribune quoted Duisenberg as saying that giving governments any control over monetary policy would impede the sound management of the EU's economy by hampering the bank's ability to maintain price stability and a stable euro.</p>
<p>Duisenberg, who is due to replace European Monetary Institute (EMI) head Alexandre Lamfalussy in July this year, has been widely tipped as to stay on to become first head of the European Central Bank, of which the EMI is the forerunner.</p>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac cautioned in December, however, that Duisenberg's appointment as head of the EMI did not mean that he would automatically become ECB head.</p>
<p>The newspaper said Duisenberg made no comment about its own future. But it quoted a senior European official as saying that when Duisenberg was asked to run the EMI he had received assurances from 14 of the European Union's 15 government heads that he would be in a prime position to serve all or part of his term as European central bank head.</p>
<p>It said Duisenberg had also called for labour market reforms, echoing comments made by Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer, to help bring down unemployment.</p>
<p>He said it would take three to five years to make a dent in the EU's high unemployment levels.</p>
<p>&quot;We need measures that are agreed with trade unions in order to achieve more flexibility in labour markets. We also have to revisit the structure of our social security systems, We don't want to copy the American system, but in many European countries we have been far too liberal in the past,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
