<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318942" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: NATO says talks positive despite differences.</title>
<headline>NATO says talks positive despite differences.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>NATO hailed a five-hour meeting on Monday between alliance Secretary-General Javier Solana and Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov as positive, but said deep differences remained over alliance enlargement plans.</p>
<p>NATO officials and diplomats said the very fact negotiations had started represented a step forward -- even though they admitted both sides simply used the occasion to underline how far apart they were over the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a long way to go, we are very far apart on a number of issues,&quot; said one senior official.</p>
<p>One Western ambassador added Solana had succeeded in getting across the message the alliance wanted to deal and had won an agreement to talk again in the near future although no date was set.</p>
<p>&quot;It was positive, at least now the negotiation process has been launched,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Officials said Solana presented detailed proposals to Primakov on a permanent consultative mechanism on offer to Russia to help it accept the alliance's expansion into former communist central and eastern Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;We wanted to show we had specific proposals, not just ideas. We think Primakov was impressed we had done our homework,&quot; said another senior official.</p>
<p>He added, however, that Solana stressed a deal with Russia on a charter encompassing all aspects of a new relationship between the former Cold War foes was not a &quot;consolation prize&quot; for enlargement.</p>
<p>&quot;The Russia-NATO relationship stands on its own merits,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>NATO is due to name its first new members for almost two decades at a special summit in Madrid next July at which it also hoped to crown a new deal with Russia.</p>
<p>Officials said however the enlargement summit would go ahead as planned even if the talks with Russia had not by then borne fruit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
