<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318993" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany must develop an equity culture - Rexrodt.</title>
<headline>Germany must develop an equity culture - Rexrodt.</headline>
<byline>Clifford Coonan</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt, praising the record year on the country's bourse in 1996, said on Monday the period for tax relief on share market gains should be only modestly be extended.</p>
<p>Under current German law, gains are not taxed if investors hold onto shares for a six-month speculation period after their purchase. Recent market rumours have expressed fears the minimum time period will be extended to one year.</p>
<p>Rexrodt stopped short of calling for a more comprehensive tax on share market gains but said &quot;a moderate extension&quot; of the minimum time period for share ownership.</p>
<p>&quot;When it comes to shares, any attempt to introduce a full tax on capital gains would nullify all our attempts to boost the risk-based capital markets. This would noticeably weaken Germany as a financial centre,&quot; Rexrodt said at a reception in Frankfurt to officially open the exchange for 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Innovation in production and manufacturing are the keys to long-term welfare and to new jobs. More risk capital means more independence, more new companies, more innovation and more growth and employment,&quot; Rexrodt said.</p>
<p>The German stock exchange had a record year last year as the 30-share DAX index posted an increase of 28 percent over the 1995 closing level. Share trading volumes surged some 40.5 percent to 2.43 billion marks.</p>
<p>Interest in the German market surged last year, in part due to the flotation of telephone monopoly Deutsche Telekom, and Rexrodt said changes in the tax law could dampen interest.</p>
<p>Rexrodt also said there were precedents for economic turnaround in neighbouring countries -- the Netherlands and Sweden -- and also in the United States, where he said 8.5 million jobs had been created in the last five years.</p>
<p>He expressed hope that German savers would invest more in shares from the current level, where five percent of savings goes into equities, to closer to models in other countries like the U.S., with 21 percent, and Sweden, with 35.3 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The equity must play a greater role in pension provision. The dependency ratio between generations is under pressure because of demographic developments, which means that individual pension provision will become more and more important,&quot; Rexrodt said.</p>
<p>Also speaking at the bourse opening was Werner Seifert, management board chairman of the bourse operating company Deutsche Boerse AG.</p>
<p>Seifert said it was now only 50 days until the opening of the new innovation bourse called Neue Markt, which is aimed at helping young innovation companies develop.</p>
<p>He said that 20 companies had so far applied for flotation on the new exchange when it is launched on March 10.</p>
<p>Ensuring liquidity for the fledgling companies, predominantly engaged in the technology/multi-media area, was a priority, Seifert said, and he echoed Rexrodts calls for a greater risk capital culture.</p>
<p>&quot;There is enough risk capital in Germany and there are enough venture capitalists. We hope that the Neue Markt exchange will allow venture capitalists to move out of their investments and start putting money into start-ups,&quot; said Seifert.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
