<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318912" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Pharmacia &amp; Upjohn CEO quits, stock drops.</title>
<headline>Pharmacia &amp; Upjohn CEO quits, stock drops.</headline>
<byline>Abigail Schmelz</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM, Sweden</dateline>
<text>
<p>John Zabriskie, the American chief executive of Swedish-U.S. drug company Pharmacia &amp; Upjohn, will step down immediately, the company announced Monday, triggering a drop in its stock.</p>
<p>The announcement that Zabriskie would resign and be replaced temporarily by Jan Ekberg, the head of Pharmacia &amp; Upjohn's board, raised new doubs about the merged company, analysts said.</p>
<p>On the New York Stock Exchange, Pharmacia stock dropped $2.75, or about 6.7 percent, to close at $38.125. More than 3.8 million shares traded, making it among the day's 10 most active issues.</p>
<p>In Stockholm, the stock fell by as much as 6.2 percent, or 17.5 crowns ($2.45) to a low of 266.5 crowns ($37.59), but closed at 273 crowns ($38.50), down 11 crowns ($1.55).</p>
<p>&quot;Things have not been going as well as perhaps they hoped they would in terms of delivering on the financial side, and Zabriskie has taken a fall for that,&quot; one London-based pharmaceuticals analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;It must have been some kind of disagreement (as) he must leave immediately. Clearly, the merger has not developed according to expectations,&quot; another analyst said.</p>
<p>The company, formed through the merger of Kalamazoo, Mich.-based Upjohn Co. and Sweden's Pharmacia AB in mid-1995, was quick to say it still believed in the merger and tried to reassure the market the resignation was not due to any surprise move in its financial results.</p>
<p>&quot;The board would like to emphasise its continued belief in the merger between Pharmacia &amp; Upjohn and the long-term strength in the company,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no reason to believe that the financial results will fall outside the market's expectations,&quot; acting Chairman Richard Brown said in an interview.</p>
<p>Analysts were less optimistic, saying the resignation flagged a warning about the company's future profits and meant the merger was not living up to expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;We had two profit warnings last year, and I suppose maybe people are concerned that there's a third one on the way and that's why he's resigned,&quot; pharmaceuticals analyst Janet Dyson of Merrill Lynch said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there's a lot of pressure on him from some of the bigger shareholders,&quot; another analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;The share's performance in the second half of 1996 was appalling because of the two profit warnings -- underlying business is squeezed, pressure from generics and currency problems that haven't been fully explained,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Some analysts said personal problems could have prompted the move, even saying that Zabriskie was just homesick. Pharmacia &amp; Upjohn set up headquarters in London after the merger.</p>
<p>&quot;If it comes out that Zabriskie is going to another company, then it's entirely natural and the slide is completely unmotivated,&quot; said Handelsbanken analyst Stefan Wikholm.</p>
<p>But analysts said the two profit warnings in just three weeks late in 1996 were more likely reasons for the upset.</p>
<p>James McKean, Morgan Stanley analyst, said the bank had not changed its neutral view on the stock since the first profit warning but said much depended on the company's new product line.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm inclined to give it the benefit of the doubt, but they have to start delivering,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Markets are eager for news about Zabriskie's successor. His temporary replacement, Ekberg, has a good reputation.</p>
<p>&quot;With Ekberg taking over, even on a temporary basis, I think that will focus their minds a bit better, more on getting the new company back on track,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>But this marked a genuine low point for the company, and possibly a turnaround, another analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;The only positive thing we can say at this stage is that maybe they'll get somebody in who will shake up a lot of the problems because there clearly are a lot of them,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM, Sweden"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
