<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318991" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Madrid stocks end firmer, but market tiring.</title>
<headline>Madrid stocks end firmer, but market tiring.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Madrid stocks ended firmer but off session highs, and while dealers remain bullish they warned that the market may need a rest in the short-run.</p>
<p>The general index closed 2.84 bps, 0.60 percent, higher to 477.59. The Ibex-35 index of leading shares gained 20.20 points, or 0.37 percent, to 5,490.43.</p>
<p>&quot;Stocks are still strong but this afternoon we saw a tired and more volatile market. At this point a technical correction is possible, but I wouldn't expect anything too severe,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Trading volume remained high, with more than 100 billion pesetas changing hands.</p>
<p>Telefoncia again attracted much interest after it opened its 21 percent share offer and paid a 35 peseta gross dividend.</p>
<p>The telecommunications group rose 10 pesetas to end at 3,385, in heavy trade with turnover reaching 4.14 billion pesetas.</p>
<p>Among other stocks, Repsol added 40 pesetas to 5,920, while Endesa gained 80 pesetas to 10,160, and Iberdola was up 10 to 1,710.</p>
<p>BBV and Banesto also ended higher, gaining more than 1.8 percent.</p>
<p>-- Madrid Newsroom, + 341 585 8340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
