<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="318988" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU delays plan to force VAT on non-EU telecoms.</title>
<headline>EU delays plan to force VAT on non-EU telecoms.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission has delayed by a few weeks a plan to force non-EU telecommunications operators to levy VAT on &quot;call-back&quot; and calling card services offered in the European Union, Commission sources said on Monday.</p>
<p>The delay is to give time for study of comments made by European telecoms rivals who argued at a meeting with Commission tax officials on Friday that the draft rules were not properly addressing their concerns.</p>
<p>The plan, which is backed by all 15 EU states, was initially due to be approved on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Commission wants non-EU telecoms firms to charge their European customers Value Added Tax to put them on an equal footing with their European competitors.</p>
<p>Foreign, mostly U.S.-based, telecoms firms, are increasingly competing with local European companies by offering EU customers cheaper international calls. This is possible with so-called 'call-back' services by which an EU citizen or firm rings a number in the U.S. and gets called back with an open line thus avoiding the local, more expensive, operator.</p>
<p>EU-based telecoms operators argue that part of the price difference is due to the fact that foreign rivals do not currently have to charge VAT.</p>
<p>The Commission proposal was thought to put an end to this, but British Telecommunications Plc and other operators argued on Friday that the new rules would not entirely remove the distortions in competition.</p>
<p>A BT official in Brussels told Reuters the rules would still be less cumbersome for non-EU operators since the plan foresees that their business customers would invoice themselves for VAT.</p>
<p>In comparison, a French telecoms operator selling its services to a British firm must charge VAT at the French rate. It is up for the British firm to claim it back from the French authorities.</p>
<p>Commission sources said this distortion would only apply until EU finance ministers agreed on the revised VAT rules on telecoms services.</p>
<p>Under the plan, the Commission would also adopt a derogation which would enable the application of intermediate rules without delay, but with the difference that non-EU operators would not yet be required to establish themselves in Europe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
