<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="319307" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Grobbelaar picked up cash for match-fixing - witness.</title>
<headline>Grobbelaar picked up cash for match-fixing - witness.</headline>
<byline>David Ljunggren</byline>
<dateline>WINCHESTER, England 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Liverpool goalkeeper Bruce Grobbelaar flew to London to receive a 40,000 pound ($66,400) pay-off from a Far Eastern betting syndicate for rigging a match in late November 1993, a court heard on Monday.</p>
<p>Chris Vincent, chief prosecution witness in a match-fixing trial against Grobbelaar and three others, said the goalkeeper chose to throw the game against Newcastle after talking to a betting syndicate middleman the keeper called the &quot;Short Man.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;In the weekend leading up to the Newcastle game, after one of the calls to the Short Man, Grobbelaar said to me: 'I'm doing the business this weekend',&quot; said Vincent, who like Grobbelaar comes from Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>Grobbelaar is accused of fixing matches with the help of former striker John Fashanu and Malaysian businessmen Heng Suan Lim, who both received large cash sums from the Far East. Neither could explain where the money had come from.</p>
<p>The prosecution says the &quot;Short Man&quot; is Lim and telephone records show the two men talked constantly, especially in the run-up to soccer matches.</p>
<p>Vincent, who exchanged several long glances with Grobbelaar across the court room before giving evidence, saw the footballer in his car after the game, which Newcastle won 3-0, and said &quot;Good result&quot;.</p>
<p>Grobbelaar, who had a passenger with him, replied &quot;Ja&quot; (yes) but said nothing else.</p>
<p>&quot;To me personally he said he was going to collect the money,&quot; said Vincent, who flew down to London the following Thursday with the keeper to pick up the money.</p>
<p>Vincent was a former business associate of Grobbelaar who helped break the story in November 1994 when he covertly recorded the keeper admitting he had tried to throw games. He then handed over the tapes to the Sun tabloid newspaper.</p>
<p>Vincent, in prison on another matter, said Grobbelaar decided to fix games because he was unhappy at being paid less than newcomers to the Liverpool team such as midfielder Paul Stewart and striker Dean Saunders.</p>
<p>&quot;He said he knew he only had a couple of years left in top flight soccer and would make as much money from soccer as he could,&quot; Vincent told the court in the southern English city of Winchester.</p>
<p>In the middle of 1993 Grobbelaar said Fashanu had introduced him to men from the Far East who were prepared to pay 1,500 to 2,000 pounds a week for predicting the outcome of soccer games, Vincent said, adding that the keeper had then decided to go further.</p>
<p>&quot;You know the people I talked to from the Far East? I will meet one of them and we're going to discuss getting paid for fixing soccer games,&quot; Vincent quoted Grobbelaar as saying. Vincent then asked how this could be done.</p>
<p>&quot;He said he'd been the Liverpool keeper for 14 years and if he was standing a foot off his line nobody would know.&quot;</p>
<p>Grobbelaar, with Vincent in tow, met the Short Man in September 1993 at Manchester airport to pick up 1,000 pounds.</p>
<p>&quot;He told me the guy he'd just met was prepared to pay big bucks to throw soccer games, in the region of 40,000 to 60,000 pounds,&quot; Vincent said.</p>
<p>Grobbelaar met the Short Man again about a week later in early October at London's Heathrow airport, where he picked up another 750 pounds. Vincent said there was no doubt the Short Man was Lim.</p>
<p>Grobbelaar first met Vincent in July 1992 and soon started investing money in a company Vincent had set up to promote safari tours to Zimbabwe. In all, the keeper invested 65,000 pounds before the two men fell out in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;We became incredibly good friends,&quot; Vincent told the court.</p>
<p>The other man on trial is former Wimbledon goalkeeper Hans Segers, accused with Lim and Fashanu of taking part in a separate bid to fix matches. All four pleaded not guilty.</p>
<p>($1=.6021 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINCHESTER, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
