<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="319320" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BT eyes Labour tax and denies it is a utility.</title>
<headline>BT eyes Labour tax and denies it is a utility.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Telecommunications (BT) insisted on Monday that it was neither a monopoly nor a utility and should not be forced to pay a windfall tax on its profits under a Labour government.</p>
<p>&quot;Labour hasn't made its position absolutely 100 percent clear with regard to BT,&quot; a company spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;We are neither a utility nor a monopoly therefore the notion of a windfall tax should not apply to BT.&quot;</p>
<p>Labour's finance spokesman Gordon Brown earlier confirmed in a keynote speech that the party would levy a one-off windfall tax on &quot;privatised utilities&quot; run by so-called fat cat executives in its first budget if it comes to power.</p>
<p>The BT spokesman noted that since privatisation 12 years ago, the company had given 47 billion stg back to the government from contributions such as income tax, value added tax and employees national insurance contributions.</p>
<p>Telecoms regulator Oftel says BT accounted for 92.7 percent of exchange line numbers in the UK, with cable companies accounting for the difference.</p>
<p>But BT was quick to point out that it has 150 competitors at home which can squeeze margins and market share.</p>
<p>Details of the levy, which newspapers have speculated could raise 10 billion stg and apply to companies as diverse as electricity, water, gas, telecoms, airline and airport firms, will only be announced after winning the election, Brown said.</p>
<p>The next election is due to be held by May 22.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7987</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
