<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="319392" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dollar breaks 1.63 marks as mark sinks on crosses.</title>
<headline>Dollar breaks 1.63 marks as mark sinks on crosses.</headline>
<byline>Chizu Nomiyama</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar climbed to new multi-year highs against the mark, yen and Swiss franc in European trade on Monday, with traders saying there was little standing in its way to more gains except the need for some retracement.</p>
<p>Breaching hurdles at 1.6300 marks and 118 yen, dollar/mark pushed up to its highest level in 31 months while dollar/yen rose to its highest since March 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very well bid today... mainly on the back of mark selling against other European currencies. I suppose we'll see some correction, but it's just not a very good idea to sell dollars at the moment,&quot; said a trader at a U.S. bank in London.</p>
<p>At 1157 GMT, the dollar was at 1.6305/10 marks, just off its high of 1.6315, its highest since June 1994, and well above 1.6112/22 in late European trade on Friday.</p>
<p>Rosy U.S. economic fundamentals coupled with mark weakness meant there was little to stop the dollar from reaching new heights, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sentiment at the moment is very pro-dollar, anti-mark and anti-yen, and it's difficult to (say) what in the short term will change that, although there will be the odd retracement,&quot; said David Coleman, chief economist at CIBC Wood Gundy.</p>
<p>&quot;You need a very specific reason at the moment to be bearish on the dollar,&quot; Coleman said.</p>
<p>The market was waiting for December German M3 money supply data, which were forecast to grow 7.5 percent after a 8.0-percent rise in November.</p>
<p>However, few traders expected the data to have a tremendous impact on the market.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank is not overly concerned with where the mark is against the dollar. It's more concerned with mark crosses in Europe as a lot of currencies trading strongly against the mark would slightly undermine the mark's reserve currency status,&quot; said Bankers Trust economist Ian Amstad.</p>
<p>&quot;But because of the strong disinflationary forces within the domestic economy, the Bundesbank doesn't have a problem with dollar/mark at 1.62,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The mark continued its weakening trend across the board in the European crosses. It sunk to a 31-month low against the lira at 966.45. The mark was at 968.20/55 lire at 1145 GMT, down from its late Friday level of 970.60/10.</p>
<p>The Norwegian crown and the Finish markka also surged against the mark. Norway's crown was at 3.8970/00 from Friday's 3.9350/80, while the markka was at 2.9295/15, its highest since September 1995, and up from 2.9630/50 on Friday.</p>
<p>Bundesbank council member Hans-Juergen Krupp said on Monday that German financial policy was hindering economic growth. Another council member, Franz-Christoph Zeitler, said he saw a good chance of Germany qualifying for European monetary union despite relatively high new public borrowing in 1996.</p>
<p>The dollar also continued on its bullish way against the yen, hitting a high of 118.18 yen in European morning trade, its highest level since March 1993. It had backed down to 118.03/13 by 1150 GMT but was still one yen higher than at the European close on Friday.</p>
<p>A huge 3.37-percent drop overnight in the Tokyo stock market's key Nikkei average had given the dollar more upward momentum, traders said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom, +44-171-542-6721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
