<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="319463" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli M1 money supply rose 2.2 pct in December.</title>
<headline>Israeli M1 money supply rose 2.2 pct in December.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's M1 money supply grew a preliminary 2.2 percent in in December, bringing the full-year figure to 12.3 percent, the Bank of Israel said on Monday.</p>
<p>The December rise follows a revised 0.6 percent increase in November.</p>
<p>The money supply increase for the month was relatively high, but analysts attributed it to seasonal factors. The government usually runs a big budget deficit in December, and this year it ballooned to 4.27 billion shekels, compared with 670 million shekels in November.</p>
<p>The full-year figure reflects the influence of the Bank of Israel's restrictive monetary policy, a source in the banking sector said. Inflation last year was 10.6 percent, while gross domestic product grew an estimated 4.4 percent, according to the Central Bureau of Statistics.</p>
<p>Total credit in December rose a preliminary 0.9 percent to 251.4 billion shekels, following an identical rise in November. Unlinked shekel credit rose a much slower 0.3 percent to 81.2 billion shekels, following an 0.6 percent decline in November.</p>
<p>Total credit for last year rose 20.5 percent, while unlinked shekel credit rose 13.4 percent.</p>
<p>Money supply is one of several indicators the Bank of Israel uses to determine short-term interest rates. The central bank's February monetary programme is scheduled to be announced on January 27.</p>
<p>The Bank of Israel cut rates by 0.5 percentage point to 14.76 percent at the end of December, but expectations of a further cut later this month have fallen since the release of the December consumer price index (CPI). The December CPI rose 0.8 percent, which was at the high end of expectations.</p>
<p>In the bond market, inflationary expectations for the next 12 months have risen slightly in recent days to 9.35 percent.</p>
<p>($1 = 3.27 shekels)</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
