<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="319597" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Tietmeyer warns on economy.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Tietmeyer warns on economy.</headline>
<byline>Scott Miller</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer warned on Monday that Germany's fledgling economic recovery was not yet self-sustaining and that a long-awaited pick up in growth could be delayed.</p>
<p>Reflecting an increasingly widespread worry, Tietmeyer said that cold winter weather could hold back growth here in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we are on the way to recovery but we don't have enough of a self-supporting economic recovery yet,&quot; Tietmeyer told the International Hearld Tribune newspaper.</p>
<p>Although no economists are revising down their growth forecasts yet, the first few months of the year will indicate whether Germany will live up to hopes of growth near 2.5 percent this year -- growth which may be needed for the country to qualify for European economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>To pass the EMU test, countries must cut their deficits to no more than three percent of Gross Domestic Product. Slower growth makes this target harder to reach.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer's fellow council member Hans-Juergen Krupp, an opposition Social Democrat, added to the nervousness, saying that Bonn's tight fiscal policies were choking off growth and that the government should do more to prime the economic pump.</p>
<p>&quot;Financial policy is hindering still continuing economic recovery,&quot; Krupp said.</p>
<p>And yet another Bundesbank policy maker, Franz-Christoph Zeitler, said that private investment, one of the keys to recovery, has failed to take off despite favourable economic conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite a favourable environment for prices, interest rates and currencies, private investment has not yet sprung to life as an economic motor, the spark from exports has not yet jumped to investment,&quot; Zeitler said.</p>
<p>Of most immedate concern to Tietmeyer and others is a cold spell that has blanketed many parts of Germany under several inches of snow for weeks and kept temperatures at or below freezing - severly cutting building activity.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Otmar Franz, the head of Germany's HDB construction industry organisation said he feared that continued hard winter weather in February would lead to around 400,000 being unemployed in the industry.</p>
<p>That would mean even lower tax revenues and even higher unemployment claims, making the drive to monetary union even harder.</p>
<p>Although recovery could be delayed, Tietmeyer said he still expected the German economy to grow between two to 2.5 percent this year.</p>
<p>The growing ranks of unemployed at the same time the government is imposing tight fiscal policies is increasing pressure to bend the EMU criteria, to allow more spending.</p>
<p>Krupp, who is known for his pro-growth views, said Bonn's efforts to meet Maastricht Treaty deficit targets by cutting spending and raising taxes where putting the economy at risk and urged that the criteria be viewed flexibly.</p>
<p>In order to qualify for EMU, German finance minister Theo Waigel plans to cut federal spending by two percent in real terms and has increased pension contributions to record levels.</p>
<p>The stakes for getting the economy going, increasing tax revenues and cutting government red ink are high.</p>
<p>Germany's deficit to GDP ratio must be cut to the three percent mark by the end of this year from 3.9 percent at the end of 1996 to qualify it for monetary union. And without Germany, monetary union would probably not happen at all.</p>
<p>Last week, a former head of the Bundesbank, Karl Otto Poehl said he could not see how Germany would close the deficit gap and warned that monetary union could fail.</p>
<p>&quot;What appears particularly worrying is the fact that Germany is far away from meeting the (Maastricht) target,&quot; Poehl told a conference. &quot;It could still be possible that the whole exercise will be postponed or may even fail.&quot;</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
