<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="319663" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany's Waigel, under fire, backed by Kohl &amp; Co.</title>
<headline>Germany's Waigel, under fire, backed by Kohl &amp; Co.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Busvine</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Finance Minister Theo Waigel started a crunch week on Monday with powerful allies defending him against calls to resign from the wings of Chancellor Helmut Kohl's own Christian Democrat party (CDU).</p>
<p>Waigel wanted to wrap up details of a big tax-cutting plan on Thursday, but, in rare public criticism, up-and-coming CDU officials said he had lost his way by letting talk of a hike in value-added tax dominate the reform debate.</p>
<p>Lower Saxony CDU chief Christian Wulff led a clique of CDU young Turks at the weekend who called for Waigel to step down, and he kept up his barrage on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;This week is the moment of truth in German finance policy,&quot; Wulff told Monday's Hamburger Morgenpost newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;Our chief task must be to fight unemployment. And for that we need tax cuts so that our European competitors do not steal business from us,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Weekend reports that Chancellor Helmut Kohl's three-party coalition had agreed to hike Germany's 15 percent VAT rate by two percent -- not one percent as earlier announced -- flushed out another critic on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The great challenge for government is to achieve a tax reform without hiking VAT,&quot; Peter Mueller, CDU head in Saarland province, told ARD public television.</p>
<p>&quot;If Theo Waigel cannot manage this, we must ask whether there are others who can,&quot; Mueller added.</p>
<p>Also among the critics were Hesse party chief Rudolf Koch and Hamburg's Ole von Beust -- figures likely to rise to the top of the CDU once Kohl, 66, heads into retirement.</p>
<p>Waigel, who at the weekend received the Chancellor's full backing, on Monday dismissed weekend calls for him to resign as &quot;improper and underhand&quot;.</p>
<p>And CDU general secretary Peter Hintze said the attacks on Waigel were unfair and unjustified. &quot;We will get a reform that deserves the name,&quot; he told Berlin Radio.</p>
<p>But the criticism looked to have been enough to convince Waigel on Monday to drop plans for the two-point VAT hike.</p>
<p>Speaking after a meeting in Munich of his Christian Social Union (CSU), the Bavarian sister party to Kohl's CDU, Waigel said: &quot;Based on the concept that I am following we will manage with an increase of one point.&quot;</p>
<p>Waigel's tax reform plans to cut the top rate of German income tax to below 40 percent from 53 percent now, while the entry bracket would fall below 20 percent from 26 percent.</p>
<p>But overshadowing plans to lighten the tax load by up to 30 billion marks ($18.4 billion) has been a running debate over taxing pensions, unemployment benefits and property sales, among others.</p>
<p>An Allensbach institute poll last week found that a majority of Germans actually believed the main element of the planned reforms was raising value-added tax.</p>
<p>The attacks further undermined the position of Waigel, who has struggled over the past year to contain state borrowing and faces a huge challenge to bring Germany's budget deficit this year down to qualify for European monetary union.</p>
<p>Waigel will also review a government annual economic report this week which will give fresh clues over whether he can cut state borrowing below three percent of gross domestic product this year, down from 3.9 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry has said that no decision had yet been taken on whether to slap a freeze on extra government spending this month to prevent a borrowing overshoot.</p>
<p>($1=1.6285 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
