<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="319605" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Algiers car bomb kills 23, wounds 100 - newspapers.</title>
<headline>Algiers car bomb kills 23, wounds 100 - newspapers.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A powerful car bomb exploded on a bustling street in the centre of Algiers on Sunday evening, killing 23 people and wounding more than 100, Algerian newspapers reported on Monday.</p>
<p>The bomb followed a massacre of dozens of villagers in Medea province, a stronghold of the feared Armed Islamic Group (GIA).</p>
<p>The leading Algerian newspaper Liberte said guerrillas raided the village of Sidi Abdelaziz 70 km (40 miles) south of Algiers, in the early hours of Sunday and slit the throats of 48 villagers, including women and children. The government put the death toll at 36.</p>
<p>Liberte dubbed the killings &quot;Ramadan massacres&quot;, referring to the Moslem holy month of Ramadan in which Moslem guerrillas usually step up attacks against the Algerian government.</p>
<p>More than 100 people have been killed and more than 150 others wounded in the first 10 days of Ramadan in Algeria, according to a toll compiled by Reuters from official statements and newspaper reports.</p>
<p>The Algiers bomb, the second in the city in 12 days, exploded in Belouizdad avenue during rush hour after people ended their daily Ramadan fast.</p>
<p>&quot;Limbs of the victims, many of them hawkers in the street, were strewn on the pavement,&quot; said another resident. &quot;Windows were shattered in many buildings nearby and some balconies collapsed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts believed the killings were a message to President Liamine Zeroual as well as to mainstream Algerians that the fundamentalists are still a formidable force despite repeated claims by the government that it has crushed the guerrillas.</p>
<p>A doctor in Algiers's Mustapha hospital, speaking by telephone, said of Sunday's bomb: &quot;It was one of the worst bombings in Algiers since 1995 because of the casualties.&quot;</p>
<p>Algiers experienced its deadliest bombing in 1995 when Moslem guerrillas slammed a car laden with explosives into a police station killing more than 40 and wounding more than 300.</p>
<p>Zeroual reasserted this week his government was committed to wipe out the guerrillas.</p>
<p>&quot;One theory is that it is a statement -- sort of Ramadan message -- to the authorities and to the public that the rebels are still very much able to operate,&quot; said an analyst in Algiers who did not want to be named.</p>
<p>The attacks appear indiscriminate, hitting even areas which are associated with the guerrillas.</p>
<p>&quot;These massacres have no message but killing for the sake of killing...&quot; said Liberte newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;What was the point in bombing Belouizdad, some metres (yards) from 'Kabul mosque' symbolising the guerrillas?&quot; the Algiers analyst said.</p>
<p>Khaled ibn Alwalid mosque in the area became known as Kabul mosque because many Algerians who fought in Afghanistan with the Mudjahideen against the Soviet Union prayed there.</p>
<p>About 60,000 people have been killed in civil violence in Algeria since the cancellation in 1992 of a general election in which radical Islamists had taken a commanding lead.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Mustapha Benmansour, who visited the scene of the bombing to present his condolences to the families of victims, condemned what he described as &quot;a criminal, cowardly and odious act,&quot; the Algerian news agency APS said.</p>
<p>He vowed &quot;to hunt down and punish the perpetrators of the crime in Belouizdad neighbourhood, following the crime in Medea province.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
