<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="319798" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chartwell in alliance with Hilton Inns.</title>
<headline>Chartwell in alliance with Hilton Inns.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chartwell Leisure Inc. Monday said it will invest nearly $200 million to own, develop, manage and operate 20 Hilton Garden Inn hotels in target markets nationwide under a franchise license.</p>
<p>The strategic alliance with Hilton Hotels Corp.'s franchising subsidiary Hilton Inns, Inc. will initially last three years.</p>
<p>&quot;This alliance helps to diversify our active expansion programme, which began more than a year ago through our relationship with HFS Inc., one of the world's leading hotel franchisors,&quot; said Richard Fisher, chairman and chief executive of Chartwell.</p>
<p>Chartwell said it will begin construction of its first Hilton Garden Inn soon at Albuquerque International Airport. It will start construction of its second Hilton Garden Inn site in Santa Fe, N.M., in the spring. Chartwell will break ground on other Hilton Garden Inns as more sites are secured.</p>
<p>Construction financing and permanent mortgage financing have been arranged for the Hilton Garden Inn development programme through Nationsbank and Nomura Securities. Of the total construction costs, Nationsbank will provide up to 80 percent of the financing, with Hilton guaranteeing 25 percent of the loan. Chartwell will put up the remaining 20 percent of the capital as equity.</p>
<p>Chartwell owns, directly or with joint venture partners, about 130 hotels with 11,500 guest rooms in 26 states and six Canadian provinces.</p>
<p>Chartwell's stock rose $1.25 to $13.625 early on Nasdaq. Hilton edged up 25 cents to $26.375 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
