<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="319800" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia gives Barrick, Bre-X Busang deadline.</title>
<headline>Indonesia gives Barrick, Bre-X Busang deadline.</headline>
<byline>Muklis Ali</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA, Indonesia 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian Mines and Energy Minister Ida Bagus Sudjana has warned Canada's Bre-X Minerals Ltd and Barrick Gold Corp. to settle with their local partners in a month or lose the huge Busang gold find in East Kalimantan.</p>
<p>In a letter sent to the firms on Jan. 17, Sudjana said failure by Bre-X and Barrick to meet the deadline would result in cancellation of discussions between them and the government.</p>
<p>The letter, a copy of which was obtained by Reuters on Monday, also warned the companies that the government would assume full rights over the richest parts of the finds, Busang II and III, if they missed the deadline.</p>
<p>&quot;In one month, your companies should be able to settle a partnership agreement with your legal partners and then should with your respective partners report in writing to the government of Indonesia that you have reached an agreement without government intervention,&quot; the letter said.</p>
<p>&quot;If in that one month that agreement mentioned is not achieved, then everything that had been discussed previously will be cancelled, and the government will have full right to further manage Busang II and III,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The letter was addressed to Bre-X Vice-Chairman John Felderhof and Barrick's chief executive officer and chairman, Peter Munk.</p>
<p>The letter was a reply to the joint submission made by Bre-X and Barrick dated Dec. 16 outlining their agreement to develop Busang II and Busang III jointly.</p>
<p>Bre-X has estimated the Busang property on Borneo island contains at least 57 million ounces of gold.</p>
<p>Bre-X and Barrick have agreed to split the property 22.5 percent and 67.5 percent respectively, with the balance going to the Indonesian government.</p>
<p>PT Askatindo Karya Minerals, controlled by local businessman Syakareni and his family, has a 10-percent stake in Busang II and III in partnership with Bre-X, which holds the rest.</p>
<p>Syakareni said last week he had sold a stake in Askatindo to timber baron Muhammad &quot;Bob&quot; Hasan but did not want to give details. Industry sources said Hasan, who is a close associate and golfing partner of President Suharto, bought a 50 percent stake.</p>
<p>Bre-X late last year announced a deal with a company controlled by Suharto's eldest son, Sigit Harjojudanto, under which it would receive $1 million a month for 40 months and a share of the Busang find when Bre-X received a contract of work.</p>
<p>Barrick has announced a partnership deal with a company controlled by President Suharto's eldest daughter, Siti Hardiyanti Rukmana, who has extensive business interests.</p>
<p>But complicating the issue is a C$2 billion ($1.48 billion) lawsuit filed in Canada last week by local businessman Jusuf Merukh, who claims 40 percent of the entire Busang find. His claim to 30 percent of Busang II and III has not been recognised by Bre-X.</p>
<p>Merukh has an undisputed 10-percent interest in Busang I in partnership with Bre-X.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA, Indonesia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
