<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="319939" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia-Japan steam coal settlement near.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia-Japan steam coal settlement near.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's A$3.0 billion thermal coal export industry could settle prices with Japanese buyers at meetings to be held in Cairns, Queensland, next week, leading producers told Reuters on Monday.</p>
<p>The expected settlement follows more than two months of negotiations and are expected to confirm a falling world market price for internationally-traded coal.</p>
<p>Several Australian steaming coal producers told Reuters on Monday that prices were heading toward a settlement down US$2.00 to $3.00 a tonne on last year's benchmark price of $40.30 a tonne.  </p>
<p>Producers, who declined to be named because of the sensitivity of Australia-Japan coal negotiations, said the expected price fall would reflect the market confronting both Australian sellers and Japanese buyers.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a very good chance there will be a settlement next week,&quot; one producer told Reuters.</p>
<p>Settlement of Australia's steaming coal prices on exports to Japan for that country's fiscal year, which begins April 1, will cover the bulk of Australia's thermal coal exports, forecast by the Australian Bureau of Agricultural and Resource Economics (ABARE) at 66.7 million tonnes worth A$3.14 billion in 1996/97.  </p>
<p>Thermal coal pricing negotiations, which do not involve negotiations on tonnages, will cap a round of disappointing results negotiated by Australian coking and semi-soft coking coal producers with Japan for 1997/98.</p>
<p>Against earlier expectations of a price rise, hard coking coal producers negotiated an effectively steady price for 1997/98, with some &quot;modest&quot; increases for top quality brands and some price cuts for lower-quality coals announced by the leading producer, The Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd.  </p>
<p>Semi-soft coking coal producers, led by 71 percent RTZ Corp Plc-CRA Ltd -owned Coal and Allied Industries Ltd and Oakbridge Pty Ltd, 42 percent owned by U.S.-based Cyprus-Amax Minerals Co, reluctantly settled for price cuts which ranged from rollovers to $2.00-$3.00 a tonne.</p>
<p>The round of semi-soft coking coal agreements between Australia and Japan, which followed hard coking coal settlements in December, are now effectively concluded.  </p>
<p>Just before the Australia-Japan coal pricing round opened in November last year, Australian producers had been looking for a price rise of about $2.00 a tonne for hard coking coal, $1.00 a tonne for semi-soft coking coal and rollover for thermal coal. Four Australian thermal coal producers are this year negotiating the benchmark prices which will flow through to the rest of the Australian thermal coal export industry and then to much of the rest of the world.</p>
<p>They are QCT Resources Ltd, MIM Holdings Ltd, Ulan Coal Mines Ltd and Shell Australia Ltd.  </p>
<p>Chubu Electric Power Co Inc is negotiating for Japan.</p>
<p>-- Michael Byrnes Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I11000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
