<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="319919" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian dlr steals past distracted sellers.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian dlr steals past distracted sellers.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar crept higher to gingerly probe resistance atop 78 cents Monday as the world was occupied with selling the yen, mark and Swiss franc.</p>
<p>The latter trio were all saddled with stuttering economies which seemed certain to keep interest rates low or even force further easings. That saw investors bail out for higher yielding climes, being primarily the U.S. dollar although the local currency benefited from the spillover.</p>
<p>Traders cautioned that the Australian currency had many of the same problems when compared with the U.S. dollar and the balance of risk was to the downside as long as US$0.7835 capped.  </p>
<p>By 5.00 pm (0600 GMT) the local dollar was hovering at US$0.7800/05 after an early US$0.7813/18, but was still up on Friday's late US$0.7788/93 here.</p>
<p>It advanced as far as US$0.7820 in early trading as speculators looked to build on last week's bounce from US$0.7740 support and trigger stop loss buying at US$0.7835 resistance.</p>
<p>Traders said local importers and Japanese investors had sold and there was much talk of a player defending a strangle options position with strikes variously put at US$0.7810 and US$0.7830.</p>
<p>Ultimately it was cushioned by flows out the mark and yen which, despite the odd fluctutation, were mainly one-way.  </p>
<p>The local dollar climbed to 91.79/89 yen from 91.19/29 late Friday as a renewed slide in the Tokyo stockmarket -- the Nikkei 225 index dropped 609 points or 3.37 percent -- reinforced the impression that Japanese rates will stay at record lows.</p>
<p>A run of weak data in Germany, meanwhile, had stoked speculation of another policy easing there which boosted the dollar to 1.2644/60 marks from 1.2468/84 last Friday.</p>
<p>The Swiss franc was another currency dumped as a low yielder and the AUD swelled to 1.0957/71 francs, its highest reading since March 1993 when it briefly topped 1.1000, from 1.0821/35. All this lifted the trade weighted index to 58.7 from 58.4.  </p>
<p>The sluggish economy/low rate scenario contrasted most with the U.S. situation where growth looked to be running above trend again and risks favoured the next move in rates being upwards.</p>
<p>The Australian scene was more complicated since analysts still saw a reasonable chance the Reserve Bank would ease policy this quarter for the fourth time since last July.</p>
<p>The speculation of a cut had cooled last week when it became clear jobs growth had been substantially underestimated in official data since August. However, inflation for the December quarter, out next week, was expected to slow enough to allow another easing if the RBA felt the insurance was needed.  </p>
<p>Today's merchandise imports figures for December were too mixed to advance the argument any farther.</p>
<p>Imports rose 0.8 percent, before rounding, much in line with market forecasts of a flat result.</p>
<p>The breakdown showed consumer imports up 1.5 percent due largely to increased imports of cars which at least suggested demand had not fallen away that month.</p>
<p>Capital imports dropped 6.3 percent but this was largely due to a fall in civil aircraft imports and excluding those one-off items imports were one percent lower.</p>
<p>-- Wayne Cole 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
