<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="319963" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea's Kim seeks peaceful end to labour crisis.</title>
<headline>S.Korea's Kim seeks peaceful end to labour crisis.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Browne</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>In a dramatic climbdown, South Korean President Kim Young-sam on Monday agreed to meet opposition parties to try to resolve an industrial crisis sparked by a new labour law.</p>
<p>In another sign authorities are seeking a peaceful end to confrontation with labour unions, prosecutors said they would hold off arresting seven strike leaders sheltering in Seoul's Myongdong Cathedral.</p>
<p>Kim has turned down repeated demands by opposition parties to discuss the new bill, which makes it easier to sack workers and maintains a ban on free trade union association until 2000.</p>
<p>His about-face follows a decision by the militant Korean Confederation of Trade Unions to call off an indefinite strike, a move that put South Korean factories back to work on Monday with no interruptions for the first time since the law was rammed through parliament on December 26.</p>
<p>Opposition parties, who have thrown their weight behind the unions, welcomed Kim's offer.</p>
<p>The stock market jumped. Brokers said Kim's move lifted a dark cloud over the market and predicted a bull run.</p>
<p>There was immediate speculation that Kim, under pressure from right-wingers in his New Korea Party to crush militant unions in the final year of his presidency, would seek to meet unionists half-way.</p>
<p>Political analysts said Kim might agree to build into the labour law more guarantees of job security and advance the timetable for recognising the outlawed confederation, whose leaders are hiding in the cathedral.</p>
<p>While many South Koreans agree the country's rigid labour practices need overhauling, there is widespread anger at the way the law was adopted in a half-empty chamber of ruling party deputies during a six-minute clandestine dawn session.</p>
<p>The tactics of the New Korea Party gave further fuel to critics who say Kim's presidency is growing increasingly harsh and authoritarian.</p>
<p>&quot;President Kim will meet leaders of political parties represented in parliament to discuss the current situation tomorrow (Tuesday),&quot; a presidential spokesman told reporters.</p>
<p>Kim has previously been adamant he will neither scrap the law nor revise it, arguing South Korea needs the bill to recover its international competitive edge.</p>
<p>Spokesman Park Hong-yeop of the main opposition National Congress for New Politics said: &quot;We, of course, will attend the meeting&quot;. He added the bill must be reviewed in parliament.</p>
<p>A senior prosecutor said arrests would be delayed to give dialogue a chance.</p>
<p>&quot;The principle of serving the arrest warrants still stands but execution of the warrants is being delayed in view of the prospect of resolving the current situation with dialogue,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Police have so far picked up five of 20 unionists on a wanted list.</p>
<p>Confederation president Kwon Young-kil said on Saturday he would limit stoppages to one day every week on Wednesdays.</p>
<p>On Monday he told a news conference he was proposing talks between himself, the head of the officially-recognised Federation of Korean Trade Unions and heads of the country's three main political parties.</p>
<p>Kim's breakthrough offer followed meetings with the heads of South Korea's Roman Catholic and Protestant churches, who both urged restraint. He also met the country's Buddhist leader.</p>
<p>Members of a 10-strong team of world labour leaders headed by Bill Jordan of the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions visited the cathedral on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;World opinion is a factor in this issue because what is at stake is the reputation of Korea, not just its politics but its trading relations,&quot; Jordan said.</p>
<p>&quot;The events of the last two weeks have seriously undermined Korea's trade image as a reliable country and one with which you can do trade.&quot;</p>
<p>In a sign that the economy was getting back on track, Kia Motors said its workers would put in two hours overtime on Monday to try to make up for losses in 25 days of stoppages.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
