<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="320034" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: E.Asian Grain - S.Korea mulls more China corn buys.</title>
<headline>E.Asian Grain - S.Korea mulls more China corn buys.</headline>
<byline>Jae Hur</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean feed millers are likely to start purchasing up to 450,000 tonnes of corn for April arrival this week and there is a distinct possibility they may buy some of this corn from China rather than the U.S. traders said on Monday.</p>
<p>Chinese corn has a significant freight advantage over U.S. corn and is available in convenient smaller shipments while the FOB price is the same as U.S. origin, they added.  </p>
<p>Freight rates from the U.S. Pacific Northwest to South Korea were quoted at between $14 to $14.50 a tonne and the rate from the U.S. Gulf was put as ranging from $24 to $24.50, while Chinese corn freights were indicated at $11 to $12 a tonne.</p>
<p>&quot;We can buy corn in lots of less than 20,000 tonnes from China and without any vessel premium for the minor ports like Kunsan,&quot; a trader with a local grain import company said.</p>
<p>The National Livestock Cooperatives Federation (NLCF) and five local feed millers bought at least 36,000 tonnes of Chinese corn at between US$142-$145 a tonne C&amp;F last week.  </p>
<p>The NLCF plans to buy two further 50,000-tonne cargoes of corn, the Korea Feed Association (KFA) five 50,000-tonne cargoes and private companies are also expected in the market for two 50,000-tonne shipments, the traders said.</p>
<p>South Korean traders normally buy corn from the U.S. when the size of the shipment exceeds 50,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Regional traders have previously estimated that China may sell between 1.0-2.0 million tonnes of corn in the first quarter of 1997 because of a bumper crop in its corn-growing provinces.</p>
<p>But exports had been held up because Chinese corn was quoted at higher levels than other origins.  </p>
<p>The prospect of Chinese corn returning to the market in force, following the easing of a 1994 export ban, was welcomed by Taiwanese buyers who believe this may push world prices lower, but Japanese purchasers were cautious, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope the corn exports from China will change the recent bull trend in the futures market,&quot; a member of Taiwan's Members Feed Industry Group said.</p>
<p>The March corn contract on the Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) closed unchanged on Friday at $2.73-1/4 a bushel. The price hovered at between $2.65-$2.70 a bushel last month.  </p>
<p>Taipei traders said the Chinese now seemed willing to sell their corn at more competitive prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Earlier, the market was saying that China wanted to export corn at about $170 a tonne, but prices are better now,&quot; a buyer at Taiwan's Hui Shung Corp said.</p>
<p>Taiwanese grain and oilseed importers have been active in the internaional market and are expected to buy up to 272,500 tonnes of soybeans and 136,000 tonnes of corn in the next two weeks, traders said.</p>
<p>In Japan, traders showed limited interest in the prospects for Chinese corn re-entering the market.  </p>
<p>&quot;We've received some offers from Chinese exporters, but its price competitiveness was not attractive enough to shift from U.S. corn,&quot; a Tokyo-based trader said.</p>
<p>Japanese traders said they've also covered up to 30 percent of their U.S. corn requirements for April-June shipment, and would continue to buy this week.</p>
<p>Premiums for U.S. corn were quoted at around U.S. 96 cents a bushel over the CBOT May contract, the traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the right time to buy U.S. corn for the April-June period. If the premiums falls below 95 cents, Japanese trade houses may accelerate buying further,&quot; a corn trader said.  </p>
<p>The freight cost from the U.S. Gulf to Japan for bulk grains was quoted at slightly below $26.00 a tonne.</p>
<p>Local traders said they are buying Argentine corn and are also monitoring South Africa's capacity for exporting the grain this year.</p>
<p>&quot;If South Africa has enough corn, we'd like to start buying from mid-February,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Agriculture's (USDA) agricultural attache in Pretoria said earlier this month that 1996/97 corn exports will probably reach 2.3 million tonnes, up from the 1.3 million tonnes that it had previously estimated.  </p>
<p>Soybean traders said they would buy U.S. soybeans this week for March shipment. Japanese premiums for U.S. soybeans were quoted at about 130 U.S. cents a bushel over the CBOT March contract, traders said.</p>
<p>Most Philippine flour firms will be sidelined this week to await softer U.S. wheat prices, traders said. Prices of spring wheat in Minneapolis, where Manila buys most of its wheat, closed nine U.S. cents down on Friday at $3.85-1/4 a bushel.</p>
<p>Some Manila-based firms could not wait and bought 35,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat for February shipment at $3.90 to $3.94 a bushel, traders said on Monday.  </p>
<p>EAST ASIAN GRAIN AND OILSEEDS PRICES:</p>
<p>JAPAN (Yen)				   Jan 20	   Jan 13</p>
<p>Wheat, a tonne (Canada)		*US$464.57	*$471.37</p>
<p>Wheat, a tonne (U.S.)		    *$418.69	*$424.82</p>
<p>Soybeans, a tonne (U.S.)		  62,350	   62,250</p>
<p>Corn, a tonne (U.S.)			19,500	   19,400</p>
<p>SOUTH KOREA (US$)</p>
<p>Corn, C&amp;F a tonne +			     143	     140</p>
<p>HRW wheat, FOB a tonne			  180	     182</p>
<p>Soybeans, C&amp;F a tonne #			 319	     314</p>
<p>PHILIPPINES (Pesos)</p>
<p>Wheat flour, per 25 kg bag, Manila	  290	     290</p>
<p>Yellow corn, per kg, Manila		 10.52	   10.71</p>
<p>TAIWAN (NT$)</p>
<p>Soymeal, per kg, Taipei		 9.45-9.65     9.40-9.60</p>
<p>Wheat flour, per kg, Taipei	 14.55-15.68   14.55-15.68</p>
<p>Corn flour, per kg, Taipei		   8.20	    6.75</p>
<p>* Rates quoted to end-users by Japan's Food Agency in yen and</p>
<p>converted to U.S. dollars.</p>
<p>+ March shipment.</p>
<p># February shipment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
