<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="320227" id="root" date="1997-01-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL short-term interbank up on cash withdrawals.</title>
<headline>KL short-term interbank up on cash withdrawals.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-01-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Short-term interbank rates were quoted broadly higher as banks withdrew cash for the festival season, dealers said on Monday.</p>
<p>One-week interbank rate was quoted at 7.30/40 percent against 7.10/15 on Friday, two-week was at 7.20/30 percent against 7.10/20 and one-month was at 7.25/30 against 7.20/25.  </p>
<p>Three-month money at 7.25/30 percent and six-month at 7.30/35 were both unchanged from their previous levels.</p>
<p>Dealers said most local banks were also running short because they had been selling the ringgit against the U.S. dollar. The ringgit has risen by over 400 points since the beginning of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;While local banks are short, foreign banks, which seem to have the funds have internal restrictions against lending to many in the market seeking funds,&quot; said a dealer with a Malaysian bank.  </p>
<p>He said merchant banks and finance companies are considered higher risk borrowers in the local market, and foreign banks lend to only a select few.</p>
<p>&quot;So with most institutions running short on the near dates and a lot of cash sitting in bank vaults, short-term rates are going up,&quot; a dealer with another Malaysian bank said.</p>
<p>He said this was why the overnight rate has been volatile since late last week.</p>
<p>The overnight is expected to continue above eight percent, the dealers said.</p>
<p>-- Madhav Reddy (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
