<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="320418" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: DEC's AltaVista says no date for IPO yet.</title>
<headline>DEC's AltaVista says no date for IPO yet.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Digital Equipment Corp's AltaVista Internet Software Inc unit said Tuesday it had not set a date for its planned initial public stock sale and reports of a January offering were unreliable.</p>
<p>&quot;It's still our plan to go ahead. But we have not announced any dates,&quot; Ilene Lang, AltaVista chief executive officer, said in an interview.  </p>
<p>Reuters quoted underwriter Lehman Brothers last week as saying the IPO could occur later this month.</p>
<p>&quot;I have no idea where that came from,&quot; Lang said after speaking at a computer conferece. &quot;I would not put any store in that ... What we think it means is there is a lot of interest and our underwriter, Lehman, was expressing that it is an important event on the calendar.&quot;</p>
<p>But she said that the report was &quot;not reliable information....There was a misunderstanding.&quot;  Digital said in August it planned to sell 20 percent of AltaVista in an IPO. The firm makes a popular Internet search engine. </p>
<p>Lang said that timing of the public offering would hinge on market conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;We filed on August 27 and at that time it was towards the end of...the concept stock offerings. Our view was that because we are a subsidiary of Digital we have the flexibility to wait until the valuation is right,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Lang said AltaVista would announce over the next 90 days more &quot;mirror sites&quot; for its search engine in Asia and Europe. It currently has agreements in Sweden and Australia under which affiliates establish local AltaVista sites to provide users faster access and quicker response to search queries.</p>
<p>AltaVista began publishing advertisements on its web site on December 17. Lang declined to disclose revenues so far but said that the company's partner in the effort believes the site has the potential to be one of the top earners of advertising revenue.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a big revenue opportunity. We've been very pleased with the acceptance and the sales of advertising from the start...,&quot; Lang said.</p>
<p>((Cynthia Osterman, Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
