<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="320746" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. to sell $7 bln of inflation-protected notes.</title>
<headline>U.S. to sell $7 bln of inflation-protected notes.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Treasury will sell $7 billion of inflation-indexed 10-year notes in its initial auction of the new security next Wednesday, Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The sale amount was the final detail that Treasury had to announce about the new security that it initially proposed in May last year. The 10-year note, sold in minimum denominations of $1,000, is designed to keep pace with inflation so that its value upon maturity is not eaten away by rising prices.  </p>
<p>At a press conference, Rubin said he expected the new type of security to have a major impact on financial markets and to benefit both investors and the government.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe this is an extremely important development for the United States' financial markets,&quot; Rubin said. &quot;It has the potential to increase the rate of savings and it will in time also enable tht Treasury to borrow at a lower cost of money.&quot;</p>
<p>Rubin said other maturities of inflation-portected securities will be offered in future, but said he was unsure whether they will carry a longer or shorter term than the initial 10-year note.  </p>
<p>In response to questions, Rubin said he expected financial markets to begin when-issued trading in the new securities immediately. They will be sold on a quarterly basis, he said.</p>
<p>Rubin emphasized the Treasury has &quot;a strong, long-term commitment to this product&quot; and said the decision to sell $7 billion worth of the 10-year notes was intended to demonstrate that commitment. It also was intended to ensure that enough were in the market for trading to occur, he said.</p>
<p>But he noted the size of the first isue was &quot;small relative to the debt structure of the U.S. government,&quot; so that there was little need to cut back on other debt issues.  </p>
<p>&quot;Over time, we will have to deal with the question of where we see this as fitting in the yield curve of our debt structure,&quot; Rubin acknowledged, adding: &quot;We have some thoughts on that, obviously.&quot;</p>
<p>The inflation-protected 10-year notes will pay interest twice a year, on July 15 and Jan 15. Next week's sale will raise cash for the government rather than pay down existing debt.</p>
<p>They will be auctioned in a single-price auction format, or a so-called Dutch auction.</p>
<p>Rubin said the new securities might spawn big changes in financial markets by encouraging investors to think more about real rates of return.</p>
<p>That, in turn, might make intermediaries like mutual funds to start offering competitive products like indexed annuities, Rubin suggested.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
