<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="320860" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FIGURE SKATING-GRITSCHUK AND PLATOV LEAD ICE DANCE.</title>
<headline>FIGURE SKATING-GRITSCHUK AND PLATOV LEAD ICE DANCE.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oksana Gritschuk and Evgeny Platov, the Olympic, world and European ice dance champions, showed the benefits of a last-minute change of coach by again holding off their would-be successors on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Russian couple, on top of the ice dancing world ever since they captured the 1994 Olympic title in Norway, won both compulsory dances as their event began at the European championships.</p>
<p>But they may have felt the crowns sitting uneasily on their heads when they left long-time coach Natalia Linichuk in the United States in favour of the renowned Tatiana Tarasova just last month.</p>
<p>Linichuk, they felt, had shown too much favouritism to her other Russian couple, Anjelika Krylova and Oleg Ovsiannikov, who were again second on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;She didn't give us the attention we wanted,&quot; Platov said, while Gritschuk added: &quot;It had been like that for a couple of years.&quot;</p>
<p>The formidable Tarasova was the coach of Natalia Bestemianova and Andrei Bukin during the period when they were second-best to Jayne Torvill and Christopher Dean of Britain from 1981 to 1984 and then during their successful reign until 1988.</p>
<p>Since then she has been involved with ice shows.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very happy to be working with her,&quot; Platov said.</p>
<p>Even so, they had a struggle to be here, missing last month's national championships when Platov arrived home with a knee problem.</p>
<p>Because of that, they were listed as reserves for this week until they appealed last week to the president of the Russian federation, Valentin Piseyev, that they were fit again to compete.</p>
<p>On Tuesday they proved they were right.</p>
<p>Krylova and Ovsiannikov were second in both the Golden Waltz and the Yankee Polka and will look to Thursday's Tango as a chance to move up before the free skating final on Friday.</p>
<p>They have their hands full, for Gritschuk and Platov have not lost any section of an ice dance championship since their Olympic title in 1994.</p>
<p>Marina Anissina and Gwendal Peizerat won a French battle for third place against team mates Sophie Moniotte and Pascal Lavanchy, who were fourth.</p>
<p>&quot;We were happy with how we skated but everyone other than the top couple would like to be higher in the order,&quot; Peizerat said.</p>
<p>Lavanchy said: &quot;We could not have skated better. We made no mistakes and it was up to the judges to decide.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
