<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="320834" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: TENNIS-MOYA, COETZER WIN AS OPEN GOES INDOORS.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-MOYA, COETZER WIN AS OPEN GOES INDOORS.</headline>
<byline>Philippe Naughton</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unseeded Spaniard Carlos Moya coolly earned a place in the semifinals of the Australian Open on Tuesday after organisers decided to take the heat out of the year's first grand slam.</p>
<p>On the third day of a heatwave which has seen courtside temperatures exceed 50 degrees Celsius (122 Fahrenheit), tournament referee Peter Bellenger sparked a blazing row by ordering that the stadium roof be shut.</p>
<p>&quot;I was going to play anyway so even if it's snowing, raining or 60 degrees (Celsius), I don't care,&quot; Moya told reporters after beating fellow-Spaniard Felix Mantilla in four sets.</p>
<p>&quot;I was prepared to play in these conditions,&quot; retorted a furious Mantilla. &quot;I think it may have been a different match in the sun and wind.&quot;</p>
<p>In the first women's quarter-final, South African 12th seed Amanda Coetzer showed the same form which helped her bring down top seed Steffi Graf as she ousted American hopeful Kimberly Po.</p>
<p>Coetzer is seen as the player with the best chance of beating Swiss starlet Martina Hingis if both win through to Saturday's final. Her performance on Tuesday could only have reinforced that view.</p>
<p>Moya put friendship aside as he disposed of 16th-seeded Mantilla 7-5 6-2 6-7 6-2 in two hours and 29 minutes in the air-conditioned stadium. The two men are training partners in the former Olympic city of Barcelona.</p>
<p>Since ousting defending champion Boris Becker in the first round, tournament heart-throb Moya has cut a swathe through the draw. The local press has dubbed him &quot;King Carlos of Spain&quot;.</p>
<p>Once considered just another Spanish clay-court baseliner, Moya has grown in confidence throughout the championship and on Tuesday he added delicate sliced drop shots and volleys from the net to his usual strong groundstrokes.</p>
<p>&quot;Felix does not make stupid mistakes, so if you want to beat him you have to take risks,&quot; Moya said.</p>
<p>Mantilla, who started practising with the roof open and only had four trial serves after it was closed, fought back in the third set and won a tie-break 7-5.</p>
<p>But Moya was back in control in the fourth set, breaking his friend's serve in the fourth game and producing a second-serve ace three games later to go up 5-2. He broke Mantilla's serve again to wrap up the match.</p>
<p>It was the best performance by a Spanish man at the Australian Open since Andres Gimeno lost the 1969 final to Australian great Rod Laver.</p>
<p>Moya's semifinal opponent will be either world number two Michael Chang of the United States or Chilean danger man Marcelo Rios, the ninth seed.</p>
<p>Number 12 seed Coetzer, who toppled Graf on Sunday, beat Po 6-4 6-1 in a match lasting 67 minutes.</p>
<p>Although Po managed to break Coetzer's serve once in each set, the South African converted six of six break points. She wrapped up the match by breaking Po to love.</p>
<p>Coetzer also criticised the decision to shut the roof for the day's play, although she conceded that it had given her and Po a break from the heat.</p>
<p>&quot;I definitely would have preferred playing outside ... I love playing out in the sun,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Coetzer's next opponent will be either 1995 champion Mary Pierce of France or Belgian 16th seed Sabine Appelmans. Pierce and Applemans were due to play on Tuesday night with the stadium roof once again opened, barring possible rain.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
