<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321129" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Kohl says German-Czech accord a big step forward.</title>
<headline>Kohl says German-Czech accord a big step forward.</headline>
<byline>Klara Gajduskova</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl and Czech Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus on Tuesday signed a joint post-World War Two reconciliation accord which both countries say is important for future European integration.</p>
<p>&quot;We Germans want to be good neighbours for you...We want forgiveness and we want to forgive,&quot; Kohl said in a speech after the ceremony.</p>
<p>The declaration, the fruit of two years of delicate negotiations, is intended to heal an often turbulent past.</p>
<p>In the accord, Bonn expresses sorrow for the 1938-45 Nazi occupation of the Czech lands and Prague its regret at the post-war expulsion of around 2.5 million ethnic Germans.</p>
<p>&quot;The declaration which we have signed is a big step forward for both of our nations,&quot; Kohl said. &quot;We cannot stay in the past or, in the end, the past will win,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Klaus said Czech-German relations, which have been close but uneasy for centuries, had never been better.</p>
<p>&quot;I am convinced that today's visit to Prague heralds a new stage in relations between our countries,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The declaration also includes German support for Czech membership of the European Union and the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation. EU accession talks are due to begin in 1998.</p>
<p>Czech officials hope the signing and Kohl's speech will give a fresh impetus to their bids to join both organisations.</p>
<p>The Czech Republic, along with Hungary and Poland, are the leading contenders to be among the first new members.</p>
<p>Germany has been the chief political sponsor of the integration with the West of post-communist East European states and the Czech Republic is the only one of its neighbours not to have signed a reconicliation pact.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not support entry of the Czechs into the EU if I did not think they were ready,&quot; Kohl told a later news conference when asked if Prague was ready for membership.</p>
<p>&quot;If all countries had the same standards as the Czech Republic, then the discussions after January 1998 would be easier,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Klaus thanked Kohl for Bonn's support &quot;for our attempt with you and other democratic countries to build a prosperous, stable and secure Europe,&quot; he told the news conference.</p>
<p>The accord has proved controversial in both countries. Relatives and supporters of the Sudeten Germans, mainly living in Bavaria, have criticised the deal as it does not include compensation for confiscated property.</p>
<p>Kohl acknowledged that property issues remained unresolved.</p>
<p>The two countries agree to set up a 160 million mark ($98 million) &quot;Future Fund&quot;, mainly with German money and primarily intended to benefit victims of Nazi aggression.</p>
<p>Czech far-right Republicans and communists also oppose the accord and staged a small demonstration as Kohl arrived.</p>
<p>Klaus urged the parliaments of both countries to approve the accord. A Czech diplomatic source, who asked not to be identified, said Kohl's call for mutual forgiveness would help ease the accord's path through the Czech parliament.</p>
<p>Kohl was scheduled to dine with Klaus on Tuesday evening and then have a private lunch with President Vaclav Havel before leaving on Wednesday. ($1=1.6223 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
