<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321107" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Jan 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Jan 21.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Kenyan press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY NATION</p>
<p>- Minister Simeon Nyachae says last week's cabinet reshuffle in which he was 'demoted' from the Ministry of Agriculture to that of Land Reclamation does not bother him.</p>
<p>- Kenya Revenue Authority makes a major reshuffle affecting 78 middle and senior level management staff in the Customs and Excise department.</p>
<p>- Valentine Kodipo, the man who claims to be a witness to the killing in Kenya of tourist Julie Ward, appears to have gone missing in Denmark.</p>
<p>EAST AFRICAN STANDARD</p>
<p>- A schoolgirl is murdered in a chilling human sacrifice ritual by a woman relative who wanted 'the spirits' to guarantee her own children's success in education.</p>
<p>- Veteran politician Paul Ngei wins his bankruptcy battle when the High Court discharges his case thus opening the door for the ex-minister's re-entry into politics.</p>
<p>- In two separate incidents, three policemen are shot dead by their colleagues on Monday.</p>
<p>KENYA TIMES</p>
<p>- Five tourists and ten other travellers die on the spot when a bus they were travelling in overturns and rolls several times along the Lamu-Garsen road in North Eastern Kenya.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
