<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321357" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia's Ecopetrol chief heads for cenbank job.</title>
<headline>Colombia's Ecopetrol chief heads for cenbank job.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of Colombia's state-run oil company Luis Bernardo Florez is quitting Ecopetrol to take up a post on the board of the central bank, Mines and Energy Minister Rodrigo Villamizar said Tuesday.</p>
<p>An Ecopetrol source said the move, to take effect from early February, is a &quot;professional step&quot; based on Florez's background as an economist and had been in the pipeline since last September.</p>
<p>The man tipped to take over the country's top oil post is Antonio Urdinola, known for his expertise in the energy and finance sector.  </p>
<p>Villamizar did not confirm the appointment, but an Ecopetrol source said it was &quot;very probable&quot; that President Ernesto Samper would officially name Urdinola as the new chairman sometime Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Companies go through different stages and right now Ecopetrol needs to develop a more international profile,&quot; Villamizar said.</p>
<p>Urdinola is currently head of the financial institutions guarantee fund FOGAFIN and energy companies Isagen and Empresa de Energia del Pacifico.  </p>
<p>If Urdinola's appointment is confirmed, he will be the third chairman of Ecopetrol since the start of the Samper administration in 1994. Florez has held the post since August 1995.</p>
<p>Florez is one of two new members to be appointed to the central bank. The second, not yet named, is widely rumored to be the serving head of the banking superintendency, Maria Luisa Chiappe.  </p>
<p>Both are seen as strong presidential allies and would effectively mean Samper supporters become the majority on the seven-person board, taking into account the current composition of the board.</p>
<p>One board member, however, said it was unlikely the bank would sacrifice its independent role in overseeing inflation, foreign exchange and interest rate policy.</p>
<p>The Ecopetrol source denied Florez's move was motivated by a disagreement with Samper over the way in which an announcement about the prospects of the Coporo oil field was handled.</p>
<p>On a visit to New York in September, Samper claimed the field, in Colombia's eastern plains, could be bigger than the giant Cusiana-Cupiagua field and had reserves of 700 million barrels in one level alone. Villamizar has since said the field is not commercially viable.</p>
<p>((-- Karl Penhaul, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
