<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321358" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian chief's &quot;banner year&quot; off to bad start.</title>
<headline>Colombian chief's &quot;banner year&quot; off to bad start.</headline>
<byline>Tom Brown</byline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>It was supposed to be a banner year for President Ernesto Samper, who spent most of 1995 and 1996 fighting for his survival amid Colombia's worst political crisis in decades.</p>
<p>But economic problems and deepening social unrest, coupled with possible U.S. trade sanctions, could spell disaster for Samper in 1997, his last full year in office and the one in which many believed he would finally get down to the business of governing what he often describes as &quot;the most violent country in the world.&quot;</p>
<p>With the crisis over his alleged ties to drug lords fully behind him, Samper announced late last year that 1997 would be &quot;the year of the people&quot; in which he would make good on ambitious campaign promises to eradicate extreme poverty, create hundreds of thousands of new jobs and work to improve Colombia's dismal human rights record.</p>
<p>He also vowed that it would be the year in which Colombia's economy, which slowed sharply in 1996, would return to the path of solid growth and prosperity.</p>
<p>But 1997, which many believed held the promise of a thaw in Bogota's icy relations with Washington, got off to a bad start for Samper and his embattled government. Public sector unions, representing about 800,000 workers nationwide, announced on Monday they will stage an indefinite strike beginning on Feb. 11 to protest government plans to hold them to an average pay increase of no more than 13.5 percent this year despite inflation of more than 26 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>Dock workers in the Pacific port of Buenaventura are on strike already, paralysing much of the country's key exports, and the leading business group announced it will boycott a new wage-and-price control agreement with the government to protest economic emergency measures unveiled last week.</p>
<p>The measures, aimed at slashing the government's widening fiscal deficit and pushing the overvalued peso currency lower against the dollar, included a 6 percent tax on new foreign loans. This, in turn, prompted a public outcry from importers who finance much of their business with credits abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;The emergency measures have been received very badly by the private sector,&quot; Armando Montenegro, head of the National Bankers' Association, said.</p>
<p>&quot;This year is going to be very bad in terms of the social and economic climate. It has begun very badly,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Montenegro said the tax on foreign loans will cut economic growth to no more than 3.5 percent this year, well below the government's forecast of growth up to 4.5 percent, and make it impossible for inflation to drop below 20 percent. &quot;The emergency was a shot in the foot of the government,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He and other analysts said the economy could be in for more damage on March 1 when Washington announces whether Colombia will remain on a virtual blacklist of countries that failed to participate actively enough in the global struggle against drugs. So-called decertification of Colombia for a second consecutive year could trigger punitive economic sanctions that the government of U.S. President Bill Clinton decided against imposing on the Andean nation last year.</p>
<p>A judge's decision on Friday to give prison sentences to two of the world's most powerful drug lords could see them walk free in as little as five years and has fuelled widespread speculation that sanctions may already be in the pipeline.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
