<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321349" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: FOCUS - Mexico to boost spending for infrastructure.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Mexico to boost spending for infrastructure.</headline>
<byline>Timna Tanners</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>After two years of concentrating on major privatizations, the Mexican Communication and Transport Ministry in 1997 plans major repairs of land and sea infrastructure in a bid to to make up for years of neglect and natural disasters.</p>
<p>Communication and Transport Minister Carlos Ruiz Sacristan said Tuesday that 12.6 billion pesos have been slotted for capital investments this year, up from 1996 expenditures of 12.35 billion pesos.  </p>
<p>&quot;Of this investment, 70 percent will be destined for highway and road infrastructure, about 20 percent to (other) transportation and about 10 percent to telecommunications,&quot; Ruiz said in a public forum before President Ernesto Zedillo.</p>
<p>The government plans to repair more than 260 bridges and about 1,860 miles (3,000 km) of roads in poor condition of the more than 26,000 miles (42,000 km) of roads under the ministry's jurisdiction.  </p>
<p>In a report on the ministry's 1997 work program, the government said it plans to modernize and expand infrastructure and improve the quality of transit.</p>
<p>&quot;No effort is sufficient if we cannot attend to one of the most recurrent demands of the society:  security,&quot; the report read.</p>
<p>Shippers have complained of rampant highway theft and looked to alternate transportation, such as rail or sea.</p>
<p>Deputy secretary for transportation Aaron Dichter said improving highway security, and steering more transit to the nation's freeways, is a &quot;top priority.&quot;  </p>
<p>Years of hurricanes and earthquakes have wreaked havoc on some of the country's weakest roads, and most of the repairs will be contracted to private companies, deputy minister of intrastructure Manuel Rodriguez said.</p>
<p>Expected Communication and Transport Ministry (SCT) spending for 1997 amounts to just a two percent increase from 1996, for a year-on-year decrease in real terms as inflation in 1996 totalled almost 28 percent.</p>
<p>But private investments, expected from new port and railway concessionaires, could supplement federal expenditures.  </p>
<p>He also said the government aims to resolve the border conflict with the United States that prevents crossing of Mexican trucks.</p>
<p>In telecommunications, the ministry applauded the new investment in long-distance service as Telefonos de Mexico SA (Telmex) lost its monopoly earlier this month.  The government hopes to extend phone service to rural areas currently unequipped, the ministry report said.</p>
<p>&quot;I have the confidence that this effort will be reciprocated by the private sector, taking advantage of the new legal codes that facilitate their participation in this important task,&quot; Zedillo said.</p>
<p>Last year the ministry auctioned key cargo ports and successfully sold a concession for the Northeast Railway for a surprisingly high $1.4 billion.</p>
<p>For 1997, the government plans to continue its privatization with auctions of smaller ports and railways, and begin selling operating right for airports, radio spectrum bands and satellites.  </p>
<p>((--Mexico City newsroom, +525 728-7903))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
