<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321423" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News-Jan 22.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News-Jan 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>In a move endorsed by the Commonwealth, the Australian Chamber of Commerce and Industry has asked the Industrial Relations Commission to arrange a special Full Bench to set out a core set of 20 subject areas for the stripping back of industrial awards under the new Workplace Relations Act. Page 2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Trade Minister Tim Fischer said yesterday that Australia intended to use the disputes processes of the World Trade Organisation more actively this year, starting with a request today for the formation of a disputes panel to take up a complaint against Hungarian subsidies on exports of agricultural products. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Federal Opposition Leader Kim Beazley said yesterday Labor would not support a goods and services tax, but would consider a streamlining of the indirect taxation system and would support a tax crackdown on high income earners in the May budget. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a budget submission it claims also caters for business needs, the Australian Council of Social Service has called on the federal government to strengthen the tax base in the May budget to boost revenue by A$1.2 billion in 1997/98 and A$5 billion in 1998/99. ACOSS supports strengthening the tax base rather than increasing rates. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>The option being pushed by state premiers, legislation to extinguish native title on pastoral leases, was rejected by supporters of native title yesterday. Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Commission chairman Gatjil Djerrkura warned that legislation for the removal of native title would make negotiation between the federal government and Aboriginal leaders impossible and Native Title Tribunal president Justice Robert French said Australia would face &quot;international political questions&quot; if it took such action. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A 12-year-old boy died and at least 20 homes were destroyed yesterday in the worst bushfires to hit Victoria since Ash Wednesday. At least 10 major fires raged around state capital Melbourne, with the worst blazes in the Dandenong Ranges and on the Mornigton Peninsula. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Business Council of Australia and the Australian Chamber of Commerce and Industry last night questioned the direction of the federal government's A$2 million inquiry into the future of higher education, claiming universities were making decisions against the national interest. Victorian Council of Deans of Education head Professor Richard Bates also criticised the inquiry, calling for the replacement of the inquiry head, retired school principal Roderick West. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Retired Supreme Court judge Sir James Gobbo will be sworn in on April 24 for a four-year term as Victoria's 25th Governor. The son of Italian migrants, Gobbo has pledged to promote multi-culturalism during his reign and will take on more ambassadorial duties to complement the traditional responsibilities of the Queen's representative. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>The government has backed a call from the Australian Chamber of Commerce and Industry for a test case in the Industrial Relations Commission to set down a template for simplification of federal awards. The case would set down ground rules forthe stripping back of more than 2000 complex federal awards. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>At the start of a summit of Aboriginal groups in Cairns, Aboriginal leaders called on the federal government to guarantee that it would not extinguish native title on pastoral leases nor make changes to the Racial Discrimination Act. Aboriginal and Torre Strait Islander Commission chairman Gatjil Djerrkura said indigenous groups would also demand all future talks involve a guarantee of social justice. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Bushfires continued to ravage Victoria yesterday, with hundreds of people being evacuated and at least 20 houses destroyed. Firefighters switched their attention last night to the Dandenong ranges where several houses were guttered by jumping fires, spured on by strong, hot winds. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>National Party Leader Tim Fischer is searching overseas for a job for disgruntled New South Wales back bencher Adrian Cruickshank in an attempt to entice him not to leave state Parliament before the 1999 poll. Cruickshank has threatened to leave politic after differences with his state leader Ian Armstrong. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Fires continued to burn out of control in Victoria, resulting in one person dead, 44 homes destroyed and hundreds of people evacuated from their homes. A drop in temperature of 15 degrees early in the evening brought no relief for firefighters as the continued to battle with fires throughout the state. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian Defence Force was placed on alert last night as fire conditions worsened throughout the evening. A statement by the Defence Force last night said that if conditions continue to deteriorate, Victoria could request assistance from the navy, army and air force. Page A2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Victorian Community Services Minister Denis Napthine said last night that people affected by bushfires may be eligible for financial and personal assistance after the Department of Human Services arranged emergency accommodation for more than 100 people who were unable to return to their homes. Page A2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>On the eve of today's Premier's Conference in Sydney to discuss the High Court's Wik decision, Victorian Premier Jeff Kennett said he wants state governments to negotiate directly with Aboriginal communities on land claims without the input of lawyer. Page A6.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
