<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321495" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: PM admits misjudgement as spill cleanup toll rises.</title>
<headline>PM admits misjudgement as spill cleanup toll rises.</headline>
<byline>Brian Williams</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto admitted on Tuesday that the government had misjudged the seriousness of Japan's worst oil spill disaster as the death toll in the cleanup operation rose to three.</p>
<p>With oil from a sunken Russian tanker still washing up along an ever-growing length of the Sea of Japan coast, authorities raced to put together a fleet of 1,000 boats for an an all-out effort to contain the damage.</p>
<p>The polluted area is dotted with shellfish farms, scenic beaches and marine bird sanctuaries along a 900-km (560-mile) stretch of coastline about 300 km (190 miles) west of Tokyo.</p>
<p>On Tuesday morning, one of the hundreds of volunteers involved in the cleanup had a heart attack on a polluted beach while lifting a drum used to scoop oil from the sand.</p>
<p>&quot;Matsubara Shigeki suffered a heart attack while lifting an oil drum. He was taken to hospital but he died shortly after,&quot; a police spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Matsubara, 53, was among a group of teachers involved in helping to clean their local stretch of polluted coastline.</p>
<p>Japanese media later reported that a 69-year-old fisherman from Fukui Prefecture also died during the cleanup, bringing the total number of deaths related to operation to three. A 77-year-old volunteer from Hyogo Prefecture died on Saturday.</p>
<p>The 13,157-tonne Nakhodka, carrying 19,000-tonnes (133,000-barrels) of heavy oil, broke in two in stormy seas in the Sea of Japan on January 2 some 130 km (80 miles) off the coast of Shimane Prefecture.</p>
<p>The captain is missing and presumed drowned, but the 31-man crew was rescued.</p>
<p>Takako Doi, leader of the Social Democratic Party, which supports Hashimoto's minority Liberal Democratic Party government, told reporters Hashimoto that told her during a meeting on Tuesday that the government had &quot;misjudged&quot; the seriousness of the accident.</p>
<p>Hashimoto told her the government's mistake was in believing the wrecked tanker could easily be salvaged, an assessment that turned out to be wrong when heavy seas prevented lines from being attached to the vessel.</p>
<p>She also quoted Hashimoto as saying that the government thought the oil would freeze in the cold weather, making it easy to collect.</p>
<p>But the fuel oil, a shipment from China, was a non-freezing variety destined for use in the bitter cold of Russia's Siberian winter.</p>
<p>In a bid to make up lost ground, Hashimoto has ordered a worldwide search for oil cleanup ships and his transport minister, Makoto Koga, has announced plans to put together a fleet of 1,000 boats of all types to tackle the spill.</p>
<p>Koga has said the vessels would include small fishing boats and any other volunteer private craft.</p>
<p>Koga told reporters the effort would be a hand-to-hand battle and anyone was welcome to join in.</p>
<p>&quot;In order to get rid of the oil as fast as possible we have to use the extremely unscientific, but most effective method of collection by hand,&quot; Koga said on Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
