<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321433" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Two dead as Australian forest fires tamed.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Two dead as Australian forest fires tamed.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forest fires have ravaged the outer suburbs of Australia's second biggest city, killing two people and destroying over 40 homes on the outskirts of Melbourne, police said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The smell of burning timber hung over the southern city as hundreds of firefighters worked feverishly to extinguish the last of the fires, which broke out in heatwave conditions on Melbourne's heavily wooded eastern fringe.</p>
<p>The fires were among about 10 major, scattered outbreaks in tinder-dry forest this week, forcing the evacuation of at least 800 people from their homes east, west and south of the city.</p>
<p>Firefighters, helped by a cool change in the weather and light rain, brought the last of the fires under control in the early hours of Wednesday, as police counted the cost of the state of Victoria's worst outbreak of fire in 14 years.</p>
<p>Two people were found dead after their house burnt down in the Dandenong mountain range on Melbourne's eastern fringe, a police spokesman told Reuters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Local media said the victims were a young couple aged in their 20s who took refuge from the fire in the basement of their home, but police said they were unable to confirm this.</p>
<p>&quot;It's now the job of mopping up,&quot; police spokesman Kevin Loomes said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're quite grateful more lives have not been lost...It certainly is the worst (fire outbreak) since the infamous Ash Wednesday fires,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Seventy-six people died and over 2,400 houses burnt to the ground in the so-called Ash Wednesday forest fires of summer 1983 in Victoria and the neighbouring state of South Australia.</p>
<p>At the height of the Dandenong fires on Tuesday, about 700 firefighters battled six major blazes fuelled by dry northerly winds and forests left parched by several days of temperatures hitting 40 degrees Celsius (104 degrees Fahrenheit).</p>
<p>The cause of the fires was not immediately known. The police arson squad is investigating.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard praised firefighters on Wednesday for risking their own safety to tame the blazes.</p>
<p>&quot;I just want to again thank on behalf of the public those magnificent volunteer and other firefighters who always perform so splendidly and in great danger on an occasion like this,&quot; Howard said in a television interview.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
