<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321449" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Britain to protest China plans for Hong Kong laws.</title>
<headline>Britain to protest China plans for Hong Kong laws.</headline>
<byline>Diane Stormont</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain will lodge a protest against China's plans to dilute laws guaranteeing civil liberties in Hong Kong after the 1997 handover, said Governor Chris Patten who denounced the proposals as &quot;legal nonsense.&quot;</p>
<p>China's intention of amending or repealing a list of 25 laws and ordinances have ignited a storm of protest in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Pro-democracy groups described it as a blow to democracy and human rights that would dent international confidence in Hong Kong beyond the handover at midnight on June 30.</p>
<p>&quot;We are discussing with London the diplomatic steps that we will now take, that will include of course raising our very deep concerns through the Joint Liaison Group machinery, but we will be going further than that,&quot; Patten told reporters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Chinese and British diplomats appointed to the Joint Liaison Group (JLG) meet regularly to thrash out transitional issues.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking at what more we can do. But clearly, we are concerned about what appears to be the reckless disregard which some Chinese officials seem to show for the impression created about Hong Kong, about its future, about its freedom, about its success and stability,&quot; Patten added.</p>
<p>China responded with alacrity. &quot;We cannot accept Patten's so-called statement,&quot; a foreign ministry spokesman said.</p>
<p>He urged the Hong Kong government to refrain from making statements that misled the inhabitants of the territory or undermined morale in the countdown to the handover.</p>
<p>Fears that China might embark along this particular track have been lurking since Beijing exploded in fury over democratic reforms spearheaded by Patten, who arrived in 1992 to lead Hong Kong through the changeover.</p>
<p>Sino-British relations nosedived and Chinese suspicion deepened about virtually every change put in place by the British in the twilight of colonial rule.</p>
<p>China has already selected a provisional legislature to replace the elected body returned in 1995 under the auspices of the Patten reforms.</p>
<p>On Sunday, a legal panel of the China-appointed Preparatory Committee responsible for transforming the British colony into a Special Administrative Region (SAR) of China drew up a list of laws and regulations it wants to reverse or amend.</p>
<p>At the top of the list were Patten's electoral reforms that broadened democracy and human rights legislation passed during Patten's stewardship to bring Hong Kong in line with the U.N. Convenant on Civil and Political Rights.</p>
<p>China argues that some clauses in the human rights ordinances conflict with the Basic Law, the post-1997 constitution for Hong Kong promulgated by Beijing in 1990.</p>
<p>Patten dismissed the arguments.&quot;They are, to be honest, legal nonsense and they would raise serious question-marks over the early days and weeks and months of the (future Hong Kong) Government,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chinese delegate to the JLG, Chen Zuo'er, praised the proposals for &quot;putting history back on the right track&quot;.</p>
<p>One group in Hong Kong however argued the Chinese-appointed panel did not go far enough.</p>
<p>The Heung Yee Kuk, which represents the clans of Hong Kong's New Territories hinterland, is furious that recent Hong Kong laws swept away traditional privileges accorded by the British to indigenous residents of the New Territories.</p>
<p>They were permitted to maintain a social system based on Qing dynasty practices, which precluded female inheritance.</p>
<p>This clashed with the human rights ordinance and was repealed to the fury of male clan leaders who said they plan to petition Beijing to repeal the laws and restore ancient rights.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
