<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321643" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. senators offer Superfund reform bill.</title>
<headline>U.S. senators offer Superfund reform bill.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two U.S. senators introduced a bill to accelerate cleanups of Superfund toxic waste sites nationwide among the first 10 bills offered Tuesday by the Senate Republican leadership.</p>
<p>The proposal by the chairman of the Senate Environment and Public Works Committee John Chafee of Rhode Island and Sen. Bob Smith of New Hampshire was similar to legislation that was deadlocked last year in face of solid opposition from Democrats and environmentalists.</p>
<p>Industry officials saw the early introduction of the bill as a move to renew debate soon on overhauling Superfund.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're not saying it's the end-all and be-all (bill),&quot; Chafee, a Rhode Island Republican, said on the Senate floor.</p>
<p>He said he hoped the final bill that his committee eventually would send to the Senate floor would have the Clinton administration's support.</p>
<p>The latest proposal would cap cleanup cost liability for municipalities which legally owned or operated a landfill where toxic wastes were dumped.</p>
<p>It would &quot;eliminate liability for anyone who legally sent waste to a municipal landfill,&quot; Chafee said.  </p>
<p>It would end the system of joint and several liability, which requires that any company that contributed toxic waste at a dump could be held liable for any or all cleanup costs at the site.</p>
<p>Instead, the bill would set up a process to proportionally allocate cleanup costs to make each polluter pay its fair share, Chafee said.</p>
<p>Industry officials said with the bill being introduced by a moderate Republican, environmentalists who resisted broad changes last year could not totally dismiss the new effort.</p>
<p>The insurance industry, which pushed for more sweeping liabilty relief, saw the bill as a positive sign.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's positive from the standpoint that it indicates there's still interest within the Senate and a commitment by Senator Chafee and the Senate leadership to Superfund reform,&quot; said David Farmer, senior vice president of the Alliance of American Insurers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
