<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321710" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYS gov supports phasing out sales tax on clothes.</title>
<headline>NYS gov supports phasing out sales tax on clothes.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York State Gov George Pataki on Tuesday said that while it would be hard to eliminate the four-percent state sales tax on clothing this year, he would back gradually eliminating the tax.</p>
<p>&quot;And I would be supportive of that as well,&quot; Pataki told reporters in Albany, estimating that ending the state's share of the sales tax on articles of clothing that cost less than $500 would cost the state $400 million a year in tax revenues.  </p>
<p>But he said some of the expected losses might be offset if sales rose and stores hired more workers.  </p>
<p>He continued: &quot;So it's a significant sum but as I look at it, it's a significant savings to the taxpayers as opposed to a loss to the state. But on the other hand, it has to be part of a balanced fiscal plan.&quot;</p>
<p>The Republican governor said he was encouraged by the first few days of a state-wide moratorium on sales taxes imposed on articles of clothing. The vast majority of local governments, including New York City, also have dropped their share of sales taxes on clothing for the week.</p>
<p>Sheldon Silver (D-Manhattan), the House Speaker, who pushed for the one-week tax break to be included in the state's fiscal 1997 budget, said earlier he would reintroduce a bill to end the state's share of the tax on clothing and footwear that cost less than $500. However, Pataki appeared to give another Republican, New York City Mayor Rudolph Giuliani, the credit for making the proposal, saying the mayor had &quot;three excellent ideas.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition to ending the clothing sales tax, which hurts the state and city because nearby states have lower or no such taxes, Giuliani proposed extending the current tax break through the weekend, though the governor said that would be difficult as he might lact the administrative authority to &quot;ply the legislature&quot; to do so. The mayor also had proposed having another one-week moratorium on sales taxes on clothing, and slating it just before the start of the new school year. ((--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
