<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321723" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton backs campaign finance reform.</title>
<headline>Clinton backs campaign finance reform.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton Tuesday challenged Republicans to agree to a bipartisan ban on large political contributions and renewed his endorsement of campaign finance reform legislation.</p>
<p>Speaking to the Democratic National Committee, Clinton said his party would stop accepting so-called &quot;soft money&quot; contributions if the Republican Party would do the same. These contributions are unlimited in size and are directed toward &quot;party-building,&quot; rather than specific candidates, but critics say they give large donors undue influence on the political process.  </p>
<p>Challenging Republicans to ban soft money, Clinton said: &quot;If you will do it, we will do it. We have offered our hand again and again. Why not just say yes?&quot;</p>
<p>Heavily criticized for the campaign financing tactics of himself and his party last year, Clinton also endorsed the reintroduction into Congress of a bipartisan bill to tighten rules for raising political funds sponsored by Arizona Republican Sen. John McCain and Wisconsin Democratic Sen. Russell Feingold.</p>
<p>&quot;It is tough, it is balanced, it is credible. It should become the law of the land,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>He chastised news media for their coverage of Democratic fundraising practices, saying Republicans were doing the same as Democrats and not receiving the same scrutiny.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
