<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321997" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Bonds trigger record Danish securities investment.</title>
<headline>Bonds trigger record Danish securities investment.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish investment associations' investments in securities last year grew by a record 53 percent to 55.3 billion crowns, boosted by bonds, the Danish Investors' Association Council said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;(Bank) interest rates in Denmark have fallen generally to very low levels, making investors more interested in the somewhat better yields offered by securities,&quot; Council chairman Carsten Mahler told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Another factor behind the record growth rate is the fact that Danes now seem to have more money at their disposal for investment purposes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the solid growth in overall association investment was due mainly to an &quot;explosive&quot; growth in investment in bonds.</p>
<p>Mahler said some 20.5 billion crowns of members' total investments were in bonds, about double the amount one year ago, and added that he saw no reason for the trend not to continue in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;There is every reason to expect the trend that we have seen in 1996 continue at the same tempo this year, with total invested association funds realistically capable of reaching 65 billion crowns at end-1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mahler said he foresaw greater investment activity among institutional investors this year, with pension funds in focus.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a definite tendency now for pension funds increasingly to use investment associations. Eight to nine billion crowns of the association's total investments emanate from pension funds,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he added that he expected 1997 to be a year of moderate earnings for investors, with average return on share investments a little over 10 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Shares have already climbed solidly since the new year, but we expect return on investment in stock this year to be on the right side of 10 percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Association figures showed Danish stocks recorded average pre-tax yields of 27.84 percent in 1996, compared with the Copenhagen Stock Exchange's all-share index rise of 28.83 percent for the year.</p>
<p>Global share portfolios posted an average 20.37 percent yield, while investments specialising in specific geographic areas showed earnings of an average 24.19 percent, the association said.</p>
<p>The equivalent figures for Danish and foreign bonds showed average pre-tax yields of 8.51 percent and 15.26 percent compared to J.P. Morgan index returns of 10.71 percent and 11.12 percent respectively.</p>
<p>The Danish Investors' Association Council is the umbrella organisation for Denmark's 18 investment societies, with over 100 branch offices and 350,000 members. --Chris Follett, Copenhagen newsroom +45-33969652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
