<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321916" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: FOCUS-Santander '96 profits rise 13.5 pct.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Santander '96 profits rise 13.5 pct.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's leading bank Banco Santander said on Tuesday its profits rose 13.5 percent last year, bolstered by strength in retail banking and its expansion in Latin America.</p>
<p>Net attributable income climbed to 85.60 billion pesetas ($631.5 million) in 1996 from 75.39 billion pesetas a year earlier. Profits were in line with analysts' average forecasts of 85.85 billion pesetas, according to a Reuter survey.</p>
<p>&quot;Reflecting a management commitment to maximising recurrent income, core business provided the backbone for 1996 results with group retail banking business making up 78.8 percent of operating profit,&quot; the group said in a statement.</p>
<p>Retail banking profits rose 31 percent from a year earlier.</p>
<p>Chairman Emilio Botin said Santander had forged a leadership position in loans, deposits and mutual funds both at home and abroad during the year.</p>
<p>He also pointed to growth from new acquisitions.</p>
<p>&quot;We have intensified the strategy of diversifying into new markets,&quot; Botin said.</p>
<p>Key purchases in 1996 included a $495-million purchase of Chile's Banco Osorno y La Union and a $280-million investment in Banco Central Hispano Puerto Rico, as well as buys in Peru and Germany.</p>
<p>Analysts noted the group had had heavy extraordinary earnings, but had used these to good purpose, helping to boost net bad debt provisions.</p>
<p>&quot;They have some capital gains but they are not letting it go to the bottom,&quot; said Inigo Lecubarri, director of Southern European banking research at Salomon Brothers in London.</p>
<p>Earnings on group transactions rose to 37.8 billion pesetas from 16.6 billion in 1995, the amount swelled by the bank's sale of a 2.2 percent stake in U.S. financial group First Union.</p>
<p>Net loan-loss provisions were 59.4 billion compared to 34.1 billion a year earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;These results were largely as expected. In general they shouldn't have surprised the market. One would have to point out the atypical receipts that have served to provision net bad debts,&quot; said Juan Berberana, analyst at AB Asesores in Madrid.</p>
<p>Analysts were also impressed by the solid jump in financial and trading income, which rose to 79.0 billion pesetas in 1996 from 55.7 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;They have had a big jump in trading income and I like to see that,&quot; Lecubarri said.</p>
<p>He said Santander could have considered some of these earnings as portfolio earnings, but did not need to because of the growth in traditional interest income.</p>
<p>--Madrid Newsroom +34 1 585 2167 ($ = 135.5 Spanish Pesetas)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
