<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="321921" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Peseta remains limp against mark in late trade.</title>
<headline>Peseta remains limp against mark in late trade.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The peseta remained limp against the mark in late trade on Tuesday, and traders said the Spanish currency would remain at the whim of developments in the mark and dollar in coming sessions.</p>
<p>By 1700 GMT, the peseta was trading around 83.59/61 compared with 83.43/45 in late trade on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have very much been linked to movements in the dollar and mark today,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The mark held strong against the European crosses in late trade after recent sharp falls, but traders said it remained vulnerable amid rate cut talk.</p>
<p>The dollar erased early gains after Treasury Secretary Rubin said he was not concerned about the effects of a strong dollar on the trade deficit.</p>
<p>Traders said there were few domestic issues on the agenda in the short-term, and the peseta would remain under the influence of developments in other key currencies.</p>
<p>Some traders also said technicals were playing an important role at the moment, and failure to break the 83.30 barrier in recent sessions had assisted a weakening of the Spanish currency.</p>
<p>Against the dollar, the peseta was trading at 135.52/57, compared with 134.40/50 late on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom + 34 1 585 2161</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
