<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="322322" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ashland Coal coal costs decline in Q4.</title>
<headline>Ashland Coal coal costs decline in Q4.</headline>
<dateline>HUNTINGTON, W.Va. 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ashland Coal Inc Tuesday reported its best quarterly results of 1996, citing reduced coal production costs.</p>
<p>And the company said it expects further cost improvements.</p>
<p>But fourth quarter profits of $9.4 million, or $0.50 per share on a fully diluted basis, still trailed the year earlier $11.6 million, or $0.61 per share.</p>
<p>Revenues for the fourth quarter were $152.1 million in 1996 and $169.2 million in 1995.  Coal sales were 5.8 million tons in the fourth quarter of 1996 compared to 6.0 million tons in the same period in 1995.  </p>
<p>&quot;As expected, fourth quarter results improved substantially over the previous quarters of this year,&quot; commented chief executive William C. Payne.</p>
<p>&quot;The cost of coal sold in the fourth quarter was a record low $22.51 per ton, $1 per ton lower than last year's fourth quarter. The operation of the dragline at Dal-Tex, which began in August of 1996, was the primary contributor to this improvement. &quot;With the dragline, production at the Dal-Tex (mine complex in southern West Virginia) increased 19 percent and cost per ton decreased 17 percent from fourth quarter 1995 levels.  </p>
<p>&quot;We expect further improvements in per ton cost as a result of both the move of the Hobet 21 dragline across Mud River, which occurred earlier this month, and the completion of a $10.5 million overland conveyor extension at the same mine, which is expected in the third quarter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>For the year, Ashland Coal earned $16.5 million, or $0.86 per share. In 1995, net was $41.4 million, or $2.16 per share.</p>
<p>Results throughout 1996 were adversely affected by the expiration of above-market contracts with CINergy Corp's Cincinnati Gas &amp; Electric Co at the end of 1995, Ashland Coal said.</p>
<p>In addition to these contract, the fourth quarter comparison is affected by a reduction in employee benefit expenses related to a revision of an actuarial estimate and operating revenue related to the termination of a coal supply agreement, both recognized in the fourth quarter of 1995.</p>
<p>These two nonrecurring items added $2.1 million to income before tax in the fourth quarter of 1995 relative to the fourth quarter of 1996. Because of the effects of percentage depletion, however, a lower effective tax rate (which was negative) in the fourth quarter of 1996 more than offset the effect of the above two items.</p>
<p>((-- Jim Brumm 212-859-1710.))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I11000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HUNTINGTON, W.Va."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
