<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="322693" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan seeks bids for second mobile phone network.</title>
<headline>Jordan seeks bids for second mobile phone network.</headline>
<byline>Dominic Evans</byline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan will announce a tender in March for a second mobile phone licence, breaking a monopoly which has existed since mobile phones were introduced to the kingdom in 1994, officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Youssef Abu Jamous, director-general of Jordan's Telecommunications Regulatory Commission (TRC), said the search for a second operator aimed to cut prices for phone users.</p>
<p>&quot;Competition is the name of the game,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>The TRC will formally announce the tender in March, but it is seeking preliminary applications by the end of January.</p>
<p>Those applications should give details of qualification to operate the system, compatibility with the existing operator, and proposed radio spectrums, licence fees, rates and geographical area covered by the phones.</p>
<p>Jordan, facing a serious shortage of fixed telephone lines, signed an exclusive four-year deal in 1994 with Jordan Mobile Telephone Services Company (JMTSC). The company is owned by Jordanian businessmen but the system was built up by U.S. firm Motorola Inc.</p>
<p>The new operator will be allowed to start in parallel with JMTSC in November 1998, when the exclusive deal runs out.</p>
<p>Abu Jamous said Jordan might accept more than one offer if the terms were attractive.</p>
<p>He said the TRC would set a price cap on customer charges once other operators started. Charges currently stand at 70 dinars ($100) for installation, 21 dinars per month subscription, and 180 fils to 245 fils a minute for local calls a peak rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The trend is for cellular phones and once the price is reasonable, people will prefer them,&quot; Abu Jamous said. Jordan now has around 27,000 mobile phone subscribers, he said.</p>
<p>($=0.71 dinars)</p>
<p>(1000 fils=one dinar)</p>
<p>-  Amman newsroom 9626 623776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
