<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="322779" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Korean union federation vows to continue strikes.</title>
<headline>Korean union federation vows to continue strikes.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Korean Confederation of Trade Unions (KCTU), South Korea's outlawed umbrella union group, said on Tuesday strikes would continue if the Seoul government did not promise to scrap controversial labour and security laws.</p>
<p>&quot;The plan of the KCTU is to continue for the moment the one day a week strike, which is on Wednesday this week,&quot; Yoon Young-mo, international spokesman for the KCTU, told a news conference in Paris.</p>
<p>Yoon added that if a statement declaring the legislation null and void was not forthcoming, there would also be a general strike on February 18.</p>
<p>&quot;We are calling on the government to make a clear statement that the labour and security laws are null and void,&quot; Yoon, who was due later to attend an OECD committee review of Korean labour law, told reporters.</p>
<p>Referring to South Korean President Kim Young-sam's earlier concession on reconsidering the laws, he added: &quot;We believe the decision of the Korean government is unsatisfactory and does not respond to our demand.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue to demand that these laws, passed in a secret meeting, be declared null and void,&quot; he said. He added his views were shared by representatives of other Korean trade unions present in Paris for the meeting of the Organisation for Economic Co-Operation and Development.</p>
<p>Yoon said representatives of the Federation of Korean Metalworkers Trade Unions were also in Paris. Both the KCTU and the Metalworkers were set to attend the OECD Labour Committee meeting later on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Earlier in Seoul, Kim Young-sam conceded that a new labour law had sparked public anxiety and hurt the economy, and agreed to send it back to parliament.</p>
<p>Labour strife had defeated the law's aim of revitalising a sluggish economy, he said. Production losses from stoppages have been estimated at more than $3 billion.</p>
<p>Kim agreed to reopen debate on another controversial law reviving a once notorious domestic spy agency.</p>
<p>Both laws were rammed through parliament in a six-minute dawn session on December 26 while opposition deputies slept.</p>
<p>In a further about-face, Kim told heads of three main political parties he would instruct officials to suspend arrest warrants served on strike leaders.</p>
<p>Kim's dramatic climbdown, after more than three weeks of strikes, followed a decision by the confederation to call off indefinite stoppages and limit action to one day each week.</p>
<p>The labour law makes it easier for firms to sack workers and replace strikers. It keeps a ban on freedom of union association by delaying recognition of the confederation until 2000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
