<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="322816" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Selective buying gives Austria shares late boost.</title>
<headline>Selective buying gives Austria shares late boost.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian shares recovered from a weak start on Tuesday to end just 1.08 points lower and traders forecast the market would make a cautious advance over the next few days.</p>
<p>Vienna airport company Flughafen Wien and brickmaker Wienerberger led a recovery that took the ATX index of 21 blue-chip shares to a 1,174.99 points close from a session low of 1,163.97.</p>
<p>February ATX futures were three points down at 1,179.</p>
<p>&quot;The recovery was all down to selective buying interest. People aren't buying the market but individual stocks,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Market participants pointed to 1,200 points as a short-term target for the ATX index but noted it would first have to overcome a hurdle at 1,175.</p>
<p>Overall nine shares finished up and 12 down. Flughafen Wien was the biggest gainer, apparently buoyed by a big buy order from abroad. Its stock rose 33 schillings, or 6.19 percent, to 566 schillings on turnover of almost 140,000 lots.</p>
<p>Wienerberger, which will present its provisional 1996 results on Thursday, climbed 34 schillings to 2,185 on volume of 18,012.</p>
<p>Ordinary shares in bank Creditanstalt-Bankverein were the biggest decliner, down 15 schillings, or 2.15 percent, at 682 schillings.</p>
<p>The broad-based Vienna Bourse index slipped 0.96 points to 438.44 -- Vienna Newsroom, 43-1-53112-258</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
