<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="322830" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Sulzer Medica market cap seen 3.0 bln Sfr.</title>
<headline>Sulzer Medica market cap seen 3.0 bln Sfr.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pierre Borgeaud, chairman of the board of Sulzer Technology Corp. said market estimates of the market capitalisation of Sulzer Medica of three billion Swiss francs were a fair esimtes.</p>
<p>&quot;That is a fair estimate,&quot; Borgeaud told a news conference, when asked about analysts' views of Medica having a market capitalisation of around three billion francs.</p>
<p>Earlier today Sulzer said it would sell off around 25 percent of its Medica unit sometime this year.</p>
<p>But chief financial officer Erich Mueller said the exact value of Medica would still have to be settled in talks with a bank that would be consulted on the public offering.</p>
<p>Sulzer has not yet decided on which bank should manage the public offering.</p>
<p>&quot;In no way do I want to commit myself to a particular figure,&quot; Mueller said.</p>
<p>Mueller said firms' like Medica generally traded at a price-earnings ratio (P/E) of at least 25 or more. The three billion Swiss franc figure was based on that assumption.</p>
<p>&quot;If you take the profit of Medica, then many analysts come up with with a figure of about this size,&quot; Mueller said.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
