<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="323045" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: PRESS DIGEST - Chinese newspapers - Jan 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Chinese newspapers - Jan 21.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Chinese political and business stories in leading newspapers, prepared by Reuters in Beijing. Reuters has not checked the stories and does not guarantee their accuracy. Telephone: (8610) 6532-1921. Fax: (8610) 6532-4978.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PEOPLE'S DAILY</p>
<p>Minister of Foreign Trade and Economic Cooperation Wu Yi says China's foreign trade volume is expected to reach $310 in 1997, up by 6.4 percent compared with last year.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA SECURITIES</p>
<p>Vice-minister of Finance Liu Jibin says China's T-bill issue system needs further reform, and cites problems in the secondary market.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>FINANCIAL NEWS</p>
<p>The People's Bank of China, the central bank, pledges to speed up reform of its notes processing and handling systems.</p>
<p>An analysts says China's booming stock market is partly attributed to a fall in M2 growth and a rise in M1 growth in 1996.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA BUSINESS DAILY</p>
<p>The head of China's grain reserve administration Luo Zhiling says domestic grain prices will rise in 1997.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA DAILY</p>
<p>China will allocate some of its rapidly growing foreign reserves as seller's credit for power projects to buy domestic generating systems.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>XINHUA DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>U.S.-based Hewlett-Packard Co captured an 11.4 percent share of China's personal computer market in 1996.</p>
<p>Sales of personal computers in China increased 56 percent to 1.8 million units.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ECONOMIC INFORMATION DAILY</p>
<p>Ningbo in eastern China's Zhejiang province handled 76.3 million tonnes of cargo in 1996, becoming the third largest seaport in China.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ECONOMIC DAILY</p>
<p>China cracked 230,000 economic crimes involving nearly 10 billion yuan ($1.2 billion) in 1996.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
