<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="323536" id="root" date="1997-01-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea set for talks to defuse labour crisis.</title>
<headline>S.Korea set for talks to defuse labour crisis.</headline>
<byline>Moon Ihlwan</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean President Kim Young-sam and opposition leaders were expected to meet on Tuesday to try to defuse a crisis over a new labour law that sparked more than three weeks of wildcat strikes.</p>
<p>The nation's attention was riveted on the lunch-time meeting after Kim, in a dramatic turnaround, agreed on Monday to discuss opposition criticism of the controversial legislation.</p>
<p>But union leaders and businessmen warned that a political compromise risked papering over their core concerns.</p>
<p>The talks at the presidential Blue House take place after unionists returned to work under a directive by the outlawed Korean Confederation of Trade Unions to call off indefinite strikes.</p>
<p>Opposition parties, who have thrown their weight behind the unions, said they would seek to reopen debate on the law.</p>
<p>The law allows firms to sack workers and replace strikers in a bid to free up the labour market to cut corporate costs and improve competitiveness. Under the law a ban on the militant confederation stands until 2000.</p>
<p>The officially-sanctioned Federation of Korean Trade Unions issued a statement urging the government to delay implementation of the law until June to give all political parties time to review the legislation.</p>
<p>&quot;The revision of the labour law has to be the enhancement of the living standards of the workers and in compliance with internationally recognised labour standards,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The legislation, rammed through parliament on December 26 in a dawn session by the ruling New Korea Party as opposition deputies slept, is due to take effect on March 1.</p>
<p>Stocks fluctuated early on Tuesday as investors delayed buying decisions until the talks. The main index fell 4.54 points to 713.92 after the first 25 minutes of trading.</p>
<p>A member of the outlawed confederation who declined to be named said the government appeared to be seeking a quick fix by offering a few carrots to unions.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is making a huge mistake and is misreading the situation if it thinks everything would be resolved by patching up a few clauses,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An official at the Korean Employers' Association said he believed the government would have to yield to pressure to immediately legalise the confederation, which had led the strikes that hobbled key export industries.</p>
<p>&quot;But deals should not be sought to make it more difficult for companies to lay off workers. This will worsen the labour market's rigidity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In a sign that authorities want a peaceful end to violent confrontation with labour unions, prosecutors have said they would hold off arresting seven unionists from the confederation sheltering at Seoul's Myongdong Cathedral.</p>
<p>South Korean factories operated normally for the first time on Monday since the law was rammed through parliament.</p>
<p>Political analysts said Kim would seek a compromise in a way to avoid becoming a lame duck in his last year of office.</p>
<p>&quot;If he declares the law void and agrees to start anew, that will be a full surrender and he would lose control over the national agenda for the rest of his tenure,&quot; said Kim Young-jin, a labour expert at Korea University.</p>
<p>President Kim, due to end his five-year term early next year, is barred by the constitution from seeking re-election but is expected to try to install a protege.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
