<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="323553" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Air Canada rises on seat sale, traffic.</title>
<headline>Air Canada rises on seat sale, traffic.</headline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Air Canada shares rose sharply on Wednesday after the airline announced a major seat sale in which certain fares would be cut up to 70 percent.</p>
<p>Air Canada was up 0.55 to a 52-week high of 7.80 in Toronto, in active trading of more than 3.4 million shares.</p>
<p>Research Capital Corp analyst Jacques Kavafian said the market was comparing Air Canada's favorable profit outlook with a cloudy one for domestic competitor Canadian Airlines Corp. Air Canada's seat sale was seen helping the airline protect market share in the face of a similar seat sale announced by financially troubled Canadian on January 9.  </p>
<p>&quot;Investors are basically saying Canadian is finished. Sooner or later, I think sooner, Air Canada's fortunes will rise substantially,&quot; Kavafian said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Air Canada announced a seat sale on more than 100 domestic and international destinations. The sale began today and was slated to continue until January 30 for travel until May 15.</p>
<p>Canadian's 12-day seat sale, which began on January 9, reduced prices by up to 50 percent on flights to more than 100 domestic and international destinations. The Canadian fares were reduced for flights between January 16 and May 15.</p>
<p>Kavafian said Air Canada's stock was also boosted by its strong December traffic numbers. On Tuesday, Air Canada said passenger traffic rose by 12.2 percent in December from the year earlier month. Canadian's passenger traffic numbers for December declined 6.1 percent from a year earlier.</p>
<p>Canadian was down 0.02 to 1.66 today in Toronto.</p>
<p>((Reuters Montreal bureau 514-985-2434))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
