<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="323774" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IPO HIGHLIGHTS - Mostly flat debuts for new issues.</title>
<headline>IPO HIGHLIGHTS - Mostly flat debuts for new issues.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Companies making their market debuts met with mostly lukewarm demand on Wednesday although analysts says stronger deals are expected next week.</p>
<p>After putting its IPO on hold during the July rough season, EarthLink Network Inc finally made it public. The company offered two million shares which priced at $13 a share, below its estimated pricing range of $14 to $16. The shares were flat at $13 in afternoon trading.  </p>
<p>CD Warehouse Inc, which franchises and operates stores that sell, trade and buy new and used compact discs, shares were flat at $5 after their IPO debut.</p>
<p>The Oklahoma City-based stock priced at the low end of its pricing range of $5-$6.25. Capital West was the lead underwriter of the offering.  </p>
<p>Another music company, Paradise Music &amp; Entertainment Inc, went public offering one million units for $6 each.</p>
<p>Like many of the other deals priced for trading today, it priced at the low end of its estimated range of $6 to $7 each.</p>
<p>The company makes original music scores for television, radio and movies and produces music videos and specials. It also manages music artists through a company called All Access, which manages Carly Simon, Daryl Hall and John Oates, and other including the Screaming Headless Torsos, according to its prospectus.  </p>
<p>SEEC Inc shares posted slim gains, rising to 9-5/8. It was the sole offering today that did not reflect weakness at its pricing, at a cost of $7.25 a share from its estimated range of $6 to $7.50 each.</p>
<p>HC Wainwright &amp; Co Inc was the lead manager of the 1.8 million-share offering. SEEC provides software for legacy COBOL software applications and related databases.</p>
<p>Printed circuit board maker Eltek Ltd crept up 1/2 to 5-1/2. The 1.5 million shares of the Israeli firm priced below their estimated pricing range of $6 to $7.</p>
<p>-- J Westhoven, Wall St Desk  (212) 859-1881</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
