<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="323977" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-MALDINI MAKES WINNING START AS ITALY'S NEW MANAGER.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MALDINI MAKES WINNING START AS ITALY'S NEW MANAGER.</headline>
<dateline>PALERMO 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cesare Maldini made a winning start as Italy's new national coach on Wednesday as goals from Gianfranco Zola and Alessandro Del Piero gave his new-look team a 2-0 win over Northern Ireland in a friendly match in Palermo.</p>
<p>Zola, of English premier league Chelsea, scored the opener in the 10th minute. He rounded goalkeeper Tommy Wright before finding the net from an acute angle after the referee had played the advantage rule for a foul on Pierluigi Casiraghi.</p>
<p>Del Piero of Juventus added a last minute second with a trademark, curling free-kick from wide on the left of the area.</p>
<p>In a rare display of national unity, 38,000 Sicilians crowded into &quot;La Favorita&quot; stadium to celebrate former under-21 manager Maldini's debut on the senior bench in place of Arrigo Sacchi, who resigned last December.</p>
<p>&quot;Forza Italia, let's start again,&quot; read one banner, unfurled as Maldini led his team through their pre-match warm-up.</p>
<p>The national side joined  in the nationalist spirit swapping their usual blue shirts and white shorts for an all-blue strip -- a colour which traditionally symbolises Italian soccer.</p>
<p>The new manager included most of the players picked by Sacchi for Italy's ill-fated Euro 96 adventure but fielded a five-man defence as preparation for a crucial World Cup qualifier against England at Wembley next month.</p>
<p>Northern Ireland, who have never won on Italian soil, rarely looked capable of equalising although James Quinn forced a full-length save from goalkeeper Angelo Peruzzi with a volley in the 55th minute.</p>
<p>At the end of the match, Maldini's team was applauded off -- a sharp contrast with Sacchi's side, booed and whistled on their last visit to Palermo in 1994 after a 2-1 defeat to Croatia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALERMO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
