<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324070" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products mixed, Italian buying lifts fuel.</title>
<headline>Med oil products mixed, Italian buying lifts fuel.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Med oil products ended mixed on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In gas oil, Russian heating oil remains very long because of an acute shipping shortage in the Med.</p>
<p>Outright prices slipped 75 cents in late futures weakness that wiped out earlier screen gains.</p>
<p>Traders said up to eight Russian cargoes are on offer between January 23 and February 3 alone. Only one buyer was seen, bidding cif high -$1 for Russian into Koper.</p>
<p>Russian elsewhere is at cif high Med +$1 basis Genoa, around unchanged. Cross-Med rates for a 30,000 tonner of gas oil remain at WSC 250. An Algerian is offered into NWE but high freight has made it difficult to place.</p>
<p>High and low sulphur fuel oil prices were notionally firmer alongside a recovery in NWE prices, and following Italian buying on Wednesday.</p>
<p>An Italian utility was heard to have bought two low sulphur cargoes on Tuesday, at least one of which was from a trader. Dealers said they thought this business had been done at around $118/$119 cif Italy.</p>
<p>Offers on Wednesday were heard out of Northwest Europe at $119 cif.</p>
<p>High sulphur cargoes were very thinly talked.</p>
<p>Gasoline prices edged up a notional $2, tracking higher NWE prices and a stronger crude market.</p>
<p>Local demand for lower octane material and for unleaded to U.S. destinations have also underpinned prices, traders said.</p>
<p>Naphtha was steady to slightly higher but traders said deals were very scarce due to high freight rates. End-users were reluctant to ship material either to the U.S. or to NWE.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 7646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
