<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324230" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SUDAN: Political isolation may force Sudan out of IMF.</title>
<headline>Political isolation may force Sudan out of IMF.</headline>
<byline>Christine Hauser</byline>
<dateline>KHARTOUM 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Perceptions of Sudan as an Islamic fundamentalist state could hurt its chances of avoiding expulsion from the International Monetary Fund after it defaulted on about $1 billion in debt, an IMF official said.</p>
<p>Jose Pedro de Morais, an IMF alternate executive director for 20 African countries, said Sudan defaulted last year on $5.5 million a month in repayments and the only fair alternative to &quot;compulsory withdrawal&quot; -- expulsion -- was to reschedule debt.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless there are impressive changes on how the Sudanese government is perceived outside, I don't see any possibility to avoid a compulsory withdrawal decision,&quot; he told Reuters late on Tuesday in Khartoum, where he met Sudanese ministers to prepare for an IMF meeting on January 31 that will consider expulsion.</p>
<p>Last month some directors on the IMF board argued for Sudan's expulsion if it did not pay its arrears, de Morais said.</p>
<p>Asked what he thought the chances were of expulsion, de Morais said: &quot;In previous meetings they made their point very strongly and very clearly, particularly the United States.&quot;</p>
<p>The United States says Sudan sponsors international terrorism, a charge Sudan denies. De Morais noted that the United States has almost 17 percent of the total capital of the IMF and corresponding influence among its directors.</p>
<p>&quot;The border (in the IMF) between economic and political aspects with economic implications...is really very weak and the tradition is that the fund has been dealing with political considerations which have major economic implications.&quot;</p>
<p>It &quot;seems...Sudanese authorities are perceived as a fundamental Islamic regime. And this is perceived by the major Sudanese partners as not good for this region,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Any decision on expulsion has to be approved by the annual IMF board of governors meeting.</p>
<p>Sudan, one of the world's poorest countries, is also facing a rebel offensive in the east and southeast of the country.</p>
<p>Since 1992 the Islamist military government has liberalised the economy with privatisation and import-export deregulation. The IMF has been trying to reach a debt agreement with Sudan on the basis of its economic and fiscal policies.</p>
<p>Sudan's current outstanding debt to the IMF is almost $1 billion, de Morais said. An IMF mission visited Khartoum this month to reassess Sudanese policies and the debt issue.</p>
<p>&quot;Concerning payments, the Sudan authorities were not able to commit anything for 1997. This is a point of major concern for the board,&quot; de Morais said. &quot;We think that Sudan is not able at all to commit $5.5 million a month to pay the fund.&quot;</p>
<p>De Morais said he did not think expulsion was a solution and that the Sudanese people would suffer if it happened.</p>
<p>&quot;What we need is IMF agreeing with the Sudan authorities a payment restructuring to rely upon Sudan's economic and financial policies, monitored by the IMF,&quot; de Morais said.</p>
<p>He said Sudanese authorities told him they planned to continue reforms in 1997 such as levying a tax on oil products and completing the elimination of fuel subsidies.</p>
<p>Subsidies are a sensitive issue in Sudan and their progressive reduction has sparked riots in Khartoum.</p>
<p>De Morais said the other major policy matter which Sudan intended to implement from mid-February is to narrow the gap between dollar customs valuation and the official exchange rate.</p>
<p>He said Sudan's GDP grew five percent in 1996 and inflation was falling. Sudan Finance Minister Abdel Wahhab Osman has said inflation is expected to fall to 70 percent in 1997. Inflation in 1996 was about 140 percent.</p>
<p>But de Morais said Sudan had $20 billion in total external debt in 1996, $17 billion of it in arrears. Its debt service last year was 150 percent of balance of payment receipts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KHARTOUM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SUDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
