<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324221" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TANZANIA: Tanzania's northern arabica coffee hit by drought.</title>
<headline>Tanzania's northern arabica coffee hit by drought.</headline>
<byline>Maja Wallengren</byline>
<dateline>DAR ES SALAAM 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Drought in northern parts of Tanzania has hit the country's premium arabica coffee and the volume of the 1997/98 crop is expected to drop, industry officials and traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>They said while the drought did not have any large impact on the 1996/97 crop that is estimated at between 41,000 to 43,000 tonnes and is almost completely harvested, it would affect the 1997/98 crop for which the coffee trees have started to flower.</p>
<p>&quot;The current drought is going to affect the 1997/98 crop,&quot; said Tanzania Coffee Board Managing Director Edward Sannda.</p>
<p>&quot;If the long rains come early, (as early as) in February, the effect on the coffee won't be that bad, but if the rain doesn't come until April then it will be quite serious.</p>
<p>&quot;There is (coffee) flowering at the moment which is being affected, but it's difficult to forecast the 1997/98 crop right now,&quot; Sannda told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Short rains which normally fall in late November or early December failed to come last year leading to widespread drought that has caused the worst water shortage in the capital Dar es Salaam in 40 years, according to weather experts.</p>
<p>The drought has especially hit the coffee crops in the northern Moshi region surrounding Mount Kilimanjaro, which comprises about 50 percent of Tanzania's arabica production.</p>
<p>The mild washed arabica coffee grown in this region are of high quality and sold at the world's coffee markets at prices only surpassed by those of Kenya and Colombia, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's quite dry here now and we are praying for the rains to come soon, but the situation is not very good, there is definitively going to be a drop,&quot; a trader told Reuters by telephone from the northern Tanzania coffee town of Moshi.</p>
<p>Jeremy Lefroy, managing director of the African Coffee Co and an official of the Tanzanian Coffee Traders Association said his association would have problems supplying all their customers with coffee in the coming season.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to have quite a serious effect, unless we'll have rains within the next few weeks. We are not going to have enough coffee for our customers as it stands at the moment,&quot; Lefroy told Reuters by telephone from Moshi.</p>
<p>He said that while it was impossible at this time to make any forecasts, the association was looking more towards improving overall standards of coffee production by replanting ageing coffee trees, many of which are close to 100 years old.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a crop, but it's difficult to say how big right now. We are instead looking at the long-term development by trying to improve the quality through replanting,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the coffee stock is newer and younger you will have a better crop, even in years with poor rains and drought.&quot;</p>
<p>The board's Sannda said rains in the southern Mbeya region, which also grows arabicas, had been &quot;very good&quot; and reports from the western robusta-growing Bukoba region were also positive.</p>
<p>&quot;In the south we are now getting reports about very good rains and Bukoba this (crop) year is going to produce a record harvest. We estimated it at about 16,000 tonnes but it's already passed that figure and they are still not finished with the harvesting,&quot; Sannda said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAR ES SALAAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TANZANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
