<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324366" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Quality makes Pick a &quot;buy&quot;-OTP Securities.</title>
<headline>Quality makes Pick a &quot;buy&quot;-OTP Securities.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>An analyst report recommended Hungary's leading meat processor company Pick as both a short- and long-term buy despite forecasts of slower sales growth than other companies on the Budapest Stock Exchange (BSE).</p>
<p>&quot;Pick is a mature company and is unlikely to experience high growth,&quot; OTP Securities, part of the OTP banking group, said in its latest report.</p>
<p>&quot;At the same time it would be wrong to regard the high level of development as a negative factor.&quot;</p>
<p>Since acquiring its largest competitor Herz in 1994, Pick has seized more than 90 percent of the Hungarian high-quality salami market, OTP Securities analyst Andras Szalkai said.</p>
<p>But confidence in Pick is also founded on its success in Western markets, which other companies are unable to penetrate, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Pick alone accounts for one-third of all Hungarian meat exports,&quot; Szalkai said. &quot;Pick's largest export market is Germany, a traditionally demanding market.&quot;</p>
<p>Szalkai said the 128-year-old company's finances were stable and predicted sales slightly higher than inflation over the coming years, helped by an expected increase in Hungarians' purchasing power.</p>
<p>He forecast price/earnings ratios of 10.52 and 8.94 for 1997 and 1998 results, respectively and expected the company to campaign more aggressively to increase sales to Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>In the short-term said Pick will benefit from the BSE's continued good performance, he said, while he projected 1996 pre-tax profit and net sales figures six to seven percent above the company's targets of 2.2 billion and 25.6 billion forints respectively.</p>
<p>&quot;Our recommendation is for the short-term buy (and) we rate Pick a long-term buy due to its steady growth prospects,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>-- Duncan Shiels, Budapest newsroom (361) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
