<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324307" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech PX50 edges down, blue chips make up losses.</title>
<headline>Czech PX50 edges down, blue chips make up losses.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czech shares closed mostly higher on Wednesday, with blue chips rebounding from early losses on inflows of foreign funds, dealers said.</p>
<p>Further gains were likely on Thursday, they said.</p>
<p>SPT Telecom fell 12 crowns to 3,385 and CEZ closed four crowns lower at 1,954 to drag the RPIX index down 0.5 points to 1,159.6. Komercni Banka was unchanged at 2,370 crowns.</p>
<p>Blue chips, which have been rising steadily in recent weeks, fell in early trade but made up ground before the close.</p>
<p>&quot;There is renewed interest and basically all the losses we made in the morning we covered in the afternoon,&quot; said Marco Anderegg, trader at Patria Finance.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the official market, it was maybe slightly down, but if you look at the OTC market, we are above yesterday's levels,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Some analysts have said many blue chips now appear fairly valued and that upside may be limited. However, Anderegg said there had been a comfortable flow of funds, mainly from foreign investors.</p>
<p>Cigarette maker Tabak, majority-owned by U.S.-based Philip Morris Cos Inc, was the day's big gainer, jumping 280 crowns to a 52-week high of 8,080. The stock is highly illiquid.</p>
<p>Insurer Ceska Pojistovna closed 166 higher at 3,499 crowns.</p>
<p>Engineering giant Skoda a.s. rose six crowns to 1,009. Analysts say the company's acquisitions of truck-makers Tatra and Liaz will depress otherwise healthy results.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
