<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324447" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Bema explores for gold in Chile belt.</title>
<headline>Bema explores for gold in Chile belt.</headline>
<byline>Margaret Orgill</byline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian mining firm Bema Gold Corp will invest $30 million this year in exploration in Chile's Maricunga gold belt including drilling at the newly discovered Cerro Casale gold deposit, said president Clive Johnson.</p>
<p>&quot;There are numerous exploration targets in the Maricunga district,&quot; Johnson told a news conference.</p>
<p>The firm is investing $2 million a month at Cerro Casale with drills reaching two kilometers into the mineral body which lies on the desolate southern fringes of the gold belt close to the border with Argentina.</p>
<p>Cerro Casale, which could be among the world's largest gold mines, is one of a number of sites in the mineral-rich belt which have caught geologists' attention, he said.</p>
<p>This week Bema will start drilling at a site known as Quebrada Seca -- Spanish for &quot;dry ravine&quot; -- which lies high in the Andes east of Cerro Casale, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our geologists think this could be the best target in the whole of the Maricunga district,&quot; said Johnson.</p>
<p>Preliminary results from the prospecting should be released within the next six weeks, he said.</p>
<p>Quebrada Seca is one of four exploration sites on the Quebrada property which is wholly owned by Vancouver-based Bema.</p>
<p>Johnson said his company has also discovered another possible gold ore body known as Cerro Roman which, like Cerro Casale, lies on the nearby Aldebaran property which is owned by Bema and its subsidiary Arizona Star Resource Corp  AZS.Vu.</p>
<p>&quot;This has potential to be another multi-million ounce gold discovery,&quot; said Johnson.</p>
<p>Cerro Casale is expected to produce one million ounces of gold a year although this figure could be higher if drilling shows reserves are larger than the company's &quot;very conservative&quot; estimate of 15 million ounces.</p>
<p>The deposit is unusual in that it also contains a large amount of copper.</p>
<p>Once built, it will be Chile's largest gold mine and more than three times the size of Bema's only Latin American gold operation -- the 230,000-ounce Refugio pit which lies nearby.</p>
<p>Cerro Casale will cost up to $1 billion to develop and Bema will consider bringing in a larger mining company to help finance, and possibly operate, the pit, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the right circumstances we might allow companies which have built mines of this size before to become the operator,&quot; said Johnson.</p>
<p>&quot;That could free Bema to build other mines in Chile like Refugio.&quot;</p>
<p>Bema has protected itself from a hostile takeover by a larger firm by asking companies interested in studying Cerro Casale to sign an agreement not to buy shares in Bema or Arizona for the next two years, said Johnson.</p>
<p>Twelve companies have signed this agreement so far, he added.</p>
<p>((-- Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595x212))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
