<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324435" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Miners in Mexico dig for colonial crumbs.</title>
<headline>Miners in Mexico dig for colonial crumbs.</headline>
<byline>Chris Aspin</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY</dateline>
<text>
<p>Miners in Mexico are increasingly scratching around for gold and silver leftovers at old colonial sites rather than trying to locate a new El Dorado.</p>
<p>Turning old prospects that were originally opened up by Spanish conquistadores into new projects is the new style in Mexican mining.</p>
<p>For 465 years, the Real del Monte mine at Pachuca, in the state of Hidalgo, north of Mexico City, has been churning out gold and silver. But in recent years output has increasingly been on the wane.</p>
<p>Now, Denver-based Consolidated Nevada Goldfields Corp. has bought up the property and has designs on reviving former glories.</p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Geoffrey Hoyl said he will boost output 300 percent in five years, mainly by rehabilitating the rusty plant and machinery and improving mining methods.</p>
<p>&quot;At the end of the day, we will be producing 6.7 million ounces (of silver) per year at Pachuca which will make us one of the biggest producers in the hemisphere,&quot; Hoyl said.</p>
<p>Over the years, Real del Monte has produced 1.3 billion ounces of silver and 6.2 million ounces of gold.</p>
<p>At Real de Catorce, Vancouver-based Britannia Gold Corp. is starting a drilling programme in February in the silver-rich area of the central state of San Luis Potosi.</p>
<p>Real De Catorce, now reduced to a ghost town, was first mined in 1773. Production there only ground to a halt in 1990 because of low grades and high costs.</p>
<p>Over its 224-year history it has produced 200 million ounces of silver. The only entrance to the dusty town, now visited mostly by tourists, is through a 1.5 mile tunnel that was formerly the main mine shaft.</p>
<p>&quot;We are generally looking at historic Mexican sites,&quot; said Fred Felder, mineral exploration consultant for Britannia. &quot;These camps are extremely good ones to explore,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Britannia is on the hunt for around 2 million tons of ore in high-grade ranges and has not discounted processing tailings -- leftovers from previous miners -- which total around 2 million tons. &quot;Working tailings would not be a primary objective, though,&quot; Felder said.</p>
<p>Toronto-based Metallica Resources Inc. will revive another gold-silver mine next year at Cerro San Pedro, also in San Luis Potosi state, a mine that was worked for 427 years.</p>
<p>A company official said plant construction work was scheduled to start in August this year, with output expected between March and June next year.</p>
<p>Metallica's objective is to reach annual gold output levels of 150,000 ounces and a silver production of 4 million ounces per year using open-pit mining and leach pad methods.</p>
<p>Over the years the richest veins at San Pedro have been exhausted by Mexicans using picks and spades. But there is still enough low grade ore present and within easy access to make the $75 million project feasible, he said.</p>
<p>San Pedro still has proven and probable reserves of 1.5 million ounces of gold and 62 million ounces of silver, he added.</p>
<p>A Metallica executive anticipated total operational costs of $230 per ounce of gold which still translates to heathy profits despite the recent slump of gold prices to just over $350 per ounce.</p>
<p>Over the years, San Pedro has produced around 2.5 million ounces of gold and between 40 million to 50 million ounces of silver, the executive said.</p>
<p>Canada's Teck Corp. openly admits its mining strategy in Mexico is to revamp former mines.</p>
<p>&quot;We are into turning old prospects into new prospects,&quot; Vice President Joseph Ruetz said. Teck's Mexico unit Minera Teck SA is currently &quot;digging around&quot; at its Nukay gold mine in Guerrero state.</p>
<p>Nukay, although not a mine from colonial days, has been mined for decades.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
