<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324506" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil sees no problem with arabica coffee prices.</title>
<headline>Brazil sees no problem with arabica coffee prices.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's government does not see any problem with world arabica coffee prices but it is open to discuss any measure backing the market, said an official at the Industry and Commerce Ministry.</p>
<p>&quot;We said at the last meeting of the Association of Coffee Producing Countries (ACPC) that there was no problem with arabica. The problem at the moment is robusta coffee,&quot; Mauricio Assis, head of the ministry's primary commodities department, told reporters at an international coffee seminar.</p>
<p>&quot;But whatever measure which supports the market is in the interest of Brazil,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Members of the ACPC meet Jan 23 in Rio to discuss an African proposal to cut 2.5 million 60-kg bags of exports in the first half of the year.</p>
<p>Some producers delegates held preliminary technical discussions this afternoon, but they declined comment on the outcome of the talk.</p>
<p>One of the key factors in the plan is if and by how much major robusta producer Indonesia would cut exports in the first half of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;We are all in one family, that is the ACPC family,&quot; Paian Nainggolan, director general of the Indonesian department of trade, restricted to say.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not had the statistics, we have not had a full meeting. We need to sit down and see the statistics which will only take place tomorrow,&quot; said Derek Watson, advisor to the Indonesian delegation. ((--Caroline Bulloch, Rio de Janeiro Newsroom 5521 5074151))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
