<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324633" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: INTERVIEW - Motorola eyes Thai telecoms.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Motorola eyes Thai telecoms.</headline>
<byline>Anuchit Nguyen</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Motorola Inc sees potential for more involvement in the development of Thailand's growing telecommunications market as the country liberalises the sector further, a senior official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The potettial here is still very large. There remains very strong demand around. I am very optimistic (about Thailand),&quot; Richard E.Sell, Corporate vice president and General Manager of Motorola Asia/Pacific Cellular Infrastruture Group, told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;I can say that Thailand is one of our largest markets in the Asia/Pacific region. If the economy stays strong, the growth will continue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He was in Thailand for the signing of a $120 million loan agreement to support the sale of an advanced phone system to local mobile phone operator, Total Access Communication Plc.</p>
<p>Sell declined to give Motorola's total revenue generated in Thailand, but added that growth has been at double digits since it first got involved in the country a decade ago.</p>
<p>Motorola wanted to provide more sophisticated telecommunication equipement to other Thai phone operators as the market liberalised, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We view (the liberalisation) an increasing opportunity to provide other operators equipment. We will continue to watch that carefully,&quot; Sell said.</p>
<p>Under Thailand's new telecommuniation master plan which is being drafted by the transport and communications ministry, the government plans to allow additional mobile phones and fixed-line telephones operators into the market.</p>
<p>The Thai market has so far been dominated by three mobile phone operators and two fixed line operators who were in the past given concessions by the government for the business.</p>
<p>The move to allow more operators in the market will be aimed at increasing competition in the industry and to reduce most telecommunication service fees, analysts said.</p>
<p>Sell said the low penetration rate of wireless telecommunications in Thailand would also make the country a high potential market for further development in that sector.</p>
<p>Motorola also had a strong interest in the Vietnam market where the telecommunication network was underdeveloped, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Vietnam market is just getting started. They are also showing a tremendous interest because the telecommunication system there is very underdeveloped,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
