<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324601" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>philippines: Fierce fighting in southern Philippines kills 23.</title>
<headline>Fierce fighting in southern Philippines kills 23.</headline>
<byline>Roel Pareno</byline>
<dateline>ZAMBOANGA, Philippines 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine troops backed by helicopter gunships killed 21 Moslem rebels in fierce fighting on southern Mindanao island, the military said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Two soldiers died and four others were wounded in Tuesday's three-hour gunbattle that forced about 2,000 civilians to flee their homes in Buldon in Maguindanao province, officials said.</p>
<p>In Manila, President Fidel Ramos said he had directed government negotiators to arrange a ceasefire with the guerrillas to halt the bloodshed.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope it will be done through the efforts of our panel and the MILF panel with the support of a lot of people,&quot; Ramos told his weekly news conference.</p>
<p>Major-General Romeo Padiernos told reporters he had ordered about 1,000 troops into the offensive against an estimated 400 guerrillas of the Moro Islamic Liberation Front (MILF).</p>
<p>&quot;I said, give it to them...They get what they deserve,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Government forces, backed by seven helicopter gunships, pounded rebel positions with mortars and rockets in the fiercest fighting in months with the MILF, which is demanding an Islamic state in the southern islands, military spokesmen said.</p>
<p>MILF vice-chairman for political affairs Ghazzali Jaafar said in a radio interview later he had met with an army general and they had agreed on a &quot;cessation of hostilities&quot; effective immediately.</p>
<p>The military initially reported 20 MILF rebels were killed but Padiernos said the rebel death toll had risen to 21.</p>
<p>The MILF is a breakaway faction of the mainstream Moro National Liberation Front, which reached a peace deal with Manila in October last year.</p>
<p>The MILF is not a party to the pact but held preliminary talks with a government panel on January 7 on ending their rebellion.</p>
<p>Both sides then agreed to resume their talks on February 25. They also agreed on a temporary ceasefire but that agreement did not cover Buldon.</p>
<p>The military reinforced its forces around Buldon last week after suspected MILF rebels ambushed a convoy carrying Buldon town Mayor Macarampat Manalao on Saturday, killing two soldiers.</p>
<p>The MILF claims to have 80,000 fighters, but the military estimates their strength at between 6,000 and 8,000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAMBOANGA, Philippines"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
