<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324621" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Handover themes dominate Hong Kong 1997 fashion.</title>
<headline>Handover themes dominate Hong Kong 1997 fashion.</headline>
<byline>Sonya Hepinstall</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chinese flag, fast-food packaging and traditional costumes have taken centre stage in Hong Kong fashion this year, reflecting designers' &quot;real world&quot; preoccupations in the year of the transition to Chinese rule.</p>
<p>The models of Hong Kong designer Peter Lau sported symbols of rebellion at this year's &quot;Fashion Week&quot; shows on Wednesday, slinking down the catwalk with bright red Chinese flags masking their faces and carrying candles.</p>
<p>His collection, labelled Winter Under the Red Flag, is &quot;about the period now going into 1997,&quot; Lau told Reuters.</p>
<p>Britain will hand the territory back to China at midnight on June 30, ending more than 150 years of colonial rule.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese flag represents the influence of Beijing getting bigger and bigger, and is an expression of the feelings of youngsters... in a rebellious mood,&quot; Lau said.</p>
<p>The collection was characterised by body-revealing silhouettes but also featured thick jackets with the high collars and extra-long sleeves characteristic of traditional Chinese dress.</p>
<p>Chinese style also dominated the collection of Flora Pavlova Cheong-leen, whose dramatic show began with a woman with a baby strapped to her back in the style of rural China.</p>
<p>Her clothes were anything but rural, however -- a bright red silk tunic with high collar revealing one slinky arm, patterned with Chinese embroidery over deep green slim velvet trousers.</p>
<p>Even the most daring outfits -- of revealing lace or sheer materials, cut backless or paired with sultry hosiery hitched halfway up the thigh -- made concessions to tradition with a piece of antique embroidery here and there.</p>
<p>Pavlova refused to say her collection was focused on the 1997 handover, however, saying that theme was too &quot;kitsch&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm a costume designer so I like using the old styles and changing it into the more contemporary... what I think it really is, is about change... I think China and the Western world are merging,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>On the first day of the show on Tuesday designer Pacino Wan clothed his models in a dress of noodle soup packaging and a hoop skirt covered in cup-cake wrappers, which he said reflected Hong Kong people's obsession with fast food.</p>
<p>The designs showed &quot;what Hong Kong people will look for in life after the handover&quot;, Wan told reporters.</p>
<p>Organisers say Hong Kong fashion week is one of the largest annual fairs of its kind in Asia. This year's is the biggest ever with 840 exhibitors.</p>
<p>The fact that it would also be the last before the handover of Hong Kong, considered Asia's fashion capital, was foremost in the minds of many there.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the last fashion week before the important, historic changes in the middle of this year,&quot; Hong Kong Governor Chris Patten, who is currently wrangling with Beijing over the territory's future, said when he launched the event on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that we are looking at winter and fall designs for the end of the year and next year is a reminder that here in Hong Kong, life will go on being spectacularly successful,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFAS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
