<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324805" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBC seen as bidder for LIN Television.</title>
<headline>NBC seen as bidder for LIN Television.</headline>
<byline>Lisa Marie Pane</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Speculation that General Electric Co's NBC television network was a leading contender to buy Lin Television Corp flared anew on Wall Street this week.</p>
<p>That scenario &quot;has come up more frequently lately,&quot; said UBS Securities analyst Edward Hatch. &quot;It would be a natural fit for them.&quot;</p>
<p>In late afternoon trading, LIN's stock rose 1-1/4 at 42-3/4.</p>
<p>Still, other analysts said they could see AT&amp;T keeping its 45 percent stake in LIN -- and encouraging the Providence, R.I.-based company to pursue its own acquisitions.  </p>
<p>AT&amp;T spokesman Jim Byrnes said the company would have no comment beyond its statement last month that it was assessing its investment in LIN. NBC officials were not immediately available to comment.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very skeptical the company is actually up for auction,&quot; Bankers Trust analyst Mark McFadden said.</p>
<p>LIN owns three television stations affiliated with NBC, three CBS affiliates and two ABC affiliates.</p>
<p>In addition to NBC, other potential suitors include Cox Communications Inc, Gannett Co, E.W. Scripps Co and Walt Disney Co's ABC.  </p>
<p>Byrnes said that since AT&amp;T outlined its plans in a filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, &quot;there have been a few&quot; inquiries from companies interested in its LIN stake.</p>
<p>&quot;On the surface, NBC is the most logical,&quot; Smith Barney analyst William Meyers said.</p>
<p>An ABC acquisition of LIN would extend a string of big consolidations and mergers in the broadcast industry during the past year.</p>
<p>Although LIN has been trading at about $43 per share, at least one analyst said the deal could be valued at more than $50 per share.  </p>
<p>&quot;Based on some recent dealings, $50 to $52 a share wouldn't be unreasonable,&quot; Hatch said.</p>
<p>Smith Barney's Meyers pegged it at closer to the &quot;upper $40s to $50s.&quot;</p>
<p>Bankers Trust's McFadden said he thought LIN was more inclined to pursue acquisitions of its own, using its stock as currency.</p>
<p>He said he had doubts that NBC or other television networks would actively pursue LIN since it has held on to its television stations for long enough to allow for a low taxation basis. That would mean that any buyer would have to pay a premium in taxes.</p>
<p>His sentiments were echoed by Salomon Brothers' Paul Sweeney, who also said LIN may pursue its own acquisitions. Even if the company ends up on the auction block, Sweeney said, &quot;I don't think it's a foregone conclusion&quot; that NBC is the leading contender.</p>
<p>&quot;It just persistent rumors,&quot; Sweeney said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
