<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324831" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cyprus expects higher coal earnings in '97.</title>
<headline>Cyprus expects higher coal earnings in '97.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cyprus Amax Minerals' coal earnings and output will be higher in 1997, despite some of the company's sales contracts having been ripped up and replaced with lower priced deals, company officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;The coal market in general is a real challenge right now,&quot; Milton Ward, president, chairman and CEO of Cyprus told an analysts briefing Wednesday.</p>
<p>Cyprus claims to be the largest U.S.-owned coal producer, and second largest operating in the domestic market.</p>
<p>Cyprus produced 80 to 82 million tons of coal in 1996, with an additional 10 to 11 million tons expected in 1997. U.S. coal production is over one billion tons per year.</p>
<p>During 1996 Cyprus &quot;reached accommodation&quot; with several coal customers after renegotiating long-term high-priced contracts for &quot;reasonable terms&quot;, said Garold Spindler, president of Cyprus Amax Coal Co.</p>
<p>Total impact in 1997 coal earnings due to renegotiating the contracts will be about $20 million, he said.</p>
<p>However, Cyprus was better off having renegotiated some of its contracts and worse off with others, but the company would not hesitate to renegotiate any contract on an &quot;opportunistic&quot; basis if it offered cash up front or other benefits, Ward said.</p>
<p>Cyprus expected its 1997 coal earnings to be somewhat better than the $90 million it earned last year. Earnings in 1995 were $137 million.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not going to do as well in the near-term in that business as we thought we were,&quot; Ward said. &quot;It's a fairly brutal market out there, particularly in the (Wyoming) Powder Basin.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;None of our contracts at the current time are threatened but it's always a battle in this business when you have above-market contracts,&quot; Ward added.</p>
<p>Cyprus said it was looking at possibilities of swapping contracts and embarking on joint ventures with other players in the industry.</p>
<p>Powder River Basin coal producers were obviously selling on an incremental cost basis, Ward said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that, in itself, tends to cause prices to go down because in order to capture a sale you are selling at prices lower than a typical price one would expect,&quot; Ward said.</p>
<p>But over the next few years as contracts expire &quot;people are going to have to sell based on full cost, and that's when we expect to see a turnaround in that market area,&quot; Ward said.</p>
<p>This improvement would come around 1998, Spindler noted.</p>
<p>Apart from Powder River, coal markets in the rest of the country were surprisingly strong, Spindler said.</p>
<p>&quot;Utah is a tight market, as is Colorado. The east has seen some pretty steady and consistent growth since the first quarter of last year,&quot; Spindler said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are seeing some general trends which are very encouraging in most of the market places that we are in,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>((Huw Jones, New York Commodities 212-859-1646))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
