<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324837" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Papers show how Gingrich PAC used tax-exempt money.</title>
<headline>Papers show how Gingrich PAC used tax-exempt money.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Documents released over the weekend show how a political action committee run by House Speaker Newt Gingrich used tax-deductible money to fund Republican congressional candidates, the Los Angeles Times reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The &quot;internal memos and documents&quot; cited by the Times were included in papers the House Ethics Committee used in a two-year investigation of Gingrich. Federal law prohibits non-profit charities from engaging in partisan politics.</p>
<p>The Times reported GOPAC, the political action committee run by Gingrich until 1995, urged donors to pay a minimum of $10,000 in charter dues to the Abraham Lincoln Opportunity Foundation, a non-profit group formed to help inner city youths. The money was forwarded to GOPAC, which used it to fuel Republican campaigns for public office.</p>
<p>In one case, papers show a GOPAC official told an unnamed New York businessman that if he paid dues to the foundation he would &quot;be of enormous help in our efforts to change Congress in 1992.&quot; The businessman contributed $25,000 to the foundation and nine days later it sent the money to GOPAC.</p>
<p>The House Tuesday ended a two-year investigation into ethics violations by Gingrich by formally reprimanding him and ordering him to pay a $300,000 penalty. It found Gingrich had violated House rules by not seeking legal advice and providing false information to the House ethics committee, which was conducting the investigation.</p>
<p>Specifically, the committee had been looking at how GOPAC used money donated to charities to fund a college course taught by Gingrich. The committee found the course was aimed at winning Republican control of the House, which the party did in the 1994 election year.</p>
<p>The documents were turned over to the IRS for an inquiry into tax-exempt organisations that helped advance Gingrich's political career, the Times said. Representatives of the IRS and Gingrich declined to comment for the Times story.</p>
<p>Taken as a whole, the documents showed more than $1.6 million was used to produce national broadcasts of Gingrich's college course and other televised workshops. Of that total, $260,000 was funnelled to GOPAC through the Abraham Lincoln Opportunity Foundation, the Times reported.</p>
<p>The paper said the foundation was formed in 1984 by the Colorado Republican Party but initially struggled and eventually became dormant. In 1990, GOPAC revived the group.</p>
<p>The foundation and GOPAC shared headquarters, officers, staff, resources, telephones and financial support, the Times said. The foundation's founder and president was former Representative Howard Callaway, who also served as GOPAC's chairman.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
