<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324823" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ukrainian skater speeding before crash - police.</title>
<headline>Ukrainian skater speeding before crash - police.</headline>
<dateline>HARTFORD, Conn. 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukrainian Olympic figure-skating champion Oksana Baiul was driving at an estimated 97 mph (156 kph) shortly before she crashed her car in a Hartford suburb this month, according to court documents obtained on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Baiul, 19, was charged with driving while intoxicated and reckless driving in the Jan. 12 accident in which she ran her Mercedes off a road in Bloomfield, Connecticut, and crashed. She faces a court appearance in West Hartford on Jan. 27.</p>
<p>A native of the Ukraine, Baiul shot to fame after she won a gold medal in the 1994 Olympics.</p>
<p>Baiul, who lives in Simsbury, Connecticut, suffered a concussion and a laceration on the back of her head that required 14 stitches.</p>
<p>The officer on the scene said Baiul had &quot;a very strong odour of alcoholic beverage about her breath,&quot; according to a Bloomfield police affidavit filed in the West Hartford Superior Court.</p>
<p>The document also quotes an officer who interviewed Baiul more than six hours after the crash, who said: &quot;I still detected an odour of alcoholic beverage about her breath.&quot;</p>
<p>The officer said Baiul remembered losing control of the vehicle, but not much else.</p>
<p>Calculations based on skid marks left on the road showed the car was travelling at 97.11 mph in an area whose legal speed limit was 45 mph (72 kph), the affidavit said.</p>
<p>Baiul's lawyer, Paul Collins, told Reuters he could not comment on the affidavit because he had not seen it. He said Baiul, who is under the state's legal drinking age of 21, did not plan to contest the charges.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be asking that she be enrolled in the state-sponsored alcohol education and treatment programme,&quot; Collins said, but did not elaborate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARTFORD, Conn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
