<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324815" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PacifiCorp already helping Big River sales.</title>
<headline>PacifiCorp already helping Big River sales.</headline>
<dateline>LOUISVILLE, Ky. 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>PacifiCorp is working with Big Rivers Electric Corp to sell the utility's surplus power into the eastern power markets, Big Rivers said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Commenting on PacifiCorp's agreement to operate Big River's power plants if its bankruptcy proposal is approved, chief executive Michael Core said &quot;Western Kentucky is already seeing benefits of this agreement because of the interim marketing and economic development agreements Big Rivers and PacifiCorp have signed.&quot;</p>
<p>Power sales under the interim agreement are increasing the use of the power plants, fueled by western Kentucky coal.  </p>
<p>Big Rivers said it burned an additional 130,000 tons of coal during the first nine months of the agreement in 1996.</p>
<p>Core said he was also pleased that the bankruptcy proceeding has allowed Big Rivers to bring all its coal purchase contracts to market prices, resulting in savings of $165 million and removing a major obstacle to the PacifiCorp lease and operating transaction.</p>
<p>Big River spokeswoman Susan Sauls said an agreement has been reached with Costain Coal while talks continue with Green River Coal.  </p>
<p>She said the aluminum smelters which have agreed to new competitive rates, under contracts which run until 2010, are Southwire's Hawesville, Ky., plant and Alcan Aluminum Ltd's Sebree plant.</p>
<p>Sauls said the New York banks that will pay Big Rivers to be released from letters of credit obligations are Bank of New York Co Inc and Chase Manhattan Corp.</p>
<p>She said the company is due to return to court on February 19 to report on the status of its coal talks and preparation of a rate case filing.</p>
<p>Big River's power plants are the 480 megawatt Coleman Station at Hawesville; the 440 megawatt D.B. Wilson Station at Island, Ky.; and the 482 megawatt Green Station and 66 megawatt Reid Station, both at Sebree.</p>
<p>These plants are 100 percent owned and coal fired, Sauls said. She said the company also operates the City of Henderson's Station Two. ((-- Jim Brumm 212-859-1710.))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOUISVILLE, Ky."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
