<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="324996" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. fed cattle numbers seen above year ago.</title>
<headline>U.S. fed cattle numbers seen above year ago.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The number of cattle in major U.S. feedlots in December exceeded last year's levels because profit margins remained strong and feed prices continued to slide, livestock analysts said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Agriculture Department is expected to confirm the expected jump in supplies on Friday in its monthly Cattle on Feed Report, set for release at 1400 CST/2000 GMT.</p>
<p>Analysts projected the data will show the number of cattle on feed in feedlots of 1,000 head or more capacity in the seven key states on January 1 at 104.2 percent of a year ago, in a range of 102.0 to 105.0.  </p>
<p>December placements ranged widely and this part of the report was seen by some as the most important data. Estimates averaged 108.2 percent of a year ago in a Reuter pre-report survey of analysts, and ranged from 103.0 to 112.0 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;When you look at the kind of environment we had in December, I think the cheaper feed was still an incentive for people to put cattle on feed,&quot; said Tom Tippens, chief executive officer of Professional Cattle Consultants Inc based in Weatherford, Okla.  </p>
<p>Tippens noted that along with lower feed costs, cattle were still selling for high prices in early December which created incentive to put cattle on feed.</p>
<p>He estimated placements at 110.8 percent, which is the top of the range of placement estimates.</p>
<p>Other analysts see the trend for placements to exceed year-ago levels coming to an end following the USDA December data.</p>
<p>&quot;We delayed placements when corn was at four and five dollars (per bushel),&quot; said Ron Plain, senior livestock economist at the University of Missouri.  </p>
<p>&quot;The calves that didn't go on feed then went on feed this fall, but we're starting to work through those (cattle).&quot;</p>
<p>Plain said the industry &quot;can't just continue to increase the number of cattle on feed forever,&quot; and said a slowdown in placements was imminent.</p>
<p>Analysts said December marketings data will reflect brisk cattle sales as feedlots worked to stay current. Marketing estimates averaged 101.8 percent, ranging from 99.0 to 107.1 percent.</p>
<p>Tippens was also at the high end of estimates on marketings, projecting marketings at 107.1 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;We just had tremendous movement of these fed cattle out of the yards that I do business with,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Jim Robb, analyst at the Livestock Marketing Information Center in Denver, forecast December marketings to fall below year-ago levels, but said that figure should not be considered bearish. He estimated marketings at 99 percent of a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Marketings were down because cattle supplies were very tight,&quot; Robb said. &quot;It was mostly a function of the cattle just not being there and ready to go.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts continued to estimate only the seven-state part of the report with feedlots over 1,000 head even though USDA began a 12-state report more than a year ago. More time was needed to compare historical data, they said.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
