<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="325075" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian reform drive gets parliamentary nod.</title>
<headline>Italian reform drive gets parliamentary nod.</headline>
<byline>Paul Holmes</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Parliament set its seal of approval on Wednesday on a drive to change the constitution after months of political wrangling over what reforms it will take to give Italy stable government and an effective legislature.</p>
<p>The vote in the Chamber of Deputies (lower house) was the fourth and final ballot in parliament on the plan to create a commission made up of 70 members of both houses to draft a package of proposed reforms.</p>
<p>It brought overwhelming endorsement of the proposal by 534 votes to 70 after Silvio Berlusconi's opposition centre-right Freedom Alliance bloc resolved internal differences this month and decided to back the commission.</p>
<p>Italy has had 54 governments since World War Two and three general elections since 1992 in the upheavals that followed the exposure of entrenched political corruption and the collapse of the old governing class.</p>
<p>Berlusconi and political rival Massimo D'Alema have been the most enthusiastic supporters of the bicameral commission and, as leaders of the two largest parties, are widely seen as the men with the most to gain from change.</p>
<p>But it has already taken six months to debate the proposal and the commission will have just five months to come up with complex draft changes to the powers and structure of government, parliament and the state.</p>
<p>The recommendations will then return to parliament for approval before going to a referendum, possibly in mid-1998, the 50th anniversary of the existing constitution.</p>
<p>D'Alema, whose Democratic Party of the Left (PDS) is the biggest in the centre-left government, told the debate that an agreement in the commission would require courage and the capacity to look at national rather than partisan interests.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an opportunity to give the country the reforms which we have until now been incapable of providing,&quot; said D'Alema, a front runner to chair the new body.</p>
<p>Former prime minister Berlusconi, leader of the conservative Forza Italia, also left no illusions about potential obstacles to the exercise. Two similar attempts since constitutional reform was first debated 15 years ago ended in failure.</p>
<p>&quot;We are embarking on this trail with the parties of the centre-left already aware of the differences which separate us. If they prevent us from pursuing this work, we will take note,&quot; Berlusconi said.</p>
<p>Virtually all political parties agree on the need to give Italy a federal structure, reduce the number of members of parliament and end the duplication that marks the work of the Chamber and the Senate, slowing legislation to a crawl.</p>
<p>The main differences lie in what powers to invest in the government, with the centre-right bloc insisting that the prime minister should be directly elected by voters.</p>
<p>The centre-left wants the prime minister, now appointed by the president, to have a less direct mandate.</p>
<p>A key player in the fate of the reform drive will be Gianfranco Fini, Berlusconi's hard-right ally and the leader of parliament's third largest force, the National Alliance.</p>
<p>He had opposed the bicameral commission until this month and last year scuppered efforts to establish a cross-party government to oversee constitutional reform.</p>
<p>Fini, who described the commission as a &quot;fragile&quot; mechanism for effecting change, told the debate his party would not be satisfied with a &quot;touch up&quot; to the constitution and wanted profound reform.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
