<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="325187" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU Commission backtracks on enlargement date.</title>
<headline>EU Commission backtracks on enlargement date.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission on Wednesday withdrew an embarrassing statement that no new country was likely to join the European Union before 2002.</p>
<p>Earlier the Commission said in a 30-point fact sheet on enlargement that the length and complexity of forthcoming talks meant that &quot;the earliest realistic date for the first accessions is likely to be no earlier than 2002.&quot;</p>
<p>Commission spokesman Thierry Daman told Reuters the document was a mistake and did not reflect the Commission's official position. A new statement would be issued later on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He said the Commission position remained that a firm date could not be set because this depended on such unknown factors as when the EU's inter-governmental review of its treaty ended and how long the membership negotiations took.</p>
<p>On Tuesday evening the EU's External Relations Commissioner Hans van den Broek told a seminar on the separate enlargement plans of EU and NATO that he was not allowed to talk about dates.</p>
<p>The withdrawn document appeared days after French President Jacques Chirac told Hungary he saw no reason why it and other central European neighbours could not join by 2000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
