<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="325130" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: U.S. seen to renew WTO panel against EU over grain.</title>
<headline>U.S. seen to renew WTO panel against EU over grain.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States said on Wednesday it expected to renew a request next month for a World Trade Organisation panel on European Union grain import tariffs.</p>
<p>The warning was issued at a meeting of the WTO's Dispute Settlement Body (DSB), trade sources said.</p>
<p>But they quoted a U.S. trade envoy as telling the DSB Washington would not pursue the request if Brussels took measures to adjust its tariff system.</p>
<p>The development was the latest in a long-running dispute between the two powers partly linked to the accession of three new members -- Austria, Finland and Sweden -- to the EU in 1995.</p>
<p>A new tariff system based on a reference price for wheat, rye, barley, corn, sorghum and rice -- was introduced later that year and brought protests from the United States and Canada.</p>
<p>U.S. officials argue this runs against agreements in the 1986-93 Uruguay Round of world trade talks which brought agricultural produce under global rules for the first time.</p>
<p>In October 1995, Washington sought a WTO panel after initial bilateral talks failed to resolve differences. But the EU blocked the request in the DSB, saying talks were continuing. Later that year, U.S. sources say, an agreement was reached and confirmed in an exchange of letters, and the request for a panel was withdrawn.</p>
<p>But Washington argues Brussels has not implemented the accord.</p>
<p>After saying it would be renewing the panel request at a DSB meeting in December, the United States pulled back because of what one official said was &quot;a technical problem.&quot;</p>
<p>At Wednesday's session of the body, diplomats said, the EU implicitly challenged the U.S. right to renew a request for a panel after withdrawing it in 1995.</p>
<p>Trade sources said consultations were likely to be held on this point involving DSB officers and WTO legal experts as well as U.S. and EU officials.</p>
<p>If the U.S. position is found to be correct, a panel will be automatically created at the next DSB meeting on February 25.</p>
<p>Under WTO dispute settlement rules, countries which are the object of complaints cannot block a second request for a panel.</p>
<p>Once created, a WTO panel normally has six months to return its findings on whether a complaint alleging violation of open trade rules is justified.</p>
<p>But last month the United States, arguing that because the case involved perishable goods, said it should be treated as urgent -- meaning a finding should be returned in three months.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
