<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="325132" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy lira seen firm then, easing in late 1997.</title>
<headline>Italy lira seen firm then, easing in late 1997.</headline>
<byline>David Jones</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Italian lira is set to hold firm over the next few months despite Tuesday's discount rate cut, but it is likely to ease in late 1997 as international interest rate expectations alter, economists said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Economists forecast the Italian currency to stay firm around current levels until the middle of 1997 and then come under some downward pressure.</p>
<p>The major plank of support for the lira has been the weak German mark against the dollar because the Italian unit is often seen moving in line with the U.S. currency, but economists are not sure this mark/dollar relationship will continue into late 1997.</p>
<p>The Bank of Italy cut its key discount rate on Tuesday to 6.75 percent from 7.5 percent, and economists now expect a further 75 basis point cut in the second quarter and possibly more in the second half of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;It is difficult to believe the lira can appreciate much from here, and we see a 970-980 lire vs mark band in the short term,&quot; said senior international economist Ros Lifton at HSBC.</p>
<p>The lira firmed to near 967 lire/mark on Monday to touch a 31-month high. Even a rate cut did little to undermine the currency, which traded around 972 lire/mark late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Economists said the discount rate cut was expected, but the big surprise was the timing. Most had forecast the cut to come after a key pay dispute between Italian employers and 1.7 million metal and engineering workers was settled.</p>
<p>Instead, the rate cut came after preliminary consumer price figures on Monday and Tuesday that indicated a January consumer price index (CPI) near 2.6 percent, unchanged from December. The Bank of Italy has stressed CPI as its major factor in cutting rates.</p>
<p>The lira has firmed on the foreign exchange market in its run-up to and after its re-entry into Europe's Exchange Rate Mechanism in November 1996 at a central rate of 990 lire/mark.</p>
<p>In the short-term, economists say the lira is supported by the strong dollar and also perversely, by hopes of Italian rate cuts. Interest rate cuts are seen helping Italy's public finances, which help fuel domestic bonds and hence, the currency.</p>
<p>But by the mid-year, perceptions may change as international interest rate expectations alter and the weak Italian economy could weigh on the lira.</p>
<p>&quot;All hinges on interest rates in the rest of Europe,&quot; said international economist Ken Wattret at Paribas. He said the dollar was vulnerable in the long-term, and he sees a lire/mark rate at 1,020/1,030 in the second half of the year.</p>
<p>HSBC's Lifton says the picture is clouded by the uncertainty of the dollar in the second half and of interest rate expectations in the Group of Three (G3) nations of the U.S., Germany and Japan. She sees the lira moving towards 1,000 lire/mark during the second half of 1997.</p>
<p>Other economists stress the importance of international events in late 1997 and note that although the dollar is currently strong, it is vulnerable to weakness in the longer term.</p>
<p>Paribas's Wattret emphasized that with Italy's fiscal policy likely to remain tight in an effort to join a single European currency, and if the Italian economy stays weak, the only stimulus that can be applied to the economy will be to loosen further monetary policy.</p>
<p>Wattret pointed out the Bank of Italy is likely to want to shadow informal 2.25-percent bands around the 990 lire/mark ERM central rate. The 31-month high near 967 lire on Monday was near the top of this band.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
