<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="325323" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's CRISIL assigns 'AAA' rating for BPCL bond.</title>
<headline>India's CRISIL assigns 'AAA' rating for BPCL bond.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's CRISIL (Credit Rating Information Services of India Ltd) has given an 'AAA' rating to Bharat Petroleum Corporation Ltd's (BPCL) 3,000 million rupee bond programme.</p>
<p>In a statement on Tuesday, CRISIL said this rating indicated the highest degree of safety regarding timely payment of financial obligations on the instrument.</p>
<p>CRISIL said:</p>
<p>- The rating of the Fixed Deposit Programme of BPCL has been retained at 'FAAA' indicating that the degree of safety regarding timely payment of interest and principal is very strong. The rating of the short term debt programme of BPCL has been retained at &quot;P1+&quot; indicating that the degree of safety regarding timely payment on the instrument is very strong.</p>
<p>- BPCL is one of the three integrated downstream oil companies in the country involved in both refining and marketing operations. The petroleum industry is highly regulated by the government and under the existing system, both the refiners and the marketers are protected by retention pricing which ensures a post tax return of 12 percent on equity funds employed, as well as the reimbursement of operating and financing costs as per norms.</p>
<p>- India is in supply deficit with relation to petroleum products. This coupled with high growth in demand is likely to ensure that domestic refining and marketing companies like BPCL will have an assured market for their products in future. BPCL has a strong retail network which has enabled it to steadily increase its market share over the past few years. Retail sales of High Speed Diesel (HSD) and Motor Spirits (MS) account for about 50 percent of BPCL's sales volume. The company has the highest number of company owned retail outlets in the country and this would stand the company in good stead if competition intensifies after decontrol.</p>
<p>- BPCL has a six million MT per annum refinery at Mahul (Bombay), which has been operating at over 120 percent capacity utilisation. As the returns to the refinery are calculated based on a standard throughput, the company is eligible for incentives for the higher throughput under the current Administered Price Mechanism (APM).</p>
<p>- The burgeoning oil pool deficit has resulted in an increase in the claims receivable by the company from the oil pool account. BPCL's receivable position from the oil pool account is expected to increase in future unless measures are taken to reduce the deficit in the oil pool account.</p>
<p>- Although decontrol of the oil sector seems certain, the timing and form of decontrol are difficult to predict. BPCL's refining margins are likely to improve significantly in the event of decontrol as the capital costs (depreciation and interest costs) are quite low.</p>
<p>- Over the three-year period 1993-94 to 1995-96, BPCL's operating income has increased from 58.28 billion to 81.96 billion, at the CAGR at 18.59 percent per annum. The operating margins have increased from 8.9 percent to 9.9 percent during the same period. Interest costs are low at less than one percent of operating income, due to the low level of debt. Leveraging has been historically low, with Total Debt/Networth at 0.30 as at March 31, 1996, Interest coverage (PBIDT/Interest &amp; Finance charges) is favourable at 22.8 times.</p>
<p>Source: CRISIL</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
