<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="325716" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: DUTCH CLOSING SHARE MARKET REPORT.</title>
<headline>DUTCH CLOSING SHARE MARKET REPORT.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares reached record intra-day and closing highs on Wednesday with the surging dollar the key to stronger multinationals and exporters, dealers said.</p>
<p>The AEX index of 25 leading stocks ended up 8.96 points at 681.28, having earlier hit an intra-day peak of 685.10. All but two of the AEX stocks rose.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody wants to sell right now even though they think its overbought,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Behind much of the rise was the soaring dollar which for most of the day held above 1.84 guilders, the dollar's highest level the since its tumble in June 1994.  </p>
<p>Despite the bull run, nervousness was a common sentiment.</p>
<p>&quot;There doesn't seem to be any structure at the moment. There's been a lot of short-covering. But there's not that much confidence,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the reluctance to sell and buy on any dip persisted.</p>
<p>&quot;When it does sell-off, everybody rushes in to buy again,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Some traders said the market could hold around an AEX level of 680, but might need a few days to consolidate. One said the market greatly needed a &quot;time out&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
