<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="325913" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Lebanon cannot try Iraqi diplomats - minister.</title>
<headline>Lebanon cannot try Iraqi diplomats - minister.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lebanese Foreign Minister Faris Bouez said on Wednesday that his country cannot put on trial three Iraqi diplomats suspected of involvement in the 1994 murder of an Iraqi opposition leader in Beirut.</p>
<p>Two days ago a Lebanese investigative judge ordered the release of the three diplomats Mohammad Kazem, Ali Darwish and Hadi Hassan on a bail of 50,000 Lebanese pounds ($32) each.</p>
<p>&quot;Our opinion, based on all international jurisprudence and laws, is that Lebanon as a host country can cut diplomatic relations and kick out the diplomats and consider them persona non-grata but it cannot try them,&quot; Bouez said.</p>
<p>The three, who have not yet been released, have been held without trial at Lebanon's biggest jail at Roummieh since their arrest immediately after the April 12, 1994 killing of Iraqi dissident Taleb as-Suheil.</p>
<p>The murder of Suheil, an opponent of Iraqi President Saddam Hussein, brought a swift rupture in diplomatic ties between Baghdad and Beirut which ordered the closure of the Iraqi embassy.</p>
<p>Lebanese authorities said in 1995 they were waiting for a reply by Lebanon's foreign ministry on whether the suspects were listed as diplomats or non-diplomatic staff.</p>
<p>Judicial sources said on Monday the ministry confirmed the suspects' diplomatic identity last week. They gave no explanation for the prolonged delay in the ministry's response.</p>
<p>The sources said Suheil's widow on Tuesday appealed to a judicial committee against the decision to bail out the diplomats and a Lebanese shop owner who is also accused of links to her husband's murder.</p>
<p>A fourth diplomat, commercial attache Khaled Khalaf who was also arrested in connection with the murder, died in custody of a brain haemorrhage in June 1995. He had not faced trial.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
