<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="326038" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Governors warn administration on welfare law.</title>
<headline>Governors warn administration on welfare law.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Governors and state legislators Tuesday asked the Clinton administration to give them flexibility in implementing a new welfare law, warning any effort to set tight rules for state spending could undermine their efforts.</p>
<p>The warning from the executive directors of the National Governors' Association, National Conference of State Legislatures and American Public Welfare Association came as the Department of Health and Human Services was preparing rules to implement the law.</p>
<p>The welfare law, signed by Clinton last year, ends a six-decade guarantee of federal aid to poor women and children. Instead, states will receive block grants to design and run their own welfare programs. Benefits would be limited to five years and work required after two years.,</p>
<p>The law, which reduces federal spending by $54 billion over six years, also requires states to continue their own spending on welfare reform, pegging state maintenance at 80 percent of historic amounts.</p>
<p>Governors can use state funds to aid certain individuals who may lose benefits under the law, such as legal immigrants who will be cut off from a host of federal programs.</p>
<p>But the federal government is looking at a tighter interpretation of the law than states expected that would apply federal requirements, including work requirements, to state spending.</p>
<p>&quot;We strongly believe that any effort to apply all federal ...prohibitions and requirements to state maintenance-of-effort spending is unacceptable and would be a misinterpretation of the law,&quot; the groups said in a letter to Health and Human Services Secretary Donna Shalala.</p>
<p>&quot;It would have the immediate effect of curbing state flexibility and innovation in providing a variety of services and greatly inhibit the ability of states to expend state dollars for vulnerable children and families,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Some top House Republicans were expected to send a letter to the Clinton administration supporting the governors.</p>
<p>&quot;What we hare (trying) to do and hope to do soon is answer these questions that states have, clarify these questions,&quot; an HHS spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Given that there has been significant concern out there and certainly legislatures are coming into session... were really looking at very soon&quot; providing an answer, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
