<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="326182" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Dresdner confirms keen on UK funds buy.</title>
<headline>Dresdner confirms keen on UK funds buy.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Dresdner Bank AG confirmed on Wednesday that it was interested in taking over a UK fund manager and added that it was also investigating expanding its asset management in France and Italy.</p>
<p>The Financial Times on Wednesday quoted Dresdner board member Gerhard Eberstadt as saying the bank might restart talks with an independent UK fund management group that it spoke to before buying investment bank Kleinwort Benson in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not on the acquisition trail,&quot; a Dresdner spokesman said. &quot;But if there is a possibility in the UK, then we are ready to make a purchase.&quot;</p>
<p>The spokesman declined to name the UK fund management group in question and said talks had not yet begun with it or any other candidates.</p>
<p>&quot;We have reached the point where we have consolidated Kleinwort and we are now interested in more business, specifically in institutional fund management,&quot; the Dresdner spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>He added that Dresdner was also keen on acquisitions in France and Spain and that the U.S. &quot;can never be ruled out, but is not a priority&quot;.</p>
<p>Eberstadt told the Financial Times that Britain was &quot;one of the most interesting markets in asset management&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We are keen to get more mandates in the UK. Our ambitions are not yet satisfied. But as well as wanting to secure more mandates, we are also interested in an acquisition if a reputable firm is available,&quot; he told the newspaper.</p>
<p>Britain's fund management industry has been in the spotlight recently as a result of fund manager Nicola Horlick's stormy departure from the asset management arm of Deutsche Morgan Grenfell, part of Deutsche Bank AG.</p>
<p>Horlick was suspended from the company and later resigned amid accusations she had tried to lure a group of colleagues to leave with her and join rival firm ABN AMRO.</p>
<p>Horlick repeatedly denied the allegations against her. ABN AMRO also denied it tried to poach Horlick's team.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 755625</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
