<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="326157" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France rushes to combat pollution.</title>
<headline>France rushes to combat pollution.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Government representatives across France must draft emergency anti-contamination plans following an alarming spate of pollution this month, Environment Minister Corinne Lepage said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Authorities limited car traffic and industrial activity in several major cities last week as contamination rose to alert levels in a cold, windless spell which trapped fumes.</p>
<p>Trucks were banned from Lyon, speed limits cut to 60 kph (35 mph) on an eastern motorway, and production halved at a major Paris region power plant.</p>
<p>Contamination reached alert levels although France produces most of its electricity from nuclear plants. The alert came less than two weeks after parliament passed a law spelling out guidelines to protect the purity of air.</p>
<p>Lepage said after a cabinet meeting she was asking prefects (government representatives) to put flesh on the guidelines by the end of the month with emergency regulations that should include traffic curbs.</p>
<p>They would then work on longer-term plans.</p>
<p>She said that at the next alert in Paris, speed limits on fast city highways would be lowered by 20 kmh (13 mph), tourist coaches would be banned from the central Cite and Saint-Louis islands on the river Seine, and parking fees suspended for residents.</p>
<p>President Jacques Chirac asked the cabinet to encourage the development of electricity-powered cars and non-polluting transport.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
