<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="326151" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: New Austrian chancellor loosens ties with left.</title>
<headline>New Austrian chancellor loosens ties with left.</headline>
<byline>Janet McBride</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austria's government line-up began to take shape on Wednesday with some familiar faces from the left of the ruling Social Democratic Party out in the cold and moderates poised to take on key ministerial roles.</p>
<p>Chancellor-in-waiting Viktor Klima has yet to name his team but already three out of six Social Democrat ministers have resigned and a fourth exit looks likely. The post of finance minister, which Klima is vacating, must also be filled.</p>
<p>No changes are expected among ministers from the conservative People's Party, the junior coalition partner.</p>
<p>One top cabinet member likely to lose his job is Interior Minister Caspar Einem -- a move which has pleased the far-right Freedom Party, orchestrator of a campaign against Einem and Social Democrat Arts Minister Rudolf Scholten.</p>
<p>&quot;We are overjoyed that the ideologues are going,&quot; said Freedom Party secretary Peter Westenthaler.</p>
<p>Einem, whose public image suffered after it emerged he had made a donation to a leftwing newsletter, faces demotion to the transport ministry, according to media reports. And Scholten, who irritated the establishment with his patronage of a provocative theatre director, has confirmed his resignation.</p>
<p>Klima also won far-right approval for ousting Women's Issues Minister Helga Konrad, who made it clear she was forced to quit.</p>
<p>&quot;I would have loved to stay on to finish the projects that I started...But the new chancellor has told me that he wants to put together a new team,&quot; Konrad told Austrian radio.</p>
<p>The former regional politician had drawn criticism for a costly advertising campaign that encouraged men to do half the housework and a proposal that refusal to help out in the home should provide grounds for divorce.</p>
<p>The People's Party remained tight-lipped about the changes in the Social Democratic Party in the wake of Chancellor Franz Vranitzky's surprise resignation at the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;They are horrified by the press jubilation at Klima's appointment,&quot; Freedom Party whip Susanne Riess-Passer told Kurier daily.</p>
<p>The Freedom Party denied claims that it made the People's Party a coalition offer over the weekend. &quot;The Freedom Party is open to the Social Democrats too,&quot; Westenthaler said.</p>
<p>Media reports say incoming ministers will include Chamber of Labour chief Eleonore Hostasch, Upper Austrian regional politician Barbara Prammer and State Secretary for Public Works Karl Schloegl.</p>
<p>The Social Affairs and Health Ministries are likely to be combined under Hostasch, a signal from Klima to voters that the government is willing to cut costs, commentators said.</p>
<p>Prammer, the next women's issues minister, is an environmentalist who will challenge the opposition Greens' for votes. Schloegl, who slashed public sector spending last year, will win the Interior Ministry as a reward, media reports say.</p>
<p>Only the key Finance Ministry remains wide open. A new favourite emerged in Austrian newspapers on Wednesday -- Vienna City council finance chief Rudolf Edlinger.</p>
<p>Klima is expected to name his team next week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
