<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="326289" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian interest rate cut seen rekindling economy.</title>
<headline>Italian interest rate cut seen rekindling economy.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Hurst</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Italy's interest rate cut will help rekindle an economy that badly needs to grow faster if Italy's ambitions of joining a single European currency are to stay on course, economists said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But the easing of monetary policy came too late to keep alive government hopes of achieving a relatively healthy two percent growth rate in the economy. Most economists believe the economy will grow by no more than 1.2 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>Reviving a faltering economy is crucial if Italy is to stay in a race against time to straighten out public finances and qualify as a founder member of a European economic and monetary union (EMU), planned for launch in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;The short-term impact on the economy of the rate cut is not huge but it's very good for investment and it stops the lira appreciating too much,&quot; said Francesco Giordano, an economist with San Paolo in London.</p>
<p>The central bank announced on late on Tuesday it was cutting its key discount rate to 6.75 percent from 7.5 percent. The fixed-term advances rate was lowered to 8.25 percent from nine.</p>
<p>The long-awaited move was greeted with relief by financial markets when trading opened on Wednesday, with stocks and bonds powering to new highs.</p>
<p>The latest cut is a shot in the arm for Prime Minister Romano Prodi's government which is anxious to see a fall in the stiff interest bill -- equivalent to 11 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) -- it pays on Italy's huge public debt.</p>
<p>Most economists see interest rates falling even further in the coming months before stabilising at around six percent by mid-year. Every percentage point fall shaves 11-13 trillion lire ($6.9 to $8.2 billion) off the interest bill in a full year.</p>
<p>The government has been caught in a double bind as it piles on new taxes to bring in the extra revenues needed to cut the ratio of public deficit to GDP to three percent -- a target it must meet in 1997 to be sure of securing a berth in EMU.</p>
<p>But as it tightens the fiscal screws, with a raft of measures including a 5.5 trillion lira &quot;Euro-tax&quot;, the government also risks squeezing the life out of an economoy which last year grew at a paltry rate of just 0.8 percent.</p>
<p>Tight monetary policy, at a time when inflation has been tumbling, has added to the misery.</p>
<p>High interest rates have fuelled a strengthening in the lira, blunting a competitive advantage for exporters.</p>
<p>Italy has lagged behind other European nations in bringing down borrowing costs because of Bank of Italy governor Antonio Fazio's determination to tame inflation, now running at 2.6 percent year-on-year, before easing up on the monetary reins.</p>
<p>Tuesday's rate cut was the third reduction in six months and brings the discount rate to its lowest since September 1975.</p>
<p>Financial markets had been waiting for the move for weeks but most commentators had resigned themselves to not seeing a cut until enginering and metalworkers and their employers settled a long-standing dispute over new wage contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy clearly needed a loosening of policy. By postponing the recovery for so long there was a risk of delaying the stabilisation of the economy,&quot; said an economist with a European investment bank in London.</p>
<p>Even with interest rates on a downward path, the economy is expected to grow sluggishly this year although an upturn in activity is on the cards in the second half.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect a very slow recovery in the second quarter of 1997 and in the third quarter it could speed up, pushed along by investments,&quot; said Lorenzo Codogno, an economist at Bank of America in Milan.</p>
<p>Prodi's government will need to introduce a supplementary budget in the coming weeks of at least 20 trillion lire in order to rein in the public sector deficit and keep it from exceeding the government's three percent target, economists said.</p>
<p>$=1,594</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
