<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="326303" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: EU's Van Miert wants to vet any GAN aid.</title>
<headline>EU's Van Miert wants to vet any GAN aid.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert said in an interview on Wednesday any new state aid in the pipeline for French state insurer GAN would require European Commission approval.</p>
<p>Van Miert said in La Tribune newspaper the prospect of new state aid, on top of that approved by the Commission, had arisen after a delay with the privatisation of GAN's regional bank unit Credit Industriel et Commercial (CIC).</p>
<p>French government sources said it was too early to speak of a new aid plan and also confirmed that the CIC privatisation schedule was still unresolved.</p>
<p>In his newspaper interview Van Miert said: &quot;It's a matter of course that as soon as the new aid is notified to us we will open an inquiry procedure.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The Commission approved the payout of state aid in July in return for a formal commitment by the French authorities on a restructuring which included, among other asset sales, the sale of a majority of CIC,&quot; Van Miert said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have since then learned that the privatisation procedure had been interrupted and that a new state aid was needed.&quot;</p>
<p>The Commission, which controls government aid to companies in the European Union, approved a French state capital injection of 2.8 billion francs in July.</p>
<p>French Finance Minister Jean Arthuis called off a tender to privatise CIC in November after getting just two offers, of which only one was deemed eligible by France's privatisation commission.</p>
<p>Van Miert also reiterated that a fresh rescue plan being drawn up for state-owned bank Credit Lyonnais would have to be fully assessed by the Commission and that conditions imposed by the Commission would have to be commensurate with the size of the payout.</p>
<p>Government sources say a rescue plan will be ready in a &quot;few weeks&quot;.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
