<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="326576" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks end lower, banks lead decline.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks end lower, banks lead decline.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks finished weak on Wednesday, dragged lower by a decline in banking counters after investors took advantage of an early surge in prices to take profits, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index fell 40.00 points, or 0.29 percent, to 13,692.79 after climbing to an early high of 13,898.27. Turnover was HK$11.16 billion compared with HK$9.45 billion on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the market opened higher after strong gains on Wall Street, people are still worried about the U.S. economy and took advantage of the opportunity to take profits,&quot; said Percy Au-Young, director of research at DBS Securities.  </p>
<p>The Dow industrials rose to their 10th record close of the year on Tuesday, gaining 40.03 points to 6,883.90 after U.S. Federal Reserve chairman Alan Greenspan said the U.S. economy showed vigour with little sign of inflationary tensions.</p>
<p>Andrew Fernow, director of research at Vickers Ballas, said uncertainty still lingered ahead of the Fed's February meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;It is difficult for investors to get in at this level with a bit of uncertainty in the weeks ahead relating to the Fed policy meeting and other economic developments that may surface,&quot; he said. &quot;People are a bit more cautious right now so the market is going to have a pause which is long overdue.&quot;  </p>
<p>But, Fernow said the downside was limited. &quot;The underlying fundamentals are good and people are expecting good results from Hong Kong stocks during the upcoming earnings season.&quot;</p>
<p>Shares in HSBC Holdings fell HK$2.00 to HK$178.50 and Hang Seng Bank closed on a loss of HK$0.75 at HK$93.25.</p>
<p>&quot;It may be perceived that there is not a lot of upside among the bigger blue chips because they have already come up substantially - HSBC being a prime example,&quot; said Fernow.</p>
<p>But conglomerates Hutchison and Swire Pacific pushed ahead, adding HK$1.00 to HK$64.25 and HK$1.00 to HK$74.75 respectively.  </p>
<p>&quot;They can be described as laggards,&quot; said Au-Young, adding that Hutchison got a further lift from Tuesday's annoucement that it and Cheung Kong had won a tender for the Mass Transit Railway Corp's Tung Chung Station Package Three development.</p>
<p>&quot;They are setting themselves up for good growth beyond the year 2000,&quot; said Fernow. Cheung Kong rose HK$0.75 to HK$75.50.</p>
<p>Volume in Wheelock shares boosted turnover after a block of 50 million shares was traded at HK$22.80 at the opening bell. The stock closed at HK$22.90, down HK$0.985. Market sources said that 50 million existing shares were placed late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Jennifer Genevieve (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
