<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="326694" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo stocks jump on hopes of early share tax move.</title>
<headline>Tokyo stocks jump on hopes of early share tax move.</headline>
<byline>Hiroko Nakata</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese stocks jumped nearly three percent on Wednesday, perked up by reports that the government may abolish taxes on securities transactions.</p>
<p>After falls in recent sessions because of worries that not enough was being done to revive the economy, the key Nikkei index rose more than 500 points in morning trade after ending down on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was cheered, as the government finally appears to be trying to tackle the securities transaction tax,&quot; said a trader at a second-tier Japanese brokerage firm.</p>
<p>The rally started with a rise in Nikkei futures in Chicago overnight and by the end of the morning session the key Nikkei average of 225 leading shares was up 511.87 points, or 2.95 percent, at 17,870.03.</p>
<p>The catalyst was a series of hints by key government policy makers that a review was imminent of the securities transaction tax which brokers complain dampens stock trade.</p>
<p>A senior official of the ruling Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) party told Reuters the LDP wanted to abolish the tax as early as 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;Given our policy task of carrying out &quot;Big Bang&quot; financial reforms and opening Japan's securities market up to world, we must consider abolishing the securities transaction tax because there are no such tax systems abroad,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>In a newspaper report, a senior Ministry of Finance (MOF) official was quoted as saying the ministry would likely reach a conclusion on how to revamp the tax by June.</p>
<p>&quot;We had been dubious about whether the government was going to take steps to support the stock market, but it looks as if they are finally trying to take action,&quot; said a trader at a second-tier Japanese securities house.</p>
<p>Brokers, who have been looking for action from the government to halt the market's recent downward spiral, jumped on the reports, bying back shares they had sold earlier.</p>
<p>The sharp rise in stocks put a damper on Japanese government bonds, because weak stocks are generally seen as supporting the view that Japan needs to maintain its low interest rate policy.</p>
<p>Key March Japanese government bond (JGB) futures were down 0.15 at midday at 126.00, after falling as low as 125.88.</p>
<p>&quot;JGB futures fell as the Nikkei rose sharply. But if the Nikkei does not rise any further in the afternoon, the JGB market may show a recovery,&quot; said a brokerage house trader.</p>
<p>The dollar was clinging near 118 yen in quiet Tokyo morning trade, with the stock recovery suppressing buying interest.</p>
<p>U.S. Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan had delivered an upbeat assessment of the U.S. economy to the Senate Budget Committee on Tuesday and some dealers said his comments provided reassurance for dollar-buying sentiment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
