<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="326771" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Jan 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Jan 22.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Egyptian press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-AHRAM</p>
<p>- Deputy Prime Minister and Agriculture Minister Youssef Wali will meet a World Bank delegation led by Howard Handy today to discuss the framework for World Bank participation in Egypt's big desert irrigation project (Note: Handy is an official of the International Monetary Fund and the IMF office in Cairo said he was not expected to discuss the irrigation project.)</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Amr Moussa said that Israeli withdrawal from Hebron was an important step towards setting up a Palestinian state.</p>
<p>- The Ministry of Manpower has finished preparing a new system for giving government jobs to university graduates.</p>
<p>- In Geneva Egypt said Israel must sign the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty and open its nuclear facilities to international inspection.</p>
<p>- The cabinet will today discuss what has been accomplished on the South Valley Development project to irrigate the Western Desert since President Hosni Mubarak visited the project.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Kamal Ganzouri approved the creation of the Egyptian Company for Media Production, with a paid capital of 1.3 billion pounds ($380 million). The state has a 45 percent stake in it and the rest will be offered to public subscription.</p>
<p>AL-AKHBAR</p>
<p>- Mutiny in eastern Sudan. Pilots refuse to bomb civilians and the infantry refuses to go to the front.</p>
<p>- His Grace the Mufti, Nasr Farid Wasil, said women should not hold high state office. He said that women have a gentle nature, sensitive, compassionate, soft-hearted and easily moved. If they take leadership positions in the state, which require toughness, perhaps cruelty and sometimes violence, then women would be departing from their nature and this is not possible in practice.</p>
<p>- February 9 and 10 will be bank holidays for Eid al-Fitr, the feast at the end of the fasting month of Ramadan.</p>
<p>- It has been decided to close the Egyptian-Libyan border temporarily at the request of the Libyan authorities. Trucks and vehicles will not be able to cross and work will stop completely at the customs post.</p>
<p>AL-GOMHURIA</p>
<p>- President Hosni Mubarak meets Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat today for important talks. Arafat will brief Mubarak on details of the Hebron agreement and future negotiations between Israel and the Palestinians.</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Amr Moussa's seminar at the Cairo International Book Fair turned into a debate between supporters and opponents of normalisation with Israel. The confrontation began when Lotfi el-Khouli said we can defeat Israel only on paper and Saadeddin Wahba said we do not negotiate with Israel because we are dealing with a problem between a thief and his victim. Moussa said war was unacceptable but a Palestinian state was inevitable.</p>
<p>$1 = 3.40 pounds</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +20 2 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
