<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="326724" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: INDONESIAN STOCKS - factors to watch - Jan 22.</title>
<headline>INDONESIAN STOCKS - factors to watch - Jan 22.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main factors likely to affect Indonesian stocks on Wednesday:</p>
<p>* The Dow Jones industrial average closed up 40.03 points at 6,883.90 on Tuesday as Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan's upbeat remarks on the economy propelled blue-chip stocks to their 10th record close this year and sparked a rally in the bond market.</p>
<p>* Although Greenspan warned about the risks of wage-driven inflation, he said the U.S. economy showed vigour and little sign of inflationary tensions.</p>
<p>* State-controlled tin miner PT Tambang Timah said it has officially submitted a proposal to have a five to 20 percent stake in the huge Busang gold find in Kalimantan.</p>
<p>MARKETS</p>
<p>* The Jakarta Composite Index closed up 6.75 points, or one percent, at 680.88 points on Tuesday, just off the record high of 681.56 points recorded on April 4, 1990, after active buying almost across the board.</p>
<p>* On Wednesday, the rupiah was quoted at 2,371.00/71.75 in early trading against the opening of 2,371.00/71.75.</p>
<p>STOCKS TO WATCH</p>
<p>* Astra International on news there may be changes in the automobile conglomerate's management following announcement that it would hold an extraordinary general meeting on February 19.</p>
<p>* State-controlled tin miner Tambang Timah on news reports it has submitted a proposal to have a stake in the huge Busang gold find in Kalimantan.</p>
<p>* Bakrie Brothers on reports it was in negotiation to sell its 49-percent stake in PT Indocopper Investama which has a 9.36-percent stake in PT Freeport Indonesia, operator of one of the world's largest copper and gold mines in Irian Jaya.</p>
<p>* Astra Graphia on announcement that the firm had agreed to merge with footwear company PT Mitracorp Footwear International from January 1, 1997.</p>
<p>* Bank BNI on news it plans to issue $145 million Yankee bonds through its New York office</p>
<p>* Semen Gresik on reports that it will hold a tender to operate its 50-megawatt power plant to supply electricity to its Tonasa-IV plant in south Sulawesi following technical problems.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
