<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="326845" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Hochtief, Holzmann mull cooperation - report.</title>
<headline>Hochtief, Holzmann mull cooperation - report.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German construction rivals Hochtief AG and Philip Holzmann AG have been discussing closer cooperation in foreign countries due to weak industry conditions, a German newspaper reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung said the talks have focused on the companies helping one another in countries where one group has a stronger position than the other.</p>
<p>The talks have also focused on closer cooperation in Germany, where the industry has been suffering from recessionary conditions. But any deal in Germany must be approved by the German cartel office.</p>
<p>The newspaper cited as an example of international cooperation Hochtief's chance to benefit from Holzmann's strong position in the U.S. and Thailand while Holzmann could benefit from Hochtief's presence in Australia.</p>
<p>The talks come ahead of a decision expected on February 5 by a Berlin court on whether Hochtief may raise its stake in Holzmann to 35 percent from 20 percent. The German cartel office ruled against the deal but Hochtief has appealed.</p>
<p>Holzmann told the newspaper that it expected break-even results for 1996 and that losses in general construction and in roads construction would be subsidised by reserves.</p>
<p>Holzmann's financial results will be released after a supervisory board meeting on January 30, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
