<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="326907" id="root" date="1997-01-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo stocks jump, Nikkei back above 18,000.</title>
<headline>Tokyo stocks jump, Nikkei back above 18,000.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese stocks recovered strongly on Wednesday, with the key share index soaring more than four percent to above the psychologically important 18,000-point level after reports that the government may scrap taxes on securities transactions, brokers said.  </p>
<p>At 0545 GMT, the key Nikkei average of 225 leading shares was up 692.45 points, or 3.99 percent, at 18,050.61, after hitting 18,065.98. Its March futures were up 760 points at 18,090.</p>
<p>The rise was fuelled by comments by key policy makers about a review of a securities transaction tax, which brokers complain is dampening stock trade. Brokers have been looking for action from the government to halt the market's recent downward spiral.</p>
<p>&quot;Trade is thin, rather thin, but the media reports in the morning gave a stagnating market hope that a change for the better may come, encouraging buy-backs,&quot; a broker at one of Japan's &quot;Big Four&quot; brokerages said.</p>
<p>Brokers said Nikkei futures in sectors such as banking were being bought back after facing heavy selling in the past weeks. Cash blue-chip shares were also being sought by foreign investors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
