<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="326938" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Placer Las Cristinas construction delayed.</title>
<headline>Placer Las Cristinas construction delayed.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Placer Dome Inc said Thursday that construction on its Las Cristinas gold mine in Venezuela has been delayed because its joint venture partner has not signed the shareholder agreement for the development.</p>
<p>Construction on the US$576 million mine in southeastern Venezuela was due to start before the end of last year but a Placer spokesman said Thursday the company could not project when it would begin.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope it will be very soon. We are all ready to go. All we need is a signature&quot; from Placer's partner, state-owned Corporacion Venezolana de Guyana, he said.  </p>
<p>The delay has prompted Placer to lay off 100 of its 190 staff on the project. Placer has 70 percent of the gold project and CVG the rest.</p>
<p>CVG &quot;were going to sign (the shareholder agreement) in December and that didn't happen. It remains to be seen when they will,&quot; the Placer spokesman said.</p>
<p>He said CVG has given no reason for the delay.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the delay could be &quot;problematic&quot; if it lasts for several months because the onset of the rainy season in the area could interfere with construction.</p>
<p>Placer had previously planned to begin producing gold at Las Cristinas in the fourth quarter of 1998. The mine is projected to produce 450,000 ounces of gold a year for at least 16 years.</p>
<p>The mine would be an open pit. Ore reserves are estimated to be 233 million tonnes grading 1.21 grams of gold per tonne containing nine million ounces of gold.</p>
<p>((Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
