<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327088" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Trust preferreds top issuance, more due on Friday.</title>
<headline>Trust preferreds top issuance, more due on Friday.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>New corporate issuance held the spotlight on Thursday led by a steady flow of trust preferred issues, dealers said, most of which were expected to tighten when freed to trade.</p>
<p>High-yielding issues were firmer, but extremely quiet, meanwhile, with masses of investors traversing the continent from conference to conference, traders said.</p>
<p>Back in investment grades, new capital securities issues totaling more than $750 million topped overall issuance. Much of the issuance featured floating rate structures as issuers moved to forego swaps from fixed coupons at a later date.  </p>
<p>&quot;Floating rate trust preferreds have all been tightening, but not as much as the fixed-rates did when they were first issued,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>The largest issue, however, was $400 million 40-year 8.175 percent capital securities from Texas Utilities Electric Capital IV, priced at par to yield 129 basis points over the Treasury curve. TU Electric Capital IV also issued a $100 million tranche of floating rate notes priced at a discount to yield 90 basis points over the three-month LIBOR.</p>
<p>Goldman Sachs &amp; Co was lead manager for the TU issues.  </p>
<p>Also on Thursday, Wells Fargo Capital Trust II, a unit of Wells Fargo &amp; Co, issued $150 million 30-year floating rate capital securities at 58.326 basis points over three months LIBOR via Credit Suisse First Boston.</p>
<p>And in the high-yield area, Arvin Industries sold $100 million 30-year capital securities as 9-1/2s to yield 273 basis points over Treasuries via Merrill Lynch &amp; Co Inc.</p>
<p>Analysts said the date at which the tax-deductable feature of dividend payments on trust preferreds may close could occur at any time after the beginning of February when the Clinton Administration presents its budget proposal.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think everybody is saying it could happen sooner than later,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Looking ahead to Friday, a unit of First Chicago is expected to issue $250 million 30-year non-call 10 floating rate trust preferreds at LIBOR plus 62 basis points. That spread was seen as attractive on Thursday, one trader said, compared with the the similarly rated and tighter Wells Fargos. Citicorp affiliate Citicorp Capital II is expected to tap the market with $450 million 30-year non-call 10 capital securities on Friday. That deal could see a significant increase in size, sources said.  </p>
<p>In straight corporate debt issuance, Chrysler Corp unit Chrysler Financial issued $300 million 6-3/8 percent notes of 2000 to yield 29 basis points over Treasuries via a J.P. Morgan Securities syndicate. Also, Carlisle Cos Inc issued $150 million 7-1/4 percent 10-year notes to yield 72 basis points over Treasuries through Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>Spreads in the secondary market were mostly unchanged.</p>
<p>Turning to high-yields, prices were largely unchanged in thin trade as buyers were largely inactive due to a Salomon Brothers conference in Colorado earlier this week and a Merrill Lynch conference in New York on Thursday.  </p>
<p>Some junk-rated wireless issues traded higher, including Paging Network's 10s of 2008 after the company announced a 27.7 percent increase in operating cash flow. The notes, issued last October in a $500 million deal, were quoted up 1/4 to 3/8 to late bids of 98-3/4 and 98-7/8.</p>
<p>Separately, Pegasus Communication Corp's $100 million 10-year exchangeable preferred stock, issued on Thursday at par with a 12-3/4 percent dividend, was seen trading at par plus 1/8 point near the close.</p>
<p>In the Treasury market, The benchmark 30-year bond closed down 9/32 to yield 6.86 percent.</p>
<p>((--Al Yoon, 212-859-1672))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
