<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327289" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Investor makes big downside bet.</title>
<headline>U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Investor makes big downside bet.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>An investor placed a big bet on a market correction by June with a put bear spread in S&amp;P 500 stock index options on Thursday.</p>
<p>The SPX June 725 put and the June 775 put each traded 14,770 contracts. The 725s went out mostly at 10-5/8 and the 775s went out mostly at 22.</p>
<p>&quot;They did a June 775-725 put bear spread for 10 points,&quot; said Michael Schwartz, managing director at Oppenheimer &amp; Co. &quot;The profit potential if the market is at 725 or lower (at expiration) is 40 points.&quot;  </p>
<p>The profit would be the difference between the 50-point spread of the options and the net cost to do the trade.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like a big speculation on a correction or just a hedge fund hedging a large portfolio,&quot; Schwartz said.</p>
<p>He said the trade, done throughout the day in small blocks, was likely driven by an institutional investor because SPX options are geared toward insitutions, with European-style expirations.</p>
<p>Options with European-style expirations can only be exercised on the expiration day. American-style options can be exercised at any time up to the expiration.  </p>
<p>In afternoon trading, the underlying SPX was up 1.49 poitns at 787.72, off its session high of 794.67, which was a record intraday peak.</p>
<p>The index had reached five-straight record closing highs through Wednesday, when it finished at 786.23, shrugging off a drubbing in blue chip International Business Machines Corp</p>
<p>The SPX June 725 put had open interest of 36,278 through Wednesday and the 775 put had open interest of 4,450.</p>
<p>Most other SPX options were not particularly active, with few trading more than 3,000 contracts.  </p>
<p>In the S&amp;P 100 index .OEX, put options continued to be the option of choice, with put volume outpacing call volume by 55,501 to 41,846.</p>
<p>The OEX was up 2.37 at 773.55 after hitting an all-time intraday high at 779.85.</p>
<p>The heaviest OEX volume was in the February 790 call, which traded nearly 5,200 contracts, and the February 775 put, which traded about 5,040.</p>
<p>Other actives included the February 700 put, the February 760 put, the Febraury 775 call adn the February 780 call. ((--G. Crawford, 312 408 8750/Email: derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
