<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327490" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SOCCER-MEXICANS DRAW WITH PERU TO WIN U.S. CUP.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MEXICANS DRAW WITH PERU TO WIN U.S. CUP.</headline>
<byline>Steve James</byline>
<dateline>PASADENA, California 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico retained the U.S. Cup Wednesday by drawing 0-0 with Peru in the four-nation tournament.</p>
<p>The Mexicans finished with seven points, one ahead of Denmark, who earlier in the day beat the United States 4-1. Peru ended the tournament with four points in third place and the Americans finished last after losing all three of their matches.</p>
<p>Despite the lack of goals, the match between Mexico and Peru was an exciting affair played on a rain-sodden pitch in pouring rain.</p>
<p>The goalkeepers were the stars. The Mexicans could have been two goals up at half-time, but Peruvian goalkeeper Julio Balero Correa saved a 15th-minute penalty, diving to his right to palm out a firmly struck shot by Mexican captain Alberto Garcia Aspe. Later he brilliantly tipped over a header from veteran Mexican striker Carlos Hermosillo.</p>
<p>In the second half, Mexico's Adolfo Rios, standing in for the injured Jorge Campos, several times came to the rescue, diving at the feet of Peruvian forwards.</p>
<p>In the first game, Danish striker Per Pedersen, born in Hans-Christian Andersen's hometown of Odense, lived out a real-life fairy tale by scoring four goals as Denmark outclassed the United States.</p>
<p>Pedersen, who plays for his hometown club, Odense Boldklub in the Danish league, had only scored once before for his country in five internationals.</p>
<p>For the Americans, who face crucial World Cup regional qualifying matches starting in two months, the third loss in three U.S. Cup matches was a bitter disappointment.</p>
<p>Coach Steve Sampson was forced to experiment with several young internationally inexperienced players in place of regulars such as captain John Harkes and leading goalscorer Eric Wynalda, both recovering from injury.</p>
<p>Afterwards, Sampson lambasted his players for lack of effort. &quot;There was no fighting spirit, their commitment in defence was the worst I have seen in two years.</p>
<p>&quot;I was disappointed with their ability to represent what's on their chest,&quot; he said, referring to the U.S. name.</p>
<p>Pedersen struck in the 16th minute when defender Alexi Lalas weakly headed out. The Danish striker chested the ball down, beat Jeff Agoos and drilled a low left-footer past goalkeeper Brad Friedel.</p>
<p>Ten minutes later he scored with a similar low angled shot and completed his hat-trick on the stroke of half-time with an almost identical left-foot blast, seconds after Joe-Max Moore had pulled one back for the Americans with a curling free-kick over the defensive wall.</p>
<p>Just ten minutes into the second half, Pedersen staked a claim for a permanent place in coach Bo Johansson's team for World Cup qualification when he hooked home a loose ball for his fourth goal. He was substituted five minutes from the end.</p>
<p>Denmark, the 1992 European champions, were playing without British-based star players such as goalkeeper Peter Schmeichel and striker Brian Laudrup. They had lost the first match of the four-nation tournament 3-1 but rallied to beat Peru on Sunday 2-1.</p>
<p>Mexico - Adolfo Rios, Claudio Suarez, Duilio Davino, Ramon Ramirez, Alberto Garcia Aspe, Pavel Pardo, Alberto Coyote, Benjamin Galindo (Luis Garcia, 68th minute), Enrique Alfaro, Carlos Hermosillo (Ricardo Palaez, 81st), Luis Roberto Alves (Luis Hernandez, 46th)</p>
<p>Peru - Julio Balero Correa, Juan Reynoso Guzman, Percy Olivares Polanco, Roger Serrano Ruiz, Jose Soto Gomez, Nolberto Solano Todco, Juan Jose Jayo Legario, Roberto Farfan Quispe, Alex Magallanes Jaime (Paolo Maldonado Farje, 68th). Jose Pereda Maruyama (Juan Carlos Bazalar Cruzado, 82nd), Waldir Saenz Perez</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PASADENA, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
