<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327418" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. FTC announces joint venture policy review.</title>
<headline>U.S. FTC announces joint venture policy review.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Trade Commission said Thursday it will examine and update antitrust policies on joint ventures and other competitor collaborations.</p>
<p>&quot;Global and innovation-based competition is driving firms toward ever more complex collaborative agreements, which sometimes raise new competition issues,&quot; FTC Chairman Robert Pitofsky said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The FTC said the project may lead to additional guidelines on joint ventures. The FTC and Department of Justice have already issued guidelines on health care and intellectual property that provide guidance on joint ventures in those areas.</p>
<p>Pitofsky said in an interview. that joint ventures often include far more participants and are for a shorter period than they were in the past.</p>
<p>He said, for example, a joint venture might be &quot;to distribute 'The English Patient' in Spain for six months.&quot;  </p>
<p>Pitofsky said it was speculative to try to predict whether there would be new rules for joint ventures, or merely a clarification of existing law as a result of the project. But he said that either way he believed joint ventures would be facilitated.</p>
<p>Pitofsky speculated that if there were new rules they would be aimed at helping American firms have a freer hand as they competed in the world market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
