<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327435" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bankers Trust Q4 affected by reserve.</title>
<headline>Bankers Trust Q4 affected by reserve.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Establishment of a reserve by Bankers Trust New York Corp to revise items reported in prior periods had a $14 million after-tax impact on reported fourth-quarter net income of $147 million, or $0.17 per share, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>The company's fourth-quarter earnings release noted the reserve, but did not give figures. Including the reserve, the company reported primary earnings per share of $1.59 for the quarter. Adding $0.17 per share to the earnings resulted in a figure of $1.76 per share, which was slightly higher than the $1.74 consensus view on Institutional Brokers Estimate System.  </p>
<p>Raphael Soifer, analyst at Brown Brothers Harriman, said that before the one-time charge, the earnings at Bankers Trust were about as expected.</p>
<p>&quot;The good news is that a year ago Bankers Trust said it hoped to earn approximately $615 million in 1996 and they earned $612 million,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The analyst said that, while it was good the company achieved the plan, the bad news may be that some other investment banking companies with which Bankers Trust is often compared had great quarters. J.P. Morgan &amp; Co Inc, for example, had a good quarter, Soifer said.  </p>
<p>The reserve was taken &quot;as a result of an internal review of operating procedures&quot; in place between 1989 and 1995 in the Bankers Trust transaction processing businesses, the spokesman said. He said the review found accounting and procedural errors occurred, although none were material in any quarter.</p>
<p>He said the issues involved internal bookeeping items such as charge-offs that should have been taken and recoveries that should not have been realized.</p>
<p>The pre-tax charge was believed to be about $20 million, although Bankers Trust declined to be specific.  </p>
<p>The Bankers Trust fourth-quarter net income of $147 million compared with $176 million in the third quarter of 1996 and $126 million in the fourth quarter of 1995.</p>
<p>The third-quarter of 1996 included an $18 million after-tax gain from the sale of the Golden American Life Insurance subsidiary.</p>
<p>Net income from investment banking slipped to $60 million in the fourth quarter from $77 million in the third quarter, while net income from risk management services rose to $9 million from $3 million. Net income from trading and sales rose to $35 million frm $29 million.  </p>
<p>Bankers Trust said total non-intereset expense for 1996 increased $390 million, or 13 percent, from 1995, primarily due to higher incentive compensation and employee benefits related to improved financial performance.</p>
<p>Frank Newman, chairman and chief executive, said the year's results were marked by a &quot;significant recovery&quot; in earnings and expansion of business with clients across a range of global activities. He said the aim is to improve some business sectors and increase the growth rate of the best-performing sectors.</p>
<p>Bankers Trust was unchanged at 87-1/4 in early afternoon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
