<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327622" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Brent hits new session high on bullish US data.</title>
<headline>IPE Brent hits new session high on bullish US data.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE oil futures jumped to fresh session highs after today's U.S. Department of Energy data painted a more bullish picture for distillate inventories, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The DOEs turbocharged the APIs,&quot; said Charles Gray, energy analyst at Prudential in London.</p>
<p>Crude also rallied, he said, on news rebel Kurdish guerrillas attacked a twin oil pipeline from Turkey to Iraq.</p>
<p>It caused an oil spill and fire but no interruption of Iraq's crude sales under a U.N. deal, oil officials said.</p>
<p>At 1557 GMT, March Brent was up 38 cents at $22.86 a barrel. It hit a session high of $22.90 which is within a hair of an upside gap at $22.94 to $23.04.</p>
<p>The Energy Information Administration said distillate stocks fell last week by 4.8 million barrels, against Tuesday's American Petroleum Institute reported drop of nearly 3.0 million.</p>
<p>But the EIA said crude stocks fell only 1.5 million barrels, against an API draw of 3.4 million.</p>
<p>Feb gas oil gained $5.50 to $208.50 a tonne.</p>
<p>Leslie Nicholas, energy analyst at GNI, said weather forecasts for the Northeast U.S. through Feb 1 were not overly bullish for heating oil and distillate supplies were keeping up with demand.</p>
<p>But refinery turnarounds eventually could improve the heating oil picture as the &quot;need to produce gasoline ahead of the driving season will soon become a focus.&quot;</p>
<p>-- John Hanley, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8185</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
