<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327650" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Labour pressures Major for early poll.</title>
<headline>UK's Labour pressures Major for early poll.</headline>
<byline>Paul Mylrea</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>British opposition leader Tony Blair put his party on election footing on Thursday as speculation mounted the ruling Conservatives may not be able to hang on to power until their favoured poll date in May.</p>
<p>Britain's biggest bookmaker, Ladbrokes, cut the odds in favour of a March election after it became clear Prime Minister John Major will find it increasingly difficult to push through business now he has lost his overall parliamentary majority.</p>
<p>In a pep-talk to Labour candidates for the election which must be held by May 22 at the latest, Blair said: &quot;Today, I am putting you on an election war footing.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The Conservatives are in a state of decay and disintegration. They are in a state of panic. They are in such a state that anything could happen to bring the election forward.&quot;</p>
<p>Major has said he wants to wait until the last moment before calling an election. Labour is 20 points ahead in the polls and Major's grip on parliament is increasingly precarious.</p>
<p>Deaths and defections have left Major equal with the combined oppositions, at 322 seats each in the House of Commons. Labour has only 271 seats and would need the support of all other parties to defeat Major's government in a vote.</p>
<p>But in a sign of its crumbling hold on power, the government agreed on Wednesday night to give up its majority on a parliamentary committee scrutinising the Finance Bill, the crucial piece of legislation implementing the November budget.</p>
<p>It was the first time in 18 unbroken years of Conservative government that the ruling party has been forced to concede a majority on a parliamentary committee.</p>
<p>By parliamentary convention, the committee chairman is bound to break any deadlock by rejecting any amendments to a bill. This means the Conservatives should be able to frustrate any opposition attempts to sabotage the bill in the committee.</p>
<p>But it also means the government will be unable to &quot;tidy up&quot; problems it discovers as the bill goes through the committee.</p>
<p>In another threat to the government, the Ulster Unionist party from Northern Ireland, the Scottish Nationalist Party and the Welsh nationalists, Plaid Cymru, joined forces on Thursday to try and defeat a proposal to double a tax on air passengers.</p>
<p>SNP leader Alex Salmond attacked the plan as an &quot;outrageous imposition on fragile communities&quot; such as the highlands and islands of Scotland which depend on air transport to maintain their links with the mainland or the rest of the country.</p>
<p>Salmond and his allies can muster 17 members of parliament between them and need the backing of all the other opposition parties to even draw level with the ruling Conservatives.</p>
<p>A Labour source said the party was considering the idea. The air passenger tax increase is contained in the Finance Bill.</p>
<p>All the manoeuvering had an immediate effect on the election odds. Ladbrokes said a May polling day remained favourite. But Simon Clare, Ladbrokes' political betting spokesman, said: &quot;There have been some fairly hefty investments (on March).&quot;</p>
<p>He said the odds on March were now 6-4, against 9-2 on Monday and 7-2 on Wednesday. May now stood at 4-6 against Wednesday's 4-9.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
