<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327638" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dollar power fails to dazzle European bond markets.</title>
<headline>Dollar power fails to dazzle European bond markets.</headline>
<byline>Adam Cox</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dollar strength typically is a boon for many European bond markets yet the currency's latest surge will fail to inspire investors, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>For markets in Italy and Spain, a dose of dollar power equates to mark weakness and usually allows BTPs and Bonos to sneak up on benchmark Bunds. But such peripheral markets have outperformed so much already that further gains may prove tough.</p>
<p>&quot;If you think the dollar will go to 1.67-68 marks that's going to keep the convergence bandwagon alive in Europe. But I don't like the risk/reward ratio,&quot; said analyst Kirit Shah.</p>
<p>The dollar has powered above 1.64 marks, having surged more than 10 pfennigs since the start of 1997 and more than 15 pfennigs in the past two and a half months. By 1230 GMT it was at 1.6408/13 marks, having touched a 1.6455 high on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But Shah, chief strategist at Sanwa International in London, said the European yield convergence movement was losing momentum.</p>
<p>He said 10-year BTP yields could possibly narrow the spread against Bunds down to around 135-140 basis points but the risk of underperformance was much larger.</p>
<p>The BTP/Bund spread was around 150 basis points, steady on the day. It has narrowed from around 475 at the start of 1996. Spanish bonds reveal a similar success story and there the yield gap to Bunds is a paultry 89 basis points.</p>
<p>Paul Horne, chief international economist at Smith Barney in Paris, said the dollar's strength came against a backdrop of already overvalued bond markets in much of Europe. Furthermore, any dollar setback would not go down well.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar has had an absolutely remarkable move,&quot; Horne said. &quot;If the dollar were to consolidate, this could be a trigger for some intra-European corrections,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He rated Britain, Italy and Finland as most vulnerable and said these three were all sectors where investors had been overweight.</p>
<p>Shah said he favoured the gilt market on a fundamental basis. &quot;I still like gilts from a total return perspective but I'd be hedging currency risk here.&quot;</p>
<p>He pointed out sterling's strength in the later months of 1996 had been a selling point for the gilt market. Now that the dollar was on the move, hedging the currency side was a good idea. But for those who were able to ride the pound's rally, gilts were the place to be.</p>
<p>Sanwa data show gilts as the top performing market in dollar terms in the fourth quarter, with a 14.6 percent return against a local currency return of 4.5 percent. Italy was second best in dollars with an 11.3 percent return in the quarter, Shah said.</p>
<p>Horne of Smith Barney thought sterling could retreat towards 2.40 marks over the next quarter. It was last at 2.6804/13.</p>
<p>&quot;We are a little bit worried about overvaluation in some markets. This would be both for foreign exchange and bond yields. Notably it's pretty clear sterling is way overvalued.&quot; Rob Hayward, economic advisor at BankAmerica in London, expected dollar strength to continue, with a chance of the Federal Reserve raising interest rates after its policy-setting meeting in March.</p>
<p>He said European bond convergence has not run its course completely.</p>
<p>&quot;In general, European bonds will outperform the U.S. just because of the state of the European economy,&quot; said Hayward.</p>
<p>&quot;Sure, the stronger U.S. dollar will to some extent help European exports but I think that's going to be a relatively marginal effect on the overall depressed conditions in Europe,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He favoured five-year Italy paper, with more interest rate cuts ahead.</p>
<p>--International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6784</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
