<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327795" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania bans pyramid schemes, to arrest operators.</title>
<headline>Albania bans pyramid schemes, to arrest operators.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's parliament on Thursday passed a law banning pyramid investment schemes and enabling authorities to take tough action against operators, with minimum jail terms of 20 years and confiscation of their assets.</p>
<p>The draft law was initiated by President Sali Berisha's right-wing government in an effort to quell growing protests across the country from investors who stand to lose their life savings in the crumbling investment schemes.  </p>
<p>The vote in parliament was passed by 93 votes in favour, with none against. The ruling Democratic Party occupies most seats in parliament after the main opposition parties boycotted disputed general elections last May.</p>
<p>Another draft law concerning compensation for the thousands of investors who have lost money will be considered in a special session on Monday, deputies said.</p>
<p>Thousands of people have staged demonstrations across Albania in the past two weeks, some calling on the government to resign for failing to take action against the pyramid operators earlier.</p>
<p>Pyramid schemes have proliferated in Europe's poorest country since the fall of communism in 1990.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
