<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327753" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Demonstrators plan to blockade Serbian city.</title>
<headline>Demonstrators plan to blockade Serbian city.</headline>
<byline>Mark Heinrich</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Opposition protesters planned to blockade the Serbian city of Kragujevac on Thursday to demand that the ruling Socialists relinquish control of radio and television in the region.</p>
<p>Demonstrators besieged the broadcasting building in the city on Wednesday after President Slobodan Milosevic's Socialists, defeated in local elections, refused to hand it over.</p>
<p>Scores of police &quot;occupied&quot; the building after outgoing city authorities reneged on a deal to relinquish it on Wednesday morning, the independent news agency Beta said.</p>
<p>Around 10,000 supporters of the incoming Zajedno (Together) coalition government surrounded the building later on Wednesday and did not disperse until the early hours of Thursday morning.</p>
<p>Protesters planned to block all access roads to Kragujevac at 2 p.m. (1300 gmt) on Thursday to ratchet up pressure and to rally outside the media centre again later in the afternoon.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Kragujevac dispute was a textbook example of Socialist resistance to democratic reform dramatised by their annulment of municipal election results in 14 cities won by the opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition in November.</p>
<p>Kragujevac was not one of the 14. Zajedno won the elections there and there have been no Socialist allegations of &quot;irregularities&quot;, the pretext for annulments elsewehere. The industrial city has already convened its municipal assembly.</p>
<p>But Socialists anxious to prevent a liberalisation of Serbia's mainstream media were manoeuvring in the courts to preserve their grip on the Kragujevac station (RTK), the main broadcaster in the central hinterland.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation was pretty explosive overnight. People were on the verge of breaking into the building because they fear the Socialists' behaviour is foot-dragging that could last forever,&quot; said Nenad Vasiljevic, a Zajedno coalition committee member in Kragujevac.</p>
<p>Beta said that when the Socialist Party realised it would lose last November's vote in Kragujevac, it hastily enacted legislation under which RTK would be merged with the national, Socialist-run Radio and Television Serbia (RTS).</p>
<p>A Belgrade court quashed the measure on appeal, saying the right of the new Zajedno-dominated city assembly to appoint new management at the Kragujevac station took precedence.</p>
<p>Local sources said the Socialists had agreed to formally vacate RTK at 8 a.m. on Wednesday but instead had dozens of loyal police occupy it to thwart a handover.</p>
<p>RTS, meanwhile, appealed to a higher court and sent two managers from Belgrade to run the Kragujevac station.</p>
<p>Independent local media said Zajedno did not intend to turn Kragujevac radio and TV into its own media organ but merely open up its programming to a variety of news and opinion.</p>
<p>Zajedno says it is committed to democratic and free-market reform in Serbia, in part by ending Socialist domination of the mainstream media and much of the judicial system.</p>
<p>Daily demonstrations by students and Zajedno demanding that the government reinstate opposition victories in all 14 cities in dispute are now in their 10th week.</p>
<p>President Slobodan Milosevic is grappling with the gravest challenge to a half century of monolithic leftist rule in federal Yugoslavia, comprising Serbia and small Montenegro.</p>
<p>He has not deigned to acknowledge the opposition triumphs despite great pressure by the West, which has told him democratic reform is a condition of foreign economic aid.</p>
<p>In the capital Belgrade, where Zajedno's election victory was nullified, non-stop student protests stretched into a fifth day on Thursday in cat-and-mouse games with riot police.</p>
<p>Protesters' sudden appearances and disappearances in different parts of town kept police racing from district to district to prevent local columns from joining forces for a march into the city centre.</p>
<p>Belgrade's election commissioners, whose earlier ruling that Zajedno indeed won control of local government in the capital is being challenged in court, awarded four more seats to Zajedno on Wednesday, increasing its claimed majority.</p>
<p>But the Socialists and their neo-communist allies, the Yugoslav United Left led by Milosevic's powerful wife Mira Markovic, have appealed to the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a world champion-class legalistic mess, meticulously crafted to exhaust just about everyone -- Zajedno, the students and the West. Sorry, it won't work,&quot; a Western diplomat said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
