<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327807" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares set high, seen extending gains.</title>
<headline>Polish shares set high, seen extending gains.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares on Thursday set a third consecutive 33-month high in heavy trade and post-fixing buying was seen pushing them to another high on Friday, but analysts said a profit-taking correction was likely next week.</p>
<p>The bourse has risen 23 percent since December 10.</p>
<p>&quot;After today's session I believe there might be more growth tomorrow, but I think next week investors will start taking profits after such a surge,&quot; said Maciej Matusiak, an analyst at PKO BP brokerage.</p>
<p>Analysts expected 16,000 points to privide strong support for the WIG index next week.</p>
<p>The main market's WIG index rose 308.1 points, or 1.9 percent, to 16,341.2, and turnover rose 26.6 percent to 205.9 million zlotys ($69.3 million) on both markets as 69 issues rose, eight fell and nine were flat.</p>
<p>Some analysts said the profit-taking correction was likely to be brief and the market could return to its uptrend later on, possibly on growing foreign interest in Polish stocks, which were luring new investors.</p>
<p>Analysts said computer maker Optimus surged 9.6 percent, extending Wednesday's 9.8-percent jump on the back of strong December earnings.</p>
<p>They said construction firm Espebepe's 10-percent rally was speculative, as the firms fundamentals were weak.</p>
<p>Continuous trade turnover was at 20.8 million zlotys ($7 million) with eight stocks rising, seven falling and six staying flat.</p>
<p>Mass privatisaton NFI units fell 1.9 percent to 157 zlotys ($52.8) in 18.2-million-zloty ($6.1 million) continuous trade but rose 2.6 percent in 18.3-million-zloty ($6.2 million) trade in the regular session.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
