<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327841" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin proves little with quick return to Kremlin.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin proves little with quick return to Kremlin.</headline>
<byline>Timothy Heritage</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin's sudden return to the Kremlin after pneumonia was bravado typical of Russia's battling leader, but it has done nothing to dispel doubts about his ability to rule.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's unexpected visit to the Kremlin on Wednesday, less than two full days after leaving hospital, was clearly designed to prove to Russians that he is well enough to rule.</p>
<p>But the absence of television pictures or new photographs to trumpet his return has left many questions unanswered and had the unintended effect of kindling speculation that he may not be able to see out his four-year second term.</p>
<p>&quot;Even Yeltsin's sudden arrival in the Kremlin is not convincing,&quot; the liberal newspaper Izvestia said.</p>
<p>&quot;Information is coming from several sources that Boris Yeltsin's illness was not as straightforward as was said at first,&quot; it said, without giving details.</p>
<p>The 65-year-old president's talks in the Kremlin with Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin coincided with a parliamentary debate initiating efforts to oust him.</p>
<p>His opponents have little chance of achieving anything more than drawing attention to Yeltsin's ill health and what they regard as flaws in a constitution which makes it a long and difficult process to remove the president.</p>
<p>But Yeltsin has been provoked yet again into risking his health to prove he can still rule the vast country despite two heart attacks in 1995, a quintuple bypass operation last November, pneumonia and other illnesses during his life.</p>
<p>In an unusual departure from the tradition when Yeltsin has resurfaced after previous illnesses, the Kremlin released no television footage of the president on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The only pictures shown were of his motorcade arriving at the Kremlin gates. They did not show the president himself.</p>
<p>Yeltsin has not been seen in public, in television pictures nor in photographs since he had a meeting in the Kremlin on January 6, two days before he was taken to hospital with pneumonia. In those last pictures, he looked shaky.</p>
<p>Chief Kremlin doctor Sergei Mironov made clear Yeltsin was rushing his convalescence. He has also suggested the president was depressed by his pneumonia, which struck two weeks after he ended nearly six months out of the Kremlin with heart problems.</p>
<p>His press secretary, Sergei Yastrzhembsky, seemed to be caught off guard by Yeltsin's unscheduled return. Two days earlier, he had played down the likelihood of Yeltsin returning to the Kremlin quickly.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no point in expecting the president to rush back to full-time work, which also means the Kremlin,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In another departure from usual procedure, the presidential press service did not make clear how long Yeltsin spent in the Kremlin. Media reports ranged from 30 minutes to three hours.</p>
<p>&quot;It does not look like Yeltsin being back as a born-again person,&quot; said Andrei Kortunov, a political analyst who heads the Russian Science Foundation.</p>
<p>Predicting more delays in economic and political reforms while Yeltsin recovers from his pneumonia, Kortunov said: &quot;I think Russia will again be muddling through. Some of the most crucial problems will not be tackled and put on the shelf.&quot;</p>
<p>Some Russian newspapers, often more cautious than Western media in expressing concern over Yeltsin's health, openly questioned the wisdom of his Kremlin visit.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems nobody has reliable information about the president's condition and the extent of his work capacity today,&quot; said the liberal daily Sevodnya.</p>
<p>Sevodnya said one possible scenario was that Yeltsin had wanted to establish himself back at the Kremlin but was froced to leave after feeling ill.</p>
<p>But it expressed hope that Yeltsin had briefly escaped his doctors and would now continue his recovery as planned outside the Kremlin.</p>
<p>&quot;Otherwise, the president's long-awaited return to the Krmelin is not only disappointing, but leads to sad contemplation of the need for an early presidential election -- the worst of the possible Russian woes,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
