<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327932" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil party insists on further re-election delay.</title>
<headline>Brazil party insists on further re-election delay.</headline>
<byline>William Schomberg</byline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's government faces an uphill struggle in putting a re-election bill to a key vote next week as senior figures within Congress' biggest political party continue to insist on further delay, party officials said.</p>
<p>Senators from the Brazilian Democratic Movement Party (PMDB) met on Thursday and agreed the party must stock to its decision not to vote on re-election until after elections for the new presidents of the Chamber of Deputies  and the Senate February 4.</p>
<p>But the PMDB's pro-government whip in the lower house, Dep. Michel Temer, was meeting with government allies in an attempt to find a solution to the impasse that would allow for a first vote in the lower house on re-election next week.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now it's impossible to make any assessment of which way the party may go,&quot; said a spokesman for Temer.</p>
<p>President Fernando Henrique Cardoso called a special session of Congress to run through the January recess, principally to put a constitutional amendment allowing his re-election to the two votes it needs for approval in the Chamber of Deputies.  </p>
<p>That would have allowed the government to get back to its reforms of the pension and tax systems and the civil service, which have been on hold for months amid re-election fever.</p>
<p>The government's timetable was thrown off course by the insistence of senior figures within the PMDB that the internal congressional elections had to come first.</p>
<p>The PMDB's move was seen as preventing the government from backing Antonio Carlos Magalhaes, a powerful political boss who is running for Senate president as the candidate of the Liberal Front Party, a closer government ally than the PMDB.  </p>
<p>Government attempts to persuade the party to back down and vote on re-election before February 4 have so far failed. &quot;All the (PMDB's) senators and a good chunk of the deputies agree on the party's position,&quot; said a PMDB official in the Senate.</p>
<p>The idea of putting re-election to a vote in the Chamber of Deputies right after the elections for the Congressional presidencies is considered too risky, according to a government source in Congress.</p>
<p>As a constitutional amendment, the re-election bill requires two three-fifths majorites in the lower house, which would be hard to guarantee in the wake of the potentially destabilizing internal elections, the source said.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be too much of a gamble. Whatever the outcome of the elections, people are going to be upset,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The government was still hopeful it would win its &quot;tug-of-war&quot; with the PMDB and put the bill to a vote next week.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll have to sit down on Monday and see who's with us,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>((-- Brasilia newsroom 5561 2230358))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
