<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327907" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine small business joins labor reform debate.</title>
<headline>Argentine small business joins labor reform debate.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's small and medium-sized companies said Thursday they had agreed to talks on employment with the government and trade unions in parallel with three-way talks involving big business.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't want our problems to be resolved without our participation,&quot; said Osvaldo Cornide, head of the small business lobby CAME which took part in talks with Cabinet Chief Jorge Rodriguez late Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Argentina's most powerful industrial lobbies agreed this week to resume three-way discussions of labor reforms, which broke down when the CGT labor federation held a general strike, its third in the year, on December 26.</p>
<p>But smaller businesses are more closely allied to unions and have supported some of the recent strikes.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a common interest in preserving the domestic consumer market, reaching full employment, having decent wages which create selling opportunities for goods that small and medium companies manufacture or sell,&quot; Cornide told local radio.  </p>
<p>Smaller firms are also more cautious about labor reforms that President Carlos Menem has unsuccessfully tried to push through by decree. Menem argues that his reforms are the only way to combat unemployment that stands at 17.3 percent.</p>
<p>Menem wants to reduce union control of collective pay talks, replace redundancy payouts with unemployment insurance and dismantle union control of the health care system.  </p>
<p>But labor courts have sided with unions by declaring Menem's decrees on collective bargaining unconstitutional. Menem has vowed to defend them in the courts while the big business lobbies, who originally said they wanted reforms by consensus only, are now urging Menem to rush through reforms by decree.</p>
<p>&quot;It is one thing to modernize labor legislation, for example the redundancy system that prevents us from taking on new staff, but quite another to act in the interests of some economic groups who want two or three million unemployed to impose a labor system like Singapore's,&quot; said Cornide.</p>
<p>Cabinet Chief Rodriguez told reporters after Wednesday's meeting that he would seek union agreement to parallel talks with small businesses, which he said would also include broader issues such as tax evasion, dumping and interest rates.</p>
<p>((-- Stephen Brown, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0695))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
