<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="327952" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Chile sees Clinton re-election boosting Nafta hopes.</title>
<headline>Chile sees Clinton re-election boosting Nafta hopes.</headline>
<dateline>CANCUN, Mexico 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chile's Finance Minister on Wednesday said U.S. President Bill Clinton's re-election may bolster chances of achieving &quot;fast-track&quot; status to join the North American Free Trade Agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States is a question mark...I hope that at some point, sooner rather than later, President Clinton will put his own weight behind a global fast-track project. Now he's re-elected he's more popular,&quot; Finance Minister Eduardo Aninat told reporters.</p>
<p>Aninat, attending a Latin American investment conference in this Caribbean resort, said Chile was not staking everything on NAFTA membership.</p>
<p>Chile, Latin America's strongest economy, was supposed to become a full member of the treaty with United States, Mexico and Canada in mid-1996, but was frustrated in its bid chiefly because the U.S. Congress resisted granting &quot;fast-track&quot; authority which speeds the approval process.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope (fast-track) happens,&quot; Aninat said. &quot;If it does Chile will negotiate firmly, well, as it should, and if it doesn't occur we will continue advancing with other treaties.&quot;</p>
<p>President Eduardo Frei was due to visit the White House next month and he evidently will press Clinton to throw his personal backing behind fast-track.</p>
<p>&quot;What we still don't see is a fast-track project from the White House, that's the weight that's missing, the rest is very positive good intentions,&quot; Aninat said.</p>
<p>Chile signed a NAFTA-style agreement with Canada last year and also has a free trade agreement with Mexico. Seperately, last year it signed a trade treaty with the trading bloc that includes Brazil, Argentina, Paraguay and Uruguay.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANCUN, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
