<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="328059" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX heatoil falls in consolidation late session.</title>
<headline>NYMEX heatoil falls in consolidation late session.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX heating oil fell Thursday afternoon, consolidating earlier gains amid a bearish weather outlook and views that supplies are ample despite a recent drop in distillate stocks, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;We had some supportive information last night in the APIs, but it does not get rid of the general downtrend in heat,&quot; said Al Lindseth, manager of oil &amp; gas hedge programs at GSC Energy in Atlanta.</p>
<p>At 1402 EST, February heating oil was off 0.29 cent a gallon at 66.60 cents. March crude was up 10 cents at $24.34 a barrel.  </p>
<p>February gasoline was up 0.18 cent at 68.40 cents a gallon, with traders citing one fund in particular buying around the 68.35 area.</p>
<p>On Thursday, the Department of Energy's (DOE) Energy Information Administration (EIA) said distillate stocks, comprised of heating oil and diesel, dropped 4.8 million barrels for the week ended January 17.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the American Petroleum Institute (API) said Wednesday that distillate stocks dropped 2.95 million barrels for that week.</p>
<p>Traders expected a draw of three million barrels.</p>
<p>Dealers noted heating oil's price rise Wednesday on expectation of a stock draw for the most part absorbed the upside effect of the actual inventory data.</p>
<p>&quot;The second half of today is about those who got in heat yesterday and getting out after we have penetrated yesterday's highs,&quot; said a New York dealer.</p>
<p>Dealers noted distillate stocks are about steady with last year, creating sufficient supply amid a six to 10 day forecast from the National Weather Service that calls for above average temperatures in the key heating oil market of the U.S. Northeast.</p>
<p>Crude stocks declined for the January 17 week as well. But, crude was also off earlier highs as dealers expected the open arbitrage from Europe to result in an influx of imports near term when crude demand was being softened by a slew of refinery turnarounds.</p>
<p>((-- Harry Milling, New York Energy Desk, 212-859-1761))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
