<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="328100" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France's Bardot cleared of racist slur.</title>
<headline>France's Bardot cleared of racist slur.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Paris court on Thursday cleared former film star Brigitte Bardot of inciting racial hatred in saying that France was being invaded by sheep-slaughtering Moslems.</p>
<p>The court said her comments were &quot;above all the expression of rebellion against animal distress made as part of a passionate struggle for animal rights&quot;.</p>
<p>Cheered by fans and animal lovers, the 62-year-old former screen sex symbol who has come under fire for far-right views, had denied the charges at a December 19 hearing.</p>
<p>The Movement Against Racism (MRAP) said it would appeal against the ruling which it criticised as &quot;incomprehensible&quot; and tantamount to granting impunity to authors of racist comments.</p>
<p>MRAP, the Human Rights League and the League Against Racism and Anti-Semitism had filed the complaints agains Bardot which if upheld, could have led to up to a year in prison and a 300,000-franc ($60,000) fine under French laws against inciting racial hatred.</p>
<p>The ex-actress turned animal rights activist was sued for her outspoken criticism of the Moslem ritual slaughter of sheep and of immigration into France from Moslem countries.</p>
<p>The court found her criticism of Moslem &quot;overpopulation&quot; was excessive but could not be banned in a democratic society.</p>
<p>&quot;Ruling otherwise would go against our democratic principles by making some issues taboo and virtually allowing prosecution of opinions, which is not what the legislator wanted,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>In an opinion column in the conservative daily Le Figaro last April, Bardot said the traditional throat-slitting of sheep for the Aid-al-Kebir Moslem feast was barbarous and went against French law.</p>
<p>&quot;France, my country, my homeland, my land is again being invaded with the blessing of successive governments by a foreign overpopulation, mainly Moslem, to which we pay allegiance,&quot; she wrote.</p>
<p>&quot;Mosques flourish while our churchbells go silent for lack of priests,&quot; she wrote.</p>
<p>Public prosecutor Marie-Jeanne Vieillard had accused Bardot of denouncing Moslem traditions but had not requested a specific punishment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
