<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="328134" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian bonds/futures.</title>
<headline>Italian bonds/futures.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian bond futures held to slightly firmer levels after making new record highs helped by the lira's strength, but weakness in other bond markets pared back gains in later trading, dealers said.</p>
<p>The lira pushed to near the 676 lire/mark area helping BTP futures and the cash market to hit new record levels. The lira's strength edged it to near 31-month highs prompting investors to again show buying interest in Italy, dealers added.</p>
<p>German December M3 money supply data came in stronger than expected and helped put an early cautious tone to bond markets as hopes of a German rate cut were put on the backburner.  </p>
<p>As largely expected, the Bundesbank held German interest rates steady at its regular council meeting today.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength of the dollar and lira helped BTPs to scale fresh highs, but with most other bond markets doing nothing much, futures simply slipped back,&quot; said one LIFFE trader.</p>
<p>Dealers added that the Italian BTP market is currently at very high levels, and susceptible to profit-taking on the slightess opportunity.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been seeing this stop-start trend as investors keep one eye firmly on the international situation,&quot; the LIFFE trader added.  </p>
<p>On the domestic front, investors were awaiting a meeting on Friday of Prime Minister Romano Prodi with unions and employers to discuss a long-running bitter dispute over pay increases for 1.7 million workers in the metalworker and engineering industry.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
