<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="328183" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bonn tax plan can boost GDP - if it clears hurdles.</title>
<headline>Bonn tax plan can boost GDP - if it clears hurdles.</headline>
<byline>David Crossland</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German economy will benefit as early as this year from a proposed tax reform but the impact will be moderate even in the unlikely event that the changes pass through parliament intact, analysts said.</p>
<p>The draft reform presented by the ruling coalition on Thursday is an important step towards curbing the disincentives which have Europe's biggest economy in a stranglehold, keeping unemployment high and growth weak, the economists said.</p>
<p>But they added that far more needed to be done to encourage companies to invest here.</p>
<p>Hailed by finance minister Theo Waigel as the biggest tax overhaul since the war, it cuts 81.9 billion marks ($50 billion) in taxes but raises an extra 38.1 billion by broadening the tax base.</p>
<p>&quot;At last we're getting a secure idea of what tax system to expect, it will help companies to plan investments and will at least boost sentiment,&quot; said Adolf Rosenstock, an economist at Industrial Bank of Japan in Frankfurt. &quot;We may see the first positive effects in the second half of 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>Current forecasts for Germany's 1997 growth range from two to 2.5 percent, up from a meagre 1.4 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>But economists warned that the reform had yet to be implemented and would get a rough ride from the opposition Social Democrats (SPD) who can block the measures through their control of the upper house of parliament.</p>
<p>There was no decision yet on Thursday on a controversial proposal to raise value-added-tax (VAT) by one percentage point to 16 percent to help finance the changes.</p>
<p>Overall, if VAT is increased, the package will cut the net tax burden by about 30 billion marks -- roughly 0.75 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) -- split between 1998 and 1999, the two years over which the changes will take effect, economists said.</p>
<p>They include a two-step drop in corporate taxation, starting in 1998 and ending in 1999, when retained company profits will be taxed at 35 percent and profits distributed to shareholders at 25 percent.</p>
<p>Economists said the removal of tax breaks for companies next year may cause firms to bring forward investments they had planned for 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;But it will only be a small effect, one should not expect wonders,&quot; said Ralf Kugelstadt at UBS in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Together with the planned two-percentage point cut next year in the 7.5 percent income tax surcharge which helps fund state spending in east Germany, companies face a net tax reduction of about 10 billion marks in 1998, said Ruetger Teuscher, an economist at DB Research in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>&quot;That could give economic growth a push,&quot; Teuscher said. &quot;But we have to be sceptical because it won't be easy for the government to push the changes through in this form.&quot;</p>
<p>The reform cuts the top income tax rate to 39 percent from 53 percent, taxes pay up to 18,000 marks at 15 percent and then has a sliding scale running from 22.5 percent to 39 percent at 90,000 marks. Income below 13,000 marks per year is tax-free.</p>
<p>The income tax changes take effect in 1999.</p>
<p>The SPD was quick to attack the plan on Thursday, saying an income of 13,000 marks was too low to be taxed. The party's finance spokesman Joachim Poss called the package a &quot;mixture of reform, retouches and tricks.&quot; ($1=1.6383 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
