<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="328242" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian cult linked to sex trade driven underground.</title>
<headline>Indian cult linked to sex trade driven underground.</headline>
<byline>Savita Kirloskar</byline>
<dateline>SAUNDATTI, India 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's efforts to stamp out an outlawed religious cult linked to child sex slavery has driven rituals underground and fewer girls are being trapped into prostitution, police and social workers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>This year's annual celebration of Yelamma, a manifestation of the Hindu goddess Renuka, moved into full swing at Saundatti, a town in the south Indian state of Karnataka, on Thursday.</p>
<p>But there was no sign of public &quot;dedications&quot; of children to become Devadasis, meaning &quot;handmaidens to the deity&quot;, as tens of thousand of pilgrims converged on Yelamma's temple under the watchful eye of police and social campaigners.</p>
<p>Many girls chosen as Devadasis are destined to become teenage prostitutes.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not expect any dedications of children (at the temple) this year. If any do take place it will be in secret,&quot; Latha Mala, a social worker running a rehabilitation centre for Devadasis in the nearby town of Belgaum, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Pilgrims, including whole villages, travelled for days by foot, car, bus and bullock cart to reach the temple and pitched tents around Saundatti for three days of festivities.</p>
<p>&quot;If any dedications of young girls are taking place it will be furtively in the camps or back home in their villages,&quot; Suresh, another social worker, said pointing to the camps.</p>
<p>Most devotees of Yelamma, drawn largely from the Dalits, or low caste Hindus, have nothing to do with the Devadasi cult.</p>
<p>But many older women and transvestites belonging to the Devadasis were among worshippers here for the festival.</p>
<p>Several older Devadasi women told Reuters how they were dedicated to the goddess as children, and once they reached puberty sold to a man for sex before being returned to their parents, who sold them on to pimps and brothels.</p>
<p>But young girls wearing the telltale red-and-white bead necklace of a Devadasi bride to Yelamma were nowhere to be seen.</p>
<p>&quot;They are afraid of the police,&quot; Suresh said.</p>
<p>&quot;The cult members may hold a secret, quick puja (ceremony) and tie the beads around the girls' necks, but there will not be the elaborate ceremonies of the past, akin to marriage, where the necklace is transferred from the goddess's neck to the girls,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Police said around 250 officers, including 40 undercover detectives, mingled with the hordes of worshippers.</p>
<p>Social workers said they had around 100 former Devadasis and volunteers looking out for illegal &quot;initiations&quot;.</p>
<p>Dr Ishwarprasad Gilada, of the privately-funded Indian Health Organistion in Bombay, said he believed around 1,000 girls a year were inducted into a system that would eventually lead many of them to brothels in Bombay and other cities.</p>
<p>The figure marks a sharp fall from 6,000 less than 10 years ago, Gilada said.</p>
<p>&quot;Prostitution is still being practised under the guise of the Devadasi system,&quot; Mala said, but added that the cult was dying.</p>
<p>Awareness of AIDS and campaigns to debunk superstition and educate people in backward rural areas have made an impact.</p>
<p>Social workers said police handed over anyone caught holding initiation rites to counsellors, who try to dispel the superstitions binding people to the cult.</p>
<p>Campaigners against the centuries-old system then conduct re-education programmes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAUNDATTI, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
