<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="328865" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</title>
<headline>Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain and oilseed exports reported by USDA and private export sources.</p>
<p>WHEAT SALE - Iraq has finalised contracts to buy between 250,000 and 275,000 tonnes of French wheat for March and April at prices between $184 and $185 per tonne C and F, European grain traders said Wednesday.</p>
<p>CORN SALE - China concluded the sale of 145,000 tonnes of corn to the Philippines on a governmment-to-government basis at US$157 a tonne C&amp;F, a U.S. government official said. The sale was for February to April shipment and was done at a higher level than current U.S. corn export quotes to the region.  </p>
<p>CORN SALES - South Korean feed millers bought at least 76,000 tonnes of Chinese corn through private negotiations, traders said. The purchase prices ranged from $139.50 to $143 per tonne, and shipment dates were from March 10 through May 20.</p>
<p>- Taiwan's CK group bought a 54,000 tonne shipment of U.S. No.2 corn from Mitsui, traders said. One shipment of 37,500 tonnes from cost $120.53 per tonne, and the rest was priced at 38.15 cents per bushel over CBOT March futures. Shipment was slated for March 3 to 15.  </p>
<p>SOYBEAN SALE - South Korea's Sam Yang Foods Co Ltd it bought 15,000 tonnes of U.S. No. 2 soybeans from Japanese trading house Marubeni, the company said. Shipment was slated for first half February from the U.S. Gulf.</p>
<p>WHEAT TENDERS - India's state-run trading corporation will tender for 50,000 tonnes of wheat for arrival by the end of March. The tender will close on January 29, traders said.</p>
<p>- Jordan will tender on February 5 for 50,000 tonnes of U.S. hard wheat or equivalent origin for shipment by March 31, traders said. U.S. wheat would be under the GSM 102 program said.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDER - Moroccan importers will buy a total of 27,000 tonnes of optional-origin milling wheat, traders said. One tender for 12,000 tonnes is set for January 21, with delivery slated for January 31. A second tender will be held for 15,000 tonnes on January 23. Shipment for that purchase is set for February 25 through March 5, export sources said.</p>
<p>- Lebanon's economy ministry plans to buy 50,000 tonnes of U.S. hard wheat later this month, the government said.</p>
<p>- Results were awaited on Bangladesh's tender for 100,000 tonnes of U.S. No.2 wheat or Australian or Canadian winter red/spring wheat for shipment by February 21.  </p>
<p>BARLEY/WHEAT TENDER - The Cyprus Grain Commission invited tenders for one shipment of 12,000 tonnes of European milling wheat and one 25,000 tonne shipment of barley. Shipment for the wheat was March 13 to 28 and February for the barley.</p>
<p>CORN TENDER - News was awaited on South Africa's Maize Board's tender for 15,000 tonnes of yellow maize for either export or domestic use. The offer was seen closing January 16.</p>
<p>RICE TENDER - Syria's General Foreign Trade Organization for Chemicals and Foodstuffs is seeking to buy 12,000 tonnes of white rice for March shipment. Results would be February 13.  </p>
<p>SOYBEAN TENDERS - South Korea's state-run Agricultural and Fishery Marketing Corp invited tenders for 40,000 tonnes of U.S. No. 1 soybeans on January 29. Shipment of one 20,000 purchase will be for January 30 to February 18 from the U.S. Gulf or from February 14 to March 5 from the U.S. Pacific Northwest. Shipment of the other 20,000 tonnes will be from the U.S. Gulf between February 24 to March 15 or from PNW March 11 to 30.</p>
<p>PALM STEARIN TENDER - The Egypt's state Food Industries Company said it sought 10,000 tonnes of Malaysian or Indonesian palm stearin for March delivery. The tender will close 1000 GMT on February 12.</p>
<p>MARKET TALK - A shortage of export possibilities to both EU and non-EU countries is keeping Europe's domestic grains markets on a downward drift, traders said.</p>
<p>- Up to one million tonnes of soybean meal is clogging Chinese ports, filling warehouses and forcing domestic prices down, traders said. Traders polled by Reuters varied in their view of just when the stocks would dwindle to a point that inspires buying. Optimists said February and pessimists said July.</p>
<p>((Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
