<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="328902" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Virgin Express says profitable in 1996.</title>
<headline>Virgin Express says profitable in 1996.</headline>
<byline>Bert Lauwers</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Richard Branson's Virgin Express low-cost European airline had a profit in 1996 despite soaring fuel prices and currency depreciation, the carrier's chief executive said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We were profitable in 1996 in spite of the fact that we had fuel increases that amounted to $5 million, currency fluctuations -- the Belgian franc depreciated against the dollar -- which probably cost us another $3 to 4 million,&quot; Jonathan Ornstein said in an interview with Reuters.  </p>
<p>&quot;Those two things alone would have wiped out the profits of 1995 and yet we were still profitable... plus, we grew very significantly. If you look at the big picture, 1996 was a very successful year for us,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said the performance of Brussels-based Virgin Express last year had exceeded all expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;No question, We have had some serious challenges. One of them is that we've gone from 300 scheduled departures a month to over 1,200...we are no logner a little sleepy charter company,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Revenue soared 30 percent to six billion francs in 1996, the airline carried 1.8 million passengers, up 35 percent from 1995, and its workforce increased by 25 percent to 550.</p>
<p>In 1996, Virgin Express added new services from Brussels to Nice, Copenhagen, and - in conjunction with Belgian national airline Sabena - 18 flights a day between London's Heathrow airport and Brussels.</p>
<p>In addition, it started direct daily scheduled services from Rome to Barcelona and Madrid.</p>
<p>Ornstein said Virgin Express was making &quot;a nice profit&quot; in the charter business which had plenty of room for expansion.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have huge market opportunities in places like Rome, Madrid, Barcelona and Copenhagen, where we fly currently. From Copenhagen for instance we only fly to Brussels, why can't we fly from Copenhagen to Madrid or to Rome some day?&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The company now flies to 150 charter destinations and operates scheduled daily services between 10 major European cities.</p>
<p>It will focus this year on adding frequencies, and trying to connect new city pairs within its existing system.  </p>
<p>&quot;For 1997 we're pretty full up as far as what we are going to do. We are scheduled to go to 18 airplanes. I don't think we can look at a whole lot of new services,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The average age of its 14 Boeing 737 planes is now under five years and bound to drop further.</p>
<p>Virgin Express was launched last April after Branson's Virgin Group bought 90 percent of EuroBelgian Airlines (EBA).</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6815, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
