<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="328927" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares end bourse up within narrow range.</title>
<headline>German shares end bourse up within narrow range.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's DAX index ended bourse trade on Thursday slightly higher in range-trade dealings, recovering from earlier weakness after German M3 money supply growth was higher than expected in December.</p>
<p>The 30-share index ended up 4.79 points at 3,033.46 points after spending the session within a 20-point range, helped in part by the ongoing strength in the dollar and on Wall Street.</p>
<p>The German share market also showed little reaction to the Bundesbank keeping key interest rates steady at its fortnightly council meeting on Thursday, a move the market had expected.</p>
<p>Hopes for even a modest trimming of the German central bank's key money market rate, the repo, were dashed after December M3 money supply grew at an annual 7.9 percent rate compared with 8.0 percent in November.</p>
<p>The M3 data also grew by 8.1 percent in the final quarter of 1996 from the final quarter a year earlier, which was above the bank's four to seven percent expansion corridor for 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;The money supply figures were a shock,&quot; said one trader, noting the modest drop in the DAX after information about the Bundesbank's key monetary policy indicator was released.</p>
<p>Dealers also expressed some concern about details emerging on Germany's planned tax reform, with the Bonn government's tax working group saying earlier on Thursday that it plans included a proposal to tighten rules on short-term share market gains.</p>
<p>&quot;That acted as a dampener, largely because the market is rather nervous in any case,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Among individual shares, engineering group Mannesmann ended up five marks at 648 marks after announcing that its DBKom domestic communications joint venture, renamed as Arcor, would invest some 800 million marks in 1997.</p>
<p>Mannesmann also confirmed that U.S. telephone giant AT&amp;T would take a stake in the project along with Germany's largest commercial bank, Deutsche Bank AG.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
