<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="329025" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: MARKETS-PRECIOUS 1STLD.</title>
<headline>MARKETS-PRECIOUS 1STLD.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold prices lumbered lower on Thursday afternoon to fresh 40-month lows below $350 an ounce amid steady selling pressure, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Every time gold pokes its head above $350 an ounce it gets sold,&quot; one said, pinning the selling on Australian producers, speculators and investment funds.</p>
<p>Bullion was fixed at $348.00 an ounce, a fresh low fixing since September 15, 1993, and down $1.80 from the morning's level.</p>
<p>Most activity was concentrated on New York's Comex futures market, with volumes in Europe remaining light, dealers said.</p>
<p>Prices were bid as low as $346.50 ahead of the fixing, then firmed slightly to hold just above $348.</p>
<p>Some dealers expected prices to range between $348 and $352 for the time being.</p>
<p>But $345 is frequently cited by technical analysts as the next likely target for gold.</p>
<p>Dealers were doubtful that gold, which was oversold with an RSI of 25, would make much progress even if it managed a bounce.</p>
<p>The surging U.S. dollar, which had put crushing pressure on gold earlier this week, was off its 30-plus months highs against the mark and yen posted yesterday.</p>
<p>But sentiment remained darkened by fears of central bank gold sales ahead of European Monetary Union and the potential of renewed producer hedging, dealers said.</p>
<p>In sharp contrast to gold, silver was up five cents from Wednesday's close, at $4.77/$4.79 an ounce.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though gold is weaker, silver can't be budged and the gold-silver ratio is really moving,&quot; a dealer said, noting that market players were buying silver as they sold gold as a play on the ratio.</p>
<p>The gold-silver ratio was close to 73, down from about 77 at the start of the year.</p>
<p>Platinum, however, has been closely shadowing gold and also fell to its lowest fixing since September 15, 1993 when it was fixed at $355.85 per ounce.</p>
<p>Dealers said platinum was attracting very little interest despite its low price.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been caught in the downdraft from gold and has virtually no life of its own,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Palladium, which has been holding steady despite weakness in gold and platinum, was barely changed at $120.50/$121.50.</p>
<p>--Lida Poletz, London newsroom +44 171 542 2936</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
