<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="329146" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks end weaker, extend losing streak.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks end weaker, extend losing streak.</headline>
<text>
<p>CHANGE				    CHANGE</p>
<p>TSE	  6058.67    -17.31   HI 6070.78	    LO  6048.36</p>
<p>DJI	  6850.03    -33.87   GOLD (LONDON)   US$351.20 -3.50</p>
<p>FTSE100    4219.10    +23.60   GOLD (NY-COMEX) US$351.90 -1.90</p>
<p>NIKKEI    18013.88   +655.72   LME CASH NICKEL US$7150  -120.0</p>
<p>CANDLR	1.3379		 LME CASH ALUM   US$1604.5  -3.5</p>
<p>CAN 30-YR   108.25     -0.75   FEB BRENT CRUDE US$22.46  +0.12</p>
<p>--------------------MARKET COMMENT----------------------------</p>
<p>* Toronto stocks ended softer on Wednesday, extending their recent losing streak to three days * Canada market followed losses on Wall St * 123.09 million shares traded worth C$1.97 bln  </p>
<p>Toronto's three-day is considered a healthy breather after strong gains earlier this year, Meisels said. &quot;A pause is perfectly natural.&quot;</p>
<p>Toronto's 14 sub-indices were equally split between gainers and losers. The weaker side was led by battered golds, oils, base metals and consumer products. Stronger sectors included media, transports and pipelines.</p>
<p>Declining stocks outnumbered advances 559 to 450 while 271 traded unchanged.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Shares in the nation's largest airline Air Canada rose 0.75 to 8.00 on ten million shares. Investors were comparing Air Canada's favourable outlook with financially troubled competitor Canadian Airlines Corp as both waded back into a seat sale, one analyst said.</p>
<p>* Small prospector Golden Rule rose 1.10 to close at 12.00 on speculation about a property in Ghana.</p>
<p>* Barrick Gold Corp slipped 0.60 to 35.55 after news that potential partner Bre-X Minerals Ltd said it acknowledged the 30-day deadline provided by the Indonesian government and will strive to resolve issues with its Indonesian partners. Bre-X shares rose 0.05 to 22.65. ((Lydia Zajc, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100))  </p>
<p>Toronto's three-day decline is a healthy breather after strong gains earlier this year, Meisels said. &quot;A pause is perfectly natural,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The TSE's 14 sub-indices were equally divided between gainers and losers. The weak side was led by battered golds, oils, base metals and consumer products. Strong sectors included media, transportation and pipelines.</p>
<p>Declining stocks outnumbered advances 559 to 450 with 271 issues unchanged.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Air Canada rose 0.75 to 8 on 10 million shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
