<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="329204" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-SFE has record wheat delivery in January.</title>
<headline>RTRS-SFE has record wheat delivery in January.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A record 22,000 tonnes of wheat has been delivered on the expiry of the Sydney Futures Exchange (SFE) contract for January, the SFE said in a statement.</p>
<p>Chief executive of the SFE Les Hosking said the record 440 contract deliveries was a reflection of the increasing activity of the wheat futures contract and also of price volatility in the second half of 1996.</p>
<p>In the second half of 1996, the Australian Wheat Board's pool price fell by A$60.00 to A$185.00 a tonne.  </p>
<p>The regular price revisions of 1996 demonstrated that even with a statutory pool price, significant price risk could be experienced, he said.</p>
<p>Unforeseen changes in weather, economic conditions and overseas prices were all factors over which the industry had no control.</p>
<p>Dmestic wheat futures and options were a simple and cost-effective means to protect against adverse economic and environmental factors, he said.  </p>
<p>The high level of deliveries in the January contract indicated that those who sold futures at higher prices in early 1996 were happy to realise their hedge benefit by delivering their wheat and receiving prices much higher than today's levels, he said.</p>
<p>Hosking said that more than 6,000 wheat futures contracts, representing 300,000 tonnes of wheat, had traded since the launch of wheat futured in March 1996.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
