<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="329237" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea ruling party attacks opposition in law row.</title>
<headline>S.Korea ruling party attacks opposition in law row.</headline>
<byline>Dean Yates</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's ruling party called the opposition shameless on Thursday for rejecting an offer to reopen parliamentary debate over a controversial labour law that sparked more than three weeks of industrial strife.</p>
<p>&quot;It is really shameless behaviour...for the opposition to demand the nullification of the law, while it could not provide an alternative and has not put forward its own draft,&quot; said a statement from the New Korea Party.</p>
<p>&quot;The opposition should agree to the talks that our party proposed,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Separately, police released a South Korean unionist who had been arrested for obstructing business by helping lead strikes in protest against the law, a prosecution official said.</p>
<p>Four other unionists are still held, he said.</p>
<p>As part of a concession to the opposition, President Kim Young-sam agreed on Tuesday to send the law back to parliament after conceding it caused public anxiety and hurt the economy.</p>
<p>He also ordered authorities to suspend execution of arrest warrants, issued for 20 leaders of the Korean Confederation of Trade Unions for organising strikes in protest against the law, which allows companies to dismiss workers and replace strikers.</p>
<p>But on Wednesday the opposition rejected the offer by Kim, who is president of the ruling party, saying any debate in parliament would be held on condition the law was first dumped.</p>
<p>Kim's sudden reversal followed a decision by the outlawed confederation to call off indefinite work stoppages and limit industrial action to one day each week on Wednesdays.</p>
<p>A Labour Ministry official said on Thursday that factories and businesses across the nation were operating normally.</p>
<p>Political analysts said the tussle over the law would likely develop into a battle for public opinion.</p>
<p>The opposition was capitalising on Kim's blunder in a presidential election year of allowing the ruling party to railroad the bill through parliament on December 26 during a dawn session while opposition deputies slept, they said.</p>
<p>They have also said Kim was bowing to public criticism over the forced passage of the law, with many commentators comparing his tactics to those of previous military rulers.</p>
<p>The prosecution official said Kim Im-shik, a union leader from Hyundai Heavy Industries in the southeast city of Ulsan, was released overnight after requesting a review of the legality of his arrest. He was picked up on Saturday.</p>
<p>The other four detained unionists, all from a shipyard run by Halla Heavy Industries, had not requested a review pending a decision by prosecutors on whether charges relating to their arrest should be dropped.</p>
<p>Prosecutors would soon decide whether to drop outstanding arrest warrants for 15 other leaders of the outlawed confederation, the official added.</p>
<p>The ruling party statement said the president's concession to reopen debate on the law removed grounds for any opposition or union resistance.</p>
<p>It also said the confederation should not use Myongdong Cathedral as its protest headquarters since arrest warrants had been suspended and police had withdrawn from the area.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, police allowed confederation boss Kwon Young-kil to lead a protest march through Seoul streets after he left the church where he has been sheltering from arrest. Kwon later returned to the cathedral, located in central Seoul.</p>
<p>President Kim, who says the law would free up the labour market and trim company costs as well as boost competitiveness, said dumping the legislation would go against the constitution.</p>
<p>Until his stunning about-face, he had refused even to meet opposition leaders to discuss the law.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
