<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="329308" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks close moderately lower.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks close moderately lower.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks closed moderately lower on Thursday in cautious trading, pulled down by profit-taking in the market leaders particularly property stocks, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is hard for the market to make headway with the U.S. long bond yield at current levels,&quot; said Chris Geiger, associate director of Vickers Ballas. &quot;But the lower volume is a good sign and confirms we are just in a trading range.&quot;</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index closed 82.46 points lower at 13,610.33, slightly above the day's low of 13,591.35. Turnover was HK$8.28 billion, well off Wednesday's HK$11.16 billion.</p>
<p>The U.S. 30-year Treasury closed Wednesday trading in New York off 19/32 at 95-24/32 to yield 6.83 compared with 6.79 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Chartists said the 6.90 percent level is the danger zone, indicating a possibility of higher U.S. and Hong Kong interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw quite a bit of switching, out of properties, and into laggards like Hongkong Electric,&quot; said one local broker.</p>
<p>Hongkong Electric closed the day unchanged at HK$27.00.</p>
<p>Brokers said there was some concern that direct Sino-Taiwan shipping links would have a negative impact on the territory's economy, but the magnitude would not be great.</p>
<p>Properties led the market down, followed by the utilities. Only the finance sector managed a positive performance.</p>
<p>New World Development lost HK$1.15 to HK$49.60 and Henderson Land slipped HK$1.00 to HK$72.25.</p>
<p>In the utility sector, Hongkong Telecom lost HK$0.20 to HK$13.25 and HK &amp; China Gas slipped HK$0.15 to HK$14.60.</p>
<p>Infrstructure plays were active. New World Infrastructure gained HK$0.25 to HK$22.45, while Cheung Kong Infrastructure was unchanged at HK$22.40.</p>
<p>&quot;Infrastructure plays with high quality earnings and good growth potential may come to replace utilities in Hong Kong/China portfolios,&quot; said Vickers' Geiger.</p>
<p>In the finance sector, HSBC made a late advance of HK$1.50 to end the day at HK$180.00, while Hang Seng Bank led the loss leaders with a fall of HK$1.75 to HK$91.50.</p>
<p>CITIC Pacific dropped HK$1.00 to HK$38.20 on heavy volume of HK$552.72 million. Brokers said the share was likely to continue to be weak, due to the large discount to market of the 15.47 percent stake offered to management at HK$33.00 per share.</p>
<p>H share sector market leaders suffered heavy profit taking.</p>
<p>Guangdong Kelon plunged HK$0.20 to HK$5.75 and Tsingtao Brewery slid HK$0.15 to HK$3.10.</p>
<p>Red chip China Pharmaceutical put on HK$0.04 to HK$1.15.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
