<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="329327" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Prudential sets sights on Vietnam market.</title>
<headline>Prudential sets sights on Vietnam market.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Prudential Corp Plc on Thursday said it was keen to enter Vietnam's nascent life insurance market, which is being gradually opened up.</p>
<p>&quot;Our commitment is firm,&quot; Lord David Gillmore, director of Prudential's board, told a news conference on the launch later this year of the Prudential Invest Direct Asia Fund (PIDA).</p>
<p>&quot;We hope to be able to operate in the life insurance system in Vietnam. We are encouraged by and greatly welcome recent government statements on the opening and liberalisation of the insurance market in Vietnam.&quot;</p>
<p>Vietnam's first life insurance company, an arm of the state-owned market leader Bao Viet, started operations five months ago. It has so far taken in less than $100,000 in premiums for its limited range of products.</p>
<p>Some two dozen foreign insurers now have representative offices in Vietnam.</p>
<p>But only one joint venture with foreign partners has been licensed, and foreign firms are not allowed to conduct insurance business on their own in Vietnam.</p>
<p>Prudential, which said it backed the government's approach of gradually opening up its market, became the first British insurer to open an office in Hanoi in 1984. It plans to open another office, in Ho Chi Minh City, on Saturday.</p>
<p>Copmany officials also pointed to the PIDA Fund as a sign of Prudential's interest in Asia's emerging markets.</p>
<p>The PIDA Fund will be launched this year. Its assets, initially $150 million, are expected to grow to $1 billion.</p>
<p>Eric Sandlund, managing director of Prudential Portfolio Managers Asia, said no sectors had been ruled out for investment.</p>
<p>&quot;We're in the development capital business. That could lead us from bridges to breweries,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the fund's primary approach would be to invest as equity partners, although debt investments were also possible.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
