<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="329436" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: RESEARCH ALERT - Telekom Malaysia a buy.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - Telekom Malaysia a buy.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Telekom Malaysia Bhd was rated a buy in a report released on Thursday by Hong Kong-based Asia Equity Research Ltd.</p>
<p>Telekom's stock has dropped by about 12 percent since the beginning of the year to a low of 20.20 ringgit. The stock was trading at 20.60 ringgit at midday on Thursday.</p>
<p>Asia Equity said it believed the adverse performance was due to the U.S. Federal Communications Commission's (FCC) proposal for lower settlement rates with international telecommunications companies, and alleged discrepancies in awarding a supply contract to Sweden's Ericsson.  </p>
<p>&quot;Whilst negative sentiment may suppress the price further, we see this as a good opportunity to accumulate the stock,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Asia Equity said that while the FCC's proposal would have a tremendous impact on most Asian telecom companies, Telekom would only be minimally affected. That's because its U.S. incoming and outgoing calls ratio was almost balanced. In comparison, Hong Kong and Philippine companies have sharp imbalances in incoming versus outgoing traffic with the United States at the ratio of 7:1 and 9:1 respectively, it said.</p>
<p>Asia Equity estimated that about 12 percent of Telekom's call revenue, or eight percent of total revenue, is derived from international in-payments, of which 20-25 percent are calls originated from the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;As such, we do expect significant impact to Telekom's profitability should the new FCC ruling be approved,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Asia Equity said it also believed the alleged discrepancies in the awarding of a contract to Ericsson were targeted at individuals linked to the deal, adding that it did not expect Telekom to fork out compensation.  </p>
<p>On competition, Asia Equity said that with an established customer base of 3.8 million, Telekom's market dominance would not be affected.</p>
<p>&quot;Though newcomers offer attractive 10-25 percent discounts on tariffs, take-up rates have been slow due to high infrastructure costs,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The brokerage estimated Telekom's market share would decline gradually from a virtual monopoly to about 80-85 percent over the next five years.</p>
<p>To counteract the growing competitive environment, Telekom would control costs more stringently to boost margins, it said.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
