<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="329446" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Fujimori says use of force possible to end crisis.</title>
<headline>Fujimori says use of force possible to end crisis.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peruvian President Alberto Fujimori has said he would not rule out the possibility of using force to end the Lima hostage crisis, Japan's Kyodo news agency reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;If some hostages are killed or injured, we might choose a different option,&quot; Kyodo quoted Fujimori as saying in an interview with Japanese reporters.</p>
<p>Marxist rebels stormed the Japanese ambassador's residence in Lima on December 17, taking more than 500 hostages and demanding the release of some 400 imprisoned comrades.</p>
<p>Although the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels have released most hostages, they still hold 73 captives and negotiations for their freedom have stalled.</p>
<p>Fujimori told the Japanese reporters on Wednesday that he would not accept the rebels' main demand of freedom for the jailed comrades, Kyodo said.</p>
<p>&quot;A release of jailed MRTA members will pose a threat not only to Peru but also to foreign countries,&quot; Fujimori said.</p>
<p>Fujimori said he would not agree to the rebels' demand that the Peruvian government pay them &quot;war taxes&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We won't pay a penny,&quot; he was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Putting aside the issue of the release of the jailed MRTA rebels, Fujimori said his government was ready to discuss a variety of other issues in a &quot;flexible&quot; manner in face-to-face talks with the rebels.</p>
<p>Fujimori said his government was considering having parliament enact a special law to ensure the safe passage to a third country of the rebels, including their leader Nestor Cerpa Cartolini, holed up in the ambassador's residence.</p>
<p>Fujimori refused to say in which country the rebels could seek asylum, Kyodo said. But he added: &quot;There are family members of Cerpa in France and Mexico.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
