<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="329545" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwaiti MPs want all laws to stem from Islam.</title>
<headline>Kuwaiti MPs want all laws to stem from Islam.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most of Kuwait's elected deputies have proposed making Islam the sole source of law in the Moslem Gulf state, newspapers reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>Thirty-five members of parliament's 50 elected deputies, including speaker Ahmad al-Saadoun, have signed a motion advocating changing the constitution to make Islam the sole source of law, newspapers said.</p>
<p>Article two of the constitution says Islam is &quot;a main&quot; -- thus not the only -- source of legislation. Any constitutional change is subject to the approval of the emir Sheikh Jaber al-Ahmad al-Sabah.</p>
<p>A similar proposal by 39 deputies was rejected in 1994.</p>
<p>The government has said it supports the introduction of Islamic law but it sees that a constitutional change is unnecessary.</p>
<p>A committee of academics and officials apointed by the emir has been studying ways to make laws in full compliance with Islam since shortly after the 1991 Gulf War. It has yet to issue recommendations.</p>
<p>Kuwait's law is based on a variety of legal traditions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
