<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="329642" id="root" date="1997-01-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Finnish foreign currency borrowing on hold - fin min.</title>
<headline>Finnish foreign currency borrowing on hold - fin min.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish Finance Minister Sauli Niinisto said on Thursday the state would not repatriate already negotiated foreign currency loans and would not for the time being negotiate new foreign currency loans.</p>
<p>&quot;Those currencies will not be repatriated,&quot; Niinisto told Reuters in an interview, referring to loans recently signed by Finland.</p>
<p>The new non-repatriation policy would apply to a loan with pay date next week, Niinisto said. The pay date on a three-year 150 million sterling bond announced by lead manager Yamaichi on January 7 is January 27. @</p>
<p>&quot;For the time being we will also refrain from any new foreign currency borrowing,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>This is part of a new policy agreed by the finance ministry and the Bank of Finland in response to the sharp appreciation of the Finnish markka against the German mark on Monday, he said.</p>
<p>The markka stopped firming on Monday afternoon after the Bank of Finland said the state would start buying foreign currency needed for debt servicing directly from the markets and no longer via the central bank. @</p>
<p>Niinisto said a major motive behind a finance ministry decision last autumn for the state to borrow more in foreign currencies in 1997 than in 1996 and 1995 had been the need to boost the central bank's foreign currency reserves.</p>
<p>&quot;Now this need has disappeared,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he declined to say if this signalled that the state would now focus more on borrowing in markka. @</p>
<p>Including amortisation and debt servicing, state gross borrowing will be around 190 billion markka this year, up from 167 billion in 1996.</p>
<p>The state's net borrowing requirement is forecast at slightly over 28 billion markka this year. It was 34 billion markka in 1996.</p>
<p>Niinisto said the markka could be considered a stable currency despite its recent sharp appreciation.</p>
<p>&quot;In a slightly longer perspective this move is only a slight blip on a stable curve,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Peter Starck, Helsinki Newsroom  +358 - 9 - 680 50 245</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
