<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="329790" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: CRICKET-NZ OFF TO STRONG START VS ENGLAND AT LUNCH.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-NZ OFF TO STRONG START VS ENGLAND AT LUNCH.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand were off to a strong start against England on the first day day of the first test on Friday after being put into bat by the tourists.</p>
<p>On a pitch which promised assistance for the England seam bowlers, openers Bryan Young and Blair Pocock got through to 37 and 25 respectively by the break.</p>
<p>They were helped by some wayward bowling from England's fast-medium quartet, who were guilty of wasting the encouraging pitch conditions.</p>
<p>Only occasionally were the batsmen drawn into a false stroke and with England captain Mike Atherton setting attacking fields, there were some easy runs on offer once the ball beat the inner field.</p>
<p>Left armer Alan Mullally had one strong leg before wicket appeal against Pocock turned down in the second over of the day.</p>
<p>Young had a close shave when he got an inside edge to a ball from fast-medium Darren Gough and it flew past the wickets to the fine leg fence.</p>
<p>The closest England came to a wicket was three minutes before the lunch break when Pocock would have been run out by metres had a throw from Craig White at point hit the wickets.</p>
<p>Pocock, playing his first test since facing England at Lord's in 1994, was called through for a short single and White moved quickly to gather and throw.</p>
<p>The 50 partnership came up in 117 balls and at lunch New Zealand were on track for their first century opening stand in a test since last January, when Craig Spearman and Roger Twose put on 214 on the same ground against Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>The pick of a poor England attack was fast-medium Dominic Cork, but it was a session the tourists would want to forget.</p>
<p>The added worry for England was wicketkeeper Alec Stewart, who required attention after injuring a finger in his left hand early in the session.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
