<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="329813" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: SOCCER-BANNED DE BILDE WANTS TO LEAVE ANDERLECHT.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-BANNED DE BILDE WANTS TO LEAVE ANDERLECHT.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgium striker Gilles De Bilde, banned from playing until March 31 for punching another player in the face, is determined to leave his club Anderlecht, his coach said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Gilles wants to leave. He realises that he has to start all over again but that that is impossible in Belgium. Mentally he is also perhaps too weak to (start again in Belgium),&quot; Anderlecht coach Johan Boskamp told Het Nieuwsblad newspaper.</p>
<p>Chairman Roger Vanden Stock said Anderlecht would decide next week whether to keep De Bilde after his suspension.</p>
<p>De Bilde cannot move abroad for now as FIFA, the game's world governing body, has made it clear that a player cannot be transferred to a foreign club while serving a ban.</p>
<p>De Bilde, who became a national celebrity when he won the 1994 award for best Belgian league player, was charged with assault and grievous bodily harm after striking Aalst's Krist Porte in a match on December 21.</p>
<p>Porte suffered a broken eye socket and nose.</p>
<p>Belgian media have said that Dutch clubs PSV Eindhoven and Feyenoord are keen to sign De Bilde.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
