<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="329939" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Ldn Freight - Easier Panamaxes, few grains fixture.</title>
<headline>Ldn Freight - Easier Panamaxes, few grains fixture.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Baltic Freight Index fell 15 points on Friday to 1,407 on weakened Panamax rates.</p>
<p>Capers were steadier but may see some erosion as the weakness on Panamaxes saps Caper demand, brokers reported.</p>
<p>New fixtures mainly involved timecharter business which included Western Trader 70,327 dwt taken by Navix delivery Japan early Feb for Cape Flattery round at $10,850 daily and Royal Ocean 70,677 delivery Japan early Feb New South Wales round $10,800.</p>
<p>K Prime 136,211 dwt delivery Kaohsiung mid Feb trip Queensland redelivery Japan reported Thursday at $15,000 daily is now reported at $14,550/$14,650 daily.</p>
<p>Truckers demanding &quot;standby&quot; payments for time lost during a nine-day dockworkers' strike in Colombia's main Pacific Coast port prevented work there from returning to normal Friday, authorities said.</p>
<p>Buenaventura dockworkers returned to work Friday morning, a day after winning a deal with shipowners and cargo handling operators that should more than double their wages and provide a host of job-related benefits, union officials said.</p>
<p>But about 100 truck drivers, caught up in the strike since last week, were refusing to allow their cargo to be unloaded until they received additional payment for time lost while the port was paralyzed.</p>
<p>The U.S. Navy has intercepted a ship suspected of trying to carry computers, vehicle parts and tyres to Iraq in violation of U.N. sanctions, a navy spokesman in the Gulf said on Friday.</p>
<p>Minerals fixtures included Equinox 108,000 tonnes coal Hampton Roads/Dunkirk East 15-25/2 $7.40 fio three days shinc/25,000 shinc for Capeklav.</p>
<p>Simeon CH was fixed for 55,000 tonnes Roberts Bank/Hansaport mid Feb $11.50 fio 25,000 shinc/25,000 shinc to Frapaco.</p>
<p>Ore fixtures included Tien Shan 120,000 tonnes Tuburao/Kaohsiung Mar $10.70 fio 40,000 shinc/38,000 shinc to CSC.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
