<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="330056" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbian SPS and opposition strike deal over TV. [CORRECTED 18:33 GMT]</title>
<headline>Serbian SPS and opposition strike deal over TV. [CORRECTED 18:33 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Jovan Kovacic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbian Socialist hardliners and opposition leaders from a provincial city where political violence has flared struck a compromise deal on Friday over the control of local media to avert more bloody clashes there.</p>
<p>But minutes later, the ruling Socialist Party (SPS) led by President Slobodan Milosevic slammed the opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition for &quot;destabilising&quot; the country under foreign patronage.</p>
<p>In the industrial city of Kragujevac, south of Belgrade, opposition officials who took control of the city in municipal elections last November said they had negotiated a temporary accord with the SPS after it refused to give up control of the media.</p>
<p>&quot;We achieved a compromise at our meeting today, all with the aim of easing tension and the situation in Kragujevac,&quot; Aca Radosavljevic, an opposition spokesman in the city of 200,000, told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>He said that under the agreement, valid until the country's courts deliver a final ruling, Radio Kragujevac would broadcast only commercial and entertainment programmes.</p>
<p>The Socialists, faced with the loss of control over the local media, moved to integrate Kragujevac's radio and television stations into the SPS-controlled national Serbian television network (RTS), a move a Belgrade court later ruled as illegal.</p>
<p>RTS appealed to a higher court and sent some 200 police into the buildings to prevent the opposition taking over, prompting thousands of Zajedno supporters to surround the station and block roads into Kragujevac on Thursday.</p>
<p>The police left the buildings shortly after the deal was negotiated, local officials said. (Corrects to add dropped para.)</p>
<p>The dispute led to one of the few violent incidents in more than two months of anti-government demonstrations across Serbia when riot police clubbed protesters seated on a highway into Kragujevac, beating one member of parliament unconscious.</p>
<p>Thursday's clashes in Kragujevac and several other towns, including a scuffle in Belgrade, marked an upsurge in violence in almost 10 weeks of protests to force the SPS to concede losses in municipal elections in 14 Serbian cities.</p>
<p>Vuk Draskovic, a Zajedno co-leader, told some 30,000 supporters at a rally in centre of Belgrade on Friday that another three opposition deputies were beaten and arrested in Cacak, Kraljevo and Krusevac.</p>
<p>Despite pressure from the West and threats by the United States to impose fresh sanctions, the SPS has not budged.</p>
<p>In a hardline statement, the SPS Board accused Zajedno of waging a terror campaign under foreign tutelage, although the opposition coalition has adhered strictly to non-violence.</p>
<p>&quot;Zajedno is receiving support from those international circles whose aim has always been to break up and destabilise Serbia and Yugoslavia,&quot; the board said.</p>
<p>The protesters, into their 68th day of demonstrations across Serbia, showed no signs of giving up and students were entering their sixth day of non-stop stand-off with the police.</p>
<p>&quot;We have returned the ideals of democracy to Serbia and again become a people who believe in something. This is our investment in our accelerated reintegration into the world,&quot; Zajedno co-leader Zoran Djindjic told the Belgrade rally.</p>
<p>&quot;In order to secure our future, we must change the entire system which is founded on lies and corruption,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Calling for restraint and perseverance, Draskovic told his supporters the &quot;regime must fall -- it is crumbling slowly, but we must keep up our efforts to complete the process.</p>
<p>&quot;If we miss this chance, God help us all.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
