<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="330019" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Banking stocks boost volume at Mauritius bourse.</title>
<headline>Banking stocks boost volume at Mauritius bourse.</headline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Market index Semdex at the Stock Exchange of Mauritius gained 2.24 points to 367.97 on Friday in a trade dominated by banking sector shares, bourse officials said.</p>
<p>Transactions jumped to 35.30 million rupees on 1,595,421 shares from 8.72 million rupees on 471,110 shares on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Officials said one outstanding feature was active trading in Mauritius Commercial Bank (MCB) and State Bank of Mauritius. MCB rose by one rupee to 83.50 on 147,178 shares while State Bank was unchanged at 11 rupees on a hefty 1,050,300 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;The banks' shares have traditionally led the market especially when the Semdex has been in an upward run. Let's hope that this is announcing something positive for the future of the market,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Shares of the leading hotel groups also rose in active volume, still on forecasts that tourist arrivals in the Indian Ocean island would exceed 500,000 in 1997, up from 480,000 in 1996.</p>
<p>Sun Resorts added 50 cents to 40.10 rupees on 112,176 shares and New Mauritius Hotels gained 20 cents to 32.50 rupees on 56,060 shares.</p>
<p>New Mauritius Hotels on Wednesday reported a 44.2 percent rise in pre-tax profit to 231.1 million rupees ($11.5 million) for the financial year ending 30 September 1996 from 160.3 million rupees in the previous year.</p>
<p>The strong performance of the banks and hotel stocks somewhat overshadowed the entry of a second series of 6-year secured bonds by Finlease, brokers said.</p>
<p>The leasing firm rose 125 million rupees through a public offer in December in which it sold the 10.5 percent coupon bonds. The Finlease bonds, which were introduced on the official list at 1,000 rupees, closed Friday at 1,010 rupees on 500 units traded.</p>
<p>Shares in the rest of the market were mixed in moderate volume, brokers said.</p>
<p>Rogers was down 50 cents to 96 rupees on 10,000 shares still on concerns after the conglomerate reported in January profit before tax for the financial year ending 30 September 1996 eased by 1.14 percent to 423.7 million rupees on account of &quot;difficult conditions&quot; in the commercial, engineering and shipping sectors.</p>
<p>But the other listed conglomerate Ireland Blyth held steady on Friday at 14.50 rupees on 10,010 shares.</p>
<p>--Port Louis ++230 211-9555.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
