<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="330059" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania pyramid protesters block southern town.</title>
<headline>Albania pyramid protesters block southern town.</headline>
<byline>Leon Cika</byline>
<dateline>LUSHNJE, Albania 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanian protesters blockaded the southern city of Lushnje on Friday, occupying a main road and burning a police truck in anger at the right-wing government over their losses in failing pyramid schemes.</p>
<p>Albanian state-run television said around 5,000 residents of Lushnje, 85 km (55 miles) southwest of Tirana, gathered to demand the return of their money from pyramid schemes, whose assets were frozen by the state last week.</p>
<p>They hurled stones at the city hall and pelted riot police sent in to disperse them. Some protesters set up a blockade on the main artery linking southern Albania with the capital and set fire to a police vehicle, state television said.</p>
<p>&quot;Inside the town it is calm now but the main road is blocked with people and damaged cars. Cars cannot pass without the people's permission,&quot; an eyewitness said.</p>
<p>&quot;The police are completely paralysed,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>At an urgent meeting President Sali Berisha ordered the setting up of a commission to look into ways of reimbursing pyramid scheme investors.</p>
<p>On Thursday, the right-wing government banned the controversial schemes in a bid to quell popular unrest. It also warned operators they could face up to 20 years in jail.</p>
<p>The authorities have seized around 25.5 billion leks ($255 million) deposited with banks by two bankrupt schemes but the money may not be sufficient to satisfy thousands of Albanians who have poured their life savings into the companies.</p>
<p>&quot;All the frozen money plus the bank interest will be returned to the investors,&quot; television quoted Berisha as saying.</p>
<p>The Lushnje protest was the latest incident in two weeks of popular unrest directed against the crumbling pyramid schemes.</p>
<p>&quot;All Lushnje has put its money into the Xhaferri and Gjallica (investment schemes). We refuse to stand by while they gobble up our money,&quot; one woman told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not leave this place until we get our money back,&quot; a young man said.</p>
<p>Mario Kempes, the Argentine coach of the Lushnje soccer team, was led away by friends from the scene of the protest. The club is owned by the Xhaferri family, which operates one of the controversial schemes.</p>
<p>Albania's official ATA news agency said Lushnje town hall suffered broken windows and riot police sent to end the disturbance came under a hail of stones.</p>
<p>&quot;For 45 minutes riot police sheltered behind their trucks while the crowd hurled stones and other objects,&quot; ATA said.</p>
<p>Residents said some police officers removed their caps as a sign of solidarity with the crowd.</p>
<p>Police intervened to disperse the crowd, but succeeded only in driving some protesters onto Albania's main north-south artery, where they brought traffic to a standstill and attacked government vehicles.</p>
<p>Four trucks full of riot police, sent to break up the road block, failed and protesters set fire to one of the trucks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSHNJE, Albania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
