<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="330075" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Krasnoyarsk 97 aluminium exports to fall.</title>
<headline>Krasnoyarsk 97 aluminium exports to fall.</headline>
<dateline>1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Primary aluminium output at Russia's Krasnoyarsk smelter may rise 10,000 tonnes in 1997 on last year's 777,000 tonnes, but exports may fall 40,000-90,000 tonnes, Krasnoyarsk's board chairman said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Output will be no less than last year's level and may rise by 10,000 tonnes,&quot; Gennady Druzhinin told Reuters in a telephone interview from Krasnoyarsk. &quot;But we plan to sell 150,000 tonnes, maybe even 200,000 tonnes, on the domestic market this year, compared to 100,000 tonnes in 1996.&quot;  </p>
<p>Druzhinin said the plant, Russia's second largest, would produce 450,000 tonnes of metal under tolling operations this year, down slightly from 460,000 tonnes in 1996.</p>
<p>All metal not produced under tolling and not sold on the domestic market last year was exported, he said. He declined to give single absolute figures.</p>
<p>&quot;I would be very happy if all of our output went to Russian users,&quot; he said. &quot;Unfortunately, the market is not yet there.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Kranosyarsk wanted to sell to SAMECO, Russia's biggest aluminium processor.</p>
<p>&quot;There's sense in working with SAMECO,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Samara Metallurgical Company (SAMECO) said on Thursday that it planned to boost 1997 rolled aluminium output to 134,700 tonnes from 76,900 tonnes in 1996, after a 50.8 percent drop in last year's output on 1995 levels.  </p>
<p>He said Krasnoyarsk was completing purchases of alumina, the raw material used to make aluminium, for 1997, but that the smelter had bought nothing from Ukraine's Nikolayevsky plant because it was asking prices above world levels.</p>
<p>&quot;We've basically covered our supplies,&quot; he said, adding that Krasnoyarsk shareholders had helped out for tolling operations.</p>
<p>Krasnoyarsk shareholder London-based Trans-World Metals at one point was crossed off the plant's registry, and officials have declined to say whether this question has been resolved.</p>
<p>Krasnoyarsk's annual capacity is 760,000 tonnes but may grow to 800,000 tonnes once modernisation works are carried out.</p>
<p>The plant is as nearly as big as Russia's Bratsk, the world's largest primary aluminium smelter.</p>
<p>--Lynnley Browning, Moscow Newsroom +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
