<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="330173" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Chronology of Serbian anti-government protests.</title>
<headline>Chronology of Serbian anti-government protests.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Street protests by Serbia's opposition against alleged municipal election fraud by the government entered their 68th day on Friday after bloody clashes in Kragujevac over control of a television station.</p>
<p>Here is a chronology of related events:</p>
<p>Nov 3 - President Slobodan Milosevic's leftist coalition, led by his ruling Socialist Party, wins majority in Yugoslav parliament in federal elections. In parallel local elections, run-off polling was required in most municipalities in Serbia.</p>
<p>Nov 17 - Second round of voting held in those municipalities where no candidate managed to obtain a majority.</p>
<p>Nov 18 - Zajedno (Together) opposition coalition claims victory in 14 of Serbia's biggest cities including Belgrade, citing evidence from representatives on electoral commissions.</p>
<p>Ruling Socialists claim victory in 134 of 189 councils. List does not include major towns the opposition says it won.</p>
<p>Demonstrations begin in southern town of Nis where supporters suspect authorities will cancel Zajedno victory.</p>
<p>Nov 19 - Opposition holds another rally and Belgrade electoral commission confirms Zajedno victory in the capital.</p>
<p>Authorities, citing irregularities reported by Socialist Party, begin to annul results in Nis and several other towns.</p>
<p>Nov 21 - Some 20,000 people march in Belgrade. Zajedno leaders vow daily protests until election victory recognised. Socialists accuse Zajedno of &quot;prematurely&quot; declaring victory and accuse its leadership of inciting violence.</p>
<p>Nov 24 - Belgrade municipal court annuls opposition victory in city council.</p>
<p>Nov 25 - University students launch strike in Belgrade faculties. Some 100,000 opposition supporters attend Belgrade demonstration, the biggest yet.</p>
<p>Nov 26 - Supreme Court rejects appeal from opposition lawyers on annulment of poll results.</p>
<p>Nov 27 - Vuk Draskovic, a leader of Zajedno coalition, calls for Milosevic's resignation at demonstration.</p>
<p>Nov 28 - Socialists say they secured majority in Belgrade assembly after third round of voting which Zajedno boycotted.</p>
<p>Dec 3 - Authorities switch off transmitter broadcasting independent Radio B-92 and student-run Radio Index. Washington says &quot;outer wall&quot; of sanctions against Belgrade will remain in place until Serbia shows respect for democracy.</p>
<p>Dec 4 - Serbia, in meeting between Yugoslav Foreign Minister Milan Milutinovic and Deputy Secretary of State Strobe Talbott, promises U.S. it will not use force to stop protests</p>
<p>Dec 5 - Belgrade rally draws 150,000; B-92 back on air.</p>
<p>Dec 6 - European Union condemns annulment of elections and refuses to grant preferential trade terms to Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>Dec 7 - U.S. State Department demands Serbian government open dialogue with opposition; Serbian Supreme Court dismisses opposition complaints on disputed electoral districts.</p>
<p>Dec 8 - Belgrade electoral commission awards poll victory in the capital to the Socialists and their allies.</p>
<p>Dec 10 - Serbian opposition parties boycott Yugoslav federal parliament, vow to stay away until Milosevic backs down. Federal supreme court rejects Zajedno appeal.</p>
<p>Dec 11 - Independent trade unions join opposition protests. European parliament condemns Serbian authorities over polls.</p>
<p>Dec 13 - Milosevic invites Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) delegation to assess the fairness of the elections. Some 200,000 rally in Belgrade.</p>
<p>Dec 17 - Milosevic meets student delegation, vows not to bow to foreign interference.</p>
<p>Dec 20 - OSCE delegation led by former Spanish prime minister Felipe Gonzalez arrives in Belgrade.</p>
<p>Dec 24 - Rival government, opposition rallies in Belgrade lead to street battles in which one man is shot in the head.</p>
<p>Dec 26 - Serbian interior ministry ban rallies which block traffic. Riot police force demonstrators off the streets.</p>
<p>Dec 27 - OSCE's Gonzalez backs opposition claims to 22 disputed municipalities. Demonstrators clash with riot police.</p>
<p>Dec 31 - At least 250,000 people hold New Year rally, blowing whistles and ringing alarm clocks. Milosevic address promises market reforms but makes no mention of protests.</p>
<p>Jan 1 - Student marchers bang pots, pans and drums and blow whistles to drown out state television news.</p>
<p>Jan 3 - Serbian authorities admit opposition won some disputed municipal elections but make no mention of Belgrade city assembly and say results unclear in other key cities. Concession fails to satisfy opposition or OSCE.</p>
<p>Jan 5 - Demonstrators paralyse Belgrade with slow-moving car parade which gets round ban on street marches.</p>
<p>Jan 6 - Orthodox Christmas festivities bring biggest crowd onto streets. Bomb at leftist party building raises tension.</p>
<p>Jan 7 - Students mount charm campaign to win police support. Army and church leaders have already implied support for the opposition, undermining Milosevic.</p>
<p>Jan 8 - Opposition coalition win in second city of Nis conceded by ruling Socialists.</p>
<p>Jan 9 - Students confront police barricades until security forces back down and remove cordons blocking streets. Belgraders celebrate their success with impromptu street party.</p>
<p>Jan 11 - Two Serbian deputy prime ministers accept opposition victories in 14 of Serbia's largest towns. But the words fail to translate into action by the divided Socialists.</p>
<p>Jan 13 - Opposition calls on army and police to resist calls by government hardliners to crush street protests.</p>
<p>Jan 14 - Half a million people jam central Belgrade on Orthodox New Year's Eve for the biggest anti-government protest yet staged.</p>
<p>Jan 16 - OSCE chairman Helveg Petersen, the Danish foreign minister, says Socialists must recognise the election results and stop making &quot;piecemeal&quot; concessions to the opposition.</p>
<p>Jan 17 - Vuk Draskovic, on visit to Rome with other leaders of the Zajedno coalition, says he does not think Western pressure so far has been very effective.</p>
<p>Jan 18 - Riot police withdraw from central Belgrade after all-night standoff with students, letting them march. Later in the day thousands of Zajedno supporters wear uniforms to rally.</p>
<p>Jan 19 - Opposition holds &quot;bark for democracy&quot; demonstration, with pet-owners bringing hundreds of dogs to rally.</p>
<p>Jan 20 - Serbian courts deal opposition a double blow, suspending a ruling that Socialists had lost in Belgrade and handing them victory in another disputed town.</p>
<p>Jan 21 - Serbian government says Justice Ministry found no fraud in a number of disputed elections; U.S. State Department says Socialists are &quot;tying up&quot; elections in a legal quagmire.</p>
<p>Jan 23 - Riot police club demonstrators in city of Kragujevac demanding Socialists relinquish control of regional television station; opposition member of federal parliament beaten unconscious in bloodiest confrontation in two months of protests.</p>
<p>Jan 24 - Opposition official in Kragujevac says compromise deal reached over control of the television station.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
