<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="330190" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>LITHUANIA: Nomura to give ideas on Lithuania telecoms sale.</title>
<headline>Nomura to give ideas on Lithuania telecoms sale.</headline>
<dateline>VILNIUS 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>International investment house Nomura has said it wants to help the Baltic state of Lithuania privatise its state-owned telecommunications firm Lietuvos Telekomas, the communications minister said on Friday.</p>
<p>Communications Minister Rimantas Pleikys told Reuters that Nomura is to draw up a privatisation strategy for the telecommunications company, whose assets are estimated to be worth some 1.5 billion litas.</p>
<p>&quot;Nomura will submit suggestions expressing their opinion on how some of the communications companies could be privatised, including Lietuvos Telekomas,&quot; Pleikys said after he met a Nomura delegation, on a visit to Lithuania.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not decided who will prepare the privatisation and who will implement it. Investment partners will be chosen through international tenders. One of the potential partners is Nomura,&quot; Pleikys added.</p>
<p>The sale of the telecommunications company is one of the pledges that the new right-wing government of Prime Minister Gediminas Vagnorius made when it came to office.</p>
<p>It has said that it wants generally to speed up privatisation and the sale of a stake in the national airline has also been mentioned.</p>
<p>The head of Lietuvos Telekomas was due to meet Nomura later on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom, +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VILNIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LITHUANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
