<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="330180" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: U.S. tells Ukraine &quot;do more to attract investment&quot;.</title>
<headline>U.S. tells Ukraine &quot;do more to attract investment&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukraine should be working harder to attract money from private United States investors, the U.S. ambassador to the former Soviet republic said at the start of bilateral trade talks on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;U.S. investment is very small, far smaller than it should be,&quot; William Miller told the Ukrainian side, headed by Foreign Economic Relations Minister Serhiy Osyka. &quot;It should be considerably more.&quot;</p>
<p>Ukraine, the third largest recipient of U.S. aid after Israel and Egypt, has attracted about $1.2 billion in foreign investment since achieving independence from the Soviet Union in 1991. The United States is Ukraine's largest foreign investor.</p>
<p>Before the official meeting, U.S. business people complained of the slow rate of privatisation, high import tariffs and taxes, corruption, and Ukraine's failure to enforce court decisions won by U.S. firms.</p>
<p>Ukraine's tax system can take up to 110 percent of a company's profits and has been blamed for enlarging a black economy that accounts for up to half of national output.</p>
<p>One businessman whose company is importing cleaning products said import tariffs of 20 percent were forcing it to compete with its own goods smuggled in from Poland.</p>
<p>Miller said Ukraine's success with its macroeconomic reform programme, which has resulted in slowed inflation and a stable currency, should result in increased investment.</p>
<p>U.S. officials told Ukraine late last year to iron out corruption if it hoped to bring in more foreign investment.</p>
<p>--Irene Marushko, Kiev Newsroom, +380 44 2292264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
