<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="330247" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru seeks to rattle rebels, irks Red Cross.</title>
<headline>Peru seeks to rattle rebels, irks Red Cross.</headline>
<byline>Martin Langfield</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marxist rebels holding 73 hostages chanted their defiance on Friday as the government sent armoured cars rumbling past the occupied Japanese ambassador's house for the first time since the 38-day-old siege began.</p>
<p>Two armoured personnel carriers with special forces police aiming their rifles at the residence made two passes directly in front of the siege site as a helicopter flew overhead with an armed policeman in a harness riding on its skids.</p>
<p>In response, the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels broadcast a revolutionary song for the second time and chants of &quot;Long Live the Revolution&quot; and &quot;Long Live Freedom&quot; could be heard from inside the residence. The rebels had broadcast the same song earlier as dawn broke.</p>
<p>After the vehicles passed, an unidentifed hostage, looking worried and tired, appeared briefly at a window.</p>
<p>The International Red Cross, which is carrying messages between the two sides as well as providing humanitarian relief to the hostages, suspended its activities at the siege site, saying it should have been informed of the police's plans.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope this suspension will not last long,&quot; Red Cross representative Michel Minnig said before entering talks with police officials. &quot;The hostages are waiting for their food.&quot;</p>
<p>President Alberto Fujimori, speaking to a group of Japanese citizens, condemned the rebels as hypocrites.</p>
<p>&quot;This MRTA group has tried to transmit the message that it is fighting poverty, when the opposite is true,&quot; Fujimori told about 100 Japanese members of the non-governmental &quot;Peace Boat&quot; organisation who arrived in Lima on Friday. The group was visiting Peru as part of an international tour, unrelated to the hostage crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;Something like the Japanese Embassy event ... could happen in Europe, the United States and anywhere in the world,&quot; he added. &quot;Relations between Peru and Japan ... will not be affected by this isolated incident, they will be strengthened.&quot;</p>
<p>The armoured vehicles, each with a heavy machine gun on top, appeared at the siege site on Wednesday but Friday was the first day they crossed police cordons and lines of journalists two blocks from the residence to enter the restricted zone in front of the house.</p>
<p>They also crossed an area, marked out on Thursday by the Red Cross with white paint, which police were supposed to stay out of while the Red Cross was working at the residence.</p>
<p>The new police manoeuvres followed a warning by Fujimori on Thursday that he wanted to wipe out the MRTA after the crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking for the total eradication of the group in the region,&quot; he told reporters during a brief visit to Bolivia. &quot;This government is going to hunt them down.&quot;</p>
<p>Fujimori, whose younger brother Pedro is among the captives, has built much of his popular support on an aggressive fight against the MRTA and the larger and bloodier Maoist Shining Path rebel group. Local analysts say his efforts have reduced the MRTA to less than 250 active members.</p>
<p>The MRTA has responded to the government's latest moves on the Internet, slamming Fujimori as a &quot;dictator&quot; and alleging that security forces were preparing to storm the residence.</p>
<p>The roughly 15 rebels in the house are armed with assault rifles and grenade launchers and have mined and booby-trapped the compound against possible attack.</p>
<p>Though both sides have said they were willing to sit down to discuss a peaceful end to the crisis, Fujimori has ruled out starting talks until the rebels drop their demand for the release of about 400 jailed comrades.</p>
<p>The rebels have said there is no point in talking unless that demand is on the agenda.</p>
<p>The MRTA originally seized hundreds of guests when they stormed a cocktail party at the residence on Dec. 17.</p>
<p>They freed most of them in what they called &quot;goodwill gestures,&quot; keeping those they consider the best bargaining chips including two Peruvian government ministers, generals, security chiefs, about two dozen Japanese businessmen, and diplomats and the ambassadors of Bolivia and Japan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
