<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="330315" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Alfa says'97 outlook good despite cycles.</title>
<headline>Alfa says'97 outlook good despite cycles.</headline>
<byline>Daniel Perez</byline>
<dateline>MONTERREY, Mexico 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican conglomerate Grupo Industrial Alfa S.A. is not fretting about this year despite a cyclical downturn in world markets for two of its main products, petrochemicals and steel, the company's chairman and CEO told reporters.</p>
<p>Alfa managed to sidestep cyclical weakness in products such as Purified Therephatalic Acid (PTA), a material used in plastic bottles, and flat steel in 1996, mostly by boosting sales volumes.  </p>
<p>But analysts have voiced their doubts about Alfa's 1997 prospects, especially if weak prices in petrochemicals and some steel products continue.</p>
<p>For the Monterrey-based company, the solution consists in &quot;keeping companies not subject to such cycles suitably profitable and (also) increasing volume (again),&quot; CEO Dionisio Garza Medina said.</p>
<p>Alfa's non-cyclical firms in 1996, such as food company Sigma Alimentos and autoparts maker Versax, offset a slump in business for petrochemical firm Alpek and steelmakers Hylsamex, Garza said.  </p>
<p>A sign of Alfa's confidence was $700 million in investment earmarked for the group, $520 million of it for Alpek and Hylsamex, he added.</p>
<p>Another tactic to reduce dependency on cyclical companies has been to balance the group's business portfolio.</p>
<p>&quot;The strategey will take time. It will take time for the telecommunications project, Alestra, and Sigma, which balance the portfolio well, to grow,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Alestra is a joint venture between AT&amp;T and VISA- Bancomer, set up to enter the Mexican long-distance telephone market, opened up to competition on Jan 1.</p>
<p>The new company is looking into the market in Personal Communications Systems and wireless telephony, Garza said, adding that Alfa's partners were prepared to invest $1 billion.</p>
<p>Garza saw Alpek and Hylsamex's share of company earnings falling over the next five years, but not significantly, as Alestra and Sigma take time to grow.</p>
<p>The overall idea, Garza said, is to maximize Alfa's company value and eventually list all of its divisions on the stock market. He did not see an IPO this year for Alpek, however.</p>
<p>Alfa did have plans to offer American Depositary Receipts (ADRs) in New York, but assigned a higher priority to listing Alpek and Onexa, the holding company for Alestra.</p>
<p>Another example of possible diversification for Alfa would be through international acquisitions, Garza said. Hylsamex has expressed an interest in the forthcoming privatization of Venezuelan steelmaker Siderurgica del Orinoco. ((--Monterrey bureau +528 345-7617))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTERREY, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
