<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="330376" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - Jan 24.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - Jan 24.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE DOMINION</p>
<p>The government wanted to screen migrants with connections to Asian Triad gangs to prevent them entering New Zealand, Police Minister Jack Elder said on Thursday. Page 1</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Foreign Affairs Minister Don McKinnon remains optimistic New Zealand will be given more information about the route of a nuclear waste shipment between Europe and Japan. The issue arose in talks in Adelaide on Thursday between McKinnon and Australian Foreign Affairs Minister Alexander Downer. McKinnon has expressed opposition to the ship passing through New Zealand's 200-mile exclusive economic zone or through Pacific waters.</p>
<p>Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Youth gangs are spreading to smaller communities and becoming a serious street policing concern, police say. Page 2</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The operation and performance of the Serious Fraud Office was under scrutiny at the Winebox inquiry in Auckland on Thursday. Commision of inquiry counsel Colin Carruthers QC questined the office over its decision not to prosecute in the case of Cook Islands tax transactions involving European Pacific. Cross-examination by Carruthers of fraud office investigator Gib Beattie will resume this morning. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Serious Fraud Office believes both it and the Inland Revenue Department will be cleared of corruption in the Winebox Commission findings, but is saying it may need extra resources to act on recommendations. Briefing papers issued by Attorney-General Paul East on Thursday say it was too early to predict the outcome of the Winebox hearings, but said it was confidently expected there would be no finding of corruption agains the SFO or IRD. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Labour has called for a select committee inquiry into underfunding of the Children, Young Persons and Their Families Service. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The financial transactions tax proposed by the Alliance would hit the minnows and be avoided by the whales, according to an assessment prepared by the Business Roundtable. The tax, levied on bank withdrawals, is advocated by the Alliance as a replacement for Goods and Services Tax. Executive director Roger Kerr said the assessment, issued today, had been prepared before the election but had been held back till after so &quot;that the issues could be examined dispassionately rather than in a political context&quot;. Page 2.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Growth in production-based gross domestic product had continued to fall, Statistics New Zealand said on Thursday. Seasonally-adjusted growth rose 0.6 percent over the September quarter for 2.3 percent total in the year to September. That compared with a 4.3 percent annual increase in the previous 12 months. &quot;Annual growth has been tracking down since the peak of 6.7 percent recorded for the June 1994 year,&quot; government statistician Len Cook said. Economists were expecting weak growth, with a quarterly increase of about 0.2 percent. Page 10.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The New Zealand dollar dropped three-quarters of a cent against the American currency in the wake of a weak Australian dollar and strong selling from Asia. The Kiwi dollar was down 0.77 cents at 0.6980 late yesterday, with the trade-weighted index 21 basis points lower at 68.52. Dealers said sell-offs overnight in the United States could push the Kiwi further down. Page 10.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business confidence lifted slightly in the last quarter of 1996, consolidating the gain made in the previous quarter, the latest Quarterly Survey of Business Confidence shows. Firms expecting an improvement in the next six months now outweigh those expecting a deterioration. A net eight percent surveyed expect business to improve over that period compared with a net one percent expecting a deterioration in the previous survey. Page 10.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Restructuring the Bank of New Zealand's sales and services functions could cost jobs but branch closures were not being considered, a spokesman said yesterday. Between 220 and 250 middle management staff in rural, personal and business banking areas would be affected by the proposed change. &quot;Some new positions will be created, some will be altered and some will be removed,&quot; a bank spokesman said. The bank has sought comment from the staff involved by mid-February. Page 10.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Reserve Bank Governor Don Brash on Thursday reinforced the need for tight monetary policy, avoiding any reference to the high exchange rate and telling an audience in Christchurch that only greater investment in education, technology and efficiency would produce the higher economic growth New Zealanders appeared to want. Dr Brash told the Canterbury Employers' Chamber of Commerce that if the public thought the government's widening of the bank's underlying inflation band -- from zero to two percent to zero to three percent -- meant the bank was going to tolerate and extra one percent of inflation, that would feed into higher wage demands, lower saving and increased borrowing. Page 10.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Analysts' tips this week that Asian carrier Cathay Pacific would soon start a code-sharing service with Air New Zealand were &quot;pure speculation,&quot; Cathay's New Zealand boss, David Figgins, said on Thursday. He said Cathay began code-sharing with Ansett New Zealand 18 months ago on domestic services between Auckland and Christchurch as it has international flights to Hong Kong from both gateways. Page 10.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Manufacturers Federation has continued its fight to get the government to prune expenditure, issuing a study by Bankers Trust on the effect of the enlarged government budget. &quot;Monetary conditions are forecast to be considerably tighter over the March quarter this year becuase of the coalition's increase in expenditure,&quot; Manfed said. &quot;This tightening is equivalent to the trade weighted index being 1.5 percent higher than would otherwise be the case.&quot; Page 10.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>THE NEW ZEALAND HERALD</p>
<p>The government will look at tougher immigration screening to keep people with triad gang connections out of New Zealand and allow deportion of these with proven links. But Asian community leaders on Thursday wondered why only Asian criminals might be targeted. One said he was more concerned his children might be radically abused than attacked by triads. The Minister of Police, Jack Elder, said on Thursday he favoured the tighter immigration and citizenship barriers, although legal and human rights issues would have to be sorted out.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Stubbornly persistent inflationary expectations had left New Zealand with more expensive houses, higher interest rates and a higher dollar than need be, the governor of the Reserve Bank, Dr Don Brash, said on Thursday. Speaking to the Canterbury Chamber of Commerce Brash avoided comment on current monetary conditions. Instead, he lamented the persistence of excessive inflationary expectations, and warned that New Zealanders seemed to have exaggerated expectations of how much growth the economy was capable of.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business confidence picked up late last year but the Institute of Economic Research says its latest quarterly survey of business opinion gives mixed signals about the state of the economy. &quot;The survey hasn't given a clear indication of whether the economy has turned  up or is about to,&quot; institute economist David Cooling said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Two of New Zealand's largest retailers have reported tough trading conditions over the Christmas period. Clothing retailer Hallenstein Glasson said on Thursday that same store sales for December had falled by 4.6 percent compared with a year ago, although group sales, including new stores, lifted by 2.7 percent. Pacific Retail Group, formed last year when Noel Leeming merged with Bond and Bond, said that Christmas had not been quite as strong as it would have liked. It would now struggle to meet its forecast $7 million pre-tax profit for the March 1997 year.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Economic growth was stronger than expected in the September quarter. Real gross domestic product grew 0.6 percent in the three months (making 2.3 percent for the year), while most market expectations had been around 0.2 percent. But the antiquity of the data, and inevitability of revisions, meant the numbers had minimal implications for the financial markets or the Reserve Bank's pregnostications, analysts said.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
