<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="330623" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AOL CEO says he is not considering refunds.</title>
<headline>AOL CEO says he is not considering refunds.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>America Online Inc chairman and CEO Steve Case said in an interview on CNBC that he is not considering customer refunds to compensate irate members, amid a barrage of complaints that users cannot access the service.</p>
<p>On Thursday, AOL's attorneys met with a group of 20 attorneys general from 20 states, to discuss a remedy for the customer complaints that have inundated their offices since AOL initiated unlimited access for $19.95 a month on December 1.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not going to discuss what is on the table with the attorneys general,&quot; Case said. But when asked about refunds to customers, Case said, &quot;It's not something we are considering.&quot;  </p>
<p>Case said that the meeting on Thursday with the attorneys general in Chicago was &quot;constructive,&quot; adding that the attorneys general asked AOL not to talk about the meeting. &quot;Our interests are really in parallel,&quot; Case said.</p>
<p>Earlier Friday, New York Attorney General Dennis Vacco said that he served AOL with a formal notice stating that if negotiations break down with AOL, he will sue the company to halt its allegedly deceptive business practices and to win refunds for frustrated customers.</p>
<p>&quot;Most customers have seen a tremendous price cut, they have doubled their usage,&quot; Case told CNBC.  </p>
<p>Case said that he understands the frustration that users feel when they cannot log onto AOL, saying that he too experiences the same problem when he logs on from home in the evening, using the typical access numbers.</p>
<p>&quot;The reason we went to unlimited pricing is because our customers asked for it,&quot; Case said. &quot;Once they are online, they don't have to worry about the clock ticking. We did say there will be a surge in demand and there will be some busy signals. It will probably take us a few months to build out our capacity. That's our intent and we are doing everything we can to do it as soon as possible,&quot; Case said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
