<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="330777" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton, Bush, Powell push summit of volunteerism.</title>
<headline>Clinton, Bush, Powell push summit of volunteerism.</headline>
<byline>Steve Holland</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton Friday joined two prominent Republicans, former President George Bush and retired Gen. Colin Powell, in announcing an April summit to encourage more Americans to volunteer to help the needy.</p>
<p>It was a show of bipartisanship in the White House East Room with Democrats Clinton, his wife Hillary, Vice President Al Gore and ex-Housing Secretary Henry Cisneros appearing with Bush, who lost to Clinton in 1992, and Powell, often mentioned as a Republican presidential hopeful, to promote &quot;The Presidents' Summit for America's Future.&quot;</p>
<p>It will take place in Philadelphia April 27-29.</p>
<p>&quot;It must be true that the things which unite us as citizens are bigger than any one person, one party, one election or ideology,&quot; Clinton told the gathering of community service advocates and corporate sponsors.</p>
<p>Said Bush: &quot;When it comes to addressing many of the problems we face as a nation, it isn't a question of partisan politics, of one side against another, it's a question of all pulling together for the common good.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton and Bush are to serve as honorary co-chairmen of the summit. Powell will serve as general chairman and Cisneros vice chairman. The White House said former Presidents Gerald Ford, Jimmy Carter and Ronald Reagan have all pledged their active support. Ford has agreed to attend and former first ladies Lady Bird Johnson and Nancy Reagan will participate.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as I know,&quot; Clinton said, &quot;there's not much of a precedent for this sort of thing, at least in recent history.&quot;</p>
<p>The summit is the result of joint efforts by the Corporation for National Service, Clinton's community service programme and Bush's legacy, the Points of Light Foundation. It will be a national summople to help in areas where government funds are absent or insufficient, such as helping children read and caring for the poor.</p>
<p>&quot;Much of the work of America cannot be done by government. Much of the work cannot be done by government alone,&quot; Clinton said. &quot;The solution must be the American people through voluntary service to others.&quot;</p>
<p>Powell, the former chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff who is now involved in charity work and who considered running against Clinton on the Republican ticket last year, described Americans as a &quot;caring and compassionate people ... But we need to do more. We need to do a lot more, because the need is so great.&quot;</p>
<p>It was Bush's fourth trip back to the White House since he left office four years ago. His right foot was in a cast due to a torn tendon from a jog in his hometown of Houston. His daughter, Dorothy Bush Koch, was with him but not wife Barbara Bush, who had a previous engagement.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr. President,&quot; he told Clinton, &quot;I'm very proud to be a part of this and proud to be at your side in this very noble effort.&quot;</p>
<p>Bush's chief of staff Jean Becker said afterward the Points of Light Foundation had originated the idea of a summit last summer. &quot;It kind of started with us and got bigger,&quot; she said. &quot;Very quickly it was decided that it was important to have the sitting president involved.&quot;</p>
<p>The White House announced that some commitments from the private sector have already been made as part of summit preparations. LensCrafters will provide 1 million needy people, especially children, with vision care by 2003 and Columbia/HCA Healthcare Corp. will immunise 1 million children by 2000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
