<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="330726" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: BOJ's comments leave SIMEX Euroyen, JGBs unmoved.</title>
<headline>BOJ's comments leave SIMEX Euroyen, JGBs unmoved.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Japan's (BOJ's) slew of comments on Friday left the SIMEX Euroyen and Japanese Government Bond (JGB) futures largely unscathed.</p>
<p>Short-covering and position-squaring ahead of the weekend dominated the day's activity, dealers said.</p>
<p>The dollar's continued rally against the yen, which saw it briefly hit a 47-month high at 120 yen, was said to have little impact, they added.  </p>
<p>&quot;The markets were not affected much by BOJ's announcements. Players were mainly pre-occupied with short-covering and squaring their positions ahead of the weekend,&quot; said a dealer with a Japanese institution.</p>
<p>Euroyen opened firmer on short-covering following BOJ's announcement on Thursday that it would be postponing the February tankan to early April, triggering speculations that the tankan might be &quot;quite bad&quot;, dealers said.</p>
<p>The lead September Euroyen futures traded within a narrow three-tick range, dealers said as players awaited further information from Tokyo.  </p>
<p>The September Euroyen contract was trading around 99.33 in late trade against its previous IMM close at 99.30.</p>
<p>It was expected to maintain a firm note next week and trade within 99.25-99.36. A break above 99.36 could prompt upside towards 99.40, dealers said.</p>
<p>JGBs rose on BOJ's concerns about the impact of falling Japanese stock prices on corporate sentiment.</p>
<p>March JGBs tested 126.25 but ended at 126.17 on 279 lots. Its near-term support and resistance were seen at 126.10 and 126.40 respectively.  </p>
<p>Eurodollars saw keen local buying in the morning. Activity on the futures only picked up in the afternoon, fuelled by eagerness to short-cover ahead of the weekend. The futures were trapped in narrow range trade after London opened.</p>
<p>September Eurodollars ended unchanged from their IMM close at 93.99 on volume of 11,000 lots.</p>
<p>Dealers said players would keep a close watch on the U.S. fourth quarter Employment Cost Index (ECI), due next Tuesday, for an indication of potential wage pressures.</p>
<p>&quot;People will watch the ECI like a hawk and that will definitely set the tone,&quot; said a trader.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
