<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="331668" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dounreay atomic plant to reprocess foreign waste.</title>
<headline>Dounreay atomic plant to reprocess foreign waste.</headline>
<dateline>INVERNESS, SCOTLAND 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The second reprocessing plant at Scotland's Dounreay has been given the go-ahead to recycle overseas radio-active plutonium and uranium fuel-rods, the plant's operator said on Thursday.</p>
<p>State-owned UK Atomic Energy Authority said it had won a government go-ahead to sign deals with foreign clients which will keep the plant open beyond the year 2,003.</p>
<p>The move by the Department of Trade and Industry to authorise future foreign deals for the 25-year-old plant will help offset more than two billion pounds of decommissioning costs at Dounreay's nuclear facilities.  </p>
<p>The D 1206 facility, that has been shut down since last autumn after a radioactive leak in an associated plant, was originally established to reprocess the nuclear fuel from Doureay's own prototype fast reactor. But that plant was closed in 1994.</p>
<p>With no date yet for fixing the D 1206 plant, it is not expected to be able to take on international reprocessing contracts until the backlog of home-produced materials has been cleared at Dounreay in 2,003.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, anti-nuclear campaigners were furious at the news that the life of the plant would be extended.</p>
<p>&quot;The government would be better advised to support the sustainable developments in the north of Scotland instead of picking up dangerous and dirty scraps off the table of the world's nuclear industry,&quot; said George Baxter from environmental pressure group Friends of the Earth.</p>
<p>-- Bill Mowat, London Newsroom +44 171 542 4017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I15000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1610109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="INVERNESS, SCOTLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
