<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="331757" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: Cyprus bourse chairman explains fall. [CORRECTED 16:52 GMT]</title>
<headline>Cyprus bourse chairman explains fall. [CORRECTED 16:52 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A price correction is one reason why shares on the Cyprus stock exchange have tumbled 22 percent since the bourse opened, its chairman said on Friday.</p>
<p>Prices on the 41-share bourse dropped to their lowest level in its 10-month history on Wednesday, closing at 77.45 points.</p>
<p>The bourse recovered somewhat on Friday, gaining 0.65 percent to close at 77.96 points.</p>
<p>It was a decline which many investors said was ignited by renewed tension with Turkey on the divided island, but also mirrored the gloomy outlook many investors had on the island's economy which relies heavily on tourism, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;This decline is not a pleasant thing but I think we have to look at it in relation to what happened before the bourse opened,&quot; Cyprus Stock Exchange (CSE) chairman Dinos Papadopoulos told parliament.</p>
<p>Prices started tumbling almost immediately after the bourse opened last March 29, replacing years of unofficial over-the-counter transactions. It also put an end to a bull run which saw shares rise 60 percent in the four months before the bourse was launched.</p>
<p>But the decline gained momentum earlier this month after threats by Turkey of a military strike on the island if Cyprus went ahead with the deployment of an anti-aircraft missile system from Russia.</p>
<p>Turkey has occupied the northern third of Cyprus since an invasion in 1974 sparked by a brief Greek Cypriot coup in Nicosia engineered by the military ruling then in Greece.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people feel there are problems in some sectors of the economy and there have been some concerns about the political situation,&quot; said Papadopoulos. &quot;This has had an effect on prices.&quot;</p>
<p>Papadopoulos was prompted into making the remark during a parliamentary debate on an insider trading bill by finance committee chairman Alexis Galanos, who said the decline was &quot;a reflection of the economy&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We are witnessing a daily rally on prices in Europe but we are not seeing it in Cyprus,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Official estimates have forecast gross domestic product (GDP) growth of 3.5 percent in 1997. Unofficial estimates put the growth lower, at 2.6 percent as fears grow that the tension could have an impact on tourism bookings, Cyprus's main money-spinner. (Corrects to make clear tourism is main source of revenue and not offshore business as originally stated.)</p>
<p>Tourism represents 21 percent of the island's GDP. Last year GDP is estimated to have grown 2.5 percent.</p>
<p>-- Michele Kambas, Nicosia newsroom 357 2 365089</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
