<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="331726" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London silver captures spotlight, lifts gold fix.</title>
<headline>London silver captures spotlight, lifts gold fix.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold bounced from Thursday's 40-month low fixing on Friday morning, largely fuelled by a fund-led rally in silver, dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Business this morning involves buying silver. Silver has captured the imagination,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Gold began to chug along behind silver in New York after investment funds decided there was a play in the gold-silver ratio and began to buy silver.</p>
<p>Bullion fixed at $352.95 per ounce, up from the recent low fix of $348.00 on Thursday and a close of $349.20/$349.70.</p>
<p>Since the beginning of the year silver had moved sideways overall while gold was being sold down and confidence in silver as an investment grew as its resilience became more recognised.</p>
<p>&quot;The complex, through silver, was supported by a major U.S. fund on Thursday,&quot; a senior European market analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;There was growing confidence that the white metals had been drawn down by the weight of selling in gold and not with economic justification and that they would not follow gold to the same extent,&quot; the analyst added.</p>
<p>The short position holders in gold had &quot;a lot of comfort&quot; until the rally began, a dealer said, but now they had been forced to cover.</p>
<p>&quot;But a short covering rally in gold will be inhibited because all the usual stuff (producer and professional selling) will come into the market and slow it down,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>But the jury was still out on gold's recovery prospects. &quot;There is no doubt that gold remains oversold, and that should help it correct upwards,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Producer selling could be expected, especially from South African and North American producers which the market perceived to be under hedged, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold has not recovered out of its downside channel yet. It will need positive closes for two or three days in a row to suggest that,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>Silver, having largely survived weakness associated with gold's fall, could continue to drive the complex, dealers and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Silver's move was justified somewhat but it is not convincing yet. Today it would have to close between $4.88 and $4.92 before there would be a good chance it could go further,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>A London-based dealer was more direct. &quot;Silver looks very dangerous, very volatile,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added, &quot;Shorts in silver are worried now. Any short covering rally will not be sold into.&quot;</p>
<p>Silver was indicated at $4.95/$4.97 up seven cents.</p>
<p>Platinum was $1.25 ahead at $357.50/$358.50 having recovered from a 40-month low fix on Thursday of $355.85, and palladium showed $0.25 up at $121.25/$122.25.</p>
<p>-- Brian Spoors +44 171 542 8058</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
