<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="331896" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - Jan 24.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - Jan 24.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Times reported the following business stories Friday:</p>
<p>* PepsiCo Inc announces plans to spin off its multibillion dollar restaurant business into a publicly traded fast-food company that would be second only to McDonald's Corp.</p>
<p>* After peaking at 6,900, the Dow Jones industrial average takes a 94.28-point plunge to close at 6,755.75 in the busiest trading day in the history of the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>* The stock of Texas Instruments rose 11 percent after the company announces plans to sell its notebook computer business to Acer Inc.</p>
<p>* Kohlberg Kravis Roberts &amp; Co says it will buy control of Amphenol Corp, the second largest maker of coaxial cable, for about $1.2 billion cash.</p>
<p>* Xerox Corp reports better than expected earnings and says it will sell its Coregis insurance unit to General Electric and its Apprise computer services unit to Anderson Consulting.  </p>
<p>* Boeing and McDonnell Douglas shares fall after the companies' fourth quarter earnings come in below Wall Street's expectations.</p>
<p>* Sears posts a 25 percent increase in earnings on strong sales and an increase in credit card revenue.</p>
<p>* Delta Air Lines says its second quarter earnings rose 79 percent, but Southwest Airlines reported lower fourth quarter earnings that it attributed in part to higher fuel prices.</p>
<p>* Sony Corp says it may add a second headquarters in New York to support its U.S. operations.</p>
<p>* Bonds traded in a narrow range, and the 30-year Treasury rose to 6.86 percent from 6.82 percent.</p>
<p>* Outgoing secretary of HUD Henry Cisneros accepts a job as president and chief operating officer of Univision Communications, the largest Spanish television broadcaster in the U.S.  </p>
<p>* Last weekend's winter freeze in Florida could lead to price fruit and vegetable price hikes across the nation.</p>
<p>* Sega Enterprises said it would buy Japanese toy company Bandai Co Ltd in a stock swap worth about $1 billion, becoming the world's largest toy and video-game company.</p>
<p>* A divorce case involving a General Electric executive worth $100 million raises questions about how much a spouse is entitled to claim.</p>
<p>* Gyrations in the Tokyo stock market spur worries about the Japanese economy.</p>
<p>* Christie's, the auction house, is negotiating a move into a 300,000-square-foot space at Rockefeller Center, where it would consolidate its warehouses, offices and auction space.</p>
<p>* The latest stock market-Super Bowl theory favors the New England Patriots over the Green Bay Packers. -- Market Place.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
