<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="331944" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Actor Woody Harrelson wins marijuana case.</title>
<headline>Actor Woody Harrelson wins marijuana case.</headline>
<dateline>BEATTYVILLE, Ky. 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A judge ruled on Thursday that an anti-marijuana law under which actor Woody Harrelson was charged is vague and overly broad, giving the star a victory in his challenge to the statute.</p>
<p>Harrelson's lawyer, Beryl McCoy, said he was &quot;delighted&quot; at the decision, adding: &quot;This is the first step to being able to grow hemp in the Commonwealth of Kentucky.&quot; McCoy said he hoped prosecutors would appeal the decision so the matter can be settled by the state's supreme court.</p>
<p>Lee County Judge Ralph McClanahan did not dismiss the charges against Harrelson, but called for a hearing into whether four seeds Harrelson planted last June on a Kentucky plot he owns really were industrial hemp and not marijuana.</p>
<p>Harrelson's lawyer said the hearing would be a formality leading to the charges being dropped.</p>
<p>The actor, famous on television as the bartender in &quot;Cheers&quot; and for his roles in &quot;Natural Born Killers&quot; and other Hollywood films, said he planted the seeds to challenge the law and allow Kentucky farmers to grow hemp legally. He said hemp was Kentucky's leading cash crop 50 years ago and could be again, particularly for farmers wanting to abandon tobacco.</p>
<p>The judge ruled that the law was vague because it did not distinguish between hemp and marijuana. Hemp contains only a fraction of the active ingredient in marijuana that gives users a &quot;high.&quot;</p>
<p>Harrelson owns a California firm, Hempstead Co., which sells hemp-based products. The company had about $1.5 million in sales last year but U.S. laws required it to buy the raw material from China and elsewhere.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEATTYVILLE, Ky."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
