<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="331908" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Irish-American secretly gave away $610 million.</title>
<headline>Irish-American secretly gave away $610 million.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish-American businessman Charles Feeney secretly gave away $610 million over the years to medical research centres, universities, charities and the political wing of the Irish Republican Army, the New York Times reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>The newspaper quoted Feeney as saying in a rare interview that he never set out to build a fortune with his Duty-Free Shoppes chain but he never forgot that as a poor boy from Elizabeth, New Jersey, he made it to a university on the post-Second World War G.I. Bill and a scholarship.</p>
<p>&quot;Money has an attraction for some people, but nobody can wear two pairs of shoes at one time,&quot; said Feeney, 65. &quot;I simply decided I had enough money. It doesn't drive my life. I'm a what-you-see-is-what-you-get kind of guy.&quot;</p>
<p>Feeney, who has both Irish and U.S. citizenship, said he was interested only in making a good living for his family. He agreed to discuss his gifts because the duty-free stores were sold this month and a lawsuit over the sale would have revealed his anonymous donations, the Times reported.</p>
<p>His personal fortune had been estimated in the billions, but he transferred most of his assets to his two charitable foundations and is worth less than $5 million, it said.</p>
<p>Feeney and a Cornell University classmate founded the Duty Free Shoppers Group in 1960 that grew into the world's largest chain of airport luxury goods stores, with annual sales of $3 billion, more than Saks Fifth Avenue and Nieman Marcus combined. Duty-Free Shoppes was sold this month to France's LVMH Moet Hennessy Louis Vuitton.</p>
<p>Feeney, who described himself as a &quot;shabby dresser,&quot; said the size of his fortune revealed only that &quot;we caught a wave. We were lucky. We had more luck than we deserved.&quot;</p>
<p>In 1982, the president of Feeney's Atlantic Foundation, Harvey Dale, began helping the billionaire orchestrate his gifts and to keep his anonymity. Dale, a New York University tax law professor, suggested Feeney make an irrevocable gift of his assets of $3.5 billion to the foundations and do it in Bermuda to avoid disclosure laws in the United States.</p>
<p>The foundations have given away $610 million over 15 years, including more than $50 million to Cornell University in Ithaca, New York. One of those gifts is to help students of modest means pay off their loans if they earn good grades, work and volunteer.</p>
<p>Feeney said he had given personal donations, not from the foundations, to Sinn Fein, the political wing of the Irish Republican Army fighting to end British rule in the province of Northern Ireland and unite it with the Republic of Ireland.</p>
<p>He is the single largest American donor to Sinn Fein, having given the group's Washington office $280,000 in the last two years, public records showed.</p>
<p>The New York Times quoted Feeney as saying his gifts to Sinn Fein had been monitored to ensure they supported only nonviolent activities. He said he continued supporting the Washington office despite the fact that the IRA last February broke the ceasefire it had entered into in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
