<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="331988" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Gle des Eaux falls on broker downgrade.</title>
<headline>Gle des Eaux falls on broker downgrade.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in French utilities company Cie Generale des Eaux fell on Friday following a downgrade by Morgan Stanley to neutral from outperform, market sources said.</p>
<p>A Morgan Stanley executive confirmed the downgrade but gave no details.</p>
<p>The stock was down 2.73 percent at 678 francs on volume of 344,510 shares at 1421 GMT. It hit its high for the past 12 months at 721 francs on Janaury 15. Since the start of the year, it has gained 5.44 percent after rising 31.5 percent last year.</p>
<p>Analysts said the stock has benefited from the replacement of former chairman Guy Dejouany by Jean-Marie Messier.  </p>
<p>Messier's arrival brought a new, open, approach to investor communications. &quot;We were not used to that,&quot; said one analyst who follows the stock.</p>
<p>Messier took over control in mid-1996 and set out to focus the sprawling group on its core businesses, tackle its weak property assets and reduce debt.</p>
<p>He has also built up the telecommunications side through the Cegetel consortium with partners British Telecomunications Plc, SBC Communications Inc and Mannesmann.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
