<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="331953" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Police complain about Foreign Legion in metro.</title>
<headline>Police complain about Foreign Legion in metro.</headline>
<byline>Bernard Edinger</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A French police union complained on Thursday that foreign legionnaires deployed on the Paris Metro to beef up security had insulted and threatened non-white travellers.</p>
<p>Leaders of the FASP uniformed policemen's union went to Prime Minister Alain Juppe's office on Wednesday to complain at the conduct of the legionnaires, sent to reinforce them after a December 3 bomb on a Paris commuter train killed four people and wounded nearly 100.</p>
<p>A union spokeswoman said some legionnaires had hurled racist insults and levelled assault rifles at non-white travellers and carried out identity checks they were not empowered to conduct.</p>
<p>Defence Minister Charles Millon said in a radio interview he did not believe the accusations but: &quot;if some people behaved a bit brutally, well the public likes that style, and are happy to have soldiers ensuring their security.&quot;</p>
<p>He said petty crime had dropped sharply in Paris as a result of the increased security.</p>
<p>Military sources said the complaint might result from police jealously at the military presence.</p>
<p>FASP secretary-general Yvon Castel stood by his accusations and confirmed to Reuters that police trade unionists wanted the army, and especially the Legion, out of the metro.</p>
<p>&quot;The legionnaires are not trained for this kind of work. They're not used to using kid gloves or diplomacy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Under the Vigipirate security plan, 3,000 soldiers have been deployed in the Paris area. Units of one policemen and three stations and airports.</p>
<p>Only the policeman is allowed to make spot identity checks.</p>
<p>Some 320 legionnaires were drafted in for the first time on January 7. They patrolled the metro until January 21 when they returned to their bases in southeast France.</p>
<p>Algerian Moslem fundamentalist guerrillas who claimed responsibility for an earlier wave of bombings in 1995 are suspected of being behind the December blast, which involved an identical bomb concealed in a gas cylinder.</p>
<p>Most Paris commuters hurrying to catch trains did not seem to notice the legionnaires.</p>
<p>Legionnaires in the Metro wore the green berets and combat fatigues which are their operational gear rather than the familiar white kepi hats or dress uniforms which the public is used to seeing in the annual Bastille Day march-past.</p>
<p>Legionnaires are generally older, physically fitter and tougher than the young conscripts who have been on Metro duty in the past.</p>
<p>Newspapers said the last time the Legion had done police duty was in the 1956-1957 &quot;Battle of Algiers&quot;, when they used torture to break a bloody nationalist bombing campaign against French neighbourhoods of the North African territory.</p>
<p>The 8,500-strong Legion was long banned from serving in mainland France but some units have been garrisoned here since 1962, when France lost Algeria where it was based.</p>
<p>When the Legion first apppeared in the metro, army officiers insisted their presence was nothing extraordinary although they admitted some people might be critical of foreign mercenary soldiers on police duty in the capital.</p>
<p>Made up of men from about 80 countries, the Legion is famed both for iron discipline on duty as well as for robust behaviour on the battlefield and sometimes on leave.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
