<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="332165" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian bonds close weaker amid new supply, CPI.</title>
<headline>Canadian bonds close weaker amid new supply, CPI.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-01-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian bonds closed weaker in moderate trade on Thursday, softening amid weakness in U.S. Treasuries, new Canadian corporate supply and the release of consumer price index, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Really we are just down in sympathy with the U.S., the spreads are pretty much unchanged,&quot; said a dealer at one bank-owned brokerage. &quot;We've basically had some selling today in a quiet market with a weak tone in the States.&quot;</p>
<p>Canada's 30-year bond fell C$0.25 to C$107.95 to yield 7.314 percent. The U.S. 30-year bond fell 8/32 to yield 6.86 percent.  </p>
<p>The spread between the benchmark 30-year bonds widened to 45 basis points from 44 basis points at Wednesday's close.</p>
<p>Both Canadian and U.S. bonds were affected by the injection of new supply. The U.S. saw the auction of US$12.5 billion of five-year government notes. In Canada, two corporate issues were set in financial markets.</p>
<p>Canada's Broadcast Centre Trust on Thursday set a C$400 million non-fixed price bond due May 1, 2027 in financial markets. The bond was set to yield 7.53 percent, 23 basis points over the 8.0 percent Government of Canada bond due June 1, 2023.  </p>
<p>Proceeds of the issue would be used to repay the trust's debt, which was incurred in the construction of the Canadian Broadcasting Corp's Broadcasting Centre. The CBC is owned by the Canadian government.</p>
<p>The Canadian Mortgage and Housing Corp on Thursday also set a C$130 million, 5.0 percent medium-term note due January 2, 2002, on financial markets. The issue was priced to yield 5.662 percent on a semi-annual basis.</p>
<p>In economic news, Statistics Canada reported Canada's consumer prices index, seasonally adjusted, rose 0.2 percent month-over-month in December.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the data had little impact on Canadian bond prices.</p>
<p>In other prices, the Government of Canada's 7.0 percent bond due 2006 fell C$0.25 to C$102.50 to yield 6.648 percent. The U.S. 10-year bond fell 8/32 to yield 6.59 percent.</p>
<p>The spread between the benchmark bonds widened to six basis points from four basis points at Wednesday's close.</p>
<p>The three-month cash bill traded with a yield of 2.84 percent against the U.S. bill which last yielded 5.16 percent.</p>
<p>((Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
