<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="332187" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREEK GENERAL NEWS - JAN 24.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREEK GENERAL NEWS - JAN 24.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek general press:</p>
<p>KATHIMERINI</p>
<p>--The government and a visiting delegation of the OECD are working together to find a feasible solution to the Greece's ailing social security system. Major changes are in the pipeline as many funds will find themselves unable to meet obligations in the next few years.</p>
<p>--The government has offered a 25 percent discount on all fines levied by courts if debtors pay up this year. The tax department will be in charge of collecting these revenues, which are expected to total 150 billion drachmas.</p>
<p>--Following the successful negotiated end to the dockers strike, the government is now turning its attention to a compromise with the General Confederation of Workers of Greece (GSEE). Deputy Finance Minister Minister George Drys said one of their main demands - the indexation of the tax scale and the increase in the tax-exemption amount - would be met.</p>
<p>--Archaeological ruins have popped up once again to delay work on another major public works project: this time at the Zagani Hill, to disrupt work on the new international airport at Spata.</p>
<p>--The European Commission said yesterday that it could not impose any restrictive measures on a petrochemical plant to soon begin operating on the Turkish coast, directly opposite the Greek island of Mytilini.</p>
<p>ELEFTHEROTYPIA</p>
<p>--The US Congress, according to the Turkish press, will request a report from German courts regarding the alleged involvement of Turkish Foreign Minister Tansu Ciller in the trafficking of narcotics. German judges insist they have hard evidence while Greek Eurodeputy Alekos Alavanos will bring the issue to the European Parliament.</p>
<p>--More confusion in the parliamentary fact-finding commission on what actually happened in the granting of a licence for a casino in the Athens seaside suburb of Floisvos. New Democracy deputy and commission member Bellos appears to contradict himself.</p>
<p>--Four new faces at the White House - including one as aide to Secretary of State Madeleine Albright - are of Greek descent.</p>
<p>TA NEA</p>
<p>--Hundreds of patients are at risk, reports say, due to faulty equipment at the state-of-the-art Onassion Cardiology Centre.</p>
<p>--Greece leads the European field in the number of smokers, with 61 percent of men and 26 percent of women smoking.</p>
<p>ELEFTHEROS TYPOS</p>
<p>--The teachers' strike is worsening as teachers vote to extend their five-day strike and the farmers' deadline of January 28 looms.</p>
<p>--A truck driver convicted of murdering three prostitutes and raping and terrorising many others yesterday received 13 life sentences, the heaviest non-death sentence ever handed down in Greece.</p>
<p>ETHNOS</p>
<p>--A 48-year-old mother of fine confessed to poisoning her 21-year-old unwed daughter in her eighth month of pregnancy to save her family from the disgrace of an illegitimate child. --Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
