<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="332268" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-National Jet suspends Christmas Is service.</title>
<headline>RTRS-National Jet suspends Christmas Is service.</headline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Private airline operator National Jet Systems (NJS) said on Friday it would indefinitely suspend its service to the Indian ocean resort of Christmas Island due to the impact on bookings of a legal dispute.</p>
<p>NJS executive chairman Warren Seymour said the service to the island would be suspended from February 17, following Chinese New Year celebrations. However, the Broome-Denpasar and Lombok-Darwin return services would continue as usual.</p>
<p>Seymour said a legal dispute involving the owners of the Christmas Island casino had caused a drop in bookings.  </p>
<p>&quot;The legal wranglings have caused passenger loads to drop considerably during the last month to the point we can no longer afford to carry the cost burden on behalf of the Christmas Island community,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>The casino's owner, Indonesian based businessman Robby Sumanpow, is reported to be involved in a dispute with casino operator Casinos Austria International Ltd.</p>
<p>Seymour said the Australian government had been approached to maintain support for the service, introduced last year to carry Asian-based gamblers to the island's betting tables.  </p>
<p>&quot;We will seek every opportunity to recommence the service as soon as it proves viable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Casinos Austria has said the casino's owners have withdrawn financial facilities to cover high rollers' bets, meaning the casino can no longer cover large bets.</p>
<p>This has caused a sharp fall in the number of international gamblers visiting the island to gamble.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
