<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="332396" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: South Korea's overstaffed banks prepare for layoffs.</title>
<headline>South Korea's overstaffed banks prepare for layoffs.</headline>
<byline>Katherine Bruce</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's overstaffed banks could be first in line for layoffs if a controversial new labour law takes effect, economists said on Friday.</p>
<p>But industries such as automaking and shipbuilding would probably escape large scale sackings, partly because of strong unions and the need for skilled workers, they said.</p>
<p>Banks employ more than 100,000 workers and are a weak link in the economy, struggling under bad loans made under government duress or as a result of poor credit analysis. Plunging stock prices last year wiped almost $6 billion from their stock investment portfolios.</p>
<p>As President Kim Young-sam begins to push for financial sector reform, even bank unions appear to accept that the axe is likely to fall on jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;We recognise that banks are overstaffed,&quot; said an official at the Korean Federation of Banks and Financial Workers Unions.</p>
<p>Analysts said banks could comfortably shed 30 percent of their staff. Layoffs on that scale were needed to shore up the profits of the nation's 25 commercial banks, which slumped by an average of 2.4 percent last year to a combined 846.8 billion won ($997 million).</p>
<p>&quot;The average city bank spends more than 400 billion won a year on employee-related costs, including severance reserves and fringe benefits. This is more than four times net earnings,&quot; said Yoon Yong-chul, a banking analyst at SBC Warburg.</p>
<p>&quot;If they reduced this cost by only 20 percent, earnings could double.&quot;</p>
<p>Some analysts predict government-directed mergers and acquisitions between city banks and their regional counterparts to achieve greater efficiencies.</p>
<p>In addition, domestic banks would have to undergo drastic restructuring to prepare for greater competition from foreign banks that will be allowed to set up wholly owned subsidiaries by the end of 1998, boosting assets and expanding branch networks.</p>
<p>But payroll savings could be achieved only with worker layoffs, analysts said.</p>
<p>A new labour law that makes it easier for companies to shed staff was rammed through parliament last month, but its fate is now uncertain after President Kim agreed to send it back to parliament following almost a month of strikes.</p>
<p>Bank employees were among tens of thousands of workers who joined protest rallies against the bill, although most ignored union calls to join the stoppages.</p>
<p>Park Yoon, an investment manager at Prudential Portfolio Managers in Hong Kong, said manufacturing companies were loathe to lay off workers, hoping their export order books would soon fill after a prolonged export slump.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is even a hint that the Korean economy or exports may turn around, manufacturers can't afford to lose trained workers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>South Korea's trade deficit ballooned to a record $20.38 billion in 1996 from a $10.06 billion shortfall in 1995. Many economists are predicting a turnaround in the economy in the second half of this year.</p>
<p>Powerful unions in big factories would also deter mass layoffs, regardless of the law, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Management has very little power against workers in heavy industries,&quot; said Park Young-bum, a researcher at the state-run Korean Labour Institute.</p>
<p>&quot;Large manufacturers have about 20,000 or 30,000 workers. If a company tried to dismiss maybe 5,000, the remaining 25,000 people would go on strike, which would mean stoppages.&quot; ($1 = 854 won)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
