<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="332516" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Lizhu to issue rights shares to A shareholders.</title>
<headline>Lizhu to issue rights shares to A shareholders.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zhuhai Special Economic Zone Lizhu Pharmaceutical Group Inc said on Friday it would make a three-for-10 rights offer to A-share and founder-share holders, and use proceeds to expand operations.</p>
<p>The offer, approved by the China Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC), has been priced at 4.70 yuan per rights share, the drug-maker said in a prospectus published in the Shenzhen-based Securities Times.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Lizhu's A shares closed at 10.61 yuan each. The registration deadline was set at February 24 and Lizhu's A shares were slated to go ex-rights the following day, it said.</p>
<p>Lizhu said it had a total of 199.42 million shares at the end of 1995, consisting of 71.58 million A shares, 5,900 rights shares tranferred from founder shareholders, 63.84 million shares held by founders and 64.00 million B shares.</p>
<p>A company official contacted by telephone told the Hong Kong-based newsletter China Securities Bulletin that Lizhu planned to apply to the CSRC for a three-for-10 rights offer to holders of B shares in May and hoped to implement it this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The pricing of the planned second-tranche rights issue is subject to the condition of the Shenzhen B share market,&quot; the official said without elaborating.  </p>
<p>Lizhu said it would use money raised from the first-batch offer to finance a series of technological improvements and a new line of pharmaceutical products, expand sales and acquire several weaker competitors to sharpen its competitive edge in domestic market.</p>
<p>The official said Lizhu's 1996 net profits would roughly equal the 1995 level of 80.15 million yuan, compared with 113.21 million yuan in 1994. Detailed results for last year would not be released to the public until an audit was done, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;Competition from domestic counterparts grew fiercer last year but the impact was somewhat offset by Lizhu's success in expanding its sales network,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The official said Lizhu foresaw better profits in 1997 when the newly acquired drug production plants start contributing to earnings.</p>
<p>Lizhu's 1996 interim net profits declined 21 percent to 43.12 million yuan compared with 54.86 million yuan in the first half of 1995 due to strong competition, which forced it to trim prices and increase sales commissions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
