<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="332626" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea drops charges against arrested unionists.</title>
<headline>S.Korea drops charges against arrested unionists.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean police have released four arrested unionists after state prosecutors dropped charges against them for leading illegal strikes in protest at a new labour law, a prosecution official said on Friday.</p>
<p>The official said that 15 other outstanding arrest warrants for leaders of the outlawed Korean Confederation of Trade Unions would be returned to several courts, thus invalidating them. Another detained unionist was freed on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>&quot;The four were freed overnight,&quot; the official told Reuters. &quot;This means that no union leaders are under detention in connection with recent illegal strikes.&quot;</p>
<p>The release of the four is in line with a peace offer by President Kim Young-sam who said on Tuesday he would order the suspension of the arrest warrants.</p>
<p>In a meeting with opposition leaders, Kim also made a dramatic concession by agreeing to reopen parliamentary debate on the controversial labour law, which allows companies to sack workers and replace strikers.</p>
<p>Kim had previously ruled out a revision of the law or any compromise with the unionists who led more than three weeks of wildcat strikes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
