<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="332713" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Jan 24.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Jan 24.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in the Swedish papers on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAGENS NYHETER</p>
<p>- A merger between Swedish banks S-E-Banken and Nordbanken could happen already next week, according to newspaper sources. All investments have been halted and the banks have a general freeze on hiring, the sources told the newspaper. There are also reports that managers within S-E-Banken have been instructed to cancel any travel plans.</p>
<p>- The minority Social Democratic government's cooperation partner, the Centre Party, is worried after Prime Minister Goran Persson's promise to allocate ten billion crowns annually of coming budget surpluses to health care, schools and child and elderly care. The Centre Party's leading tax politician Rolf Kenneryd wants to use some of the surpluses to finance tax cuts.</p>
<p>- Prolonged Swedish energy negotiations about phasing out nuclear power are expected to be finalised after next weekend, Energy Minister Anders Sundstrom said.</p>
<p>SVENSKA DAGBLADET</p>
<p>- A total of 32 Swedish companies are among the Financial Times' list of the 500 largest companies in Europe. Pharmaceutical company Astra AB was number 19 and telecoms group AB LM Ericsson placed number 21.</p>
<p>- In the first week of February, the government will present a proposal for how and when nuclear power will be phased out, according to energy minister Anders Sundstrom. The Christian Democrats might decide to leave the drawn-out energy negotiations. Then three of seven parliamentary parties would remain: the Social Democrat minority government, its informal cooperation partner the Centre Party and the Left Party.</p>
<p>- The weakening of the Swedish crown on Thursday might not only be a reaction to Prime Minister Goran Persson's promise to direct ten billion crowns of coming budget surpluses annually towards public services. Other Nordic currencies also dropped, albeit not as much. The Swedish crown plummeted 1.8 percent against the mark, while the Finnish markka fell 1.4 percent and the Norwegian crown slid 1.0 percent.</p>
<p>DAGENS INDUSTRI</p>
<p>- Sweden's business community is united in favour of participation in the planned European Monetary Union (EMU), according to chairman of the Swedish Association of Employers Anders Scharp. Regardless of whether or not Sweden joins the EMU, Scharp said that &quot;the companies will have to adjust to it, and in that case it is easier if we are members.&quot;</p>
<p>- SBAB, a state-owned Swedish firm which finances public housing, has made a policy decision to make use of securitisation as a means to reduce finance costs. This method of raising money, which has long been popular in the U.S., would be extremely helpful to Sweden's hardpressed county housing firms. County-owned housing firms have outstanding loans amounting to some 200 billion crowns.</p>
<p>- Sweden's largest temporary employment companies, Manpower, Teamwork, Proffice and Olsten Personalkraft, expect to recruit a total of 4,000-4,500 new employees during 1997, boosting their collective turnover by about 50-60 percent.</p>
<p>-- Birgitta Forsberg, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1006</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
