<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="332776" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan seeks big uranium supply, backlash possible.</title>
<headline>Taiwan seeks big uranium supply, backlash possible.</headline>
<byline>George Hsu</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>State utility Taiwan Power Co has begun seeking a three-year uranium supply to fire its three nuclear plants in a routine move that nonetheless could rekindle anti-nuclear protests and raise eyebrows in rival China.</p>
<p>The public notice comes at a time of growing popular opposition to Taiwan's pro-nuclear policy as well as a new dispute with South Korea over Taipower's deal to ship nuclear waste to North Korea.</p>
<p>The tender also could rekindle frictions with arch rival China, which voiced concern in August over Taiwan's unsuccessful efforts to import uranium from Australia.</p>
<p>China, Taiwan's arch rival since a civil war split them in 1949, said in August that uranium was no &quot;ordinary commodity&quot; and called its export to Taiwan a highly sensitive issue.</p>
<p>Beijing, which has a nuclear arsenal and nuclear power, strongly opposes sales of strategic or advanced arms to Taiwan, which it regards as a renegade province that must be unified with the mainland -- by force if it pushes for independence.</p>
<p>Environmentalists have waged a vocal but losing war against Taipower's construction of a fourth nuclear station and rioted in October after the state managed to overturn parliament's veto of its $4.1 billion budget. Opponents say Taiwan does not need nuclear power and has no place to store nuclear waste.</p>
<p>The plant is rising on the outskirts of the capital Taipei.</p>
<p>Taiwan's nuclear waste dump at Lanyu island is almost full and local opponents have extracted a government pledge to remove the dump by 2002. Taipei has been seeking sites overseas, including China, the Marshall Islands and Russia.</p>
<p>Seoul hopes to persuade Taipei to back out of its contract to ship up to 200,000 barrels of nuclear waste to North Korea, citing environmental risks to the Korean peninsula due to the questionable safeguards of its cash-starved Stalinist rival.</p>
<p>Pyongyang's nuclear power programme caused international uproar in the early 1990s. The United States and others alleged the programme aimed to develop nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>Taiwan's foreign ministry on Friday defended Taipei's determination to work with North Korea as &quot;correct&quot;.</p>
<p>The economics ministry had spoken more bluntly on Thursday, saying no &quot;political interference&quot; by Seoul could stop what it called a purely business activity.</p>
<p>Two contracts to import up to 750,000 pounds (340,000 kg) of uranium a year would specify delivery in September 1997, March 1998 and March 1999, a Taipower official said.</p>
<p>The deadline to enter the tender is 0830 GMT on February 27 and results should be available the next day. The tender is open to any uranium exportable to Taiwan. The United States, Canada and Namibia have been main suppliers.</p>
<p>Bids for Taipower's uranium tenders must comply with a 1971 safeguards framework reached with the International Atomic Energy Agency and the United States, utility officials said.</p>
<p>Australia bans export of uranium to Taiwan due to differences in safety regulations, but has been studying whether Taiwan's non-proliferation safeguards were adequate.</p>
<p>Taipower has three operating nuclear power stations, each with two reactors, which consume a total of 2.5 million pounds of uranium fuel rods a year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
