<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="332764" id="root" date="1997-01-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Trinidad courts India business headed to S. America.</title>
<headline>Trinidad courts India business headed to S. America.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-01-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trinidad and Tobago Prime Minister Basdeo Panday said on Friday his country was a good platform for Indian businessmen to launch into South American markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Trinidad and Tobago is a strategic platform for launching the economic penetration of Central and South America,&quot; Panday told a meeting of businessmen in the Indian capital.</p>
<p>Seven miles (12 km) off the coast of Venezuela, Trinidad and Tobago is a member of the 137-member Association of Caribbean States, which offers entrepreneurs a market of 200 million consumers, Panday said.</p>
<p>&quot;My government welcomes foreign investment, having recognised the advantages deriving from it,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Last year, Trinidad and Tobago attracted $4 billion in foreign investment, Panday said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our country has now achieved the critical mass which would allow the establishment of a wide range of downstream industries,&quot; Panday said.</p>
<p>&quot;Indian entrepreneurs and business people who wish to increase their exports in the Western hemisphere would be tempted to set up their industries and businesses in Trinidad itself so that they may reduce the cost of transport,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Panday began a two-week visit to India on Friday. He will be the chief guest at India's Republic Day celebrations on Sunday. The two countries were to sign an agreement later on Friday to boost bilateral trade.</p>
<p>Indian Commerce Minister Bolla Buli Ramaiah said earlier this week the trade pact would give exporters and investors in each country better access to the other's markets.</p>
<p>India exports cashew nuts, tea, diamonds, fabric, leather, turmeric and pharmaceuticals to Trinidad and Tobago, Panday said. Its exports totalled $6 million last year, up from $2 million in 1992.</p>
<p>In turn, India buys lubricant oil-based stock and anhydrous ammonia. Panday said Trinidad wants to be the world leader in methanol and ammonia exports by the turn of the century, thanks to abundant reserves of the cheap feedstock, natural gas.</p>
<p>Panday, a 64-year-old lawyer and trade unionist, is Trinidad and Tobago's first ethnic Indian prime minister. He was accompanied by Foreign Minister Ralph Maraj and Trade Minister Mervyn Assam.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TRTO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
