<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="332866" id="root" date="1997-01-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: CRICKET-ENGLAND'S HOPES KEPT ALIVE IN NZ TEST.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-ENGLAND'S HOPES KEPT ALIVE IN NZ TEST.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1997-01-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lefthander Stephen Fleming confirmed himself as New Zealand's new batting lynchpin with a maiden test century against England on Saturday, but the visitors' hopes were kept alive with a spirited comeback.</p>
<p>Fleming's 129 anchored New Zealand's first innings 390 after the home team had been sent in by England captain Mike Atherton on Friday.</p>
<p>When bad light brought the close forward by 11 overs, England had responded impressively to be 123 for one, with Alec Stewart in fine touch on 65 and Atherton on 48.</p>
<p>Fleming is playing his 23rd test. His previous 38 innings had produced 10 half centuries and there have been expectations that he would come through as the heir apparent to the recently retired Martin Crowe as New Zealand's premier batsman.</p>
<p>On Saturday Fleming showed his class in crafting 254-ball innings, which included 18 fours and one six.</p>
<p>Starting the day on 58, with Chris Cairns for company and New Zealand 233 for five, Fleming batted beautifully, as the pair added 118 for the sixth wicket.</p>
<p>Effortless driving was the hallmark of Fleming's innings before he was last man out, smartly caught and bowled by Dominic Cork.</p>
<p>But England bounced back in the middle session, as fast-medium Darren Gough ripped out three New Zealand batsmen in the space of 12 balls.</p>
<p>Captain Lee Germon was caught attempting a hook, Dipak Patel was leg before wicket next ball and Simon Doull edged a catch to second slip.</p>
<p>Gough finished with four for 91 from 32 overs and Cork, the pick of an England attack which failed to take advantage of favourable seam bowling conditions, ended with three for 96 in 32.5 overs.</p>
<p>England opener Nick Knight didn't last long, but Stewart was quickly into his stride, benefitting from some ill-directed bowling from Cairns in particular.</p>
<p>He hooked Cairns for six behind square leg then blazed a series of boundaries after tea.</p>
<p>Atherton, badly out of the runs on the tour of Zimbabwe and New Zealand, was more circumspect, but still produced the occasional fluent stroke.</p>
<p>The pair put on 55 in an hour after tea, Stewart scoring 40 of them, and he went to his 22nd half century in tests off only 57 balls.</p>
<p>The 100 partnership came at run-a-minute rate and when bad light stopped play Stewart was not out on 67 and Atherton was in sight of his 50.</p>
<p>Stewart admitted his left hand had been tender today. He dislocated the little finger of that hand yesterday sprawling down the leg side to stop a wayward Gough delivery. He taped the finger, had it iced and batted comfortably.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
