<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="332814" id="root" date="1997-01-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: ALPINE SKIING-FRITZ STROBL WINS DEMANDING KITZBUEHEL DOWNHILL.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-FRITZ STROBL WINS DEMANDING KITZBUEHEL DOWNHILL.</headline>
<dateline>KITZBUEHEL, Austria 1997-01-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>In-form Austrian Fritz Strobl again edged out compatriot Werner Franz to clinch his second World Cup victory on Saturday, on the most demanding downhill slope on the men's circuit.</p>
<p>Last month Strobl stopped Franz claiming his first-ever victory at the season's opening downhill in Val D'Isere, by only two-hundredths of a second.</p>
<p>On Saturday, Strobl performed a breathtaking run on the dreaded 3,312-metre long Streif piste, for a winning time of one minute 51.58 seconds to beat Franz by 0.57 seconds.</p>
<p>Strobl slashed compatriot Guenther Mader's course record from last year of 1:54.29 by almost three seconds, even though the piste was flagged with more gates this winter and was longer.</p>
<p>Frenchman Luc Alphand, who won Friday's two-run sprint downhill on a shortened version of the course on the Hahnenkamm mountain, was third in 1:52.20.</p>
<p>A delighted Strobl said: &quot;I didn't think I was doing that well during the run because I felt I was all over the place. But when I saw the number one on the scoreboard, I knew it wouldn't be such a bad day after all.&quot;</p>
<p>Strobl is the only Austrian to have won downhills this winter and has therefore virtually guaranteed himself a starting bib at the world championships in Sestriere, which begin on February 2.</p>
<p>He is also the only skier other than Alphand and Italian Kristian Ghedina to have won in the downhill this season.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KITZBUEHEL, Austria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
