<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="332983" id="root" date="1997-01-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbia opposition warns against nationalist card.</title>
<headline>Serbia opposition warns against nationalist card.</headline>
<byline>Dan De Luce</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-01-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbia's opposition leaders warned their supporters on Saturday that ruling Socialists were preparing to enlist the help of hardline nationalists in an attempt to undermine nearly 70 days of street demonstrations.</p>
<p>Vuk Draskovic, one of the leaders of the opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition, told a rally in Belgrade that President Slobodan Milosevic &quot;has decided to replay his patriotic song&quot; that helped ignite four years of war in the Balkans.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless we stop him, he'll 'unify' Serbia in the way he 'unified' Yugoslavia,&quot; Draskovic told a small crowd in the city centre.</p>
<p>Draskovic's comments coincided with reports that Milosevic's ruling Socialists had turned to the ultra-nationalist Serbian Radical Party to help shore up its damaged position.</p>
<p>Milosevic, widely blamed for plunging former Yugoslavia into war in 1991, has accused the Zajedno coalition of plotting to destabilise Serbia in daily street protests.</p>
<p>Zajedno, joined by university students, has vowed to keep up its campaign until authorities recognise opposition victories in Belgrade and elsewhere in November municipal elections.</p>
<p>Saturday's rally drew several thousand people to Republic Square, a smaller turnout than previous protests.</p>
<p>Many supporters were joining neighbourhood &quot;promenades&quot; which Zajedno organised after increasingly tough police action had prevented mass street marches that blocked traffic.</p>
<p>Opposition followers were concerned over a rising number of reports of police beatings. Riot police on Thursday clubbed protesters seated on a highway into the central town of Kragujevac, beating one member of parliament unconscious.</p>
<p>Independent radio stations B-92 and Index reported beatings in several Belgrade districts as police ambushed small groups of people making their way to a student rally on Friday.</p>
<p>University students braved winter temperatures on Saturday to keep up a round-the-clock vigil on Kolaceva street in front of a police cordon.</p>
<p>The stand-off began last Sunday when police blocked attempts to hold a march through the city centre.</p>
<p>University students have organised a 24-hour vigil in a bid to outlast the police cordon, rotating groups of students in shifts.</p>
<p>A group of journalists from the state-run Politika newspaper, considered a government mouthpiece, lent support to the students on Saturday, delivering a cake to the protesters.</p>
<p>Milosevic's Socialists discussed the unprecedented threat to five decades of unbroken communist and socialist rule at a session of the party's central committee on Friday.</p>
<p>Belgrade independent media reported party officials were ready to invite hardline nationalists to join the government to help them portray the opposition as traitors.</p>
<p>The independent daily &quot;Nasa Borba&quot;, citing unnamed sources, said the party was planning a government reshuffle and a renewed media assault on the Zajedno opposition.</p>
<p>The Zajedno protests that have swept Belgrade and cities across the country represented an &quot;attack on the state by the same people who broke the old Yugoslavia&quot;, the paper quoted Milosevic as saying at the session.</p>
<p>The former communist party chief has relied on his vast police force and his state television station to try to stifle the wave of street demonstrations.</p>
<p>The protests -- marked by an irreverent, carnival atmosphere -- have won strong Western support and sparked divisions within the Socialist ranks.</p>
<p>The republic of Montenegro, which together with Serbia comprises what is left of Yugoslavia, has also sharply criticised Milosevic's handling of the crisis.</p>
<p>Milosevic has remained aloof and out of public view during the crisis while his deputies have sent out mixed signals, shifting from promises of concessions to stern warnings and communist-style rhetoric.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
