<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="333050" id="root" date="1997-01-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine VP seen gearing for presidency bid.</title>
<headline>Philippine VP seen gearing for presidency bid.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-01-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine Vice President Joseph Estrada, apparently preparing for a run at the presidency next year, called on opposition politicians on Saturday to join his new party.</p>
<p>Estrada said in a nationwide radio broadcast that he expected more political leaders to join his Party of the Filipino Masses (PMP) to bolster growth, good governance and grassroots empowerment.</p>
<p>On Friday, Estrada inducted about 70 local and national officials into the party in a ceremony that many newspapers said closely resembled the start of an election campaign.</p>
<p>Estrada did not formally declare his candidacy, but he told reporters after the ceremony, &quot;It's almost sure I will run.&quot;</p>
<p>Under Philippine law, people can only formally declare their candidacy three months before an election, when campaigning starts. The next presidential elections are in May 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;We need an opposition party. It's part of the democratic system,&quot; Estrada said in his radio programme.</p>
<p>Estrada is not a member of President Fidel Ramos's ruling Lakas-NUCD coalition. The president and vice president are elected separately in the Philippines, not on a joint ticket.</p>
<p>Estrada, known for his pro-poor and nationalistic stance, said the PMP was for all Filipinos.</p>
<p>&quot;Our party is not only for taxi drivers, not only for fish vendors and sidewalk vendors. Our party is for all Filipinos, rich or poor...,&quot; he said, adding: &quot;Our purpose is to narrow the gap between the rich and the poor.&quot;</p>
<p>But Estrada said he would maintain the liberalisation thrust of the Ramos administration.</p>
<p>&quot;As much as possible, the government should not intervene in business, especially in big businesses. We are not going to impose stiff regulations against businessmen,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>PMP president Orlando Mercado said during the radio broadcast that, &quot;We are trying to strengthen the party. In fact, we are going to get more allies into our party.&quot;</p>
<p>Mercado, a senator, also said the induction ceremony &quot;was not a proclamation rally&quot; and the party was still &quot;testing the waters.&quot;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the names of other potential presidential candidates have been swirling about the local political scene.</p>
<p>Defense Secretary Renato de Villa, a close Ramos aide, has said big business is backing his candidacy.</p>
<p>Senator Gloria Macapagal Arroyo, an economist, recently quit the main opposition Laban Ng Demokratikong Pilipino (Struggle of Democratic Filipinos) and hinted she would form her own party to run for the presidency.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
