<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="333120" id="root" date="1997-01-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton asks for new food safety ideas.</title>
<headline>Clinton asks for new food safety ideas.</headline>
<byline>Steve Holland</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alarmed at a deadly bacteria that turned up in apple juice, President Clinton Saturday directed three departments to report to him within 90 days on ways to improve food safety in America.</p>
<p>His order was part of what he wants to be a $43 million frontal assault to develop a nationwide early warning system for food-borne illnesses and use state-of-the-art technology to prevent them from spreading.</p>
<p>He proposed the spending for the fiscal year 1998 budget that he will submit to Congress for its consideration Feb. 6.</p>
<p>In addition, Clinton said he wanted the heads of the Department of Agriculture, Department of Health and Human Services and the Environmental Protection Agency to work with communities, farmers, businesses, consumer protection groups and all levels of government on measures to improve food safety.</p>
<p>&quot;I want them to pay special attention to research and public education efforts,&quot; Clinton said in his weekly radio address. &quot;I want them to focus on what sort of partnerships the government can form with the private sector to meet our goals.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton was acting in response to an outbreak of the E. coli bacteria linked to unpasteurized apple juice. One child died and 50 other people were sickened in California, Washington state, Colorado and the Vancouver area of Canada last fall as a result of the juice, produced by Odwalla Inc., a California company.</p>
<p>Four years ago this month, the E. coli bacteria struck again in the western United States. Five hundred people became ill and four children died as a result of eating fast-food restaurant hamburgers tainted with the bacteria.</p>
<p>&quot;Hard-working American parents deserve the peace of mind that comes from knowing that the meal they set before their children is safe,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>Clinton's $43 million food safety program would include an $11.5 million early warning system. Another $10 million would go to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in Atlanta to keep track of data on food-borne illnesses and $1 million for the Food and Drug Administration.</p>
<p>About $23 million would go to the FDA for seafood safety inspection, including research, risk assessment and education.</p>
<p>Food and consumer groups welcomed the news.</p>
<p>Under a Clinton directive from last summer, new safety rules will begin to take effect requiring all meat and poultry plants to test for E. coli. The Agriculture Department this year is implementing a massive overhaul of its meat and poultry inspection system for the first time in 90 years.</p>
<p>In the Republican radio address, a House Republican said Clinton and the Republican Congress had to use &quot;honest language&quot; if they were to work together.</p>
<p>Rep. Jim Talent of Missouri said it was a good sign that the two sides were using similar rhetoric to describe their goals, but that when Republicans talked about ending the era of big government, &quot;we mean that it is absolutely necessary to change the federal government so that it stops hurting the American people and starts helping them.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If the president truly understands that as we in Congress understand it, we will be able to move forward together honestly,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
