<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="333115" id="root" date="1997-01-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gingrich defends honor before Georgia constituents.</title>
<headline>Gingrich defends honor before Georgia constituents.</headline>
<byline>David Morgan</byline>
<dateline>MARIETTA, Georgia 1997-01-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>House of Representatives Speaker Newt Gingrich said on Saturday that admitting to ethics violations was the &quot;most honourable thing to do&quot; to resolve the issue and flatly denied deceiving Congress.</p>
<p>In a series of public meetings in his home district, the Georgia Republican sought to defend his position as congressional leader and deflect criticism brought about by his unprecedented $300,000 penalty for ethics breaches.</p>
<p>Gingrich, in his first public comments since the House voted a reprimand and the $300,000 penalty on Tuesday, said he had made a mistake by trusting his lawyers to guide him safely through the complex congressional code of conduct.</p>
<p>&quot;I trusted the law firm to have done the job right. They didn't do the job right and I didn't catch them, so I thought the most honourable thing to do when you have done something wrong is to say, 'This was a mistake,'&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Saying upfront, this was a mistake, is the only honourable thing you can do if you've made a mistake,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some 1,000 people attended the first two meetings in Roswell and Marietta, which were marked by raucous exchanges between supporters and critics of the controversial speaker.</p>
<p>Gingrich bristled at one constituent's suggestion that the penalty could be considered a &quot;fine&quot; for intentionally deceiving Congress. Instead, he said he had agreed only to being careless.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no suggestion of intent to deceive. A mistake had been made. That is the total of what I agreed to,&quot; on the the report by the House ethics committee, he said.</p>
<p>He added that he would never have accepted the six-figure penalty if it had been described as a &quot;fine.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I would have fought a fine, because if the ethics committee, which is a non-judicial system, were in a position to destroy middle-class representatives you've got a precedent of enormous danger,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier, Gingrich said he was the victim of a House double standard in judging ethics cases and that Democrats including minority leader Representative Richard Gephardt had run into problems but been let off lightly.</p>
<p>He also noted that a number of tax-exempt organisations were able to keep their status despite political objectives, singling out the Sierra Club which has stated that his ouster is one of its goals.</p>
<p>Gingrich said the media was partly responsible for his ethics troubles, and accused Democrats of trying to keep public attention on his problems in order to avoid talking about the &quot;things that really matter,&quot; namely the Republican legislative agenda.</p>
<p>He proposed that penalties be proposed against members of Congress who file frivolous ethics charges against their colleagues -- with triple damages levied against those found to be &quot;repetitively and maliciously&quot; calling their colleagues on the carpet</p>
<p>&quot;David Bonior (Democrat of Michigan) and his friends have filed some 70 false charges. How much have they cost the taxpayers?&quot; Gingrich said.</p>
<p>Gingrich supporters passed out handouts detailing his position on the ethics problem, saying the ethics panel had not found him in violation of U.S. tax laws and comparing his problems favourably scandals that have rocked the White House.</p>
<p>The meetings came as the 53-year-old conservative and his allies struggled to weather a storm of controversy in Washington raised by the ethics committee report and Tuesday's 395-28 vote to reprimand him and impose the penalty.</p>
<p>The committee made no finding as to whether Gingrich used tax-exempt funds illegally for partisan political purposes in the form of his college course, but the speaker admitted he should have sought legal advice on the issue.</p>
<p>Gingrich must now find a way to pay his six-figure penalty that would not arouse a new furore.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARIETTA, Georgia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
