<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="333251" id="root" date="1997-01-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-COMEBACK SIDES CHELSEA AND FOREST HANDED AWAY TIES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-COMEBACK SIDES CHELSEA AND FOREST HANDED AWAY TIES.</headline>
<byline>Mike Collett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chelsea and Nottingham Forest, who both came from behind to clinch famous F.A. Cup victories on Sunday, were given scant reward for their efforts when they were both drawn away from home in the fifth round.</p>
<p>Chelsea, who fought back from 2-0 down to beat last season's beaten finalists Liverpool 4-2 at Stamford Bridge must travel to premier league rivals Leicester.</p>
<p>And Forest, who overturned a single goal deficit to defeat Newcastle United 2-1 at St James' Park earlier in the day, will most likely play first division leaders Bolton, who should account for second division Chesterfield in their delayed fourth round match.</p>
<p>F.A. Cup holders Manchester United, bidding to become the first club in the Cup's 126-year history to reach four successive finals, will play a London side for the third successive round if they overcome Wimbledon in their fourth round replay.</p>
<p>They were drawn at home to first division Queens Park Rangers, who beat Barnsley 3-2 in the fourth round at home on Saturday.</p>
<p>The only other clear cut tie, not dependent on replays or delayed matches, handed first division Bradford City a home tie against premier league Sheffield Wednesday, which gives Chris Waddle, who scored with a 35-yard shot when Bradford knocked out Everton on Saturday, the chance to knock out one of his old clubs.</p>
<p>Waddle scored for Wednesday when they lost the replayed 1993 Cup final to Arsenal and was unhappy at being released by Wednesday manager David Pleat at the start of the season.</p>
<p>The winners of the delayed fourth round tie between Arsenal and Leeds will be at home to first division Portsmouth, while premier league Derby County, bidding to reach their first Cup final since 1946, will play either Blackburn Rovers, Coventry or minor league Woking, who drew 1-1 in a third round tie at Coventry on Saturday.</p>
<p>Middlesbrough, the bottom side in the premier league who survived a scare before beating minor league Hednesford Town 3-2 on Saturday, face a tricky fifth round tie at either Manchester City or Watford.</p>
<p>Barry Fry, one of the most colourful managers in the league, will go back to Birmingham, one of his former clubs, if his Peterborough side overcome Wrexham, surprise winners over West Ham on Saturday.</p>
<p>The matches are due to be played on the weekend of February 15-16.</p>
<p>Chelsea player-manager Ruud Gullit said he was looking forward to the match against Leicester after his side's remarkable comeback victory over Liverpool.</p>
<p>&quot;I am pleased we are playing a premier league club because if you play a smaller club you are on a hiding to nothing,&quot; he said afterwards.</p>
<p>Gullit was doubly delighted his side were still in the draw after they looked down and out trailing Liverpool 2-0 at halftime.</p>
<p>&quot;But I told the players if they scored within 15 minutes of the restart they would win,&quot; he added, &quot;and when Mark Hughes scored the first there was fear among the Liverpool players.&quot;</p>
<p>The introduction of Hughes, and the deployment of Roberto di Matteo to stay closer to John Barnes helped turn the match Chelsea's way and they gave a dazzling second-half display to win with two goals from Gianluca Vialli and one each from Gianfranco Zola and Hughes. Robbie Fowler and Stan Collymore scored for Liverpool.</p>
<p>Nottingham Forest, who last won the Cup in 1959, could be forgiven for thinking this could be their year after their victory at Newcastle who led with a Les Ferdinand goal.</p>
<p>Defensive errors, which new Newcastle manager Kenny Dalglish must eliminate, proved costly with Ian Woan pouncing to score twice.</p>
<p>Forest have won six out of eight matches since player-manager Stuart Pearce took over from Frank Clark and look to have run into form at the right time of the season for a successful cup run.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
