<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="333439" id="root" date="1997-01-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Thousands march in Bulgaria, talks deadlocked.</title>
<headline>Thousands march in Bulgaria, talks deadlocked.</headline>
<byline>Liliana Semerdjieva</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-01-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of protesters marched through the Bulgarian capital on Sunday to demand a general election but the ex-communist Socialist party repeated its insistence on forming a new cabinet.</p>
<p>Whole families with dogs and children took to the streets, booing and whistling as they passed the cabinet building.</p>
<p>Bulgarian students protesting at economic hardship staged a mock emigration to western Europe, and the main opposition trade union Podkrepa called for strikes from Monday.</p>
<p>Students wearing signs saying &quot;I'm emigrating, I see no alternative here&quot; and &quot;I'm emigrating to Albania without luggage&quot; passed through a mock border checkpoint flying the flags of Bulgaria and the European Union, set up at the mausoleum of Bulgarian communist hero Georgi Dimitrov.</p>
<p>&quot;Let them go, they had enough time to show their incompetence. We want to live here and will protest until we win,&quot; said student protester Svetla Slavova.</p>
<p>Bulgarian Socialist Party (BSP) leader Georgi Parvanov said the party was insisting on forming a government under Interior Minister Nikolai Dobrev, unacceptable to the opposition who hold him responsible for clashes between police and demonstrators outside parliament on the night of January 10.</p>
<p>&quot;For us there is no question of giving up the nomination of Nikolai Dobrev,&quot; Parvanov said.</p>
<p>Despite 21 consecutive days of street protests, the Socialists kept to their insistence on forming a broad-based cabinet of technocrats, which President Petar Stoyanov has said is unlikely to win public confidence.</p>
<p>&quot;The BSP is trying to ignore the protests...insisting it is able to form a government, calling it an experts' cabinet. We know that this government will be a government of the mafia,&quot; opposition leader Ivan Kostov told the crowd.</p>
<p>The constitution requires Stoyanov, who took office on Wednesday, to ask the Socialists as the biggest party in parliament to form a government.</p>
<p>Stoyanov met political leaders separately on Sunday and mediation efforts were expected to continue on Monday.</p>
<p>The opposition wants immediate elections, while the Socialists have proposed polls by the end of 1997 -- a year ahead of schedule.</p>
<p>Before and after the main news, state television journalists protesting against censorship put up a sign saying &quot;Warning, protest action&quot; and played the Beatles song &quot;Let it be&quot;, a song used by anti-communist protesters in 1990.</p>
<p>Economists said last week Bulgaria's economy had plunged into hyper-inflation for the first time, with price rises in January expected to hit 50 percent per month.</p>
<p>The central bank warned that it alone could not contain the crisis and lifted administrative controls on interest rates from Monday, which economists say will boost inflation.</p>
<p>Bulgaria urgently needs a credible government to negotiate a new accord with the International Monetary Fund, which has suspended disbursements because the Socialist government failed to implement the last reform programme.</p>
<p>The national currency, the lev, dipped to new lows of 920-930 to the dollar on expectations of further political instability and the central bank fixed the currency at 813.87 for Monday, down on Friday's 731.71.</p>
<p>Shops have closed down as prices change within hours and impoverished consumers are buying only basic foods.</p>
<p>&quot;I will keep my shop open until I sell the kitchen equipment I have already imported and then I will probably close the shop,&quot; said Ivo Milanov, an owner of a small store selling electrical appliances in central Sofia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
