<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="333628" id="root" date="1997-01-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Disney Comcast to buy E! stake.</title>
<headline>Disney Comcast to buy E! stake.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-01-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Walt Disney Co. is teaming with Comcast Corp to buy Time Warner Inc.'s majority stake in E! Entertainment Television cable network for $320 million, Daily Variety newspaper reported in its Monday editions.</p>
<p>The entertainment industry newspaper quoted sources as saying the deal was signed Thursday and may be announced as early as this week.</p>
<p>Disney is expected to provide the bulk of the cash to buy Time Warner out. However, the partnership structure will leave Comcast and its programming arm C3 -- which already owns 10.4 percent of E! -- in control of the network.</p>
<p>Spokesmen for Comcast, Time Warner or Disney could not be reached for comment late Sunday.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the deal, it is expected that C3 will control 51 percent of the 70 percent majority stake, with Disney controlling 49 percent.</p>
<p>C3 Chief Executive Rich Frank, a former Disney senior executive, will oversee the cable network for the partnership.</p>
<p>The boards of Comcast and Disney will formally approve the deal Monday, Variety quoted sources as saying. Comcast will tell Time Warner of its intention to buy the stake formally in early February and the deal will close 30 days after that.</p>
<p>No major plans or shake-ups are said to be in the works for E!. The network, which is headed by Lee Masters, has 42 million subscribers and made a profit last year.</p>
<p>The other cable partners in the network -- Cox Communications Inc. ; U S West Communications Group's Continental Cablevision and Tele-Communications Inc.'s Liberty Media -- will remain for the present.</p>
<p>&quot;Although Disney is putting up the majority of the money for the Time Warner stake, it is understood that there are provisions in the agreement that call for Comcast to pay Disney back over time for its 51 percent stake,&quot; Variety said.</p>
<p>E! went up for sale last year after Comcast triggered a buy-sell provision in the ownership partnership. Comcast wanted a partner for the deal to reduce the cost.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
