<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="333610" id="root" date="1997-01-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel's Sharon has plan to thwart PLO state.</title>
<headline>Israel's Sharon has plan to thwart PLO state.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-01-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli Infrastructure Minister Ariel Sharon said on Sunday if the PLO unilaterally declared an independent state Israel should immediately annex the land such a state would claim as its own.</p>
<p>&quot;If (the PLO) declares a Palestinian state, Israel (should) immediately annex all these areas,&quot; Sharon said in broadcast remarks.</p>
<p>Sharon, staunch supporter of Jewish settlement of the occupied West Bank and Gaza Strip, parts of which are now under PLO rule, has been sidelined by Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu during recent negotiations with the PLO.</p>
<p>But Netanyahu, in reaction to Palestinian President Yasser Arafat's recent declarations he will eventually unilaterally declare an independent state, has also warned he would take severe action against the move which he says would violate peace deals.</p>
<p>Netanyahu has not elaborated on what the action would be other than to say he has a plan &quot;in the drawer&quot;.</p>
<p>Since Israel's handover of 80 percent of the West Bank town of Hebron to Palestinian rule more than a week ago, Arafat, in defiance of Israel, has stepped up statements that he will declare a Palestinian state.</p>
<p>The Authority now controls most of the Gaza Strip and eight West Bank towns handed over by Israel under several agreements signed since 1993. Israel retains control of parts of the West Bank and Gaza known as area C which includes Jewish settlements and military bases.</p>
<p>The final status of the West Bank and Gaza Strip, which Israel captured in the 1967 Middle East war, is to be determined in negotiations ending no later than May 1999.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
