<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="333657" id="root" date="1997-01-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spanish villagers hurl goat from tower at fiesta.</title>
<headline>Spanish villagers hurl goat from tower at fiesta.</headline>
<byline>Merissa Marr</byline>
<dateline>MANGANESES DE LA POLVOROSA, Spain 1997-01-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Residents of a northern Spanish village defied protests from animal rights activists and hurled a goat from the top of a church tower on Saturday in an annual ritual to honour their patron saint.</p>
<p>Amid cheers and heckling, young villagers paraded the goat through the streets before taking it to the church and throwing it out of the belfry as part of the &quot;Jump of the Goat&quot; fiesta.</p>
<p>Hundreds of people, many in fancy dress, poured into the central square to take part in the revelry and witness the ritual.</p>
<p>The goat emerged better off than some of its predecessors and survived the fall, caught in a canvas sheet held open by villagers below.</p>
<p>Animal rights activists were still horrified at the ritual in the remote village of 1,000 people.</p>
<p>&quot;The village doesn't have a permit to do this but even if the local government says no, the locals still go ahead,&quot; said Eva Vallejo, a spokeswoman for the National Association for the Defence of Animals.</p>
<p>The ritual was officially banned in 1992 by the governor of Zamora province, but villagers reacted so violently when police attempted to stop it that the authorities were forced to rethink the ban.</p>
<p>Animal protection groups celebrated a minor success when villagers later agreed to a compromise and carried out a &quot;goat-lowering&quot; ceremony, easing the animal down on a rope.</p>
<p>But on Saturday, villagers brushed that aside and tossed the animal the full 50 feet (15 metres) from the belfry.</p>
<p>Some animal activists say they have seen goats fall to their death on a number of occasions when they have missed the canvas sheet held out below.</p>
<p>The village's new mayor Demetrio Prieto firmly denied this and said throwing the goat out of the belfry instead of lowering it was less cruel.</p>
<p>&quot;We throw the goat because it's better for the animal...it suffers less and spends less time in the air,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Villagers also defended the ritual. &quot;No one is going to take this tradition away from us,&quot; said Maria Jose Veleda.</p>
<p>Although stories differ, some villagers said the ritual dated back to the 19th century when goats sneaked into the church tower to eat food left out for doves. Legend has it that when the priest shooed them away, the goats would jump out of the belfry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANGANESES DE LA POLVOROSA, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
