<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="333733" id="root" date="1997-01-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbian economy in decline after Balkan turmoil.</title>
<headline>Serbian economy in decline after Balkan turmoil.</headline>
<byline>Michael Roddy</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE, Yugoslavia</dateline>
<text>
<p>The sprawling IMT tractor factory in Yugoslavia once produced 40,000 tractors a year and exported to more than 100 countries. Now it makes at best 4,000 and sells mainly to former Yugoslav republics .</p>
<p>&quot;I won't go into all the details, but because of everything that happened we are now producing at less than 10 percent of capacity,&quot; said acting manager Vidan Dokovic.</p>
<p>The &quot;everything that happened&quot; in Yugoslavia included the bloody breakup of the federal republic, international sanctions imposed from 1992 to 1996 and a standoff, now in its third month, between Serbia's Socialist President Slobodan Milosevic and the opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition over annulment of Zajedno victories in November municipal elections.</p>
<p>The standoff has brought stern warnings from the West and veiled hints that sanctions could be employed again if Milosevic does not give way.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the saddest things for a manager is to see the machinery and hear everything quiet,&quot; Dokovic said as he led a reporter on a tour of his plant, deserted after the one shift by 4,000 workers of what used to be a 6,500-man work force.</p>
<p>&quot;You don't know how many millions of dollars of machinery are just sitting there, doing nothing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Economists say the problems in Yugoslavia, now comprising Serbia and tiny Montenegro, run deeper than anything caused by wars, sanctions or the political impasse.</p>
<p>&quot;Our economy is in deep crisis and there are so many problems,&quot; said Aleksandra Posarac, economist at the Institute of Economic Sciences and an adviser to Vesna Pesic, head of the Civic Alliance party and a Zajedno co-leader.</p>
<p>&quot;Industry is working at 40 percent (of capacity) ... and many branches work at 10 percent,&quot; she said, adding that per capita income had plunged from $3,000 in 1990 to about $1,500.</p>
<p>The government says 2.1 million people are employed, but independent institutes put the number at 700,000 to 800,000.</p>
<p>Strikes are frequent, those who are working often are paid less than full wages, and some factories skip paychecks, among them IMT, which missed four of 12 months last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The problems were all there before the sanctions, but when the sanctions were imposed, the immediate effect in three months was a 30 percent drop in industrial production,&quot; Posarac said.</p>
<p>&quot;It made all foreign trade illegal, more or less, so we were selling cheap and buying dear.&quot;</p>
<p>It amounts to a huge comedown for Yugoslavia, which as a communist but non-aligned nation under the late Marshal Tito, had perhaps the most liberal economy in Eastern Europe and granted state enterprises a fair amount of autonomy.</p>
<p>Yugo cars produced by Zastava were sold in the United States, which also bought tractors from IMT, once the biggest tractor producer in Eastern Europe outside the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>While other former Communist bloc countries such as Hungary, Poland and Czechoslovakia adopted free-market reforms when communism collapsed, Serbia stuck to a mixed socialist economy under Milosevic, and went into decline.</p>
<p>The Serbian government has issued statements saying it intends to privatise government-owned businesses, but so far has done little, economists say, although Montenegro has gone ahead with reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;You cannot privatise overnight, you cannot restructure in a year. This process will probably take at least five or 10 years, but we need to start as soon as possible,&quot; said Zoran Popov, an economist at the Economics Institute, which is considered to have close links to the government.</p>
<p>&quot;But you see, if the government or the party is to prepare a decent and honest privatisation and restructuring programme I think it would be suicide for this party,&quot; Popov said.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to tell, say, 400,000 people employed in the metals sector that for half of them there are no prospects.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists said many company directors are ministers or high-level Socialists who owe their jobs to party patronage.</p>
<p>Dokovic, who has been acting manager at IMT for only a month, said he is trying to strike deals with foreign buyers.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a question of politics. What I am interested in is the factory itself and the 4,000 people who work in it.&quot;</p>
<p>Posarac and other economists think that Yugoslavia's industry-oriented economy has largely been outstripped by competitors. A massive readjustment is in order.</p>
<p>&quot;Who's going to buy these tractors?&quot; she asked. &quot;The peasants haven't got the money and I really don't know about exports because there are cheaper and better tractors around.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE, Yugoslavia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
