<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="333879" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries end lower before wage inflation data.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries end lower before wage inflation data.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prices of U.S. government securities ended lower for the fourth straight session on Monday, as market players worried a key U.S. labor cost gauge due Tuesday would show inflation clouds gathering.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been down four days in a row, mainly on more anxiety ahead of the Tuesday number,&quot; said Josh Stiles, senior bond strategist at I.D.E.A., referring to the government's fourth-quarter Employment Cost Index (ECI) that financial markets have been awaiting.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're down in anticipation of higher employment costs and strong fourth-quarter GDP (Gross Domestic Product),&quot; said Chase Securities chief economist Charles Lieberman. &quot;People are adjusting their positions to hedge against those risks.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters predicted, on average, that the fourth-quarter ECI would be up 0.9 percent after a more-moderate-than-expected 0.6-percent third-quarter gain.</p>
<p>The so-called advance fourth-quarter GDP estimate, due on Friday, will be up 3.9 percent, according to the Reuters poll.</p>
<p>The 6-1/2-percent 30-year benchmark Treasury bond ended at 94-14/32, down 21/32, on Monday.  </p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond closing yield of 6.94 percent was the highest since September 24, when it ended at 6.99 percent.</p>
<p>Besides the pervasive anxiety about the Employment Cost Index, a break below support at 109-26 on the March T-bond futures contract triggered selling, participants said. Also, heavy corporate issuance weighed on the debt markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Important technical support was pierced, there was a lot of corporate issuance today and a lot more is coming and some longs finally gave up,&quot; said Carey Leahey, senior vice president at Lehman Government Securities Inc.  </p>
<p>A Tenet Health Care Corp $2.0 billion high-yield bond issue, the unloading of mortgage-backed securities by NationsBank Corp and the need to distribute the two- and five-year notes that the Treasury sold last week all weighed on a market where sellers had to look hard for players willing to buy before Tuesday's ECI report, strategists said.</p>
<p>&quot;People are contending with supply and asking themselves (at what price) do we want to own these,&quot; said Stiles.</p>
<p>Nervousness was also present in the stock market, where the Dow Jones Industrial Average fell for the fourth day in a row, off 35.79 points to 6660.69.  </p>
<p>In the stock market, analysts talked of the increased competition to stocks posed by bonds offering yields of nearly seven percent.</p>
<p>In the bond market, participants said a fourth-quarter ECI rise of 1.0 percent or higher could easily push the 30-year bond yield above seven percent. But they also said falling prices and rising yields in the bond market had largely discounted the consensus ECI forecast of up 0.9 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;To see more selling, you'd have to see a sizable ECI increase,&quot; said Kevin Flanagan, first vice president and money market economist at Dean Witter Reynolds.  </p>
<p>&quot;Otherwise, you'll hear people talking that we're oversold right now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The market also could not get a boost from a fall in December existing home sales to an annualized rate of 3.87 million from a revised annualized rate of 4.01 million in November.</p>
<p>&quot;The bullish impact was undermined because the inventory of unsold homes plunged to 5.1 months from 6.7 months and the year-over-year median home price rose 4.3 percent,&quot; said Stiles.</p>
<p>At the short end of the maturity curve, the three-month Treasury bill rate closed up two basis points at 5.05 percent. Six-month and year-bill rates rose three basis points each to 5.16 percent and 5.33 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>Two-year notes closed down 3/32 at 99-18/32, yielding 6.11 percent. In the intermediate sector, the five-year note traded off 7/32 at 99-6/32 to yield 6.44 percent. The ten-year note closed down 11/32 at 99-24/32, yielding 6.68 percent.</p>
<p>(( -- North American Treasury Desk 212-859-1679 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
