<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="333976" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Most IMM currencies end down, but up from lows.</title>
<headline>Most IMM currencies end down, but up from lows.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>IMM currency futures ended mostly lower amid technical weakness as the dollar kept its eye on upside targets.</p>
<p>Talk of comments from Swiss Finance Minister Kaspar Villiger that he was &quot;relieved&quot; by weakness in the Swiss franc spawned a wave of selling in March Swiss francs near midday. March marks slid to a fresh contract low at $0.6079, in sympathy with the troubled Swiss unit.</p>
<p>Traders said marks were also plagued by continuing worries about Russian President Boris Yeltsin's health. Yeltsin has canceled a trip to the Netherlands next week.  </p>
<p>Early in the day, there were perceptions that a threat of central bank intervention looms at key dollar resistance. That notion initially kept key currencies underpinned.</p>
<p>But dollar bullishness persisted, and traders eyed dollar targets in marks at 1.65, and 120.00 to 125.00 in yen.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a strong dollar close and everything is in place for the dollar to go higher,&quot; one IMM futures analyst said.</p>
<p>He said the dollar was not affected by losses in stock and bonds because bullish dollar momentum was too powerful. Others said stock losses and weak T-bonds underpinned currencies late and helped them close up from their session lows.  </p>
<p>An IMM trader said Swiss francs led the dim currency tone and called the franc's decline &quot;a silent downmove.&quot; She said volume overall was only light to moderate in Swiss francs. Support in Swiss francs was now at $0.7002, the contract low set Jan 22, other traders said.</p>
<p>Many said they were focusing on key U.S. labor cost data on Tuesday, when the fourth quarter employment cost index (ECI) will be released. Economists polled by Reuters, on average, forecast an 0.9 percent rise in ECI.</p>
<p>Some traders said hints of escalating U.S. wage costs could prompt the Federal Reserve to tighten credit.  </p>
<p>March Canadian dollars posted slight gains and closed above support at $0.7450 after struggling earlier in the day. Some traders said Canadian dollar upside momentum was faltering, but others said good support remains below the market. They put floors at $0.7444 and $0.7425.</p>
<p>March Australian dollar also eked out gains, closing up slightly after testing its contract low at $0.7700 for a third consecutive session. Technicians said that triple bottom formation should kep the market underpinned for now.  </p>
<p>At settlement, March yen fell $0.000038 to $0.008427, marks fell $0.0060 to $0.6096, Swiss francs lost $0.0103 to $0.7037, sterling eased $0.0032 to $1.6230, Canadian dollar rose $0.0026 to $0.7464, Aussie dollar rose $0.0013 to $0.7726, Mexican peso fell $0.000375 to $0.124450. ((DerivativesDesk(312)408-8750/E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
