<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="334115" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-ENGLISH/SCOTTISH FIXTURES FOR JANUARY 31 TO FEBRUARY 2.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ENGLISH/SCOTTISH FIXTURES FOR JANUARY 31 TO FEBRUARY 2.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>English and Scottish soccer</p>
<p>fixtures for January 31 to February 2</p>
<p>Friday, January 31:</p>
<p>English division three - Colchester v Torquay, Fulham v</p>
<p>Cardiff, Swansea v Cambridge.</p>
<p>Saturday, February 1:</p>
<p>English premier league - Aston Villa v Sunderland, Blackburn</p>
<p>v West Ham, Derby v Liverpool, Everton v Nottingham Forest,</p>
<p>Leeds v Arsenal, Manchedster United v Southampton, Sheffield</p>
<p>Wednesday v Coventry, Tottenham v Chelsea, Wimbledon v</p>
<p>Middlesbrough.</p>
<p>English division one - Bolton v Birmingham, Bradford v</p>
<p>Huddersfield, Grimsby v Charlton, Norwich v Barnsley, Port Vale</p>
<p>v West Bromwich, Portsmouth v Oldham, Queens Park Rangers v</p>
<p>Crystal Palace, Southend v Ipswich, Swindon v Sheffield United,</p>
<p>Tranmere v Reading, Wolverhampton v Stoke.</p>
<p>English division two - Bournemouth v Blackpool, Bristol</p>
<p>Rovers v Shrewsbury, Crewe v Burnley, Millwall v Bristol City,</p>
<p>Notts County v Luton, Peterborough v Walsall, Plymouth v</p>
<p>Wycombe, Preston v Chesterfield, Stockport v Brentford, Watford</p>
<p>v Rotherham, Wrexham v Gillingham, York v Bury.</p>
<p>English division three - Carlisle v Northampton, Darlington</p>
<p>v Lincoln, Doncaster v Scunthorpe, Hartlepool v Scarborough,</p>
<p>Hereford v Wigan, Hull v Chester, Leyton Orient v Exeter,</p>
<p>Mansfield v Brighton, Rochdale v Barnet.</p>
<p>Scottish premier division - Aberdeen v Kilmarnock, Dundee</p>
<p>United v Celtic, Dunfermline v Motherwell, Hibernian v Raith,</p>
<p>Rangers v Hearts.</p>
<p>Scottish division one - Clydebank v Airdrieonians, Falkirk v</p>
<p>Dundee, Partick v East Fife, St Johnstone v Greenock Morton, St</p>
<p>Mirren v Stirling.</p>
<p>Scottish division two - Ayr v Livingston, Berwick v</p>
<p>Stranraer, Clyde v Stenhousemuir, Hamilton v Dumbarton, Queen of</p>
<p>the South v Brechin.</p>
<p>Scottish division three - Alloa v Forfar, Arbroath v Queen's</p>
<p>Park, Cowdenbeath v East Stirling, Montrose v Inverness, Ross</p>
<p>County v Albion.</p>
<p>Sunday, February 2:</p>
<p>English premier league - Newcastle v Leicester.</p>
<p>English division one - Oxford v Manchester City.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
