<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="334150" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-PACKERS ARE SUPER BOWL CHAMPIONS AGAIN.</title>
<headline>NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-PACKERS ARE SUPER BOWL CHAMPIONS AGAIN.</headline>
<byline>Bill Berkrot</byline>
<dateline>NEW ORLEANS 1997-01-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Somewhere Vince Lombardi is smiling -- the Green Bay Packers are Super Bowl champions again.</p>
<p>Twenty-nine years after the Lombardi-coached Packers won the last of three consecutive National Football League championships, the sport's most fabled franchise is back on top as Green Bay beat the New England Patriots 35-21 to win Super Bowl XXXI on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the Vince Lombardi trophy, so it's going back home,&quot; said ecstatic Packers receiver Antonio Freeman, who caught the longest touchdown pass in Super Bowl history -- an 81-yard bomb from Green Bay quarterback Brett Favre.</p>
<p>Favre threw two touchdown passes and ran for another to complete a brilliant season in which he was named the league's Most Valuable Player.</p>
<p>But the game's MVP honours went to return specialist Desmond Howard, the former Heisman Trophy winner who became the first special teams player to be named Super Bowl MVP.</p>
<p>Howard had a record-setting day, including a spectacular 99-yard kick return for a touchdown late in the third quarter just when it appeared the Patriots had gotten back into the game.</p>
<p>&quot;He's a great guy, he's rejuvenated his career. That return was unbelievable,&quot; said Favre, who completed 14 of 27 passes for 246 yards and did not throw an interception.</p>
<p>Howard returned four kicks for 154 yards and six punts for a Super Bowl record 90 yards more, a total of 244-return yards -- also a record.</p>
<p>The 99-yard kick return was the longest in NFL post-season history.</p>
<p>And his first punt return of the game, a 32-yarder, put Green Bay in excellent position to score its first touchdown -- a 54-yard pass by Favre to Andre Rison.</p>
<p>&quot;I was so excited when it worked out just the way we practiced it,&quot; said Favre. &quot;It hasn't really hit us yet that we're Super Bowl champions.&quot;</p>
<p>The victory marked the 13th consecutive win for the National Football Conference team in the Super Bowl. It was also the first title for several veteran players, most notably future Hall of Fame defensive end Reggie White, who sacked New England quarterback Drew Bledsoe three times.</p>
<p>&quot;Now I can sit back with my son for years and watch the highlights of this Super Bowl and he can see daddy getting three sacks,&quot; beamed the 12-year veteran.</p>
<p>&quot;Today God was a Green Bay Packer,&quot; said White, an ordained minister.</p>
<p>&quot;When I come down from the high I'm on, maybe I'll realise what I did.&quot;  </p>
<p>:	</p>
<p>&quot;I'm really humbled by this experience. This is the greatest group of players I've ever been around,&quot; said emotional Green Bay coach Mike Holmgren.</p>
<p>The defeat cost New England's Bill Parcells a chance to become the first coach to win Super Bowls with two different teams. He won twice with the New York Giants.</p>
<p>&quot;No one could be more disappointed than I am because I do think we had a chance there for a moment,&quot; said Parcells, who is widely expected to leave the Patriots for another coaching job next season.</p>
<p>&quot;You never know when this opportunity is going to come again, so I'm grateful I had the chance to be here,&quot; Parcells said.</p>
<p>Conventional wisdom that says a team must establish a ball-control running game to win a championship went out the window almost immediately as Favre and Bledsoe took to the air early and often in a classic quarterback duel in the first half.</p>
<p>Bledsoe was red-hot in the first quarter, completing 8-of-15 passes for 123 yards and two touchdowns, the second putting New England ahead 14-10.</p>
<p>But Bledsoe finished with four interceptions, and those turnovers, combined with Howard's heroics, did in the Patriots.</p>
<p>&quot;The Packers made more big plays than we did...and they basically played a mistake-free football game,&quot; said Bledsoe. &quot;My hat's off to them.&quot;</p>
<p>The Packers seized the early momentum on Green Bay's second play from scrimmage as Favre found Rison streaking past defender Otis Smith and delivered a perfect touchdown pass. Rison was so far ahead of Smith that he slowed to high-step into the end zone.</p>
<p>Bledsoe's first interception, when Doug Evans stepped in front of Patriots receiver Terry Glenn for the pickoff, led to a 37-yard Chris Jacke field goal and a 10-0 Green Bay lead.</p>
<p>But Bledsoe then went to work, moving his team up the field, and a pass interference penalty by Green Bay's Craig Newsome put the ball on the 1-yard-line.</p>
<p>On the next play, Bledsoe found Keith Byars in the back of the end zone and the Patriots were on the scoreboard, trailing 10-7.</p>
<p>On their next possession, Bledsoe connected with Glenn on a 44-yard pass to the Green Bay 4, and followed it with a touchdown pass to tight end Ben Coates for a 14-10 New England lead with two and a half minutes to go in the first quarter.</p>
<p>The lead held up until the first minute of the second quarter when Favre opened a Green Bay drive with his 81-yard bomb to a streaking Freeman for a 17-14 advantage. The Packers never trailed again.</p>
<p>A 32-yard Jacke field goal with 8:15 left in the half increased Green Bay's lead to 20-14 and the Packers added another touchdown before the half was over.</p>
<p>Green Bay made it 27-14 with 1:11 left in the half when Favre capped a nine-play, 74-yard drive by scrambling for a touchdown from the 2-yard line.</p>
<p>The shootout mentality calmed down in the second half as both teams' defences began asserting themselves.</p>
<p>But the Patriots made another run at the title late in the third quarter.</p>
<p>Bledsoe directed an eight-play, 53-yard scoring drive as Curtis Martin barrelled 18 yards through the middle of the Green Bay defence for a touchdown that brought New England within 27-21 with 3:27 left in the quarter.</p>
<p>But the New England euphoria was short-lived as Howard took the Adam Vinatieri kickoff and galloped away on his historic run that put a spike through the hearts of Patriot fans.</p>
<p>The Patriots never really recovered from the shock of surrendering the touchdown and a two-point conversion that put them 14 points in a hole so soon after closing the gap to realistic striking distance.</p>
<p>&quot;I think what really deflated them was Desmond,&quot; White said. &quot;When he ran that touchdown back that really deflated them.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW ORLEANS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
