<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="334201" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: SLOVAK C.BANK SETS TWO REV REPO TENDERS FOR MONDAY.</title>
<headline>SLOVAK C.BANK SETS TWO REV REPO TENDERS FOR MONDAY.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Bank of Slovakia (NBS) on Monday said it had set two securities reverse repurchase tenders for 10 a.m. (0900 GMT), offering to sterilise an unspecified volume of market liquidity.</p>
<p>The NBS said the operations would consist of a one-day reverse repo tender, as well as a three-day reverse repo tender.</p>
<p>&quot;To stress our liquidity sterilisation effort, we decided to hold two tenders on Monday,&quot; Peter Andresic, head of the NBS Open Market Operations Department, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;On Friday, the banking sector minimum reserve demands had been overfulfilled for the first time this year, for the time being we will react to it in this way,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>According to official NBS figures, the Slovak banking sector has a liquidity surplus, with banks' minimum reserve demands fulfilled at 102.6 percent as of Sunday, after being at 99.72 percent the previous day.</p>
<p>The NBS said in a statement that the American-style tenders would have no fixed minimum rate.</p>
<p>A week ago, Slovak interbank money market rates rose sharply due to a liquidity crunch, attracting some $150-200 million in foreign short-term capital, the bulk of which is currently deposited on the market.</p>
<p>The NBS holds tenders on a daily basis, if needed, instead of quoting securities repo and reverse repo rates.</p>
<p>However, the NBS said the move was rather meant to serve as a limited refinancing option, aimed at curbing the country's loan expansion by reducing refinancing volumes.</p>
<p>-- Tatiana Vacova, Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-563-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
