<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="334357" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Rainbow flies on hopes for local chickens.</title>
<headline>Rainbow flies on hopes for local chickens.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Rainbow Chicken flew higher on Monday, stirred by talk there could be a turnaround in the local chicken industry, dealers said.</p>
<p>They added that Rainbow had been hit hard recently and that hopes for the industry could have triggered some speculation with a number of players taking up positions.</p>
<p>By 1027 GMT on the Johannesburg Stock Exchange the share had added 16 cents to 124 cents after earlier touching a day's high of 130 cents a share. About 355,000 shares had changed hands.  </p>
<p>&quot;There is talk of a turnaround in the (local) chicken industry. Rainbow was hard hit previously by cheaper imports and chicken disease here,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>But she added that it was unlikely the South African chicken industry could compete with the lower cost of imported chickens and therefore Rainbow's recovery would be shortlived.</p>
<p>&quot;It could soon start to look a tad overdone. It could steady a bit and then head lower. This is more than likely as the hopes for the industry are likely to be shortlived,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Rainbow, hit by rising feed costs and fierce competition, recorded an attributable loss of 159.8 million rand in the year to end-March on sales of 1.88 billion rand.</p>
<p>Last August 16 it hit a record low of 63 cents.</p>
<p>Dealers said that a recovery in the stock had been expected for some time now and, in addition to hopes for the industry, the appointment of a new managing director may have started to impact positively on the share.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been expected for a while now. Rainbow had a very tough time. The new managing director might be having an effect. Shareholders might have high hopes for him to turn it around,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems like it's mostly speculators taking positions.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Melanie Cheary, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41230">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
