<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="334346" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FOCUS-South Africa rand swept to two-month high.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-South Africa rand swept to two-month high.</headline>
<byline>Paul Richardson</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The South African rand's new year bull run continued apace on Monday as the relentless flow of dollars into the market swept the currency to its strongest level against the dollar in two months.</p>
<p>The rand touched an intraday high of 4.5890 against the dollar -- a level last seen on November 29, 1996 -- and analysts said the currency looked set to recapture further lost ground in the short term.</p>
<p>Traders have pinned the rand's rally to a continuing inflow of dollars into the market by local and foreign speculators as well as local exporters.</p>
<p>&quot;It's becoming pass the parcel with dollars,&quot; said one currency trader. &quot;As it (the rand) goes lower more dollars are coming out of the woodwork...exporters panicking or stop losses being triggered.&quot;</p>
<p>A rallying bond market, where long bond yields have fallen more than 80 basis points since the beginning of the year, has also contributed to the bullish mood with foreigners already having bought 1.4 billion rand's ($304 million) worth of bonds this month.</p>
<p>That compares with net foreign purchases in the whole of 1996 of 3.38 billion rand.</p>
<p>&quot;The foreigners are looking for markets that are moving contra to their own and given what happened in our markets last year, we are a prime candidate for that,&quot; Chris Doyle, assistant general manager at UAL Merchant Bank Treasury said.</p>
<p>While U.S. and European interest rates are expected to rise this year, local economists have predicted as many as three one-point interest rate cuts in South Africa.</p>
<p>Currency analysts said the optimism on the rand stemmed from a raft of factors ranging from expectations that government will make substantial progress this year on objectives set out in its macro-economic plan to signs of an improvement in the country's balance of payments.</p>
<p>On Monday sentiment was bolstered further by a report by the Union Bank of Switzerland (UBS) which predicted the rand would strengthen sharply this year.</p>
<p>A report by UBS a year ago stating that the rand was overvalued was cited at the time as one of the triggers for the rand's 30 percent devaluation against the dollar last year.</p>
<p>In its latest report, UBS said that the present rise in the country's trade surplus suggested the rand would appreciate strongly during 1997 after taking account of inflation differentials.</p>
<p>It noted that in the 10 months since the rand's devaluation in February last year, the trade surplus had risen to 10.046 billion rand from 264 million rand in the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>A lower import bill is expected to help reduce South Africa's current account deficit, which Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals told Reuters last week he expected to improve to 4.0-5.0 billion rand from around 10 billion rand in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;On the basis of the rising trade surplus and the real interest rates, we continue to forecast dollar/rand at 4.8500 at year-end,&quot; UBS said.</p>
<p>That is well below the end-1997 rate indicated by the forward foreign exchange rate of 5.09, and would represent a real appreciation of the rand given that the inflation differential between South Africa and its major trading partners is seven to eight percent.</p>
<p>($=4.6 rand)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
