<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="334352" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Mauritius share index slightly up in mixed market.</title>
<headline>Mauritius share index slightly up in mixed market.</headline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mauritius stock exchange share index SEMDEX inched up on Monday by 0.33 points to 368.30 in a mixed market where stocks prices moved within narrow ranges, brokers said.</p>
<p>Volume was down at 13.6 million rupees on 526,293 shares from 35.3 million rupees on 1,595,421 shares on Friday.</p>
<p>Brokers said the small SEMDEX change on Monday reflected a lack of fresh factors.</p>
<p>&quot;Trading was very quiet today in that stable looking market. But this should not come as a big surprise after the rapid gains of the SEMDEX during the past two months,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Since the start of December, the SEMDEX rose by 42 points after having been depressed during most of last year's second semester on concerns about local politics, brokers said.</p>
<p>Most of Monday's transactions were in hotel stocks Sun Resorts and New Mauritius Hotels. Sun Resorts was unchanged at 40.10 rupees on 181,404 shares while New Mauritius Hotels eased by 10 cents to 32.40 rupees on 25,400 shares.</p>
<p>Mauritius Commercial Bank gained 50 cents to 84 on 3,882 shares and State Bank of Mauritius was stable at 11 rupees on 163,400 shares.</p>
<p>Conglomerates Rogers was unchanged at 96 rupees on 2,000 shares and Ireland Blyth edged up by 10 cents to 14.60 rupees on 2,725 shares.</p>
<p>Mauritius Oil Refineries remained at 10 rupees on 12,105 shares and building materials manufacturers United Basalt Products rose 60 cents to 38 rupees on 11,652 shares.</p>
<p>In the investment sector, United Docks was 70 cents higher to 45 rupees on 32,898 shares. Mauritius Development Investment Trust was 40 cents up to 9.30 rupees on 4,315 shares.</p>
<p>Commerce-based Courts lost 20 cents to 6.30 rupees on 7,704 shares and national carrier Air Mauritius fell by 30 cents to 46.20 rupees on 4,500 shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
