<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="334555" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Leading candidates in Chechen presidential vote. [CORRECTED 10:00 GMT]</title>
<headline>Leading candidates in Chechen presidential vote. [CORRECTED 10:00 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>GROZNY, Russia 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the leading candidates running for president in Monday's election in the breakaway Russian region of Chechnya:</p>
<p>SHAMIL BASAYEV, 32, a national hero in Chechnya, but a figure of hate in Moscow, made his name when he and his guerrilla fighters stormed the southern Russian town of Budennovsk in June 1995, taking more than 1,000 hostages.</p>
<p>The brash act forced Moscow to the negotiating table, but it took another two years for a final peace deal to be agreed.</p>
<p>Basayev's toughness and his promise to stamp out post-war crime has won him many backers, especially among young people. He has advocated public executions for serious crimes.</p>
<p>But some voters fear that electing such a controversial figure would hurt Chechnya's image in the outside world and damage relations with Moscow.</p>
<p>ASLAN MASKHADOV, 45, was chief commander of Chechnya's resistance army during the 21-month war with Russian soldiers sent to crush its independence bid.</p>
<p>He led peace negotiations that culminated in the full Russian withdrawal from Chechnya, leaving it a de facto independent state, although a final decision on its status has been postponed for five years.</p>
<p>Many in the Kremlin leadership see Maskhadov as the most pragmatic and acceptable of major Chechen political figures.</p>
<p>With a modest manner, Maskhadov kept a low profile during the campaign, making only one swing through the tiny republic. He does not have a published political programme.</p>
<p>MOVLADI UDUGOV, 34, is a longshot candidate who rose to fame when he served as information minister during the fighting and broadcast his message from mountain hideouts by satellite telephone.</p>
<p>The wily, slightly built Ududgov often defeated Russia's propaganda machine with his version of events. He was not always accurate, but he repeatedly beat Moscow to the punch.</p>
<p>His presidential campaign, the most professional of any of the candidates, stresses his devotion to &quot;Islamic Order.&quot;</p>
<p>His home life echoes his Moslem-oriented politics. He has two wives and is the only major presidential candidate to practice polygamy, as permitted by Moslem custom.</p>
<p>ZELIMKHAN YANDARBIYEV, 45, Chechnya's current leader and one of the region's best-known poets, was vice president to separatist president Dzhokhar Dudayev, but many observers say his chances of winning are slim.</p>
<p>He was one of the first Chechens to oppose Russian control openly, but he was not one of the more visible wartime figures, and this has hurt his current image.</p>
<p>Born in Kazakhstan, where the entire Chechen population was deported in 1944 by Soviet dictator Josef Stalin, he returned to Chechnya with his family after Stalin died.</p>
<p>Yandarbiyev has worked as a mason, assistant shepherd and as an oil-well driller. He has emphasised his adherence to Islamic principles and takes credit for setting up Koran-based Shariat courts.</p>
<p>Nine others (corrects from twelve others) are also contesting the January 27 presidential election, during which Chechen voters will also choose a 63-member parliament.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GROZNY, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
