<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="334799" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Ayala says only testing debt markets now.</title>
<headline>Ayala says only testing debt markets now.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ayala Corp of the Philippines, which has aggressively sought funds in international debt markets in the past year, said on Monday that it would have far greater capital needs in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;We're charting a new path and at the same time we are doing it at times when we don't really need the funds,&quot; company president Jaime Augusto Zobel de Ayala told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;We're trying to build a reputation up only because we see our capital needs growing quite substanitally over time. If ever we need to tap these markets in a more aggressive way, our presence will be known,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ayala Corp set a $100 million Euro-convertible bond earlier this month, a $90 million floating rate note issue in November and a $110 million straight Euro-bond in May.</p>
<p>Ayala said as the company bid for more infrastructure projects in the Philippines, its capital needs would grow. He forecast that the Philippines would need to invest about $50 billion in infrastructure in the next 10 years and that Ayala Corp, the country's oldest conglomerate, would like to be involved in strategic projects.</p>
<p>Ayala said raising capital in the Philippines was not the restrictive factor it used to be in past years.</p>
<p>The Philippines declared a moratorium on debt payments in 1983 and returned to international debt markets only a decade later.</p>
<p>But, buoyed by a growing economy, its sovereign debt has since been well received and Moody's Investors Service last week placed its foreign currency sovereign ceiling on bonds and papers on review for a possible upgrade from its current Ba2 rating.</p>
<p>Ayala said his company's strategy of building its reputation in debt markets and the fact that the country's rating was on an upswing would help in easily raising future capital needs.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8914</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
