<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="334746" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Prime says earnings fall due to write-off.</title>
<headline>Prime says earnings fall due to write-off.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Utilities Bhd said on Monday its pretax loss of 214 million ringgit in the six-month period to October 31, 1996, was due to a write-off by a key subsidiary.</p>
<p>Prime, which manages Malaysia's sewerage systems through its unit Indah Water Konsortium Sdn Bhd, posted pretax loss of 430,000 ringgit in the previous corresponding six-month period.</p>
<p>Prime said it expects its performance to improve with contributions from Indah Water from January 1 this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The exceptional loss for the current period is mainly attributed to the write-off by Indah Water Konsortium Sdn Bhd of its entire revenue in compliance with the Tariff Review exercise initiated by the government in May 1996,&quot; the company said in its earnings statement.</p>
<p>It said the government will provide Indah Water with an additional soft loan of 450 million ringgit and extend the company's concession period by 33 months due to its agreeing to revised sewerage charges.</p>
<p>Indah Water was granted the concession to take over the country's sewerage services in April 1994 but met with consumer complaints over its desludging methods and high charges, prompting a review of the charges.</p>
<p>&quot;With the resolution of the tariff charge rates and other post implementation problems being resolved, it is expected that contributions from (Indah Water0 will be normalised from January 1, 1997 onwards,&quot; Prime said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
