<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="334764" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Asian Metals - Zinc prices lure Chinese exports.</title>
<headline>Asian Metals - Zinc prices lure Chinese exports.</headline>
<byline>Lynne O'Donnell</byline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chinese zinc producers are expected to take advantage of high international prices to export, though  this may lead to a domestic supply squeeze and firmer prices at home, Far East metal traders said on Monday.</p>
<p>With London Metal Exchange (LME) zinc prices having risen by around $50 a tonne since the start of 1997 to the highest levels in nearly two years, Chinese producers are seen accelerating sales, they said.  </p>
<p>Three month LME zinc was little changed at $1,137/39 a tonne in early trade in London on Monday, after a kerb close of $1,139 on Friday. The market was seen consolidating after a blistering rise that peaked last week at $1,157.</p>
<p>Already this year, Torch Metal in Hong Kong, which sells on behalf of Chinese producers, has exported 30,000 tonnes of Chinese zinc to end-users &quot;because the price is right,&quot; a company source said by telephone from the British colony.  </p>
<p>None of this metal had gone to the LME warehouse in Singapore, he said, adding that Torch had a further 50,000 tonnes of zinc to sell in the course of 1997 and would not hesitate to take advantage of price rallies.</p>
<p>A Chinese trader in Beijing said one of the major smelters had sold between 20,000 to 30,000 tonnes of Chinese metal in late December at 9,800 yuan ($1,180) a tonne FOB (free on board) southern Chinese ports.</p>
<p>That metal was exported after the government wiped out the five percent zinc export tax on January 1, 1997, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;That zinc was sold before the rally, but it was still quite expensive,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A futures trader with a state Chinese firm in Singapore said Chinese producers who sold into the market before price rises could well deliver their metal to the LME to record a paper loss, but a healthy profit in the cash market.</p>
<p>&quot;They (producers) would only look at the premium picture,&quot; he said. &quot;If physical sells at a nice premium, they could sell their LME position, and sell physical based on LME prices plus a nice premium,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Sources in Asia said LME price levels over $1,150 a tonne would make Chinese exports worthwhile.</p>
<p>&quot;If the price goes up further, the quantity of (Chinese) exports will move up,&quot; a source in China said.</p>
<p>That echoed the view of a number of traders in China, Hong Kong and Singapore polled by Reuters.</p>
<p>Some said it could lead to another round of boom-bust trading that saw domestic Chinese zinc prices rise to 10,700 yuan ($1,289) a tonne, ex-smelter, two years ago.</p>
<p>The Beijing trader said China had 250,000 to 300,000 tonnes of zinc metal available for export this year.  </p>
<p>China exports around a quarter of its annual zinc output.</p>
<p>Official figures show 1996 exports of unwrought zinc and zinc alloys rose to 226,777 tonnes, over 1995's 191,526 tonnes. December 1996 exports alone were 29,519 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;We always believe Chinese metal will pressure the market,&quot; another Chinese source said. &quot;Most people will see a good chance in the price rises.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said that once Chinese zinc producers saw they could get attractive export prices for their product, they could desert their domestic customers.  </p>
<p>&quot;This will squeeze domestic supplies, then domestic prices will move up, then it makes more sense to keep the metal at home because the prices are better,&quot; he said. &quot;Here we go again.&quot;</p>
<p>The Beijing trader said special high grade zinc accounted for around 30,000 tonnes of Chinese exports so far this year, with the same quantity of high grade metal.</p>
<p>Up to 70 percent of the exports had gone to end users, he and other sources said, much of it to Japan.  </p>
<p>Under its General System of Preferences (GSP) programme, Japan exempts metal imports from developing countries submitted for customs clearance before the April 1 start of the fiscal year.</p>
<p>The latest Hong Kong indications of premium or discount in US$/tonne over LME cash prices on a CIF basis:</p>
<p>				Jan 27		  Jan 20</p>
<p>COPPER			 70			70-100</p>
<p>ALUMINIUM (Western)     100-105		 100</p>
<p>	    (CIS)	    75			75</p>
<p>LEAD			  100		     120-130</p>
<p>ZINC (Chinese)	     50			N/A</p>
<p>     (Western alloys)   100-120		  N/A</p>
<p>($1=8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
