<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="334923" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US CREDIT OUTLOOK - Wage report to dominate bond mkt.</title>
<headline>US CREDIT OUTLOOK - Wage report to dominate bond mkt.</headline>
<byline>John P. Hughes</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The much-awaited fourth quarter Employment Cost Index was expected to be dominant on the minds of bond traders Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Labor Department was scheduled to release the data at 830 EST/1330 GMT. Consensus estimates had the index increasing by 0.9 percent, but should it come in stronger than 1.0 percent, analysts warned it could spark a sharp sell-off of Treasuries. Many traders were betting that a stronger-than- expected reading would prompt the Federal Reserve to tighten monetary policy as soon as its February meeting.  </p>
<p>Likewise, economists said an as-expected reading would allow the policy-making Federal Open Market Committee to remain on hold at least until its March 25 meeting.</p>
<p>Thomas Pearl, managing director at Chase Securities Inc, looked for a huge amount of price volatility beginning with the ECI's release Tuesday morning and culminating in fourth quarter GDP on Friday. In between, Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan was slated to testify before the Senate Finance Committee on Thursday and durable goods were due Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We could see incredible volatility this week. There was a lot of selling ahead of this (ECI) number,&quot; Pearl said.  </p>
<p>Pearl expected to see an exaggerated movement when ECI hit traders' screens Tuesday morning. The ECI will be the pivotal number for bond market participants and Greenspan's possible reaction to the reading when he testifies before the Senate on Thursday will be crucial.</p>
<p>&quot;If the number's strong and he says he's worried about it, the market will back off. If he downplays high numbers, the market will rally,&quot; Pearl said. The ECI is seen as the best gauge of employment costs as it includes the cost of benefits, which comprise about 29 percent of the index. And wages account for two-thirds of producer prices.  </p>
<p>Pearl said an increase of 0.8 percent had probably been factored into the market and some bullish observers even called for growth of 1.0 percent to 1.2 percent in the ECI.</p>
<p>&quot;People have been microanalyzing and dissecting the number to death. But, essentially, if we get a strong gain it probably solidifies another Fed tightening, but probably not in February,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A.S.K. Financial Research Ltd economist Samuel Kahan said there are some upward biases to the number itself.</p>
<p>&quot;If you include the effect of the rise in minimum wages, you can add on another 0.2 percent to the level,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;So, if the number prints at 0.9 percent, when you adjust it, it really is more like 0.7 percent,&quot; Kahan said. Another factor is that the entire compensation system has changed with many more workers receiving yearly and quarterly bonuses the index does not account for.</p>
<p>&quot;The important issue is not so much whether wages rise or not, but rather if we get a rise does it represent the beginning of a process or just a temporary phenomenom,&quot; Kahan said. &quot;The truth is it's not clear we have shifted gears and one can make the case that we will moderate back into the more sustainable 2.0 percent to 2.5 percent growth range in 1997.&quot;  </p>
<p>Kahan argued that it was hard to imagine growth continuing at the same pace experienced in the fourth quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;If the dollar stays strong and the economies of Japan and Europe continue to languish, that just creates a higher hurdle for the U.S. to keep growing,&quot; Kahan said.</p>
<p>Late Monday, the two-year note was 99-18/32, down 3/32, to yield 6.11 percent. The 10-year was down 10/32 at 98-25/32 to yield 6.67 percent. The 30-year bond was down 21/32 at 94-14/32 to yield 6.94 percent. Dealers indicated that Federal funds would open at 5-5/16 percent on Tuesday.</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk 212-859-1663))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
