<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="334959" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lyondell sees strong supply, demand in '97.</title>
<headline>Lyondell sees strong supply, demand in '97.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lyondell Petrochemical Co said Monday petrochemical industry suppy and demand factors look strong as 1997 begins while expressing concern about the continued impact of high feedstock costs on margins.</p>
<p>&quot;The supply and demand factors for our petrochemicals business look strong as we enter 1997,&quot; chief executive Dan F. Smith said. &quot;However, we are concerned about the extent that high feedstock costs may continue to affect margins.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to begin to see the benefits of the advantageous provisions of our refining venture during 1997 as the upgrade project comes on stream.&quot;  </p>
<p>The company said it recognizes it may be during the second half of the year before the upgrade will be fully operational.</p>
<p>Reporting a drop in annual earnings to $126 million from $389 million in 1995, he cited &quot;a difficult year for Lyondell with higher feedstock costs for petrochemicals and planned and unplanned downtime at the (Lyondell-Citgo) refinery.&quot;</p>
<p>Smith said the petrochemical markets were strong in 1996 and Lyondell benefited from good performance from its olefins and polymers operations. However, price increases were outpaced by rapidly escalating feedstock costs and this eroded margins for the olefins business.  </p>
<p>Results from Lyondell-Citgo Refining Co Ltd were hurt by a decline in aromatics margins as well as scheduled and unscheduled turnarounds associated with completion and tie-in of new units for the upgrade project.</p>
<p>By year-end, Lyondell-Citgo had completed construction of all major units for the refinery upgrade, which is expected to start up in the first quarter of 1997. Once the project is complete, Citgo's ownership will increase to about 40 percent.</p>
<p>As a result, effective January 1, Lyondell started reporting the refinery's results under the equity method of accounting, the company said.</p>
<p>Fourth quarter 1996 earnings included gains from asset sales and settlement of a claim associated with an ARCO Pipe Line Co fire which shut down Lyondell's Channelview, Texas, olefins plants for about two weeks in the early part of the third quarter. This settlement offset most of the impact of that event and, in effect, transferred earnings that would have been made in the third quarter to fourth quarter results.</p>
<p>((-- Jim Brumm 212-859-1710.))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
