<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="335168" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Milan airport authority forms cargo logistics firm.</title>
<headline>Milan airport authority forms cargo logistics firm.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>SEA, which is responsible for managing Milan's Linate and Malpensa airports, said it has formed a new company called Malpensa Logistica Europe in order to meet European Union anti-trust requirements.</p>
<p>The new company will operate at Malpensa 2000 Cargo City, an integrated logistical freight hub, serving air, rail and road transportation that is due for completion at end-1998.</p>
<p>Malpensa is used mainly for Milan's long-haul, primarily inter-continental flights while Linate is the city's main airport for domestic and inter-European services.</p>
<p>SEA said Malpensa Logistica 2000 is capitalised at 1.2 billion lire and has three equal partners -- SEA, Sinport (part of the Fiat SpA group) and European logistics operator Tecnologistica.</p>
<p>Alfredo Giannetti, president of SEA and board chairman of the new company, said: &quot;The objective of Malpensa Logistica Europe is to provide high-value added logistics and intermodal services -- all within a free market system.&quot;</p>
<p>--Air Cargo Newsroom Tel +44 171 542 7706 Fax+44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
