<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="335166" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany to cut pensions, raise contributions.</title>
<headline>Germany to cut pensions, raise contributions.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany must cut pensions, raise contributions and set up a tax-financed &quot;family fund&quot; to keep its state pensions scheme going in the 21st century, proposals announced on Monday by a coalition policy group showed.</p>
<p>A pensions commission chaired by Labour Minister Norbert Bluem recommended cutting pensions to 64 percent of average net wages by the year 2030, while contributions would rise to 22.9 percent of wages over the same period.  </p>
<p>Pensions are currently paid at 69 percent of average net wages, a level which is too high to cope with the expected &quot;greying&quot; of the German population in coming decades. The government recently raised pension contributions to a record 20.3 percent of wages after reserves ran dangerously low.</p>
<p>&quot;The pensions insurance scheme is adaptable and can cope with future needs,&quot; Bluem told reporters after a final meeting of his pensions commission.</p>
<p>The so-called family fund would transfer some non-related welfare payments out of the pensions insurance system and would be tax financed.</p>
<p>Chancellor Helmut Kohl's government wants to reform Germany's compulsory pensions scheme as well as pass a major tax reform -- but the cross-financing of the two measures remains a matter of dispute within the 14-year-old coalition.</p>
<p>-- Douglas Busvine, Bonn newsroom, 49-228-26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
