<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="335334" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Existing homes sales fall sharply in December.</title>
<headline>Existing homes sales fall sharply in December.</headline>
<byline>Alver Carlson</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brutal winter weather contributed to a sharp drop in home sales last month, though sales of existing homes still set a record for the year, a real estate agents' group said Monday.</p>
<p>The National Association of Realtors said sales of existing homes fell 3.5 percent in December to a seasonally adjusted annual rate of 3.87 million, from a revised rate of 4.01 million in November. The December total was lower than the rate of 4 million forecast by Wall Street economists.</p>
<p>For all of 1996, sales rose 7.5 percent to a record 4.09 million, beating the previous record of 3.99 million homes sold in 1978.</p>
<p>The group said snowstorms in the West caused much of December's decline. Sales also fell in the the Midwest and South. Sales in the Northeast improved.</p>
<p>Industry officials and analysts said December's drop was weather-related, and that the results were still respectable after a strong November.</p>
<p>&quot;In general, the market is as strong now as it was a year ago,&quot; association President Russell Booth said. &quot;Consumers often avoid moving in the winter months.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think we will probably need another month of activity to see how big the weather factor was,&quot; said economist John Bailey at Donaldson, Lufkin and Jenrette.</p>
<p>The association estimated that existing home sales this year would probably mirror December's annual sales rate, which would mean a drop of about 5 percent from last year's record.</p>
<p>The group's chief economist, John Tuccillo, said the jump in home sales last year reflected improved consumer sentiment that was likely to continue in 1997, though demand would probably slacken.</p>
<p>&quot;The psychological-driven demand has been pretty much used up so that it is not going to be there during 1997 to bolster the housing market,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Despite the expected drop this year, the overall market should remain strong by historical standards, he added.</p>
<p>Last month's sales rate was equal to the pace in December 1995, just before sales accelerated in early 1996 and remained strong despite a slight rise in mortgage rates for much of the year.</p>
<p>Thirty-year, fixed-rate mortgage loans averaged 7.60 percent in December, down from 7.62 percent in November, but up from 7.20 percent in December 1995.</p>
<p>Analysts said a rise in housing prices and a sharp drop in the number of homes available also pointed to resilient strength in the market for existing homes.</p>
<p>The median price -- half of homes sold above the median price and half below -- rose to $118,800 in December from $117,400 in November. The average price rose to $147,100 from $144,200.</p>
<p>The supply of homes fell to 5.1 months from 6.7 months in November. It was the lowest level since December 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm encouraged when I look at prices and the supply of homes,&quot; said Anthony Chan at Banc One.</p>
<p>Sales fell 7.7 percent in the West, 4.1 percent in the South and 3.8 percent in the Midwest. Sales in the Northeast rose 5.1 percent.</p>
<p>Previously, the group reported November sales at an annual rate of 4.04 million but revised that to 4.01 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E61">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
