<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="335583" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Brazil mark Eurobond possible next week - dealers.</title>
<headline>Brazil mark Eurobond possible next week - dealers.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil was taking bids for a mark Eurobond this week and a deal could surface next week, syndicate managers said on Monday.</p>
<p>A 500 million mark 10-year deal was expected, they said.</p>
<p>Seven banks were said to be trying for the mandate, but it was difficult to pinpoint a likely launch spread due to the intense competition to lead manage the deal, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Competition to get Brazil is very strong, and this will reflect in the pricing,&quot; said a Frankfurt-based syndicate manager. &quot;It's likely to be below 300 basis points over.&quot;</p>
<p>Another trader said the deal was likely to be launched next week, subject to market conditions.</p>
<p>Brazil last tapped the mark sector in 1995, when it launched a 1.0 billion mark three-year deal. Other Brazilian borrowers, such as state development bank BNDES and Companhia Energetica de Sao Paolo (CESP), issued five-year deals in 1996.</p>
<p>Argentina and Mexico were also active users of Euromarks last year, tapping into German retail demand for high coupons.</p>
<p>In February Argentina is due to issue a mark bond for up to 1.5 billion marks. No mandate had yet been awarded, but a long-dated deal was likely, dealers said.</p>
<p>Last October it issued a 500 million mark 30-year bond, its longest-dated issue, via Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>-- Aline van Duyn, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7748</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
