<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="335606" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: ICI shares rebound from recent weakness.</title>
<headline>ICI shares rebound from recent weakness.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Imperial Chemical Industries Plc rose on Monday amid bargain-hunting after their recent slide and as a small German acquisition allayed worries over a rumoured huge European takeover, dealers said.</p>
<p>The stock was up 11-1/2p at 754-1/2 by 1213 GMT in modest volume of 657,855 shares. ICI shares touched a low of 715p earlier this month, their lowest since March 1995.</p>
<p>Earlier ICI said it was buying BASF AG's syngas catalyst business, which had sales of about 15 million stg.  </p>
<p>&quot;One or two people had been saying they were about to do a big deal and this has just taken the pressure off a bit,&quot; said one market-maker in the stock.</p>
<p>A report in the Daily Mail earlier this month said ICI was poised to finance an acquisition in continental Europe with a one billion stg rights issue. ICI subsequently announced the purchase of a small Swiss paints business.  </p>
<p>&quot;What we are seeing today is just a bit of bottom-fishing going on,&quot; said another dealer.</p>
<p>Added another: &quot;The stock has been a bit bombed out and this is just a bounce.&quot;</p>
<p>Others pointed out that export and international stocks like ICI had been squeezed by the recent strength of sterling and could have come back into favour as the currency weakened.</p>
<p>The pound was recently trading at 2.6548 marks, down from last week's high of 2.7240.</p>
<p>-- David Holmes, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5106</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
