<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="335826" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Intel sees Internet transforming business.</title>
<headline>Intel sees Internet transforming business.</headline>
<byline>Neal Boudette</byline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Internet is transforming the way many industries do business, but Europe is &quot;way behind&quot; in taking advantage of the changes, Intel Corp chief Andy Grove said on Monday.</p>
<p>Electronic mail, video conferencing and other Internet applications have injected a &quot;texture of immediacy&quot; in the way many American and Asian companies do business, Grove told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;These applications let you react in minutes and hours instead of the the time frame of days. In that sense, Europe is way behind,&quot; said Grove, who will deliver a similar message next week in a keynote address at the World Economic Forum in Switzerland.</p>
<p>&quot;I would be very concerned if our company was like that,&quot; he said, adding that many American companies were forced to develop new business models during lean years in the 1980s.</p>
<p>&quot;My biggest concern for Europe is that its companies operate like oldline U.S. companies did 10 years ago,&quot; Grove told journalists. &quot;Internet is a break in the way business is done.&quot;</p>
<p>Europe may face even tougher competition from Asian firms, he said. &quot;The Asian economies are the children of the '90s. These companies are using information technology to their competitive advantage.&quot;</p>
<p>Europe has about 10 million to 15 million users of the Internet -- a global computer network through which users can send messages and access data sources. That is half as many Internet users as the United States, Grove said.</p>
<p>The number in Europe was expected to more than triple by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Over the next several years, the Internet would completely revolutionise the way many industries do business, he said.</p>
<p>Telecommunications companies would have to adapt their businesses to provide phone calls over the Internet at a fraction of the cost of regular calls. &quot;This could become a dominant part of the telephone business,&quot; Grove said.</p>
<p>The Internet also gives magazines, television broadcasters, movie producers and music companies a means of delivering their products directly to consumers -- without retail stores, distrubutors or packaged products, Grove said.</p>
<p>Internet advertising generated $312 million in revenues in the U.S. last year, and was seen growing to $5 billion by 2000, according to market researchers.</p>
<p>As an example, he pointed to the software industry, which is more and more delivering computer programs directly over the Internet instead of through mail order or retail outlets.</p>
<p>&quot;This allows new companies ot enter the marketplace and reach millions of customers almost overnight,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Intel, which is the world's leading producer of computer micro-processors, posted a 45 percent increase in 1996 income to $5.16 billion. Grove said computer chip power should keep increasing at its torrid pace for the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>For more than two decades, the power of PCs has doubled about every 18 months. &quot;There is no reason to think this performance growth rate is going to slow down in the forseeable future,&quot; Grove said.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, +49-228 26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
