<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="335867" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU finance ministers call for tax harmonisation.</title>
<headline>EU finance ministers call for tax harmonisation.</headline>
<byline>Myra MacDonald</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union finance ministers, reviving a controversial issue that has stumped them for years, said on Monday the bloc must make greater efforts to bring national tax regimes into line to prevent unfair competition.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a subject which has been neglected far too long,&quot; Italian Treasury minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi said at a televised opening of an ECOFIN Council.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a vital question, we must look for harmonisation,&quot; French Finance Minister Jean Arthuis said.</p>
<p>Europe has long put on hold the idea of reducing disparities in indirect and direct taxes in its single market, fearing domestic resistance on an issue that touches on sensitive concerns about national sovereignty.</p>
<p>But ministers said the question had become more pressing as Europe moves towards monetary union in January, 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;We want and need competition between the various tax systems in Europe, but priority must be given to measures to prevent unfair competition,&quot; German Finance Minister Theo Waigel said.</p>
<p>Ministers gave few details on how they could narrow tax disparities, though Belgian Finance Minister Philippe Maystadt cited the example of a profitable company which moved to another European Union country where the tax burden was lower.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a situation which public opinion will no longer be able to understand,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He also complained about banks in other EU countries encouraging Belgians to put their savings abroad to avoid taxes.</p>
<p>Many Belgians bank their savings in neighbouring Luxembourg, with whom Belgium has a currency union and which has built a thriving banking centre, drawing savers with a generous tax regime and tight secrecy laws.</p>
<p>Maystadt's comments drew a sharp response from Luxembourg Prime Minister Jean-Claude Juncker. &quot;I too receive at my private address, letters from Belgian banks inviting me to put my money in Belgium,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Juncker, who is also finance minister, denied however that Luxembourg was responsible for blocking any progress on tax harmonisation in Europe. &quot;Luxembourg cannot use its veto in the way the big states do,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Europe should look at harmonising all taxation, rather than focus simply on savings' taxes, he added.</p>
<p>EU officials had said the ministers could also discuss informally a French proposal to set up a special council to co-ordinate economic policies inside monetary union after 1999.</p>
<p>The proposal has come under fire from the German Bundesbank which fears the council may be used to undermine the independence of the future European central bank.</p>
<p>But ministers have played down any chance of a major row over the proposal, which seems to enjoy some support from the German government.</p>
<p>&quot;I've seen that the Bundesbank had a strong reaction, but as far as I could see, the German finance minister did not,&quot; Juncker told reporters as he arrived for the one-day talks.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't see there are any reasons for a row at all. We will have this stability council as we had the stability pact,&quot; Juncker said.</p>
<p>EU leaders agreed in December on a budget discipline pact to ensure monetary union members keep deficits low after 1999.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
