<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="335908" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: TFL sales rise 6.0 pct, buys Ciba plant.</title>
<headline>TFL sales rise 6.0 pct, buys Ciba plant.</headline>
<dateline>BASLE, Switzerland 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>TFL Ledertechnik GmbH &amp; Co KG, a Darmstadt-based supplier of chemicals and dyestuffs to the leather industry, said group sales in its first year of existence rose six percent and it fulfilled its profit goals.</p>
<p>In a statement issued from the Swiss subsidiary of TFL (Together for Leather), the company also said its French unit had acquired Ciba-Geigy AG's synthetic tanning chemical production plant in Huningue, France for an undisclosed amount.</p>
<p>The Huningue plant has a 15,000 tonnes capacity for tanning and retanning agents. TFL will also run is central warehousing operation from this site, which will serve as a shipments centre for European and worldwide exports.</p>
<p>TFL was formed on January 1, 1996 as a 50-50 venture between Swiss Ciba and German companies Roehm and Stockhausen. Ciba has since then merged with Sandoz AG into Novartis AG.</p>
<p>The aim was to pool the leather activities of the three companies into one company that would offer the entire range of products and activities to the leather industry.</p>
<p>At the time of its creation, TFL employed 400 people as the leather chemicals and dyestuffs were produced at its parent companies. Now it employs around 800 people as it has started to take over production facilities from its parents.</p>
<p>There are no plans to list TFL, a company spokesman said.</p>
<p>He declined to provide a profit figure or goal for TFL, but said the company forecast it would achieve 1996 sales of 350 million marks at the time of its beginning.</p>
<p>Profits are expected to rise strongly in the next few years as the synergi effects from the collaboration of the three companies takes full effect, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The statement quoted Heider Krenz and Peter Schaller, joint presidents of TFL, as expecting comparable sales growth in 1997 and continuing improvements in the group's profitability.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25670">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BASLE, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
