<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="336059" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - Jan 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - Jan 27.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>-- RENAULT TO SIGN UP 40 CAR PART SUPPLIERS IN THE UK</p>
<p>French car manufacturer Renault is reported to be preparing to sign over 40 UK car parts companies as suppliers in a fast- track recruitment programme. Under the fast-track scheme, the timetable for becoming a Renault supplier is reduced from five to two years. The move is seen as part of a trend among French companies to look to UK suppliers to reduce costs, with rival car giant Peugeot-Citroen and rail company SNCF also considering UK suppliers.</p>
<p>-- BBC PLANS TO LAUNCH US CHANNELS IN JOINT VENTURE</p>
<p>The BBC is set to agree a venture with Telecommunications Inc (TCI), the largest US cable operator, in which the UK broadcaster would launch its own branded channels in the US. Initially two channels, one devoted to general and entertainment programming and one to news and factual programmes, are envisaged, though the corporation is also understood to be considering involvement in further channels which would not necessarily carry its name.</p>
<p>-- PM PLANS RATES REFORM TO WOO SMALL BUSINESS</p>
<p>Conservative ministers are due to meet on Monday to consider a draft general election manifesto which is expected to include a package of measures designed to win back the support of small businesses. The manifesto will contain commitments to reform business rates and to ease the burden of regulation. The thrust of the proposals is to appeal to small business in an effort to combat the Labour party's attempts to woo industry.</p>
<p>-- YORKSHIRE ELECTRICITY MONITORS WEBSITE FOR PREDATORS</p>
<p>Yorkshire Electricity is likely to be the next UK regional electricity company to be bid for, although an adviser to the company has said no approach has yet been made. Shares in the company have risen 4.5 percent since the beginning of the year, prompting one analyst to conclude: &quot;its share price is saying it is about to be bid for&quot;. Yorkshire has begun to monitor 'hits' to its website in an effort to identify potential predators, and has already tagged US company Mission Energy as one of the most frequent visitors to the site.</p>
<p>-- EUROPE FALLING BACK IN IT, US HIGH-TECH FIRMS WARN</p>
<p>Executives at several US high technology companies have warned that Europe is falling behind the US and Asia in the use of information technology (IT), and that protective labour laws are discouraging new investment in manufacturing plant by overseas IT companies. Both IBM and Digital Equipment have expressed concern at 'inflexible' labour laws which are obstructing their attempts to cut workforce numbers and close facilities. Andrew Grove, chief executive of semiconductor maker Intel, warns that an 'unenthusiastic approach' to IT is putting the competitiveness of Europe at risk.</p>
<p>-- BT, MCI PONDER DEMAND BY AT&amp;T</p>
<p>AT&amp;T, the largest US telecoms operator, has submitted a statement to the US Federal Communications Commission suggesting that further liberalisation of the UK telecoms market be a precondition to the planned merger of British Telecom and US firm MCI. The $20 billion merger, in which BT is seeking to acquire the other 80 percent of MCI it doesn't already own, is subject to approval from the FCC, and under US laws the deal will be approved as long as the home telecoms market of the acquirer is judged to be at least as open as the US.</p>
<p>-- SUBSIDIES CRITICISED BY ENVIRONMENT ADVISERS</p>
<p>A group set up by prime minister John Major following the Rio 'Earth Summit' in 1992 is set to publish a report calling for the government to review up to 20 billion stg in environmentally harmful 'subsidies', and warning that the lowering of prices expected from the liberalisation of energy markets planned from 1998 could exacerbate climate change. The group, the Panel on Sustainable Development, valued the subsidies at 20 billion stg by including any tax arrangement which fails to make the price of goods and services fully reflect the cost of their damage to the environment.</p>
<p>-- BP SEEKS CONSENT FOR POWER STATION</p>
<p>Energy group British Petroleum has submitted an application for government approval for a planned 300 million stg, 1,100-MW combined gas-fired power station at one of its petrochemical plants in south Wales. The move confirms a shift towards gas-fired power stations in the UK, and for oil companies to move into electricity generation. It is also expected to herald a stiffening of competition in electricity generation, and possibly lower prices.</p>
<p>-- ESPRIT TELECOM TO FLOAT IN US AND UK</p>
<p>Esprit Telecom, the five-year old European telecoms operator, is reported to be set to announce an international public offering in New York and London. The company, which provides cut-price international services to the UK government, is looking to tap investor interest in new telecoms entrants as liberalisation of the European market in 1998 draws closer. Esprit is estimated to have an enterprise value of about $200 million, and investment bankers expect it to raise about $100 million in the offering.</p>
<p>-- CAT EYES 30 MILLION STG FLOATATION</p>
<p>Biotechnology company Cambridge Antibody Technology, a world leader in creating human monoclonal antibodies, is set to announce its intention to float in a listing that is expected to value the company at between 85 million stg and 100 million stg. The company, which has already signed a series of agreements to collaborate with a number of leading drugs companies, including Pfizer, BASF and Mitsubshi, also lists Eli Lilly and Genentech among its current shareholders.</p>
<p>For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
