<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="336012" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: European bourses fear worst as Dow falls again.</title>
<headline>European bourses fear worst as Dow falls again.</headline>
<byline>Peter Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>European bourses, which had drifted flat or mixed in thin trade all day, turned generally lower on Monday as Wall Street slid again in early New York trade after its near 60-point setback on Friday.</p>
<p>The early weakness in the U.S. did nothing to help sentiment in Europe, where investors have been pondering whether they are seeing the begining of the end of the bull run in world markets.</p>
<p>On the currency front the dollar was steady in quiet trading below the sessions highs, a contrast to the frantic currency trading of last week which took the U.S. currency to multi-year peaks against the mark and the yen.</p>
<p>With the currency market lacking fresh incentive of its own, traders were looking to Wall Street for cues following its Friday selloff</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing that might get things moving today is if the Dow starts falling again. That might put pressure on the dollar, but otherwise everyone is waiting for the (employment) data out tomorrow,&quot; said Pat Magill, head of corporate trading at Daiwa Europe.</p>
<p>In London, Europe's busiest stock exchange, shares which had been flat most of the morning dropped into negative territory after Wall Street opened. Investors were wary however, unsure whether New York could be on the verge of a more substantial downside correction.</p>
<p>In the European mid-afternoon the Dow Jones Industrial Average was down 22 points or around a third of a percentage point.</p>
<p>&quot;There hasn't been a lot of selling but marketmakers are on their guard,&quot; the head of trading at a large brokerage said.</p>
<p>&quot;People are talking about Wall Street coming off several hundred points and don't want to be around if that happens.&quot;</p>
<p>The blue chip FTSE 100 has some support at around the 4,200 level and a move below that area could attract some near-term buying, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;If we fall much below, institutions will be tempted to buy on the dips,&quot; one dealer said. &quot;But if Wall Street has another bad day, the FTSE could head a lot lower.&quot;</p>
<p>J Sainsbury, which plunged 13 percent after a profits warning on Friday, once again led supermarket shares lower on worries about a possible full-scale price war.</p>
<p>The FTSE index was down 4.1 points at 4,214.7 at 1530 GMT</p>
<p>Earlier, British equities and gilts had showed little reaction to the latest British gross domestic product figures showing the  economy grew 0.8 percent in the fourth quarter for annual growth of 2.6 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>The statistics, which were in line with analysts' expectations, should reinforce growing market confidence that base rates will not rise ahead of the general election, which must take place by May 22, analysts said.</p>
<p>In Frankfurt, German shares ended the bourse session slightly lower before the Dow opened. Trading volumes had been low with some dealers saying they saw the threat of further declines. However the firm dollar, which is good for German exports, was providing some support and enabled the Ibis Dax index of electronic trading to remain postive, though well off its highs of the day.</p>
<p>In Paris, French stocks also lost their gains after New York's open and were trading flat in mid-afternoon. One boost for Paris stocks came from Rhone-Poulenc, which jumped after its unit Rhone-Poulenc Rorer reported good 1996 results.</p>
<p>Foreign exchange dealers said the market was loath to push the dollar much higher before key U.S. data due later this week and amid fears of central bank intervention on a rise above 120 yen. By 1530 GMT the dollar was trading at around 119.28 yen.</p>
<p>Against the mark the dollar was trading at around 1.6378</p>
<p>U.S. employment cost data, due on Tuesday, was the focus for now, analysts said, as the results could provide indications on the Federal Open Market Committee's (FOMC) decision on interest rates at its next meeting on February 4 and 5.</p>
<p>&quot;The Fed likes to watch the quarterly employment cost index closely. The monthly earnings data are more narrowly based, but provide good clues,&quot; said Robin Aspinall, strategist at National Australia Bank.</p>
<p>The fourth-quarter employment cost index is forecast to rise by 1.2 percent after a 0.6 percent increase the previous quarter, according to a Reuters poll of economists.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1530 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 119.28 yen and 1.6378 marks compared with late Europe's Friday level of 118.93 yen and 1.6265 marks.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1530 GMT</p>
<p>The FTSE 100 index of leading British shares was down 4.1 4,214.7.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index was up 0.23 at 2,430.57.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt closed down 3.71 at 2,994.53.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold fixed in London at $353.60 compared with its Friday London close of $353.35 an ounce. Silver was steady at $4.95</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
