<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="336556" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: OFFICIAL JOURNAL CONTENTS - OJ C 26 OF JANUARY 25, 1997.</title>
<headline>OFFICIAL JOURNAL CONTENTS - OJ C 26 OF JANUARY 25, 1997.</headline>
<text>
<p>*</p>
<p>(Note - contents are displayed in reverse order to that in the printed Journal)</p>
<p>*</p>
<p>Action brought on 26 November 1996 by Salini Costruttori SpA against the Commission of the European Communities (Case T-187/96)</p>
<p>Action brought on 21 November 1996 by Mutual Aid Administration Services NV against the Commission of the European Communities (Case T-186/96)</p>
<p>Action brought on 15 November 1996 by Partex, Companhia Portuguesa de Servicos, SA, against the Commission of the European Communities (Case T-182/96)</p>
<p>Action brought on 14 November 1996 by Mediocurso, Estabelecimento de Ensino Particular Limitada, against the Commission of the European Communities (Case T-181/96)</p>
<p>Action brought on 14 November 1996 by Mediocurso, Estabelecimento de Ensino Particular Limitada, against the Commission of the European Communities (Case T-180/96)</p>
<p>ORDER OF THE PRESIDENT OF THE COURT OF FIRST INSTANCE of 29 November 1996 in Case T-179/96 R: J. Antonissen v. Council and Commission of the European Communities (Milk quotas - Damage caused by the Community - Application for interim relief - Application for damages against the Community - Provisional nature - None)</p>
<p>Removal from the register of T-162/95</p>
<p>Partial removal from the register of T-154/96</p>
<p>JUDGMENT OF THE COURT of 26 November 1996 in Case C-68/95 (reference for a preliminary ruling from the Hessischer Verwaltungsgerichtshof): T. Port GmbH &amp; Co. KG v. Bundesanstalt fur Landwirtschaft und Ernahrung (Bananas - Common organization of the markets - Import rules - Cases of hardship - Assessment of validity - Interim measures)</p>
<p>Reference for a preliminary ruling by the Bundesverwaltungsgericht by order of that court of 25 September 1996 in the case of Aher-Waggon GmbH against the Federal Republic of Germany (Case C-389/96)</p>
<p>Reference for a preliminary ruling from the Svea Hovratt by order of that court of 22 November 1996 in the case of Anders Sjoberg v. Public Prosecutor (Case C-387/96)</p>
<p>Reference for a preliminary ruling from the Amtsgericht Aachen by order of that court of 6 November 1996 in the administrative penalty proceedings against Hermann Josef Goerres (Case C-385/96)</p>
<p>Reference for a preliminary ruling by the Tribunal du Travail, Charleroi, by judgment of that court of 7 November 1996 in the case of Louisette Cordelle against Office National des Pensions (Case C-366/96)</p>
<p>JUDGMENT OF THE COURT (Third Chamber) of 24 October 1996 in Case C-335/95 (reference for a preliminary ruling from the Cour du travail, Liege): Institut national d'assurances sociales pour travailleurs independants (Inasti) v. Michel Picard (Social security for migrant workers - Old-age and death insurance - Benefits - Concurrent award of pensions under the legislation of two Member States - Automatic award on submission of a claim to the competent institution of one of the Member States - Claim to be made to the institution of the Member State of residence in order to obtain award of both pensions concurrently)</p>
<p>JUDGMENT OF THE COURT (Fifth Chamber) of 14 November 1996 in Case C-333/94 P: Tetra Pak International SA v. Commission of the European Communities (Appeal - Competition - Dominant position - Definition of the product markets - Application of Article 86 of the Treaty to practices carried out by a dominant undertaking on a market distinct from the dominated market - Tied sales - Predatory prices - Fine)</p>
<p>JUDGMENT OF THE COURT (Second Chamber) of 14 November 1996 in Case C-305/94 (reference for a preliminary ruling from the Tribunal du Travail, Brussels): Claude Rotsart de Hertaing v. J. Benoidt SA, in liquidation, and IGC Housing Service SA (Safeguarding of employees' rights in the event of transfers of undertakings, businesses or parts of businesses - Transfer to the transferee of the rights and obligations arising from a contract of employment - Date of transfer)</p>
<p>JUDGMENT OF THE COURT (Sixth Chamber) of 24 October 1996 in Case C-288/94 (reference for a preliminary ruling from the VAT and Duties Tribunal): Argos Distributors Ltd v. Commissioners of Customs and Excise (Value-added tax - Sixth Directive - Taxable amount)</p>
<p>JUDGMENT OF THE COURT of 12 November 1996 in Case C-201/94 (reference for a preliminary ruling from the High Court of Justice, Queen's Bench Division): The Queen v. The Medicines Control Agency, ex parte: Smith &amp; Nephew Pharmaceuticals Ltd and Primecrown Ltd v. The Medicines Control Agency (Proprietary medicinal products - Parallel imports - Direct effect of Directive 65/65/EEC - Marketing authorization)</p>
<p>JUDGMENT OF THE COURT (Fourth Chamber) of 24 October 1996 in Case C-172/95 (reference for a preliminary ruling from the Tribunal Administratif, Amiens): Societe sucriere agricole de Maizy and Societe sucriere de Berneuil-sur-Aisne v. Directeur regional des impots (Common organization of the markets in the sugar sector - Chargeable event for storage, production and elimination levies - Period in respect of which elimination levies are payable)</p>
<p>JUDGMENT OF THE COURT (Fifth Chamber) of 7 November 1996 in Case C-126/94 (reference for a preliminary ruling from the Tribunal d'Instance, Paris XII): Societe Cadi Surgeles and Others v. Ministre des Finances and Directeur general des douanes (Free movement of goods - Common Customs Tariff - Common commercial policy - Fiscal rules applicable to French overseas departments - Goods from non-member countries) END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
