<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="336522" id="root" date="1997-01-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London gold fixes firmer, silver stays steady.</title>
<headline>London gold fixes firmer, silver stays steady.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Precious metals prices opened the week generally up from Friday's firmer closes in markets that one dealer characterised as quietly enthusiastic.</p>
<p>&quot;What a difference a week makes,&quot; the dealer said, referring to the anxiety in the market during its descent to a fresh 40-month low fixing of $348.00 last week.</p>
<p>Gold fixed at $353.10 per ounce on Monday against $352.50 on Friday afternoon, when prices closed at $351.10/$351.60.</p>
<p>The rally by precious metal from their lows last week was largely powered by buying in silver, which rose to its highest fixing since October 27 last year on Friday at 497.25 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;Silver might be looking a bit toppish on the charts,&quot; a dealer said of the market, which was steady at 494/496 cents on Monday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;It could manage another 10-15 cents, then come off about eight or nine,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The short term target for silver was 500 cents, which was also the key strike price for the over the counter (OTC) options which expire later this week, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It should be fairly steady up to the option expiry,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>The expiry was likely to be less significant for gold. &quot;This is new territory for gold. The strike prices this month are either well in or well out of the money,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Gold was forecast to begin trying to catch up with the silver market after it managed to rally from its low last week.</p>
<p>&quot;Any dip will be bought,&quot; a dealer said, forecasting a base under the current market at $352.50.</p>
<p>The market might take some encouragement from the easier tone at the end of last week in both the stock markets and in the dollar, although dealers said this was essentially &quot;background&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a lot of nervous producer selling around over the past few weeks but they seem to have worked that out now,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Platinum and palladium were both firmer following the general trend.</p>
<p>Both markets were also supported by the continuing delay in opening talks between Russian exporters and Japanese importers for 1997 supply contracts.</p>
<p>Platinum was indicated at $357.50/$358.50, up 25 cents, and palladium was 50 cents firmer at $122.50/$123.50.</p>
<p>--Brian Spoors +44 171 542 8058</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
