<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="336971" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ATHLETICS-SLANEY AT 38 LOOKING TO WIN AT MILROSE GAMES.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-SLANEY AT 38 LOOKING TO WIN AT MILROSE GAMES.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mary Decker Slaney hopes it will be like old times when America's best women's middle-distance runner competes at the Millrose Games next week for the first time since 1989.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to come and do my very best and my very best in my mind is to run fast as well as win, and at this point my training is indicating that 'hey I can do this,' and I want to do this,&quot; Slaney said at a Track Writers' luncheon in a tele-conference call on Monday.</p>
<p>Slaney, 38, will run against a stellar group of milers at Madison Square Garden February 7 in a bid to add to her 1982, '83 and '85 titles at that distance in the famed indoor meet.</p>
<p>The assembled field features 1992 Olympic 1,500 meter champion Hassiba Boulmerka of Algeria, defending Millrose champion Kathy Franey and 1995 champion Angela Chalmers of Canada.</p>
<p>But Slaney, the holder of 10 U.S. indoor and outdoor records, including the indoor and outdoor mile marks, is feeling primed for all challengers after a series of strong road race wins in the last six weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;I plan on going out and run my race, and at this point, everything that I have been doing indicates that I can run between 4:20 and 4:25 and if I have a really good night then I can run under 4:20,&quot; said Slaney, from her home in Eugene, Oregon.</p>
<p>According to meet director Howard Schmertz, the last person to even break the four-minute, 30-second mark in the Millrose Mile was Paula Iven of Romania in 1989 with a 4:23.72 clocking.</p>
<p>&quot;The first thing you want to do in a race is win and I suppose at this point I'm being a little bit greedy because I want to win and run fast,&quot; said Slaney.</p>
<p>&quot;Part of that is because it is Millrose and that I haven't been there for a long time and who knows when I will be back,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Slaney has been hobbled by long list of leg and foot injuries and even asthma throughout her career, but recently has been running free of pain which has convinced her to return to the Millrose Games where she made a memorable debut as a California schoolgirl by winning the 1,000-yard race in 1974.</p>
<p>&quot;Over the last few years when I have been hurt, inujured, sick, I thought that if I ever got healthy enough that I could run at least one indoor race, it would be Millrose,&quot; Slaney said.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not have come if I didn't feel like I  would be in good shape and very, very, and very competitive,&quot; Slaney said.</p>
<p>&quot;I couldn't be happier.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
