<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="336903" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GTE Q4 results impress analysts.</title>
<headline>GTE Q4 results impress analysts.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fourth quarter results from GTE Corp on Tuesday impressed analysts with the company's ability to improve its core businesses while simultaneously expanding into long distance services.</p>
<p>&quot;All the trends are in place for double digit earnings growth into the future,' said Barry Sine of SBC Warburg.</p>
<p>GTE reported an eight percent jump in local access lines to customers -- well ahead of most rivals -- and a long distance customer base of 825,000 in its first nine months of operation, ahead of its own 750,000 target.  </p>
<p>The company made an operating profit per share of $0.82 against $0.74 a year ago, $0.01 above the First Call analysts' consensus estimate.</p>
<p>The most impressive aspect was that the costs of getting into long distance did not seem to eat into the benefits of core business growth, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;A very strong result, definitely indicating that the long distance entry is not affecting earnings momentum,&quot; said Bill Vogel of broker Dillon Read.  </p>
<p>GTE is not a regional Bell, and so was not forced by the 1996 Telecom Act to open up its local calling areas to competition before offering long distance services.</p>
<p>The greater the regulatory delays for regional Bells and long distance companies to enter each others' markets, the better GTE's advantage is, analysts say.</p>
<p>&quot;For the time being GTE is the only company that is getting the best of both worlds,&quot; said Vogel.</p>
<p>GTE also produced a very strong increase of 25 percent in U.S. cellular subscribers to a total of 3.75 million.</p>
<p>&quot;That was a positive surprise,&quot; Sine said.</p>
<p>The stock rose 5/8 to $44-3/8 by 1115 EST/1615 GMT.</p>
<p>(( Nick Louth, New York Newsroom 212 859 1712))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
