<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="337075" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE white sugar ends hardly changed, dull.</title>
<headline>LIFFE white sugar ends hardly changed, dull.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>LIFFE sugar futures ended mostly just easier after trading in a narrow range with nothing to give the market new direction.</p>
<p>March last traded at $298.00 which was down just 10 cents on volume of 990 lots. May was down 60 cents at $297.60 on volume of 1107 lots. Total volume at that point was 1,886 lots.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a bit of pre-restitution selling early in the day,&quot; said one trader, referring to the EU's sugar tender Wednesday.</p>
<p>But New York's performance helped bring LIFFE futures up later in the day, he said.</p>
<p>The European Union's sugar management committee will discuss the final sugar balance sheet for 1995/96 on Wednesday, an EU official said on Monday. The committee will also discuss the provisional balance sheet for 1996/97, the official said.</p>
<p>Pankobirlik, an influential union of Turkish sugar beet cooperatives, expected 2.05 million tonnes of overall sugar production in 1997/98, up from 1.85 million tonnes in 1996/97, it said in a report.</p>
<p>Turkey's state-run sugar refinery Turkseker is planning to export 50,000 tonnes of sugar soon, its general manager Selahhatin Hun said on Tuesday. &quot;We are planning to sell about 50,000 tonnes more after our first sale two weeks ago,&quot; Hun told Reuters.</p>
<p>Mexican sugar cane growers, threatening to stage a &quot;down machetes&quot; strike against industrialists, won a 26 percent increase in cane prices, daily newspaper Reforma said Tuesday.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom, +44 171 542 7928</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
