<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33700" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: OPEC exceeded output limit in August - survey.</title>
<headline>OPEC exceeded output limit in August - survey.</headline>
<byline>Karen Matusic</byline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries again flouted its own crude oil output quotas in August, a Reuters survey showed Thursday, but the market was able to absorb the extra oil.</p>
<p>The crisis in Iraq has put on hold the return of Iraqi oil exports and analysts say it probably means the market will be short 650,000 barrels per day of additional oil, which it had expected this month.</p>
<p>The loss of the Iraqi oil comes when demand is robust, production from rival producers is lower than expected and inventories of heating oil are thin heading into the winter.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand is so strong and stocks are low. So the market really does need that extra Iraqi oil now,&quot; said Leo Drollas, chief economist at the Centre for Global Energy Studies.</p>
<p>A Reuter survey of analysts, industry officials and OPEC delegates showed that the oil cartel pumped 25.88 million barrels per day in August, up 20,000 barrels from 25.86 million in July and well over the 25.03 million ceiling.</p>
<p>&quot;OPEC has been overproducing for a long time but that overproduction becomes a problem only when demand is lower than supply. Now it is not a problem,&quot; said Bo Van Wijk, vice president of energy risk managment at Swiss bank UBS.</p>
<p>Baghdad's attacks this week on Kurdish strongholds sparked retaliatory U.S. missile attacks and prompted an indefinite delay in the implementation of a U.N. pact allowing Iraq to sell $2 billion worth of oil to pay for food and medicines.</p>
<p>Oil prices currently stand about $5 a barrel higher than at this time last year, defying predictions of weaker oil prices when the oil-for-food deal was signed in May.</p>
<p>On Thursday, October crude oil futures rose 20 cents to $23.44 a barrel on the New York Mercantile Exchange.</p>
<p>The OPEC reference basket hit $21.17 on Wednesday, nearly $2 above early August levels and above its $21 &quot;minimum&quot; target.</p>
<p>The Centre for Global Energy, a London energy think-tank headed by former Saudi Oil Minister Sheikhh Ahmed Zaki Yamani, reckons that OPEC producers stand to earn $2 billion more in the fourth quarter than was previously forecast.</p>
<p>&quot;OPEC has had a very good ride this quarter and things look better for the fourth quarter. We have seen a dramatic change in market sentiment,&quot; Drollas said.</p>
<p>Virtually every OPEC-member country is exceeding its production quota, but some Middle East Gulf producers only modestly so.</p>
<p>According to the Reuter survey, higher production in August was recorded in three of OPEC's largest members -- Venezuela, Nigeria and Iran. Venezuela pumped 3.12 million barrels a day, up from 3.03 million in July and well above its 2.36 million quota.</p>
<p>The group's other main overproducer, Nigeria, has fully recovered from a midsummer supply shortfall in the giant Bonny system because of pipeline leaks.</p>
<p>OPEC's largest member, Saudi Arabia, has not provided its official August production figures to the group but analysts estimate that it produced 8.10 million barrels, below July's 8.22 million.</p>
<p>The Reuter survey seeks a best estimate of wellhead flows in OPEC countries based on the views of officials, industry monitors and analysts inside and outside member countries.</p>
<p>OPEC quotas are based on supply to market, defined to exclude movements to, but not sales from storage.</p>
<p>Table of average of findings from the Reuter survey of OPEC production as follows:</p>
<p>		  AUG     JULY     JUNE    3 MTH AV   QUOTA</p>
<p> Algeria	0.83     0.83     0.82     0.83	0.750</p>
<p> Indonesia    1.40     1.40     1.43     1.41	1.330</p>
<p> Iran	   3.66     3.65     3.60     3.63	3.600</p>
<p> Iraq	   0.60     0.60     0.60     0.60	1.200</p>
<p> Kuwait	 2.05     2.05     2.05     2.05	2.000</p>
<p> Libya	  1.40     1.40     1.40     1.40	1.390</p>
<p> Nigeria	2.05     2.01     2.01     2.02	1.865</p>
<p> Qatar	  0.48     0.48     0.48     0.48	0.378</p>
<p> S. Arabia    8.10     8.22     8.19     8.17	8.000</p>
<p> UAE	    2.19     2.19     2.19     2.19	2.161</p>
<p> Venezuela    3.12     3.03     3.00     3.05	2.359</p>
<p> Total	 25.88    25.86    25.77    25.83     25.033</p>
<p>Figures, in million bpd, exclude condensate and NGLs. Quotas apply to supply, not wellhead output. Saudi and Kuwaiti data include Neutral Zone. (R) = revised.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="OPEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
