<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="337077" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: N.Sea crude markets firm as Ekofisks snapped up.</title>
<headline>N.Sea crude markets firm as Ekofisks snapped up.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea crude markets firmed on Tuesday as a clutch of Ekofisks changed hands at strong premiums and transatlantic buying looked set to support the physical Brent market into late February, traders said.</p>
<p>Four Ekofisk cargoes, loading in the second and third decades of February, traded at premiums to Dated Brent of between 30 and 34 cents.</p>
<p>A Statfjord loading Feb 21-23 fetched a firm Dated Brent +50 cents, while a Draugen loading 23-25 was sold at Dated +48 cents, four cents up on its last traded level.</p>
<p>Two third decade Forties were also believed traded on a p+c basis at Dated Brent +40/45 cents.</p>
<p>Narrowing refining margins have so far failed to dampen the crude market's strength, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm just a little surprised at the firmness at which these barrels are moving,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Underscoring the market's bullish tone, the two Brent dates nominated from the paper chains on Tuesday were kept ahead of the five o-clock deadline.</p>
<p>A U.S. refiner confirmed that it had bought an end-Feb loading Brent cargo into the Gulf Coast at around March WTI -40 cents for March 10-15 delivery. Two other refiners were also heard to have picked up cargoes.</p>
<p>&quot;That's a bullish sign, because if anything (the third decade) was the top heavy end of the month,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;It indicates to me that there is going to be a tight Brent market to keep premiums up,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>On the Brent paper market, intermonth spreads edged higher from earlier discussion. Feb/Mar was valued at +42/46 cents and Mar/Apr traded at +41 and +42.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
