<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33712" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Granada sells Spring Grove to Davis.</title>
<headline>Granada sells Spring Grove to Davis.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>British restaurants-to-rental television company Granada Group said Thursday it was selling textile service firm Spring Grove Services to Davis Service Group for 136.5 million British pounds ($213.9 million).</p>
<p>The sale is conditional on Davis shareholder and regulatory approval. Granada said the disposal was part of its strategy to focus on core businesses.</p>
<p>Since the company won its hostile bid battle for hotels group Forte in January, its disposals, spanning bowling centre interests to the White Hart Hotels portfolio, have generated more than 350 million pounds ($546 million) of cash proceeds to cut debt, Granada said.</p>
<p>Davis, which earlier reported a 10 percent rise in half year pretax profits to 12.3 million pounds ($19 million), said the acquisition of Spring Grove would start benefiting earnings in 1997 with the full positive impact flowing through in 1998.</p>
<p>Spring Grove, which mainly provides rental and cleaning services for workwear as well as washroom towels and mats to business customers in Britain, Ireland and Germany, made a pretax profit of 11.6 million pounds ($18 million) in 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I84600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
