<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="337264" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: FOCUS-IMF offers Albania help over savings scandal.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-IMF offers Albania help over savings scandal.</headline>
<byline>Crispian Balmer</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA. 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has offered to help the Albanian government overcome a dramatic financial crisis sparked by the collapse of popular pyramid investment schemes, an IMF official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A wave of violent unrest has swept Albania in recent days following the failure of leading private savings schemes, which have left many people facing economic ruin.</p>
<p>&quot;The IMF will do everything it can to assist the government in resolving the crisis,&quot; the IMF's resident representative in Albania, John King, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Economists estimate that more than $1.0 billion may have been plunged into a myriad of high-yielding pyramid funds, which mushroomed across Albania following the fall of the old hardline communist regime in 1990.</p>
<p>Five of the top nine national schemes have either declared bankruptcy or had their bank assets seized by the government in the past month. The others are still paying interest but are not allowing investors to withdraw their capital.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Aleksander Meksi earlier this week promised that the government would re-pay investors who had been caught out by the scams. Commentators believe that almost all Albanians have been directly or indirectly hit by the crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;We have offered to give the government any help that they think we can best provide,&quot; King said, adding that the IMF was already supplying technical advice to the ruling right-wing Democratic Party on how to overcome the growing scandal.</p>
<p>The IMF has provided two loan facilities to Albania, the poorest country in Europe, since 1992 and is currently negotiating a third lending programme.</p>
<p>However neither the Washington-based group nor other international agencies are likely to hand Meksi a blank cheque to appease furious investors without a firm undertaking that pyramid schemes are eradicated.</p>
<p>The IMF and World Bank urged the government last year to impose strict controls on the pyramid groups, some of which promised to double investments in two or three months.</p>
<p>The World Bank's resident representative in Tirana, Carlos Elbirt, told Reuters that it was in Albania's long-term interest to see the back of the pyramids, which have stopped money being invested in much-needed development projects.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot hand over money to bail these schemes out,&quot; Elbirt said. &quot;This is a tragedy for Albania...but the sooner these schemes collapsed, the better,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Many Albanians, struggling with the recent arrival of free market enterprise, would disagree.</p>
<p>The pyramid investments offered many people the hope of making quick, easy profits and the early success of the schemes encouraged some people to sell all their property and belongings to funnel more funds into the pyramids.</p>
<p>&quot;People hoped they could generate the sort of money that they saw in the West. What they didn't realise was that it takes many generations to accumulate that sort of wealth,&quot; said Zef Preci, director of the independent Albania Centre for Economic Research.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
