<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="337226" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: Rwanda concerned at eastern Zaire counterattack.</title>
<headline>Rwanda concerned at eastern Zaire counterattack.</headline>
<byline>Christian Jennings</byline>
<dateline>KIGALI 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rwanda's military strongman said on Tuesday he was concerned at a government counter-offensive in eastern Zaire and hoped the campaign would not spill over into Rwanda.</p>
<p>Vice-President and Defence Minister Paul Kagame however said Zairean rebels currently appeared to be winning in fighting with Zairean troops backed by foreign mercenaries in the east.</p>
<p>&quot;We are taking seriously the possibility of a counter- offensive by the Zaireans and of course we want to keep this outside Rwanda,&quot; Kagame, Rwanda's former Tutsi rebel leader, told reporters at Kigali airport.</p>
<p>&quot;But at the moment it appears this is a fight the rebels are winning and the Zaireans seem to be more talk than action on the ground as events are showing,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Kagame was speaking at departure ceremonies for Tanzanian President Benjamin Mkapa, who ended a 24-hour visit to Rwanda where he discussed security issues with the country's leaders.</p>
<p>Zairean rebel leader Laurent Kabila denied on Monday a Zairean government announcement that its troops last week recaptured the town of Walikale, 120 km (80 miles) from rebel headquarters in the city of Goma, and had killed 100 rebels.</p>
<p>Kabila told the British Broadcasting Corporation that the rebels had so far had no trouble from the counter-offensive announced by Kinshasa. He said foreign mercenaries had stopped fighting and resumed training after two were killed by rebels.</p>
<p>He denied Walikale had fallen and dismissed the government report of its capture as propaganda to fool the Zairean people.</p>
<p>Kabila said the government campaign would fail to wrest a swath of eastern Zaire from the rebels because the Zairean army was ineffective and mercenaries wanted to live to spend their salaries.</p>
<p>Witnesses said the shrouded body of a white mercenary killed fighting rebels arrived by helicopter over the weekend in the city of Kisangani, the headquarters for the counter-offensive.</p>
<p>Up to 300 soldiers of fortune, many Serbs from the former Yugoslavia, are in eastern Zaire to help the campaign to regain control over the east ordered by President Mobutu Sese Seko.</p>
<p>The Rwandan-backed rebels, who launched their revolt in October, hold territory along the border with Rwanda, Uganda and Burundi. Rwanda denies sending its troops to Zaire to fight alongside the rebels.</p>
<p>Reacting to concern by aid agencies over attacks this month in northwestern Rwanda, Mkapa told reporters he saw no evidence the security situation in Rwanda was as bad as in Burundi, where the Tutsi-dominated army and Hutu rebels are waging civil war.</p>
<p>Rwandan troops killed at least 80 people in a crackdown in the northwestern province of Ruhengeri last week after suspected Hutu militiamen shot dead three Spanish aid workers and wounded an American.</p>
<p>Mkapa said his government had no agreement to push Burundian refugees in Tanzania back to Burundi and would ensure they abide by international law, which bars them from launching attacks.</p>
<p>Burundi's army has admitted killing 126 Hutu refugees forced back into Burundi by Tanzanian authorities on January 11 but said some of the refugees were armed and 10 soldiers had been arrested.</p>
<p>Rwandan President Pasteur Bizimungu said 99 percent of Rwanda was calm and the problems in the northwest were a result of Rwandan refugees returning from Tanzania and Zaire without being screened.</p>
<p>Bizimungu said morally Rwanda still supported the ethnic Tutsi Banyamulenge rebels behind the revolt in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>Joseph Bideri, the president's media advisor, said at the airport the government was working to bring peace to Ruhengeri and Kibungo prefectures. &quot;We are killing people but these are the people who carried out the genocide in 1994,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIGALI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
