<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="337451" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Jan 28.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Jan 28.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in Latvian newspapers on Tuesday. Prepared for Reuters by the Co-operation Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- President Guntis Ulmanis visited the foreign ministry to mark the 76th anniversary of Latvia's de jure recognition. At the press conference following the event he announced his support to the government's foreign policy and the activities of Foreign Minister Valdis Birkavs.</p>
<p>- Politicians forecast that President Ulmanis might re-nominate Andris Shkele yet the three major factions have not so far agreed on one common candidate.</p>
<p>- Ulmanis confirmed that this Wednesaday he would nominate the next prime minister regardless of the support for the candidacy of the three major factions. He said the government might be created without one of the major factions.</p>
<p>- Minister of Transport Vilis Krishtopans announced a possible opening of a cargo ferry line between Ventspils and Norkoping. As for the passenger line between Stockholm  and Riga, it may be opened either before the end of this year or at the beginning of the next.</p>
<p>NEATKARIGA RITA AVIZE</p>
<p>- A Lithuanian delegation has been invited to Latvia between January 27 and February 4 to continue talks on the delimitation of the sea border between the two states.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom, +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
