<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="337633" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Minor Metals - Vanadium continues upward march.</title>
<headline>Minor Metals - Vanadium continues upward march.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Minor metal markets showed spotty signs of firmness, with molybdenum and especially vanadium continuing to rise, due in part to supply difficulties, Asian traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Worldwide tightness in the vanadium market continued to drive prices higher, Japan traders said, reflecting cuts in raw material supplies from South Africa, Russia and other sources.</p>
<p>&quot;The point is, there's nobody selling it,&quot; said one trade house source, who added that the latest quotations from Europe were at $18 a kg for ferrovanadium, with prices seen rising further.</p>
<p>Sentiment was also bullish, though less so, for molybdenum, with trouble at a U.S. supplier expected to continue at least through the first half of this year, traders said.</p>
<p>Song Xiaoying, managing director of Shangxiang Minmetals Ltd, expected molybdenum oxide prices to go to $5 a lb, with Chinese molybdenum oxide now at 4.60-4.80 a lb and ferromolybdenum close to $11.20 a kg.</p>
<p>Song, whose Hong Kong-based company represents producers in China of a wide range of base and minor metals, said supply problems in Western countries, coupled with slowed Chinese output during winter, would keep supply tight in the near term.</p>
<p>Official Chinese molybdenum production figures for 1996 have yet to be released, though Song estimated total output at 38 million pounds, similar to 1995.</p>
<p>One Japanese trader said there were offers at $10 a kg for low quality Chinese ferromolybdenum, but the quality of metal that Japanese users wanted would fetch closer to $12.</p>
<p>In the longer term, however, he said U.S. producers may lift output to cool the market and try to forestall overly volatile price swings.</p>
<p>Chinese magnesium prices were on the rise, one trader said, due to the increase on January 1, 1997 of fees levied on producers and exporters, which added $50 a tonne to prices.</p>
<p>&quot;So producers will get a better price but they will lose market share,&quot; he said, adding they were competing not only with the higher quality European product but also with Russian material that was welcomed by U.S. buyers.</p>
<p>Chinese magnesium was being offered FOB at $2,000 to $2,100 per tonne, he said, compared with the FOB Rotterdam price of $3,300 for much higher quality product.</p>
<p>The closure of plants producing less than 1,000 tonnes of magnesium metal a year would bring a significant cut in China's magnesium output for this year, a European trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Output will fall to 50,000 to 60,000 tonnes, from more than 80,000 last year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the antimony market, traders in China and Hong Kong said activity that marked the beginning of the year had waned.</p>
<p>One source with a European trading firm said traders who had bought antimony earlier this month failed to find buyers.</p>
<p>But antimony was keeping one Guangzhou trader busy with spot business. He said he sold 80 tonnes to Japanese customers on Tuesday morning at an FOB price of $2,350 per tonne at the southern Chinese port of Haikou.</p>
<p>&quot;Sourcing is tight so close to Chinese New Year,&quot; he said. &quot;But in the short term I don't see any slowdown.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders gave the following current prices for minor metals, on a CIF basis at major Japanese ports, except for antimony, which is FOB southern China:</p>
<p>						Jan 28	    Jan 21</p>
<p>    Cobalt (high grade, $/lb)    $21.00/22.00    $21.00/22.00</p>
<p>    Cobalt (Russian, $/lb)	 $19.00/20.00    $19.00/20.00</p>
<p>    Molybdenum Oxide ($/lb)	 $4.70/4.80	$4.40/4.70</p>
<p>    Ferromoly (Chinese, $/kg)    $11.00/12.00    $10.00/11.00</p>
<p>    Magnesium (Chinese, $/tonne) $2,450/2,550    $2,450/2,550</p>
<p>    Antimony (Chinese, $/tonne)     $2,350	 $2,300/2,400</p>
<p>--Lynne O'Donnell, Shanghai Newsdesk +86-21-6279-7004</p>
<p>--Edmund Klamann, Tokyo Commodities Desk +81-3-3432-6179</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
