<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="337697" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish beet producers seek 1997/98 price rise.</title>
<headline>Turkish beet producers seek 1997/98 price rise.</headline>
<byline>Ercan Ersoy</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's 1996/97 sugar beet harvest has ended with an improved crop that will allow for more exports, but farmers told the government on Tuesday they will need a large rise in purchase prices in 1997/98.</p>
<p>&quot;The harvest has been completed and better results will be obtained,&quot; said Selahattin Hun, general manager of state sugar refineries Turkseker, which operates 25 of the 28 refineries in Turkey.</p>
<p>He said Turkey would achieve increassed output in 1996/97 and Turkseker planned further exports after selling 50,000 tonnes earlier this month to a local trader.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to calculate our stocks carefully. We will definitely have some surplus and some 50,000 tonnes more is planned for exports,&quot; he told Reuters on the sidelines of the general assembly of Pankobirlik, a union of cooperatives representing 450,000 growers in Turkey.</p>
<p>Turkseker earlier said some 300,000 tonnes could be earmarked for exports in 1997.</p>
<p>A Pankobirlik report presented at the meeting said the union expected 2.05 million tonnes of sugar production in 1997/98, up from 1.85 million tonnes in 1996/97.</p>
<p>It said consumption was expected to reach 1.95 million tonnes in 1997/98, up from 1.9 million 1996/97.</p>
<p>A Pankobirlik official said the total beet area was 422,000 hectares in 1996/97 with an expected beet output of 12.981 million tonnes, up from 312,000 and 10.989 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Industry Minister Yalim Erez reiterated the sugar production figure of 1.85 million tonnes for 1996/97 and told the meeting Turkey would not be a sugar importer again.</p>
<p>But Pankobirlik president Mehmet Bayrakli said that unless beet farmers were satisfied with beet purchase prices for 1997/98 Turkey would face a shortfall and imports could follow in calendar 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;The government first gave a good base price last year, but they failed to keep their promise of increasing the base price in line with inflation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the government makes the same mistake this year our sugar production will not suffice.&quot;</p>
<p>The government usually announces beet purchase prices in the spring.</p>
<p>Turkey imported about 500,000 tonnes of sugar in calendar 1996, up from 400,000 tonnes a year earlier, the Pankobirlik report said, adding no imports were expected in calendar 1997.</p>
<p>In 1994/95 and 95/96 farmers opted for what were then more profitable crops such as grains, vegetables and cotton.</p>
<p>This reduced overall beet area by 25 percent and led to imports.</p>
<p>The Pankobirlik report suggested a rise in the purchase prices to 11,500 lira per kg for 1997/97 from 4,400 lira.</p>
<p>Erez would not say what kind of rise the government was planning for this year, but told farmers, &quot;The mistakes made in previous years will not be repeated this year.&quot;</p>
<p>He said payments to cover Turkseker's debts to farmers for beet purchases from the 1996/97 campaign would be completed in February. &quot;All payments totalling 55.18 trillion lira from last year's purchases will be paid in February,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Ankara Newsroom, 90-312-4462940</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100128">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
