<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="337673" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan plans first nuke waste shipment to N.Korea.</title>
<headline>Taiwan plans first nuke waste shipment to N.Korea.</headline>
<byline>Alice Hung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan and North Korea on Tuesday forged ahead with preparations to ship some 60,000 barrels of low-level Taiwan nuclear waste to the Stalinist state despite escalating protests in South Korea.</p>
<p>State utility Taiwan Power Co said North Korean advisers had arrived to inspect port facilities at Taiwan's only nuclear dump site, Lanyu island, which is rapidly approaching its capacity.</p>
<p>&quot;We are accompanying people from North Korea to inspect our port at Lanyu,&quot; Taipower official Chen Fan-hsien said on state television.</p>
<p>&quot;The North Korean side then will make shipping arrangements according to port conditions,&quot; Chen said. &quot;North Korea will be in charge of all shipping details under the contract.&quot;</p>
<p>The broadcast said Taipower planned initially to move 40,000 barrels of nuclear waste to North Korea from the Lanyu dump and an additional 20,000 barrels from storage at Taiwan's three nuclear power stations.</p>
<p>Lanyu's 98,112-barrel facility has room for only 440 more barrels, according to recent disclosures by Taiwan Power Co.</p>
<p>The utility gave no shipping timetable, but local media said the first shipment would leave Taiwan as early as February.</p>
<p>There was no evidence to support South Korean state media reports that North Korean ships already had arrived in Taiwan and were waiting to load shipments.</p>
<p>South Korean environmentalists have mounted increasingly militant protests in recent days, burning Taiwan flags and effigies of Taiwan leaders and vowing to begin hunger strikes in a bid to halt the shipments.</p>
<p>South Korea, worried the deal could pollute the Korean peninsula with radioactivity, says there is no verification that the North -- Seoul's arch rival -- can store the waste safely.</p>
<p>Taiwan maintains the Taipei-Pyongyang waste pact complies with all international regulations and that shipments would be securely packed in steel barrels.</p>
<p>The state utility said North Korea's proposed shipping procedures needed approval of the Taiwan cabinet's Atomic Energy Council, requiring a review that could take some time.</p>
<p>Under a January 11 contract, Taiwan Power can ship up to 200,000 barrels of waste to impoverished North Korea, whose secretive nuclear programme has long aroused U.S. and regional suspicions that Pyongyang was building an atomic bomb.</p>
<p>Taipower declined to disclose financial terms, but Taiwan media have said the utility has agreed to pay cash-starved Pyongyang US$1,150 for each barrel it takes.</p>
<p>North Korea's Soviet-inspired heavy-water nuclear programme caused international uproar in the early 1990s, with Washington, Seoul and other Pacific countries alleging it aimed to develop nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>A key concern was a lack of international supervision.</p>
<p>Under intense pressure, Pyongyang agreed in 1994 to freeze and eventually junk the programme in exchange for US$4.5 billion in safer nuclear technology and interim power.</p>
<p>Taiwan has no diplomatic ties with either North Korea or South Korea, both of which recognise Taiwan's own arch rival -- the communist Chinese government in Beijing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
