<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="337882" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ala. defends ban on money for gay campus groups.</title>
<headline>Ala. defends ban on money for gay campus groups.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The state of Alabama told a federal appeals court Tuesday it should be allowed to block college and university groups that promote homosexuality from obtaining state funds.</p>
<p>The 11th Circuit Court of Appeals was asked to uphold a 1992 Alabama law banning public funds for any campus group &quot;that fosters or promotes a lifestyle or actions prohibited by the (state's) sodomy and sexual misconduct laws.&quot;</p>
<p>A federal district judge ruled last year that the law violated the First Amendment to the U.S. Constitution because it limited discussions of sexuality in state universities.</p>
<p>Alabama Assistant Attorney General Tom Parker told a panel of three federal judges state money should not be used to promote the violation of state laws. &quot;This is not protected First Amendment speech when you're advocating violation of a criminal statute,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems highly improbable that the state should be required to fund the advocacy of violating its laws,&quot; he told reporters after the hearing. &quot;This is not a case of the state attempting to silence speech of these organisations.&quot;</p>
<p>American Civil Liberties Union lawyer Matthew Coles argued that the law &quot;inhibits the formation and actions of gay and lesbian groups on campuses throughout Alabama and it ought to be struck down.&quot;</p>
<p>The ACLU challenged the law on behalf of the Gay Lesbian Bisexual Alliance at the University of South Alabama in Mobile. Coles said the group had lost members and funding because of the law's &quot;chilling effect.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Myron Thompson ruled last January that the group &quot;has been denied on-campus banking facilities, disqualified from receiving funding, and subjected to an intrusive and highly personal-fact finding investigation&quot; because of the law.</p>
<p>There was no indication when the appeals court would rule on the case.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
