<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="337823" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Federal probe into mutual funds continuing.</title>
<headline>Federal probe into mutual funds continuing.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>It has been a year since the Illinois General Assembly sent a chill through the municipal bond market by repealing a state subsidy for incinerators -- a move that imperiled nearly $500 million of tax-exempt bonds.</p>
<p>And it has been nearly nine months since the public revelation that the U.S. Justice Department had launched a probe targeting alleged mutual fund retaliation against the state for yanking that subsidy.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the justice department said the investigation into &quot;the possibility of collusive practices that may impact tax-exempt bonds&quot; was continuing.</p>
<p>A source familiar with the investigation said that the department had devoted a lot of effort to the probe, which was active.</p>
<p>Still some mutual funds that bought the incinerator bonds and were contacted last year by the federal agency reported hearing nothing for months regarding the probe. Those funds included John Hancock Funds Inc, Vanguard Group Inc, Scudder, Stevens &amp; Clark Inc, and IDS Mutual Fund Group.</p>
<p>&quot;I haven't heard boo,&quot; said one mutual fund executive.</p>
<p>Some municipal industry observers have speculated that the matter may have became clouded by a subsequent challenge to the legality of certain Illinois certificates of participation that are at the heart of the federal probe.</p>
<p>The probe was spurred by three environmental groups that asked the U.S. Attorney in Chicago to investigate possible antitrust actions on the part of fund managers who snubbed a $52 million state COPs sale shortly after the incinerator subsidy was repealed.</p>
<p>The lack of buyers forced the sale of the two insured COPs issues to be pulled last January, although the issues were eventually sold.</p>
<p>Then in June, a group of Democrats from the Illinois House filed suit charging one of the COPs issues exceeded the constitutional and statutory authority of the Illinois Department of Central Management Services, which entered into a lease-purchase agreement for a building that led to the sale of $19.2 million of COPs.</p>
<p>The U.S. Justice Department spokeswoman declined to comment on any relationship between the COPs lawsuit and the federal probe.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a state lawmaker is mulling the introduction of a bill to reinstate the subsidy -- a move that a top aide to Gov. Jim Edgar, who signed the repeal into law in March, said the governor would likely oppose.</p>
<p>And Illinois has been hit with lawsuits contesting the legality of eliminating the incinerator subsidy. So far the state has also been successful in some of the litigation brought by developers Foster Wheeler Corp, CGE Ford Heights, CGE Fulton and Polsky Energy Corp on behalf of bond-financed incinerator projects in Robbins, Ford Heights, Fulton and Wood River.</p>
<p>Foster Wheeler's lawsuit was dismissed by a U.S. District Court judge in Chicago on Nov. 1 on the grounds the 11th Amendment to the U.S. Constitution precludes lawsuits against states dealing with public funds. The company has appealed the dismissal at the U.S. Appeals Court in Chicago and has refiled its lawsuit in Cook County Circuit Court.</p>
<p>Rick Redmond, a Chicago attorney representing the state, said federal appellate court action on the lawsuit has been staid pending the resolution of the circuit court case, which the state is hoping to consolidate with a similar lawsuit filed by the CGE Ford Heights and Fulton developers.</p>
<p>Some of the CGE developers' lawsuit against the state was dismissed last fall by a circuirt court judge who also removed bondholders as plaintiffs from the case.</p>
<p>Redmond said the state has also filed a motion to dismiss a third lawsuit filed by Polsky Energy in November in Madison County Circuit Court.</p>
<p>Only two of the four incinerators were ever built and only one is operating. All were largely dependent on the state subsidy, which guarenteed the incinerators a higher rate at which they could sell to utilities the electricity they produced.</p>
<p>Larry Collings, public affairs manager for Foster Wheeler's Illinois subsidiary, said the Robbins plant reached full operation last week despite the loss of the subsidy.</p>
<p>&quot;Foster Wheeler never ever walked away from any contract it entered into,&quot; Collings said. &quot;Foster Wheeler is in the project for the long haul.&quot;</p>
<p>In October, Robbins restructured $320 million of unrated bonds it sold for the project in 1994 with lower interest rates and different maturities, covenents, redemption provisions and added credit support from Foster Wheeler.</p>
<p>The CGE Ford Heights incinerator was mothballed last year after the company filed for bankruptcy protection, triggering an event of default on $79.6 million of bonds sold for the project by the Illinois Development Finance Authority in 1994.</p>
<p>A bankruptcy court-approved agreement between the developer and bondholders allowed for interest-only payments on the bonds through October.</p>
<p>Neither the Fulton incinerator, financed with $84.6 million of bonds sold in 1995, or the Wood River project, that had yet to be financed, were built.</p>
<p>((--Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
