<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33794" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks end higher but below 2,000 on CAC.</title>
<headline>French stocks end higher but below 2,000 on CAC.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>French shares finished firmer on Thursday but failed to breach 2,000 on the CAC-40 index, as market operators grew cautious ahead of U.S. jobless figures due on Friday.</p>
<p>The market got a lift from companies' first-half profits, which were well received, and strong German second-quarter growth statistics, which should feed through to the French economy, traders said.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index closed up 11.46 points or 0.58 percent at 1,996.23, while the CAC-40 futures contract was up at 2,003 from 1992 on Wednesday's close.</p>
<p>Volume was a respectable 3.59 billion francs.</p>
<p>Christian Noyer, a senior aide to Economy Minister Jean Arthuis, reaffirmed that France would meet its Maastricht treaty target of three percent of GDP by 1997. Paris must meet that goal to join a single European currency in 1999.</p>
<p>He added that France and Germany both had growth of 0.7 percent over the first half and that the question was whether France would see growth of between 1.5-two percent, or stronger growth of 2.5 or three percent.</p>
<p>But the mood in equities was cautious and operators would watch tomorrow's U.S. jobless data for clues on the next move on U.S. interest rates.</p>
<p>Food group Danone rises 29 francs to 721 on broker upgrades. Goldman Sachs upgraded Danone to &quot;trading buy&quot; from &quot;market performer,&quot; while  Societe Generale Delahaye upped it to &quot;outperform&quot; from &quot;neutral&quot;.</p>
<p>Several stocks traded on expectations of a shakeup of the constituents of the CAC-40 index. Among risers who might join the index were steel producer Usinor-Sacilor, up 3.05 at 75.95, caterer Sodexho up 60 to 2,458,  insurer AGF up 2.90 at 134.60, consumer finance house Cetelem up four to 1,051.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
