<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="338161" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: GREEK CASH RATES HOLD, ECU/DRS STABLE, BONDS SUBDUED.</title>
<headline>GREEK CASH RATES HOLD, ECU/DRS STABLE, BONDS SUBDUED.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek money market rates were fluctuating narrowly in late trade holding morning levels and ecu/drachma was still oscillating in the 303.80/304 band, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been very quiet with the interbank depo and swap curves frozen,&quot; said a money dealer at a private bank. &quot;There has been some deals in tomnext funds but that's about it.&quot;</p>
<p>Banks were split over trading activity in the secondary bond market with some reporting active dealing in recently auctioned FRNs and fixed bonds but others reporting little activity due to pending tax issues, traders said.</p>
<p>Greece will auction 300 billion drachmas of 12-month T-bills on February 3 and issue two-year zero coupon bonds on December 31, the finance ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>The terms of the auction of T-bills will be announced on January 30.</p>
<p>Greek Deputy Finance Minister Nicos Christodoulakis told reporters in late December that Greece would issue two-year zeros and 12-month T-bills on December 31 but apparently changed his mind.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a positive development the treasury has decided to auction the 12-month T-bills,&quot; said a bond trader. &quot;It would be even better if deeds matched earlier announcements.&quot;</p>
<p>The auction of 250 billion drachmas of seven-year floaters with the first coupon set at 12.40 percent produced an average accepted bid of 101.04. Another 75 billion drachmas were allocated in non-competitive bids.</p>
<p>The auction of the three-year, 10.20 percent coupon bond produced an average accepted bid of 99.91. The finance ministry allocated 120 billion drachmas in competitive bid and 36 billion drachmas in non-competitive bids.</p>
<p>The mark was quoted at 156.50/60 drachmas from Monday's 156.560 fix, the dollar at 258.76/86 drachmas from 256.320 and the Ecu at 303.85/95 from 303.900 drachmas.</p>
<p>&quot;Ecu/drachma is trading at 303.93/98 in late dealings close to intraday high of 304 but higher than intraday low of 303.80,&quot; said a forex trader at a foreign bank.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Greece, the domestic money market's biggest player, quoted the following early rates:</p>
<p>** Overnight at 11.90-12.40</p>
<p>** T/N at 11.90-12.40</p>
<p>** S/N at 11.90-12.40</p>
<p>** One week at 11.90-12.40</p>
<p>** Two weeks at 11.80-12.30</p>
<p>** Three weeks at 11.70-12.20</p>
<p>** One month at 11.60-12.10</p>
<p>** Two months at 11.55-12.05</p>
<p>** Three months at 11.40-11.90</p>
<p>** Six months at 11.20-11.70</p>
<p>** Nine months at 11.10-11.60</p>
<p>** Twelve months at 11.00-11.50</p>
<p>--Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
