<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="338109" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: OSCE says no plans to mediate in Serbia talks.</title>
<headline>OSCE says no plans to mediate in Serbia talks.</headline>
<byline>Elizabeth Fullerton</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's main security forum said on Tuesday it had no plans to mediate in talks between the Serbian government and opposition over the disputed results of last November's local polls, which have sparked mass protests.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not brokering any talks because the government does not want that and nor does the opposition,&quot; said Lars Vissing, head of the Danish delegation of the OSCE and chairman of its permanent council.</p>
<p>Vissing gave a news briefing on the occasion of a visit by Serbian opposition co-leader Zoran Djindjic to the Vienna-based Organisation of Security and Cooperation in Europe.</p>
<p>Vissing said the OSCE's task was to protect democracy but that it could not intervene in national politics.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of people have demonstrated daily for the past ten weeks in a bid to reinstate victories by the opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition in Belgrade and 13 other cities, annulled by the ruling Socialists who claimed unspecified &quot;irregularities&quot;.</p>
<p>Djindjic said the Socialist Party of Serbian President Slobodan Milosovic was not ready for talks.</p>
<p>&quot;The basis for any talks is that legality must be restored...Without recognition (of the election results) we are not prepared to talk,&quot; Djindjic said.</p>
<p>The OSCE council backed a report made recently by former Spanish premier Felipe Gonzalez, who visited Serbia on behalf of the organisation to study the polls and found the opposition had won. The report called on Belgrade to respect the results.</p>
<p>&quot;By standing by the Gonzalez report and insisting on the legality of the elections, there can be no support from the IMF (International Monetary Fund) and other organisations for Serbia,&quot; Vissing said.</p>
<p>The opposition leader said the OSCE's backing of democracy in the former Yugoslav republic was all that was needed. He has repeatedly said he does not want sanctions to be imposed.</p>
<p>&quot;If the OSCE insists there must be no compromises over the results, then that is sufficient. There can be no discussion whether the law should be followed 100 percent or 50 percent,&quot; Djindjic said.</p>
<p>&quot;Naturally we will be very grateful to the OSCE if they convince Milosevic to accept the results,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Djindjic said he was confident Milosevic would eventually bow to international pressure.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe when he sees there is no chance of splitting the European Union and that it is too expensive to fight the whole world, then he must give in...I know him.&quot;</p>
<p>The opposition formed a parallel government in the major provincial town of Smederevska Palanka on Tuesday after taking control of Serbia's second largest city Nis on Monday, ousting leftists who had ruled the city since 1945.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
