<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="338289" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: FEATURE-Investors await new Pakistan government.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Investors await new Pakistan government.</headline>
<byline>Amir Zia</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The advent of a pro-business government after Pakistan's election next Monday could prompt renewed direct foreign investment in the nation's battered economy, analysts say.</p>
<p>&quot;If the elections bring a pro-business government which implements a privatisation programme and gives economic incentives, the present downward trend in portfolio and direct investment will be halted in the next financial year (1997/98 July-June),&quot; said analyst Nadeem Naqvi.</p>
<p>Sales of state assets would spur private sector investment in expansion plans and stimulate the energy sector, said Naqvi, head of Research of International Asset Management Co Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;A turnaround in the textile sector, specially the value-added spinning sector, is also expected, boosting investment prospects in Pakistan,&quot; Naqvi said.</p>
<p>An Asian diplomat said major concerns for foreign investors were political instability -- four Pakistani governments have been dismissed on corruption charges since martial law ended in 1985 -- law and order, and inconsistent economic policies.</p>
<p>&quot;If Pakistan manages to overcome these problems, it would boost investors' confidence,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The tax-packed 1996/97 budget, economic woes and political uncertainty have hurt the overall investment climate.</p>
<p>Naqvi said the June budget had had a recessionary impact. &quot;Foreign and local investors started pulling out investments after the budget was announced,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The industry outlook changed dramatically as earnings of industrial units were downgraded by foreigners after the announcement of the tax-laden budget. As political uncertainty increased, they further discounted Pakistan,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Money flowed out of portfolios faster than it flowed in during the first half of 1996/97 as foreign investors siphoned 7.362 billion rupees out of the Pakistani market.</p>
<p>Direct investment flows plummeted as major projects were shelved or delayed by political crises and economic problems.</p>
<p>President Farooq Leghari's November 5 removal of Benazir Bhutto's government on disputed charges of corruption and nepotism had further dampened foreign investors' interest.</p>
<p>Naqvi said direct foreign investment was likely to reach $500-$600 million in 1996/97, against $1.1 billion in 1995/96.</p>
<p>According to the Board of Investment, foreign direct and portfolio investment totalled $1.295 billion in 1995/96 compared to $670 million in 1994/95. Britain, the United States and Japan were the top three sources of investment.</p>
<p>Mahmood Ahmed, vice-president of the Federation of Pakistan Chambers of Commerce and Industry, said investments had been at a near standstill for the past few months.</p>
<p>&quot;Where there were projects, they have either been stopped or delayed. Only 20 percent of the memoranda of understanding signed by the previous government have been honoured,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nor was any attempt being made to help floundering firms. &quot;There are no efforts to revive sick industry as the caretaker government has a short-term agenda,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Investors have grown wary of inconsistent government policies. &quot;For example, the concessions given for setting up industries in industrial zones were withdrawn just 10 months after the announcement,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Naqvi said there had been a &quot;mini-flight&quot; of capital by local investors over the past eight months because of fears of rupee devaluation and high taxes.</p>
<p>A foreign fund manager said the decline in portfolio investment in Pakistan had been aggravated by a general fall from favour of emerging markets, especially in South Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. market is so strong, there is no point in investors coming here,&quot; he said, adding that Pakistan's economic troubles also had an impact on the inflow.</p>
<p>&quot;Pakistan's balance of payments has been exposed...June to December payments were financed through reserve funds and they plummeted to $400 million from $2 billion,&quot; said the fund manager, who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors were hit by the sharp falls in the currency last year which eroded 17 percent against the dollar. There still is a currency risk of 15 to 20 percent in 1997,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>($1 = 40.22 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
