<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="338253" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan to tighten bank capital requirements.</title>
<headline>Pakistan to tighten bank capital requirements.</headline>
<byline>Ovais Subhani</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>State Bank of Pakistan moves to tighten capital requirements could inhibit the growth of banks with low capital bases and big loan portfolios, bankers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The central bank has sent a circular asking commercial banks to submit within three months their current equity positions and minimum capital requirement, factoring in risk-weighted assets.</p>
<p>The circular, received by Reuters on Tuesday, said this was a step towards enforcing internationally accepted standards on capital adequacy on banks incorporated in Pakistan.</p>
<p>Bankers said this could restrict lending or force banks to raise their capital base to stay within the capital adequacy ratio. State banks, most of which have large non-performing portfolios or have very liberal lending policies, would probably be the hardest hit, they added.</p>
<p>The U.S.-based Moody's Investors Services Inc in October assigned not prime long- and short-term bank deposit rating of B2 and a financial strength rating of E to three Pakistani state-run banks. It said they were suffering from poor asset quality, inadequate capital and low profitability.</p>
<p>Analyst Waheed Hasan of KASB &amp; Co said stricter lending regulations in respect to capital adequacy would require banks to conform to the internationally accepted capital standards of the Basle-based Bank for International Settlements. &quot;The new standards will necessitate a risk-adjusted capital adequacy, that is, capital as a percentage of risk-weighted assets, of a minimum of eight percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A foreign banker said most Pakistani banks now calculate capital adequacy as a percentage of total demand and time liabilities, without factoring in risk-weighted assets.</p>
<p>The risk-adjusted capital adequacy ratio of most state-owned commercial banks currently averages around three percent, while most foreign and some new private banks are well above eight percent, said the banker, who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>If the central bank strictly enforces the eight percent risk-adjusted capital adequacy requirement, growth for banks will become increasingly difficult unless they raise fresh capital, retain earnings or cut back on lending, he said.</p>
<p>Hasan said most private banks already had large capital bases, but more stringent measures would inevitably favour well-capitalised foreign banks and some private ones, including Faysal Commercial Bank and Askari Bank.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
