<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33833" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-ORIOLES GET THREE HOMERS IN INNING TO BEAT ANGELS.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-ORIOLES GET THREE HOMERS IN INNING TO BEAT ANGELS.</headline>
<dateline>ANAHEIM, California 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brady Anderson and Todd Zeile hit back-to-back home runs and Rafael Palmiero added a two-run homer, all in the sixth inning, as the Baltimore Orioles beat the California Angels 4-2 Wednesday.</p>
<p>Anderson, who got his 44th home run of the season, is 11-for-29 with six homers and nine RBI in his last eight games. Zeile is 11-for-23 with three homers in six games since joining the Orioles. Palmeiro's shot was his 32nd of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;We have the type of offence that can put up a big inning like that,&quot; Anderson said of the four-run sixth inning off knuckleballer Dennis Springer (4-4).</p>
<p>&quot;It was a big win, it would've been an average trip if we'd lost tonight.&quot;</p>
<p>The Orioles completed their road trip 4-3 and remained four games behind first-place New York in the American League East. Baltimore, a game behind Chicago in the wild card race, increased its major league-leading home run total to 225.</p>
<p>Scott Erickson (10-11) won for the fifth time in six decisions, allowing two runs -- one earned -- and five hits over 7 1/3 innings.</p>
<p>Baltimore designated hitter Eddie Murray went 1-for-4 without a homer, leaving him one shy of the 500 mark.</p>
<p>In Oakland, Andy Pettitte pitched seven strong innings to become the first 20-game winner in the American League and Paul O'Neill and Tino Martinez homered as the New York Yankees defeated the Athletics 10-3.</p>
<p>Pettitte allowed three runs and seven hits, walking one and striking out seven in becoming the first 20-game winner in the A.L. since Jack McDowell won 22 games with the Chicago White Sox in 1993. He struck out six of the first seven batters he faced and improved to 13-2 after Yankee losses.</p>
<p>The Yankees finished 4-6 on their 10-game West Coast trip.</p>
<p>Oakland starter Dave Telgheder (2-6) was tagged for six runs and six hits over 2 1/3 innings.</p>
<p>In Chicago, Harold Baines's run-scoring single snapped a seventh-inning tie and Frank Thomas added a three-run homer in the eighth to lead the White Sox to an 11-6 victory over the Detroit Tigers.</p>
<p>Tony Castillo (3-3) worked 2 2/3 scoreless innings for the victory.</p>
<p>Chicago has won six of its last seven games and handed Detroit its fourth loss in five contests.</p>
<p>Curtis Pride homered for Detroit and Tony Phillips homered and had three hits, three RBI and three runs for Chicago.</p>
<p>In Seattle, Rudy Pemberton and Bill Haselman stroked two-run doubles and Heathcliff Slocumb made the lead stand up by getting the final five outs as the Boston Red Sox defeated the Mariners 7-5 in the rubber game of a three-game series.</p>
<p>Boston reliever Pat Mahomes (2-4) notched the victory with 1 2/3 innings in relief of starter Mike Maddux. Vaughn Eshelman, Mark Bradenburg and Slocumb combined to hold the Mariners scoreless over the last three innings.</p>
<p>Seattle starter Sterling Hitchcock (12-8) took the loss.</p>
<p>Jay Buhner hit his 39th homer and Ken Griffey Jr his 43rd for Seattle.</p>
<p>The Mariners fell three games behind the White Sox in the race for the wild-card spot and are six games behind the Rangers in the A.L. West.</p>
<p>The Red Sox are 3 1/2 games behind Chicago and 6 1/2 games behind the Eastern Division-leading New York Yankees. Boston has won 23 of its last 31 games.</p>
<p>In Milwaukee, Chad Ogea pitched a four-hitter for his first career shutout and Jim Thome and Kenny Lofton homered as the Cleveland Indians defeated the Brewers 7-0 to salvage the final game of a four-game series.</p>
<p>All four hits off Ogea (8-5) were singles as Cleveland avoided its first series sweep in nearly three months.</p>
<p>Lofton's 13 homers and 185 hits are career highs.</p>
<p>In Texas, Scott Stahoviak homered with one out in the third to lift the Minnesota Twins to a 7-6 victory over the Texas Rangers.</p>
<p>Juan Gonzalez hit his 42nd homer and Dean Palmer his 34th in the second inning when Texas scored six runs to tie the game at 6-6 before Stahoviak's blast brought in the last run of the game.</p>
<p>Rich Becker homered for Minnesota in the first.</p>
<p>Rich Robertson (7-13) allowed one run and four hits over 5 1/3 relief innings for the win. Mike Trombley threw 2 1/3 scoreless innings for his fourth save.</p>
<p>In Toronto, Woody Williams allowed five hits over eight innings and Carlos Delgado hit a three-run homer to cap a five-run sixth as the Blue Jays ended a five-game losing streak with a 6-0 victory over the Kansas City Royals.</p>
<p>Williams (2-2) walked two and had a career-high nine strikeouts in the longest outing of his career.</p>
<p>Jose Rosado (5-5) took the as the Royals had a four-game winning streak stopped.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANAHEIM, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
