<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33835" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CYCLING-BOARDMAN GOES FOR ONE-HOUR RECORD.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-BOARDMAN GOES FOR ONE-HOUR RECORD.</headline>
<dateline>MANCHESTER, England 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>World champion Chris Boardman, who says he is enjoying the best form of his life, goes for the world one-hour cycling record on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not going to be a cruise, however,&quot; the Briton said after a workout on the 250-metre wooden track at Manchester Velodrome where a week ago he won the world 4,000 metres pursuit title with a world record best of four minutes 11.114 seconds.</p>
<p>With 55.291 kilometres to beat to regain the blue riband of records, he said: &quot;Racing against the clock I am going better than ever, that is why I decided to go for it.</p>
<p>&quot;I have a good chance and I hope to beat it by 10 metres. It is such a tremendous standard that Tony Rominger has set, and any future improvements will be by bits.&quot;    </p>
<p>In half-an-hour's workout on Wednesday Boardman maintained a 55-kph pace, but pointed out that he had to keep that up -- and more -- for a full hour.</p>
<p>&quot;I am prepared to lose. I will treat it like a defeat in any other race. Conditions are not perfect.&quot;</p>
<p>Boardman said the temperature was nearly four degrees colder than he would like, but the long-range weather forecast promised a change to the temperature and humidity.</p>
<p>It will be nothing like his first hour record on the indoor track at Bordeaux in France.</p>
<p>&quot;It was the worst possible conditions. Eighty per cent humidity in a building with a tin roof in the middle of summer in France,&quot; said Boardman. But he still broke the record with 52.270 kms.</p>
<p>Graeme Obree recaptured the record in April 1994, but Spain's Miguel Indurain. then Rominger pushed the record further away, all riding on the Bordeaux track.</p>
<p>Switzerland's Rominger established the last record in November 1994.</p>
<p>Boardman has had to modify the Superman posture, developed by Obree, that he used to win the world title last week.  In this riding position a rider's arms are fully outstretched.</p>
<p>&quot;After 20 kilometres of riding it become a problem for the shoulder muscles, so I have changed my position so that there is support from my skeletal structure.</p>
<p>&quot;It means losing some ground, but those muscles are used for steering, and when you are taking two to three Gs on the banking at the track bends that is important.&quot;</p>
<p>Boardman is ready to try again if Friday's attack fails. &quot;It depends on the reasons for missing it. If it is something that we can change, then I may try again. Maybe not the next day but possibly in a week's time.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANCHESTER, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
