<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="338411" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Eagle Financial Corp to acquire MidConn.</title>
<headline>Eagle Financial Corp to acquire MidConn.</headline>
<dateline>BRISTOL, Conn. 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eagle Financial Corp said Tuesday it had signed an agreement to buy MidConn Bank in a tax-free exhange of shares, with the merger to boost Eagle's deposits in Hartford County by about 40 percent.</p>
<p>Eagle Financial, the holding company for Eagle Federal Savings Bank, said it would give MidConn sharelholders 0.86 shares of its common stock for each share of MidConn Bank stock they own.  </p>
<p>&quot;Eagle and MidConn customers will both realize the significant advantages of an expanded network of branch and ATM locations,&quot; said Robert Britton, Eagle's chief executive officer.</p>
<p>&quot;Eagle's shareholders will benefit from an in-market acquisition that is accretive to earnings and tangible book value within the first year,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Eagle pegged the aggregate value of the merger at $49.1 million, based upon Eagle Financial's closing stock price of $29.25 per share on Monday.  </p>
<p>Eagle Federal Savings Bank operates 19 branch offices and four supermarket offices in the Hartford market, while MidConn operates ten branches in the central Connecticut market just south of Hartford, the statement said.</p>
<p>MidConn, headquartered in Berlin, Conn., had total deposits of $315 million and $35 million in shareholders' equity on Dec. 31, it said.</p>
<p>Eagle Financial had deposits of $1.07 billion and equity of $105 million on Dec. 31, the statement said.</p>
<p>((- New York Newsdesk, 212 859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISTOL, Conn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
