<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="338833" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oregon regulators set Enron, Portland hearing date.</title>
<headline>Oregon regulators set Enron, Portland hearing date.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-01-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Enron Corp said on Monday its proposal to acquire Portland General Corp would be presented directly to the Oregon Public Utility Commission in a public meeting on February 14.</p>
<p>This was the first date all three of the commissioners are available, Enron said.</p>
<p>Previously, the company had expected settlement of last week's conferences with the commission's staff to result in the issue of a final recommendation and proposed order on January 31, with the commission seen making a final decision on March 17.</p>
<p>The companies and the staff were unable to resolve their differences last week and the meetings ended without an agreement, Enron said.</p>
<p>It said unresolved issues included a staff proposal to require payments from Enron's existing and future non-regulated competitive businesses for Portland General Electric's customers.</p>
<p>The &quot;staff's proposal requests cost savings that Enron and PGC believe far exceeds the level of cost savings that could be achieved by the merger&quot;, Enron said.  </p>
<p>The staff's proposal would fund additional rate cuts for the power customers by taking revenues from Enron's non-regulated businesses without the customers assuming the costs and risks of such businesses, it added.</p>
<p>It noted both Enron and Portland General have asked that as a condition of the merger the commission require the segregation of the costs, risks and benefits of regulated and non-regulated activities.</p>
<p>&quot;Our merger does not contemplate the employee layoffs or significant short-term cost cutting typical of mergers between neighbouring utilities or overlapping competitors,&quot; said Enron chief executive Kenneth L. Lay.</p>
<p>--New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
