<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33889" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIA BUDGET DEFICIT UP AT 72.4 BLN LEVS AUG 31. [CORRECTED 15:45 GMT]</title>
<headline>BULGARIA BUDGET DEFICIT UP AT 72.4 BLN LEVS AUG 31. [CORRECTED 15:45 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's central government budget deficit rose by 2.7 billion levs in the second half of August to 72.4 billion levs or 89.7 percent of the revised 1996 deficit target, finance ministry figures show.</p>
<p>Expenditure rose by 12.7 billion levs to 235.3 billion levs between August 17-30, which is 53.6 (corrects from 76.3) percent of that planned for the whole year in the revised budget.</p>
<p>Revenue grew by 10 billion levs to 162.9 billion levs or 45.5 (corrects from 65.1) percent of the target.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's parliament revised on July 30 the country's 1996 budget in a move to meet higher foreign and domestic debt payments and to keep the structural reform on track.</p>
<p>Revenue was set at 358.2 billion levs and spending at 438.9 billion levs. The deficit was assumed at 4.9 percent of gross domestic product or 80.7 billion levs, up from the original 58.3 billion levs.</p>
<p>Under the revised 1996 budget Bulgaria will allocate  52.6 percent or 321 billion levs of expenditure planned for the year to cover interest payments on foreign and domestic debt. -- Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
