<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="338807" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSTANT VIEW - US Q4 employment costs up 0.8 pct.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - US Q4 employment costs up 0.8 pct.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are comments from economists after the Labor Department reported that its employment cost index rose 0.8 percent in the fourth quarter against a 0.6 percent gain in the third quarter.</p>
<p>U.S. economists in a Reuters survey expected a 0.9 percent rise in fourth quarter employment costs.</p>
<p>JAMES GLASSMAN, SENIOR ECONOMIST, CHASE SECURITIES INC: &quot;Although wages have picked up a a little bit, overall compensation which is what matters, is rising barely steadily at three percent. I think this is pretty good news.&quot;  </p>
<p>KEVIN FLANAGAN, ECONOMIST, DEAN WITTER REYNOLDS INC: &quot;It looks as if the market was saved by a smaller than expected increase on the benefits side, but wages were up -- no doubt about it.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is taking some comfort as the number failed to live up to investor expectations which had been priced in yesterday.&quot;  </p>
<p>ASTRID ADOLFSON, FIRST VICE PRESIDENT AND ECONOMIST, MCM MONEYWATCH INC: &quot;It is a very good number. It shows that wages continue to be well contained, and of course the bottom line is that the (Federal Reserve) is on hold.</p>
<p>&quot;The high estimates were too aggressive ... They were just wrong because the minimum wage typically doesn't do much for the total economy. Wages are still contained by the job insecurity.&quot;  </p>
<p>DAN SETO, SENIOR ECONOMIST, NIKKO SECURITIES CO INTERNATIONAL INC: &quot;Obviously the number came in close to expectations. Not much of a surprise. The market, however, was bracing for some upside risk.</p>
<p>&quot;If you take a large perspective it's really kind of curious. The Employment Cost Index rarely moves the market like this, and there's a good reason: it's a lagging indicator. Greenspan had used (ECI) as an excuse not to raise rates all last year, and the markets have followed through and attached greater significance to this number.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;But what we've seen lately is that the Fed's shifted its gears a little and placed more emphasis on the leading indicators. While the argument can be made that the number today does not push the Fed into tightening, it certainly does not prevent them from tightening.&quot;  </p>
<p>EVELINA TAINER, CHIEF ECONOMIST, INDOSUEZ CARR FUTURES: &quot;I think the numbers look really good. Benefit costs ... are still slow on a year-over-year basis. They only rose 2.0 percent. We still can get some ... favorable effects as benefit costs continue to be held in check.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the wages and salaries component though will continue to edge higher going forward. In terms of the Fed, I think that this is going to allow them to hold (rates steady).&quot;  </p>
<p>ROBERT BRUSCA, CHIEF ECONOMIST, NIKKO SECURITIES CO: &quot;The market likes the numbers because they weren't as terrible as what people thought. But it's not a great number. The question is how much impact the minimum wage hike had on wages and salaries.&quot;</p>
<p>Both wages and benefits continue to erode, Brusca said. &quot;It's like finding out you have a slow leak in the ship rather than a big leak...we still have termites in the woodwork.&quot;</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1660 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
