<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33896" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: ROMANIA EX-PREMIER STRIKES POLL PACT WITH MINERS. [CORRECTED 16:52 GMT]</title>
<headline>ROMANIA EX-PREMIER STRIKES POLL PACT WITH MINERS. [CORRECTED 16:52 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Roxana Dascalu</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's first post-communist premier Petre Roman, ousted in 1991 by rioting miners, on Thursday (corrects from Wednesday) struck a deal with pit unions to support his presidential bid in November elections.</p>
<p>Roman, 50, said the pact with the miners' confederation (CNFSMR) would foster mining reforms in line with European Union standards, in exchange for the miners' political support.</p>
<p>&quot;We are getting ready to govern for a durable economic development,&quot; Roman said after signing the agreement with Marin Condescu, whose labour union claims 160,000 members nationwide.</p>
<p>Condescu said his miners were not involved in the violence in early post-communist years staged by vigilante coalminers from the western Jiu Valley led by his rival Miron Cosma.</p>
<p>The 42,000 Jiu Valley pitmen led by Cosma were not part of the deal struck on Thursday (corrects from Wednesday).</p>
<p>Roman hopes the pact with the miners will help him oust President Ion Iliescu at the November 3 elections, which will coincide with parliamentary polls.</p>
<p>&quot;This accord is the groundwork needed in order to avoid social conflicts,&quot; said Roman, who blames the coalminer-led riots that brought him down five years ago on a putsch engineered by communists opposed to market reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;The miners did not come on their own, they were summoned to Bucharest,&quot; Condescu said, adding that his unions and those in related industries could muster around 1.3 million votes.</p>
<p>Six people were killed and hundreds injured when Iliescu summoned Jiu Valley miners to stamp out marathon opposition protests in Bucharest in 1990.</p>
<p>Cosma's coalminers also spearheaded riots in September 1991 when three people were killed, the government building was torched and Roman was forced to quit.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1991 Iliescu signed an illegal document with the leader of the violence in Bucharest,&quot; Roman said, in a reference to a deal which Iliescu signed with Cosma, agreeing to sack Roman.</p>
<p>&quot;I have no hard feelings against the miners. But I'd like Cosma to be brought to justice,&quot; Roman added.</p>
<p>Opinion polls give Iliescu 36 percent in the presidential race, while crediting his main rivals, Emil Constantinescu of the opposition Democratic Convention bloc, with 28 percent, and Roman up to 21 percent.</p>
<p>Miners are still a force to be reckoned with in Romania, an impoverished country where restructuring and privatisation of the economy have been slow over the past five years.</p>
<p>Roman's candidacy is expected to boost the performance of his opposition Democratic Party (PD), which emerged third at local elections in June.  REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I11000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
