<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="339119" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Clyde issues valuation in bid defence.</title>
<headline>UK's Clyde issues valuation in bid defence.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Clyde Petroleum Plc, fighting a 105 pence per share offer from Gulf Canada Resources, on Tuesday released its final defence document, saying its net assets were valued at between 120 and 144 pence per share.</p>
<p>The net asset value estimates were made by Energy Resource Consultants and compare with previous market estimates roughly ranging between 70 and 80 pence per share. Clyde forecast its operating cash flow to grow by 18 percent to at least 150 million pounds ($243.5 million) in 1997.  </p>
<p>UK's Clyde issues valuation in bid =2</p>
<p>Clyde, which also announced a 21.7 percent increase in full-year earnings to 32 million pounds, said independent independent cash flow studies implied that Clyde shares should be trading at at least 144 pence</p>
<p>&quot;Now it is crystal clear quite how seriously Gulf Canada has undervalued Clyde's potential under its existing management team,&quot; said chairman Malcolm Gourlay in a statement.</p>
<p>Managing director Roy Franklin said: &quot;Whether you use cash flow multiples or net asset values, Gulf Canada's offer comes nowhere near the value of Clyde's existing business let alone its future potential.&quot;</p>
<p>Gulf Canada Resources launched its hostile 432 million pound bid for Clyde on December 18 and extended its offer yesterday until February 4 after it received acceptances for around 0.17 percent of Clyde's shares. ($1=.6161 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
