<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="339412" id="root" date="1997-01-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam puts cap on foreign beer ventures.</title>
<headline>Vietnam puts cap on foreign beer ventures.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1997-01-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam said on Tuesday it had temporarily closed the door on foreign beer producers in a bid to protect local manufacturers in an already overcrowded market.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea of the government is temporarily to stop calling for investment in this field,&quot; said Vu Huy Hoang, General Director of the Ministry of Planning and Investment's Foreign Investment Department.</p>
<p>&quot;I mean just for some years, because...production is a little higher than demand. Therefore it is not necessary for us to set up new breweries and new production units.&quot;</p>
<p>Beer is big business in Vietnam, where men crowd into open-air bars to sup unpasteurised brews -- known as &quot;bia hoi&quot; -- fresh from the barrel.</p>
<p>Once the domain of local brewers, &quot;bia hoi&quot; is now also produced by foreign ventures, while canned and bottled brands known worldwide such as Tiger, Heineken, Carlsberg and San Miguel have grabbed a large share of the market.</p>
<p>Eleven foreign-backed firms, with total capital of some $370 million, have now been licensed. Hoang said their production capacity, of about 400 million litres a year, was equivalent to around 55 percent to 60 percent of the country's total capacity.</p>
<p>Hoang said the government had also decided to refuse new licences for foreign-invested soft drinks ventures, unless they agreed to use raw materials from Vietnam.</p>
<p>The Ministry of Planning and Investment's weekly magazine, the Vietnam Investment Review, said recently that the beer and soft drinks plan was being considered in reaction to an outcry by local manufacturers who had lost market share to global giants.</p>
<p>&quot;Tribeco, a local soft drinks maker, had a large market share before Coca-Cola and PepsiCo came to town,&quot; it said. &quot;Tribeco had to close down one of its Ho Chi Minh City factories when sales dropped.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
