<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33973" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Dylex to consolidate Braemar, Fairweather.</title>
<headline>Dylex to consolidate Braemar, Fairweather.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian retailer Dylex Ltd said on Thursday that it was consolidating the infrastructures of its Braemar and Fairweather women's clothing chains.</p>
<p>&quot;The synergies generated from consolidating Braemar and Fairweather will put Dylex in a position to dominate the women's specialty store market in Canada, and will result in significant overall cost reductions which should begin to be realized in the next fiscal year,&quot; Dylex president and chief executive officer Elliott Wahle said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The 62-store Braemar chain and 73-store Fairweather chain will fall under the leadership of Steven Somers, currently president of Fairweather.</p>
<p>Dylex earlier today reported a second-quarter profit of C$0.01 per share, down from C$0.03 a share a year earlier.</p>
<p>In the first six months ended August 3, Dylex posted a loss of C$0.10 a share compared to a loss of C$0.18 a share in the first half of last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite a difficult retail environment in the first half of 1996, we are cautiously optimistic about our company's prospects for this year,&quot; Wahle said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Our overall strategy of gaining efficiencies through the centralization and standardization of corporate functions is well underway, and we believe that the cost efficiencies will be increasingly reflected in our third and fourth quarters,&quot; Wahle said.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
