<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340183" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GDR REPORT-India down after local market falls.</title>
<headline>GDR REPORT-India down after local market falls.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian global depositary receipts eased again on Wednesday after the local market ended a two-day rally with a 2.2 percent fall, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw a small sell-off in GDRs today but nothing big. The local market was led up in speculative trade in the last couple of days but there has been very little foreign participation,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Dealers said a mid-session bout of selling had been comfortably absorbed by the market.</p>
<p>Bombay stocks came under pressure on profit-taking after rising nearly five percent in the past two days.</p>
<p>The trader said GDRs would be less sensitive than the local market to an announcement planned this week on an economic policy package, but could still head lower if it fell short of expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;We are waiting for the speech (by prime minister H.D. Deve Gowda). Unless it has something spectacular we may see a fall,&quot; he said. The HSBC James Capel Indian GDR index closed down 1.04 points at 68.22, with the premium over the local market at 10.98 percent from Tuesday's 9.67 percent.</p>
<p>The Bombay Stock Exchange 30-share index closed 78.23 points lower at 3,525.97.</p>
<p>The Capel Korea GDR Index ended 0.46 point down at 66.01, a premium of 52.51 percent over the local market after the Korea Composite index rose 0.71 point to 663.56.</p>
<p>The Capel Taiwan GDR Index ended 0.32 point up at 98.51, a premium of 5.20 percent after the Taiwan Weighted Index rose 3.33 points to 7,149.54.</p>
<p>-- Andrew Gill, London newsroom 44 171 542 5887</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
