<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340176" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: New York airports generate $200m cargo funding.</title>
<headline>New York airports generate $200m cargo funding.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Port Authority of New York and New Jersey says it has generated almost $200 million in private funding over the past year to redevelop the NY-NJ region's air cargo infrastructure at JFK and Newark international airports.</p>
<p>&quot;This private capital will result in the construction of more than 700,000 square feet of new air cargo space at the two airports,&quot; George Marlin, executive director of the authority, which operates both JFK and Newark, said in a statement issued here.</p>
<p>Three new air cargo facilities encompassing 440,000 square feet are being built at JFK, while at Newark a new 292,000 square-foot international air cargo centre is under construction on the site of the old passenger North Terminal.</p>
<p>&quot;Our marketing efforts at JFK have also secured an air cargo tenant for 250,000 square-feet of space at Building 208 and Hangar 19, which haven't used since the original Pan American World Airways went out of business in 1991,&quot; said Marlin.</p>
<p>&quot;Polar Air will conduct its air cargo and aircraft maintenance operations in that space. In all, more than one million square feet of air cargo space was leased last year at JFK and Newark airports,&quot; he noted.</p>
<p>The Port Authority said the region's three airports -- JFK, Newark and La Guardia -- handled nearly two million tons of air cargo during the first nine months of 1996 compared to a record total of 2.6 million tonnes valued at $130 billion, in 1995.</p>
<p>-Air Cargo Newsroom Tel +44 171 542 7706 Fax+44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
