<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340227" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Golden Rule falls after brokerage report.</title>
<headline>Golden Rule falls after brokerage report.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Golden Rule Resources Ltd lost some of its newfound glitter on Wednesday, falling in heavy trading after a brokerage recommended selling the stock.</p>
<p>ScotiaMcLeod, in a report to its retail sales team, said the stock had risen too high too fast, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Shares in Golden Rule were down C$1.65 to C$11.10 by mid-afternoon, with more than 2.2 million shares trading hands.</p>
<p>The stock has soared since the beginning of the year, to a high of C$13.10 on January 27, from C$5.25 on January 6, on the strength of results from its Ghana gold prospect.  </p>
<p>Initial trenching results from the company's exploration property, the Stenpad gold prospect in Ghana, have caught the market's attention, analysts said.</p>
<p>Drilling is not scheduled to start until March, however, and some analysts have warned the results may be enhanced by surface enrichment, which is common in the area.</p>
<p>&quot;It is likely to be at least two months before questions as to the influence (if any) of enrichment processes in the near surface grades can be answered by drilling,&quot; Yorkton Securities analyst Jim Taylor said in a recent report.</p>
<p>Golden Rule's partner at Stenpad, Hixon Gold, was down C$1.05 to C$11.80 in trading of more than 741,000 shares on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The focus on Golden Rule has put a spotlight on other Canadian companies active in the area around Stenpad, analysts said.</p>
<p>Shares in Nevsun Resources Ltd have risen to C$8 on Wednesday from about C$6.50 at the start of the year. Nevsun is exploring to the northeast of Stenpad.</p>
<p>Opawica Explorations Inc, which is exploring southwest of Stenpad, has risen to C$3.25 on Wednesday from C$2 on January 6.</p>
<p>((Heather Scoffield, Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8104))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
