<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340294" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - Jan 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - Jan 29.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are significant stories in the Nigerian press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY TIMES</p>
<p>- Faced with continuing petrol shortages in the commercial capital, Lagos, government has revived a military task force it first established in 1994 to deal with the problem.</p>
<p>- Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation (NNPC) suspends a new policy insisting that oil marketing companies pay cash down for petroleum products.</p>
<p>- Nigerian Ports Authority official says 3.8 billion naira will be wasted on dredging eastern port of Calabar if new navigational equipment is not put in place along the 80 km (50 miles) river channel.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>- NNPC has withdrawn 15,000 tonnes of aviation fuel which marketers had refused to lift citing quality concerns. Domestic flights have been disrupted by a two week shortage of fuel.</p>
<p>THISDAY</p>
<p>- The central bank has given the go-ahead to commercial and merchant banks for discussions with their long-term creditors on converting debts into equity capital.</p>
<p>- Government will soon restructure the Nigerian Postal Service to improve its efficiency</p>
<p>- Unipetrol says it will soon begin operations at the Freetown oil refinery in Sierra Leone, processing an initial 10,000 barrels per day for consumption in Sierra Leone, Guinea and Liberia.</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
