<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340369" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania to sign $200 mln Chase loan for oil.</title>
<headline>Romania to sign $200 mln Chase loan for oil.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Dascalu</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania will sign next week a long-delayed $200 million loan with Chase Manhattan Corp to allow monthly imports of 800,000 tonnes of crude oil through December, a senior industry official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Vifor Ionita, president of the state-run National Oil Company (CRP), said the accord for the syndicated loan arranged by Chase would be signed on February 3 in London.</p>
<p>&quot;The credit, a revolving one, will help us carry out smoothly our import programme of 800,000 tonnes of crude a month for the rest of the year,&quot; Ionita told Reuters.</p>
<p>The loan, guaranteed by the government, would be given to the state  Petrolexportimport SA, the country's main oil trader, with CRP as the beneficiary of the imports, he said.</p>
<p>CRP is a holding grouping Romania's 12 state-owned refineries, four transport and 41 oil distribution companies.</p>
<p>The signing of the accord with Chase will end months of delays caused by a legal dispute involving CRP and the private local General Trading and Investments Co SA (GTI) company.</p>
<p>Last October, GTI launched a court action to suspend the CRP, accusing it of monopolistic practices.</p>
<p>Chase suspended negotiations on the loan pending court clarification. It eventually accepted a government proposal to arrange the deal with Petrolexportimport.</p>
<p>The suspension of talks disrupted vital supplies of crude oil to refineries during the cold months. Motorists queued for days at petrol stations across Romania.</p>
<p>&quot;Matters are clear now. We can also be part of the deal as last week the court rejected GTI's demands as groundless,&quot; Ionita said.</p>
<p>The CRP is to repay 68 percent of the $200 million loan with earnings from exports of products processed from the imported crude oil, he said.</p>
<p>The rest would come from the country's interbank market and from a fund created by the government last year for energy imports. The accord can be extended for a year if payments are made without disruption.</p>
<p>Romania needs to import large quantities of crude oil for domestic demand and to keep in operation its oversized refining capacity inherited from the former communist regime.</p>
<p>The Balkan country has a refining capacity of 34 million tonnes a year. Under a government project it will be cut to some 18 million over the next few years.</p>
<p>-- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
