<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340320" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania protests go on as investors fear for cash.</title>
<headline>Albania protests go on as investors fear for cash.</headline>
<byline>Crispian Balmer</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanian police broke up a anti-government rally on Wednesday hours after President Sali Berisha said investors caught up in a widespread savings scam might not be fully compensated.</p>
<p>Police swept demonstrators off the streets, punching and jostling people who tried to stay to hear rally organiser Hazem Hajdari, one of the leaders of a 1990 revolt which toppled the former communist regime.</p>
<p>&quot;Look at them, and they call this a democracy,&quot; one woman shouted as determined police officers cleared a crowd of about 200 people from a soccer field on Tirana's outskirts.</p>
<p>Street protests have erupted across Albania since several hugely popular pyramid investment schemes hit trouble, depriving thousands of people of their savings.</p>
<p>The government has frozen some $300 million from two pyramid schemes and Berisha said this would be handed back to investors starting next week.</p>
<p>&quot;The date of February 5th fixed by the government will be the starting date for the distribution (of the funds),&quot; he told his first news conference since the troubles began.</p>
<p>His comments implied that people who put cash into other funds with no bank accounts to freeze might not be so lucky.</p>
<p>&quot;I have never said the people would get all their money back. I have said they would get back the money that has been frozen,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>About 100,000 people are believed to have put money into a high-yielding scheme run by gypsy woman Sude who was arrested after she said she had no money left to repay them.</p>
<p>&quot;Why should people from two of the pyramids get their money back and we get nothing,&quot; said an elderly man at Wednesday's demonstration.</p>
<p>Witnesses saw three protesters bundled into waiting police vans which then sped away. A group of women set upon police officers to prevent them dragging away a fourth person.</p>
<p>&quot;The protests will go on. We will protest in a civilised way to defend the economic and social interests of the workers,&quot; Hajdari, a former student leader, told reporters.</p>
<p>Hajdari, who now heads an independent trade union with an estimated 130,000 members, said a comprehensive solution had to be found to the crisis.</p>
<p>Parliament has given Berisha temporary powers to use the army to maintain order, but the government appeared to be taking no chances by cancelling all sporting events for the rest of the week.</p>
<p>&quot;It was decided that (soccer matches) should not be held this week because the situation is still not calm,&quot; Sports Minister Marjeta Zace said.</p>
<p>Protesters last weekend set fire to government buildings and offices of the ruling right-wing Democratic Party in southern towns, where two failed schemes had been popular. Scores of people were hurt in clashes with police in Tirana on Sunday.</p>
<p>Some analysts have warned that the collapse of the pyramid schemes could unleash financial chaos in the small Balkan state, sparking hyper-inflation and causing an economic slump.</p>
<p>Berisha stressed that the government would not print money just to bale out the luckless investors. &quot;We are determined...to ensure the stability of the currency. There is no greater enemy of the poor than inflation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But the finer details of such economics may well be lost on many Albanians, especially impoverished rural workers, who just want their money back.</p>
<p>Economists say up to $1.5 billion may be tied up in the various schemes, some of which are still active.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
