<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340306" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - Jan 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - Jan 29.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- The government has announced a timetable for finding a strategic equity partner for South African Airways  SAA.CN, a foreign equity partner for the Airports Company and for the privatisation of state-owned Sun Air.</p>
<p>- Details of how security policemen burned the bodies of anti-apartheid activists in the 1980s were released at a news conference held by the &quot;truth commission&quot;.</p>
<p>- The Gauteng housing and land affairs department is to introduce new housing legislation this year, paving the way for a development fund. Around two billion rand in private sector money is already under negotiation.</p>
<p>- Three-quarters of South Africa's chartered accountants leave the country soon after qualifying and only about a third of them return, according to research by auditing firm Deloitte and Touche.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- The average rate of consumer price inflation fell to a 24-year low of 7.4 percent last year, despite rising to 9.4 percent last month, the Central Statistical Service (CSS) said.</p>
<p>- Anglo American and its foreign minerals division Minorco have emerged as the leading contender in Brazil's plans to sell a controlling interest in Companhia Vale do Rio (CRVD), the country's largest mining company, Brazilian sources said.</p>
<p>- Gentyre, the tyre manufacturing group, is believed to have made a profit of 88 million rand for last week's sale of eight million shares in Tiger Wheels Holdings, industry sources said.</p>
<p>- The rand continued its relentless march forward yesterday, strengthening for the fifth day in a row to hit 4.5650 against the dollar in late trade from 4.5840 late on Monday.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SAKE BEELD</p>
<p>- South Africa's average consumer price inflation fell to a 24-year low last year, despite an increase in the inflation rate last month.</p>
<p>- Growth in money supply, as well as the rate of private sector credit extension, slowed more sharply in December than most economists expected.</p>
<p>- Chances are better than half-half that banks' prime lending rates will fall within six months, according to a survey of economists.</p>
<p>- Labour federation Cosatu is seriously considering a programme of mass action over proposed legislation on minimum employment standards.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- A group of former security policemen, including a retired general, have confessed to taking part in killing 10 Eastern Cape anti-apartheid leaders, including Steve Biko.</p>
<p>- The theft of an automatic cash-dispenser with about 22,000 rand from police headquarters in Pretoria revealed security gaps which had to be addressed urgently, police said.</p>
<p>- Almost 370,000 households in Johannesburg's Southern Metropolitan Council area who are in arrears on rates payments could face a legal battle to hold on to their properties.</p>
<p>--- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
