<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340406" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania oil output flat at 6.6 mln tonnes in 1996.</title>
<headline>Romania oil output flat at 6.6 mln tonnes in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil extraction in Romania last month rose 41,000 tonnes from November to 566,000 tonnes, bringing 1996 output to 6.6 million tonnes (around 132,000 barrels per day), unchanged from the previous year's level, the Industry Ministry said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The ministry's oil and gas department said gas output last year was down to 18.2 billion cubic metres from around 19 billion in 1995, with December production rising to 1.77 billion cubic metres from 1.61 billion in November.</p>
<p>Romania plans this year to keep crude oil production at the 1996 level. But to meet domestic demand and keep its 12 refineries in operation, Romania will have to resort to imports, ministry sources said.</p>
<p>No estimate was immediately available for oil imports this year. Over Jan-Nov last year, Romania imported 6.5 million tonnes, according to latest statistics.</p>
<p>Romania plans gas output of 17.1 billion cubic metres this year. Gas imports are estimated at 7.0 billion cubic metres, close to 1996 import levels, the department said.</p>
<p>In a attempt to boost crude output -- which has been sliding for 20 years from peaks of 14 million tonnes in the early 1970s -- Romania has launched a licensing round for 15 onshore and offshore prospective oil blocks.</p>
<p>The National Agency for Mineral Resources said some 50 oil operators had bought packages of data on the blocks. Offers have yet to be evaluated and successful bidders announced. Winners will be able to start work on the blocks in June.</p>
<p>Romania has 186 million tonnes of recoverable oil in its known reserves, according to sources with oil exploration company Petrom RA.</p>
<p>-- Luli Popescu, Bucharest Newsroom +40 1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
