<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340563" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ECUADOR: Anti-reform protesters holed up in Quito cathedral.</title>
<headline>Anti-reform protesters holed up in Quito cathedral.</headline>
<dateline>QUITO, Ecuador 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of demonstrators gathered inside the Quito Cathedral in Ecuador on Wednesday to protest against economic reforms and demand the ouster of President Abdala Bucaram.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been in the cathedral since 6 a.m.  (1100 GMT) and we won't leave until our views are taken into account,&quot; farm workers leader Cesar Cabrera told Reuters.</p>
<p>Local radio said special police squads were preparing to evacuate the building.</p>
<p>The protest, just a few steps away from the government palace, was organised by the Coordinating Board for Social Protests which groups trade unions and women's, indigenous and Christian organisations.</p>
<p>Cabrera said a deputy of indian descent, Manuel Lluco, and the former president of the CONAIE indigenous peoples federation, Jose Maria Cabascagno, were among the protesters.</p>
<p>CONAIE is the most powerful indigenous group in Ecuador, whose population is 47 percent of indian origin.</p>
<p>Cabrera said the Board sought the repeal of huge public tariff hikes and plans to launch a currency convertibility plan pegging the sucre, the Ecuadoran currency, to the dollar.</p>
<p>It also wants a plebiscite on the government's privatisation plans and is demanding the ouster of President Abdala Bucaram and the impeachments of Energy Minister Alfredo Adum and State Prosecutor Leonidas Plaza.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision of the Board is to stay at this site indefinitely. We call on all believers and Christians to come to the cathedral and back this occupation,&quot; Cabrera said.</p>
<p>Students have led violent protests in recent weeks and the unions called a general strike for Feb. 5 in reaction to economic cutbacks by the six-month-old Bucaram administration.</p>
<p>The measures have caused electricity and gas rates to soar more than 200 percent and public transport fares to rise 60 percent. Telephone rates were also expected to shoot up.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="QUITO, Ecuador"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ECUADOR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
