<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340577" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Salinas blames power struggle for Mexico's 1994 woes.</title>
<headline>Salinas blames power struggle for Mexico's 1994 woes.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Mexican President Carlos Salinas de Gortari, breaking a silence in self-imposed exile, blamed Mexico's political and economic crises of 1994 on a tremendous power struggle but refused to identify the people involved.</p>
<p>In his first interview to discuss his 1988-94 presidency since leaving office, Salinas told the daily newspaper Reforma in an article published on Wednesday he was still proud of many of his reforms.</p>
<p>He declined to answer questions about his successor, President Ernesto Zedillo.</p>
<p>Reforma said two more sections of the interview would follow on Thursday and on Friday.</p>
<p>Many of Reforma's questions concerned the March 1994 assassination of ruling party presidential candidate Luis Donaldo Colosio, Salinas's hand-picked successor. Opponents of Salinas have accused him of plotting the murder after falling out with Colosio, a charge Salinas has always strongly denied.</p>
<p>Colosio's murder, along with the Zapatista Indian uprising of January 1994, and the September 1994 killing of a top ruling party politician, formed part of Mexico's disastrous year of 1994.</p>
<p>Those shocking events helped trigger the December 1994 collapse of the peso, plunging the economy into recession.</p>
<p>The interview was conducted in Boston, Massachusetts, and was keenly awaited here because Salinas -- who fled Mexico in disgrace in March 1995 after his brother Raul was arrested on murder charges in the assassination of another politician -- had hitherto refused to discuss his presidency.</p>
<p>Salinas now lives in a self-imposed exile in Ireland, and is a frequent visitor to the United States.</p>
<p>Salinas told Reforma Colosio's murder &quot;seriously damaged&quot; his political and economic reform programmes, and said enemies of reform tried to force a successor on him after Colosio was gunned down at a campaign rally in the border city of Tijuana.</p>
<p>&quot;Although to date the investigation has not turned up proof to confirm a conspiracy to kill Luis Donaldo, I do believe there was a conspiracy to try to impose a substitute (candidate),&quot; he said. &quot;Those behind it seem to continue relentlessly in the tremendous struggle for power.&quot;</p>
<p>Salinas told Reforma that even before Colosio's funeral, infighting was rife in the Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI) over the selection of another presidential candidate.</p>
<p>Mexican presidents traditionally choose their successors but Salinas said he was subjected to &quot;offensives&quot; from people inside the PRI promoting their candidates.</p>
<p>Former President Luis Echeverria (1970-1976) put forward Emilio Gamboa, Salinas's former Transport and Communications Minister, and other Colosio followers tried to veto Zedillo, Salinas said.</p>
<p>Zedillo eventually was chosen to be the PRI candidate and went on to win a resounding victory in the August 1994 vote.</p>
<p>Salinas said the disasters that struck Mexico in 1994 &quot;could not be understood without linking them to the profound reforms previously carried out and, above all, in the face of the interests affected by them.&quot;</p>
<p>Salinas said reforms that hurt interest groups included greater democracy, accepting opposition victories for the first time in governorship elections, making vote fraud more difficult and creating the openly critical National Human Rights Commission.</p>
<p>&quot;Every one of the changes impacted interest groups that supported and benefited from existing structures and that for decades had blocked the country's progress,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Reforma made available the whole text of the interview free on the Internet at its site: http://www.infosel.com.mx.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
