<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340534" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: FORECAST-Net 1996 loss seen for Vitro.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Net 1996 loss seen for Vitro.</headline>
<dateline>MONTERREY, Mexico 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Glassmaker Vitro is expected to post a net loss for 1996 due to selling U.S.-based Anchor Glass Container Corp., but should show improved operating results for its basic divisions, analysts said.</p>
<p>A survey of five analysts showed average predicted losses of of 10.03 pesos per share for 1996, with estimates ranging from 9.01 to 11.37 pesos per share.</p>
<p>Santiago Pique, of Bear Stearns in New York, estimated net losses of $3.46 per ADR, equivalent to three nominal peso-denominated shares, but noted the market had already discounted these losses.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market has discounted 1996 and is looking ahead to 1997. It doesn't matter whether the (net loss per ADR) is three, four or five dollars per share, that's irrelevant. What the market is looking for is the operating side, which are Vitro's basic operations, its five divisions,&quot; Pique said.</p>
<p>Vitro's flat glass division was the most likely to rebound in the near future, Pique said, due to a recovery in the auto and construction industries.</p>
<p>Sandra Morfin of Caspian Securities agreed that operating results were the ones to look for.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're expecting operations to improve... Also, a weaker exchange rate could help to improve Vitro's operating performance in the fourth quarter, compared to the third,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Sergio Torres, an analyst with Inverlat International, estimated an operating margin of 18.7 percent for 1996, compared to approximately 23 percent in 1995, after adjusting for the sale of Anchor Glass.</p>
<p>&quot;I see no nasty surprises, we all know Vitro is going to post a loss for 1996. There could, rather, be pleasant surprises,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Torres also pointed to the company's basic divisions.</p>
<p>&quot;Domestic appliances could have had a good 1996, due to exports... Flat glass, on the other hand, could not export as much as it wanted, so its 1996 operating margin may fall to 22 percent, from 23.8 percent in 1995,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Envases Mexico (containers) will be good...with margins around 19.8 percent, compared to 18 percent in 1995,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>((--Jacqueline Lerma, Monterrey bureau, +528 345-7677))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTERREY, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
