<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340624" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: FORECAST-Bufete 1996 loss seen narrowing.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Bufete 1996 loss seen narrowing.</headline>
<dateline>MONTERREY, Mexico 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican construction company Bufete Industrial SA is expected to post a much more narrow loss for 1996 as the company begins to leave the dark days of 1995's recession behind, analyst said.</p>
<p>Five analysts surveyed forecast an average net loss of 1.45 pesos per CPO share for 1996, down from a net per-share loss of 8.97 pesos in 1995.</p>
<p>Analysts said, however, that net losses for the year were less important than a rebound in revenues and operating earnings, lower financial costs and a bulkier backlog of projects.  </p>
<p>&quot;Bufete had a strong fourth quarter, but it won't be as meteoric as the third quarter of '96.  I believe revenues and operating income for the fourth quarter could be lower than those of the third quarter,&quot; said Ben Uglow, an analyst with Flemings Research in New York.</p>
<p>Bufete may post sales of 4.364 billion pesos for 1996, 46 percent more than in 1995, Gerardo Saenz, an analyst with OBSA-GSerfin brokerage, said.  He said operating earnings could be 184 million pesos, or 148 percent more than in 1995, and net losses be cut from 589 million to just 68 million pesos.  </p>
<p>For some analysts, one of the brighter aspects of Bufete's 1996 performance was to replace costly peso-denominated debt with dollar-denominated debt contracted at more favorable rates.</p>
<p>There were some lingering concerns, however.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to look at the balance sheet.  There are still some concerns regarding working capital and accounts receivable,&quot; said Christopher Hussey, an analyst with Goldman Sachs in New York.  Bufete has a substantial amount of accounts receivable from the Federal Electricity Commission, which have drained its cash flow and raised financial costs.</p>
<p>((-- Daniel Perez, Monterrey bureau +528 345-7617))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTERREY, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
