<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340668" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ commodity prices rose slightly in Dec 1996-ANZ.</title>
<headline>NZ commodity prices rose slightly in Dec 1996-ANZ.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The average New Zealand dollar price of the country's commodity exports rose 0.6 percent in December 1996 after a fall of one percent in November, ANZ Bank said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The corresponding average world price of New Zealand's commodity exports rose 0.2 percent in December after declining 0.5 percent in November.</p>
<p>The New Zealand dollar index rose to 99.6 in December from 99.1 in November, while the World Price index rose to 123.8 from 123.6.  </p>
<p>On an annual basis, the New Zealand dollar index was down 11 percent in December, while the World Price index dropped by 3.1 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Continued weakness in a number of key commodity prices including wool, beef, butter, woodpulp and logs was evident during December,&quot; ANZ said. But the indices were supported by price increases for lamb, cheese, whole milk powder and skim milk powder.</p>
<p>ANZ said 1996 was a mediocre year for commodity prices generally, partly because moderate economic growth in most industrialised countries constrained demand.  </p>
<p>Forestry and dairy prices weakened perceptibly from early 1996, partly due to an increase in world supplies and, in the case of dairy products, some resistance on the part of consumers to high prices.</p>
<p>Chronically weak prices for wool and beef were to some extent offset by strong returns for lamb from mid-1996.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
