<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340722" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Toyota sees more investment in UK as excessive.</title>
<headline>Toyota sees more investment in UK as excessive.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toyota Motor Corp president Hiroshi Okuda said on Wednesday that any additional investment by Toyota in car plants in Britain may be excessive.</p>
<p>&quot;Regardless on whether Britain joins (the EMU), I have a feeling that it would be excessive if we made additional (investments) in Britain,&quot; Okuda told reporters.  </p>
<p>Okuda told reporters at a reception that Toyota would shift its European investments to continental Europe if Britain did not join the European economic monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>Asked if Toyota's future strategy in Britain will change depending on whether that country joins the EMU, Okuda said, &quot;It will change.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if the car maker's investment will decrease if Britain opts out of the EMU, he said: &quot;Rather than decreasing the amount, we will leave investments as they are now. But if we were to make fresh investments, we would prefer to make them in continental Europe rather than Britain.&quot;</p>
<p>Okuda added that Toyota is not currently reviewing its investment strategy in Britain as &quot;everything is still up in air regarding the future of a single European currency&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
