<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340873" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bethlehem Steel lost nearly $350 million in quarter.</title>
<headline>Bethlehem Steel lost nearly $350 million in quarter.</headline>
<dateline>BETHLEHEM, Pa.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bethlehem Steel Corp. said Wednesday it lost nearly $350 million in the fourth quarter of last year as the company's results were impacted by large restructuring charges.</p>
<p>The giant steel maker posted a loss of $346.5 million, or $3.19 a share, on sales of $1.14 billion vs. a profit of $32.4 million, or 20 cents a share, on sales of $1.15 billion in the fourth quarter of 1995.</p>
<p>It said the loss stemmed from previously announced restructuring charges of $450 million to improve its financial performance and boost stockholder value. Excluding the charges, Bethlehem said it earned $23 million.</p>
<p>For the 1996 year, Bethlehem said it lost $308.8 million, or $3.15 a share, on sales of $4.67 billion compared with 1995 profits of $179.7 million, or $1.24 a share, on sales of $4.87 billion.</p>
<p>Bethlehem announced the restructuring in October, including plans to sell Bethlehem Structural, BethForge, CENTEC and BethShip. The company said it is currently negotiating to sell BethForge, CENTEC and BethShip, which had a total operating loss of $218 million in the fourth quarter and a loss of $241 million for 1996.</p>
<p>The company said, however, that it was unable to find a buyer for Bethlehem Structural, and the unit will go out of operation in the first quarter of this year.</p>
<p>&quot;1996 was a very difficult year for Bethlehem, and yet it was a year in which significant actions were taken that will position Bethlehem for improved profitability ...&quot; said Curtis Barnette, chairman and chief executive officer.</p>
<p>&quot;As we enter 1997, we believe that the U.S. economy will continue on a course of moderate and sustainable growth and low inflation,&quot; he said. &quot;We believe that demand from the major steel-consuming sectors will continue to be good and we expect that domestic industry steel shipments in 1997 will be close to the estimated 100 million tons shipped in 1996.&quot;</p>
<p>Bethlehem's stock was up 25 cents at $8.75 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BETHLEHEM, Pa."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
