<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34082" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Sugar freight enquiry scarce, rates stay low.</title>
<headline>Sugar freight enquiry scarce, rates stay low.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>New sugar freight enquiries were thin on the ground on Thursday with Australian shipper CSR providing the only fresh quoted business, shipbrokers said. It quoted for 30,000 tonnes of bulk sugar, with five percent margin, from Queensland to Kaohsiung for 29 September/8 October. The only other firm business came from Czarnikow Rionda, reported to be on subjects with its recent order from Santos to Red Sea options.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very quiet&quot;, one shipbroker said, adding that rates were still on the low side.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, sugar shipments from Thailand slowed this week due to thin physical demand and monsoon rains which hampered traffic and loading.</p>
<p>About 60,000 tonnes of white and raw sugar was expected to be shipped or loaded between August 31 and September 11, mostly headed for Asian destinations, they said.</p>
<p>Market sources said Tate &amp; Lyle bought 25,500 tonnes of bagged white sugar to ship to Pakistan, while Nissho Iwai and Kerry bought 16,600 tonnes of raw sugar for shipment to Japan.</p>
<p>Egypt's state General Company for Wholesale Trade bought 13,000 tonnes of Brazilian sugar for October/November delivery.</p>
<p>Colombia has tendered to sell two cargoes of raw sugar for September shipment dates. The tonnage of the first cargo was between 20,000 and 25,000 tonnes for 5/15 September, and the second for between 10,000 and 15,000 tonnes for 10/20 September.</p>
<p>-- Jeremy Smith, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8064</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
