<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="340870" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Norfolk Southern reports earnings, sets meeting.</title>
<headline>Norfolk Southern reports earnings, sets meeting.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norfolk Southern Corp. said Wednesday a crucial meeting in the takeover battle for Conrail Inc. has been set for Friday and also reported a 13 percent rise in earnings for the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Last week executives of Conrail, CSX Corp. and Norfolk Southern agreed to hold discussions about the planned $9.5 billion merger of Conrail and CSX.</p>
<p>First announced in October, the deal has been fraught with troubles due to a rival $10.3 billion bid from Norfolk Southern. Philadelphia-based Conrail has rejected the Norfolk Southern offer, contending that the CSX deal was a better fit.</p>
<p>But earlier this month Conrail shareholders rejected a key measure needed for the CSX transaction to move forward.</p>
<p>Norfolk Southern Chairman David Goode said while it would be &quot;very difficult&quot; he was confident of reaching a solution in the takeover battle.</p>
<p>During a meeting with financial analysts, monitored by telephone, he also reiterated a pledge to obtain for Conrail shareholders a payment of $115 a share in cash. The Conrail-CSX merger calls for a combination of cash and stock.</p>
<p>Goode told the analysts he was pleased Conrail and CSX Corp. had responded positively to his invitation to meet.</p>
<p>&quot;We have set a meeting Friday, and I plan to be there, ready to work hard for a solution&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some Wall Street experts have speculated that the ultimate conclusion will call for a splitting up of Conrail's assets.</p>
<p>But sources close to Conrail have said its executives would oppose plans to split up the railroad and distribute its pieces to Richmond, Va.-based CSX and Norfolk, Va.-based Norfolk Southern.</p>
<p>In its earnings report, Norfolk Southern said strong rail traffic and tight expense controls offset higher fuel costs.</p>
<p>It said net income rose to $200.5 million, or $1.60 a share, from $176.9 million, or $1.37 a share, in the 1995 quarter. Sales rose 2 percent to $1.18 billion from $1.16 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite an extraordinary rise in fuel prices, we ended 1996 on a high note, setting records across the board,&quot; Goode said in a statement.</p>
<p>He cited strength in shipments of cars, coal and chemicals and noted the company's North American Van Lines trucking unit had its best operating earnings in nine years.</p>
<p>Transportation expenses actually fell 3 percent in the quarter despite higher fuel costs, Norfolk Southern said.</p>
<p>The results were about in line with expectations but Norfolk Southern stock rose $1.50 to $88.25 in midday trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
