<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34102" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Rugby Union - Counties look to tight five for edge.</title>
<headline>Rugby Union - Counties look to tight five for edge.</headline>
<text>
<p>AUCKLAND, Sept 6 - If Counties are to upset the form book at Carisbrook against Otago in their first division NPC rugby match on Sunday then the tight five forwards have to play above themselves, according to coach Mac McCallion.</p>
<p>It was the tight five that paved the way for wins over Canterbury and Auckland, but they were marginally overshadowed by Waikato in the narrow 31-28 loss, and McCallion expects Otago to be similar in approach to Waikato.</p>
<p>&quot;I know our tight five have been improving. We're one of the teams where our tight five tend to improve over the season instead of hitting their straps early,&quot; McCallion told NZPA.  </p>
<p>&quot;But on Sunday we really need them to be fired up for a big game. We'll be looking for them to give us the edge up front and set the platform so that we can release our backs out wide.</p>
<p>&quot;We also need them to establish a dominance because I think Otago have a very good backrow in Taine Randell at No 8 and Kupu Vanisi with the new boy Kelvin Middleton on the flanks.</p>
<p>&quot;They've got an enormous amount of speed to the breakdowns and I think if our tight five can do the job up front our loosies should be able to handle their own.&quot;</p>
<p>McCallion singled out Vanisi, in particular, as probably the most dangerous of the Otago backrow.  </p>
<p>&quot;The guy is just unbelievable, I think he is the most under-rated loose forward in the country. I rate him extremely highly,&quot; McCallion said.</p>
<p>McCallion has been stunned too that Otago coach Glen Ross has until this week kept his former captain John Leslie on the sidelines.</p>
<p>Otago have lacked vision and organisation in the midfield, resulting in their outside backs scoring just one try in two games.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think the teams that have played against Otago so far have been really surprised that Leslie hasn't been there. I'd have been most thankful if he weren't there again on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;He's got that ability to direct the team and get the backs going which Otago seemed to have lacked and I can't understand why he has been picked for so long.&quot;</p>
<p>However, Ross has returned Leslie to the midfield for the match against Counties, moving his previously preferred second five-eighth Tony Brown to fullback to cover for injured Greg Cooper.  </p>
<p>Counties in the meantime have replaced Pita Alatini with Paul Tom at fullback, bracketed Ora John and the in-form Craig Glendinning on the openside flank and returned the beanpole lock Gavin Giles to the second row.</p>
<p>&quot;We're the underdogs, but we do know what to expect down there and we expect to give them a bloody good shake,&quot; McCallion said.</p>
<p>Teams --  </p>
<p>Counties: Paul Tom, Joeli Vidiri, George Leaupepe, Tony Marsh, David Wood, Danny Love, Michael Scott, Errol Brain (captain), Ora John or Craig Glendinning, Jim Coe, Gavin Giles, Api Naevo, Lee Lidgard, Andrew Roose, Afa Leu'u.</p>
<p>Reserves: John or Glendinning, Matt Filipo, Chris Nicholson, Chris Rose, Dean Sheppard, Blair Feeney, Pita Alatini.</p>
<p>Otago: Tony Brown, Michael Hanning, Jason Wright, Aporosa Dauvucu, John Leslie, Stephen Bachop, Mark Chapman-Smith, Taine Randell, Kupu Vanisi, Justin Cullen, Lio Falaniko, Kelvin Middleton, Mike Mika, David Latta (captain), Carl Hoeft.  </p>
<p>Reserves: Casey Mee, Paul Martin, Ace Tiatia, John Blaikie, Richie Flannery, two backs to be added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
