<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341198" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Commission proposes VAT on foreign telecoms services.</title>
<headline>Commission proposes VAT on foreign telecoms services.</headline>
<byline>Suzanne Perry</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission proposed legislation on Wednesday that would slap a consumption tax on telecommunications services offered by foreign companies within the 15-nation European Union.</p>
<p>The initiative was prompted by the growing popularity of &quot;callback&quot; services operating in the United States, which allow consumers to bypass high European telecoms costs by routing their calls through U.S. phone lines.</p>
<p>Those calls are not now subject to national value-added taxes (VAT), which range from 15 percent in Luxembourg and Germany to 25 percent in Denmark and Sweden.</p>
<p>The Commission, responding to a unanimous request from EU governments, proposed that foreign firms be required to charge VAT on telecoms services offered to EU customers -- putting them on a par with their European counterparts.</p>
<p>&quot;These proposals aim to eliminate the unfair advantage enjoyed now by third-country service providers,&quot; EU Taxation Commissioner Mario Monti said in a statement.</p>
<p>The proposal, which must be agreed unanimously by EU finance ministers, would not apply to Internet or online services when the consumer connects through a local phone call, Alexander Wiedow, an official in the Directorate-General XXI (Indirect Taxation), told reporters.</p>
<p>He said an early draft of the Commission's proposal would have imposed VAT on some &quot;broadcast&quot; services, but was revised to conform with a narrower definition of telecommunications that the EU is advocating in World Trade Organisation talks on telecoms liberalisation.</p>
<p>With callback services, a customer can dial a number, usually in the United States, and get called back with an open line to phone anywhere in the world -- at low U.S. rates.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman in the Brussels office of U.S. phone giant AT&amp;T Corp, which operates a &quot;callback&quot; service known as AT&amp;T International Call Plan, was sanguine about the Commission's initiative.</p>
<p>&quot;We're committed to the European marketplace and will abide by its regulations,&quot; Valerie Hasselbach told Reuters. She added that callback services represented a &quot;huge market&quot;.</p>
<p>But unlike AT&amp;T, many callback services operate only from the United States, raising the question of how the EU could enforce the VAT charges. Wiedow said U.S. companies had informed the Commission they were willing to comply with the rules as long as they had enough time to prepare.</p>
<p>He said authorities can also monitor the tax returns of companies who use the phone services.</p>
<p>Once the regime is fully in place, envisaged for the start of 1999, callback operators will be required to register in an EU country and to collect and pay the VAT themselves.</p>
<p>However, the Commission proposed interim rules that would allow national governments to begin by collecting from callers themselves -- in practice likely to be companies rather than individuals, Wiedow said.</p>
<p>Britain said it faced a potential loss of 800 million pounds ($1.3 billion) a year in tax revenue, Wiedow said.</p>
<p>Consumers may still be able to save money with callback services even with the new VAT charges. Joe Chtouki, marketing director of the Belgian operations of U.S. company European Telecom, told Reuters the price of a Belgian phone call to the United States using a &quot;callback&quot; service was 60 to 70 percent cheaper than if made through a local company.</p>
<p>The Commission has proposed amending the Sixth Directive 77/388/EEC on the uniform basis of assessing VAT. It has also proposed a Council Decision allowing EU states to take urgent action to implement the interim measures.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
