<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341195" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy farmers resume protests in EU quota dispute.</title>
<headline>Italy farmers resume protests in EU quota dispute.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian dairy farmers resumed road blocks and street protests on Wednesday, two days before a deadline to pay hefty European Union fines for milk overproduction.</p>
<p>Farmers in Milan, who staged two weeks of protests to press demands for the government to pay the &quot;super-levy&quot; fines, barricaded one of the northern city's main arteries.</p>
<p>The blockade was lifted after some 10 minutes when police, ordered by Prime Minister Romano Prodi to ensure that traffic and people can move freely, threatened to break it up.</p>
<p>But the protesters took to the streets again an hour later, while in Venice about 100 farmers staged a sit-in on an access road to the city's Marco Polo airport.</p>
<p>A tense stand-off with police also occurred near Milan's main Linate airport, which was cut off last week and briefly closed. Farmers briefly blocked the roads again before being moved on by police.</p>
<p>Farmers' representatives were due to hold fresh talks with Prodi in Rome to try to resolve the dispute before Friday.</p>
<p>The row centres on EU fines of about 370 billion lire ($230 million), due to be paid by Friday, for overshooting Italy's 1995-96 milk quota by some 400,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>The government wants the farmers to pay a first instalment of 25 percent of the fines pending an inquiry, but farmers insist that the overproduction was not their fault.</p>
<p>The government said on Tuesday it was waiting to hear from Brussels whether its instalment proposal would prove acceptable.</p>
<p>It also said it would propose a law including cheap loans and grants to make up for lost farm income and a restructuring of milk production.</p>
<p>Under the quota system, farmers are allowed to produce 9.9 million tonnes of milk, compared with Italy's total consumption of 18 million tonnes. Pinto has formally asked the EU to raise Italy's quota to 10.5 million tonnes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
