<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341102" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Richard Pryor's son, great-grandson hurt in fire.</title>
<headline>Richard Pryor's son, great-grandson hurt in fire.</headline>
<dateline>PEORIA, Ill. 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 2-year-old great-grandson of comedian Richard Pryor was in critical condition on Wednesday after suffering severe smoke inhalation in a house fire that also injured Pryor's son, authorities said.</p>
<p>Firefighters rescued Antwaon Banks from the kitchen floor of the wood frame home while the boy's grandfather, Richard Pryor Jr., 34, escaped Tuesday's early morning blaze on his own, suffering mild smoke inhalation and frostbite, Peoria fire battalion chief Dave Johnston said.</p>
<p>The cause of the fire, which caused an estimated $65,000 in damage, was under investigation, Johnston said.</p>
<p>Pryor, 56, a former drug addict who starred in several movies and comedy albums, suffers from multiple sclerosis and is confined to a wheelchair but still performs occasionally. In 1980 he set himself on fire while preparing &quot;freebase&quot; cocaine. He has been married five times.</p>
<p>Pryor Jr., one of the comedian's four children, was treated and discharged from St. Francis Hospital while his grandson remained there in critical condition, a hospital spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>The central Illinois city of Peoria was the comedian's boyhood home and some of his humour was gleaned from the hustlers, pimps and other characters he met growing up in a whorehouse and bar run by his family.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PEORIA, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
