<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341115" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT wheat mixed awaiting export sales results.</title>
<headline>CBOT wheat mixed awaiting export sales results.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT wheat futures were mixed at midsession as the market sought direction from the export sector, traders said.</p>
<p>The market was rattled early this week by talk India and Egypt were entering the market for optional-origin wheat and wheat futures were showing signs of consolidating in early dealings Wednesday, they said.</p>
<p>There was talk India could be in the market for 50,000 up to 750,000 tonnes and talk Egypt this weekend may be in the market for 400,000 to 800,000 tonnes. But sources said the U.S. remains a wild card in the export derby.</p>
<p>European exporters said France could sell between 200,000 and 300,000 tonnes to Egypt and Alex Nichol, spokesman for the Australian Wheat Board (AWB) said Wednesday. Australia is pursuing further sales of wheat to India and Egypt.</p>
<p>Dry weather in the U.S. Great Plains was mentioned but there were some forecasts for rain there early next week.</p>
<p>Trading was quiet with Cargill Inc a seller of one million bushels of July, traders said. FIMAT Futures and O'Connor and Co each bought one million bushels of March, traders said.</p>
<p>At 1129 CST, wheat was one cent per bushel higher to one lower, with March up 1/2 at $3.74.  </p>
<p>Chart watchers cited a bearish slant for the March, May and July contracts stemming from the four and 20-day moving averages.</p>
<p>The first resistance level early Wednesday for the March was at $3.74-1/2 a bushel and second resistance was at $3.77-3/4. The session high was $3.75-1/2 as of 1140 CST.</p>
<p>First support for the March was at $3.71-1/4 and second support was at $3.68. The session low for March as of 1140 CST was at $3.71-1/2.</p>
<p>((Sam Nelson 312-408-8721))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
