<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34123" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Seagram shortened second-quarter profit improves.</title>
<headline>Seagram shortened second-quarter profit improves.</headline>
<dateline>MONTREAL</dateline>
<text>
<p>(All amounts in U.S. dollars)</p>
<p>Entertainment and beverage giant Seagram Co. Ltd. on Thursday posted improved results for its shortened second quarter, despite some weakness in the performance of its MCA music and entertainment subsidiary.</p>
<p>Seagram posted net profit in the two-month period ending June 30 of $62 million, or 17 cents a share, versus $58 million, or 16 cents a share, in the comparable period of 1995.</p>
<p>The truncated second-quarter and the five-month transition period reflected a change in Seagram's fiscal year to end June 30 instead of the previous year end of Jan. 31.</p>
<p>Net income for the five-month transition period was $85 million, or 23 cents a share. In the comparable five months of 1995, income before discontinued DuPont Co. activities was $117 million, or 32 cents a share.</p>
<p>Net income for the five months ended June 30, 1995, including the gain on the redemption of the DuPont shares was $3.3 billion, or $8.99 per share.</p>
<p>Seagram said the drop in earnings at MCA on a pro forma basis was expected as it boosted selected investments.</p>
<p>&quot;As anticipated, MCA's pro forma results were down due to the strategic investment in new music artists and labels, and intensified marketing efforts in anticipation of the second-quarter theme park openings of Terminator 2:3-D at Universal Studios Florida and Jurassic Park - The Ride attraction at Universal Studios Hollywood,&quot; Seagram President and Chief Executive Edgar Bronfman Jr said in a statement.</p>
<p>Bronfman said spirits and wines results rose in the two-month second quarter and the company looked forward to continued improvement in the division in the new fiscal year.</p>
<p>Spirits and wine earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization, or EBITDA, rose by $1 million in the second quarter after several sucessive declining quarters.</p>
<p>The company said growth in its Asia Pacific business, particularly in Korea, and a recovery in several Latin American units, was partly offset by certain expenses in North America and flat results in Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased to see the modest improvement in spirits and wine results in the second quarter following several difficult periods, and look forward to continued progress in our new fiscal year,&quot; Bronfman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our key brands, including Martell Cognac, Chivas Regal Scotch Whisky, Crown Royal Canadian Whisky and Absolut Vodka, which is marketed under an agreement with V&amp;S Vin &amp; Spirit AB, performed well. Our fruit juice unit maintained its strong performance during the two- and five-month periods, driven by the strength of Pure Premium in the United States and growth of Tropicana Dole Beverages in all major global markets,&quot; Bronfman added.</p>
<p>Fruit juice and other EBITDA rose 14 percent to $24 million in the quarter due to the growth in Tropicana's base business globally and the addition of the Dole juice business.</p>
<p>Seagram said its second-quarter results included three months of MCA, which contributed $88 million of EBITDA in the second quarter. On a pro forma basis, EBITDA fell 19 percent compared with the second quarter last year.</p>
<p>Seagram's stock slipped 12.5 cents to $33 in early trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
