<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341276" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Aerospatiale, Renault develop light plane engines.</title>
<headline>Aerospatiale, Renault develop light plane engines.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>French state-owned aerospace firm Aerospatiale and carmaker Renault have formed a venture to develop a new generation of engines for light aircraft, the companies said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The 50-50 venture, Societe de Motorisations Aeronautiques, expects to apply for certification of the new engines, ranging from 180 to 300 horsepower, by the spring of 1998, the two companies said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>They declined to give financial details on the venture but said it was expected to reach a capacity of 100 motors annually.</p>
<p>Renault Sport, which boasts five Formula 1 world championships, will initially develop the motors for light planes built by Aerospatiale's subsidiary Socata, which sells them to pilot schools, tourism firms and shuttle operators.</p>
<p>The venture will subsequently seek more customers.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the terms of this partnership, which has been prepared since 1995, Socata and Renault plan to propose to clients a range of motors with new technology responding to environmental, cost and reliability demands,&quot; the firms said.</p>
<p>The motors will be as powerful as the current generation but quieter, 50 percent more durable, and they will run on kerosene, cutting operating expenses.</p>
<p>Socata chairman Yves Michot told a news conference that the venture would help the firm boost plane sales.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll have an entirely new product range which will allow us to develop sales in a sector that has suffered badly in recent years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said market opportunities were presented by increased environmental and frontier surveillance and pilot training.</p>
<p>Prices would be at current market levels, with the 200 horsepower engine priced at between 150,000 francs and 200,000 francs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
