<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341260" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Porsche may make car in Finland - report.</title>
<headline>Porsche may make car in Finland - report.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>German sportscar maker Dr.Ing.h.c.F Porsche AG is aiming to build its Boxster model in Finland in an effort to slash an order backlog, a German magazine reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>According to the weekly Wirtschaftswoche, Porsche is in talks with Finnish engineering group Valmet Oy to produce at least 5,000 of the two-seat cabriolets to break a production bottleneck at its main plant near Stuttgart.</p>
<p>Porsche and Valmet refused to comment on the report. &quot;Our policy is not to give any kind of comment on this type of thing,&quot; a Valmet spokeswoman told Reuters.</p>
<p>A Porsche spokesman said, meanwhile, that the company's board had not yet decided how to deal with strong demand for the Boxster.</p>
<p>Valmet's automotive unit is currently manufacturing Saab's 900 cabriolet model, Opel's Calibra and Russian Euro-Samara cars at its Uusikaupunki plant in south-western Finland.</p>
<p>The Boxster model, which hit the market late last year, has won praise from the motoring press and demand is well in excess of what Porsche had expected.</p>
<p>The Porsche plant in Stuttgart has a capacity of around 30,000 cars, about half of which are expected to be Boxsters and the other half the 911 model.</p>
<p>The German car maker has little scope to cut production of the more-expensive 911 after sales boomed last year.</p>
<p>The Boxster sells in Germany for around 75,000 marks.</p>
<p>Porsche chairman Wendelin Wiedeking has vowed to cut waiting times for the Boxster which have stretched out to 12 months, saying a year is to long to wait for a car.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom + 49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32754">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
