<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341216" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German cocoa market stuck in routine trade.</title>
<headline>German cocoa market stuck in routine trade.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>German cocoa traders reported only replacement purchases of beans and butter from industrial buyers, who were generally waiting for lower prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Consumers would like to take cover but futures and sterling are still too high,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Consumer stocks don't look too comfortable.&quot;</p>
<p>The second position in London was last at 907 stg, down seven from Tuesday's close, but traders said industrial buyers were looking for levels between 870 and 900 before they could be activated.</p>
<p>Consumers were betting on high Ivorian cocoa arrivals and a final 96/97 crop figure above one million tonnes, which they expected to exert downward pressure on prices.</p>
<p>The annual confectionery fair ISM in Cologne, which will end on Thursday, was expected to revive the market in the weeks to come as new chocolate sales contracts were seen resulting in fresh raw materials ordering from manufacturers.</p>
<p>&quot;But sentiment is not too great because many chocolate firms feel unable to push for higher retail prices for finished products,&quot; one ISM participant said.</p>
<p>First quarter cif Ivorian bean sellers were slightly up from last week at 2.33 marks per kg (2.31) and second quarter beans were at 2.37 (2.36). The first quarter cocoa butter ratio was up one point at 2.66 and unchanged for the second quarter at 2.65.</p>
<p>Implied mark prices liquid ex-works were 6.30 marks for the first quarter and 6.38 for the second.</p>
<p>Sterling was at 2.655 marks at the Frankfurt Exchange fixing at midday.</p>
<p>-Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
