<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341368" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Spotlight on Indian oil stocks as price hike looms.</title>
<headline>Spotlight on Indian oil stocks as price hike looms.</headline>
<byline>Priya Ramani</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top Indian petroleum shares are in the spotlight as investors rush to hedge against an impending oil price hike and look towards a move to deregulate the sector, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Shares of Bharat Petroleum Corporation Ltd (BPCL) and Hindustan Petroleum Corporation Ltd (HPCL) -- two of India's largest refiners -- have risen by an average of 22 percent this month.</p>
<p>&quot;Suddenly, people seem to have re-discovered these two stocks,&quot; said Manish Singhai, analyst at Caspian Securities.</p>
<p>Brokers said around eight to 10 funds were picking up shares of both companies on the Bombay Stock Exchange. They said the increased demand was only partly due to booming local bourses.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the best hedge against the oil price hike that most people are expecting before the budget,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Analysts said they expected the government to raise oil prices ahead of, or in, the 1997/98 (April-March) federal budget due on February 28.</p>
<p>Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda -- though wary of upsetting members in his coalition government -- has admitted that an oil price hike is inevitable. But he has avoided giving a timeframe.</p>
<p>&quot;These shares are bound to run up further after the oil price increase as it will ease the liquidity crunch they are facing,&quot; said Srivatsa Kumar, analyst at Jardine Fleming India.</p>
<p>&quot;After the petroleum price hike these shares should rebound by another 10 percent,&quot; Caspian's Singhai said.</p>
<p>The budget could also hold some move towards deregulating the government's administered price mechanism (APM) for oil products, industry analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is lot of speculation whether oil market reforms will be given an additional push as regards the budget,&quot; said a London-based oil analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;What I'm hoping is that they make some moves on the road to deregulation in the oil and gas sector. My fear is that if the government doesn't move, the APM is going to collapse like a pack of cards over the next year to 18 months,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said investors could also be picking up shares of BPCL and HPCL ahead of an issue of global depositary receipts by India's largest refiner, Indian Oil Corp (IOC), due in March.</p>
<p>&quot;If people think the demand for IOC is ahead of supply they would hedge their positions by looking for alternatives... and these two are the best bets,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>An analyst at a U.S. investment bank said he had a strong &quot;accumulate&quot; recommendation on BPCL and HPCL.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect some indications of dismantling of APM in the budget. Of course we don't expect them to dismantle it overnight, but we are looking for some indication of how things will go in the future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone is enthused about energy. As a defensive sector, it's attracting a lot of money,&quot; Jardine's Kumar said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
