<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341555" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ford sees improved 1997 automotive earnings.</title>
<headline>Ford sees improved 1997 automotive earnings.</headline>
<dateline>DEARBORN, Mich. 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ford Motor Co Chairman Alex Trotman said the automaker expects improved automotive earnings in 1997, including better results in Europe.</p>
<p>In a statement accompanying Ford's fourth quarter earnings results, Trotman also said the automaker was &quot;on track&quot; to restore profitability in Brazil and Argentina.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a tough business plan in place,&quot; Trotman said of the automaker's worldwide strategy.  &quot;We expect automotive earnings to improve in 1997, driven by a strong product lineup and company-wide efforts to lower costs.&quot;  </p>
<p>Ford said Tuesday its 1996 fourth quarter profits jumped about 82 percent to $1.2 billion, or $0.99 per fully diluted share, from $660 million, or $0.48 a share a year earlier.</p>
<p>Excluding extraordinary items, Ford's fourth quarter operating earnings came to $1.10 a share, exceeding the First Call consensus Wall Street analyst estimate of $1.02 a share.</p>
<p>Ford shares were off 1/8 to 32-3/8 in early trading.</p>
<p>&quot;The first priority is to improve near-term automotive results,&quot; Trotman said.  &quot;Second, we want to continue to grow the earnings of our Financial Services Group.  It's clearly one of our undervalued strengths.&quot;  </p>
<p>Ford's earnings showed improving results in its U.S. automotive operations, which earned $628 million, up from $168 million a year ago, which was hurt by major new product launch costs.  But Ford's overseas operations continued to struggle, posting a fourth quarter loss of $238 million versus a year-ago loss of $152 million.</p>
<p>Losses widened in both Europe, where price competition has been brutal, and in South America, where Ford has been forced to launch a virtually new automotive company following the dissolution of its Autolatina joint venture with Volkswagen AG in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Europe is tough for everyone, but we expect better results in 1997,&quot; Trotman said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DEARBORN, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
