<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341785" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Saudis stand by their bullish oil price forecast.</title>
<headline>Saudis stand by their bullish oil price forecast.</headline>
<byline>Karen Matusic</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi Arabia, the world's biggest oil producer, is standing by its bullish outlook for oil prices this year, Gulf sources say.</p>
<p>The sources, familiar with oil policy in the kingdom and other key Middle East producers Kuwait and the United Arab Emirates, say world benchmark Brent Blend crude oil should &quot;easily&quot; average between $20 and $25 a barrel in 1997.</p>
<p>They say the Saudis and other Gulf Arab oil producers are content to allow oil prices to drift to the top of that range without considering hiking their output.</p>
<p>&quot;We can definitely live with the higher oil price. It basically reflects the value of oil on real terms. It is a realistic price,&quot; a Gulf source said.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia produces about eight million barrels of oil a day and exports nearly twice as much as its nearest competitor Norway. It also calls the shots within the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC).</p>
<p>With most of OPEC's 11 members and all the producers outside OPEC pumping as much oil they can, Saudi Arabia is really the only country which could significantly increase output to meet unexpected shortfalls.</p>
<p>One Gulf source said the Saudis believed that a strong oil price is not a threat to inflation of demand. When considering current inflation and tax levels, the price is not really higher than it was 10 years ago when Brent traded was valued below $15, he said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, a barrel of North Sea Brent on the London market was fetching around $22.40, six dollars above its year-ago level thanks to buoyant demand for refined products.</p>
<p>The Gulf sources, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said they based their forecast on continued strong demand, the fact that oil inventories in key consumer countries are low and their opinion that production increases will not be as high as predicted by some analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;All signs indicate that the price is going to continue strong. We see Brent in our range of $20 to $25,&quot; one Gulf source said.</p>
<p>The Saudis have more reason than most oil price pundits to be confident about their forecasts. They were alone in correctly predicting last year's rally which sent oil prices to their highest levels in nearly six years.</p>
<p>&quot;The analysts tend to follow each other in their linear thinking. You have to look at a number of factors,&quot; a Gulf source said.</p>
<p>In 1996, oil analysts and economists were forced to sharply raise their price forecasts after wrongly predicting a collapse when Iraqi oil reappeared on the market after a six year absence once the United Nations eased sanctions.</p>
<p>But an economic growth-led demand surge meant that an oil-thirsty world easily absorbed all the oil Iraq and its fellow OPEC members could churn out.</p>
<p>Saudi industry sources say the extra Iraqi oil of about 500,000 barrels daily has not made a dent in their market share of about six million barrels daily.</p>
<p>They said the kingdom and other producers have received requests from customers recently for additional supplies.</p>
<p>&quot;We could supply even more than we are producing right now. The Gulf states have had to turn down customer requests for more oil,&quot; one Gulf oil source said.</p>
<p>Even though Brent has given up almost three dollars from its mid-October 1996 peak as winter heating oil demand fades, bullish expectations for the traditional summer motoring season should keep a floor under prices, the Gulf sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;The need to build gasoline stocks coincides with heavy refinery maintenance work in the U.S. Then by the third quarter, the market will again focus on heating oil. It all looks positive for the price,&quot; a Saudi source said.</p>
<p>Even though most oil analysts think the market is overvalued right now and expect some price decline, no one is willing to predict a collapse.</p>
<p>Michael Rothman, first vice president and senior energy analyst of the futures research department at Merrill Lynch in New York says tight oil supplies and geopolitical risks have led him to increase his 1997 price forecast.</p>
<p>&quot;Our concern is that prices may continue to feel upward pressure in the absence of any price capping actions on the part of OPEC's key members,&quot; Rothman writes in a recent report.</p>
<p>--London newsroom, +44 171 542 6280</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OPEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
