<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341855" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Rover 1996 car sales back over half million.</title>
<headline>Rover 1996 car sales back over half million.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>German-owned Rover group, the British car manufacturer, said on Wednesday its sales in 1996 had totalled more than 500,000 for the first time since 1988.</p>
<p>A statement detailing export and domestic market sales at the BMW AG-owned company showed that, as expected, its domestic sales in the year slipped back. They fell by 7.0 percent, and amounted to less than half of the total, at 232,382.</p>
<p>Exports, on the other hand, forged ahead in the year supported by record sales in Japan and North America, the company said. In all, exports made up 54 percent of total Rover sales of 507,254 in the year which were up 5.0 percent on 1995.</p>
<p>Sales in mainland Europe rose by 16.5 percent to 174,900 cars while sales to non-European markets rose by 19 percent to 95,516.</p>
<p>Globally, the company said its MGF sports car, Discovery and Range Rover four-wheel drives, and Rover 200 and 400 family cars performed particularly well.</p>
<p>Sales to Italy led the way in Europe as it became the company's largest single export market with 46,700 vehicle, while sales in Germany advanced advanced by two-thirds to 21,740 vehicles.</p>
<p>&quot;Rover group's sales performance, in an environment of ever-increasing competition, has been gratifying. Success in export markets continues, giving the company a sound worldwide base for its new generation,&quot; Rover chief executive Walter Hasselkus said in the statement.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
