<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341804" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Bank of England seeks 1/2 point rate rise.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Bank of England seeks 1/2 point rate rise.</headline>
<byline>Rosemary Bennett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's central bank has forcefully warned the government that it must raise interest rates by a half point to stave off inflation, minutes from a December monetary meeting showed on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Bank of England Governor Eddie George upped the ante in the December meeting telling Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke that failure to raise rates immediately by a quarter point would mean a half-point rise in January or February.</p>
<p>&quot;To keep ahead of the game, the Bank would advise an immediate quarter percent move this month,&quot; the minutes quoted George as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the Bank could not claim that it was crucial to move again now, if rates were not raised this month, it was quite likely...the Bank would need to advise a half percent move in either January or February.&quot;</p>
<p>Clarke overruled George and kept rates on hold at 6.0 percent, saying the case had not been made for a further rise. &quot;Overall, the Chancellor thought the picture was still mixed, with the indicators giving different signals.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists said more recent comments from Clarke suggested he will fight tooth and nail to keep the cost of borrowing on hold until after the election, due by May 22.</p>
<p>&quot;The argument between the two appears to be intensifying but whatever the Bank says Clarke does not want to put up interest rates before the election,&quot; said Stephen Hannah, chief economist at IBJ International.</p>
<p>The ruling Conservatives trail opposition Labour by 20 points in the opinion polls and many backbenchers are fearful another interest rate rise will erode its support among home owners who make up a clear majority of the electorate.</p>
<p>The last rate rise, a quarter point, took place in October.</p>
<p>Hannah said George is right to be concerned about Britain's inflation performance and to point out the government is a long way from meeting its target.</p>
<p>The latest inflation figures showed the targeted rate, which excluded volatile mortgage interest payments, rose 3.1 percent in the year to December, someway above the government's target of 2.5 percent or less by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>At the December meeting, George said inflation may dip short-term thanks to the pound's recent strength, and then pick up again towards the end of next year, overshooting 2.5 percent.</p>
<p>But in a lengthy interview in Wednesday's Financial Times, Clarke said big interest rate rises could undermine the recovery, suggesting the two men will clash when they next meet on February 5.</p>
<p>&quot;To start raising interest rates too hard and too fast at this stage of the recovery will be to run the risk of beating the inflation target in a big way downwards in 18 months' time and depriving the country of some of the benefits of the recovery,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Clarke said he was confident inflation would hit the target, but stopped short of reasserting he would set monetary policy purely to this end.</p>
<p>&quot;But it is like my ambitions on tax rates, it is like my ambitions on the balanced budget -- of course you set policy to hit them but you do so in a way that is consistent with the all-round information.&quot;</p>
<p>And the report said Clarke appeared happy to live with his differences with George.</p>
<p>&quot;I think people have got to get this thing in proportion. They need to have a grown-up debate. We are not in the world of flaming rows,&quot; Clarke said.</p>
<p>But City economists said Clarke cannot afford to be too blase about a major policy rift so close to the election.</p>
<p>&quot;Clarke will have to be a little careful about having a heated argument with the Bank of England before the election. It will not serve the party's interests well to allow Labour to claim even the central bank doesn't support the government's policies,&quot; said Hannah.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
