<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="341974" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Jan 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Jan 29.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following stories were reported in Wednesday's The Wall Street Journal:</p>
<p>* International Business Machines announced a two-for-one stock split, a move that could indicate a possible dividend increase.</p>
<p>* Investment into stock mutual funds resumed at a heavy pace in January.</p>
<p>* The Labor Department's employment cost index rose just 0.8 percent in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>* General Motors said labor strikes nearly halved its quarterly net but said a strong cash position at year-end indicates that management policy changes are working.</p>
<p>* Ford said it will not accept seats made by non-union workers at two Johnson Controls factories where the United Auto Workers are striking.</p>
<p>* Hilton Hotels shares rose $2.625 to $27.875, and ITT Corp stock fell $1.625 after rising nearly $15 a share Monday, when Hilton announced a hostile bid for ITT.</p>
<p>* Walt Disney said its profit rose 33 percent in the first quarter on record attendance at Disney World and strong movie receipts. The company said it is also exploring strategic options for the publishing business it bought when it acquired Capital Cities/ABC.</p>
<p>* The Dow industrials closed down at 6656.08, after rising more than 100 points earlier in the day.</p>
<p>* Merck, American Home Products and Warner-Lambert reported earnings above estimates and signficantly higher than year-ago results.</p>
<p>* An open-skies agreement is nearly complete, but other roadblocks could delay the alliance between British Airways and AMR's American Airlines.</p>
<p>* Procter &amp; Gamble results beat analysts' forecasts.</p>
<p>* Investor Michael Price said a fund he manages has bought 4.5 million shares of Dow Jones &amp; Co representing about a 4.6 percent stake in the company.</p>
<p>* Delaware bankruptcy lawyers will begin meeting with federal judges on the way bankruptcy cases are heard there.</p>
<p>* Paper makers have been reporting dismal fourth-quarter results. Some warn that product prices are likely to remain depressed through the first quarter. Even so, many analysts think the industry is nearing the bottom of a slump that began in late 1995. -- Heard on the Street.</p>
<p>* A rally in bonds petered out in late-morning and afternoon trading as benign economic data was unable to inspire any substainable follow-through interest in investors. -- Credit Markets.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
