<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34225" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Sept 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Sept 5.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>24 CHASA</p>
<p>-- The World Bank said it has approved $24.3 million loan to Bulgaria to help finance a government's social insurance administration project.</p>
<p>The loan will be repayable over a period of 20 years including five years of grace and will cover 75 percent of the project's costs. @</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's State Fund for Reconstruction and Development (SFRR) is expected to reschedule next week the debts of the cash-strapped National Electricity Company, SFRR officials said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria posted 9.3 billion levs trade surplus in the second quarter, National Statistics Institute preliminary figures show.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's Privatisation Agency (PA) approved the sale of a 75-percent stake in the debt-ridden Plama oil refinery, initially slated for liquidation, to Bulgaria's Euroenergy holding, PA board chairman Dimitar Stefanov said. @</p>
<p>STANDART</p>
<p>-- The Supreme Court unanimously overruled the Central Electoral Commission's decision to refuse registration to the main anti-communist opposition nominees for the country's presidential elections due on October 27.</p>
<p>-- The Palestine terrorist Nazem Abdulah, who hijacked the Bulgarian TU-134 plane on Monday, surrendered at Oslo's airport and asked for a lawyer and political asylum.</p>
<p>The eight-member Bulgarian crew was released. @</p>
<p>-- Energy Minister Rumen Ovcharov and the World Bank's permanent representative in Sofia Alberto Mussalem discussed a $20 million grant to Bulgaria for purchasing central heating measuring equipment.</p>
<p>-- Bulgarian citizens will not be allowed to open foreign currency deposits in banks abroad under a currency transactions draft expected to be discussed by the parliament in September.</p>
<p>KONTINENT</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>-- The parliament is expected today to overrule President Zhelyu Zhelev's veto on the Radio and Television Law after the socialist-dominated media committee proposed that the bill should not be changed.</p>
<p>PARI</p>
<p>-- The International Monetary Fund (IMF) urged Bulgaria to build public confidence in local troubled banks by stabilising them and to boost tax collection, IMF's mission head Anne McGuirk said after a two-week stay in Bulgaria. @</p>
<p>-- The Bulgarian National Bank (BNB) is expected today to discuss the implementation of commercial banks' short-term stabilisation programmes agreed with the BNB.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
