<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="342348" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Aborigines warn of Sydney 2000 Olympic protests.</title>
<headline>Aborigines warn of Sydney 2000 Olympic protests.</headline>
<byline>Michael Perry</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Sydney 2000 Olympics would be marred by Aboriginal protests if the Australian government eroded indigenous native title land rights, the former head of Australia's peak Aboriginal body warned on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It will break down completely any trust that indigenous people have in this government,&quot; said Lois O'Donoghue, who retired in December as head of the Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Commission.</p>
<p>&quot;To legislate away our rights to native title is something that we cannot tolerate. It is really a non-negotiable position,&quot; O'Donoghue told the National Press Club in Canberra.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be back on the streets. We will be back to marching, demonstrating, and I am one who has not said up until now, but certainly the (Olympic) Games will be a platform,&quot; said O'Donoghue, a moderate Aboriginal activist.</p>
<p>Australia's conservative government of Prime Minister John Howard is under intense pressure from farmers, miners and conservative state politicians to change native title laws to ensure pastoral leases dominate over native title rights.</p>
<p>The move follows a ruling by Australia's peak High Court in December allowing pastoral leases and native title to co-exist. Previously, pastoral leases extinquished native title rights, leaving Aborigines to claim only unoccupied crown land.</p>
<p>The judgement sent shudders through the farming and mining communities, as it leaves some 40 percent of Australia's 7.68 million square km (2.96 million square miles) -- an area almost the size of India -- vulnerable to native title claim.</p>
<p>Farmers and miners warn the uncertainty of tenure will dry up investment in commodities -- the backbone of the Australian economy. Aborigines argue it will have no economic impact as the High Court ruled that farmers' rights would take precendence over Aboriginal rights where the two are in conflict.</p>
<p>Howard will meet Aboriginal leaders, farmers and miners in February to discuss the native title issue, but he has already indicated that he plans to change the 1992 native title laws.</p>
<p>&quot;On the advice available to me at the present time, this decision has the potential to create enormous uncertainty,&quot; Howard told reporters last week. &quot;It can't be left as it is.&quot;</p>
<p>Aborigines fear this means their native title rights may be wiped out on pastoral land, a move they warn would contravene the country's racial discrimination laws.</p>
<p>Relations between Aborigines and the Australian government have deteriorated since Howard was elected less than a year ago.</p>
<p>Under the previous Labor administrations of prime ministers Bob Hawke and Paul Keating, indigenous rights flourished.</p>
<p>But Howard's Liberal-National coalition government -- its junior partner the Nationals is a rural-based party -- has caused &quot;irreparable damage&quot; to indigenous relations through a series of attacks on Aboriginal rights, said O'Donoghue.</p>
<p>Aborigines warn that reconciliation between black and white Australia hinges on land rights and social justice.</p>
<p>Australia's 300,000 Aborigines are the most disadvantaged people in society. Aboriginal adults have a life expectancy 10 to 15 years lower than the rest of the 18 million population.</p>
<p>&quot;Genuine reconciliation would have to be predicated on our receiving two sets of rights -- our rights as citizens and our rights as the original occupiers of the land,&quot; O'Donoghue said.</p>
<p>&quot;Citizen rights relate to living conditions, the provision of services other Australians take for granted, equality of opportunity. Indigenous rights relate to our claims over land and to have a special status as the first Australians.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Reconciliation still seems a long way off.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
