<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="342462" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian MP charged with defaming Suharto.</title>
<headline>Indonesian MP charged with defaming Suharto.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>An outspoken member of parliament from the minority Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI) was charged on Wednesday with defaming President Suharto, a prosecutor said.</p>
<p>Aberson Marle Sihaloho, a supporter of ousted PDI leader Megawati Sukarnoputri, was also charged with defaming the armed forces and parliament during the same speech in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;The defendant intentionally defamed President Suharto... during a forum held at the PDI headquarters,&quot; prosecutor Z.W. Were told the central Jakarta district court.</p>
<p>He said Sihaloho had accused the Suharto regime of suppressing the Indonesian people for 30 years.</p>
<p>Sihaloho can be jailed up to six years if found guilty. He has not been detained following assurances from his lawyers that he will not leave the country.</p>
<p>Sihaloho is alleged to have made the remarks at the PDI headquarters in Jakarta where Megawati's supporters used to gather before being ejected by police and soldiers on July 27.</p>
<p>Their ouster led to the worst riots in Jakarta in more than two decades in which at least five people were killed.</p>
<p>Megawati was ousted as PDI leader at a government-backed party congress in June and replaced by deputy parliament speaker Surjadi. She is challenging the move in court.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, the High Court upheld a lower court decision to send sacked legislator Sri Bintang Pamungkas to 34 months in jail for defaming Suharto.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
