<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="342412" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - Jan 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - Jan 29.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following are the leading stories in the Indonesian press on January 29. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>Telephone: (6221) 384-6364. Fax: (6221) 344-8404.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>KOMPAS</p>
<p>Traders have resumed their activities in the Tanah Abang shopping district in central Jakarta after a clash between street vendors and security officers on Tuesday. Traders set fire to the district office and overturned a number of cars after the officers ordered them to move their stalls that were blocking traffic.</p>
<p>The government will not postpone increasing the price of fertiliser as it planned to reduce its fertiliser subsidy. Members of parliament have criticised the government's move, which they said will be detrimental to farmers.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>JAKARTA POST</p>
<p>Minister of Industry and Trade Tunky Ariwibowo has blamed the non-oil and gas export slowdown in recent years on the low productivity of Indonesian workers. Tunky said between 1985 and 1995 workers' salaries increased by 170 percent while their productivity only rose by 75 percent.</p>
<p>Minister of Defence and Security Edi Sudradjat has criticised the nepotistic tendencies behind the selection of candidates for the general elections in May. He said recruitment of legislative candidates should not be based on their proximity to or relations with government and military officials.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>REPUBLIKA</p>
<p>Canada's Placer Dome Inc. has said it has no intention to work with Barrick Gold Corp to develop the huge Busang gold find in east Kalimantan province. Placer Dome is holding talks with Bre-X Minerals Ltd on its proposed $5 billion merger with the company to develop the find.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE INDONESIAN OBSERVER</p>
<p>State-owned telecommunication company PT Telkom plans to invest around 4.3 trillion rupiah for the construction of new phone lines in 1997, down from 4.5 trillion rupiah in 1996.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom + 6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
