<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="342482" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo naphtha up slightly, physical buying emerges.</title>
<headline>Tokyo naphtha up slightly, physical buying emerges.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo naphtha prices were slightly firmer on Wednesday, following overnight crude price gains in London, and also supported by physical buying, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Offers are expected to edge up later today, supported by physical buying by a petrochemical product maker on Tuesday,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Open-spec naphtha second-half March was assessed at about $231.00/232.50 and first-half April at $229.50/231.00, compared to $229.00/230.50 and $228.00/229.50 respectively on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The one-month spread from first-half April was barely changed at $2.50/4.00.  </p>
<p>Traders said a Japanese petrochemical firm on Tuesday bought a first-March cargo at a high price of around $4.00 above the mean of Japanese quotes.</p>
<p>Other Japanese end-users are also probing the market for first-March cargoes, but are maintaining a cautious stance, traders said. This is because petrochemical firms are suffering profit declines as domestic product prices remain low, while naphtha prices are still at high levels.</p>
<p>In the jet kerosene market, a Japanese refiner bought a cargo on Monday, at about $2.20 above the mean of Singapore quotes, traders said.--Tokyo Energy Desk (81-3-5473-3708)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
