<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="342514" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai B index ends up slightly on rebound.</title>
<headline>Shanghai B index ends up slightly on rebound.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai's B share index closed up slightly on Wednesday on a technical rebound following Tuesday's correction, with investors staying on the sidelines in a holiday mood, brokers said.</p>
<p>The B index inched up 0.037 points or 0.06 percent to 65.438 points, on volume of 16.5 million shares worth $7.2 million against $6.4 million on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Brokers said the index would continue to consolidate at current levels ahead of the two-week Chinese lunar new year holiday which begins on February 6.  </p>
<p>&quot;After the big gains of the past week, the market began to consolidate around the 65-point level, waiting for a further rise to the 68-point level,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;With the lack of market-moving news, the holiday mood has dominated recent trading,&quot; a second broker said.</p>
<p>All 43 B shares traded, with 17 up, 10 flat and 16 down.</p>
<p>Food producer Shanghai Dajiang was the star on speculative buying, rising $0.036 or 6.64 percent to $0.578 on volume of 144,800 shares.  </p>
<p>Shanghai Narcissus Electric Appliances followed on bargain-hunting. With 2.3 million shares traded it was heaviest trade of the session and rose $0.008 or 4.34 percent to $0.192.</p>
<p>Shanghai's A share market rose on cautious buying with some funds flowing in from the primary market after continous new issues in Shenzhen and Shanghai, brokers said.</p>
<p>The A index edged up 6.21 points or 0.62 percent to 1004.17 points with 382.1 million shares traded on turnover of 3.5 billion yuan. The SSE 30 blue-chip index rose 30.95 points or 1.2 percent to 2608.67 points.  </p>
<p>Retailer Beijing Wangfujing was the star on institutional buying, surging 0.92 yuan or 10 percent to its limit-up of 10.12 yuan with 12.1 million shares traded.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
