<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="342702" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - Jan 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - Jan 29.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Greek Cypriot press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>ALITHIA</p>
<p>- Cyprus wants the European Union to give it a chance to prove it wants a solution to the political issue.</p>
<p>CYPRUS MAIL</p>
<p>- Justice minister wants more leniency to reduce prisons overcrowding.</p>
<p>FINANCIAL MIRROR</p>
<p>- The dollar reaches a 31-month high against the Cyprus pound.</p>
<p>- Cyprus stock exchange index falls to a record low.</p>
<p>- The tourism industry braces itself for a difficult year ahead.</p>
<p>HARAVGHI</p>
<p>- A split looms in right-wing Democratic Rally, with some members looking for a presidential candidate other than President Glafcos Clerides.</p>
<p>- Germany puts up obstacles to Cyprus's accession to the European Union.</p>
<p>PHILELEPHTHEROS</p>
<p>- Centre-right Diko and right-wing Disy agree to restore trust in their government partnership, but the continuing presence of Justice Minister Alecos Evangelou in the cabinet is still a cause of concern for Diko.</p>
<p>SIMERINI</p>
<p>- Eu countries will accelerate efforts to solve the Cyprus problem before entry negotiations start.</p>
<p>- Diko MP Marios Matsakis re-appears after two days in the Akamas protesting against British military exercises.</p>
<p>($=0.49 pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
