<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="342710" id="root" date="1997-01-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: PRESS DIGEST - Spain - Jan 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Spain - Jan 29.</headline>
<text>
<p>Headlines from major national newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>EL PAIS</p>
<p>- Government plans law for football broadcasts on television that would end &quot;league of stars&quot;.</p>
<p>- Ruling Popular Party and main opposition Socialist Workers Party (PSOE) support creation of parliamentry commission to investigate missing tax funds.</p>
<p>- High court releases former Basque country government delegate Julen Elgorriaga, suspected of being involved in &quot;dirty war&quot; against Basque separatists in 1980s, on bail after seven months in prison.</p>
<p>EL MUNDO</p>
<p>- Treasury ignored report from tax inspectors warning about activities of father-in-law of former Secretary of State Rafael Vera.</p>
<p>- Witnesses testified on Tuesday that Javier Rosado, suspected author of role murder is peaceful young man that has never shown signs of agressiveness.</p>
<p>- Gunman shoots dead three people in what police believe was drug-related attack.</p>
<p>DIARIO 16</p>
<p>- Government seeks truce in Digital television sector, Cabinet rules out sanctioning Canal Satellite</p>
<p>ABC</p>
<p>- Former Socialist government failed to cover almost 15 billion pesetas in 1994 and 1995 without exhausting judicial process.</p>
<p>CINCO DIAS</p>
<p>- Competition commission rules out possibility that Canal Satellite launch will shut off digital TV sector to other competitors.</p>
<p>- Europa Furniture, association that groups 89 small companies, develops plan to compete with Swedish giant Ikea.</p>
<p>- Majority of Spaniards do not believe a recovery is under way, according to CIS poll.</p>
<p>- European companies must employ ethical behaviour toward employees, clients and suppliers if they are to ensure quality.</p>
<p>EXPANSION</p>
<p>- Telefonica mulls increase to 75 percent tranche offered to Spanish investors in privatisation of 20.9 percent state stake sale.</p>
<p>- Dollar rises to 139 against peseta and stock market advances 1.8 percent.</p>
<p>- Spain exceeds Maastricht criteria on interest rates in 1996 by half a point.</p>
<p>GACETA DE LOS NEGOCIOS</p>
<p>- Iberdrola, Gas Natural and Repsol deal opens door for cooperation on multimillion peseta projects.</p>
<p>- Public works ministry promises to expand Madrid's Barajas airport in 22 months.</p>
<p>- BBV obtains billing business of Correos y Telegrafos that was maintained by Argentaria through Caja Postal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
