<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="342993" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FDA says probing death related to Ventritex device.</title>
<headline>FDA says probing death related to Ventritex device.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration said Thursday it is investigating a report of a third death of a patient implanted with a defibrillator made by Ventritex Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;We have received a report of a third death of a patient with one of the Ventritex defibrillators. We are investigating,&quot; said FDA spokeswoman Sharon Schneider.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not know exactly the nature of the problem. We don't know whether this third death was caused by this same problem that appears to have caused the other two deaths,&quot; Schneider said.  </p>
<p>Shares in Ventritex fell 1-1/4 to 18-1/8 in heavy trading late Thursday on market speculation about the death and its possible impact on Ventritex's proposed acquisition by St. Jude Medical Inc, whose shares were up 1/2 to 37-1/8.</p>
<p>&quot;St. Jude's stock has been strong today and Ventritex has been sinking. So any time you see a divergence like that, it suggests the deal could be off ... I believe this deal will go through, but I think we've opened the door to a potential renegotiation of the terms,&quot; said Montgomery Securities medical technology analyst Kurt Kruger.</p>
<p>Ventritex and St. Jude could not be reached for comment.  </p>
<p>St. Jude in October said it intended to acquire Ventritex in a stock swap valued at about $505 million.</p>
<p>On January 16, Ventritex said it had been authorized by the FDA to begin reprogramming 5,605 model V-110 and electrically similar V-112 implantable defibrillators implanted in living patients. The company said component failures in the devices were believed to be associated with the deaths of two patients.</p>
<p>Shares in Ventritex had been up in the mid-20s since the St. Jude bid, but in the past two weeks have fallen back. &quot;It's been our belief since this crisis first began two weeks ago that the value of Ventritex has declined.... St. Jude could and should renegotiate the terms of this transaction,&quot; said J.P. Morgan Securities medical technology analyst Michael Weinstein.</p>
<p>Piper Jaffray analyst Arch Smith cautioned that the market may be overreacting to the situation. &quot;I don't think there's going to be a repricing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>   ((--Kevin Drawbaugh 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
