<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="343165" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: ALPINE SKIING-WIBERG DELIVERS MEDALS RATHER THAN MAIL.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-WIBERG DELIVERS MEDALS RATHER THAN MAIL.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>SESTRIERE, Italy 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pernilla Wiberg, a postwoman during her teenage years, now delivers gold medals rather than mail.</p>
<p>For four years Sweden's first woman Olympic Alpine champion earned extra money in a summer job with the postal service.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a good job,&quot; she once recalled. &quot;Running up and down all those stairs is good training.&quot;</p>
<p>Wiberg, now 26, has swapped Norrkoping for Monte Carlo and goes into next week's world champoinships here as the outstanding woman Alpine skier of the season and, in simple gold medal terms, easily the most successful female competing at this Italian resort.</p>
<p>Austrian Anita Wachter is the only woman still on the circuit to have more medals, seven spanning six world championships and three Olympics, but only one gold.</p>
<p>Wiberg has five , all gold and all won in just two championships and two Olympics.</p>
<p>No skier in Sestriere, not even supreme showman Alberto Tomba, has stashed away more gold than that.</p>
<p>The Swede has never won silver, never touched a bronze. In fact, apart from two fourth places in the 1994 Olympics, she either wins or ends up way back.</p>
<p>Where other athletes dream of merely getting a foot on the podium, Wiberg is thinking more in terms of completing her collection with some gold she feels she lacks.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to win downhill and super-G medals at the world championships because I have them in all the other disciplines,&quot; she said in Cortina d'Ampezzo.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be nice to complete the set.&quot;</p>
<p>While others feel the pressure, the Swede, with her apartment in Monte Carlo and all the trappings of sporting success, has little to prove and much to savour.</p>
<p>Her two Olympic titles, the 1992 giant slalom and 1994 combined titles, made her Sweden's second Olympic Alpine champion only in the wake of the great Ingemar Stenmark, twice a men's gold medallist at Lake Placid in 1980.</p>
<p>Add to those three world championship titles:  the 1991 giant slalom gold and the 1996 slalom and combined.</p>
<p>It would be a rash punter who bet against Wiberg adding to her medal haul here.</p>
<p>So far this season, the Swede has won four World Cup races, two super-Gs and two slaloms.</p>
<p>She will come to Sestriere leading the super-G and slalom World Cup standings as well as the overall World Cup, a prize never before been captured by a Swedish woman.</p>
<p>&quot;Wiberg is an incredible athlete,&quot; her new Italian coach Heinz-Peter Platter said earlier this month.</p>
<p>&quot;She is similar to (Norway's Kjetil-Andre) Aamodt and (Luxembourg's Marc) Girardelli on the men's circuit. Her only weakness is that often she just wants too much.&quot;</p>
<p>Wiberg has made giant strides towards the coveted first downhill win, with some help from the specialists.</p>
<p>Outspoken American Picabo Street, the world downhill champion who will be absent from Sestriere due to injury, has given her Swedish friend some important tips.</p>
<p>The improvement has been evident with Wiberg, who finished second in a downhill here last year, increasingly among the front-runners in both training sessions and races.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that I am more relaxed now than I have ever been,&quot; said Wiberg, who blew the overall World Cup title in 1994 when she crashed in the final downhill of the season at Vail.</p>
<p>This year she says she is not thinking about the overall title and is concentrating on the slalom crown.</p>
<p>&quot;I have been in the World Cup for quite some years now and also I have been training really well so when I stand at the start I know I have been doing everything in my power.</p>
<p>&quot;That gives you a lot of self-confidence and then you can just ski in a relaxed way and have fun.&quot;</p>
<p>Wiberg missed the 1993 world championships in Japan after tearing her right Achilles tendon in the Slovenian resort of Maribor, a serious injury that has niggled her since.</p>
<p>However she ended last season on a high and was able to train over the summer without worries.</p>
<p>&quot;I think I did more training this year because I was not injured, I could run and do everything and I didn't have too much pain in my Achilles tendon,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>After her 1991 giant slalom world championship gold, Wiberg made her singing debut on Swedish television and followed up that appearance with a record called &quot;Privilege&quot;.</p>
<p>The single, a venture she has yet to repeat, did not have record company executives beating a path to the skier's door but the title was perhaps prescient.</p>
<p>In sporting terms at least, Wiberg finds herself in a genuinely privileged position -- rich, famous and relaxed with her rivals feeling the pressure in her wake.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SESTRIERE, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
