<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="343160" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ATHLETICS-IAAF PAID JOHNSON TO SETTLE DISPUTE OVER BRITISH BAN.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-IAAF PAID JOHNSON TO SETTLE DISPUTE OVER BRITISH BAN.</headline>
<byline>Gene Cherry</byline>
<dateline>RALEIGH, North Carolina 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The IAAF has paid Olympic double champion Michael Johnson about $70,000 to resolve a dispute with British officials who reneged on a deal for him to run in Britain last year, his agent said Wednesday.</p>
<p>The money and the recent resignation of British Athletic Federation (BAF) executive chairman Peter Radford, who was strongly criticised for Johnson's banning from the race at Crystal Palace last July, may lead to Johnson running in Britain this summer, his agent, Brad Hunt, said.</p>
<p>The payment to Johnson followed Hunt's complaint to the IAAF after British officals had dropped Johnson from the 400-meter race, saying his participation would be demoralising to British runners so close to the Atlanta Olympics.</p>
<p>&quot;The (International Amateur Athletic Federation) paid the amount of money that Michael would have earned by running the race,&quot; Hunt said.</p>
<p>&quot;How they then in turn decided to resolve that with the BAF, I don't know,&quot; Hunt added.</p>
<p>Radford's resignation from the financially-trouble British federation was greeted with approval by Hunt</p>
<p>&quot;Regardless of the IAAF ruling, Michael was still not prepared to go to Britain and run in an event organised under the auspice of Peter Radford's leadership,&quot; Hunt said.</p>
<p>Johnson, who broke the 200-metre world record and won the 400-metre gold at the Atlanta Games, is skipping the current indoor season, but he will run a full schedule outdoors, Hunt said. Johnson, however, will not attempt to duplicate his Olympic double at the Athens world championships.</p>
<p>&quot;He will run just a single event at the U.S. and world championships, but he has not decided on which event yet. I think he would rather run the 400, but his early season preparation will be for a 150,&quot; Hunt said, laughing.</p>
<p>Johnson and Canadian Donovan Bailey, the 100-metre world record holder and Olympic champion, are scheduled to meet May 31 in Toronto in a 150-metre race to determine &quot;the world's fastest human,&quot; a title both claim.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RALEIGH, North Carolina"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
