<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="343386" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire fights rebels on many fronts, opposes talks.</title>
<headline>Zaire fights rebels on many fronts, opposes talks.</headline>
<byline>William Wallis</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's counter-offensive against rebels has run into resistance with its mercenary-backed army fighting rebels on several fronts, government and military sources said on Thursday.</p>
<p>But the government, which has opted for a military solution to the three-month-old Tutsi-led revolt in the east, once again ruled out negotiations, saying troops from neighbouring countries must leave first.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a dynamic developing in certain quarters for Zaire to negotiate with the rebels,&quot; Deputy Foreign Minister Henri Thomas Lokondo Yoka told reporters in Kinshasa. &quot;The government will not negotiate with the aggressors until we have recovered all the territory that has been occupied,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Zaire accuses Rwanda, Burundi and most recently Uganda of invading to back the rebels, who launched their offensive in October and hold towns and territory in the east.</p>
<p>All three deny their troops are fighting inside Zaire.</p>
<p>A senior Zairean defence ministry official said Ugandan troops backing the rebels had reached Bunia in Upper Zaire. Zaire's army earlier claimed to have retaken part of Bunia.</p>
<p>An army communique issued in Kinshasa on Thursday said Ugandan troops were fighting to take towns such as Watsa and Isiro, hundreds of km (miles) into Upper Zaire province.</p>
<p>Military sources told Reuters earlier Zairean soldiers and foreign mercenaries were based in Watsa.</p>
<p>The army accused Rwandan troops of fighting on the road from Walekale, just over 100 km (70 miles) from the Rwandan border, to Kisangani, headquarters for the Zairean counter-offensive.</p>
<p>It said Burundian soldiers were aiding rebels advancing down the road to the southern mining province of Shaba and were within 30 km (20 miles) of it.</p>
<p>The defence ministry official, who asked not to be identified, said they were within 70 km (45 miles) of Kalemie, home town of rebel leader Laurent Kabila.</p>
<p>&quot;We are having to fight on several fronts,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The accounts from Kinshasa were in line with reports from Rwanda that rebels in eastern Zaire were pushing south and west, opening new fronts to frustrate the army's counter-offensive.</p>
<p>&quot;The strategy is clearly to stretch out the front as far as possible,&quot; a Western diplomat in neighbouring Rwanda said.</p>
<p>After losing a long strip of eastern territory to Kabila's rebels late last year, Zaire's ailing President Mobutu Sese Seko and his government launched a counter-attack.</p>
<p>Reports from the field suggest Zaire's army, which launched its offensive on January 20, is increasingly on the defensive.</p>
<p>Western sources in Kinshasa in radio contact with the region said Watsa had already fallen to rebels with Ugandan backing.</p>
<p>The sources said the rebels and their allies had large supplies of anti-aircraft missiles and rocket-propelled grenades. Zairean troops and allied mercenaries had fled the superior numbers and weaponry of the rebels.</p>
<p>Zaire has significantly increased its arsenal, importing combat helicopters, fighter jets, artillery and munitions as well as around 300 mercenaries.</p>
<p>But senior military officials complain in private that despite recently acquired military hardware, the army has still to be given the full logistical support and munitions it needs -- in part due to foreign restrictions on arms sales.</p>
<p>&quot;Zaire finds itself in the situation of a boxer, well trained but with its hands tied by a military embargo, happy to take and dodge the blows delivered by the enemy,&quot; the army said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
