<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="343345" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Hyder &quot;outraged&quot; at Ofwat underspend list.</title>
<headline>Hyder &quot;outraged&quot; at Ofwat underspend list.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Welsh water and sewerage company Hyder Plc is &quot;outraged&quot; that it appears to be included among companies which watchdog Ofwat regards as under-investing, head of water services Brian Charles said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I am outraged by the Ofwat statement,&quot; Charles said in a telephone interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>The dispute arises from a statement issued by Ofwat earlier on Thursday which detailed rebates and price limits volunteered by companies in an attack on those that had fallen short of investment targets.</p>
<p>The list included Hyder, which had agreed to cap price increases half a percentage point below limits set by Ofwat for 1997-98.</p>
<p>But Charles said the cut was not connected with under-investment and that Hyder would actually exceed its spending target during the current year.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be spending 250 million pounds this year compared with our profile spend of 190 million,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Charles added that last year, however, Hyder spent 219 million pounds compared with a target of 250 million pounds.</p>
<p>It trimmed price increases by half a point in the period.</p>
<p>Ofwat sets price increase limits related to inflation and based on a profile of spending over a five year period.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
