<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34334" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary to offer stakes in spirits maker.</title>
<headline>Hungary to offer stakes in spirits maker.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's state privatisation agency APV Rt will publicly offer in a one-round tender a 76 percent plus one share stake in spirits maker Gyori Likorgyar Rt, an APV official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The share package will be divided into two parts, targeting two different categories of investors, APV spokesman Adam Dudits told APV's weekly news conference.</p>
<p>A 50 percent plus one share stake, worth a nominal 190.8 million forints, will be offered to strategic investors, who will have to pay be cash, although a preferential privatisation loan can be used up to an amount of 50 million forints.</p>
<p>A 26 percent stake or a nominal 99.2 million forints will be sold to original holders of compensation coupons, such as individuals, agricultural cooperatives and local governments who have to pay 15 percent of the purchase price by cash, while the rest can be paid by coupons.</p>
<p>No bids under face value will be accepted.</p>
<p>In 1995 Gyori Likoripari Rt posted an after-tax profit of 48 million forints on net sales of 960 million, while it paid 1.5 billion forints of consumption tax.</p>
<p>Compensation coupons were awarded to victims of expropriations and persecutions under Hungary's former fascist and communist regimes.</p>
<p>On the Budapest Stock Exchange coupons soared to close at a new year-high of 506 forints, up 26.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
