<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="343443" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Variable power shares seen supporting Kenya market.</title>
<headline>Variable power shares seen supporting Kenya market.</headline>
<byline>Wambui Chege</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The volatility seen in the share price of power monopoly Kenya Power &amp; Lighting over the last two weeks is a reflection of the prevailing bullish sentiment at the Nairobi Stock Exchange (NSE), bourse officials and brokers said.</p>
<p>In a span of 10 days, the price fluctuated between 339 and 90 shillings -- all pinned to the company's announcement of an eight-shilling dividend and a bonus issue of two shares for every one.</p>
<p>Brokers at the Nairobi bourse said the movement in price from 299 on Tuesday to Wednesday's close of 90 was not unusual attributing it to a downward adjustment after the share traded without bonus or dividend for the first day on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But a financial analyst at leading brokerage house Shah, Munge and Partners said : &quot;You've also got to be able to read the signs of the times. We are now operating in a more transparent economy with better levels of accountability.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that on-going restructuring in the company under the hawkish eye of the World Bank had earned it a lot of goodwill.</p>
<p>A senior broker said previously the share was largely ignored because of a 57 percent government shareholding.</p>
<p>But heavy foreign demand for the share had raised eyebrows, especially since the same pattern appeared to have occurred with Kenya Commercial Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Local investors are now asking themselves whether they have been hurting themselves because they've realised they stand to gain from shares supported by foreign demand,&quot; the broker told Reuters.</p>
<p>The market has seen heavy foreign investment in Kenya Commercial Bank, Firestone East Africa in the last six months and more recently Uchumi Supermarket.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are simply using basic fundamental indicators as a basis for their buying decisions. Our market shares are attractive because they have lower price earnings ratios and higher dividend yields compared to international markets,&quot; another broker said.</p>
<p>Earlier this month Kenya Power &amp; Lighting confirmed that it would separate its generation and distribution functions which would leave it as the power distribution monopoly in the country and effectively transfer its debt to new sister company Kenya Power Company which would now have the burden of generating sufficient electricity to meet the country's needs.</p>
<p>Brokers said that the full impact of the expansion was yet to be felt and as such any investment would be for the long term.</p>
<p>$1=54.72 Shillings)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
