<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34365" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - Sept 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - Sept 5.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Sarajevo press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>OSLOBODJENJE</p>
<p>- The OSCE will accept absentee ballots that arrive in Bosnia by mail by September 14 because of delays in postal services for refugees abroad, OSCE's senior adviser John Reed told the paper. Reed also says municipal elections could be held around December 1.</p>
<p>- Bosnian government Prime Minister Hasan Muratovic and Bosnian Serb assembly speaker Momcilo Krajisnik agree on mass grave exhumation process to begin by end of this week.</p>
<p>- Representatives from Bosnian and Croatian ministries of traffic and communication agree on seven land corridors to be constructed between the two countries. The joint proposal will be presented at a pan-European conference of traffic ministers next year in Helsinki.</p>
<p>- Bosnian Moslem-Croat Federation lacks 1.2 million German marks ($800,000) to finance elections, government official says. Out of a total of 2.7 million needed, OSCE and Federal government provided 1.5 million marks.</p>
<p>- The last Moslem-Croat federation parliament session before elections will be held on September 12.</p>
<p>DNEVNI AVAZ</p>
<p>- About 20,000 people attend a political rally of the ruling Moslem nationalist party SDA which promoted its leading candidate Alija Izetbegovic.</p>
<p>- A meeting on Brcko arbitration will be held September 6 in the United States embassy in Vienna.</p>
<p>- A deputy for the Bosnian foreign minister sends a letter to head of OSCE mission in Bosnia Robert Frowick asking for extension of absentee voting deadline. Voting abroad ended on September 3.</p>
<p>VECERNJE NOVINE</p>
<p>- Bosnia's railway company and director of Croatian Adriatic port of Ploce sign an agreement on rail traffic from the port to Bosnia.  --Sarajevo newsroom, +387-71-663-864.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
