<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="343774" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Cardoso's party is top dog in Brazil lower house. [CORRECTED 15:15 GMT]</title>
<headline>Cardoso's party is top dog in Brazil lower house. [CORRECTED 15:15 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The party of Brazilian President Fernando Henrique Cardoso has become the largest block in the lower house following his re-election victory, officials said.</p>
<p>Cardoso's Brazilian Social Democratic Party (PSDB) joined forces with the Brazilian Labour Party (PTB) and the Popular Socialist Party (PPS) and also stole two deputies from the Brazilian Progressive Party (PPB), the Congress officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've become the largest block in the lower house,&quot; a PSDB official said (correcting party affiliation of official). &quot;The agreement has been struck and it's just a question of details now. The accord should be formalized next week.&quot;  </p>
<p>The group now numbers 115 deputies, with 90 from the PSDB, 23 from the PTB and two from the PPS.</p>
<p>The PSDB official (corrects official's party affiliation) said the surge in the party's bulk was due to the fallout from Cardoso's victory in having the Chamber of Deputies approve in a first round vote on Tuesday a bill that would allow him to stand for a second term.</p>
<p>A constitutional amendment allowing sitting presidents, governors and mayors to seek second consecutive terms must pass through the Chamber again and then twice through the Senate.</p>
<p>The two PPB deputies who switched parties actually indicated before Tuesday's vote that they would desert and join the PSDB.</p>
<p>The PSDB, of which Cardoso is a founder member, will now be able to call the shots in the lower house, nominating the heads of committees and naming deputies to draft up bills.</p>
<p>The PTB was previously allied to the rightist Liberal Front Party (PFL), a government ally.</p>
<p>((-- Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom 55-61-2230358))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
