<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="343722" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru's Fujimori to meet Clinton and Hashimoto.</title>
<headline>Peru's Fujimori to meet Clinton and Hashimoto.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Alberto Fujimori will not apologise to Japan over controversial police actions at the besieged Japanese ambassador's residence in Lima nor seek approval for a military assault, senior government sources said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Fujimori will meet Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto in Toronto on Saturday to discuss the deadlocked 44-day hostage crisis and then travel to Washington the following day for similar talks with President Bill Clinton. He is scheduled to fly from Lima to Toronto aboard the presidential jet around midnight local time (0500 GMT), officials said.</p>
<p>Senior government sources, all speaking on condition of anonymity, insisted Fujmori would not apologise to Hashimoto for provocative police tactics at the siege site, which have worried Tokyo, nor seek his approval for a military assault.</p>
<p>They said in his meeting with Clinton, Fujimori planned to thank him for Washington's strong backing during the standoff with the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels holding 72 hostages.</p>
<p>Hashimoto said on Thursday the weekend summit would confirm Tokyo and Lima's joint strategy of not &quot;caving in to terrorism.&quot;</p>
<p>But he is likely to temper that tough talk with a plea that Lima avoid steps that could prompt the Marxist rebels to harm their hostages, who include two dozen Japanese, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;The meeting is not meddling with the Peruvian government, but is a discussion,&quot; government spokesman Seiroku Kajiyama said.</p>
<p>Fujimori has not commented publicly on the meeting, but his chief crisis negotiator, Domingo Palermo, described it as a joint evaluation of &quot;strategy set out to reach a solution.&quot;</p>
<p>Palermo told a news conference the meeting also &quot;looks to make possible the carrying out of operative aspects&quot; to end the crisis.</p>
<p>As attention focused on the Toronto meeting, police outside the residence kept up their war of nerves against about 15 heavily armed rebels inside the mined compound.</p>
<p>A recording of martial music with the roar of aircraft in the background was blasted at the site around 1 a.m. local time and again soon after dawn. It created the impression helicopters and planes were approaching the fortified compound, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Police have played the music periodically for several days to wear down the rebels, but Thursday was the first time they turned on the music during sleeping hours.</p>
<p>Scores of policemen took part in a massive show of force in front of the compound on Monday, driving past in an armoured convoy to the tune of the marching music. Some made obscene gestures, provoking a burst of gunfire from the rebels which narrowly missed policemen aboard one vehicle.</p>
<p>Hashimoto called earlier this week for Fujimori to exercise caution in the deployment of police at the site to prevent &quot;accidents or incidents.&quot;</p>
<p>Canadian Prime Minister Jean Chretien said his country was chosen to host Hashimoto's meeting with Fujimori because of its mediating role in the crisis which has been accepted by both sides.</p>
<p>Efforts to start talks with the MRTA guerrillas have stalled over the main rebel demand of freedom for about 400 jailed comrades, which Fujimori has refused to discuss.</p>
<p>The MRTA rebels originally seized hundreds of guests when they stormed the residence on Dec. 17 during a diplomatic reception. They released most of the captives but kept 72 key people, including Fujimori's brother and the Japanese and Bolivian ambassadors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
