<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="343862" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan to ease ban on alcohol adverts in WTO bid.</title>
<headline>Taiwan to ease ban on alcohol adverts in WTO bid.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan on Thursday agreed to lift its ban on print alcohol advertisements and ease restrictions on alcohol television commercials as part of its bid to join the World Trade Organisation (WTO), state-run news agency reported.</p>
<p>But Taiwan would not loosen its all-out ban on tobacco advertisements on its first day of a new round of trade talks with the United States concerning the island's quest to join the global trade group, the Central News Agency said.</p>
<p>Under an initial agreement reached by the two sides, Taiwan would permit print alcohol advertisements and allow limited showing of alcohol commercials on television after the abolition of its tobacco and alcohol monopoly in two years.</p>
<p>But all tobacco advertisements would still be prohibited, the agency quoted Lin Yi-fu, head of the Board of Foreign Trade, as saying.</p>
<p>Taiwan currently runs a monopoly on the domestic tobacco and alcohol markets, with importers obliged to pay stiff monopoly fees. It also subsidises many farm products by setting government-guaranteed prices.</p>
<p>Taiwan is set to discuss tobacco and alcohol tariffs with the United States during the second day of their discussions, scheduled to last until Monday.</p>
<p>Although Taiwan has promised to end its tobacco and alcohol monopoly as part of its efforts to join the WTO, it has yet to reveal details of the liberalisation plan.</p>
<p>The last round of talks, held in Taipei in mid-November, ended without significant agreements because the sides differed on how much Taiwan should liberalise its agricultural, tobacco and alcohol industries.</p>
<p>Taiwan, keen to join the WTO in 1997, has completed necessary bilateral talks with 12 of the 26 WTO members that have sought such dialogue with Taipei.</p>
<p>Taiwan applied in 1990 to join the organisation's predecessor, the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, or GATT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
