<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="343895" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan chipmakers praise Samsung cut in chips.</title>
<headline>Taiwan chipmakers praise Samsung cut in chips.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Chen</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan computer chipmakers said on Thursday that Samsung Electronics' decision to cut production of 16-megabit memory chips may help stabilise the chips' recent freefalling prices but it would not have a lasting impact.</p>
<p>Analysts also said the South Korean company's output reduction may force its Taiwan competitors to speed up preparation for the industry's eventual entry into the next-generation 64 megabit market.</p>
<p>&quot;We obviously welcome anything that would help stop the falling chip prices,&quot; said Chien Shueh-jen, vice president of Vanguard International Semiconductor. Vanguard is an affiliate of the island's biggest semiconductor maker, Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Corp.</p>
<p>Samsung is the world's largest producer of 16-megabit dynamic random access memory chips (DRAMs), whose global prices have plunged about 80 percent in the past year.</p>
<p>But analysts in Taiwan said while Samsung's cutback may spell temporary relief for the dropping value of 16-megabit chips, it would not be a cure-all for the chips' underlying problem with oversupply.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't expect DRAM prices to start a firm recovery until late this year (1997), when new computer products are expected to come out and demand for the chips will rise again,&quot; said Michael Hung, a securities manager for Nikko Securities.</p>
<p>Vanguard's Chien said Samsung's decision to cut 16-megabit chip production might indicate the South Korean giant would launch a campaign to push the global market towards the faster but more expensive 64-megabit chips.</p>
<p>&quot;It was already inevitable that the 64MB chip would eventually take over the market; Samsung's move may just speed up the takeover,&quot; Chien said.</p>
<p>Vanguard said it aimed to attain production capability for the 64-megabit chips by 1998.</p>
<p>Joe Chiou, a securities analyst for Taiwan Securities Investment, said he did not expect the 16-megabit chip to become obsolete immediately after the arrival of the 64-megabit version, but profit yield for the lower-end DRAMs would slump.</p>
<p>&quot;There will still be things like personal computers that would use the 16MB DRAMs, because personal computer users are not going to switch their chips that quickly,&quot; Chiou said.</p>
<p>&quot;But still, the demand will be lower, meaning there is less profit to be made,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Winbond Electronics Corp, Taiwan's third largest semiconductor maker, said it would not alter plans to begin producing both types of DRAMs by the end of 1997 under a technology agreement with Japan's Toshiba Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now the 16MB DRAMs are still the mainstream chip products in Taiwan. Samsung's decision will not influence our production plans,&quot; said Winbond spokesman Michael Liu.</p>
<p>But Winbond added it would closely monitor the market trend to determine how many of each DRAM type to make.</p>
<p>&quot;If it becomes obvious that the 64MB chips are dominating the market, we would turn our production focus to them obviously,&quot; Liu said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
