<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34381" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Sept 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Sept 5.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Croatian newspapers on Thursday.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- Traffic experts from Croatia and Bosnia will ask European Union to grant them seven road and railway corridors including those to Belgrade, Budapest and Albania.</p>
<p>- Prime minister Zlatko Matesa says demining of the last Serb enclave in eastern Slavonia well under way. Slavonska banka soon to open its branches there as a step towards reintegration.</p>
<p>- Central bank's interest rate fell to eight percent in August from 32 percent in May as its hard currency reserves reached $2.34 million.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- EBRD as a European bank is still the biggest foreign investor in Croatia, but its general manager for eastern Europe Peter Bod says peace will draw other investors.</p>
<p>- Two more private secondary schools opening in Zagreb this fall in addition to six that already exist.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- Vital railway route between Croatian port Ploce and Sarajevo to become operational in January following an agreement signed between Croatian and Bosnian railway companies.</p>
<p>- Government proposes new law on war veterans envisaging more advantages for all cathegories of invalids. State to provide them with some 4,670 new flats by the end of the year. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
