<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="343959" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Blue-chip stocks end sharply higher for second day.</title>
<headline>Blue-chip stocks end sharply higher for second day.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue-chip stocks ended sharply higher for a second consecutive day Thursday as the market reversed the damage from its recent sell-off and investors got new evidence that business trends remain robust in the technology sector.</p>
<p>The 30-stock Dow Jones industrial average ended up 83.12 points at 6,823.86, adding to Wednesday's gain of 85 points, which was its first  bounce from five-straight sessions of losses.</p>
<p>In the broader market, advancing issues beat declines 1,543 to 910 on heavy volume of 520 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The market was also relieved that Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan did not come out with any surprises in his second congressional testimony about the economy in less than two weeks.</p>
<p>In prepared testimony before the Senate Finance Committee, the Fed chief gave little hint that the central bank was considering raising interest rates at the Feb. 4 and 5 meeting of the policy-setting Federal Open Market Committee.</p>
<p>&quot;I still picture them as trigger-finger ready but I don't think it will happen next week,&quot; said Allen Sinai, chief global economist at Primark Decision Economics.</p>
<p>Greenspan said that the Consumer Price Index, a leading gauge of inflation, was overstating inflation by 0.5 to 1.5 percent, and that he opposed the idea of the federal government becoming a huge shareholder in common stocks through the Social Security System.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Fed doesn't raise rates, then there's still upside,&quot; said Edgar Peters, chief investment strategist at PanAgora Asset Management Inc.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond was up 13/32 of a point, which lowered its yield to 6.88 percent from Wednesday's close of 6.90 percent.</p>
<p>Over the last two days the Dow index has recouped two-thirds of what it lost during its five-day skid.</p>
<p>Peters said the recent selloff might actually be a sign the market is behaving in a more healthy fashion than in recent years.</p>
<p>&quot;The market rose very fast and that was a little crazy,&quot; he said. &quot;You have to expect some pullbacks. The thing that's been unhealthy is the lack of pullbacks over the last year or two.&quot;</p>
<p>Semiconductor companies were among the strongest performers, boosted by Intel Corp.'s decision to hold prices essentially steady for its high-end Pentium Pro chips in the first quarter.</p>
<p>Analysts had expected Intel to cut prices to some degree from fourth-quarter 1996 levels and they viewed the news as evidence that demand remains strong for semiconductor chips.</p>
<p>&quot;The underlying tone is that it's not over in tech-land yet,&quot; said Arnie Owen, director of equities at Kaufman Brothers.</p>
<p>Intel surged 5-3/8 to 160-1/8 and others in the sector followed suit. Micron Technology Inc. climbed 2-1/4 to 35-1/4 and semiconductor equipment maker Applied Materials Inc. gained 2-1/2 to 48-3/8.</p>
<p>The rally in technology stocks was a bit of a mixed blessing, however. Largely left out of the strength were personal computer makers, which are the main buyers of microprocessors and therefore stand to lose from Intel's pricing decisions.</p>
<p>Gateway 2000 Inc. gained 1/4 to 60-1/4 and Dell Computer Corp.  rose 3/8 to 66.</p>
<p>Drug stocks were strong, as investors flocked to the group's solid earnings and defensive appeal.</p>
<p>Warner-Lambert Co. jumped 3-1/8 to 78 after announcing that the Food and Drug Administration had approved its Rezulin anti-diabetes tablets.</p>
<p>Other pharmaceutical standouts included Eli Lilly &amp; Co., which surged 4-7/8 to 86-7/8, and Pfizer Inc., up 4-1/8 to 90-3/4.</p>
<p>Procter &amp; Gamble Co. added 3-57/64 to 115-1/8 to lead all Dow index components. Since reporting earnings Tuesday morning, P&amp;G's shares have risen more than seven points.</p>
<p>Among other individual issues, Hughes Supply Inc. tumbled 5-1/8 to 33-1/4 after warning that its fourth-quarter earnings would be below Wall Street estimates.</p>
<p>Jayhawk Acceptance Corp. skidded 4-1/2 to 3-5/8 on a fourth-quarter loss. The company cited a $15.5 million charge to increase its credit loss allowance.</p>
<p>Mercury Finance Co. failed to open for trading for the second straight session since it disclosed that it had accounting irregularities that resulted in earnings overstatements totalling $90 million over the last four years.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index gained 15.85 points to 1,371.02. The Russell 2000 index of small capitalisation stocks rose 2.04 to 368.29.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks rose 11.67 to 784.17. The American Stock Exchange index was up 0.99 to 588.66.</p>
<p>The NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks rose 5.11 to 411.20. The average share was up 53 cents.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 7,556.786, up 92.720, or 1.04 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
