<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34401" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: INTERVIEW-Simec says 1997 output to rise.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Simec says 1997 output to rise.</headline>
<byline>Monica Ballesca</byline>
<dateline>GUADALAJARA, Mexico 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grupo Simec, the industrial arm of the holding company Grupo Sidek, forecasts 1997 production of 759,000 tonnes of iron and aluminium products, or 15 percent above 1996 figures, the company CEO told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We will produce 660,000 tonnes this year and in 1997 it will be 759,000 tonnes,&quot; Simec CEO Luis Garcia Limon said in an interview.  </p>
<p>The increase will come from greater production at the company's Guadalajara works, which manfactures aluminium extrusions and cast-iron steel balls for the mining industry, Garcia said.</p>
<p>Production will be boosted by investments made in 1996 of $30 million in the aluminium products line, and seven million pesos in iron.</p>
<p>Investments have raised aluminium production to 1,800 tonnes per month, compared with 600 tonnes at the beginning of 1996, Garcia added.  </p>
<p>The new aluminium extrusions line is expected to export almost 50 percent of its output. Exports would then account for 30 percent of Simec's total sales, compared with a current 25 percent, Garcia said.</p>
<p>Investment in steel production, meanwhile, would increase cast-iron ball production from a current 30,000 tonnes per month to 60,000 tonnes per month, he said.</p>
<p>Garcia added the investments will directly create 200 jobs and increase Simec's workforce to 2,119.</p>
<p>Simec's steelmaking division currently operates two plants, one in Guadalajara, the other in Mexicali, on the U.S. border, which produce 770,000 tonnes of ingots and 660,000 tonnes of non-flat strip per year. Simec has a 65 percent share of the domestic market for structural sections over three inches wide and 46 percent in iron bars.</p>
<p>-- Guadalajara newsroom, +523 817-0397</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUADALAJARA, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
