<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="344100" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar retreats modestly, pace of recent gains questioned.</title>
<headline>Dollar retreats modestly, pace of recent gains questioned.</headline>
<byline>Noah Barkin</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar retreated modestly against the Japanese yen and the German mark on Thursday, as traders questioned the rapid rise of the U.S. currency recently.</p>
<p>Remarks from an influential Japanese government official rekindled worries that Japan may intervene to defend the ailing yen, and jitters ahead of an upcoming summit meeting of the Group of Seven industrialised nations also helped push the dollar lower.</p>
<p>But dealers said the dollar remains firmly supported by a solid U.S. economic backdrop and that its retreat Wednesday was probably little more than a pause before a further run-up.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has been forced to reassess the speed with which the dollar will continue to correct upwards,&quot; said Hillel Waxman, first vice president of foreign exchange at Bank Leumi Trust Co. of New York.</p>
<p>&quot;Trading has become somewhat lackluster, but all the fundamentals are still in place for the dollar to go higher.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar ended the day at 121.79 yen, down from 122.18 yen late Wednesday. Against the mark, the dollar settled at 1.6370, below Wednesday's 1.6440.</p>
<p>Japanese Finance Ministry official Eisuke Sakakibara, known as &quot;Mr. Yen&quot; for his influence on the currency markets, told a Japanese news agency on Thursday that his government would intervene to defend the yen at the proper time if the weak currency was harming the Japanese economy.</p>
<p>The remarks knocked the dollar down from a near four-year peak against the yen, and sparked worries that G7 nations could call for an end to the dollar's sharp climb when they meet in Berlin on Feb. 8.</p>
<p>But the damage remained fairly well contained, dealers said, mainly because the United States has shown no signs of wavering from its advocacy of a strong dollar. On Thursday, Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin reiterated that U.S. policy on the dollar was unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;You never know if independent nations will take some action at some point to slow the dollar's rise,&quot; said Seth Garrett, chief foreign exchange dealer at Credit Suisse First Boston, said referring to Sakakibara's remarks.</p>
<p>&quot;But Rubin keeps reiterating that the U.S. strong dollar policy is unchanged and that is underpinning it somewhat.&quot;</p>
<p>Remarks from Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan, who testified before the Senate Finance Committee on Thursday, sparked little reaction in the currency markets. But uncertainty ahead of key fourth-quarter U.S. growth figures due Friday, and next week's Fed policy meeting, made traders hesitant to push the dollar higher.</p>
<p>In other trade late Thursday, British sterling retreated to $1.6128 from $1.6202 late Wednesday after rising initially on stronger-than-expected British consumer credit figures.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the dollar retreated to 1.4236 Swiss francs from 1.4265 on Wednesday. It climbed modestly to Canadian $1.3474 from C$1.3453.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
