<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="344113" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FDA deputy to lead agency temporarily after Kessler.</title>
<headline>FDA deputy to lead agency temporarily after Kessler.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior Food and Drug Administration official, Dr. Michael Friedman, will temporarily lead the agency while the search continues for a permanent head, the departing commissioner Dr. David Kessler announced Thursday.</p>
<p>Kessler, who told associates he plans to leave by late February, announced the transitional arrangement in a memo to FDA staff that was later released to reporters. Friedman was described as the &quot;lead deputy commissioner.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;He will perform the duties of commissioner when I depart,&quot; Kessler said. &quot;Mike is well prepared to manage the wide range of issues the FDA faces every day.&quot;</p>
<p>Friedman was currently the deputy commissioner for operations and had much day-to-day responsibility for FDA management.</p>
<p>Secretary of Health and Human Services Donna Shalala was searching for a permanent replacement for Kessler.</p>
<p>A  medical doctor with both managerial and scientific background, Friedman has often been cited as a leading inside candidate.</p>
<p>But many Washington observers expect Shalala to go outside the agency to find a candidate who has not been embroiled by the controversies over teen smoking and drug approval procedures during Kessler's tenure.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
