<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="344181" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Atlanta Hartsfield airport plans $250 mln bonds.</title>
<headline>Atlanta Hartsfield airport plans $250 mln bonds.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Atlanta's Hartsfield International Airport and its carriers have reached a runway financing agreement that will include a $250 million revenue bond issue by the end of the year, airport business manager Art Bacon said Thursday.</p>
<p>The bond issue is part of a $444 million project to add a fifth runway, to be used mainly by small commuter planes.</p>
<p>The airport will levy a $3-per ticket passenger facilities charge, raising $194 million for land acquisition and design work. The tax will take effect this spring if the Federal Aviation Administration approves it next month.</p>
<p>Construction will be funded with a $250 million revenue bond issue, to be sold by competitive bid, Bacon said. The bonds still must be approved by the City of Atlanta, which owns the airport, and are expected to be sold by the end of the year.</p>
<p>Debt service on the bonds, estimated at $23 million annually, will be paid from increases in landing fees, which are pro-rated among the carriers according to landed weights.</p>
<p>The airport will also apply for up to $150 million federal grant money for the project.</p>
<p>Construction is scheduled to begin in May 1998, Bacon said.</p>
<p>The new runway will expand Hartsfield's capacity by 25 percent, cutting passenger delays and reducing congestion by providing landing space for small commuter planes that now back up larger, faster jets.</p>
<p>Although airline landing fees will rise, Bacon said their actual costs could decline because of reduced delays.</p>
<p>The last bond issue for Hartsfield was a a $277 million revenue bond refinancing in 1996. Bacon said the airport is drafting a master plan that could call for additional building and renovation, possibly beginning in 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;There possibly will be some more underwitings, some of it using bond financing, but as to how much or when I don't know,&quot; Bacon said.</p>
<p>--Jane Sutton, 305-374-5013</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
