<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="344293" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's San Paolo bank announces privatising plan.</title>
<headline>Italy's San Paolo bank announces privatising plan.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>San Paolo, Italy's largest banking group, announced on Thursday it planned to offer a major stake on the stock market in a move which would turn the firm into an independent public company.</p>
<p>San Paolo Holding, which controls 65 percent of San Paolo bank, said in a statement it planned to offer a total 45 percent of Istituto San Paolo di Torino bank's capital through a private placement and a public sale offer (OPV).</p>
<p>&quot;At the end of the project the bank will be a public company without controlling shareholders,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>San Paolo is controlled ultimately, like many Italian banks, by a charitable foundation, Compagnia di San Paolo, but its immediate majority shareholder is San Paolo Holding SpA.</p>
<p>The bank also said Italian academic and novelist Umberto Eco, author of best selling book &quot;The Name of the Rose&quot;, had been appointed to the board of the foundation.</p>
<p>The banking group did not say when it expected the sell-off to be completed, noting it still had to obtain the necessary authorisation. But group chairman Gianni Zandano said last year the group was looking to privatise in 1997.</p>
<p>The project envisages a two-phase privatisation with around 20 percent being offered to strategic and institutional investors who would form a stable core of shareholders.</p>
<p>A further 25 percent would then be offered publically on the domestic and international markets.</p>
<p>San Paolo Holding is 100 percent controlled by the foundation and the project aims to reduce the Compagnia's stake in the bank to around 20-25 percent, with a plan also for limited voting rights on that remnant stake.</p>
<p>The move comes shortly ahead of an expected shake-up in Italy's overcrowded and underperforming banking sector, where many banks are controlled by charitable foundations which are themselves often controlled by local and national state bodies.</p>
<p>The cabinet of Prime Minister Romano Prodi earlier on Thursday approved a draft delegate law on restructuring the banking sector and the nonprofit-making foundations.</p>
<p>The draft law aims to encourage reorganisation and concentration in the sector where analysts say rationalisation is needed to match other European countries' banking industries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
