<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34434" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexicans ask if new rebels linked to ruling party.</title>
<headline>Mexicans ask if new rebels linked to ruling party.</headline>
<byline>Michael Stott</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A photograph linking suspected members of a new guerrilla group to a top official in Mexico's ruling party has led to speculation the rebels might have ties to hardliners within the government.</p>
<p>The idea that old-guard politicians in the Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI) could use a Marxist guerrilla group to hurt President Ernesto Zedillo may seem absurd. But in Mexico, where conspiracy theory is an artform and murky political plots a fact of life, the suggestion is plausible to some.</p>
<p>The talk began after a local newspaper in the southeastern state of Tabasco published on Tuesday a photograph showing two men arrested as suspected Popular Revolutionary Army (EPR) rebels flanking Gov. Roberto Madrazo on a campaign tour.</p>
<p>Government chief spokesman Dionisio Perez Jacome denied on Wednesday that the EPR had any connection to, or support from, the long-ruling PRI. He repeated the official line that the EPR, which sprang up on June 28 calling for the overthrow of the government, was linked to PROCUP, an extreme leftist party that operated in the 1970s.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no investigation in that direction because we don't have any evidence suggesting that this is happening; all we have is that the origin of the EPR is in PROCUP,&quot; he told the pro-government Televisa network.</p>
<p>Madrazo, the centre of a scandal this year over allegations he spent more than 10 times the legal limit to win election, blamed the media for creating what he termed &quot;fraudulent confusion.&quot;</p>
<p>But others were less certain about who was behind the shadowy EPR, which has attacked in several different states over the past two months and claims to have killed 27 people, mostly army or police.</p>
<p>Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador, leader of the left-wing Party of the Democratic Revolution (PRD), told reporters on Wednesday his party recognised one of the two alleged EPR sympathisers as the same man who had helped in the violent breakup of a PRD sit-in in the state capital Villahermosa.</p>
<p>&quot;If links between the suspected members of the EPR and PRI are proven, we are no longer talking about a doctrinal group but a group of people which responds more to political interests&quot;, he added.</p>
<p>Miguel Angel Granados Chapa, a leading left-wing columnist, said in Reforma newspaper on Thursday that investigators should at the very least take seriously the suggestion that PRI hardliners might be behind the EPR.</p>
<p>&quot;We now know that the EPR is a coalition of groups above all the old (PROCUP), but among its members there could be new and unidentified presences ... A clandestine grouping can be infiltrated by government elements or by diverse political tendencies&quot;, he wrote.</p>
<p>Zedillo has made enemies among old-style politicians determined to perpetuate the PRI's 67-year stranglehold on power into the next century. But Juan Molinar, a respected analyst at the Colegio de Mexico, said no conspiracy theory was necessary to explain links between the EPR and the PRI.</p>
<p>The PRI had a long tradition of co-opting radical groups into its ranks rather than confronting them directly, and as a result it was not surprising that some EPR members might know or even have been members of the ruling party, he said. This did not mean a hardliner in the PRI was pulling strings to manipulate the guerrillas.</p>
<p>As one example, Molinar said survivors from a radical 1970s guerrilla movement in Guerrero, the state that has seen most EPR activity, were later co-opted into local security forces by the state government. &quot;Those people are still around and they certainly have links to the PRI,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
