<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="344354" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian franc weakens more on political concerns.</title>
<headline>Belgian franc weakens more on political concerns.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Belgian franc weakened further below its central ERM rate on Thursday as foreign investors became nervous about an ongoing corruption scandal surrounding the country's PS Francophone socialist party.</p>
<p>By 1620 GMT the franc was trading at 20.6310/30, beyond its 20.6255 central rate in the exchange rate mechanism which was broken at midsession for the first time since May 1995. Late Wednesday the franc stood at 20.6213/33.</p>
<p>&quot;The mark/(Belgian franc) move, due to the political scandals, is a bit exaggerated. But if we break 20.6330 we could fall to 20.6500,&quot; one currency dealer in Belgium said.  </p>
<p>He said there had been no sign of the Belgian National Bank intervening today, but thought the central bank might come in to support the currency if the 20.6500 level was reached.</p>
<p>Another dealer said selling had come from New York due to increased concern about the bribery scandal.</p>
<p>He added too, though, that he did not expect Belgian central bank intervention at current levels.</p>
<p>On Thursday pressure on the Belgian government increased when an opposition liberal party offered to replace the PS in the four-party ruling coalition.</p>
<p>However the biggest coalition party - the Flemish Christian Democrat CVP - dismissed the idea, saying it was not at the stage of changing partners.</p>
<p>Two senior PS party figures have been charged with corruption in relation to a contract in 1989 to buy air defence systems for the country's F-16 fighter jets from French defence firm Dassault. The company has denied all wrongdoing.</p>
<p>Belgian foreign exchange traders as well as bond market dealers have said they are confident the government will survive, noting the Christian Democrats do not want a crisis now as the country prepares for European economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
