<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="344855" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT to re-negotiate linkage plan with LIFFE.</title>
<headline>CBOT to re-negotiate linkage plan with LIFFE.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) directors decided late Tuesday to renegotiate a linkage plan with the London International Financial Futures &amp; Options Exchange (LIFFE) in order to keep their electronic after-hours trading system open longer hours.</p>
<p>A CBOT spokesman said the CBOT would ask to delete a stipulation with LIFFE that required both exchanges to curtail their overnight electronic trading hours.</p>
<p>When asked whether the link would go ahead if LIFFE did not approve the changes, the spokesman said, &quot;We will have to see what their response is before we decide how to react.&quot;  </p>
<p>The CBOT will specifically ask to keep Project A, the CBOT's in-house trading system, open until its normal 0645 CST/1245 GMT close. It will also propose that LIFFE's after-hours system, APT, stay open until 1800 GMT/1200 CST, instead of closing at 1705 GMT/1105 CST as originally agreed.</p>
<p>Under the original agreement, the CBOT would close Project A at 0400 CST/1000 GMT. The CBOT also agreed to shut Project A down as early as 0130 CST/0730 GMT if Treasury bond futures volume exceeded 3,000 contracts.  </p>
<p>A CBOT spokesman said increased volume on Project A led to the board's decision to seek to amend the CBOT-LIFFE agreement. Any new plan approved by LIFFE must then be approved by CBOT members, the CBOT spokesman said.</p>
<p>The link is scheduled to begin on May 9 and will allow CBOT Treasury bond futures and options to trade at LIFFE during its open outcry session, and will allow LIFFE's German bund contract to trade at the CBOT during its open outcry session. ((Derivatives desk 312-408-8750;E-mail derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
