<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="344937" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Toyota stirs political row in Britain.</title>
<headline>Toyota stirs political row in Britain.</headline>
<byline>Alan Wheatley</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>If the question of whether to join Europe's single currency becomes a hot issue at Britain's coming election, the credit -- or blame -- will go to Haroshi Okuda.</p>
<p>By threatening to consider building new factories in Europe instead of Britain if London does not sign up for the single currency, the Toyota president has brought alive an issue that has long transfixed politicians but left most voters cold.</p>
<p>Just as importantly, his comments have also touched off a new round of internecine feuding within the ruling Conservative party between Euro-sceptics who oppose closer integration and Euro-philes who fret that Britain risks isolation in Europe.</p>
<p>Toyota's threat, though grim in its possible implications for British jobs, was seized on by pro-European Conservatives who have been fighting a losing battle to stem the party's anti-European drift.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a serious warning from one of the world's most important companies, and we ignore it at our peril,&quot; one pro-European, Hugh Dykes, said.</p>
<p>Euro-sceptics, who are viscerally opposed to scrapping the pound in favour of a single currency, rounded on their pro-European colleagues and Okuda in equal measure.</p>
<p>Former finance minister Norman Lamont said the Toyota chief should stay out of British politics, while another prominent Euro-sceptic, Bill Cash, spoke of a &quot;propaganda exercise&quot; by the pro-Europeans.</p>
<p>&quot;A great deal of mischief and damage has been done to British industry by misleading statements by a number of Euro-federalists who ought to know better,&quot; Cash said.</p>
<p>To Prime Minister John Major, who must face the electorate by May 22, the Toyota affair is doubly damaging.</p>
<p>Not only has it has given Conservatives another occasion to display their divisions just weeks before the election, it has also undermined Major's claim that Conservative pro-business policies have turned Britain into a mecca for foreign investors.</p>
<p>Just hours before Okuda spoke on Wednesday, Major was breaking the ground for a South Korean electronics plant in south Wales that will create 6,000 jobs, calling it a &quot;massive vote of confidence in the future of the United Kingdom&quot;.</p>
<p>Ministers, visibly discomfited, immediately took to the airwaves to play down Toyota's comments and were still dousing the flames on Thursday.</p>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Michael Heseltine said Okuda's remarks had been a gross overstatement and that any businessman would applaud Britain's decision not to make up its mind whether to join the single currency until it had all the facts.</p>
<p>&quot;No one today in the top level of business would tell you whether or when the single currency is going to work. They certainly would tell you that if the economic circumstances aren't propitious they wouldn't want anything to do with it.&quot;</p>
<p>The opposition Labour Party, 20 percentage points ahead of the Conservatives in the polls, gleefully accused the government of putting jobs at risk through its divisions over Europe.</p>
<p>But with Labour also refusing to make up its mind now on whether to join the single currency, due for launch in 1999, analysts said it was not clear that the party could reap much political capital out of the controversy.</p>
<p>&quot;What Okuda's words show are the uncertainty caused by the failure of the Tories and Labour to set out clearly what they will do about the single currency,&quot; the best-selling Sun tabloid said in an editorial.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
