<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="345253" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Dollar, Japanese stocks take a dive in Tokyo.</title>
<headline>Dollar, Japanese stocks take a dive in Tokyo.</headline>
<byline>Tatsuo Ito</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar went into retreat on Thursday, ceding almost a full yen, and Tokyo stocks also stumbled after a senior Japanese finance official held out the possibility of action to prop up the sagging yen.</p>
<p>Although dealers were sceptical about Japan's intervention resolve, the comments by the Finance Ministry's &quot;Mr Yen&quot;, Eisuke Sakakibara, were enough to check the dollar's recent rally and allow gloom to descend once more on the stock market.</p>
<p>Japanese shares had managed to rise for two days in a row as the dollar's climb to fresh 47-month highs had investors flocking to buy shares in big-name Japanese exporters whose profits would benefit from a weak yen.</p>
<p>The key Nikkei average ended with a loss of 2.57 percent, or just over 471 points, giving back almost half of the gains it had racked up in the previous two sessions.</p>
<p>After rising in early Tokyo trade, the dollar slipped back as dealers who had been betting on inaction by the Japanese authorities grew wary of possible yen-buying intervention. It also provided a pretext to cash in profits from the rally.</p>
<p>Sakakibara, head of the ministry's international finance bureau, was quoted by Jiji news agency as saying that Japan could intervene in the foreign exchange markets to protect the economy. &quot;When we judge that there is really harm being done to the Japanese economy, we will conduct (intervention) when the timing is effective,&quot; he was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Traders, notably U.S. fund operators and bank traders here, sold dollars aggressively after the reported comments, which contrasted with signals earlier this week that Japan was not unduly worried about the yen's drop in value.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that Sakakibara's comments were nothing more than verbal intervention, but caution after recent rapid rises over the past few days also grew,&quot; said a bank dealer.</p>
<p>The dollar had been buoyed earlier after Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin said the U.S. dollar policy remained unchanged.</p>
<p>Traders said that the dollar was going through a downward correction after having risen more than three yen since the start of this week.</p>
<p>Overnight comments by Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer also made traders wary of accumulating fresh dollar positions. Tietmeyer said he expected the &quot;normalisation&quot; of the dollar's moves against the mark to end soon.</p>
<p>&quot;But today's fall was merely a correction against a recent rapid rally and does not imply that the dollar's bull run has ended,&quot; said a dealer at a European bank. Buying from Japanese operators on dollar dips stayed strong.</p>
<p>The dollar stood at around 121.30 yen in late afternoon Tokyo trade, compared with a late U.S. level on Wednesday of around 122.17 yen. Its low for the day in Tokyo was 120.90 yen, a drop of more than a yen from the U.S. close.</p>
<p>Meanwhile on the stock market, the dollar's retreat stemmed buying of shares in export-oriented companies, whose products become more competitive overseas if the home currency is weak.</p>
<p>With blue-chip demand petering out, lingering worries about the health of the banking sector once again captured the market's attention. Brokers said there was uncertainty about how far bank shares still had to fall.</p>
<p>&quot;There were no investors to aggressively buy cash stocks,&quot; said a fund manager at a foreign trust bank.</p>
<p>The 225-share Nikkei dropped by 471.26 points to end at 17,864.04. It fell as low as 17,781.89 at one point.</p>
<p>The market, especially banking shares, may see another wave of selling ahead of corporate book closings in March, analysts said. Stocks have been battered this month by worries about the state of the economy, as well by concern over the bad-loan burdened banking industry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
