<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="345335" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan subway guru ordered out of court again.</title>
<headline>Japan subway guru ordered out of court again.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese doomsday cult guru Shoko Asahara, charged with murder for a deadly gas attack on Tokyo subways, was thrown out of court on Thursday for interrupting his own trial.</p>
<p>In what has become a regular occurrence in his 10-month trial, Asahara ignored pleas by his lawyers to keep quiet, shouting at witnesses and judges presiding over the hearing.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a court, so act like a judge. You have no right to stop me, the defendant, from speaking my point of view,&quot; Asahara said when the judges warned him to stop his outbursts.</p>
<p>However, Asahara, who is charged with masterminding the March 1995 sarin nerve gas attack on Tokyo's subway system which killed 12 people and made thousands ill, refused to back down.</p>
<p>&quot;Why do Japanese people have to be reverent all the time?&quot; Asahara said.</p>
<p>His outburst came during testimony by forensic experts on the deadly effects of the sarin nerve gas.</p>
<p>In what has become a regular feature of his twice-monthly appearances, Asahara swayed restlessly in his chair before launching into his tirades.</p>
<p>On Thursday, one of his targets was former disciple Yoshihiro Inoue, who was not in the courtroom at the time.</p>
<p>Inoue, who has given evidence against Asahara, is also on trial for his part in the attack.</p>
<p>&quot;Why must others be arrested for complicity when Inoue was the one who planned everything?&quot; Asahara said.</p>
<p>The remarks led the judges to order court officials to escort Asahara back to his cell.</p>
<p>Inoue, once Asahara's most loyal lieutenant, served as intelligence chief of the Aum Shinri Kyo (Supreme Truth Sect).</p>
<p>Inoue has testified that Asahara ordered the gassing to back up his mystic vision of an Armageddon that would leave the sect in power in Japan.</p>
<p>Asahara, who has refused to enter a plea, is being tried on murder charges for the subway deaths as well as other charges ranging from kidnapping to illegal production of drugs and weapons.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
