<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="345421" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Total and Unocal sign oil contract with Burma.</title>
<headline>Total and Unocal sign oil contract with Burma.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unocal Corp of the U.S. and France's Total SA have signed an oil production sharing contract with Burma's Myanma Oil and Gas Enterprise (MOGE) to explore Block M8 offshore Burma, Unocal said in a statement on Thursday.  </p>
<p>The block covers 11,068 square kilometres (4,275 square miles) and is located in the Andaman Sea. The group plans to shoot 5,000 square km (3,100 square miles) of 2D seismic surveys in the first two-year phase of the contract.</p>
<p>Unocal will hold 47.5 percent of the interest in the block. Total as operator will hold 52.5 percent.</p>
<p>State-owned MOGE has an option to acquire 15 percent of the interest, which if exercised would reduce the other participants interests proportionately, Unocal said.  </p>
<p>Block M8 is southwest of Blocks M5 and M6, which contain the Yadana natural gas field.</p>
<p>The three M8 partners, plus state-owned Petroleum Authority of Thailand Exploration and Production Co, are partners in the US$1.2 billion Yadana field, which is expected to supply 525 million cubic feet per day (mmcfd) of natural gas to the Thai border via a 400-kilometre (250-mile) pipeline.</p>
<p>The Yadana field will also supply 125 mmcfd to the domestic Burma market. First production is scheduled for mid 1998.</p>
<p>Total has signed the M8 contract through its local unit Total Myanmar Exploration and Production Ltd, while Unocal signed the contract through its subsidiary, Unocal Myanmar Offshore Co Ltd, the statement said.  </p>
<p>Multinational companies are facing growing pressure to withdraw from Burmese ventures from human rights groups citing abuses by the military government.</p>
<p>PepsiCo Inc said on Tuesday it had severed the last of its ties with Burma. Last year it sold a 40-percent stake in a Burmese venture because of growing pressure from human rights groups.</p>
<p>Several other companies have taken similar action in the past.</p>
<p>Activists have said they next plan to target major oil companies, including Unocal and Total, which have already come under pressure for their involvement in the Yadana pipeline project. -- Singapore Newsroom (+65 870 3081)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
