<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="345593" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oklahoma bomb witness wrong about second suspect.</title>
<headline>Oklahoma bomb witness wrong about second suspect.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-01-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A witness in the Oklahoma City bombing case who prompted police to search for a suspect they were never able to find, now says he was wrong, prosecutors disclosed on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In a statement filed to the court, prosecutors said the witness &quot;would testify that his description of John Doe No. 2 was in error.&quot;</p>
<p>They asked the U.S. District Court to deny a defence motion to have the witness's testimony thrown out, and said the witness's confusion should only affect the weight of his testimony, not its admissibility.</p>
<p>Authorities originally said they believed John Doe No. 2 accompanied Timothy McVeigh in renting the Ryder truck used to bomb the Alfred P. Murrah federal building in April 1995.</p>
<p>McVeigh and former army buddy Terry Nichols have been charged in the bombing that killed 168 people. The two will be tried separately, with McVeigh's trail starting on March 31. A date has not been set for Nichols' trial.</p>
<p>Tom Kessinger, a mechanic at the rental agency, changed his mind two months ago when he met with prosecutors and two Federal Bureau of Investigation agents, the filing said.</p>
<p>&quot;Kessinger now is confident that he had Todd Bunting in mind when he provided the description for the John Doe No. 2 composite,&quot; prosecutors wrote.</p>
<p>Prosecutors said Kessinger would now testify that a man named Bunting rented a truck the day after McVeigh allegedly did and that Kessinger confused them.</p>
<p>Prosecutors contend McVeigh rented the truck under the alias Robert Kling.</p>
<p>&quot;Kessinger is now unsure whether a second individual accompanied 'Kling' and he has no recall about what any such person might look like,&quot; prosecutors said.</p>
<p>However, Kessinger's new account may not put to rest the possibilty of a John Doe No. 2.</p>
<p>Two other employees at the rental store &quot;continue to believe that two men came in to rent the truck on April 17,&quot; prosecutors said in their filing.</p>
<p>Earlier, the trial judge chose a Federal Aviation Administration building in Oklahoma City, which can seat at least 300 people, as the site for a closed-circuit telecast of the proceedings for victims of the blast because it can accommodate more people than a courtroom.</p>
<p>But U.S. District Court Judge Richard Matsch denied a request from media in Oklahoma City to attend the closed-circuit telecast. The judge said the law did not provide for news organisations to view the telecast, only victims.</p>
<p>A recently enacted law on terrorism provides for such a telecast when a trial has been moved to another city.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
