<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="345544" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel ups defence spending by $91 million.</title>
<headline>Israel ups defence spending by $91 million.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel has allocated an additional 300 million shekels ($91 million) for military spending less than a month after setting its 1997 state budget, an official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The ministerial committee approved an additional 300 million shekels for stockpiles and supplies,&quot; said defence ministry spokesman Avi Benayahu. He said the defence ministry had asked for the additional funds &quot;for the sake of preparedness&quot;.</p>
<p>The extra spending was approved on Wednesday by the ministerial security committee.</p>
<p>Israel's parliament approved the government's 190 billion shekel 1997 budget earlier this month after a battle over seven billion shekels in spending cuts, higher taxes and higher fees.</p>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said the cuts were necessary to rein-in the deficit.</p>
<p>The 30.4 billion shekels allotted for military spending -- 16 percent of the total budget -- was a slight rise over last year's figure.</p>
<p>The Haaretz newspaper said on Thursday defence officials had asked ministers to approve a three billion shekel ($910 million) increase in spending to deal with the threat of war with Syria.</p>
<p>Defence officials could not immediately comment on the Haaretz report.</p>
<p>With peace talks between the two countries stalled for nearly a year, Israeli military officials and analysts have warned Syria could launch an attack on the Jewish state to break the diplomatic deadlock.</p>
<p>Tensions between the arch-foes soared in September when Syria moved thousands of its troops stationed in Lebanon to within striking range of Israeli positions on the Golan Heights.</p>
<p>Damascus said the redeployment was defensive but some Israeli officials saw it as a prelude to war.</p>
<p>Israel and Syria began peace talks in 1991 after fighting several wars but have failed to agree in sporadic negotiations on a formula to solve their dispute.</p>
<p>The United States is trying to revive the talks which Israel's previous government cut off after a wave of Islamist suicide attacks last year.</p>
<p>Syria demands the return of the Golan Heights which Israel captured in the 1967 Middle East war. Netanyahu also wants all of the strategic plateau.</p>
<p>($1 = 3.31 shekels)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
