<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34574" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian financial market splits over regulation.</title>
<headline>Australian financial market splits over regulation.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some of Australia's most powerful financial institutions on Thursday revealed a deep split over plans to overhaul rules governing financial markets, with the central bank resisting radical change.</p>
<p>At a conference called to discuss possible further market deregulation, the Reserve Bank of Australia (RBA) sided with the banking industry against calls by a major life insurance office and the nation's competition watchdog for deep changes.</p>
<p>&quot;In my view the present system is working fairly well,&quot; RBA deputy governor Graeme Thompson told the conference.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a system which has evolved a lot over the past decade and will certainly evolve further,&quot; Thompson added. &quot;I don't think there's anything inherent in the current arrangements that will prevent it evolving.&quot;</p>
<p>In May, the government announced a sweeping inquiry into the financial sector amid claims that existing regulations were outdated in the increasingly global, electronic marketplace.</p>
<p>A similar inquiry in the early 1980s led to radical reform of the sector, including the easing of exchange rate mechanisms and the lifting of controls on bank interest rates. That inquiry paved the way for foreign banks to enter Australia.</p>
<p>Treasurer Peter Costello has said he favours the creation of a &quot;super regulator&quot; to oversee banks, building societies, life insurers, pension funds and other financial institutions.</p>
<p>Australia's second-biggest life insurance office, National Mutual Life (NML), which competes with banks in the funds management industry, on Thursday backed the idea of a super regulator.</p>
<p>&quot;Regulators are structured according to the institutions they regulate rather than the nature of the financial products and services those institutions provide,&quot; NML managing director Tony Killen told the conference.</p>
<p>&quot;As convergence within the industry increasingly blurs the boundaries between financial institutions, this framework becomes less relevant...,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Australian Competition and Consumer Commission (ACCC) anti-trust body also spoke against the existing regulatory system, whereby the RBA supervises banks, another body oversees building societies and two others regulate insurers, pension funds and companies.</p>
<p>&quot;There could be pro-competitive advantages in consolidating some aspects of supervision under one regulator,&quot; ACCC chairman Allan Fels told the conference on Thursday.</p>
<p>But the RBA's Thompson, echoing the banking industry's position, opposed the idea of a &quot;super regulator&quot; and said banks should continue be supervised separately by the RBA.</p>
<p>&quot;If a mega-regulator oversaw capital-backed institutions (banks) and all funds managers, the public could come to perceive that the investment performance of the latter was 'protected' by supervision...,&quot; Thompson said.</p>
<p>By law, the RBA can take control of an ailing bank to prevent its collapse and protect depositors, but it can not take over non-banking institutions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
