<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="345770" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Ivernia West sees progress at Lisheen mine.</title>
<headline>Ivernia West sees progress at Lisheen mine.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ireland's exploration and mining company Ivernia West Plc said on Thursday considerable progress had been made in furthering the development of its Lisheen lead/zinc mine project.</p>
<p>Ivernia West said in a statement that progress had also been made in strengthening the financial resources of the company as a prelude to its major investment in the construction phase of the project.</p>
<p>The Lisheen lead/zinc mine is a joint-venture with South African owned mining-based conglomerate Minorco SA.</p>
<p>&quot;The joint venture infill drilling programme has been completed at Lisheen and the results of the programme are currently being processed,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;Results are expected to confirm the size of the rescource with a substantial increase in the portion of reserves in the proven and probable category,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Earlier, Ivernia said in its half-year results to September 30, 1996, that exploration and development expenditure had risen to 1.82 million Irish pounds from 1.05 million Irish pounds for the same period in the previous year.</p>
<p>It said general and administrative expenses had increased to 0.47 million punts from 0.33 million punts and that transfers to deferred exploration and development expenditure had risen to 2.45 million punts from 1.61 million punts previously.</p>
<p>Ivernia West said exploration activity was about to commence on a number of interesting anomalies on the Rathdowney north and south licence areas in the search for additional mineralization along the Rathdowney Trend.</p>
<p>It said exploration drilling and geophysical surveys carried out last year on the Rio Algom Joint Venture licence areas had resulted in the discovery of several new anomalous areas and these were currently being followed up.</p>
<p>--Dublin newsroom 353-1-661-3377.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
