<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="345905" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: SCA says uncertainty remains for 1997.</title>
<headline>SCA says uncertainty remains for 1997.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish forestry company Svenska Cellulosa Aktiebolaget (SCA) said on Thursday that major uncertainty for pulp and paper price developments remained for 1997.  </p>
<p>&quot;The recovery is taking place from a low level at a slow pace. Major uncertainty remains for price developments surrounding pulp and recycling paper,&quot; SCA said in its results statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Economic growth in Europe is expected to develop positively in 1997 athough the pace of recovery may be slow.&quot;</p>
<p>It said for its hygiene products division, good demand was expected to continue while sales of corrugated board would be lifted by increased industrial production in Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;For newsprint and fine paper, volumes and prices are now stabilising. For the second half of the year there will probably be continued price increases,&quot; SCA said.  </p>
<p>The group posted a profit of 3.57 billion crowns after net financial items for 1996, a 38 percent fall on 1995 results. Net sales eased to 55.41 billion crowns from 65.32 billion.</p>
<p>Consensus forecasts put the profit at 3.52 billion crowns.</p>
<p>A stronger Swedish crown wiped out some of the profit.</p>
<p>&quot;Of the decline, 13 percent was attributable to the effects of the appreciation of the Swedish crown,&quot; SCA said.</p>
<p>SCA said its hygiene products showed continued strong volume growth and a stable margin trend.</p>
<p>Packaging, graphic paper and sawn timber products saw continued weak but stabilising earnings.  </p>
<p>SCA said the business climate for the industry began to stabilise in the second half of 1996 after a period of weakening which began in mid-1995.</p>
<p>&quot;A slowing was noted during the second half of the year when it was thought that the inventory rundown phase was largely complete,&quot; SCA said.</p>
<p>SCA said the number of orders received rose in the second half of 1996 and some limited price increases were possible.</p>
<p>&quot;In the second half of the year...it was possible to increase prices, although to a limited extent, on such products such as pulp, liner and sawn timber, which are normally positioned early in the business cycle,&quot; SCA said.</p>
<p>After several unsuccessful attempts to increase them further, pulp prices stabilised at about $560 per tonne.</p>
<p>-- Abigail Schmelz, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
