<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="346079" id="root" date="1997-01-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Anti-Bhutto verdict clears way for Pakistan polls.</title>
<headline>Anti-Bhutto verdict clears way for Pakistan polls.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Lyon</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Supreme Court's endorsement of Benazir Bhutto's dismissal has cleared the way for Pakistani elections to go ahead, but may tempt the former prime minister to stir up regional feelings, analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact is that four governments of the leaders from one province were not restored, while the one headed by a leader from the other province was,&quot; an aggrieved Bhutto told a news conference after Wednesday's court verdict.</p>
<p>She was referring to previous cases in which the courts failed to reinstate dismissed prime ministers from her home province of Sindh and the 1993 restoration of a government led by Nawaz Sharif, who is from populous Punjab province.</p>
<p>Resentment against the perceived dominance of Punjabis in Pakistan's political and military establishment has long smouldered in smaller provinces, particularly Sindh.</p>
<p>If Sharif wins the election, which political analysts say is a foregone conclusion, Punjabis will occupy all three top jobs -- prime minister, president and chief of army staff.</p>
<p>Analysts said Bhutto, who has already raised the issue, might harp on it in the run-up to Monday's elections.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be difficult for her and her party activists to resist the temptation of exploiting this patently regional issue,&quot; wrote a columnist in the English-language daily The News.</p>
<p>&quot;She has been playing the ethnic card and will keep on playing it,&quot; a European diplomat said.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court's 6-1 decision to throw out Bhutto's plea against her November 5 removal by President Farooq Leghari had been widely expected, but the markets responded with relief.</p>
<p>Share prices had surged 2.06 percent by midday at the Karachi stock exchange. &quot;Uncertainty about the holding of elections has ended and people are bullish on hopes of Nawaz Sharif's victory,&quot; dealer Sajjad Mankani said.</p>
<p>Opinion polls point to a convincing win for Sharif's Pakistan Muslim League party in Monday's national and provincial elections, called by Leghari after he sacked Bhutto's government for alleged corruption and misrule. She denies the charges.</p>
<p>Bhutto has said she expects a crackdown on her Pakistan People's Party after the Supreme Court verdict and attempts by Leghari to rig the vote in at least some constituencies.</p>
<p>&quot;They can't eliminate us politically. They want to eliminate us judicially. Now they will form false murder charges against me and there would be a mass arrest of our workers,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Qazi Hussain Ahmad, leader of the religious Jamaat-i-Islami party, which is boycotting the elections, said the Supreme Court's decision had been orchestrated in advance.</p>
<p>&quot;It was not possible for the Supreme Court to do otherwise,&quot; he told Reuters on Thursday. &quot;This was a political decision.&quot;</p>
<p>Newspaper editorials said even greater efforts were needed to make sure that the election were seen to be above board.</p>
<p>&quot;In many ways, the responsibility of the caretaker government and the president to ensure transparently free and fair polls has now increased,&quot; the English-language Dawn said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
