<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="346348" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Mandela says rival to run S.Africa in his absence.</title>
<headline>Mandela says rival to run S.Africa in his absence.</headline>
<byline>Anton Ferreira</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Nelson Mandela on Friday named his bitter rival Mangosuthu Buthelezi as acting president during his planned absence from South Africa next week.</p>
<p>In what political analysts said was a conciliatory gesture towards the leader of the Zulu-based Inkatha Freedom Party, Mandela said in a speech to the Senate: &quot;I have decided to appoint the Minister of Home Affairs Chief Mangosuthu Buthelezi as acting president of the country.&quot;</p>
<p>The announcement provoked uncertain laughter in the Senate, as if members were not sure whether the 78-year-old statesman was joking.</p>
<p>Mandela will be attending the World Economic Forum in Switzerland for two days from Sunday. Deputy President Thabo Mbeki, who normally acts as president during Mandela's absence, is already in Davos.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a cute move,&quot; commented Constand Viljoen, leader of the opposition Freedom Front.</p>
<p>Buthelezi's IFP is the junior partner of Mandela's ruling African National Congress in the government of national unity but he regularly attacks the ANC. About 15,000 people have been killed in feuding between their supporters.</p>
<p>&quot;Across the length and breadth of South Africa, communities are suffering because of the weakness, indecision and ineffectiveness of the ANC government,&quot; Buthelezi said recently.</p>
<p>Mandela told Reuters he was appointing Buthelezi on merit.</p>
<p>&quot;He is an able and experienced leader of our country. That was the consideration...If it will promote reconciliation we will all be happy. But the reason is that he is a highly competent and experienced leader,&quot; Mandela said.</p>
<p>Inkatha senator Geoffrey Bhengu said his party was surprised but pleased at Mandela's decision.</p>
<p>&quot;He never fails to surprise us. His announcement about Buthelezi was another surprise. On behalf of my party, I welcome it,&quot; Bhengu said.</p>
<p>Political analyst Tom Lodge said the move would please Buthelezi's supporters. &quot;It's a gesture that's at one with the bigness of the man (Mandela). It will go down well in KwaZulu- Natal.&quot;</p>
<p>Mandela's speech marked the final sitting of the Senate, which is being replaced this year by a council aimed at giving South Africa's nine provinces a greater say in legislation.</p>
<p>He also offered an olive branch to the National Party (NP), the biggest opposition party, praising NP Senate President Kobie Coetsee for his role in negotiating an end to apartheid.</p>
<p>Coetsee was NP justice minister in the 1980s when the white minority government began talks with Mandela who was still in jail, serving a life term for treason.</p>
<p>&quot;When the history of our transition comes to be written, the name of Kobie Coetsee will be listed among the miracle workers,&quot; Mandela said.</p>
<p>Mandela has in recent weeks approached two of South Africa's smallest parties, the black radical Pan Africanist Congress and the white liberal Democratic Party, with a view to obtaining their participation in his government.</p>
<p>Buthelezi strongly denied in a South African television interview on Thursday that his party was under severe internal strain because of his autocratic leadership style.</p>
<p>A number of senior members of the IFP have quit in the past few weeks and political analysts are predicting more defections.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
