<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="346591" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: EMU unstoppable, Bundesbank's Welteke says.</title>
<headline>EMU unstoppable, Bundesbank's Welteke says.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Moves to create a common European currency have reached the point of no return, but any delay would hurt the German economy, Bundesbank board member Ernst Welteke told a Moscow news conference on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the point of no return has already been reached, I think we will start this monetary union on January 1, 1999,&quot; said Welteke, who is president of the regional central bank in the German state of Hesse.  </p>
<p>Welteke said this approach would also solve the problem of when Italy, Spain and Portugal would join.</p>
<p>But he made it clear that the convergence of interest rates alone would not be enough to determine EMU membership.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not know what the politicians will decide. I know that Italy wants to become a member of EMU from the beginning... But on the other side Germany fears that they do not have a sound fiscal policy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Any setback to the EMU timetable would hurt the German economy by pushing up the mark, Welteke said.</p>
<p>&quot;We must assume that it would lead to a revaluation of the mark and that would have a negative influence on the export capabilities of the German economy and that at a time when unemployment is already high,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Welteke was in Russia for talks with the Russian Central Bank and State Duma lower house of parliament, and also for talks on cooperation between Hesse and the Russian region of Yaroslavl.</p>
<p>--Janet Guttsman, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
