<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="346642" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: INTERVIEW-Elektra sees expansion in CentAm.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Elektra sees expansion in CentAm.</headline>
<byline>Cecilia Cardenas</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican electronic and white goods retailers Grupo Elektra SA de CV has set aside $25 million to $30 million for opening 30 stores in Central America, a company director told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We are thinking of investing $25-30 million and will be operating at the first half of this year in Guatemala, El Salvador and Honduras, and in Nicaragua, Costa Rica and the Dominican Republic by the end of the year,&quot; Elektra Investor Relations Director Enrique Fernandez told Reuters in an interview.  </p>
<p>Elektra also plans to open 50 new stores under the &quot;Elektra&quot; name in Mexico and another 30 under the &quot;Hecali&quot; name, a chain of clothing stores acquired in October 1996.</p>
<p>The company currently operates 458 &quot;Elektra&quot; stores in 191 cities and 65 &quot;Hecali&quot; stores in 49 cities across Mexico.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect Hecali to consolidate and grow in 1997 ... the clothing market is big in Mexico,&quot; Fernandez said.</p>
<p>Fernandez did not reveal the overall amount Elektra plans to invest for 1997 but said funds also would be chanelled into training and systems.  </p>
<p>The company's expansion in Mexico and Central America would allow the country to consolidate its money transfer business, which began in 1994, Fernandez added.</p>
<p>Fernandez said Elektra's share of the cash-transfers market between the United States and Mexico increased from seven percent in 1994 to 22 to 23 percent by the end of 1996 due to the increased flow of migrant Mexican workers to the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;Our 1997 financing will be in-house, bank credit lines and we are in the process of securitizing our portfolio, of withdrawing our portfolio from the market,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The securitization is subject to approval by Mexican financial authorities and rating by international agencies, Fernandez said.  He estimated the amount of portfolio to be securitized would be 1.4 billion pesos.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we will be ready during the first half of the year, which would be another souce of financing in pesos,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Fernandez said the expansion into Central America was based on the fact that these countries had populations mainly composed of the same low-income groups the firm targets in Mexico.  </p>
<p>He estimated 85 percent to 90 percent of Central Americans were low-income earners, a similar situation to Mexico, where 92 percent of workers earn $6,000 per year or less.</p>
<p>Fernandez saw the group's sales growing 30 percent in 1997. &quot;We expect 1997 to be better than 1996 ... because conditions are appropriate and well founded on the macro front.  The important thing on the micro side is for people to have jobs; then they'll have the possibility and capacity to consume more,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>((--Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9552))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="DOMR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ELSAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
