<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="346692" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: INTERVIEW - Brazil FDI seen at $800 mln in January.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Brazil FDI seen at $800 mln in January.</headline>
<byline>Michael Christie</byline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign direct investment into Brazil has already reached $800 million in January and year-end results will show &quot;significant&quot; growth over 1996, said Altamir Lopes, head of the Central Bank's economics department.</p>
<p>&quot;Up to yesterday (Thursday), foreign investment into Brazil was almost $800 million. And that in January, a holiday month, a weak month, so it's quite positive,&quot; Lopes told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>The Central Bank economist said 1997 inflows should show a significant increase over 1996's $9.44 billion in foreign direct investment, easing concerns about pressures on Brazil's external accounts this year.</p>
<p>Those pressures will be quite heavy, he acknowledged, with an estimated $32 billion in principal and interest payment due on Brazil's public and private sector external debt.</p>
<p>Lopes said that figure, one of the highest external debt-servicing costs ever in Brazilian economic history, was not considered excessive and was certainly not a problem.</p>
<p>&quot;It means the retirement of paper contracted at very poor rates, with much shorter maturities three years ago. Today we have very much better conditions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market allows us to roll this amount over perfectly at much better interest rates and more advantageous maturities. It's positive.&quot;</p>
<p>Brazil posted a 3.27 percent of gross domestic product current account deficit in 1996 and the Central Bank has acknowledged the gap will erode further this year.</p>
<p>Lopes said in the interview that the Central Bank was perfectly aware of increased pressure on the balance of payments but said the extra foreign direct investment should allieve any concerns about financing the current account deficit.</p>
<p>In addition to shortfalls in the services account, especially debt-servicing, economic analysts expect Brazil's trade gap to widen this year to over $8.0 billion after a record deficit of $5.54 billion in 1996.</p>
<p>On Friday it emerged that Brazil was likely to post a surprise monthly trade surplus in January of about $200 million due to problems with a new online import registration system, SISCOMEX. Analysts had been expecting anything from a $500 million to a $1.4 billion deficit for the month.</p>
<p>Lopes said it was clear that a January surplus could only be attributed to start-up problems with SISCOMEX but noted that exports of $3.13 billion up to January 28 were strong for the month. Total exports in January 1996 stood at $3.473 billion.</p>
<p>From the Central Bank's point of view, Brazil's trade account is not showing any alarm signals.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand for imports will start growing at a much lower rate after a while but will settle at a higher level,&quot; Lopes said.</p>
<p>As for exports, Lopes echoed government optimism that tax-exemption, the revival of an export insurance agency and special credit lines would give them a considerable boost.</p>
<p>He added that capital goods imports by Brazilian industry over the past two to three years should start helping sales. &quot;I think...manufactureds this year should have quite a reasonable impact (on export levels) because of the process of industrial modernization that has been taking place,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>((Brasilia newsroom 55-61-2230358))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
