<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34685" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia confirms Taiwan minister's visit.</title>
<headline>Indonesia confirms Taiwan minister's visit.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian Foreign Minister Ali Alatas confirmed that he had met his Taiwanese counterpart John Chang in Jakarta on Wednesday but stressed he had done so in an individual capacity.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to explain that Mr John Chang came to Indonesia yesterday on a private visit and in his private capacity,&quot; Alatas told reporters on Thursday. &quot;He was not invited.</p>
<p>&quot;During his visit he asked to meet me and I said it could be done as long as it was in a private capacity.</p>
<p>&quot;So I was not meeting him as a foreign minister. There is no Taiwan foreign minister in the Indonesian dictionary. I received him not as foreign minister but as Ali Alatas.&quot;</p>
<p>Indonesia and Taiwan do not have diplomatic links and Alatas did not give details about his talks. He also did not comment on whether Chang had met President Suharto and Research and Technology Minister Jusuf Habibie.</p>
<p>Foreign ministry sources said on Wednesday that Chang had held talks with Habibie and was scheduled to call on Suharto.</p>
<p>Alatas added that Indonesia is consistent in its policy of recognising only mainland China.</p>
<p>Beijing views Taiwan as a renegade province and routinely attacks the island's attempts to raise its international profile. A civil war separated China and Taiwan in 1949.</p>
<p>Chang's unannounced trip to Indonesia followed Vice President Lien Chan's secret visit to the Ukraine in late August.</p>
<p>Beijing protested against that trip and cancelled a visit by a Chinese delegation to Kiev after Lien, who doubles as premier, went there to promote unofficial ties.</p>
<p>Beijing accused the former Soviet republic of violating the &quot;one China&quot; commitment that it made in establishing ties with Beijing.</p>
<p>Only 30 countries, mostly in Africa and central America, recognise Taiwan's exiled Republic of China government.</p>
<p>Taiwan, maintaining that its 21 million people have a right to a voice in the United Nations and other forums, has pushed to win new foreign friends and raise its international profile.</p>
<p>Taiwanese President Lee Teng-hui made an unofficial visit to Jakarta in February 1994. China, which has diplomatic relations with Indonesia, was enraged by the visit and protested to Jakarta.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
