<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="346918" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY precious metals end lower for 4th day.</title>
<headline>NY precious metals end lower for 4th day.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York precious metals futures end lower for the fourth straight day Friday, with gold and platinum sliding to new three year lows, though volumes were not as heavy as Thursday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sentiment in precious metals is extremely poor, though volumes were not that heavy today,&quot; FIMAT New York trader John Tyree said.</p>
<p>&quot;Both the funds and bullion banks were selling today, with talk of European central bank sales still around,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>COMEX April gold ended down $1.50 an ounce at $346.00, after posting a new contract low at $345.40.  </p>
<p>Estimated total gold futures volume was 40,000 lots, down from Thursday's official volume of 79,505 contracts.</p>
<p>In the bullion market, spot gold ended quoted $344.10/60, after fixing at a $345.50 in London Friday afternoon, just up from a new three and a quarter year low at $345.00 at the London morning fix. Spot gold closed in New York Thursday quoted $345.35/85.</p>
<p>Short term implied lease rates remained high Friday morning in the bullion market, after jumping Thursday, suggesting more speculative shorting was occurring in the bullion market, analysts said.  </p>
<p>One month lease rates were around 2.06 percent, while three month rates were around 1.99 pct.</p>
<p>On Thursday gold fell sharply on renewed talk of European central bank sales and fears that the US government's successful new issue of inflation-indexed bonds removed the need for gold as inflation hedge for US investors.</p>
<p>As a result follow through selling was seen in Asia and Europe early Friday, as long liquidated positions entered recently in the belief gold may have been bottoming out around $350 after its year long slide, traders said.</p>
<p>German bank, Dresdner Kleinwort Benson, also issued a report early Friday, saying gold was set for further tests of the downside.</p>
<p>On the New York open Friday, gold initially steadied though on news suggesting Russian state stocks of gold are nearly exhausted.</p>
<p>But the report was based on an Audit Chamber report completed in September 1996, and on December 17 the Russian central bank said it had bought about 100 tonnes of gold in 1996, boosting its reserves to around 400 tonnes.</p>
<p>Further selling was seen during the New York session Friday, after Thursday's COMEX open interest data, released Friday morning, showed gold open interest had begun rising again, after several days of sharp falls.</p>
<p>Thursday's convincing breach of $350 level in spot gold had reactivated the short sellers, traders said.</p>
<p>COMEX gold open interest jumped 7,875 lots Thursday to 196,350 lots, after declining in the past ten days from 205,471 contracts.</p>
<p>Open interest in the now-active April contract jumped 16,940 lots, while open interest in February gold fell a further 10,139 lots. Friday was first notice day for the February contract's delivery period.</p>
<p>Central bank selling may well be occurring again, but the rise in open interest and in short term lease rates, suggests the funds are taking advantage of it to drive the market lower, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Could the combined weight of producer hedging, central-bank selling, official hostility and public indifference push the gold price to decisive new lows? Of course,&quot; said James Grant, editor of Grant's Interest Rate Observer.</p>
<p>&quot;The benefit of the doubt in a bear market always goes to the downside.&quot;</p>
<p>COMEX March silver, which jumped near the close Thursday, fell back to a low $4.810 intraday Friday, before ending down 3.5 cents at $4.970.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that Thursday's jump in silver was not sustained made a lot people disappointed,&quot; FIMAT's Tyree said.</p>
<p>NYMEX April platinum closed down $2.90 at $353.00 an ounce, after seeing a new contract low at $351.00.</p>
<p>Earlier spot platinum had fixed in London Friday at a new three and three-quarter year low at $350.25.</p>
<p>But NYMEX March palladium closed up $3.00 at $126.65, on good refiner buying and some stop order execution, traders said.</p>
<p>Earlier fears about supply problems, caused by the delay in Russian/Japanese contract talks, had pushed up palladium prices since late 1996, traders noted.</p>
<p>-Clive McKeef, New York Commodities Desk, +1-212-859-1641; -email: clive.mckeef@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
