<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="347048" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Commerce official sees momentum in Q4 GDP data.</title>
<headline>US Commerce official sees momentum in Q4 GDP data.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior U.S. Commerce Department official on Friday said he saw momentum in this morning's report on fourth-quarter gross domestic product.</p>
<p>During an interview with Reuters Financial Television, U.S. Commerce Undersecretary Everett Ehrlich said the data showed the economy growing &quot;substantially&quot; in the last three months of 1996, &quot;but I also think there's reason to see momentum for 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>The Commerce Department earlier reported that U.S. GDP grew by 4.7 percent in the fourth quarter, a sharp pickup from the 2.1 percent pace of the third quarter.  </p>
<p>He cited his expectation for continued strong consumer spending as one reason he believed the economy would maintain its momentum in the first half of this year.</p>
<p>Asked whether one-time occurrences were at play in producing the surprisingly strong growth, Ehrlich said those were not a big factor.</p>
<p>&quot;There's very little in the data that has to do with special factors,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The most conspicuous special factor was the late harvest, which meant farm inventories were accumulated later in the year than normal.  </p>
<p>The fourth-quarter GDP figure reported on Friday was the department's initial, or &quot;advance,&quot; estimate of growth, which will be revised when reports, such as the trade and inventory data for December, become available.</p>
<p>Asked whether those would cause a downward revision to GDP, Ehrlich said that was unlikely as his department made conservative assumptions about the two items.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we're going to see a downward revision surprise when we get export and inventory data for the month of December,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On the subject of whether the strength of the dollar will dampen exports, thus exerting a restraining influence on growth, the Commerce official played down the potential for that.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course, a rising dollar at some point is going to have some feedback for U.S. exports but the underlying competitiveness of U.S. production is so sound (and) investment has been so strong,&quot; Ehrlich said.</p>
<p>He also pointed to some positive effects of the strong dollar on the economy: &quot;It helps contain inflation and it helps keep interest rates down in the final analysis and that's good throughout the economy.&quot;</p>
<p>Regarding inflation, Ehrlich was upbeat, predicting more good price behavior in future quarters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
