<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="347194" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Coca-Cola profits rose 18 percent in quarter.</title>
<headline>Coca-Cola profits rose 18 percent in quarter.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coca-Cola Co. said Friday profits rose 18 percent in the fourth quarter, in line with expectations on Wall Street, and set a record for the full year as sales of its soft drinks posted solid growth worldwide.</p>
<p>&quot;1996 was another record year for the Coca-Cola Co., with strong earnings, unit volume and market share gains, once again meeting every one of our long-term objectives,&quot; said Roberto Goizueta, chairman and chief executive.</p>
<p>Profits rose to $762 million in the quarter from $648 million in the 1995 quarter. Earnings per share rose to 31 cents from 26 cents, matching analysts' forecasts. Revenues grew 2.5 percent to $4.44 billion from $4.33 billion.</p>
<p>For all of 1996, profits rose 17 percent to $3.49 billion, or $1.40 a share, from $2.99 billion, or $1.18 a share, in 1995. Revenues rose to $18.55 billion from $18.02 billion.</p>
<p>Coca-Cola said it sold more than 13.7 billion cases of soft drinks in 1996, more than 1 billion cases over 1995, a rise of about 8 percent.</p>
<p>Strong increases in Coca-Cola classic and Sprite, supported by growth of products such as Barq's, Powerade and Nestea contributed to the volume gains, the company said. In 1996, Sprite was again the fastest growing major soft drink brand in the United States.</p>
<p>At the Minute Maid Co., 1996 unit volume increased 9 percent due to marketing initiatives, including new advertising in support of Minute Maid Premium orange juice.</p>
<p>In Europe, unit case volume rose 8 percent, and gallon shipments grew 9 percent in 1996, boosting operating income by 2 percent. Fourth-quarter unit case volume grew 13 percent and gallon shipments rose 12 percent.</p>
<p>In Latin America, unit case volume rose 9 percent and gallon shipments grew 11 percent for the year, resulting in a 2 percent rise in the regional group's operating income.</p>
<p>In the Middle and Far East, unit case volume rose 11 percent and gallon shipments advanced 7 percent in 1996, but operating income fell 3 percent. China was one of the company's fastest-growing markets, with case volume up 40 percent there in the quarter.</p>
<p>In Africa, full-year unit case volume rose 5 percent but operating income fell 42 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>Coca-Cola stock rose 62.5 cents to $58 in late morning composite trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
