<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="347254" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S MUNICIPAL FOCUS - prices end up 1/2 to 3/4.</title>
<headline>U.S MUNICIPAL FOCUS - prices end up 1/2 to 3/4.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Municipal bonds ended 1/2 to 3/4 of a point higher Friday, lagging the more than full point gain 30-year U.S. Treasury bonds derived from morning economic news.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a slight lag,&quot; one trader said, comparing muni's gains to Treasuries. &quot;There was a New York bid list that was around, nothing too major. Otherwise, it's really quiet. Good tone, not many bonds.&quot;</p>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's Blue List of dealer inventory stood at $1.282 billion Friday, down from $1.363 billion on Thursday.</p>
<p>A municipal analyst said while the broader municipal market was up 1/2 to 3/4 of a point, dollar bonds were up 5/8 of a point-plus.</p>
<p>High-grade issues were up five basis overall, and more in spots. Secondary market activity was brisk in the morning and light to moderate in the afternoon, he said.</p>
<p>Friday's active issues included Florida State Board of Education 5-1/2 percent bonds of June 2026. The bonds had a 5.77 percent net bid, seven basis points firmer than Thursday's net bid of 5.84 percent.</p>
<p>In debt futures, the March municipal contract closed up 28/32 at 115-8/32. The March T-bond contract closed up 28/32 at 111-14/32. The MOB spread was 122 ticks.</p>
<p>In government cash, the benchmark 30-year bond closed up 1-1/32 at 96-11/32 to yield 6.79 percent.</p>
<p>The bond market got an early lift following the release of gross domestic product data for the final quarter of 1996. While the headline number was strong, rising 4.7 percent, players took heart from the implicit price deflator, a closely watched inflation gauge, which firmed only 1.4 percent, according to the Commerce Department.</p>
<p>Also Friday, the Purchasing Management Association of Chicago reported that the Chicagoland Business Barometer fell to a seasonally adjusted 55.9 in January from a revised 57.1 in December.</p>
<p>Turning to new issues, next week's competitive and negotiated sales are expected to total $1.56 billion in 66 offerings, according to Reuters Municipal Bond Information Group.</p>
<p>Competitive sales are expected total $275 million in 42 sales. The largest is a $30 million Fresno Unified School District, Calif., offering on February 6.</p>
<p>Negotiated sales are expected to total $1.29 billion in 24 offerings. The largest is a $459 million Anaheim, Calif., revenue bond offering through PaineWebber Inc.</p>
<p>Day to day muni bond sales total $750 million in 15 offerings for the week of February 3, which means dealers may bring the offerings to market if conditions warrant.</p>
<p>Among those offerings are a $150 million Platte River Power Authority issue through Smith Barney Inc and a $100 million Tacoma, Wash., refunding issue through Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.</p>
<p>--Kathie O'Donnell, 212-859-1655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
