<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34727" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK activists protest over Japan's claim to isles.</title>
<headline>HK activists protest over Japan's claim to isles.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of Hong Kong activists marched to the Japanese consulate on Thursday and presented a petition in protest of Japan's  claim to a group of islands in the East China Sea.</p>
<p>About 30 ethnic Chinese were protesting Tokyo's claim to the Diaoyu islands. The island chain, known as the Senkakus in Japan, is about 300 km (190 miles) west of Okinawa and is claimed by Japan, Taiwan and China.</p>
<p>A row broke out between China and Japan in July when the Japanese built a lighthouse on one of the islands.</p>
<p>Hideaki Ueda, Consul General of Japan in Hong Kong, said on Thursday that Japan's navy would prevent anyone from landing on the islands without Japan's permission.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they will take necessary measures,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>He also said the Diaoyu issue was trivial, and urged the media not to get over-excited.</p>
<p>&quot;I sincerely hope that the concerned people do not make this issue an artificially big issue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But China's Foreign Ministry spokesman, Shen Guofang, told a news conference in Beijing that the islands row was a not small issue.</p>
<p>&quot;The Diaoyu islands issue is, of course, not trivial. It involves the entirety of the Chinese sovereignty and territory,&quot; Shen said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Hong Kong legislator Tsang Kin-shing said about 20 people would sail to the islands at the beginning of next month to dismantle the lighthouse.</p>
<p>Hong Kong, with a population mostly of ethnic Chinese, reverts from British rule to Chinese sovereignty in mid-1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
