<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="347398" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France's Juppe cautious on jobless rate fall.</title>
<headline>France's Juppe cautious on jobless rate fall.</headline>
<byline>David Clarke</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The number of French people out of work fell by an unexpectedly large 29,000 in December, offering the centre-right government a new glimmer of hope that economic recovery could be on the way.</p>
<p>But the overall unemployment rate stuck stubbornly at a record 12.7 percent and Prime Minister Alain Juppe said it was too early to judge the figures as a firm trend.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a good figure, but I think it is far too early to proclaim victory,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Economists said more hard evidence would be needed to generate optimism about an impending recovery.</p>
<p>The French labour ministry said the number of jobless fell 0.9 percent to 3,092,500 last month, that the number of young people out of work fell a significant 2.1 percent and those unemployed for more than a year also dropped slightly.</p>
<p>This will be welcome news for the government at a time when it is facing a resurgence of labour unrest and a mood of gloom which President Jacques Chirac blames in part for the economy's failure to take off.</p>
<p>The figures come a day after a survey by the national statistics institute INSEE reported a marked rise in business confidence, which economists read as encouraging, even if it is a measure of sentiment rather than hard proof of any pick-up in activity.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very good news for politicians and should be good news for the markets with all the social tension,&quot; Patrick Mange, an economist with Deutsche Bank in Paris said. &quot;Everybody was expecting 15,000 to 20,000 more. Unemployment in France is still too high, but nevertheless this is a good thing.</p>
<p>Philippe Brossard, Paris economist for Dutch bank ABN-Amro, said the drop was &quot;amazing, even judging by the old method of calculation&quot; and that longer term forecasts of unemployment rising to 13 percent were now questionable.</p>
<p>&quot;We're almost at a peak now. We should see numbers falling regularly from around April, perhaps not every month, but in the overall trend,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a better basis for the start of the year (for the economy). But we'll probably have to wait until the end of the second quarter to measure properly. The debate will continue for some time.</p>
<p>Mange said, however, that one set of good figures should not be treated over-enthusiastically.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm extremely cautious with the unemployment figures in December as there could be short-term effects generated by the Christmas sales. We need a confirmation in further figures to see if there's a new tendency.</p>
<p>The number of people out of work of 12 months or more fell 0.2 percent, after a rise of 2.2 percent the month before, but is still at a high 1.08 million. The number of jobless people aged 25 is close to 610,000 but fell for both men and women.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
