<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34746" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Regent presses Pioneer on share rating.</title>
<headline>Regent presses Pioneer on share rating.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Regent Fund Management Ltd's bid to shake up Pioneer Industries International (Holdings) Ltd may come to a head at a special general meeting on Tuesday, when Pioneer's management will be asked to take action to improve its share performance.</p>
<p>Regent, the Regent Pacific Group unit known as an unusually aggressive investor, said Pioneer is trading at a 59-percent discount to net asset value and drastic steps must be taken to improve share performance.</p>
<p>Those steps could include selling its prime asset, a sizeable stake in Bangkok Bank Ltd, Thailand's biggest bank.</p>
<p>&quot;We're basically asking the company to do a better job of managing the company,&quot; Regent chairman Peter Everington told reporters on Thursday.</p>
<p>The fund acquired 13.64 percent of Pioneer last November.</p>
<p>Regent estimates Pioneer's net asset value at HK$12.46 per share after tax. Pioneer shares closed at HK$5.90 on Thursday, valuing the company at HK$1.81 billion.</p>
<p>Pioneer's 3.77-percent stake in Bangkok Bank is valued at HK$2.4 billion at current market price.</p>
<p>Regent also claimed Pioneer's stake in Bangkok Bank is actually much greater than the company has admitted due to another 6.5 million foreign shares held through a 49-percent stake in a Liberian company called Central Asia Ltd.</p>
<p>This increases Pioneer's stake in Bangkok Bank to 4.4 percent, including the Central Asia holding.</p>
<p>&quot;They are not informing shareholders of what is there,&quot; Everington said.</p>
<p>Pioneer officials were not available to respond to Regent's charges. Media reports indicate that Pioneer has repeatedly stated in public that its holding in Bangkok Bank is &quot;slightly less than five percent.&quot;</p>
<p>Pioneer has also said publicly that it considers Regent's move as hostile, and it intends to send a letter to shareholders urging them to vote against the resolutions.</p>
<p>Regent wants to see some action on Tuesday at a Pioneer special general meeting, otherwise it will introduce another 13 directors to Pioneer's 11-member board of directors.</p>
<p>&quot;We are only doing so because we anticipate the company is reluctant to take action,&quot; said Everington. &quot;We have no desire to run Pioneer. We have no desire to take it over. What we are trying to do is persuade management to run the company better.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843-6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
