<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="347581" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GM settles Florida liability case.</title>
<headline>GM settles Florida liability case.</headline>
<byline>June Bell</byline>
<dateline>JACKSONVILLE, Fla.</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Motors Corp. settled a product liability case with a Florida woman who suffered severe brain damage in a 1991 collision, the presiding judge in the case said Friday.</p>
<p>Circuit Judge Lawrence Fay said lawyers in the case had negotiated a settlement that would include both the $25 million in compensatory damages already ordered by a jury, plus punitive damages that were pending before the jury.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a done deal; it's a confidential settlement,&quot; the judge said in an impromptu interview outside the jury's presence.</p>
<p>The judge said jurors were being telephoned and informed of the settlement. Earlier Friday afternoon, Judge Fay released the six-member panel for the weekend and had instructed them to return Tuesday morning to hear closing arguments in the punitive damages phase of the case.</p>
<p>The family of Therese Hunter asked that GM be punished by having to pay up to $75 million.</p>
<p>A lawyer representing the family of Hunter, who was injured in the 1991 accident, said the settlement was in the best interests of his client.</p>
<p>&quot;She will finally begin to get her needs' met, and her father is truly a fighter,&quot; said attorney Lance Lock. He said terms of the settlement were to remain secret.</p>
<p>On Dec. 20, the jury awarded $25.4 million to the family of Hunter, 45, a former Jacksonville resident who now lives in a Miami assisted-living centre. The compensatory damage award exceeded the $15 million to $21.5 million requested by Hunter's attorneys for her medical care.</p>
<p>On March 3, 1991, the 1990 Chevrolet Astro van Hunter was driving was hit by a truck and pushed into a concrete light pole. The impact dislodged the van's steering column and rammed it into her jaw and skull. The jury found that General Motors, which made Hunter's van, was responsible for her crippling injuries.</p>
<p>In the punitive damage phase of the case, which began Wednesday, jurors heard from a Yale economist who testified that a $75 million penalty would have a &quot;negligible&quot; financial impact on the company.</p>
<p>But General Motors presented witnesses who testified that the company's U.S. operations were not profitable between 1985 and 1995, and reported a cumulative loss of $8.7 billion.</p>
<p>Settlement negotiations in the case began on Friday at the request of GM, according to lawyers for Hunter.</p>
<p>GM lawyers were not available for comment.</p>
<p>The decision to settle the case was made by Hunter's father, Jesus Carmona, a 78-year-old Miami dentist. Carmona said it was &quot;prudent&quot; to settle before the jury made its decision, adding that the settlement would be deposited in a special account to cover the costs of his daughter's medical care for the rest of her life.</p>
<p>Hunter was unable to testify in the case. She was injured while driving her two sons, now ages 16 and 18, to a swimming competition in northern Florida. Her husband divorced her after the accident, and her father was appointed her legal guardian.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JACKSONVILLE, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
