<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="347770" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Northwest Airlines bans disruptive passenger.</title>
<headline>Northwest Airlines bans disruptive passenger.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Northwest Airlines said Thursday it had banned a man from flying on any of its aircraft after he punched a pilot earlier this month.</p>
<p>The man, from New York state, attacked a Northwest pilot without provocation in Detroit Metropolitan Airport on Jan. 6, the airline said, without naming him.</p>
<p>It said it had sent him a letter saying he would be banned &quot;from boarding any future flight operated by our airline; furthermore, we will advise other airlines with which we maintain cooperative agreements of our decision and the background that led to it.&quot;</p>
<p>Published reports at the time quoted the FBI as saying a 28-year-old man from Geneseo, New York, became angry when the pilot would not take his ticket and told him to wait for a gate agent. The man came around a counter and punched the pilot.</p>
<p>The pilot suffered a black eye, the accounts said, and flight 1173 to White Plains, New York, was delayed for nearly two hours.</p>
<p>Northwest spokesman John Austin said the ban was the first by Northwest &quot;at least in modern, contemporary times,&quot; but other airlines had taken similar action.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
