<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="347862" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEPAL: Enron in talks to build Nepal power plants.</title>
<headline>Enron in talks to build Nepal power plants.</headline>
<byline>Gopal Sharma</byline>
<dateline>KATHMANDU 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States-based Enron Renewable Energy Corp, a unit of Enron Corp, was in talks with Nepal to develop two hydroelectric plants and export power to India and China, officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>They said the Houston-based firm wanted to develop the Karnali river hydroelectric project in western Nepal, and the $1.0 billion Arun III project on the Arun river in the east.</p>
<p>The World Bank backed out of a plan to fund Arun III in 1995 following its doubts that the project could be managed efficiently. The dam project had faced opposition from environmentalists who said it would threaten wildlife.</p>
<p>&quot;We have an interest in the possibility of developing (these projects) on a private sector basis,&quot; Robert C. Kelly, Enron Renewable's chief executive officer, told Reuters in Kathmandu.</p>
<p>Kelly, in Nepal to explain the company's plan which was submitted in September last year, briefed government ministers about the scheme on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a very preliminary meeting to discuss the concept of developing projects like Arun III and Karnali,&quot; Kelly said.</p>
<p>Plans on Arun III were given up after the World Bank stopped an intended $175 million support for the first phase of the project scheduled to produce 201 megawatts of power.</p>
<p>Nepali officials said India's Tata group had also shown an interest in Arun III.</p>
<p>The other planned project on Karnali is estimated to have a potential to generate 10,800 megawatts of electricity.</p>
<p>&quot;His Majesty's Government is doing the home work for starting a competitive negotiation process for the Karnali mega project,&quot; said Dwarika Nath Dhungel, the highest ranking civil servant in the Water Resources Ministry.</p>
<p>&quot;We will issue a public notice inviting bidders for competitive negotiations before deciding on any party,&quot; Dhungel tod Reuters earlier this week.</p>
<p>Rivers originating in the snow-covered mountains of the Himalayan kingdom are estimated to have a potential to produce 83,000 megawatts of electricity, which the impoverished nation sees as a possible passport to prosperity.</p>
<p>Nepal, which ushered in multi-party democracy under a constitutional monarch in 1990, has invited foreign investors to tap the potential under an economic liberalisation programme.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NEPAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1610107">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KATHMANDU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEPAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
