<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="347843" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Elektrim's convertible bond approved.</title>
<headline>Elektrim's convertible bond approved.</headline>
<byline>Malgorzata Rzepka</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shareholders of Polish trading and industrial firm Elektrim SA approved on Friday a 550 million zloty ($183.3 million) convertible bond issue, which will be managed by Merrill Lynch International and Poland's Bank Pekao SA.</p>
<p>Elektrim deputy president and chief financial officer Piotr Mroczkowski told a news briefing after shareholders' meeting the funds from the seven-year-bond issue would help pay off bank loans and finance investments in the energy sector.</p>
<p>&quot;The main goal (of the issue) is to shift from bank loans into other sources of financing...and to finance our planned activities in energy sector,&quot; Mroczkowski said.</p>
<p>He said Elektrim's bank loans amounted to $120 million.</p>
<p>Elektrim's shareholders also approved an issue of up to 19 million new shares ex-rights to be exchanged for the bonds.</p>
<p>Mroczkowski said Elektrim's management would later decide details of the bond.</p>
<p>The offer will be Poland's biggest convertible bond issue to date.</p>
<p>He said Elektrim wanted to attract investors, both domestic and foreign, who would seek to exchange the bonds and acquire a stake in the company rather than redeem the papers at maturity.</p>
<p>&quot;We have three currencies to choose from: the zloty, the dollar and the Deutschmark, dollar surely not because it's firming now, for now it would be either zloty or mark,&quot; Mroczkowski said.</p>
<p>He said Elektrim planned to list the bonds on the Luxembourg exchange and the new shares on the Warsaw bourse.</p>
<p>The new shares' issue price will initially be equal to that on the listed shares plus a premium of no more than 15 percent.</p>
<p>He said Elektrim wanted to place the bonds by the end of May before expected big-ticket privatisations hit the markets.</p>
<p>The company's president Andrzej Skowronski, also present, said Elektrim wanted to start preparing for privatisations in Poland's energy sector before any tenders are announced so it wins a headstart on competition.</p>
<p>He added Elektrim also wanted to participate in the expansion and restructuring of Poland's power plants.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700 ($ = 3 Polish Zloty)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
