<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="347955" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BZW upgrades Abbey on potential ScotAm deal.</title>
<headline>BZW upgrades Abbey on potential ScotAm deal.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>BZW has upgraded its recommendation on Abbey National Plc to buy from hold based on the potential from its proposed takeover of mutual life assurer Scottish Amicable, banking analyst Hugh Pye told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Pye said that despite the fact that Scottish Amicable has rejected Abbey's proposal he believes there is a reasonable chance that it will go ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a fundamentally good way of deploying surplus capital in a very positive way,&quot; Pye said. &quot;It helps to gear up the business by improving the proportion of high quality earnings.&quot;</p>
<p>Pye said that a secondary but also positive factor was that the Scottish Amicable business would be an excellent fit with Abbey's current Scottish Mutual business which it bought in 1992.  </p>
<p>He said that Scottish Mutual's business had improved considerably since then with independent financial advisers (IFAs) much happier to recommend its products since it had the backing of the Abbey.</p>
<p>&quot;Historical performance isn't as important as the improvement in the future and there is a precedent with what they have done with Scottish Mutual,&quot; Pye said.</p>
<p>He added that Abbey's tier one capital ratio would likely fall to 8.0 percent from 8.5 percent. &quot;That would bring to about the right sort of level in terms of return on equity.&quot; -- Joe Ortiz, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8864</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
