<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="348103" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - New York Times front page - Jan 31.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New York Times front page - Jan 31.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Times reported the following stories on its front page Friday:</p>
<p>-- The National Governors' Association has decided to oppose President Clinton's plan to set firm limits on federal Medicaid spending, arguing that the plan would put a heavier burden on the states for providing the poor with health care.</p>
<p>-- Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan urged Congress to limit cost-of-living increases for Social Security and other Federal benefits and revived his call for the creation of an independent commission to set more accurate increases for inflation.</p>
<p>-- New York Mayor Rudolph Giuliani's preliminary budget calls for spending $500 million to ease overcrowding in public schools and $550 million in spending cuts at city agencies, including a $155 million reduction for the municipal hospital agency.</p>
<p>-- Justice Department investigators have uncovered numerous complaints by employees at the Federal Bureau of Investigation's crime laboratory about the way their superiors handled evidence in the Oklahoma City bombing.</p>
<p>-- A plan to rescue the savings and loan industry and proposed banking legislation were among the topics discussed in a coffee meeting last May between bank industry officials, Clinton and the country's top bank regulator.</p>
<p>-- An assistant commissioner at the Internal Revenue Service acknowledged that his agency spent $4 billion on its computer systems but that the systems do not function well.</p>
<p>-- India's citizens scatter some of the ashes of Mohandas Gandhi to commemorate the January 30, 1948, assassination of one of the founding fathers of Indian independance.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
