<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="348249" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU hearing on BA/AMR deal to sift competing views.</title>
<headline>EU hearing on BA/AMR deal to sift competing views.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Chalmers</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Commission officials will stage a hearing into British Airways's planned alliance with American Airlines next week, allowing both the parties and their competitors to state their cases for and against the deal.</p>
<p>The hearing, beginning on Monday and extended into Tuesday because of the numbers wanting to speak, is intended to give Commission competition officials the necessary detail to rule on what changes are needed before the deal can be cleared.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a number of issues which we are looking at which should be clearer after the event,&quot; one Commission official told Reuters on Friday.</p>
<p>Headline news in recent weeks has been the question of how many take-off and landing slots the airlines should surrender at London Heathrow in order to win approval.</p>
<p>A report by Britain's Office of Fair Trading (OFT) gave the deal provisional approval provided that British Airways and American gave up 168 slots at the busy airport.</p>
<p>Competitors want more slots to be given up, with their demands ranging upwards of 400 weekly slots to 500 or 600.</p>
<p>The European Commission has disputed both the number of slots the OFT wants surrendered, which slots should be given up and the idea that slots can be sold.</p>
<p>Cross-Channel differences in approach broke into the open earlier this month, with European Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert threatening legal action if the OFT plan went ahead while London disputed the EU executive's powers to intervene.</p>
<p>Van Miert told a news conference that Commission concerns about the alliance went further than just slots but gave no detail on what conditions he might impose.</p>
<p>The official said conditions could include forcing the two airlines to open access to their frequent flyer programmes, which reward regular customers with air miles towards free tickets, to competing airlines.</p>
<p>The intention would be to allow smaller airlines flying routes served by the BA/American alliance to buy into the frequent flyer schemes, on a non-discriminatory basis, so as to offset the effects of such a geographically appealing perk draining their custom away to the transatlantic partnership.</p>
<p>Such a condition would be less important for competing, multi-airline alliances with their own loyalty programmes.</p>
<p>A second one relates to the increasing use by airlines of code-sharing deals with their partners, the official said.</p>
<p>Such arrangements provide customers with apparently seamless itineraries, on one flight code, for routes which in reality involve connecting flights on different airlines. Code-sharing partners get significant marketing advantages over competitors.</p>
<p>In return for allowing code-sharing, the Commission would force alliance airlines to accept &quot;inter-lining&quot; across the North Atlantic. This would allow competitors to offer point-to-point services on routes which might otherwise be swamped by the strength of an alliance monopoly on the route.</p>
<p>Obligatory &quot;inter-lining&quot; agreements would mean customers from non-alliance airlines, usually with fewer weekly services, could use their tickets on alliance flights on the same route and vice versa.</p>
<p>While next week's hearing, from which the media are barred, will concentrate on BA/American, conditions agreed for one will set a precedent for all the others, the official said.</p>
<p>A Commission investigation announced last July took in transatlantic alliances including one linking Delta Air Lines with Belgium's Sabena, Swissair and Austrian Airlines, another between United Airlines, Germany's Lufthansa and Scandinavian Airlines System, and another between KLM and Northwest Airlines.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a bit of a pity that BA/AA has been pushed so that it comes up for a decision before the others. We will have to be very careful to see that what's being decided for BA/AA is applied to them,&quot; the official said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
