<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="348362" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU faces Mideast sugar export challenge.</title>
<headline>EU faces Mideast sugar export challenge.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union's high quality white sugar export market is being challenged by new refineries in the middle east, the head of the European Commission's sugar division, Ejner Stendevad, told Reuters on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have exported a lot of white sugar to this area in the past and it is clear that there will be considerable competition from these new refineries in the future,&quot; he said, reacting to comments by sugar traders.</p>
<p>The world sugar market is already weak but the impact of surplus supplies has been delayed because large amounts were kept in stores in India last year, said a visiting trader.</p>
<p>&quot;The weakness on the world market has been delayed by about 18 months because India is sensitive to shortages and withheld large amounts of  surplus supplies last year,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>The European Union is estimating record beet sugar production figure in 1996/97.</p>
<p>Details of the latest EU sugar balance sheet have been suppressed.</p>
<p>The Commission will discuss what they call &quot;inconsistencies&quot; in the latest production and consumption statistics with the sugar trade advisory group on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been a considerable number of over-estimates and we want to get the views of the industry before presenting a balance sheet to next Wednesday's sugar management committee,&quot; an official said.</p>
<p>But, the Commission says it's is also clear that despite a poor start to the beet growing season weather conditions in the autumn have reversed expectations of poor production.</p>
<p>EU exporters are already facing competition from Brazil which produces large grain 'yellow' sugar which is not of EU quality but is acceptable in Pakistan and Africa.</p>
<p>But, a new refinery already on stream in Dubai and a second close to production in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia  will present a major challenge to the EU, the trader said.</p>
<p>The new refineries will take in Australian raws and will turn out high quality white sugar aimed at traditional EU customers, the trader added.</p>
<p>In 1995/96 the EU export target was three million tonnes but reached only 2.8 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The challenge to EU exporters is going to develop quite slowly but it is very real and one which needs to be addressed,&quot; the trader said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEAST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
