<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="348485" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Norway's Statoil plans future in state hands.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Norway's Statoil plans future in state hands.</headline>
<byline>Mark Thompson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Privatisation of Norway's oil giant Statoil may be a long way off but that will not hinder the company's drive to become a leading international energy company, Statoil president and chief executive officer Harald Norvik said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;(Privatisation) will always be on the agenda but I see no majority in Norway for privatising Statoil,&quot; Norvik told a meeting of the Norwegian British Chamber of Commerce.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the question is not who the owner is but how the owner acts and relates to the company,&quot; he said, briefing an audience on Statoil's strategy for the future, which includes doubling equity hydrocarbon production to one million barrels of oil equivalent by 2005.</p>
<p>Statoil was pressing ahead with its search for a joint venture partner for its shipping arm, but that should not be seen as a precursor to a broader sell-off.</p>
<p>Statoil's Shipping and Maritime Technology (SMT) division, the world's largest operator of offshore tankers with 19 shuttle tankers and nine conventional vessels, could be merged with a Norwegian or foreign company, he said.</p>
<p>Norvik said spinning off the SMT division was a product of the same concentration on core activities that led Statoil to merge its petrochemicals activities in 1994 with Finland's Neste, creating the Borealis joint venture.</p>
<p>Key to Statoil's future success was the rationalisation of its oil and gas assets on the Norwegian Continental Shelf and beyond.</p>
<p>To that end, the company is planning a massive series of asset swaps to allow it to concentrate on five areas in Norwegian waters which hold the bulk of its reserves and currently account for about 90 percent of its equity production.</p>
<p>Swaps agreements, which the company also hopes will give it access to major new developments in Britain and the Gulf of Mexico, could be completed by the end of the second quarter, Norvik told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the end of this story will probably be in the second quarter, maybe late in the second quarter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Norvik said it was possible Statoil may adopt a piece-meal approach to the negotiations, allowing early conclusion with some partners.</p>
<p>&quot;It might be that we can take them in sequences in which case we may be able to take some decisions on swaps earlier than in May/June, but we will probably need the time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Industry consultants Wood Mackenzie said Statoil's plans could lead to the biggest North Sea asset sale of recent years, even exceeding Kuwait Petroleum Corp's $1.23 billion sale of its North Sea explorer Santa Fe to Norway's Saga last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The combined base asset value of the commercial reserves which are on offer is in excess of $600 million. Significant additional value will also be attributable to the exploration acreage which is being made available,&quot; Wood Mackenzie said in a report.</p>
<p>Norvik was unwilling to name the companies interested in swapping assets, but he said some UK acreage had been offered.</p>
<p>Wood Mackenzie said Enterprise Oil, Amerada Hess, British Petroleum and Conoco, a unit of Du Pont, which all operate in both Norwegian and British waters, would be likely counterparties for Statoil.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
