<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="348497" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: New hepatitis vaccine gets better response - doctors.</title>
<headline>New hepatitis vaccine gets better response - doctors.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new vaccine against hepatitis B, one of the world's biggest health problems, may work for most people who have proved resistant to existing ones, British doctors said on Friday.</p>
<p>The doctors gave the vaccine, to be marketed under the name Hepagene, to 100 health care workers who had previously failed to respond to other vaccines.</p>
<p>Sixty-nine developed immunity after a single dose of the vaccine, which uses a genetically altered version of the virus and is manufactured by Evans Medical, a subsidiary of Medeva.</p>
<p>A 70th was found to have developed immunity after having a booster, the doctors reported in the British Medical Journal.</p>
<p>Many millions of people around the world catch hepatitis B each year -- two million die each year. The virus is transmitted from blood-to-blood or through sexual contact and can lead to fatal liver problems, including cirrhosis and cancer.</p>
<p>It is 100 times more infectious than the HIV virus that causes AIDS.</p>
<p>Up to 15 percent of people fail to respond to existing vaccinations and this is a particular problem for health care workers, who are likely to be exposed to the infection.</p>
<p>The study by doctors from London's Royal Free Hospital found that giving patients a single dose of the vaccine was just as effective as giving two doses.</p>
<p>But there were a number of factors that reduced the chances of anyone responding to Hepatitis B vaccines, they said.</p>
<p>These include increasing age, smoking, being overweight and immunosuppression. Men are also less likely to respond.</p>
<p>The site of the vaccination was also important -- the deltoid muscle in the shoulder is a more effective place to inject.</p>
<p>Medeva sees a large potential market for Hepagene. Chief executive Bill Bogie told Reuters last week the company could eventually sell millions of doses a year, at a &quot;three-figure&quot; price.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
