<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="348549" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Placer Pacific gold output down.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Placer Pacific gold output down.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Placer Pacific Ltd said on Friday its equity share of gold production totalled 188,607 ounces in the December 1996 quarter, down from 206,579 ounces in the corresponding period a year ago.</p>
<p>Equity share of producion for calendar 1996 was 761,624 ounces versus 770,196 in 1995, the company said.  </p>
<p>Gold production at Placer Pacific's 70 percent owned Kidston mine in Queensland for the full year was 185,204 ounces for 1996 (Placer's share 129,643) compared with 205,878 in 1995.</p>
<p>The lower production resulted from lower grade and recoveries. Gold production at the 60 percent owned Granny Smith mine in Western Australia for the full year was 267,345 ounces (Placer's share 160,407) compared with 219,083 ounces in 1995.</p>
<p>Higher grade ore from the Sunrise, pit more than offset lower recoveries and throughput, Placer Pacific said.  </p>
<p>The gold yield at the 80 percent-owned Misima mine in Papua New Guinea for the full year was 259,307 ounces (Placer's share 207,446 ounces), compared with 331,232 in 1995. Harder ore and lower gold grades resulted in the drop in production, it said.</p>
<p>Gold production at the 25 percent owned Porgera for the full year was 854,822 ounces (Placer's share 213,706 ounces) compared with 848,870 ounces in 1995. Higher throughput outweighed lower gold grades and recoveries, it said.</p>
<p>Copper production at the wholly-owned Osborne mine's first full year was above expectations at 44,026 tonnes coupled with with 50,422 ounces of gold, Placer Pacific said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
