<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="348692" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Toyota to raise carparts output in Philippines.</title>
<headline>Toyota to raise carparts output in Philippines.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toyota Motor Corp said on Friday that its affiliate Toyota Autoparts Philippines Inc (TAP) had started producing constant-velocity (CV) joints, a car component, in addition to gearboxes.</p>
<p>TAP said the increased parts production had resulted in the creation of 34 new jobs and will create another 97 new jobs when production reaches full capacity. It currently employs 443 workers.</p>
<p>The company, in Laguna, Philippines, is 95 percent owned by Toyota and will produce 56,000 CV joints in 1997 for use in Toyota's Tercel and Corona models made in its Taiwan unit and for the Soluna made in Thailand, a Toyota spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>TAP, which started gearbox production in September 1992, produced 196,000 manual transmissions in calendar 1996, down eight percent from a year earlier.</p>
<p>Of the 1996 total, 176,000 units were exported to Toyota's car production units in Taiwan, Thailand, Malaysia, Indonesia and Portugal. TAP will will boost its gearbox production to 214,000 units in 1997, the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Toyota's overall car sales in Asia rose three percent to 445,000 in 1996 from the previous record 432,000 in 1995. Toyota has no forecast but its Asian sales in 1997 are expected to continue rising, the spokeswoman said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
