<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="348844" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: INDONESIAN STOCKS - factors to watch Jan 31.</title>
<headline>INDONESIAN STOCKS - factors to watch Jan 31.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main factors likely to affect Indonesian stocks on Friday:</p>
<p>* On Thursday, the Dow Jones industrial average gained 83 points to 6,823.86, putting the average back within reach of its all-time closing high of 6,883.90 set on January 21. The rise came on the back of a broad rally, as blue chips continued to reverse the damage from recent sell-offs.</p>
<p>* A mob of Indonesian Moslems burned and wrecked churches and temples east of Jakarta on Thursday after reports that a Christian had insulted Moslems, officials and eyewitnesses said.</p>
<p>* Indonesia continued to commit serious human rights abuses in 1996, including in East Timor, the United States said.</p>
<p>* United Nations chief Kofi Annan said on Thursday that Portugal and Indonesia were ready to revive U.N.-sponsored talks on East Timor and he hoped the two sides could reach agreement quickly on the troubled territory.</p>
<p>MARKETS</p>
<p>* On Thursday, the composite index fell 4.04 points, or 0.58 percent, to close at 687.29 points after touching an intra-day low of 685.58 points.</p>
<p>* On Friday morning, spot rupiah was quoted at 2,377.0/78.0 at 0200 GMT, compared with Thursday close at 2,373.20/73.50.</p>
<p>STOCKS TO WATCH</p>
<p>* PT Tambang Timah on news it has signed an MOU with Mohammad Hasan to take part in the Busang gold project.</p>
<p>* PT Bakrie Brothers on plan to sell 49 percent share of PT Indocopper Investama Corp, which has a stake in PT Freeport Indonesia, subject to shareholders' approval in March.</p>
<p>* PT Bakrie Brothers on its plan to sell 20 percent of its stake in coal mining firm PT Arutmin.</p>
<p>* PT Astra Graphia on news it targeted sales growth of 70 percent this year.</p>
<p>* PT Multipolar Corp after winning shareholders' approval on Thursday to take a 50.1 percent controlling interest in retailer PT Matahari Putra Prima.</p>
<p>* PT Barito Pacific on rumours that new investors may enter Indonesia's largest plywood firm.</p>
<p>* PT Lippo Life on news it had revised up its 1996 net profit target to 130.8 billion rupiah from 100.3 billion rupiah initially.</p>
<p>* PT Great River Industries on news it targeted sales of 360 billion rupiah in 1997.</p>
<p>* Indosat on news it would join 12 Asian telecommunication firms, including Nippon Telegraph and Telephone Corp, to form multimedia forum</p>
<p>* State-controlled Bank Negara Indonesia on its denial of merger talk with state-owned Bank Tabungan Negara.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I46000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
