<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="348993" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: INSTANT VIEW - French Dec unemployment down 29,000.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - French Dec unemployment down 29,000.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are analyst comments on the 29,000 drop in French unemployment in December reported by the Labour Ministry on Friday, which left the ILO unemployment rate unchanged at 12.7 percent.</p>
<p>PATRICK MANGE, ECONOMIST, DEUTSCHE BANK:</p>
<p>The national figures are good, 29,000 less was far below the consensus, everybody was expecting 15-20,000 more. It's very good news for politicians and should be good news for the markets with all the social tension.</p>
<p>The unemployment figures, the dollar rise and the INSEE (business climate) survey could reinforce the assumption growth is again gaining force, but I'm extremely cautious with the unemployment figures in December as there could be short-term effects generated by the Christmas sales. We need a confirmation in further figures to see if there's a new tendency.</p>
<p>The minus 0.3 on the ILO figures can only be interpreted in a nice way. Unemployment in France is still too high, but nevertheless it's (the decline) a good thing.  </p>
<p>DAVID NAUDE, ECONOMIST, JP MORGAN:</p>
<p>Yes it was a big surprise. I think two things are playing a role. First there were probably government subsidised contracts because if you look at the composition of the fall it's really the young, the under 25s, which is usually a sign of the result of a government policy or effort to curb youth unemployment.</p>
<p>Second, 30,000 really is a big decline so there is more than just government schemes. Maybe there was a better output number or better activity at the end of the year after a weak start to the fourth quarter. Maybe activity is improving and we're seeing the impact on unemployment, it's hard to say.</p>
<p>I was expecting a 20,000 rise but I still believe the unemployment rate will rise to 13 percent. We have month to month volatility, government schemes and help from the recovery, but really the key is what the share of all the three factors is.  </p>
<p>PHILIPPE BROSSARD, ECONOMIST, ABN AMRO:</p>
<p>It's amazing, even judging by the old method of calculation it's still a significant decline. A rise to 13 percent is not guaranteed, we're almost at a peak now. We should see numbers falling regularly from around April, perhaps not every month, but in the overall trend.</p>
<p>There's a better basis for the start of the year (for the economy). But we'll probably have to wait until the end of the second quarter to measure properly. The debate (on the upturn) will continue for some time.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5542</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
