<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34894" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Key U.S. T-bond steady in Tokyo, awaits jobs data.</title>
<headline>Key U.S. T-bond steady in Tokyo, awaits jobs data.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key 30-year U.S. Treasury bond was steady by late Tokyo morning on Thursday as light position adjustments dominated activity following overnight falls.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's taking a wait-and-see stance now,&quot; a trader for a major Japanese securities house said. &quot;The market is waiting for today's weekly jobless claims data in order to get some clues for Friday's crucial jobs data.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said prices fell overnight on strong August automobile sales data. The market was also depressed on rumours that Friday's payroll data would signal strength in the U.S. economy, which could increase interest rate hike fears.  </p>
<p>At 0245 GMT, key 30-year bond stood at 95-21/32, yielding 7.10 percent, unchanged from Friday's New York close. The futures prices were mostly unchanged from previous closes.</p>
<p>&quot;People are not brave enough to take new positions now,&quot; a trader at an European securities firm said. &quot;If Friday's data shows extremely strong economic fundamentals, then the key bond yield could be sold as much as to 7.25 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said market sentiment turned weaker and had made Japanese investors nervous, particularly after Tuesday's Wall Street Journal report, which implied that the Fed was mulling a bigger-than-expected interest rate increase.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
