<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="349049" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IFC emerging market index up 0.6 pct at 314.63.</title>
<headline>IFC emerging market index up 0.6 pct at 314.63.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Finance Corporation's composite index of emerging market equities, denominated in dollars  IFC/IPRD, rose 0.6 percent to 314.63 at the start of trade on Friday.</p>
<p>Latin America rose 1.0 percent day-on-day to 581.97, Asia was up 0.4 percent at 261.21 and Europe, Middle East and Africa was up 0.2 percent at 150.05.</p>
<p>The IFC composite index began 1997 at 294.37 after making gains of 7.0 percent in 1996. It touched a high this year of 315.20 after the close of trade on January 27.</p>
<p>ING Barings' Global Emerging Market Index (BEMI), also denominated in dollars  BFFO, was up 0.71 percent day-on-day at 170.25 at 1000 GMT.</p>
<p>It began 1997 at 159.57 after rising 8.9 percent over the course of 1996. It touched a high of 171.22 after the end of trading on January 20.</p>
<p>Morgan Stanley's dollar-denominated Emerging Markets Free index  .CEMF=USD was down 0.72 percent at 504.680, calculated after the close of trade on Wednesday.</p>
<p>It began 1997 at 476.315 after gaining 3.9 percent over 1996. Its 1997 high of 508.674 was also reached on January 20.</p>
<p>All indices are capitalisation-weighted and are calculated daily. The IFC index measures returns on equities, liquid and accessible to foreign investors, from 26 emerging market countries. It is updated at 2300 GMT.</p>
<p>The BEMI index measures equity returns without dividends from some 21 emerging market countries, with the latest changes reported by 0900 GMT.</p>
<p>The MSCI Free measures equity returns without dividends from 26 emerging market nations. Changes are reported at 1300 GMT.</p>
<p>The J.P. Morgan emerging market bond index  ELMI, its returns calculated in dollar terms, rose 0.12 percent to a new 1997 high of 126.07 by the start of trade on Friday.</p>
<p>It began 1997 at 124.83 after jumping 14.86 percent over 1996.</p>
<p>By region, Latin America was up 0.17 percent at 104.64, Asia rose 0.06 to 132.35 and East Europe was down 1.16 at 161.19.</p>
<p>-- Andrew Gill, London Newsroom +44 171 542 2734</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
