<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="349027" id="root" date="1997-01-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: FEATURE - Archaeologists uncover Viking outpost in Greenland.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Archaeologists uncover Viking outpost in Greenland.</headline>
<byline>Christopher Follett</byline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Archaeologists from six countries have uncovered the remains of a 1,000-year-old Viking settlement in an icebound fjord in Greenland, casting new light on life in a Nordic outpost at what was once the world's end,</p>
<p>&quot;This is the very first time that we have investigated a Norse settlement in Greenland layer by layer down to its original foundations,&quot; Jette Arneborg of Denmark's National Museum and a leader of the six-year-old dig, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The site, known as Vesterbygden or &quot;western settlement&quot;, is located on the edge of the ice cap on Ameralik Fjord near Nuuk, the capital, about 100 kms (60 miles) inland from the Davis Strait separating Greenland from Canada's Baffin Island.</p>
<p>The oldest part of the building on the site, comprising 30 rooms, was built in the 10th century by the first Viking invaders from Iceland, Arneborg said.</p>
<p>After the settlement was finally abandoned in the mid-14th century, the ancient complex, known to archaeologists as &quot;the house under the sand&quot;, was engulfed in sand and permafrost, preserving it and its contents intact until today.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been able at last to plot the development of a Greenlandic Viking colony from its earliest 1,000-year-old Scandinavian form until around 1350, by which time it had taken on a local Greenland style of its own,&quot; Arneborg said.</p>
<p>SITE FIRST FOUND BY ESKIMOS</p>
<p>She said there were six building phases at the waterlogged site, just south of the Arctic circle, which was first discovered in 1991 by eskimo hunters who spotted pieces of carved wood sticking out of the ground.</p>
<p>Vesterbygden consists of a large complex of interconnected buildings, inhabited for over 300 years. The original Viking longhouse, with curved walls and two rows of interior posts supporting the roof, was a typical Icelandic peat construction.</p>
<p>The longhouse burned down shortly after completion, leaving a layer of scorched, reddish subsoil  which helped the archaeologists map out its shape and size.</p>
<p>A stone doorstep, a grinding slab and blackened stones from a kitchen hearth and fireplaces from the oldest building were found.</p>
<p>In the newer buildings, built in stone in local Greenlandic style, kitchen utensils, locks, keys, knives, tools, storage barrels, wooden bowls and lids were among the items unearthed.</p>
<p>Some of the artifacts, such as carvings and sculptures in wood or bone, had runic inscriptions, images of plants and Arctic birds, ornamentation or names or crosses cut into them.</p>
<p>One box lid decorated with an unfinished carving of a dragon's head has the inscription BJOERK, the name of a girl for whom it could have been a gift.</p>
<p>Among other finds were a whalebone box, a walrus tooth dice, a ritual amulet made out of a polar bear's tooth and fragments of clothing.</p>
<p>Bones of reindeer, game, seal and domestic animals, including an intact goat skeleton have been uncovered, signs of a peasant settlement which lived from hunting and farming in what was a lush, fertile part of Greenland 1,000 years ago.</p>
<p>NEW HOUSES BUILT ON FIRE SITE</p>
<p>After the first building burned down at Vesterbygden, new houses were erected on top of the ruins, with the function of the rooms often altered, stables being converted into living quarters or vice versa, Arneborg said.</p>
<p>Most of the rooms had mud or stone floors, but one had a wooden floor, using planks from a broken-up ship. All metal items had been removed from the site and there was no burial ground, indicating that the settlement was finally abandoned.</p>
<p>Led by experts from the national museums of Denmark and Greenland, the 16-strong team participating in the Greenland Viking excavations also numbers archaeologists from universities in Canada, Sweden, Britain and Iceland.</p>
<p>Greenland, the world's largest island and a Danish colony since 1721, has had home rule under Copenhagen since 1979.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREENL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-01-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
