<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="349125" id="root" date="1997-02-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-ENGLAND SUBMERGE SCOTS WITH LATE TRY BURST.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-ENGLAND SUBMERGE SCOTS WITH LATE TRY BURST.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kitson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>England rattled up the biggest winning margin over Scotland in Calcutta Cup history on Saturday with a Jekyll and Hyde performance which sets them up nicely for another Five Nations title bid.</p>
<p>There were long periods when the home side were less than impressive but they still won 41-13 with the help of three tries inside five minutes late in the second-half.</p>
<p>Scotland were ripped apart in almost identical fashion to their defeat against Wales a fortnight ago as captain Phil de Glanville, his predecessor Will Carling and scrum-half Andy Gomarsall all struck in quick succession between the 68th and 73rd minutes.</p>
<p>Fly-half Paul Grayson added 21 points with the boot to further erase the memory of a poor English first-half display and ensure a record eighth successive win over a Scotland side who have never conceded as many points against a Five Nations team.</p>
<p>The Scots did their best to entertain, especially early on, but were eventually outgunned by a powerful English pack who will be grateful not to be judged purely on the first hour of the game.</p>
<p>They were 10-0 up after 16 minutes, the result of two contentious refereeing decisions which almost certainly saved them from a very different half-time scenario.</p>
<p>Scotland had been robbed of a perfectly valid try after seven minutes when New Zealand touch judge Colin Hawke advised unsighted referee Paddy O'Brien that Rob Wainwright had not grounded the ball and worse was to follow for the Scotland captain.</p>
<p>O'Brien decided the Scots were guilty of deliberate offside in their own 22 after 15 minutes and awarded a penalty try which seemed a trifle premature to most onlookers. It showed an admirable wish to encourage open rugby in a notoriously miserly fixture, and gave England their first try against their opponents for four years, but was harsh on a Scotland team who had already shown refreshing intentions.</p>
<p>There was an element of recklessness in the way Gregor Townsend and his colleagues attempted to run from deep, but the Scots did score an excellent try in the 25th minute.</p>
<p>Kenny Logan spun out of trouble on the left, Ian Smith carried the ball on and when the ball re-emerged, Ronnie Eriksson cruised over for his first international try.</p>
<p>They were still in touch at 16-10 down at half-time and were back to within three points when Rowen Shepherd kicked his second penalty, only to leak 25 points without reply.</p>
<p>Grayson, who scored all 18 of England's points against the Scots last season, restored their advantage by taking his penalty tally to five and then the home supporters' fun really started.</p>
<p>Gomarsall finished off an individual burst by lock Martin Johnson, Carling finally broke through the dogged Scottish line shortly afterwards and de Glanville crowned a satisfying personal day with only his second try for his country.</p>
<p>&quot;In the end it was a good all-round performance,&quot; he said afterwards. &quot;As the opportunities and space came in the second-half we made the most of them.&quot;</p>
<p>Scottish captain Rob Wainwright admitted England deserved a pat on the back but again suggested his own players needed to look at themselves.</p>
<p>&quot;The first 50 minutes things were going to plan but we had the same problems we had two weeks ago. The defence weren't up to the mark,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>England - 15-Tim Stimpson; 14-Jon Sleightholme, 13-Will Carling, 12-Phil de Glanville (captain), 11-Tony Underwood; 10- Paul Grayson, 9-Andy Gomarsall; 8-Tim Rodber, 7-Richard Hill, 6- Lawrence Dallaglio, 5-Simon Shaw, 4-Martin Johnson, 3-Jason Leonard, 2-Mark Regan, 1-Graham Rowntree.</p>
<p>Scotland - 15-Rowen Shepherd; 14-Derek Stark, 13-Tony Stanger, 12-Ronnie Eriksson (16-Scott Hastings, 72), 11-Kenny Logan; 10--Gregor Townsend, 9-Bryan Redpath; 8-Rob Wainwright (captain), 7-Ian Smith, 6-Peter Walton, 5-Andy Reed, 4-Doddie Weir, 3-Mattie Stewart, 2-Graham Ellis, 1-Tom Smith.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
