<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="349272" id="root" date="1997-02-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUATEMALA: Camps being built for Guatemala rebel disarmament.</title>
<headline>Camps being built for Guatemala rebel disarmament.</headline>
<dateline>GUATEMALA CITY 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Construction has started on eight camps where Guatemala's guerrillas will disarm under international observation beginning in February, a United Nations official said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is not a set date to finish the camps but we hope it will happen the third or fourth week of February,&quot; Jose Segura of the United Nations Mission for Human Rights Verification in Guatemala told a news conference.</p>
<p>Under peace accords signed last month between the government and lefist rebels of the Guatemalan National Revolutionary Unit (URNG), the former outlaws will rejoin civil society after disarming in the camps.</p>
<p>The peace treaty ended 36 years of civil war in which an estimated 140,000 Guatemalans died or disappeared. Segura said between 250 and 600 former guerrillas of a total of 2,500 will live in the camps for 60 days.</p>
<p>Commander Pancho of the URNG told reporters that 3,000 to 4,000 guerrillas will demobilize.</p>
<p>International organisations and the Guatemalan government are financing the construction and administration of the camps, which will cost approximately $800,000.</p>
<p>Segura, a U.N. military adviser, heads a logistical commission that is overseeing the construction of eight camps, with houses, soccer fields, drinking water and latrines in six remote areas.</p>
<p>In a separate news conference, Foreign Relations Minister Eduardo Stein said the United Nations has almost completed putting together a mission of 155 unarmed U.N. observers from 15 countries, including Canada, Argentina and Sweden.</p>
<p>&quot;Spain will send the largest group, 44 observers with the chief of the mission,&quot; Stein said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUATEMALA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUATEMALA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
