<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="349234" id="root" date="1997-02-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian students march, Socialists ponder move.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian students march, Socialists ponder move.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Weeks</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-02-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgarian students marched through central Sofia on Saturday, blocking traffic to press their campaign against the ruling Socialists.</p>
<p>To chants of &quot;Victory&quot;, hundreds of boisterous university students in two separate marches paraded through the heart of the capital.</p>
<p>The processions of ragtag students beat drums, banged cymbals, and blew whistles and horns as they made their way past government ministries.</p>
<p>They stopped before each government office to boo, chant &quot;Mafia, Mafia, Mafia&quot; and then set off again. Gangs of students charged ahead with Bulgarian flags flying, blocking traffic for 15 minutes.</p>
<p>Residents watched from windows, often flashing &quot;V&quot; signs or joining in the chants and songs. Despite 27 days of protesting in bitter cold, the students remain in high spirits.</p>
<p>Students and the main opposition Union of Democratic Forces (UDF) were staging three marches and an evening mass rally in Sofia on Saturday to keep up their anti-government protests.</p>
<p>The campaign has piled pressure on dispirited and divided Socialists to quit and hold elections nearly two years ahead of schedule.</p>
<p>While the Balkan country sinks further into economic chaos, the Socialists -- the former communists -- have been struggling to form a new government. They have until Tuesday to present a new cabinet to parliament and face a vote of confidence.</p>
<p>Nationwide strikes and protests have intensified over the past week in an effort to force the Socialists to abandon their efforts to form a government and to call elections.</p>
<p>Some 1,000 UDF supporters blocked the main southern road and rail links to Greece for a fourth day. UDF said it would reinforce the blockades and offered people free rides from Sofia.</p>
<p>About 100 riot police stood nearby while tyres burned in the highway. Pop music blared, protesters pinned red carnations on police and a festive mood prevailed despite the cold.</p>
<p>President Petar Stoyanov met central bank governor Lyubomir Filipov on Saturday to discuss a letter from International Monetary Fund (IMF) managing director Michel Camdessus.</p>
<p>Camdessus said the IMF was ready to help Bulgaria through its economic crisis as soon as a valid government was in place. He urged Stoyanov to impress on all political parties the high social cost of delay.</p>
<p>The Socialists will hold a special meeting of parliamentary deputies, coalition partners and the Supreme Council of the Socialist Party on Sunday to chart their next move.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Nikolai Dobrev, who received a mandate to form a government, has appeared half-hearted in his efforts and has offered several times to stand aside, or even to return the mandate.</p>
<p>He told Reuters in an interview on Friday he was willing to accept a coalition cabinet formed under Stoyanov.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't mind if it is formed under the leadership of the president,&quot;  he said. &quot;I am ready to return my mandate if such a government is formed.&quot;</p>
<p>But he then postponed a meeting with Stoyanov, apparently under pressure from hardliners in his party. He said later the Socialists needed more time to talk with other parties.</p>
<p>The Socialists, elected for a four-year term in 1994, have overseen a caretaker cabinet since December when Zhan Videnov resigned as prime minister.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
