<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="349303" id="root" date="1997-02-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Khmer Rouge defectors decline alliance offer.</title>
<headline>Khmer Rouge defectors decline alliance offer.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-02-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Khmer Rouge defectors in northwest Cambodia will not be joining an alliance proposed by co-Premier Prince Norodom Ranariddh, a spokesman said on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;Our movement has only agreed (with) and supported the plan to establish the new front but we do not join it,&quot; said Nuth Sophearak, an aide to former rebel commander Ei Chien, reached by telephone in the northwest base of Pailin.</p>
<p>He said the Democratic National Union Movement (DNUM) wanted to remain neutral in the current political climate, marked by rivalry between Ranariddh and Second Prime Minister Hun Sen.</p>
<p>The prince had said he expected DNUM to join his Front Uni National (FUN -- United National Front), which has firm support from the officially unrecognised opposition Khmer Nation Party and a wing of the divided Buddhist Liberal Democratic Party.</p>
<p>Analysts speculated that the defectors were biding their time in the rivalry between Ranariddh and Hun Sen, who have been vying for the allegiance of thousands of Khmer Rouge defectors.</p>
<p>Hun Sen has rejected an offer for his Cambodian People's Party to join the front.</p>
<p>They said Ranariddh, who leads the royalist FUNCINPEC party, wanted DNUM support in the campaign against the CPP in local and general elections due to take place by the end of next year.</p>
<p>Nuth Sophearak denied speculation that Ei Chien, who was recently appointed a two-star general in the royal armed forces, would replace former Khmer Rouge leader Ieng Sary as DNUM head.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything is still the same. Nothing has changed and Ieng Sary will not step down from the DNUM,&quot; he said in reference to the former Khmer Rouge foreign minister, whose August split with hardliners under Khmer Rouge leader Pol Pot triggered thousands of defections.</p>
<p>Analysts fear the alliance, which should be launched this month, will exacerbate strained ties between Ranariddh and Hun Sen, who formed a coalition after U.N.-run elections in 1993.</p>
<p>The Khmer Rouge, whose brutal 1975-79 rule left more than one million people dead, reneged on a U.N.-brokered peace pact in 1991 and boycotted the polls. They had been fighting the coalition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
