<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="349302" id="root" date="1997-02-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Lien says Taiwan watching China's Hong Kong moves.</title>
<headline>Lien says Taiwan watching China's Hong Kong moves.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Parker</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-02-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan on Saturday urged arch rival China to honour a pledge to preserve Hong Kong's autonomy after its mid-year handover from Britain and again blamed Beijing for a festering impasse in Taiwan-China talks.</p>
<p>&quot;I only hope China's communists, whether from a practical standpoint or under their own international promises, can let Hong Kong people run Hong Kong...and maintain its human rights, freedom and democracy,&quot; Vice President Lien Chan said.</p>
<p>&quot;This would be a fine developement, not only for Hong Kong but for Chinese on both sides of the (Taiwan) strait and people in the Asia-Pacific region and around the world,&quot; Lien told a Lunar new year news conference.</p>
<p>Lien vowed that his Republic of China government, marooned on Taiwan since losing the mainland to communist troops in 1949, would continue to defy a Beijing-enforced diplomatic embargo.</p>
<p>China should learn to accept this, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We must go out (onto the world stage) so the outside world will not hear just one side talking,&quot; said Lien, speaking in his capacity as premier.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope China's communists can learn to treat Taiwan with an attitude of peace, equality, mutual benefit and reason,&quot; he said. &quot;This might be difficult but learn they must.</p>
<p>&quot;If they cannot get used to this, relations across the Taiwan strait cannot improve,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An angry Beijing froze what had been slowly warming talks in June 1995 after Taiwan President Lee Teng-hui's private U.S. visit, cited by China as evidence that Lee wants independence for Taiwan despite his government's pro-unification stance.</p>
<p>Beijing has set vague conditions for talks, saying Taiwan's Nationalist government must &quot;return to a one China policy&quot; and stop trying to &quot;split Taiwan from the motherland&quot;.</p>
<p>Lien attacked those conditions, saying Beijing had abandoned a breakthrough 1993 concensus in which the rivals accepted that each had its own interpretation of &quot;one China&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Their view of one China is the so-called People's Republic of China with Taiwan as a province. How can we possibly accept that?&quot; Lien said, using communist China's formal name.</p>
<p>&quot;It's as if they are digging a big hole in the ground and want us to jump in,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Taipei espouses eventual unification but only after China adopts democratic reforms. Taiwan has flatly rejected the &quot;one country, two systems&quot; model of local autonomy that Beijing pledges to implement in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Lien urged China to end a 19-month stalemate in cross-strait talks, saying he regretted that freezing contacts had scuttled a planned meeting of the rivals' top negotiators at which issues of Hong Kong's transition would have been a main topic.</p>
<p>&quot;Both sides should resume constructive talks and exchanges under their own interpretations of 'one China',&quot; Lien said.</p>
<p>Lien said only negotiations could resolve key issues about how Taiwan people and organisations could operate after mid-year in Hong Kong -- the main conduit through which more than US$20 billion in Taiwan investment has flowed into the mainland.</p>
<p>Lien reiterated his government's veiled threat to slow that flow of badly needed capital, saying Taiwan's investment and trade in China, while important, must not come at the expense of Taiwan's own economic and political development.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
