<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="349393" id="root" date="1997-02-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: California sues U.S. over radioactive waste land.</title>
<headline>California sues U.S. over radioactive waste land.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Croft</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-01-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The state of California sued Interior Secretary Bruce Babbitt Friday to try to force him to hand over federal land for a proposed low-level radioactive waste dump, officials said.</p>
<p>The lawsuit, filed in U.S. District Court in Washington D.C., is the latest move in a long-running dispute between California Gov. Pete Wilson and the Clinton administration over proposals to build the dump at Ward Valley in the Mojave Desert of southern California.</p>
<p>In February last year, the Interior Department asked for more environmental study before it transferred the land. It said tests would be carried out on whether radioactive material at the site could penetrate to groundwater near the Colorado River, which supplies millions with drinking water.</p>
<p>But the Wilson administration said the Interior Department has failed to move ahead with the tests.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the state said, low-level radioactive waste -- produced by hospitals, universities and biotechnology companies -- must either be stored on-site at dozens of locations throughout the state or shipped to South Carolina.</p>
<p>In a letter to Babbitt informing him of the lawsuit, Wilson accused the federal government of delaying tactics.</p>
<p>&quot;I no longer believe your department intends to complete this transfer under any circumstances, regardless of what risks this refusal presents to public health and safety,&quot; Wilson, a Republican, said.</p>
<p>The California Department of Health Services and its director, Kim Belshe, filed the suit against Babbitt, the U.S. Interior Department and the U.S. Bureau of Land Management, seeking to force them to hand over the land.</p>
<p>California is legally bound to provide a waste facility to serve low-level waste producers in California, Arizona and North and South Dakota. Some environmentalists have protested the selection of the Mojave Desert site.</p>
<p>Daniel Hirsch, president of the Committee to Bridge the Gap, a group opposed to the Ward Valley dump, said Wilson's action was &quot;a shameful attempt to block ongoing environmental study by the federal government of whether this proposed project would endanger the public.&quot;</p>
<p>According to the lawsuit, then Interior Secretary Manuel Lujan, following extensive environmental study, issued a &quot;record of decision&quot; in January 1993 approving the transfer of the Ward Valley land to California.</p>
<p>But Deputy U.S. Interior Secretary John Garamendi said that in the last days of President George Bush's administration a judge issued an order preventing Lujan from transferring Ward Valley to California.</p>
<p>&quot;The Clinton administration has been addressing unresolved questions surrounding the transfer ever since. Now Gov. Wilson apparently wants to go back to the discredited approach of former Secretary Lujan,&quot; Garamendi said.</p>
<p>Wilson told Babbitt the Interior Department could not be relied upon to objectively conduct testing at Ward Valley. So he said he had ordered the state Department of Health Services to immediately begin additional tests at the site, as recommended by the National Academy of Sciences in 1995.</p>
<p>He asked Babbitt to order the Bureau of Land Management to remove protesters, who have set up a permanent camp near the proposed waste dump site, so that testing can begin.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-01-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
