<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="349403" id="root" date="1997-02-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Mobutu to quit France, visit Morocco, return home.</title>
<headline>Mobutu to quit France, visit Morocco, return home.</headline>
<dateline>ROQUEBRUNE-CAP MARTIN, France 1997-02-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko, convalescing on the French Riviera, will fly to Morocco on Monday to meet King Hassan and travel home to Zaire on February 8, a spokesman said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Mobutu, facing a rebel uprising at home that is the biggest challenge to his 31-year-rule, would fly to Rabat on Monday, leaving his sprawling private mansion overlooking the Mediterranean where he has been staying since January 9.</p>
<p>The meeting with King Hassan &quot;should take place at the start of the week, Monday or Tuesday,&quot; Mobutu Nzanga, one of the president's sons who is also his spokesman, told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said that Mobutu would fly straight home to Kinshasa from Morocco next Saturday.</p>
<p>Mobutu has been in France convalescing from surgery for prostate cancer in Switzerland last August. Aides to the president said that two hospital examinations in nearby Monaco during Mobutu's current stay were satisfactory.</p>
<p>Mobutu also spent six weeks in France last year as part of his convalescence.</p>
<p>He returned to Kinshasa for three weeks on December 17 to a short-lived hero's welcome, with 100,000 people turning out to fete him on arrival. In Zaire he carried out a major reshuffle of his government and the army high command.</p>
<p>The Tutsi-led rebels launched their offensive in October, accusing Zaire of denying them citizenship and seeking to expel them to Rwanda, which their forebears left generations ago.</p>
<p>Zaire's army, which launched a much-trumpeted counter-offensive on January 20, says it has taken numerous Rwandan and Ugandan soldiers prisoner.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROQUEBRUNE-CAP MARTIN, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
