<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="349552" id="root" date="1997-02-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SWIMMING-HAN COMPLETES BRILLIANT WEEK WITH SECOND WORLD RECORD.</title>
<headline>SWIMMING-HAN COMPLETES BRILLIANT WEEK WITH SECOND WORLD RECORD.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>GELSENKIRCHEN, Germany 1997-02-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's Han Xue completed a remarkable week in the short-course pool on Sunday when she broke her own world record for the women's 50 metres breaststroke for the second time in five days.</p>
<p>Han, 15, powered through the pool to clock 30.77 seconds at the Gelsenkirchen World Cup meeting, the third world mark of the two-day event.</p>
<p>She set the previous best of 30.88 in a World Cup meeting in Glasgow only last Wednesday. But she was still surprised by the performance.</p>
<p>&quot;I can hardly believe this second world record in this season's World Cup,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>All eyes were on Russia's double Olympic champion Denis Pankratov at the start of the last day after his record-breaking performance in the men's 200 butterfly on Saturday.</p>
<p>But Pankratov, who looked capable of smashing the mark for the 100 race in the discipline, blew his chances of a second world record with a false start in the heats.</p>
<p>The Russian, who was deprived of two world records in Paris last season because of an organisational blunder, took off from his blocks early in what should have been a straightforward heat and was disqualified.</p>
<p>The mistake turned out to be costly. In addition to the $2,000 bonus swimmers earn for a world record on the World Cup circuit, Pankratov had a chance of winning a car at the Gelsenkirchen meeting.</p>
<p>The car for the best performance of the weekend went instead to triple European champion Marcel Wouda of the Netherlands, who on Saturday set a world mark in the men's 400 individual medley.</p>
<p>Wouda, who just missed out on a medal at last year's Atlanta Olympics but picked up three medley titles at the European sprint championships in December, clocked four minutes 05.59 seconds for his world mark.s.</p>
<p>The final day also saw European records for German Sandra Voelker in the women's 50 butterfly (26.97 seconds), Konstantin Ushkov in the men's 100 butterfly (52.26) and Russian Nina Zhyvanevskaja in the women's 100 backstroke ( 58.99).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GELSENKIRCHEN, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
