<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34959" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: U.S., Iraq back away from further confrontation.</title>
<headline>U.S., Iraq back away from further confrontation.</headline>
<byline>Jack Redden</byline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States and Iraq appeared on Thursday to back away from further confrontation despite conflicting claims of continued Iraqi troop movements against Kurdish rebels.</p>
<p>While the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK) said Iraqi President Saddam Hussein was continuing the offensive that triggered two days of U.S. missile attacks, CIA Director John Deutch said in Washington that Iraqi armour was pulling back from near Arbil, the city they captured last Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't see it happening,&quot; Navy Lieutenant Commander Scott Campbell, a Pentagon spokesman, said of PUK claims that Iraqi troops were on an offensive aimed at his headquarters town of Sulaimaniya. &quot;We don't see any attacks or massing of tanks in the area between Arbil and Sulaimaniya.&quot;</p>
<p>Iraq, which had vowed to resist the U.S. proclamation of an extended zone over Iraq closed to Iraqi aircraft, toned down the defiant rhetoric in the state-controlled newspapers on Thursday.</p>
<p>The papers carried frontpage pictures of Saddam meeting military commanders instead of the previous defiant editorials, printing pictures inside of casualties suffered when the United States fired 44 cruise missiles at Iraqi military targets on Tuesday and Wednesday.</p>
<p>Iraqi media shifted its focus to widespread international criticism of the U.S. attacks, which found enthusiastic backing mainly from Britain.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher won an endorsement of the expanded no-fly zone from Britain on Thursday but after subsequent talks in Paris with French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette he avoided questions on the subject.</p>
<p>Despite the anger in Baghdad at the U.S. attacks and the expanded no-fly zone imposed in reprisal for the weekend offensive in northern Iraq, Washington reported only two minor challenges on Wednesday to its own air patrols over Iraq.</p>
<p>However, reports from northern Iraq underlined the choatic conditions that existed there even before Saddam's forces backed the the Kurdish Democractic Party (KDP) to seize Arbil from their rivals the PUK.</p>
<p>Turkey staged heavy military movements near its border with Iraq, a day after officials said they were prepared to occupy a strip of northern Iraqi territory up to 10 km (6 miles) deep to prevent cross-border attacks by guerrillas of the Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK), a group fighting for the independence of Turkish Kurds.</p>
<p>Turkish Foreign Minister Tansu Ciller said a thrust into northern Iraq was not imminent but witnesses reported troop movements near the frontier and Turkish air patrols overhead.</p>
<p>Iraq had defended its attack on Arbil as necessary to prevent Iranian encroachment. It said the PUK was getting Iranian backing in its struggle for supremacy in the Kurdish area, which had been outside Baghdad's control since Saddam's defeat in the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>Despite both U.S. and Iraqi assertions of no Iraqi army action in the northern region, PUK leader Jalal Talabani said in an interview in Sulaimaniya on Thursday that he still faced a joint Iraqi-KDP offensive and would seek Iranian help if necessary.</p>
<p>&quot;We will call support from any country which is ready to help us -- from Iran, Syria or Turkey,&quot; he said in his stronghold. &quot;There is no possibility of peace now in this region.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
