<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="349657" id="root" date="1997-02-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: HORSE RACING-TERRIFIC SCENES OF JOY AS DANOLI WINS HENNESSY.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-TERRIFIC SCENES OF JOY AS DANOLI WINS HENNESSY.</headline>
<byline>Damien Lynch</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-02-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ireland's latest equine star Danoli captured the Hennessy Cognac Gold Cup at Leopardstown on Sunday and was immediately named a runner in the Cheltenham Gold Cup.</p>
<p>Danoli, a 6-1 chance, had fallen on two of his five previous outings over fences but jumped magnificently on this occasion under jockey Tommy Treacy to win the three-mile (4.8 kms) race by 1-1/2 lengths.</p>
<p>&quot;Thank God that's over. We will now go for the Cheltenham Gold Cup,&quot; County Carlow-based trainer Tom Foley told the ecstatic record 20,000 crowd. That race is on March 13.</p>
<p>Jodami (5-1), winner of three successive Hennessy Gold Cups starting in 1993 and denied the chance to bid for a fourth by an 11th hour setback a year ago, finished strongly to come home second 20 lengths ahead of evens-favourite Imperial Call.</p>
<p>Imperial Call, winner of the 1996 Cheltenham Gold Cup, finished with a cut on one one hind leg but trainer Fergie Sutherland said his stable star was fine and would attempt to retain his title in March.</p>
<p>Sutherland said Imperial Call would have one more run before the Cheltenham Festival, in a steeplechase at Gowran Park on February 15.</p>
<p>Dublin bookmakers quoted Danoli an 8-1 chance for the Cheltenham race with Imperial Call second-favourite at 6-1. Another Irish-trained runner, Dorans Pride, has been installed as the pre-race favourite at 4-1.</p>
<p>Earlier, the Michael Hourigan-trained Dorans Pride, ridden by Shane Broderick, won the Grade Two Scalp Novice Steeplechase.</p>
<p>&quot;If the ground is fast or firm at Cheltenham he will not run there,&quot; Tom Doran, his owner, said.</p>
<p>Dorans Pride (8-11 favourite) made all the running over the two miles and five furlongs (4.2 kms) trip and had six lengths to spare over Richard Dunwoody on second-placed See More Business, trained by Paul Nicholls in Britain.</p>
<p>Aidan O'Brien's Istabraq, with Ireland's champion jockey Charlie Swan riding, remained on course for one of the top hurdle races at Cheltenham with a head victory over stablemate Finnegan's Hollow in the Grade Two Deloitte and Touche Novice Hurdle over two miles and two furlongs (3.6 kms).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
