<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="349786" id="root" date="1997-02-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peruvians back Fujimori's handling of crisis - poll.</title>
<headline>Peruvians back Fujimori's handling of crisis - poll.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-02-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Alberto Fujimori, under pressure to find a peaceful solution to the 47-day-old hostage crisis in Lima, received support on Sunday from a poll suggesting 61 percent of Peruvians backed his handling of the siege.</p>
<p>The Datum survey, conducted in late January and published in El Comercio, showed 29 percent disapproved and 10 percent had no opinion.</p>
<p>Fujimori was in Washington on Sunday for meetings with U.S. officials following an emergency summit on Saturday in Toronto with Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto.</p>
<p>They were looking for progress in the stand-off that began on Dec. 17 when the rebels stormed a party at the Japanese ambassador's residence, seized more than 500 hostages and demanded that their fellow Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) members in jail be freed. All but 72 hostages have since been released.</p>
<p>At the Toronto summit, Fujimori and Hashimoto agreed to push for direct talks with the rebels, even though they reiterated they would not consider the demand for the freedom of MRTA rebels in prison.</p>
<p>The Datum poll of 400 people also indicated that 43 percent of those surveyed approved of the president's administration, versus 50 percent who disapproved.</p>
<p>It was further evidence that Fujimori's popularity remains mired at its lows since taking office in 1990.</p>
<p>The president had held high popularity ratings due to the virtual defeat of communist guerrillas, economic reforms and a strong, personalized leadership style.  But analysts say the government's failure to reduce high levels of poverty and unemployment have eroded his support.</p>
<p>While many Peruvians have seen much truth in the MRTA's complaints about poverty in Peru, there has been general disgust at their methods and strong support for what Fujimori calls his &quot;firm but prudent&quot; approach to the crisis.</p>
<p>In the new survey on Sunday, 48 percent said the MRTA attack was an isolated incident but 42 percent thought it signified a return of the guerrilla group previously thought to have been decimated.</p>
<p>Thirty-seven percent said the government and rebels will reach a peaceful solution while 24 percent felt authorities will storm the residence by force.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
