<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34986" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gale winds buffet Carolina coast ahead of hurricane.</title>
<headline>Gale winds buffet Carolina coast ahead of hurricane.</headline>
<byline>Lorrie Grant</byline>
<dateline>MYRTLE BEACH, S.C. 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. officials shut down nuclear power reactors and closed coastal roads and bridges on Thursday afternoon as gale-force winds lashed the Carolina coast ahead of Hurricane Fran.</p>
<p>Residents boarded up their stores and homes as people near the border of North and South Carolina waited for the full impact of the hurricane's 115 mph (185 kmh) winds to hit land, expected late on Thursday evening.</p>
<p>Fran was predicted to cut across the heart of North Carolina, dumping up to 12 inches (30 cms) of rain and flooding rivers swollen from late summer rains.</p>
<p>About 5,000 residents huddled in a dozen Red Cross shelters in Myrtle Beach, a popular seaside resort on the Atlantic coast, local emergency officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;All the bridges to the barrier islands have been closed,&quot; said a spokesman for Brunswick County in North Carolina, an area expected to bear the brunt of the storm. &quot;Patrol cars were out all morning with the loudspeakers saying, 'Get off the island.'&quot;</p>
<p>At 5 p.m. EDT (2100 GMT), Fran's eye was 95 miles (153 kmh) south of Wilmington, North Carolina. The storm was moving north-northwest at 16 mph (25 kmh).</p>
<p>The wind began gusting above 60 mph (95 kmh) by Thursday afternoon and overturned some cars in Myrtle Beach.</p>
<p>The port city of Wilmington, North Carolina, also steeled for the storm's arrival. The city's charming Victorian homes are the foundation of a thriving tourist industry.</p>
<p>Resident Christine Huynh, 32, said she left her mobile home to check into a hotel. &quot;I just didn't want to be in a mobile home during a hurricane. We were in the trailer park during Hurricane Bertha,&quot; she said. Bertha swirled near the Carolina coast in July, kicking up heavy surf.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a very powerful storm and it is veering toward our coast,&quot; North Carolina Governor Jim Hunt said. &quot;It is almost going to cover the whole state.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We've had tremendous flooding in the west. We've had 11 inches (28 cm) of rain in 12 hours. We've got roads washed out, and this is going to come on top of that,&quot; Hunt said.</p>
<p>Residents of Charleston, an historic port city battered seven years ago by Hurricane Hugo, breathed a sigh of relief as forecasters said Fran's course would put the eye about 100 miles (160 km) north. Hugo's 1989 path through the city killed 27 and caused more than $7 billion worth of damage.</p>
<p>Officials predicted that Fran would create a storm surge up to 16 feet (5 metres) early on Friday on a stretch of ocean between Myrtle Beach and Wilmington, threatening billions of dollars of beachfront development.</p>
<p>North Carolina farmers, who lost more than $179 million to this summer's Hurricane Bertha, feared Fran would bring greater losses of crops that had not been harvested.</p>
<p>Hurricane forecasters were also keeping a close eye on the season's eighth tropical depression far out in the Atlantic.</p>
<p>The National Hurricane Centre said the depression was 535 miles (860 km) east of the Leeward Islands and was expected to strengthen into Tropical Storm Hortense by late Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MYRTLE BEACH, S.C."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
