<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="349994" id="root" date="1997-02-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: White House committed to capping Medicaid spending.</title>
<headline>White House committed to capping Medicaid spending.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The White House is committed to imposing spending limits on the Medicaid program for the poor, elderly and disabled, despite opposition from governors, President Clinton's Chief of Staff Erskine Bowles said Sunday.</p>
<p>The National Governors' Association said it would oppose any plan that would cap federal Medicaid spending, and shift costs to the states.</p>
<p>Bowles said Clinton's Medicaid budget was based on four principles, including preserving the health care guarantee for the poor.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to make sure, secondly, that we have some cost controls so that we can restrain the growth in the out years should it come back,&quot; Bowles told reporters, after addressing the governors at their annual winter meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;Thirdly, we want to make sure that we do more for kids. And lastly, we do want to give the governors the flexibility they need to make this program work,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Medicaid is an open-ended entitlement, jointly funded by state and federal governments. The program has been the fastest growing part of many state budgets, comprising about 20 percent of state spending on average. States spent about $70 billion on Medicaid last year.</p>
<p>The governors are due to meet Clinton Monday, when they will discuss several contentious issues including welfare reform, Medicaid spending, and environmental protection.</p>
<p>Republican governors Saturday snuffed out efforts to reopen discussion of the landmark welfare law passed last year, which sharply cut federal aid to legal immigrants.</p>
<p>When he signed the law, Clinton said he wanted to change some provisions in order to restore aid to legal immigrants, especially children.</p>
<p>Bowles shrugged off the opposition by the Republican governors to reopening the law.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not going to be able to agree on all things at all times,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
