<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="34996" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton creates new commission to study health care.</title>
<headline>Clinton creates new commission to study health care.</headline>
<byline>Donna Smith</byline>
<dateline>SUNRISE, Fla. 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton, emerging from what he has proclaimed to be a successful U.S. showdown with Iraq, hit the campaign trail on Thursday to highlight education and announce a new commission on health care.</p>
<p>The stop in Sunrise was the second in a two-day swing through Florida, a populous state that has not gone Democratic in a presidential election in 20 years but where recent polls show Clinton slightly ahead of Republican challenger Bob Dole.</p>
<p>Clinton announced the creation of a new commission that will study the financing and quality of American health care in a rapidly changing system and report to the president next year. The commission is to be headed by Health and Human Services Secretary Donna Shalala and Labour Secretary Robert Reich, the White House said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to make sure that the changes that are being made do not lead to a decline in the quality of health care,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>House Majority Leader Dick Armey and other Republicans were quick to criticise the new commission at a news conference in Washington. They called it a new version of the group headed by Clinton's wife, Hillary, that produced the failed 1993 plan to provide health insurance for all Americans.</p>
<p>Armey raised the spectre of a government controlled health care system -- an argument Republicans used to turn public opinion against the 1993 Clinton health plan -- and Dan Miller, a Florida Republican, said &quot;Bill Clinton is so far ahead in the polls he thinks the real Bill Clinton can start coming out. He's going back to the liberal base he had.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton used his second stop in Florida to announced his support for legislation that would bar health maintenance organisations from restricting what treatment procedures doctors may discuss with patients. He also reiterated support for legislation that would require insurance companies to pay for at least 48 hours hospital care for new mothers and their babies.</p>
<p>Retirees are a major component of the Florida electorate and Clinton spoke to the group of senior citizens about efforts to stem the rising cost of the Medicare health care for the elderly and criticised Republican proposals.</p>
<p>&quot;We can fix it, but we don't want to destroy it,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>In his first stop in Tampa, Clinton sounded familiar themes on education,  including hooking school rooms up to the international web of computers on the Internet and a $10,000 tax break for college tuition.</p>
<p>&quot;A big part of building a bridge to the 21st century is building a bridge big enough to give every single boy and girl in America a chance to live up to their God-given abilities,&quot; he told several hundred students at Hillsborough High School.</p>
<p>Dole needs to hang on to Florida if he is to have any chance of upsetting the Democratic president on Nov. 5. But two of his top strategists, Don Sipple  and Mike Murphy, quit his faltering campaign on Thursday in what the Dole camp called a friendly departure.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly ... they are in conflict over which way to go, what message to pursue,&quot; said Clinton campaign spokesman Joe Lockhart, who was travelling with the president. &quot;I think it was inevitable that there would be another shakeup.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton, riding a strong rise in his poll ratings after last week's Democratic convention and the U.S. air strikes on Iraq, resumed campaigning after spending much of the week concentrating on the Iraqi crisis.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, he declared that U.S. cruise missile strikes had taught Iraqi President Saddam Hussein the desired lesson against aggressive behaviour towards Iraq's Kurdish minorities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SUNRISE, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
