<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="350015" id="root" date="1997-02-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French National Front leads battle for fourth town. [CORRECTED 21:55 GMT]</title>
<headline>French National Front leads battle for fourth town. [CORRECTED 21:55 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>VITROLLES, France 1997-02-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>(Corrects dateline from Feb 1.)</p>
<p>By Thierry Cayol</p>
<p>The far-right National Front came close to winning control of a fourth French town on Sunday.</p>
<p>With a third of the first round votes counted in a fiercely-contested municipal election in the southern town of Vitrolles, the National Front list headed by Catherine Megret was leading with 47.7 percent.</p>
<p>A vote of 50 percent would elect her mayor of the depressed, sprawling town of 39,000 people. Otherwise, a second round will be held next Sunday.</p>
<p>Socialist mayor Jean-Jacques Anglade trailed on 35.7 percent after a campaign marred by insults and scattered violence. Roger Guichard, candidate of the government's centre-right coalition, had 16.6 percent.</p>
<p>The election is a test of the allure of the anti-immigrant National Front ahead of 1998 parliamentary elections and amid record unemployment in France. Front leader Jean-Marie Le Pen wants to send home three million immigrants.</p>
<p>The Front, which has no seats in parliament, won control of its first three towns in France in nationwide municipal elections in 1995 -- Marignane, Orange and Toulon.</p>
<p>In those elections, Anglade overturned a big Front first round lead to win the municipal election in Vitrolles on the second round by a wafer-thin 353 votes. The vote was cancelled because of irregularities by Anglade's camp.</p>
<p>In 1995, Anglade beat Megret's husband, Bruno Megret, who is a deputy to Le Pen. Bruno Megret was banned from running this time round for exceeding campaign spending limits and is being &quot;represented&quot; by his wife, who has scant political experience.</p>
<p>Posters tell voters to &quot;Vote Megret&quot; and Bruno Megret says he will be his wife's chief advisor if she wins. He says National Front  policies of giving priority to white French people will help bring down unemployment of 19 percent in the town.</p>
<p>Among a rash of violent attacks during the bitter campaign, Front candidate Gilles Lacroix was taken to hospital after unknown attackers beat him up and left him unconscious in the street.</p>
<p>In another incident, Anglade's driver suffered face burns when a pot of glue landed on his head.</p>
<p>On the eve of the vote, a court banned the Front from publishing its newspaper &quot;Allez Vitrolles&quot; (Go Vitrolles), ruling that it contained libellous portraits of Anglade and other Socialists.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VITROLLES, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
