<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="350099" id="root" date="1997-02-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Karachi prepares for tense election day.</title>
<headline>Karachi prepares for tense election day.</headline>
<byline>Ovais Subhani</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1997-02-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rivalry between factions of the ethnic Mohajir National Movement (MQM) could erupt into conflict in the violent city of Karachi on Monday when citizens go to the polls.</p>
<p>Witnesses said activists of the mainstream MQM, which hopes to grab a dozen National Assembly seats, came under a hail of stones thrown by supporters of the splinter MQM-Haqiqi faction as the election campaign reached its climax on Saturday.</p>
<p>Several people were injured and several vehicles were damaged in the clash in Landhi, a stronghold of MQM-Haqiqi.</p>
<p>MQM-Haqiqi militants also fired warning shots to deter MQM supporters from venturing into what they see as their territory.</p>
<p>Four people have been killed in sporadic clashes between the two factions in the run-up to the polls.</p>
<p>The MQM's self-exiled leader, Altaf Hussain, warned that his party might not accept election results if it feels that the polls have been rigged or manipulated by its opponents.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not accept the results if the elections are rigged...free and fair polls are not possible in the present circumstances,&quot; he said in a speech from London relayed by telephone and loudspeaker to two rallies in Karachi.</p>
<p>Ishtiaq Azhar, chief of the MQM's coordination committee in Karachi, said the MQM-Haqiqi's actions in keeping MQM candidates out of certain areas was tantamount to &quot;pre-election rigging&quot;.</p>
<p>He said the Sindh provincial administration and police were backing MQM-Haqiqi in a violent campaign against the MQM.</p>
<p>A spokesman for MQM-Haqiqi denied the charges, saying that the trouble in Landhi began after police tried to break up a crowd chanting slogans against Altaf Hussain.</p>
<p>Both factions claim to speak for Karachi's majority Mohajirs, Urdu-speaking Moslems who left Hindu-majority India when Pakistan was formed in 1947 at the end of the British Raj.</p>
<p>Their feud and the MQM's struggle with the security forces were responsible for much of the violence that cost about 500 lives in Karachi last year and more than 2,000 in 1995.</p>
<p>Many people are pinning their hopes for a return to lasting peace in this turbulent southern port city of 12 million on full participation by the MQM in Monday's polls.</p>
<p>The MQM boycotted the last National Assembly elections in 1993, but took part in provincial assembly polls two days later.</p>
<p>&quot;The MQM's decision to participate in the polls this time should be welcomed as it is important to bring back a largely alienated population into the political mainstream,&quot; The News, an English-language daily, wrote in its editorial.</p>
<p>&quot;The crisis of urban Sindh can only be resolved if recourse is taken to negotiations and constitutional methods,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
