<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="350066" id="root" date="1997-02-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Corsican separatists mount 54-bomb show of force.</title>
<headline>Corsican separatists mount 54-bomb show of force.</headline>
<byline>Sylvie Florence</byline>
<dateline>AJACCIO, Corsica 1997-02-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Separatist guerrillas defied a French government crackdown to mount a show of force on the Mediterranean island of Corsica on Sunday, exploding 54 mostly tiny bombs in the space of a few hours.</p>
<p>The Corsican National Liberation Front (FLNC) Historic Wing said in a statement it had planted the bombs, which police said caused no injuries although some offices were damaged.</p>
<p>Police did not report any arrests despite heightened security bostered by police reinforcements from the mainland.</p>
<p>An unknown number of guerrillas defied a French government crackdown to plant charges at banks, post offices, tax offices and other symbols of French state authority in several towns and in villages around the island.</p>
<p>It was the most violent night on the tourist island since February 9 last year, when the Resistenza separatist group staged 50 blasts and attempted bombings.</p>
<p>It came after France's centre-right government pledged to crack down on the separatist violence which has gone on for 20 years in the island of 250,000 people.</p>
<p>The Historic Wing has staged attacks in mainland France recently and on Tuesday planted a powerful bomb that damaged the offices of Air France in the Riviera capital of Nice.</p>
<p>Corsican guerrillas have never been taken as seriously as IRA guerrillas in Northern Ireland or ETA Basque separatists in Spain, for instance, partly because they deliberately seek to avoid casualties and are deeply divided.</p>
<p>Opinion polls show the great majority of the island's population reject the separatist cause. A poll last year showed 90 percent of Corsicans opposed independence for the island.</p>
<p>Yet the guerrillas have managed to muster 600 armed and hooded fighters to display to the media at news conferences.</p>
<p>Forty-three of the blasts were in the north and 11 in the south. The northern town of Bastia was hardest hit with 15 blasts at state-run banks, a telecommunications office and an office for war veterans.</p>
<p>An office of national carrier Air France and a savings bank suffered the worst damage in the town. a bomb also damaged the Air France office in the main island town, Ajaccio.</p>
<p>Many of the blasts occurred between 4.30 a.m. and 5.30 a.m. (0330 and 0430 GMT), damaging post offices, bank and tax offices and chambers of commerce. Two unoccupied villas were targeted.</p>
<p>There were a total of 574 bomb attacks in 1996 and 602 in 1995, although prosecutors say many were linked to crime gangs.</p>
<p>Three leaders of the A Cuncolta Naziunalista, the political wing of the hardline Corsican National Liberation Front &quot;Historic Wing&quot;, are in police detention after a crackdown.</p>
<p>Last Wednesday, another faction of the FLNC, the &quot;Normal Wing&quot;, said it was renouncing violence and would rely on political campaigns to press its goals for greater autonomy.</p>
<p>On Friday, a group of 200 Corsican business leaders, ranging from hoteliers to farmers, urged the government to name a new mediator to help work out ways to alleviate an economic crisis.</p>
<p>They have rejected government measures, including wide-ranging tax breaks, as inadequate to revive the economy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AJACCIO, Corsica"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
