<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="350082" id="root" date="1997-02-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka Tamil rebels kill at least 24 soldiers.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka Tamil rebels kill at least 24 soldiers.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1997-02-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tamil Tiger rebels killed at least 24 soldiers in separate overnight attacks in Sri Lanka's north and east, military officials said on Sunday.</p>
<p>A large group of Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam (LTTE) rebels overran the Mavadivembu camp in Batticaloa district, 200 km (125 miles) from Colombo, just after midnight on Saturday killing 13 soldiers, including a lieutenant, they said.</p>
<p>Seven soldiers of the army's 6th Gajaba Regiment were wounded while five were missing after the raid in which the rebels captured weapons and burned down the camp, they said.</p>
<p>The camp was base for about 60 soldiers but one platoon of 30 was out on patrol when the rebels attacked, they said.</p>
<p>Army reinforcements managed to reach the camp by dawn, they said.</p>
<p>Casualties among the rebels, who are fighting for an independent homeland for minority Tamils in the mainly Sinhalese Indian Ocean island's north and east, were not immediately known.</p>
<p>One soldier was killed when rebels fired mortars at the nearby Sittandi army camp around the same time, they added.</p>
<p>The rebels killed 10 soldiers and wounded four in a separate attack on army defences at Vettilaikerni, in the northern Jaffna peninsula, 320 km (200 miles) north of Colombo on Saturday night, they said.</p>
<p>The spokesman for the defence ministry's operational headquarters confirmed the two attacks but had no details.</p>
<p>The LTTE was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>The government says more than 50,000 people have died in the ethnic war, now in its 14th year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
