<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="35016" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Key inmate found hanged in New York prison.</title>
<headline>Key inmate found hanged in New York prison.</headline>
<byline>Grant McCool</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The man at the centre of a battle between top New York officials over whether he should face the death penalty on charges of killing a policeman was found hanged in his cell early Thursday in an apparent suicide, authorities said.</p>
<p>Angel Diaz, 27, was discovered by a guard at the Rikers Island jail with a belt around his neck and medical staff could not revive him, prison spokesman John Mohan said. Diaz was not on a suicide watch, he said, and was therefore allowed to keep his belt and other personal items.</p>
<p>&quot;He was found at 12.45 a.m. with one end of a belt tied around his neck and the other end tied to the bars of his cell in an area of the prison where high-profile inmates are held,&quot; Rikers spokesman Mohan said. &quot;It's an apparent suicide, but the medical examiner's autopsy has yet to be made.&quot;</p>
<p>Diaz's death ended a case that had sparked an emotional public debate over capital punishment, which was reinstated by Republican Gov. George Pataki a year ago. Diaz was facing first-degree murder charges and possibly the death penalty for allegedly shooting New York City police officer Kevin Gillespie on a Bronx street March 14 after a carjacking.</p>
<p>In an unusual step, Pataki had dismissed Bronx District Attorney Robert Johnson as prosecutor of the case because of Johnson's reservations about applying the death penalty.</p>
<p>Pataki, relatively unknown until he defeated long-time Democratic Gov. Mario Cuomo in 1994 on a death penalty platform, appointed New York State Attorney General Dennis Vacco to handle the case. Vacco, another death penalty proponent, said he would seek capital punishment for Diaz, who had been indicted and was awaiting trial at the time of his death.</p>
<p>The death penalty is not mandatory in first degree murder cases in New York and gives prosecutors the option to seek life imprisonment with or without parole or capital punishment. In a battle of wills between Pataki and Johnson, the prosecutor sued the governor for reinstatement in the case of the murdered police officer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
