<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="350444" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: ALPINE SKIING-PRINCE A HIT IN SOCCER STRIP.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-PRINCE A HIT IN SOCCER STRIP.</headline>
<byline>Steve Keating</byline>
<dateline>SESTRIERE, Italy 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>He's the prince of the tail-enders, a skier with a cause, and he was back at the world championships on Monday.</p>
<p>Way back -- 62nd of the 66 racers to complete the super-G and 16.32 seconds behind winner Atle Skaardal.</p>
<p>But placings have seldom mattered to Prince Hubertus von Hohenlohe, who has competed in four Olympics and eight world championships, more than any active skier, but never finished better than 36th.</p>
<p>Alberto Tomba without the results, Von Hohenlohe, who began racing for Mexico when he was not good enough to make the Austrian team, believes it's not where you finish but how you look doing it.</p>
<p>In a black and white race suit designed to look like Juventus football club kit, complete with his name stencilled on the back, Von Hohenlohe played to the passions of the Italian crowd, most of whom had made the hour trek from Turin, the famous team's home.</p>
<p>The only change was a subtle one, replacing the sponsor Sony with 'Sono io' -- which means, &quot;it's me&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just a way to try and get the people excited because I'm not going to do it with my skiing,&quot; joked Von Hohenlohe, 38 on Sunday. &quot;And what better way than with football, this country is mad about football.</p>
<p>&quot;I just thought what can I do to be different?&quot;</p>
<p>Von Hohenlohe has made a career out of being different, the novelty of a ski racing prince bringing him notoriety and fame.</p>
<p>The only skiers photographed more in the finish area during Monday's race were home town hero Kristian Ghedina and the winner.</p>
<p>The Mexican-born son of an aristocratic European family, Von Hohenlohe inherited his title from his mother Ira Van Fuerstenburg whose royal roots stretch back to the Hapsburgs era.</p>
<p>His royal blood is also linked to the Agnellis, the billionaire Italian family that controls car giant Fiat and which brought the championships to the Italian resort that they founded in the 1930s.</p>
<p>Living the life of a jet-setter, Von Hohenlohe has posted better results in the studio than on the slopes. A singer, song writer, producer, his credits include a number four hit on various European rock charts -- a song about Andy Warhol, &quot;a close personal friend&quot;.</p>
<p>Von Hohenlohe is also, the inspirational leader of a group of perennial outsiders attempting to keep the Olympic spirit alive.</p>
<p>He has spent the last few years battling the International Ski Federation (FIS) to allow him and skiers from other non-traditional apline sport nations to keep their place in Olympic and world championship competition.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm kind of the lead figure for the small countries,&quot; said Hohenlohe. They (FIS) are doing a lot to try and push us out of this whole thing. I keep pushing in and telling them they need us all.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a cause -- they're cutting us out. Pretty soon there will only be 30 people racing in the Olympics and that's not what it was meant to be.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd like to race in Nagano but the qualification rules are a bummer.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to be ranked in the top 500 and with 80 Austrians and 100 Italians it's hard to get in there.&quot;</p>
<p>The prince has made it clear to the FIS that he and his subjects are not daredevils with a death wish but real athletes who bring colour and inspiration to the sport.</p>
<p>&quot;I was quite nervous today, I thought I would only go as far as the middle where the ice was and then stop,&quot; said Von Hohenlohe, who was injured in a crash in one of his rare World Cup appearances in Val Gardena.</p>
<p>&quot;But then I got there and decided that was not good enough and just went for it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SESTRIERE, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
