<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="350557" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLISH FINANCE MINISTER SEES 6 PCT GROWTH IN 1997.</title>
<headline>POLISH FINANCE MINISTER SEES 6 PCT GROWTH IN 1997.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's growth slowed to the estimated 6.6 percent in 1996 and is likely to fall to six percent this year, Finance Minister Grzegorz Kolodko said.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that the 1996 growth was 6.6 percent rather that six percent (as estimated by the Central Statistical Office),&quot; Kolodko said in an interview for Reuter Financial Television, taped over the weekend at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland and aired on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;This year I expect to have no less than six percent (growth),&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said investment was likely to be the main engine of growth this year. Last year, domestic consumption and investment replaced exports as the main growth agent of the Polish economy.</p>
<p>Kolodko also said that Poland was unlikely to have a balanced budget in near future, partly bacause the planned reform of the inefficient social security system will require a temporary increase in subsidies from the central budget.</p>
<p>The higher subsidy will help spin off new privately-managed pensions funds, due to gradually take part of the burden of providing social security.</p>
<p>But once the funds become opearational the subsidies to the social security system will start falling, Kolodko said. -- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
