<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="350682" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria's giant gas project looks to expand.</title>
<headline>Nigeria's giant gas project looks to expand.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Tostevin</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria's $4 billion project to liquefy and export natural gas is looking at plans to expand further while still fighting for compensation after its biggest order was cancelled.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be putting proposals to shareholders in the near future, so that we can move to expand as quickly as possible,&quot; managing director of Nigerian Liquefied Natural Gas (NLNG), Theo Oerlemans, told Reuters in an interview on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Eventually we could triple production starting from the basis of the infrastructure of the current project...How it can be done is part of the studies we are carrying out at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>NLNG, which is to produce 7.2 billion cubic metres of LNG per year from 1999, is 30 percent complete, despite facing numerous obstacles, the latest being cancellation of a huge order by Italian state power firm Enel.</p>
<p>Arbitration began after Enel in December pulled out of the contract to buy 3.5 billion cubic metres of gas per year.</p>
<p>Enel linked its decision to its abandonment for technical, economic and environmental reasons of its own project to build a terminal to receive the gas.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect full redress under the terms of the contract, under which it is very clear that we will get full compensation,&quot; Oerlemans said.</p>
<p>The project came under threat in 1995 when international lobby groups called on the partners to abandon the project over the Nigerian military government's hanging of nine minority rights activists, including author Ken Saro-Wiwa, for murder.</p>
<p>Work has proceeded apace at the project site in the Bonny region of the oil-producing southeast.</p>
<p>Africa's most populous nation has more reserves of natural gas than the crude oil on which it depends but 80 percent of the gas is currently flared.</p>
<p>&quot;The European market for LNG has a fairly fast growth rate, particularly for power generation as being more efficient and less polluting than nuclear,&quot; said Oerlemans.</p>
<p>&quot;Nigeria has huge reserves and a strategic location close to the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Shell Gas BV is the technical leader with 25.6 percent of the equity in the NLNG joint venture with state oil firm Nigerian National Petroleum Corp which has 49 percent.</p>
<p>The other partners are Elf Aquitaine with 15 percent and Italy's Agip with 10.4 percent.</p>
<p>Long-term supply contracts have been signed with Enagas of Spain, Gaz de France and Botas of Turkey.</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
