<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="350772" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: Kazakh oil barons, govt, clash on energy sell-off.</title>
<headline>Kazakh oil barons, govt, clash on energy sell-off.</headline>
<byline>Chris Bird</byline>
<dateline>ALMATY 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kazakhstan's oil barons are growing increasingly wary of the government's rapid sell-off of the former Soviet republic's vast energy sector to foreign investors, officials and analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>Saribay Kalmurzayev, chairman of Kazakhstan's State Property Committee, said in an interview with the weekly Panorama journal: &quot;The oil barons, who have long monopolised the oil wells and gas pipelines, are unlikely to voluntarily surrender these tidbits.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the republic's oil lobby was stirring up &quot;anti-privatisation&quot; propaganda.</p>
<p>The murky and unclear nature of the Central Asian state's tender system which has seen a giant sell-off of energy enterprises has sparked fears among oil workers that privatisation will mean losses of jobs and social benefits.</p>
<p>The government argues that foreign capital is the only way to halt declining production from the oil sector's ageing wells.</p>
<p>Yuzhneftegaz, with deposits of 581 million barrels of oil in central Kazakhstan, was sold to Canadian independent Hurricane Hydrocarbons Ltd for $120 million last year.</p>
<p>The government hopes to earn over $2 billion in taxes and royalties over the next 20 years from the deal.</p>
<p>But government and independent sources said that a backlash against similar sales may be in the works.</p>
<p>Oil workers at the potentially rich Mangistaumunaigaz oil and gas enterprise, located in western Kazakhstan near the Caspian Sea, say they fear foreign management and ownership and are ready to fight a sell-off.</p>
<p>&quot;The workforce is very against the tender because nowhere is it written that foreign investors should continue with social programmes,&quot; Zamanbek Nurkadilov, an influential opposition deputy in the Kazakh parliament, told Reuters after visiting the enterprise last week.</p>
<p>&quot;The enterprise feeds the region,&quot; he said, adding that around 350,000 people were dependent on the plant.</p>
<p>Oil sources say Kazakh Oil and Gas Minister Nurlan Balgimbayev may be growing wary of opening up the country's energy sector to foreign investors.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a view in the oil sector that the government is giving too much away,&quot; said one western analyst, who declined to be named. &quot;But the government has to get it into private hands so that output can increase.&quot;</p>
<p>The struggle between the barons and the government over massive energy privatisation has delayed several other oil and gas tenders, leaving large foreign oil companies unwilling to invest while the ground remains fogged.</p>
<p>The head of Mangistaumunaigaz, Mendesh Salikhov, said in an interview with Panorama that oil production at the plant had declined to 4.6 million tonnes in 1995 from 7.8 million in 1991.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;We stopped this tendency in 1996, producing about the same as 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;We have shown what we are capable of,&quot; said Salikhov, who opposes putting the enterprise up for tender.</p>
<p>Official sources said Prime Minister Akezhan Kazhegeldin would announce this week a &quot;reorganisation&quot; of Kazakhmunaigaz, a state holding company which controls the vast Central Asian nation's gas and oil sector.</p>
<p>Observers say the move is an attempt to break the backs of the Kazakh oil barons, most of whom have been in place since the Soviet era and who are opposed to surrendering control of their enterprises to foreign investors.</p>
<p>Output has declined dramatically at Kazakhstan's ageing production enterprises since independence from the Soviet Union in 1991, but the companies, particularly those in the west of the republic, sit on billions of dollars worth of oil reserves, say western oil executives.</p>
<p>Salikhov argued that oil enterprises should be given the same tax breaks as foreign companies and said he wanted to raise capital by placing shares, possibly in the form of depositary receipts, on the London or New York stock exchanges.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
