<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="350742" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania opposition rejects president's talks offer.</title>
<headline>Albania opposition rejects president's talks offer.</headline>
<byline>Crispian Balmer</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanian President Sali Berisha on Monday called for cross-party talks over the collapse of pyramid investment schemes, but his offer was immediately rejected by the main opposition alliance.</p>
<p>Berisha invited 20 political groups to hold a round table discussion on Tuesday to work out how to compensate thousands of people left destitute by the pyramid scandal.</p>
<p>Leading opposition parties, which last week joined forces in a &quot;Forum for Democracy&quot;, said they would not attend and instead renewed demands for the government to quit.</p>
<p>&quot;The Forum is not in favour of a technical solution as advanced by this round table but for a political solution,&quot; Pandeli Majko, a senior leader of the main Socialist party, said by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;We have already declared that the first step for a political solution is the resignation of the government.&quot;</p>
<p>The centre-left Social Democrat party accused Berisha, founder of the ruling right-wing Democratic Party, of staging a public relations exercise.</p>
<p>&quot;Instead of discussing the deep political and economic crisis and finding the right solutions to overcome it, Berisha is assembling parties to show people how worried he is,&quot; party leader Skender Gjinushi told Reuters.</p>
<p>Economists believe more than $1 billion is tied up in various schemes which flourished in post-communist Albania. The collapse of part of the system ignited street protests across Europe's poorest country last month.</p>
<p>A crackdown against alleged troublemakers and the threat of 15-year prison sentences for rioters deterred many would-be protesters from joining fresh demonstrations at the weekend.</p>
<p>People are now awaiting word on how they will be allowed to reclaim some of their savings.</p>
<p>The government met for several hours on Monday to discuss how to hand back some $300 million to investors from two of the pyramids whose bank assets have been frozen.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Aleksander Meksi told state television after the meeting that investors from the Xhaferri and Populli funds could go to state-owned banks on Wednesday to receive some of their trapped savings.</p>
<p>He said it had not yet been decided what percentage of their investments would be returned.</p>
<p>Staff at Tirana's main banks were plouging through ragged documents and receipts to determine how much to pay depositors.</p>
<p>Five national funds have failed since November but only two had bank assets. Berisha has warned that investors in the other three pyramids will get no compensation.</p>
<p>Albania's largest investment firm, Vefa Holdings, slashed salaries for its administrative staff by 50 percent on Monday and reduced monthly interest payments to three percent from five. Its directors deny that they operate a pyramid scheme, under which new deposits fund earlier interest bills.</p>
<p>In January, Vefa barred people from withdrawing their invested capital. It is not known exactly how much money has been sunk into the company.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as I'm concerned it has already collapsed. If the government wants, it can survive for a little while, but not for much longer,&quot; said a financial consultant who advises the World Bank, declining to be named.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
