<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="350870" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin-Chirac summit calms health fears, for now.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin-Chirac summit calms health fears, for now.</headline>
<byline>Philippa Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin resumed his convalescence on Monday after a brief foray onto the world stage which helped to calm fears about his health but brought no breakthrough in a deadlock over NATO's plans to expand.</p>
<p>The Kremlin said that Yeltsin, who met French President Jacques Chirac on Sunday, would spend this week working on papers in the official residence outside Moscow where he has been recovering from pneumonia.</p>
<p>A spokesman said his meetings would be limited but that he might have his traditional weekly consultation with Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin in the Kremlin on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Yeltsin would concentrate on preparing his annual state-of-the-nation speech to parliament, seen by analysts as the next big test of his return to health.</p>
<p>Chirac, the first western leader to see Yeltsin since he went down with double pneumonia on January 8, said he had been impressed by the speed of the Kremlin leader's recovery.</p>
<p>Political commentators said he had come as much to check on Yeltsin's health on behalf of the West as to try to find common ground on NATO's plan to issue invitations to some of Moscow's former communist-era allies in July.</p>
<p>The 66-year-old Russian President looked frail, but alert and good-humoured in television pictures of the start of the meeting, the first unedited footage of him since he fell ill.</p>
<p>Chirac said Yeltsin had been very tough in defending Russia's interests, implying that the West had been given a dressing-down over NATO expansion, but said this was natural.</p>
<p>&quot;Yeltsin's performance with Chirac was certainly very reassuring,&quot; said Andrei Piontkovsky, a political analyst from the Moscow Centre for Strategic Studies.</p>
<p>He said it was much more convincing than the carefully controlled coverage of a recent visit to the Kremlin and should help to calm speculation about Yeltsin's ability to rule.</p>
<p>&quot;Now it seems that we have seen him returning to duty and there is no immediate prospect of presidential elections.&quot;</p>
<p>He did not see Yeltsin's return to his residence outside Moscow as a cause for concern, putting it down to Kremlin caution after an early return to work in the wake of heart surgery in November ended in pneumonia after two weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;If it is just a stage towards returning to his normal duties then it will be okay,&quot; Piontkovsky said by telephone.</p>
<p>A western diplomat said he thought the caution evident in Monday's statement from the Kremlin was a new tactic from officials who had had their fingers burned with over-optimism.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe now they are trying to lower expectations so they can make the most of it if he pops up unexpectedly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Kremlin appeared short of new tactics in the tussle over plans by the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation to take in new members from among Moscow's former Warsaw Pact allies.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's tough line is part of a campaign of rhetoric which some analysts say hides a lack of any constructive ideas. &quot;I don't see any clear-cut policy from the Russian side. They are just complaining,&quot; said Piontkovsky.</p>
<p>&quot;Time is running out and nobody knows what to do. Our negative rhetoric has pushed us into a corner,&quot; he said, urging Moscow to come up with specific proposals to boost its security rather than railing against what he said was a fait accompli.</p>
<p>Chirac said the manoeuvring was natural and that he felt an accord was possible if both sides were prepared to compromise.</p>
<p>But when pressed on Yeltsin's health he went on the defensive. &quot;He has had an operation and it is natural that he has taken a while to recover,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I saw the Boris Nikolayevich I have always known.&quot;</p>
<p>Russia's NTV television was wary. &quot;Despite such statements by the French president, discussion about Boris Yeltsin's health is unlikely to stop until he is back at work full time.&quot;</p>
<p>The opposition-dominated parliament has used Yeltsin's illness to increase pressure on him to step down. One said on Monday he would continue his bid to unseat the president.</p>
<p>Viktor Ilyukhin, the communist chairman of the lower house of parliament's security committee, said he would press parliamentary leaders on Tuesday to put his motion calling for Yeltsin to step down back on the chamber's agenda.</p>
<p>A previous discussion of the motion -- which has little chance of success -- ended in farce on January 22 when deputies voted without being sure what they were voting for.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
