<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="351038" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil won't slow economy before March - paper.</title>
<headline>Brazil won't slow economy before March - paper.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian policy-makers will wait until March before deciding whether to slow growth to relieve pressure on external accounts, Central Bank President Gustavo Loyola told Jornal do Brasil.</p>
<p>&quot;At this moment we are not seeing a need to put a brake on the economy... The numbers are still incomplete,&quot; Loyola told the newspaper in an interview.  &quot;We are going to wait until February, March to determine the pace of consumption.&quot;</p>
<p>Brazil's current account and trade deficits soared last year due to a rapid growth in imports.  For the past five months, economists have suggested that the government would have to intervene in the first quarter of 1997 to ease consumption in order to preserve the health of its external accounts.</p>
<p>Loyola said that if measures were taken, they would be limited to credit restrictions.  He ruled out any tinkering with the current foreign exchange rate system to slow imports.</p>
<p>&quot;Our position is that the exchange rate is not an export-promotion tool,&quot; Loyola said.</p>
<p>((--John Miller, Sao Paulo newsroom, 5511 248-5414))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
