<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="35134" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole loses key advisers; poll shows Clinton surge.</title>
<headline>Dole loses key advisers; poll shows Clinton surge.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, U.S. Political Correspondent</p>
<p>Republican candidate Bob Dole lost two top consultants on Thursday in a new blow to his struggling campaign as a Reuters poll suggested President Bill Clinton could be heading for an election rout.</p>
<p>Don Sipple and Mike Murphy, the two men charged with creating Dole's crucial political advertisements, quit in what appeared to be an internal power struggle with campaign manager Scott Reed.</p>
<p>&quot;A strategic decision was made to bring the ad group ... more directly into the overall campaign structure under Scott Reed,&quot; campaign spokesman Nelson Warfield said.</p>
<p>Warfield tried to put the best face on the shakeup, describing it as a &quot;move forward in the creative process.&quot; But it suggested a campaign in some disarray, seemingly unable to close a yawning gap in the polls with Clinton.</p>
<p>The Dole campaign was to begin airing soon a five-minute commercial crafted by Sipple to reintroduce the candidate to the American people as a man of personal sacrifice.</p>
<p>A new Reuters poll conducted by John Zogby Group International found Clinton leading by 15 percentage points among likely voters after receiving a double boost, first from last week's Democratic convention and then from his decision to order air strikes against Iraq.</p>
<p>With two months to go to Election Day on Nov. 5, Clinton led Dole by 48.2 to 33.3 percent. Texas billionaire Ross Perot, the candidate of his own Reform Party, had 5.9 percent.</p>
<p>Clinton now leads among every income group, every ethnic group, every age group and in every region of the country. He leads by 10 points among men and 19 points among women. He also leads on 10 of 12 top campaign issues.</p>
<p>&quot;As the campaign officially starts, this is an impressive lead for Clinton, and given his remarkable dominance among most sub-groups, this has the potential for a rout similar to those in 1964, 1972 and 1984,&quot; pollster John Zogby said.</p>
<p>President Lyndon Johnson swamped Republican Barry Goldwater in 1964, winning more than 61 percent of the popular vote. Presidents Richard Nixon and Ronald Reagan each won 49 of the 50 states in their election triumphs of 1972 and 1984.</p>
<p>In more bad news for Dole, a new poll in the most populous state of California showed Clinton leading him by a huge 22 percentage points, 55 to 33 percent.</p>
<p>Clinton meanwhile campaigned in Florida, a state no Democratic presidential candidate has won since Jimmy Carter in 1976 but where polls show he is slightly ahead of Dole.</p>
<p>The president sounded familiar themes on education in his first speech in Tampa, including hooking school rooms up to the international web of computers on the Internet and a $10,000 tax break for college tuition.</p>
<p>&quot;A big part of building a bridge to the 21st century is building a bridge big enough to give every single boy and girl in America a chance to live up to their God-given abilities,&quot; he told several hundred students at a high school.</p>
<p>He was to head later to Broward County near Miami to speak to senior citizens on health care and his support for a bill to bar health maintenance organisations from restricting what treatment procedures doctors may discuss with patients.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
