<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="351395" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hilton Hotels sees links with ITT operations.</title>
<headline>Hilton Hotels sees links with ITT operations.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hilton Hotels Corp said its plan for ITT Corp would likely call for combining some facilities as part of its cost-savings goal.</p>
<p>In a presentation to investors at a Montgomery Securities hospitality conference, Hilton Chief Financial Officer Matthew Hart said he anticipated uniting kitchen, laundry facilities and hiring centers.</p>
<p>&quot;We see lots of opportunity for those kinds of things,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Hilton, which last week made a $6.5 billion hostile bid for ITT, has estimated annual cost savings of $100 million from the proposed union.</p>
<p>ITT's board of directors is slated to consider the bid at a Tuesday meeting but is not expected to make a decision on the $55 per share cash and stock offer.</p>
<p>Hart declined to discuss how much Hilton would be willing to raise its offer.  The company last week said it would consider a higher bid if it won access to ITT's financial data.  </p>
<p>&quot;We've put a strong offer on the table and we'll wait for a response,&quot; said Marc Grossman, senior vice president of corporate affairs.</p>
<p>He also would not comment on specific plans for ITT's $3 billion capital expansion program.  In announcing its offer last week, Hilton said a substantial portion of the spending would be unneccesary if the two companies merged.</p>
<p>Hilton is widely expected to appeal to ITT's shareholders in the proposed transaction.  ITT's stock has fallen sharply in recent months and the offer made by Hilton represents a 29 percent premium over its recent stock price.</p>
<p>Hart would not discuss whether Hilton has begun meeting with ITT shareholders.</p>
<p>Over the weekend, ITT chairman Rand Araskog rejected an offer to meet with Hilton chief executive Stephen Bollenbach.</p>
<p>((--Robin Sidel, 212/859-1723))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
