<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="351436" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton praises Fujimori for walking &quot;fine line&quot;.</title>
<headline>Clinton praises Fujimori for walking &quot;fine line&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton praised Peruvian President Alberto Fujimori on Monday for walking a &quot;very fine line&quot; on the hostage crisis in Lima without giving in to the hostage-takers, the White House said.</p>
<p>&quot;The president told President (Alberto) Fujimori that he was skilfully walking a very fine line ... between resolving this crisis peacefully without giving in to terror,&quot; White House spokesman David Johnson told reporters after Fujimori had visited the White House for talks with Clinton.  </p>
<p>&quot;He (Clinton) told him (Fujimori) that it is a hard line to walk, but it's the right one,&quot; Johnson added.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the two presidents had met for about 20 minutes at the White House, with Vice President Al Gore, Secretary of State Madeleine Albright and National Security Adviser Samuel Berger attending. Fujimori was visiting Washington after discussing the hostage crisis with Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto in Toronto on Saturday.</p>
<p>Johnson said Fujimori had thanked Clinton for his support and told him that &quot;Peru intended to continue to be careful and to be patient as it worked to try to resolve this.&quot;</p>
<p>On Dec. 17, a group of Marxist guerrillas took more than 500 people hostage during a cocktail party at the Japanese ambassador's residence in Lima. Seventy-two hostages remain in the booby-trapped residence, including two Peruvian ministers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
