<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="351450" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gore-Chernomyrdin talks face difficult agenda.</title>
<headline>Gore-Chernomyrdin talks face difficult agenda.</headline>
<byline>Laurence McQuillan</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vice President Al Gore and Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin meet this week for talks on contentious issues like NATO expansion and arms control -- items left unresolved in part because of Boris Yeltsin's lingering illness.</p>
<p>Gore and Chernomyrdin begin two days of talks on Thursday with plans to review a range of such matters and possibly work out details of a planned summit between President Bill Clinton and Russia's President Yeltsin.</p>
<p>The so-called Gore-Chernomyrdin Commission, which meets every six months, was designed to do away with barriers left over from the Cold War era by having Cabinet-level committees work out accords on economic and technological issues.</p>
<p>It has evolved into a key channel for diplomatic business between Washington and Moscow, especially in light of the health problems that have recently sidelined Yeltsin.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now the Gore-Chernomyrdin channel is sort of the main stem in the U.S.-Russian senior level discussions,&quot; said Helmut Sonnenfeldt, who served in foreign policy posts for Republican Presidents Richard Nixon and Gerald Ford.</p>
<p>&quot;Because it is more difficult for the president to communicate with the Russian president except to send get-well messages ... the Gore-Chernomyrdin channel, has become more utilized for the presidential-level issues like the expansion of NATO and the future of nuclear (arms) agreements,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The extra diplomatic dimension this time includes trying to work out dates and venue for a Clinton-Yeltsin summit planned for March.</p>
<p>Officials said Clinton, host of this summit, will offer to meet Yeltsin at a neutral site or in Russia if necessary in light of health problems hobbling the Russian leader. He is recovering from heart surgery and, more recently, pneumonia.</p>
<p>&quot;This (summit plans) may not be resolved&quot; by Gore and Chernomyrdin, a senior official said, &quot;but we hope, at least, to have a pretty good idea of what will happen ... Obviously Yeltsin's health will make the final decision.&quot;</p>
<p>Gore and Chernomyrdin also will discuss NATO's decision to expand eastward by opening membership to some former members of the Soviet bloc, a move Moscow opposes but is coming to accept as inevitable.</p>
<p>The alliance meets in Madrid in July and is expected to invite Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic to join.</p>
<p>The United States also has been pressing for Russian ratification of START-II, a landmark treaty that would reduce the huge land-based nuclear arsenals of the Cold War.</p>
<p>Washington hopes to make progress on such issues without underminging Yeltsin, who has been urged to resign by rivals.</p>
<p>The commission -- officially the U.S.-Russian Joint Commission on Economic and Technological Cooperation -- dates from 1993 and alternates meetings between Washington and Moscow.</p>
<p>Its eight Cabinet-level committees have produced more than 140 agreements ranging from defence conversion and space to ending barriers to business development and trade.</p>
<p>A senior administration official who has participated in each of its eight previous meetings and will be involved in this round too, said the talks often are blunt but honest.</p>
<p>According to several current and past participants, the effectiveness of the group stems in large measure from the fact that Gore and Chernomyrdin have enough clout to force compliance by reluctant bureaucrats.</p>
<p>&quot;In the past, it was a lot like watching a huge rocket on a pad belching fire but we kept on waiting for liftoff,&quot; said one high-level U.S. official. &quot;Now we've got the sense things are actually moving.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
