<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="351524" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian shares close off depressed by EMU worries.</title>
<headline>Italian shares close off depressed by EMU worries.</headline>
<text>
<p>1630 GMT - Italian shares closed easier weighed down by the debate over whether Italy will make the first wave of nations into Europe's economic and monetary union while lower domestic bonds and an easier Wall Street kept buyers cautious.</p>
<p>* German doubts over Italy's entry to EMU in 1999 depressed the early mood on the Milan bourse despite the efforts of prime minister Romano Prodi over the weekend to reassure investors of Italy's commitment to joining EMU. Shares in Olivetti and Fiat bucked the trend and ended firmer.</p>
<p>* All-share Mibtel index ended off 1.05 percent at 12,289 with the blue-chip Mib30 index 1.36 percent easier at 18,262.  </p>
<p>* Dealers pointed out that German doubts on Italy's early membership of EMU kept international investors away from the market, although optimism over the metalworker talks helped stocks off their worse level of the day.</p>
<p>* Earlier, Labour Minister Tiziano Treu said he believed a new government proposal to end the metalworkers pay dispute would be acceptable to both unions and employers following all-night talks between unions, employers and government.</p>
<p>* Fiat shares gained 2.22 percent to 5,256 lire on optimism over the talks which replaced the negative mood after Thursday's 1996 figures which showed a sharp fall in operating profits.  </p>
<p>* Olivetti bounced up 4.11 percent to 648.1 lire, while banking group Credito Italiano was 3.18 percent firmer at 2,269 lire after better than expected preliminary 1996 results on Friday. San Paolo was off 0.9 percent at 11,025 lire after its privatisation plans were released late last week.</p>
<p>* Telephone director publisher Seat was up 1.19 percent at 621.3 following a newspaper report that four groups were interested in bidding for the Treasury's 61 percent stake.</p>
<p>* Other stocks were lower with ENI off 1.65 percent at 8,824 lire, Pirelli down 0.86 percent at 3,554 lire and telecom stock down led by Telecom Italia down 2.95 percent at 4,511 lire.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
