<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="351625" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: OPINION - WEEKLY TECHNICAL ANALYSIS OF BOMBAY SHARE INDEX.</title>
<headline>OPINION - WEEKLY TECHNICAL ANALYSIS OF BOMBAY SHARE INDEX.</headline>
<text>
<p>BE ALERT FOR A MINOR BOTTOM FORMATION BETWEEN 3318-3262</p>
<p>is a trend analysis of the 30-share Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) index for the period February 3-7 by analyst Mehmood Khan at Times Guaranty Financials Ltd</p>
<p>								 -----oOo-----</p>
<p>Trading for the week ended on a pessimistic note, with a loss of 53.15 points (1.55 percent) at 3382.47 levels over the previous week. The BSE National was close with 24.63 points (1.64 percent). The market commenced the week, on a strong note, but the higher levels (3645.35) could not be maintained due to offloading of speculative positions.</p>
<p>At 3361.25 levels, the Sensex has corrected the rally of 1099.19 points (2713.12 to 3812.31) by 41.04 percent. Since the corrective move has broken, the vital support of 38.20 percent, it has became eminent that the minor bottom of 3342.89 (formed on January 17, 1997) would be broken and a new bottom may be formed between 3310-3260 levels. The mechanical indicators are on the verge of exhibiting a minor bottom formation on Monday/Tuesday that may be marginally higher than the 200 Weeks moving average which is placed at 3205.50 levels. The Sensex moves into the CIT.(Change In Trend) time window from February 03, 1997. It may form a down day on Monday or Tuesday but significant buying may</p>
<p>With the index already in the level and time zones of turn, it is time to look into the macro patterns for any signs of reversal. A reversal has already been signalled on Friday with the formation of a hammer candlestick pattern and a fade bar which usually occurs at the end of a trend. As per the Time Logic analysis, the decline (from 3812.31) is 12 trading days old. The cluster of time logic support the bottom formation on February 3/4 1997. The corrective down move is 3 trading days old, may lose momentum on February 3, 1997, the target for the downside can be placed at 3310-3260 levels.</p>
<p>The correctionary trend in ACC, Andhra Valley, Ashok Leyland, Ballarpur, BHEL, Century Textiles, Glaxo, Hindustan Motors, IDBI, IFCI, IPCL, ITC Bhadra, ITC, L&amp;T, MTNL, SCICI, Sterlite, TISCO Tata Power, Tata Tea and Mastergain 92 are indicating losing momentum on the weekly chart. These counters may seek lower values in the initial half of the week, but may witness buying interest in due course and may probably close the week on a strong note. The best trading opportunity for the week's trading is to be on the long side from Tuesday with a stop-loss of 3234 levels.</p>
<p>The price following oscillators on the weekly bar chart are exhibiting that the bottom may be formed at 3310-3260 levels - Relative Strength (RSI) is 54.41, Price Rate of Change (ROC) is placed at 7.43, short term stochastic is hovering at 55.54 and its trigger line is at 64.88, while the medium term stochastic is 77.35 and the trigger is 68.73, the Macd is -23.74 and the trigger is -64.88 and the 14 William's percent R is placed at -39.11. The mechanical oscillators justify that the minor correction from 3645.35 may lose momentum at 3310-3260 levels.</p>
<p>For the current week, the BSE Sensex may find support at 3331, 3305 and 3262 levels, on the higher end it may encounter resistance at 3425-3465 levels. The National Index may witness buying interest at 1440-1425 levels and resistance at 1495 and 1540 levels.</p>
<p>(The opinions expressed in this article reflect the views of the author only. They should not be taken as reflecting the views of Reuters).</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
