<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="351725" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Key facts about Pakistan.</title>
<headline>Key facts about Pakistan.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-02-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the key facts about Pakistan, where elections for the National Assembly and four provincial assemblies are scheduled for February 3:</p>
<p>Population: Officially estimated at 131.6 million in 1996 and growing by at least 2.8 percent a year.</p>
<p>Pakistan is an Islamic nation in which Sunni Moslems form the majority. About 15 per cent of Pakistanis are Shias, the main branch of Islam in neighbouring Iran. Christians, Hindus, Parsees and Buddhists form just over three per cent of the population. Some 1.2 million Afghan refugees live in Pakistan.</p>
<p>Area: 796,095 square km (307,293 square miles). Pakistan is bordered by Iran and Afghanistan to the west, China to the north and India to the east. Karachi, with about 12 million people, is its largest city and main port on the Arabian Sea.</p>
<p>Capital: Islamabad.</p>
<p>Armed forces: Army -- 520,000 men, 2,050 tanks, 20 attack helicopters. Air force -- 45,000 men, 430 combat aircraft, including F-16s. Navy -- 22,000 men, nine submarines, three destroyers, eight frigates, 13 missile/torpedo/patrol craft, four combat aircraft and 12 armed helicopters. (International Institute for Strategic Studies, London).</p>
<p>Economy: Gross National Product in 1995/96 (provisional figure from Federal Bureau of Statistics) 2,188 billion rupees ($65 billion). Annual per capita income 16,623 rupees ($495).</p>
<p>Pakistan receives loans worth more than $2 billion a year from multilateral donors and industrialised countries. Main exports are cotton, textiles and rice. Main imports are machinery, oil and oil products, chemicals and edible oil.</p>
<p>In recent years Pakistan has sought to liberalise its economy, privatise state concerns and woo foreign investment.</p>
<p>Modern history: Pakistan came into being on August 14, 1947, carved out of Moslem-majority areas of the British-ruled Indian sub-continent. Two wings, West Pakistan (present-day Pakistan) and East Pakistan (now Bangladesh) were separated by about 1,600 km (1,000 miles) of Indian territory.</p>
<p>East Pakistan declared independence in 1971 after a bitter civil war sparked by an election which proved divisive.</p>
<p>Pakistan and India fought border wars in 1947-48, 1965 and 1971. The first two were caused by the Kashmir dispute. When Pakistani troops surrendered in East Pakistan in 1971, Zulfikar Ali Bhutto became the first leader of present-day Pakistan.</p>
<p>Bhutto, the first civilian leader following military rule by Field Marshal Mohammad Ayub Khan (1958-69) and General Mohammad Yayha Khan (1969-71), was himself toppled by army chief General Mohammad Zia-ul-Haq in July 1977.</p>
<p>Bhutto was hanged in April 1979 on a disputed conviction for conspiring to commit a political murder.</p>
<p>Zia held non-party elections in February 1985. He named Mohammad Khan Junejo as prime minister and lifted martial law in December that year. Zia and many of his top military aides died on August 17, 1988, when his plane crashed near Bahawalpur.</p>
<p>Pakistan returned to party-based democracy when Bhutto's daughter Benazir and her Pakistan People's Party won 39 per cent of the votes in November 1988 elections.</p>
<p>Bhutto, then 35, was sworn in on December 2, the first woman woman elected to power in a Moslem state. But she was hamstrung by political constraints, corruption charges and a power struggle with the opposition led by Nawaz Sharif.</p>
<p>On August 6, 1990 President Ghulam Ishaq Khan sacked Bhutto's government. Ghulam Mustafa Jatoi was named caretaker prime minister until general elections in October 1990.</p>
<p>Nawaz Sharif's Islamic Democratic Alliance won the election against Bhutto's People's Democratic Alliance, amid vote-rigging allegations. He resigned as prime minister in July 1993.</p>
<p>Bhutto was re-elected in October 1993 to head a coalition government soon beset by economic woes and corruption charges.</p>
<p>On November 5, 1996, President Farooq Leghari sacked Bhutto, dissolved parliament and called elections for February 3, 1997.</p>
<p>Relations with arch-rival India, which had begun to improve under Bhutto, slumped in early 1990 as a Moslem rebellion flared in the two-thirds of Kashmir ruled by New Delhi.</p>
<p>Islamabad denies Indian charges that it gives guns and money to Kashmiri rebels seeking unity with Pakistan or independence.</p>
<p>Pakistan let Afghan mujahideen guerrillas operate from its territory during the decade-long Soviet occupation in the 1980s and funnelled arms to them from Western and Arab states.</p>
<p>Its influence has waned since guerrilla factions toppled a communist government in 1992 and began a civil war. Pakistan denies charges that it helps the purist Islamic Taleban militia that captured Kabul on September 27, 1996.</p>
<p>Traditionally a close, if prickly, ally of the United States, Pakistan became the third biggest recipient of U.S. aid after the Soviet intervention in Afghanistan in 1979.</p>
<p>But after the 1989 Soviet withdrawal, Washington suspended aid in October 1990 because of suspicion about Pakistan's nuclear programme. Pakistan denies it has nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>The United States eased sanctions in 1996 to allow delivery of some of the $1.4 billion of blocked equipment, but continued to withhold 28 F-16 fighters Pakistan had paid for.</p>
<p>Pakistan sent 11,000 troops to help defend Saudi Arabia before the 1991 Gulf War, despite popular support for Iraqi leader Saddam Hussain. It is now a major contributor of troops to U.N. peace-keeping operations around the world.</p>
<p>Pakistan is a member of the United Nations, the Non-Aligned Movement, the Islamic Conference Organisation, and the South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
