<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="351732" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Investment trend down in US, Europe, rises in Asia.</title>
<headline>Investment trend down in US, Europe, rises in Asia.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Multinational firms are expected to shift some investments from the United States and Western Europe to Asia followed by Latin America and eastern Europe, said a French government survey released on Monday.</p>
<p>In Asia, China, followed by Indonesia, Thailand and Malaysia are expected to attract the largest foreign investments over the next five years, according to Fabrice Hatem of France's Ministry of Economic Affairs.</p>
<p>His report said Africa and the Middle East had little appeal for multinational corporations because of &quot;perceived political risk&quot; and limited growth prospects compared to other developing countries.</p>
<p>The exceptions were South Africa and six North African countries bordering the Mediterranean.</p>
<p>The study, which included interviews with 310 international corporations and experts, was conducted by the ministry's Study Centre on International Investment in collaboration with the U.N. Centre for Trade and Development.</p>
<p>It predicted a rapid increase in foreign direct investment flows, both in absolute terms and as a proportion of corporate investment budgets. The companies were shifting sales, production and services abroad but keeping &quot;core&quot; functions such as research and decision-making at home.</p>
<p>Currently more than half of total global foreign investment is concentrated in Western Europe and North America.</p>
<p>&quot;Since 1992, however, there has been a marked shift in favour of developing economies, which captured 40 percent of worldwide inflows in 1993-1994,&quot; Hatem told reporters.</p>
<p>Asian economies, particularly China, were expected to reap the largest share in the developing world. But investment was expected to rise also in Argentina, Brazil, Chile and Mexico as well as Central and Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>So far the increase has mainly benefited China and members of the Association of Southeast Asian nations but India and Vietnam are expected to reap some benefits as conditions for foreign investments improve there.</p>
<p>The attraction for multinational are huge markets, moderate regulation, prospects for rapid growth -- and low labour costs coupled with improving technical skills.</p>
<p>The report warned that obstacles remained, including an &quot;uncertain regulatory environment &quot; and &quot;inadequate protection&quot; for intellectual property rights in China.</p>
<p>Despite this trend, the United States and Canada as well as Western Europe were expected to remain a priority for foreign companies in the near future.</p>
<p>The United States offered an expanding economy, a skilled flexible workforce, expertise in advanced technology and a highly liquid stock market, the study said.</p>
<p>Western Europe, which has attracted most foreign direct investment over the past 10 years, is expected to remain steady for the next five years but not increase dramatically.</p>
<p>&quot;The consequences of the move to economic and monetary union are a positive factor,&quot; the report said of Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;On the other hand, commonly cited drawbacks include modest growth prospects, along with levels of tax and welfare levies that are generally considered excessive,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
