<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="351745" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Alcatel finds allies for Thomson bid.</title>
<headline>Alcatel finds allies for Thomson bid.</headline>
<byline>Marcel Michelson</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alcatel Alsthom said on Monday it was in talks with Aerospatiale and Dassault about a joint offer for the government's 58-percent stake in defence electronics group Thomson-CSF .</p>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe said a decision about the procedure for the privatisation of Thomson-CSF would be made before the end of February.</p>
<p>&quot;There are discussions with the companies mentioned in the press,&quot; an Alcatel spokesman said when asked to react to newspaper reports about a joint bid.</p>
<p>Industry sources said that Alcatel chairman Serge Tchuruk had kept the government informed about his plans to form an alliance with Aerospatiale and Dassault in order to win the Thomson-CSF stake.</p>
<p>An industry analyst, who prefered not to be named, said the new plan improved the credibility of Alcatel's offer.</p>
<p>Alcatel in October lost out to the Lagardere Groupe in bidding for state-controlled Thomson SA, which has a stake in Thomson-CSF as well as 100 percent of consumer electronics group Thomson Multimedia (TMM).</p>
<p>But the government had to suspend the sale on December 4 after the independent Privatisation Commission rejected terms for the sale by Lagardere of TMM to Daewoo Electronics of South Korea.</p>
<p>A decision about the procedure for the relaunch of the sale, either by a private placement or a public sale, was originally expected at the end of January.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that in the days to come, between now and the end of February, we will be in a position to announce very clearly the procedure, which I want to be as clear and as transparent as possible,&quot; Juppe said in an interview on French radio.</p>
<p>&quot;All candidacies will obviously be examined in the context of the procedures we decide on,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dassault and Aerospatiale, which are currently in talks about a merger of their aircraft activities, had no comment.</p>
<p>President Jacques Chirac said a year ago that he wanted to restructure the French defence industry around a merger of Aerospatiale/Dassault and Thomson-CSF.</p>
<p>A joint bid by the aerospace group and Alcatel would speed up this restructuring. But the situation could be difficult because Aerospatiale is state-owned and the state would be the main shareholder of the merged group with Dassault.</p>
<p>&quot;It is complicated but not impossible,&quot; an industry source said.</p>
<p>According to French newspapers, Aerospatiale would transfer its missiles and satellites business to Thomson-CSF and Dassault its electronics activties, now part of Dassault Electronique.</p>
<p>Alcatel would merge its own defence activities into Thomson-CSF. It would become the main shareholder of the enlarged group which would be Europe's biggest defence company and the world's third biggest after Lockheed Martin and Boeing-McDonnell Douglas Corp.</p>
<p>At Lagardere Groupe there was no immediate comment.</p>
<p>Lagardere shares closed 1.59 percent lower at 154.70 francs on the news of the strengthened Alcatel bid. Alcatel, which rose strongly last week, closed 1.09 percent lower at 542 francs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
