<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="351908" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Feb 3.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Feb 3.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following stories were reported in Monday's electronic version of The Wall Street Journal:</p>
<p>* Apple Computer is considering selling some key business units to cut costs amid slower-than-expected sales of its Macintosh computers.</p>
<p>* The U.S. economy expanded at 4.7 percent annually in the 1996 fourth quarter, but the government's broadest gauge of inflation remains at 1.8 percent.</p>
<p>* Pacific Gas &amp; Electric said it will buy the natural gas business of Valero Energy for $722.5 million in stock.</p>
<p>* Mercury Finance faces new demands for larger payments this week after the company failed to repay $17 million of commercial debt last week.</p>
<p>* China and the U.S. agreed to renew a textile trade pact, but this is unlikely to narrow the nearly $40 billion trade deficit the U.S. has with China.</p>
<p>* U.S. auto makers are renewing complaints that the strong dollar is putting them at a disadvantage with Japanese rivals, who are expected to show strong gains in January's light vehicle sales in the U.S.</p>
<p>* ITT Corp rejected an offer from Hilton Hotels to discuss the $6.5 billion unsolicited bid for ITT that Hilton launched last week.</p>
<p>* An investment group that includes Chile's Infisa SA, Chase Manhattan and National Bank of Canada plans to invest $750 million to acquire Latin American financial companies and form a pan-Latin American financial firm.</p>
<p>* DynCorp has won a major military contract sought by Halliburton's Brown &amp; Root unit.</p>
<p>* Scotsman Industries has agreed to buy most of Kysor Industrial for about $300 million.</p>
<p>* Rockwell International is seeking to flood the market with new computer chips to beat rival U.S. Robotics in the high-speed computer modem industry.</p>
<p>* Revised &quot;circuit breakers&quot; to stop panic-driven sell-offs are scheduled to go into effect Monday.</p>
<p>* Coca-Cola reported its fourth quarter net rose 18 percent.</p>
<p>* Faced by allegations of discrimination, Nationwide Insurance Enterprise said it will revise underwriting standards to expand investment in poor urban areas.</p>
<p>* There could be smaller profits for U.S. meatpackers and higher consumer prices as cattle ranchers shrink herds to cut two years of widening losses.</p>
<p>* Nintendo America is competing closely with Sony Computer Entertainment America as the top-selling video game player.</p>
<p>* The chairman of Systems of Excellence was to sentenced to prison amid charges of market manipulation.</p>
<p>* When Seagram's Edgar Bronfman Jr in early 1995 bought control of the blundering MCA entertainment company -- now Universal Studios -- many investors dismissed him as a dilettante movie buff and part-time songwriter, unequal to the exacting world of Hollywood. Seagram's stock dropped like a stone.</p>
<p>	 But since then, the 41-year-old scion of the Canadian</p>
<p>liquor barons has turned around the MCA music group and revived its theme parks. -- Heard on the Street.</p>
<p>* As if the Fed needed any more help taming inflation, it just got a new tool, one that will likely prove useful to investors as well.</p>
<p>The new tool? The Treasury Department's long-awaited &quot;inflation-indexed&quot; securities that went on sale last Wednesday to a rousing reception from investors. -- Credit Markets.</p>
<p>- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
