<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="351946" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: European stocks mostly slip but DAX hits record.</title>
<headline>European stocks mostly slip but DAX hits record.</headline>
<byline>David Stamp</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>European shares slipped on Monday -- except in Germany -- as interest rate jitters and a weaker Wall Street encouraged profit-taking after last week's record highs.</p>
<p>The dollar eased as both equity and foreign exchange markets nervously awaited a U.S. Federal Reserve committee meeting for any news of rate hikes.</p>
<p>Economists expect no rises when monetary authorities meet on both sides of the Atlantic this week, including the two-day meeting of the Federal Open Market Committee (FMOC) starting on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But neither is anybody taking chances, in London and Paris at least, before Tuesday's third anniversary of an unexpected U.S. rate hike which sent share prices tumbling world wide.</p>
<p>Uncertainty dampened both British and French stocks, which had closed at record highs on Friday.</p>
<p>By mid afternoon on Monday, London's FTSE-100 index was down 19.8 points at 4,256 while in Paris, the CAC-40 was off 16.14 at 2,500.42.</p>
<p>Stuart Weatherby, economist at Panmure Gordon, said British investors were beginning to focus on the approaching company results season and the effect of a strong pound on exporters, while still worrying about interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;I still get the impression that interest rates will not be going up either in the UK or the U.S.&quot; Weatherby said. &quot;Although I think they should do, in both.&quot;</p>
<p>German shares were the notable exception. The blue chip DAX-30 index ended the floor session up 27.14 points, or 0.9 percent, at an all-time high of 3,062.29 while March DTB DAX futures were up 20.5 points at 3,069.5.</p>
<p>Dealers said that the gains were achieved on relatively thin volumes, mainly led by dollar-sensitive firms like Daimler-Benz AG as the U.S. currency traded firmly above 1.64 marks, but they said the broader market was cautious.</p>
<p>German investors largely ignored a lower opening on Wall Street, whose faltering performance on Friday also helped encourage the London and Paris profit-taking.</p>
<p>After an hour's trading on Monday, the Dow Jones industrial average was down 42.33 points or 0.62 percent at 6,770.76.</p>
<p>The dollar slipped from its intraday highs, after data from U.S. purchasing managers, although it remained above levels late on Friday in Europe.</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.6449 marks and 121.82 yen at mid afternoon, weaker than in the morning but up from 1.6365 marks and 121.12 yen in late European trade on Friday.</p>
<p>Dealers were also keeping an eye on a meeting of deputy finance ministers from the Group of Seven (G7) industrial nations in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>The deputy ministers are preparing the agenda for a meeting of G7 finance ministers and central bank governors at the weekend.</p>
<p>A report from the European statistics agency Eurostat, which assessed accounting practices European Union governments have used to meet the criteria for monetary union (EMU), had little effect on the mark.</p>
<p>It said that central bank gold sales could not be used for cutting deficits to meet criteria laid down in the Maastricht treaty.</p>
<p>But gold bounced up about $1.00 after the Eurostat report. Dealers said the news confused market but did not erase fears of future central bank sales. By late afternoon it was at $345.60 an ounce, up $1 from Friday's late European level.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1520 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.6449 marks and 121.82 yen, up from 1.6365 marks and 121.12 yen in late European trade on Friday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1520 GMT</p>
<p>LONDON - The FTSE-100 index was down 19.8 points at 4,256.0.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - The 30-share DAX index closed up 27.14 points at a record high of 3,062.29.</p>
<p>PARIS - The CAC-40 was down 16.14 at 2,500.42.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS - Gold was at $345.60 an ounce after being fixed at $343.75 and against $345.50 previously. Silver was at $4.88, down four cents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
