<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="351922" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>Belgium: SPANISH KING SEES EU POLITICAL WEAKNESS.</title>
<headline>SPANISH KING SEES EU POLITICAL WEAKNESS.</headline>
<dateline>LEUVEN, Belgium 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's King Juan Carlos said on Monday the European Union's success as an international economic force contrasted with its weakness as a political power able to stop tragedy in other parts of the world.</p>
<p>The Spanish King was speaking at a ceremony attended by Belgium's King Albert II and Queen Paola at the historic Catholic University of Leuven, near Brussels, which awarded him an honorary doctorate for his defence of democracy and humanity.</p>
<p>Police said they had earlier detained 10 students trying to enter the ceremonial hall to distribute left wing texts.</p>
<p>&quot;When Yugoslavia fell apart, it was made clear to us in a very cruel way how limited Europe's political influence is outside its own borders, in an area where barbaric practices abound,&quot; King Juan Carlos said in an acceptance speech which focused on the past and future development of Europe.</p>
<p>Similarly, he added, neither the EU nor the international community had been able to prevent genocide in the central African Great Lakes region around Rwanda.</p>
<p>&quot;These examples show clearly that the existing mechanisms must be improved by means of tighter collaboration, leading to improved efficiency,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Talking of the planned single European currency, due to begin in 1999, the Spanish King said member states must continue their efforts to facilitate a &quot;healthy and convincing start&quot;.</p>
<p>But governments must also make sure these efforts led to &quot;new and better opportunities for our citizens, without negative consequences for the most vulnerable parts of our population&quot;, he said, referring to the problem of unemployment as a priority.</p>
<p>Meanwhile the process of European integration - in order to bring peace and prosperity in Europe - called for both efforts within Europe and externally.</p>
<p>&quot;Europe must not become an island of prosperity and development in the middle of a chaotic world. Our internal stability depends on our capacity to export the results of our devlopment to areas outside the Union,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LEUVEN, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
