<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="352218" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU steps up pressure on U.S. over Helms-Burton Act.</title>
<headline>EU steps up pressure on U.S. over Helms-Burton Act.</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union on Monday stepped up the pressure on the United States over a long-running trade row, calling on the head of the World Trade Organisation to intervene personally in a dispute over Cuban links.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the European Commission -- the EU's executive -- said WTO Director-General Renato Ruggiero would be officially asked to name a disputes panel to rule on a complaint against Washington's Helms-Burton Act.</p>
<p>The U.S. and EU have been unable to agree since November on the composition of the three-person panel to rule whether the EU is correct in complaining the act constitutes restraint of trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we will ask the Director-General himself to choose a panel,&quot; said Peter Guilford, spokesman for European Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan.</p>
<p>The move, though expected, nevertheless escalates an issue that has already significantly soured relations between Washington and Brussels.</p>
<p>The act, an amalgamation of decades of Washington's anti-Cuba policy, among other things allows naturalised Americans to sue in U.S. courts foreign companies or individuals deemed to have profited from investments in property confiscated by the Cuban government since the Communist revolution of 1959.</p>
<p>Asking the WTO Director-General to name a panel is a last resort under the body's rules and Ruggiero will be obliged to make his nominations by February 13. Once formed, a panel must reach a decision within six months.</p>
<p>The 130-member WTO's Dispute Settlement Body (DSB) agreed on November 20 last year to an EU request, backed by many other countries in Asia and Latin America, to create the panel.</p>
<p>Ruggiero told reporters at the World Economic Forum in Davos at the weekend that he hoped the dispute could be solved between the two powers without going through the full panel process.</p>
<p>&quot;The objective of the dispute settlement system is to facilitate the solution of disputes, not to impose rulings on governments,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>WTO officials feel the case could feed opposition in the U.S. Congress to membership of the trade body, seen by many U.S. political figures as a threat to national sovereignty.</p>
<p>&quot;This is extremely dangerous territory for the whole organisation,&quot; said one trade envoy in Geneva.</p>
<p>Under Article 21 of the WTO's underlying treaty, the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, member countries are allowed to waive the rest of the accord if they believe their national security is threatened.</p>
<p>The Helms-Burton law, named after its Congressional sponsors, was signed by President Bill Clinton after Cuba shot down two small planes flown by Miami-based anti-communist exiles last January. It has also been fiercely criticised by Canada.</p>
<p>Clinton has twice suspended application of parts of the law, saying recently Brussels had signalled it would work with Washington to improve the human rights situation in Cuba.</p>
<p>Some trade diplomats say a WTO panel would have to determine whether the U.S. was justified under Article 21 in pleading a national security exception.</p>
<p>But others say the United States seems correct in arguing that the article's phrasing means if a country deems its security is at stake no WTO panel, made up of trade and not political experts, could rule on this.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
