<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="352457" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Euro stocks take breather after record run.</title>
<headline>Euro stocks take breather after record run.</headline>
<byline>David Stamp</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>European stocks took a breather on Monday after last week's record run, taking their cue from an easier Wall Street as interest rate nerves set in.</p>
<p>The dollar also had a quiet morning, but edged higher against the mark and yen as dealers watched a meeting of deputy finance ministers from the Group of Seven (G7) industrial nations in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Shares in Britain and France, which all closed at record index highs on Friday, slipped back by late morning. German shares were earlier down but later recovered.</p>
<p>Dealers looked to Wall Street, where the rally faltered on Friday and the Dow Jones industrial average ended 10.77 points lower at 6,813.09, although most broader indices held on to gains.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it will be a fairly quiet morning,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;Friday's (U.S.) figures showed there's still growth, but that inflation isn't a problem,&quot; he said, forecasting that the market would drift until data from U.S. purchasing managers later on Monday.</p>
<p>Despite Friday's soothing data, the spectre of interest rate rises continued to haunt investors before a U.S. Federal Reserve gathering this week.</p>
<p>The market is likely to remain cautious before the Federal Open Market Committee's (FOMC) two-day meeting, which starts on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Despite the signs that the United States is achieving inflation-free growth, Tuesday is the third anniversary of an unexpected U.S. interest rate hike which sent world stock markets plunging.</p>
<p>In Paris profit takers were also active, although media group Havas made an opening jump of over eight percent on news it was in talks over its stake in satellite broadcaster Canal Plus.</p>
<p>On foreign exchange markets, the dollar was slightly higher against the mark and yen although it was off overnight highs.</p>
<p>Analysts saw the dollar staying firm as the market expected the purchasing figures to confirm a healthy U.S. economy.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll probably have some reasonably firm data this afternoon... this should continue to keep a pretty firm tone on the dollar against both the mark and the yen,&quot; said NatWest Markets currency strategist Jeremy Stretch.</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.6421 marks and 121.93 yen at midmorning, up from 1.6365 marks and 121.12 yen in late European trade on Friday.</p>
<p>Although its outlook looked healthy, the dollar was not expected to break new ground on Monday as meetings of G7 finance ministers and central bank governors, plus the FOMC and German Bundesbank council meetings, all loomed this week.</p>
<p>The market would keep an eye on the G7 deputy finance ministers in Frankfurt for hints on the dollar's direction, although analysts did not expect anything definite to come out of these talks.</p>
<p>G7 ministers and central bank governors meet in Berlin at the weekend.</p>
<p>The mark's mood could be affected by a report due on Monday from the European statistics agency Eurostat, which will assess the accounting practices European Union governments have used to meet the criteria for monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>&quot;The mark isn't doing a great deal, but it might be affected by the report by Eurostat. If the outcome of that is that the peripheral markets aren't going to make the first wave of EMU, that might give the mark a little bit of strength,&quot; said NatWest Market's Stretch.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1145GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.6452 marks and 122.00 yen, up from 1.6365 marks and 121.12 yen in late European trade on Friday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1145 GMT</p>
<p>LONDON - The FTSE-100 index was down 15.0 points at 4,260.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - The 30-share DAX index was up 20.78 points at 3,055.93.</p>
<p>PARIS - The CAC-40 was down 5.75 at 2,510.81.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS - Gold was fixed at $343.75 an ounce against $345.50 previously. Silver was at $4.87/$4.89, down three cents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
