<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="35241" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fran could bring rains to eastern U.S. corn belt.</title>
<headline>Fran could bring rains to eastern U.S. corn belt.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The eastern corn belt could see rain Friday through Sunday as the remnants of Hurricane Fran push northward, but meteorologists disagreed on rainfall amounts and coverage.</p>
<p>&quot;It still looks to us that the remains of this system are going to move along, or east of the Appalachian Mountains,&quot; said Mike Palmerino, meteorologist with Weather Services Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the mountains will be enough of a barrier that Ohio would be on the fringe with only a few light showers, 0.10 to 0.50 inch with maybe 50 to 60 percent coverage,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>But Weather Express meteorologist Fred Gesser said &quot;eastern Ohio could be drenched.&quot;</p>
<p>He forecast 0.25 to 0.50 inch in eastern Indiana, 0.50 to 1.00 inch for western Ohio and and possible flooding rains in eastern Ohio with very high coverage.</p>
<p>Smith Barney meteorologist Basilio Lopez said Ohio and southeast Indiana would receive 0.30 to 1.30 inches of rain and isolated heavier with 40 percent coverage.</p>
<p>Temperatures were expected to be in the 80s Farenheit through Saturday across the corn belt, forecasters agreed.  </p>
<p>The western corn belt was expected to be mostly dry during that period with a few scattered showers possible Saturday when a cold front moves in, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Any shower activity in the western corn belt will be in the extreme northwest,&quot; Palmerino said. He expected 0.10 to 0.50 inch in South Dakota and western Minnesota with 40 to 50 percent coverage.</p>
<p>&quot;That front will weaken significantly (as it moves westward into Iowa and Illinois) and I don't think it will have much moisture in it,&quot; Palmerino added.</p>
<p>Temperatures were expected to drop into the 40s (degrees Fahrenheit) early Monday and Tuesday morning with highs in the low 70s, Gesser said. He expected below normal precipitation in the western corn belt for the next six to 10 days.</p>
<p>Meteorologists agreed freezing temperatures were unlikely in the Midwest through September 15.</p>
<p>&quot;The cooler air early next week will slow development some, but it is not a frost threat in any way,&quot; Lopez said. &quot;The return to warmer conditions late next week will help push along late development in the west.&quot;</p>
<p>--Emily Kaiser 312-408-8749</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
