<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="352418" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Coca-Cola plans big investment in South Africa.</title>
<headline>Coca-Cola plans big investment in South Africa.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG, South Africa</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coca-Cola Co. said Monday it was joining with its seven South African bottlers to invest 1.25 billion rand ($275 million) in South Africa over the next five years.</p>
<p>President and Chief Operating Officer Doug Ivester said Coca-Cola intended to double its business in South Africa as a result of the investment, which would be split 50-50 basis between the Atlanta-based company and its bottlers.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be investing well in excess of one billion rand in South Africa over the next five years targeted at expanding and improving the availability of our product,&quot; Ivester told a news conference.</p>
<p>The announcement, which local analysts saw as a vote of confidence in South Africa, help boost the rand Monday to its best levels in 3-1/2 months.</p>
<p>&quot;The country's dynamics are such that now this seems an appropriate time for this investment to take off,&quot; Ivester said.</p>
<p>The investment would be used primarily to buy refrigeration and other equipment as well as to improve support systems, which Ivester said would significantly boost the availability of its product to capture South Africa's emerging urban consumers.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not about bottling plants, it's about expanding the marketing infrastructure, this is about energising the market to increase demand and consumption,&quot; Coca-Cola Southern Africa President Charles Frenette said.</p>
<p>Frenette said the actual size of the investment per year would depend on the needs of the marketplace.</p>
<p>He and Ivester declined to say how much of a share of the South African market Coca-Cola has cornered over rival Pepsico Inc., which re-entered the market two years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not something we discuss publicly. The market is big enough here that we can expand without taking market share from anybody,&quot; Ivester said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG, South Africa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
