<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="352428" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norway bourse enter new month with new life high.</title>
<headline>Norway bourse enter new month with new life high.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwegian shares, buoyed by a rally in banking shares and some blue chips, hit an all-time high at the first trading session of February on Monday.</p>
<p>The Total share index closed 0.52 percent higher at 1,072.71 points for the 17th record close this year in a prolonged liquidity-driven rally. Turnover was brisk at 970 million crowns.</p>
<p>The index stormed to an intra-day peak of 1.076.02 before losing some ground. It fell further in late trade following a weak opening on Wall Street.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was surprisingly strong today,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;The banks have been lagging for a while for no particular reason. Investors started snapping up banking shares at the end of last week,&quot; he said. &quot;The crown stays strong and the short rates are at historic lows. There is a steady flow of money into the stock market.&quot;</p>
<p>Fokus Bank, the number three commercial bank and which will present its annual 1996 result on Thursday, rocketed 7.29 percent to 51.50 crowns. DnB, Norway's top commercial bank, shot up 3.01 percent to 27.40 crowns. Christiania Bank, the second biggest commercial bank, climbed 3.60 percent to 23 crowns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
