<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="352659" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China private sector at 20 pct of economy by 2000.</title>
<headline>China private sector at 20 pct of economy by 2000.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's burgeoning private sector will account for 20.2 percent of the national economy by 2000, compared with 12.3 percent in 1993, the China Business Times said on Monday.</p>
<p>The non-state share of the economy, including private firms and smaller businesses or one-man enterprises, was expected to soar up to the end of the century to account for 30.8 percent of the economy, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>China's private sector accounted for just 1.0 percent of the economy when paramount leader Deng Xiaoping launched his market-oriented economic reforms in December 1978.</p>
<p>The state sector would shrink further by the end of the century, but the rate of decline would start to slow, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>By 2000, the state sector would account for 35.8 percent of the economy, falling from 42.9 percent in 1993 and from a dominant 56 percent in 1978, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>However, the rate of decline would slow and the state sector was expected to acccount for 34.7 percent of the economy in 2010, the newspaper said.  </p>
<p>The share of the economy held by collective firms, most of which are effectively state-owned, would shrink more rapidly in the next four years, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>Collective firms would account for 41.3 percent of the economy by the turn of the century, and that share was expected to decline to 34.5 percent by 2010, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>That marked a reversal in the growth of collective firms, which had grown to account for 48.8 percent of the economy in 1993 from 43 percent in 1978, it said.</p>
<p>Since China formally legalised private enterprise in the late 1980s, the sector has grown rapidly. In 1994, private firms accounted for 11.51 percent of China's industrial output, but for 84.8 percent of growth in output, state media has said.</p>
<p>($1=8.3 yuan)</p>
<p>-- Beijing newsroom (8610) 6532-1921</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
