<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="352762" id="root" date="1997-02-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: LG Metals shares plunge on LME talk.</title>
<headline>LG Metals shares plunge on LME talk.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-02-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of LG Metals Corp plunged during Monday trading on continuing rumours it faced trouble due to short positions on the London Metal Exchange (LME), brokers said.</p>
<p>According to local media reports, the company was facing large losses through its metal trading on the LME.</p>
<p>In early morning trading, LG Metals dropped by 5.6 percent, 800 won to 13,500.</p>
<p>It recovered to 13,800 won in the afternoon, off 500 won from the previous close of 14,300.  </p>
<p>LG Metals' shares have been on a rollercoaster ride since last Thursday, when the rumours first began circulating on the Seoul bourse.</p>
<p>Last Thursday, the company said in a statement that no loss had been made from metals futures trading. It addded that the company had recorded 39.4 billion won ($46 million) profit from metals futures trading last year.</p>
<p>An LG Metals offical in charge of LME trading said the firm had not requested further credit lines from the exchange or received margin calls from brokers.</p>
<p>Traders in London have said the copper market was very tight, with nearby supply scarce and the premium over futures prices -- which must be paid for prompt delivery -- soaring. Large speculative shorts are having to pay high premiums to cover maturing positions which run up to mid-February.</p>
<p>-- Seoul Newsroom (822) 727-5651</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
