<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="35270" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.S. Albright says UN to continue Iraq talks Fri.</title>
<headline>U.S. Albright says UN to continue Iraq talks Fri.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>United States Ambassador Madeleine Albright told reporters Thursday that the United Nations Security Council deliberations on the Iraq crisis would continue on Friday at 1100 EDT/1500 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;We postponed the meeting at the British request,&quot; Albright said.</p>
<p>The British delgation have been working on a draft Security Council resolution and seeking support for it over the last couple of days which would condemn Iraq's incursion into protected Kurdish zones in the north of the country.  </p>
<p>The current president of the Security Council, Guinea Bisau's Alfredo Lopes Cabral, said after Thursday's session that further progress toward reaching an agreed formula was made at the talks but that more time was needed.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that we are still in the process of bridging the gap,&quot; said Lopes Cabral.</p>
<p>Security Council diplomats said that Russia's insistence on watering down the original British resolution was causing the delay.</p>
<p>Russia's U.N. envoy, Sergey Lavrov, said after Thursday's session that &quot;Russia is ready for compromise but not on those matters of principal. The resolutino should not be onesided.&quot;</p>
<p>Lavrov added that the significance of the resolution was, in any case fading. &quot;It is not an operational resolution it is an assessment resolution. Distance puts these things in perspective.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Patrick Connole, United Nations, +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
