<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="35319" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Busy timetable looms for transport issues.</title>
<headline>Busy timetable looms for transport issues.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The remainder of 1996 will be a busy time in the European Union's transport sector with a great sheath of files up for discussion in the Council and a series of sensitive issues looming for the European Commission.</p>
<p>The major theme for the latter, aside from the ongoing business of mopping up the remaining 1996 business in the transport work programme COM(95)302, will be to vet Alitalia's mooted restructuring programme and to police the aid packages already approved for Air France, Iberia and Olympic Airways.</p>
<p>&quot;The next six months is going to be highly influenced by the state aids issue in the run up to full liberalisation of aviation (on April 1 next year),&quot; a senior Commission source told Reuters.</p>
<p>Towards the top of the list will be work following on from the Commission's reopening of an Article 93(2) procedure into Greek government aid to its flag carrier Olympic Airways.</p>
<p>A lengthy letter of complaint from the Commission to the Greek government appeared in June's Official Journal C 176.</p>
<p>The central concern, aside from the issue of government interference with the airline's daily management, is an 11 billion drachma benefit which Athens granted Olympic for costs related to military service provisions. The Commission thinks the money is aid, pure and simple, and intends to block it.</p>
<p>A decision is due in October or November, the official said.</p>
<p>Work on monitoring Alitalia's restructuring programme will depend on what happens in Italy, the file has yet to land on Commission desks. In any case, no Commission decision is expected before next year, the official said.</p>
<p>Questions relating to Iberia and Air France's compliance with their agreed plans will be subject to regular review.</p>
<p>&quot;This can't simply consist of waiting six months and looking again,&quot; the official said, adding that checks would involve monitoring progress with debt reduction and profit and productivity targets.</p>
<p>&quot;State aid is of considerable concern to us. We want to end up by the middle of next year with a clean sheet, with no hangovers,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>A related issue is the Commission's planned report on full aviation liberalisation, which was intended for adoption before the August break. Existing copies of the report present reams of analysis but no Commission outlook on strategy, which Kinnock wants included. This will push Commission adoption into mid-October, the official said.</p>
<p>The executive is also due to decide whether to modifiy Regulation 95/93/EEC on slot allocation at airports. Industry consultations have failed to provide a clear line of action.</p>
<p>&quot;I cannot see that there has been a clear message from the outside consulations on that because people do not quite know what's being referred to. (The revision) will lead to more openness, without doubt, but it may not be as open as British Airways and others have been saying,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>A Commission review of airport charges is less advanced, although even at this stage it is clear that a complicating factor will be airports' wide variety of ownership structures.</p>
<p>Work will also proceed with the trans-European networks (TENs) projects, regardless of whether Kinnock gets top-up money for the plans from ECOFIN ministers or the Dublin Council. Efforts will involve the high-level group of experts charged with looking into private/public project funding.</p>
<p>Moving to maritime strategy, a central issue is the Commission's planned revision of state aid guidelines.</p>
<p>&quot;The key element is whether there is any justification for the continuation or strengthening of public support to shipping. The aim is to prevent any further erosion or delocation of maritime activity outside the Community. We will have to come forward with new guidelines this Autumn before the Council concludes on this,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>&quot;The attitude to state aid is harder than in 1989 when the guidelines were first written,&quot; the official added.</p>
<p>An end is in sight, according to the official, to the long-running negotiations with Switzerland. While the aviation element of the package has been sewn up, difficulties remain as to how to treat the questions raised by Switzerland's ban on transiting heavy goods vehicles.</p>
<p>Another external relations file concerns aviation relations between the EU and the United States, a source of acrimony for the Commission and Council until last June, when Kinnock won ministers' backing to open first-stage talks on so-called soft aviation rights. These exclude the more controversial questions of airline ownership rules and traffic rights which are for later consideration.</p>
<p>A first meeting is scheduled to take place in Washington in late October or November.</p>
<p>Less controversial is the mandate with central and east European countries, where so-called the structured dialogue will look at bringing accession candidate countries' aviation law more into line with the third package of air liberalisation.</p>
<p>Other files in the Commission work programme, which should all make through the Commission by January 1997 at the latest, if not before, are:</p>
<p>-- Minimum training levels for seafarers (Directive 94/58/EC);</p>
<p>-- Maritime safety: passenger lists for roll-on roll-off ferries;</p>
<p>-- Road transport: conditions of access to the profession;</p>
<p>-- Framework regulation on transport of dangerous goods on inland waterways;</p>
<p>-- Negotiations of a maritime accord with China;</p>
<p>-- Revision of the transport annexes of the Fourth Framework Programme for Research and Technological Development;</p>
<p>-- Communication on relations between the EU and international transport bodies (Including with Eurocontrol and the Joint Aviation Authority);</p>
<p>-- Information note on the programme for safety checks on new cars;</p>
<p>-- minimum standards of training for air cabin crew;</p>
<p>-- Licences for the operation of roll-on roll-off passenger ferries;</p>
<p>-- improvement of air passenger rights;  </p>
<p>Away from work in Commission, the Irish presidency has set itself a full agenda for its six-month term. The danger might be a bunching of agenda items at the December 12 Council because the first one falls early in October, on the third and fourth.</p>
<p>For the October Council the provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>-- Recommendation for a Council decision authorising the Commission to open negotiations on air transport agreements between the Community and Bulgaria, the Czech Republic, Hungary, Poland, Romania and Slovakia. A presidency spokesman said the proposal was up for political discussion and possible adoption in October.</p>
<p>-- Following on from the mandate discussions will be a meeting between the Council and their transport counterparts from the central and east European countries. The spokesman said talks here would cover rules governing railways, cabotage rules and those for road tolls.</p>
<p>-- Ministers will hear a Commission progress report on the state of transport negotiations with Switzerland on land and air transport.</p>
<p>-- Discussions on the proposal COM(96)106 for a European Parliament and Council directive on summertime arrangements will be delayed at least until December for want of parliament's opinion, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>-- Two road transport files, access to the road haulage profession and the Commission's proposal to revise the rules for the taxation of goods vehicles to replace Directive 93/89/EEC, are provisional agenda items. The spokesman said that discussions during September would determine whether they appeared on the earlier Council agenda. If they did, they are both due for political orientation debates.</p>
<p>-- Proposal for a Council regulation laying down the conditions under which non-resident carriers may operate national road passenger transport services within a member state. This again would be for an orientation debate.</p>
<p>-- The same is the case for proposal COM(96)190 on changing Council Regulation (EEC) No 684/92 on common rules on the international carriage of passengers by coach and bus.</p>
<p>-- Another provisional agenda item is the recent White Paper on the future of the railways, COM(96)421.</p>
<p>-- The White Paper on air traffic management has yet to make it through Commission and so is likely to slip at least until December.</p>
<p>-- Proposal COM(95)724 for a Council regulation on air carrier liabilities in case of accidents will be up for debate only in the absence of an opinion from parliament. Otherwise it also goes to December at the earliest.</p>
<p>-- Proposal COM(96)186 for a Council regulation amending Regulation 3922/91/EEC on the harmonisation of technical requirements and administrative procedures in the field of civil aviation. This is due for formal adoption, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>-- Among the maritime transport files is the planned proposal on the compilation of lists of passengers on roll-on roll-off ferries. This will depend on progress in Commission.</p>
<p>-- Another on the agenda is proposal COM(96)255) for a Council directive setting up a harmonised safety regime for fishing vessels of 24 metres or more in length.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Proposal for a Council directive amending Council directive 93/75/EEC concerning minimum requirements for vessels bound for or leaving Community ports and carrying dangerous or polluting goods.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Proposal for a Council directive amending directive 94/58/EEC on the minimum level of training for seafarers. ***</p>
<p>For the December 12/13 Council, the new items on the provisional agenda, aside from the carry overs from October, include:</p>
<p>-- A Commission report on the first stage of open skies talks with the United States;</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Follow-up to the green paper on the citizens' network, COM(95)601.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Follow-up to the green paper on internalisation of external costs, COM(95)691.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Proposals on access to the road haulage profession.</p>
<p>-- Proposal COM(94)323 for a Council regulation amending the Council directive and regulation on recording equipment in road transport.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Follow-up to high level group on air safety. This relates to the group assembled in the wake of the fatal Dominican air disaster in February.</p>
<p>-- Proposal for the establishment of a single European authority for air safety.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Proposal on airport charges.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Revision of regulation on slot allocation.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Proposals to update rules on denied boarding compensation and passenger protection.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Licensing regime for roll-on roll-off ferry operations.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Proposal to amend Council directive 93/75/EEC concerning minimum requirements for vessels bound for or leaving Community ports and carrying dangerous or polluting goods.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Shipping agreements with third countries, especially China and India.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Report on competition in the multimodal sector.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
