<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="353210" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY precious metals end lower, but palladium up.</title>
<headline>NY precious metals end lower, but palladium up.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York precious metals futures ended mostly lower Tuesday, but palladium extended its rally, as Russian supply problems continued to impact, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold has been consolidating for the past three sessions, after spot gold fell below $350 last week and became oversold again,&quot; Pell Brothers COMEX floor trader Don Tierney said.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold open interest fell further in this morning's open interest data, suggesting fund buying Monday was just shortcovering,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>COMEX April gold ended down $2.10 an ounce at $346.40, after trading a $349.20-3461.0 range.</p>
<p>In data released Tuesday, total open interest in COMEX gold futures fell 3,972 contracts Monday to 191,872 lots.</p>
<p>In the bullion market, spot gold ended quoted $344.00/50, after fixing at $345.70 in London Tuesday afternoon, compard to the New York close Monday around $346.40/90.</p>
<p>Gold prices saw fresh three year lows last week, on more concern about central bank sales and a seasonal dip in demand during the Ramadan and Chinese New Year holidays, with a strong US dollar limiting investor interest in gold also.</p>
<p>The decline in the gold price may be making some high-cost gold mines unprofitable though, analysts said.</p>
<p>The price of gold in South African rand was now at a nine month low as the South African rand stabilized after last year's sharp fall.</p>
<p>&quot;A sharp reversal of the fortunes of the (South African gold mining) industry is now in prospect because of the recent strengthening of the rand,&quot; industry consultant Edward Osborn of Edey, Rogers Pty Ltd in South Africa said.</p>
<p>&quot;With capex (capital expenditure) brought into the picture, nearly half of the number of reporting mines (in South Africa), representing 2.45 pct of national production, operated at a loss (in the fourth quarter 1996),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Silver remained weaker than gold Tuesday though, with the spot gold/silver ratio edging up to 70.78 from a 15 month low at 69.79 last Friday.</p>
<p>COMEX March silver ended down 4.5 cents at $4.857 an ounce, after trading down to $4.840, as longs liquidated positions built up last week when silver spiked above $5.00 for the first time in three months.</p>
<p>In the platinum metals group, NYMEX April platinum closed down 40 cents at $355.00, but NYMEX March palladium ended up $1.10 an ounce at $129.70, continuing its rally of the past six weeks.</p>
<p>Negotiations over one-year palladium supply contracts from Russia to Japan, usually held in mid-December, were postponed indefinitely due to a dely in the Russian budget being approved, analysts noted.</p>
<p>The Russian budget was belatedly approved on January 24.</p>
<p>But long term supply contracts between 13 Japanese companies and Russia expired at the end of December and since then Japanese trade houses have received no platinum from Russia, forcing the Japanese into the spot market to cover their needs, analysts said.</p>
<p>Russia accounted for about 54 percent of total world annual palladium supply in 1996.</p>
<p>-Clive McKeef, New York Commodities Desk, +1-212-859-1641; -email: clive.mckeef@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
