<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="353374" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: SOCCER-VENABLES TO CHECK AUSTRALIANS OVERSEAS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-VENABLES TO CHECK AUSTRALIANS OVERSEAS.</headline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE, Australia 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Australian soccer coach Terry Venables, appointed to take charge for the 1998 World Cup, is to inspect overseas-based Australian players for friendly matches in Macedonia and Hungary.</p>
<p>Briton Venables, who guided England to the semifinals of the 1996 European Championship, said on Tuesday a four-day training camp in either Britain or Holland would replace a proposed match against Croatia scheduled for February 25.</p>
<p>Soccer Australia chairman David Hill said because of time constraints the Croatian match had been scrapped by Australia out of fairness to Venables and players who had responsibilities to their clubs.</p>
<p>While Australia has not made a World Cup finals appearance since 1974, about 75 Australian players are currently signed up to teams in 20 countries in Europe, Asia and South America.</p>
<p>Venables told a news conference roughly 22 players would be selected for the European camp. He had the names he had &quot;more or less&quot; already in mind, though he had yet to make formal offers.</p>
<p>Squads would be chosen to play Macedonia on March 12 and Hungary on April 2, he said.</p>
<p>Venables said while it was difficult to reach World Cup finals, he had been pleasantly surprised by his first official duties here, leading to Australia's win in the recent four nations' tournament against Norway, South Korea and New Zealand.</p>
<p>Venables rejected concern expressed in Australia that as he would be based only part-time in Australia he would be more likely to give preference to overseas-based players in selecting the squad for the upcoming Oceania qualifying matches.</p>
<p>&quot;I have got one thing on my mind -- it is not going out dancing with footballers, or going on holiday with them, but to win football matches and I want the best,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCDNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
