<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="353499" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Major urges EU business to fight overregulation.</title>
<headline>Major urges EU business to fight overregulation.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister John Major appealed to businessmen across the European Union on Tuesday to join him in a crusade against over-regulation of their enterprises which he said had cost millions of jobs and threatened many others.</p>
<p>But the opposition Labour Party immediately countered with a charge that divisions within his ruling Conservative Party over Europe were the real threat to British prosperity.</p>
<p>&quot;Over-regulation doesn't work, and as a result nor do millions of Europeans,&quot; Major said in a speech in Brussels, the text of which was issued by his office.</p>
<p>&quot;I want the whole of Europe to wake up to the crying need for an enterprise approach so that we can get back to work and we can all prosper.&quot;</p>
<p>In a speech designed to appeal to British voters who will determine his fate in an imminent election, Major said while the lightly-regulated British economy was attracting investors, continental European countries were deterring enterprise.</p>
<p>As a result, some 18.5 million European Union citizens were now out of work. British unemployment at around seven percent is well below that in most other major EU countries. Major said if Britain joined the EU's social chapter on workplace standards, as Labour wants it to do, the wellspring of new employment could dry up.</p>
<p>&quot;One signature on the social chapter would mean half a million signatures on the dole...it would become a Trojan horse unloading on Britain the problems which brought us to a low point in the 1970s,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Labour's foreign affairs spokesman Robin Cook charged Major with vastly exaggerating the extent of the social chapter, which he said at present had adopted just one regulation requiring European multinationals to have works councils.</p>
<p>He asked where Major had come up with the &quot;suspiciously round figure&quot; of half a million jobs, and said the real threat to investment in Britain was the civil war in the Conservative Party on EU policy.</p>
<p>Accusing Major of constantly giving way to Eurosceptics in his party's ranks, he said: &quot;Our investment and our jobs depend on a successful relationship between Britain and Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>Labour, under moderate Tony Blair, leads Major's Conservatives by 16 percentage points in an opinion poll published earlier on Tuesday, with an election due by May 22.</p>
<p>Major said measures such as the EU's working time directive which limits the working week to 48 hours were &quot;the thin end of a very large wedge&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Business needs to speak up and say this. The facts are uncomfortable, but they cannot be ignored. If Europe is heading in the wrong direction...then we must face the problem and change the policy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said businessmen should help him demolish the myths about regulation such as that without it workers would be open to exploitation and that social inequalities would increase.</p>
<p>&quot;Britain has created over 900,000 new jobs in the last few years. Of these, 24 percent have been in professional occupations and 21 percent are managerial,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Conservatives plan to make British success in attracting inward investment by foreign companies a big theme in their campaign for reelection for a fifth successive term in office.</p>
<p>They claim that a combination of low taxes, a flexible labour market and government's determination not to add to employers' burdens has been the key to this success.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
