<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="353439" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLAND'S KOLODKO QUITS WITH SENSE OF SATISFACTION.</title>
<headline>POLAND'S KOLODKO QUITS WITH SENSE OF SATISFACTION.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Barker</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grzegorz Kolodko says Poland's economy became the &quot;soaring eagle&quot; of Europe during his three years as finance minister and he handed over his post on Tuesday saying with satisfaction that his job was done.</p>
<p>&quot;We managed to introduce Poland on to the path of balanced growth. We have a market economy, we are in the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD),&quot; Kolodko said at a ceremony in which he surrendered over the post he has held, since April 1994, in three leftist coalition cabinets.</p>
<p>&quot;After three years my mission has come to an end having, in my view, yielded good results for the country,&quot; the non-party, 47-year-old economist said -- adding that he was leaving the economy in Olympian form for his successor Marek Belka.</p>
<p>Few analysts dispute Poland's successes but there is debate over whether Kolodko and his ex-communist associates have developed or wasted reforms his predecessor Leszek Balcerowicz launched as finance minister after the 1989 fall of communism.</p>
<p>Balcerowicz, now head of the main opposition party, was scathing about Kolodko on Tuesday, saying: &quot;He had much more success in advertising himself than in economic policy.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Looking back at the last three years I think... he took over an economy which was gaining momentum and is leaving one with a falling growth rate,&quot; Balcerowicz told Radio Zet.</p>
<p>Poland's economic growth resumed in 1992 and under Kolodko Gross Domestic Product grew by seven percent in 1995, by six percent in 1996, and is forecast by the government to expand by 5.5 percent this year.</p>
<p>The fight against inflation has been less successful. It was 18.5 percent year-on-year in December 1996, compared with an original target of 13 percent, but was down from 29.5 percent in December 1994.</p>
<p>But even Balcerowicz conceded Kolodko had been better for the economy than most members of the coalition of ex-communists and a Peasant party, which won power from Solidarity-rooted parties in 1993 with promises to ease the pain of reforms.</p>
<p>Other commentators credit the non-party academic Kolodko with having been a relative guardian of budgetary restraint and a stubborn, if sometimes abrasive fighter for lower inflation against the demands of his leftist colleagues.</p>
<p>The head of the ruling ex-communist Democratic Left Alliance's core party, former Prime Minister Jozef Oleksy, conceded as much, telling Reuters: &quot;Kolodko is a controversial figure, but it is precisely this which allowed him to force through solutions which were good for the economy.&quot;</p>
<p>Kolodko is widely praised for his &quot;Strategy for Poland&quot;, a first signpost of official policy with clear medium to long-term goals, later updated with his book Package 2000.</p>
<p>Balcerowicz said Kolodko had not ensured that the goals set out in these plans, the basis of government policy, were kept.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear most of them have not been fulfilled -- just to mention social security reform, the stabilisation of taxes, more investment and spending on education. Also, Kolodko did not fully realise the importance of privatisation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some Kolodko tactics have been controversial -- he tried to get the central bank to cut official interest rates faster, in the hope of reducing inflationary expectations.</p>
<p>The independent bank resisted, concerned this tactic could backfire, leading to sharp exchanges in 1995 and 1996 between Kolodko and the bank's chief Hanna Gronkiewicz-Waltz.</p>
<p>His ministry's apparent slip up in granting tax breaks on personal donations, which are hard to police, cost the budget dear last year and Kolodko's attempt to blame taxpayers for taking advantage of the loophole earned him sharp criticism.</p>
<p>But Bogdan Wyznikiewicz, head of the independent Gdansk Institute for Market Economy, said Kolodko's achievements outweighed such errors and were unlikely to be responsible for the loss of his job.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not see it as a penalty for a legislative imperfection over donations because he has achievements such as maintaining budget and fiscal discipline, keeping the budget deficit under control and bringing Poland into the OECD.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;These are achievements that outweigh his slips,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
