<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="35349" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Trichet-France on track to meet Maastricht targets.</title>
<headline>Trichet-France on track to meet Maastricht targets.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of France governor Jean-Claude Trichet said on Thursday France was on track to meet the Maastricht treaty criteria to join a single European currency on time.</p>
<p>Speaking in an interview with CNN International, Trichet said, &quot;I consider that France is on track and we will make it in time. France, Germany, the Netherlands and certain other countries will be in the first train and make it for January 1, 1999.&quot;</p>
<p>Excerpts from the interview, to be broadcast at 1800 GMT, were made available in advance.  </p>
<p>Trichet-France on track to meet Maastricht =2</p>
<p>According to the statement released by CNN, regarding possible cuts in French interest rates, Trichet said they were already low.</p>
<p>On the subject of the franc, the central bank governor said the government has it under control, which is vital for maintaining confidence.</p>
<p>Trichet also said the government can make tax cuts, which would be announced Thursday by Prime Minister Alain Juppe, according to the statement.</p>
<p>Asked about recent rumours of alleged attempts by President Jacques Chirac to get him to cut rates faster, he said he was not worried, the Bank was independent and he &quot;sleeps well at night.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
