<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="353549" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Investment concerns spur C&amp;W alliance rethink.</title>
<headline>Investment concerns spur C&amp;W alliance rethink.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Marshall</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fears of too little management control and too much costly investment in infrastructure spurred Cable and Wireless Plc to reconsider plans to forge an alliance with two German utilities, industry sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said the scale of investment required by the project could curtail C&amp;W's plans to develop the Cable and Wireless Communications consortium in Europe, and may cause the British telecommunications firm to pull out of the alliance altogether.</p>
<p>C&amp;W said on Tuesday it was in talks with German utility Veba AG about &quot;the future of their partnerships in Germany and the rest of Europe&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The discussions are continuing and a more detailed statement will be made in due course,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>C&amp;W and Veba formed a strategic alliance, called Vebacom, in 1995. Last year, the firms agreed to bring RWE into the alliance and final contracts were drawn up two weeks ago.</p>
<p>But C&amp;W has not yet signed the deal, and evidence is growing that it may pull out of the alliance. Analysts say the partnership is clearly over and only the terms of C&amp;W's departure remain to be decided.</p>
<p>Industry sources said C&amp;W's strategy diverged from Veba and RWE's plans. The German firms favoured heavy investment in infrastructure in Germany but C&amp;W was wary of having to commit too many resources to Vebacom, they said.</p>
<p>Too big a commitment to Vebacom would hamper plans to expand cable company C&amp;W Communications in Europe. C&amp;W Communications is being formed by the merger of C&amp;W's Mercury subsidiary with NYNEX Cable Communications, Bell Cablemedia and Videotron.</p>
<p>Industry sources said a shift in the balance of power in the alliance if RWE came on board was also a concern. C&amp;W was said to be worried it would have too little influence in the management of the enlarged partnership.</p>
<p>Analysts say unhappiness with the German partnership is not the only reason for C&amp;W's likely departure.</p>
<p>They said the company looked set to hook up with a global telecoms alliance, with the Global One partnership of Deutsche Telekom, France Telecom and Sprint Corp of the U.S. the most likely option.</p>
<p>&quot;If C&amp;W decide that a life with Global One is better than going it alone with Veba and RWE then they may well be leaving for that reason, rather than going out of disillusionment with the German alliance,&quot; said Martin Mabbut, analyst at HSBC James Capel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
