<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="353531" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: C&amp;W can exit Veba deal on good terms - analysts.</title>
<headline>C&amp;W can exit Veba deal on good terms - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Marshall</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cable and Wireless Plc seems certain to walk away from an alliance with two German utilities and the only questions remaining are the terms of its departure and the plans it has up its sleeve once it goes, analysts said.</p>
<p>They said the British telecommunications firm should be able to exit its partnership with Veba AG on reasonable terms, although it could face short-term share weakness if Veba sells its 10.5-percent C&amp;W stake.</p>
<p>&quot;The partnership has clearly broken up,&quot; Salomon Brothers analyst Andrew Harrington said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're just waiting to see the details of their departure,&quot; he said. &quot;I think they're likely to receive more than they put in because it's a strategic asset in Germany. There are lots of potential purchasers of that strategic asset.&quot;</p>
<p>C&amp;W and Veba formed a strategic alliance, called Vebacom, in 1995. Last year, the firms agreed to bring RWE into the alliance and final contracts were drawn up two weeks ago. But C&amp;W has not signed and evidence is growing that it may pull out.</p>
<p>A source close to Veba said on Tuesday that the firm had offered to buy back C&amp;W's 45-percent stake in Vebacom and hold it in the hope of selling it to a new partner.  </p>
<p>Veba would hold on to its stake in C&amp;W, the source said.</p>
<p>Analysts said if Veba kept its stake in C&amp;W, one potential source of weakness in C&amp;W's share price would be eliminated. They said discussions were probably now centring on how much C&amp;W would get for its Vebacom stake.</p>
<p>&quot;The big worry was that Veba would be a forced seller, a careless seller of its stake in C&amp;W,&quot; SocGen analyst John Tysoe said. He said if Veba kept the stake, it would also have less incentive to be overly hostile on the terms of C&amp;W's departure. &quot;If it's true that they will keep it, then it's not in their interests to hurt C&amp;W.&quot;  </p>
<p>Even if Veba was disinclined to buy back C&amp;W's stake in Vebacom, another buyer could be found, Tysoe said. &quot;If Veba doesn't buy it, someone else might well want to buy it, someone with long pockets and different priorities.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said SBC Communications and BellSouth Corp were potential buyers of the stake. &quot;SBC makes sense,&quot; Tysoe said. &quot;I think that works.&quot;</p>
<p>Industry sources said C&amp;W was rethinking its alliance with Veba and RWE because of concerns it would have to invest too much on infrastructure and would have too little control of the alliance.  </p>
<p>But analysts said C&amp;W was likely to have an alternative plan which required leaving the partnership . Most said it looked set to join forces with a major worldwide telecoms alliance.</p>
<p>Global One, partnership of Deutsche Telekom, France Telecom and Sprint Corp of the U.S., is widely regarded as the most likely candidate.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they are going to be part of a global carrier at some point in the next year, and that will crystalise the very high strategic value of C&amp;W's asset base,&quot; Harrington said.</p>
<p>&quot;Global One is the most likely option -- either through a joint venture but more probably a stake,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 4367</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
