<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="353682" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarians protest as Socialists meet president.</title>
<headline>Bulgarians protest as Socialists meet president.</headline>
<byline>Thalia Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgarian protesters chanted anti-communist slogans outside the presidency on Tuesday as Socialist leaders met the president to discuss ways to defuse the crisis over their insistence on forming a new cabinet.</p>
<p>Protesters kept up strikes and blockades around Bulgaria on the 30th consecutive day of demonstrations, staying out all night to keep up barricades in sub-zero temperatures.</p>
<p>Protesters played &quot;The Last Waltz&quot; through loudspeakers and decorated the car of Socialist prime minister-designate Nikolai Dobrev with opposition stickers.</p>
<p>Officials said President Petar Stoyanov met Dobrev and Socialist Party leader Georgi Parvanov for more than an hour to discuss ways out of the crisis</p>
<p>The party, deeply divided between hardliners who insist on forming a new cabinet and those who want to return the mandate, on Monday drafted a new cabinet containing many old faces.</p>
<p>The presidency said Dobrev had not presented the cabinet to Stoyanov as scheduled, and Stoyanov had convened a meeting of his advisory National Security Council later on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Dobrev and party leader Georgi Parvanov left the building by a back exit to avoid the protesters.</p>
<p>Opposition leader Ivan Kostov told Reuters tension had risen noticeably overnight and the protests could easily get out of control.</p>
<p>&quot;We have appealed to police and protesters to avoid any violence because we are all part of the suffering Bulgarian nation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Public transport did not run in Sofia for a second day and students and opposition supporters blocked road junctions.</p>
<p>Protesters from Doupnitsa, where townspeople have blocked road and rail routes to Greece since Wednesday, said they were heading for Sofia to set up barricades outside parliament, which is expected to vote on the new cabinet on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Sofia shoppers queued for bread as flour supplies ran low. Petrol stations are also suffering shortages as the Neftohim refinery is running low on crude.</p>
<p>Standart daily came out with &quot;Strike&quot; printed in opposition blue across its pages.</p>
<p>Miners at Maritsa East, Pernik and Bobov Dol are on strike. Varna port has been closed since Monday but Bourgas and the Danube river port of Rousse are working normally.</p>
<p>Air traffic controllers planned a one-hour stoppage from 3 p.m. until 4 p.m. (1300 GMT to 1400 GMT). On Monday, planes were allowed to land during a similar stoppage. The Kulata checkpoint on the Greek border has been closed since Monday.</p>
<p>In Plovdiv, where the protests began on January 6, protesters kept up blockades overnight.</p>
<p>Sultana Raikova, secretary of the Union of Democratic Forces (UDF) protest committee, said major roads out of town were blocked in both directions and the railway was closed.</p>
<p>&quot;This protest has been going on for quite a long time now. I hope we can soon re-form our protest committee into a pre-election committee,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The anti-government campaign has become one of the biggest protests since the end of communist rule in 1989.</p>
<p>The Socialists were elected in December 1994 for a four-year term, but lost presidential elections in November. Prime Minister Zhan Videnov resigned in December after months of criticism of his handling of the economy, which has plunged far deeper into crisis since then.</p>
<p>A week after the lev hit 1,000 to the dollar on the interbank market for the first time, it fell below 3,000 at midday on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Bulgaria urgently needs a credible government to negotiate with international lenders, draw up a 1997 budget and set up a tough fixed exchange rate regime to halt the slide of the lev.</p>
<p>Inflation was estimated at 50 percent last month and the central bank met its January payment on Bulgaria's $10 billion foreign debt but is fast running out of foreign exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
