<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="353689" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbian opposition calls for 'passive resistance'.</title>
<headline>Serbian opposition calls for 'passive resistance'.</headline>
<byline>John Fullerton</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbia's opposition has called for a campaign of passive resistance after autocratic President Slobodan Milosevic ordered his riot police to forcibly break up pro-democracy demonstrations.</p>
<p>&quot;We must all turn into a great river of non-violent resistance,&quot; Vuk Draskovic, co-leader of the opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition, told cheering, whistling supporters in downtown Belgrade on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;All schools and faculties must close, we must not pay any taxes and bills and we must all go on strike. They are taking money from the citizens to pay the police who beat the people. Don't pay anything.&quot;</p>
<p>The call for a Gandhi-style revolt followed the most aggressive police action seen in Serbia for years, with anti-riot police repeatedly charging largely peaceful protesters on Sunday night. At least 100 people were injured.</p>
<p>On Monday, the 77th straight day of rallies demanding reinstatement of opposition victories in local elections last November, young militants hurled stones at police, provoking what witnesses said were indiscriminate beatings.</p>
<p>Initially, 80,000 people turned out to confront police and the vast majority dispersed quietly when asked to do so by their political leaders. But about 200 youths ranged through the streets in a cat-and-mouse game with heavily-armed police.</p>
<p>Spokesmen for protesting Belgrade students said police beat seven students and four other people, while one policeman was slightly injured in a scuffle.</p>
<p>A Zajedno spokesman in the provincial town of Smederevo, among 14 where opposition election victories were annulled, said police detained 10 people including a radio reporter during a protest march on Monday.</p>
<p>In Jagodina, another disputed town, Zajedno said police ejected about 3,000 people from the town hall where they had gone to protest at the formation of a new local council headed by Milosevic's Socialist Party (SPS).</p>
<p>The Belgrade police rampage prompted international denunciations of Milosevic's &quot;get tough&quot; policy. Washington protested to Serbia and strongly condemned &quot;the most serious use of force&quot; against peaceful demonstrators.</p>
<p>The U.S. State Department said an off-duty Marine who is a guard at the American embassy in Belgrade was caught up in a police charge on demonstrators while on his way home and was clubbed. He was not seriously hurt and is back at work.</p>
<p>France invited leaders of the opposition party bloc to Paris, underlining growing Western support for democratisation in Serbia, under communist/socialist rule since 1945.</p>
<p>The 54-nation Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe also bemoaned the violence and called on Milosevic on Tuesday to begin talks with opposition groups.</p>
<p>It repeated its call for Milosevic to recognise opposition election wins and begin talks with the opposition on future democratic reforms, possibly under auspices of the OSCE.</p>
<p>The Serbian Interior Ministry said 18 people were arrested on Sunday night and it would continue to take all necessary measures &quot;with the goal of preventing threats to public transport and public order, peace and security of citizens...&quot;</p>
<p>Zoran Djindjic, another Zajedno leader, echoed the call for continued non-violent protest, saying people were more determined than ever in pressing for change.</p>
<p>&quot;You must not let yourselves be drawn into a fight with the police, because you will be on their ground -- they have the physical force, but the stamina, morale, truth, international support and justice are on our side.&quot;</p>
<p>More than 1,000 schools are shut, lawyers have rallied with students, while Serbian Orthodox churchmen and army officers have backed opposition demands for election results to be restored.</p>
<p>Belgrade's popular film festival, an annual event, was suspended after foreign distributors withdrew their films within days of the opening in protest at police violence. Most theatres and cinemas in the capital have also shut down.</p>
<p>But Milosevic had other concerns on Monday.</p>
<p>The official Tanjug news agency said he congratulated leading Interior Ministry officials after a successful &quot;anti-terrorist operation&quot; in the Albanian-majority Serbian province of Kosovo.</p>
<p>The operation took place between January 22 and 29 and resulted in the arrests of 66 &quot;members of terrorist organisations... among them perpetrators of terrorist acts carried out in Kosovo,&quot; Tanjug said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
