<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="353764" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian stocks mostly higher, stability to last.</title>
<headline>Croatian stocks mostly higher, stability to last.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks were mostly higher on Tuesday with hoteliers forging ahead and blue chips easing further, and analysts foresaw no end to the current upward trend.</p>
<p>However, they said trade would remain slower due to lesser demand for market heavyweights drugs firm Pliva and Zagrebacka Banka though they are now stabilising at slightly lower levels.</p>
<p>&quot;Hoteliers will rise further and the same goes for Zagrebacka's 3E-series (preference stock),&quot; said Nenad Pavletic of Auctor brokerage, also predicting further growth for food processor Podravka.</p>
<p>Eight of 12 active issues rose and four fell on Tuesday. Volume was more than three times lower at 8,418 shares and turnover shrank to 3.0 million kuna from Friday's 11 million.</p>
<p>Top gainer was hotelier Istraturist, up 18 kuna or 7.28 percent to 248 kuna on volume of 154 shares. Demand for its shares largely outstripped supply, traders said.</p>
<p>All other hoteliers rose. Arenaturist added 10 kuna to 165 and sold 216 units, Jadranturist gained five kuna to 355, with 68 shares sold. Laguna and Riviera rose two kuna to 1,500 and 159, respectively. Suncani Hvar was up one kuna to 61.</p>
<p>Zagrebacka Banka lost 30 kuna to 1,860 on meagre volume of 78 shares, but traders did not expect it to fall under 1,800 kuna. Its 3E-series preference stock gained 50 kuna to 1,050 on volume of 477 units.</p>
<p>Pliva edged down seven kuna to 493, with 322 shares traded.</p>
<p>Podravka was Tuesday's top loser, down nine kuna or 2.5 percent to 350, but it was the most active stock with 3,520 shares sold. Traders attributed its fall to the current overabundant supply.</p>
<p>Confectioner Kras lost five kuna to 490, selling 629 shares. Cable maker Elka added five kuna 195 on volume of 150 shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
