<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="353712" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania denounces Belgrade action in Kosovo.</title>
<headline>Albania denounces Belgrade action in Kosovo.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania on Tuesday denounced Yugoslavia's crackdown on dissent and said Belgrade was trying to use recurring conflict in its Albanian-dominated Kosovo region to distract attention from opposition protests.</p>
<p>A foreign ministry statement denounced the &quot;systematic repression of the ethnic Albanian population by the Serb regime&quot; and sought help from international community to prevent violence it said could threaten regional stability.</p>
<p>&quot;(Serb leader Slobodan Milosevic) is trying to distract domestic and international public opinion from Serbia to Kosovo and to terrorise Albanians in Kosovo,&quot; said the statement, read on state television.</p>
<p>&quot;The government asks the international community to...take all necessary measures to prevent its further escalation which would endanger security, stability and peace in the region.&quot;</p>
<p>Police in Belgrade on Monday beat up dozens of protesters who have been demanding the reinstatement of opposition victories in local elections for nearly 80 days. Tanjug news agency on Tuesday said Milosevic had agreed to do so.</p>
<p>The violence was condemned by the United States, European Union and others.</p>
<p>The Albanian statement condemned the killing by Serb police of three ethnic Albanians in a gunbattle last Friday in Kosovo's main city, Pristina. Dozens were arrested and Milosevic congratulated Serb interior ministry officials for what he termed an &quot;anti-terrorist operation&quot;.</p>
<p>In 1989, Milosevic rescinded Kosovo's autonomous status, accusing the overwhelming Albanian majority there of separatism. The province has been widely seen as a powder keg that could destroy international peace efforts in the Balkans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
