<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="353972" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru rebels fire shots at hostage siege site.</title>
<headline>Peru rebels fire shots at hostage siege site.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least five shots were heard early on Tuesday morning at the site of the besieged Japanese ambassador's residence in Lima, apparently fired by Marxist rebels holding 72 hostages for a 49th day, police said.</p>
<p>A policeman on duty about a block from the residence said the shots, heard at about 5:00 a.m. (1000 GMT), were fired by the rebels as a reminder of their presence.</p>
<p>&quot;They (the rebels) are just trying to grab our attention,&quot; said the police officer, who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>The shots were immediately followed by a defiant speech broadcast via megaphone from inside the residence, witnesses said.</p>
<p>The five minute speech was apparently made by one of the 15 Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels who stormed the residence Dec. 17 and seized the hostages. It made reference to a textile factory labour dispute in which the leader of the assault participated 18 years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Today, February 4, 1997, we pay hommage to the comrade workers,&quot; who died in the strike at the Cromotex factory near Lima in 1979, the unidentified rebel shouted.</p>
<p>Witnesses said police on guard around the building did not appear to be alarmed by the shots or the rebels' shouts, although an armoured vehicle parked about 200 yards (200 metres) from the residence started its engine.</p>
<p>Nestor Cerpa Cartolini, the MRTA leader who led the assault on a cocktail party at the residence, took part in the Cromotex dispute and has named the operation after Hemegidio Huertas, one of several workers to die in clashes with police during the strike.</p>
<p>&quot;Comrades, take our blood and transform it into the torrent of revolutionary force,&quot; the rebel shouted at the end of his speech.</p>
<p>Following the speech, the rebels placed three new signs in an upper window of the diplomatic mansion commemorating the Cromotex dispute.</p>
<p>One sign read: &quot;Glory and honour to the martyr workers of Cromotex Feb. 4 1979-1997.&quot; The other signs contained the names of six workers who died in the strike.</p>
<p>The rebels have fired what police have described as warning shots into the air several times during the 49-day siege. Tuesday's shooting was apparently the first at the site since the guerrillas fired at police aboard a convoy in front of the residence Jan. 27.</p>
<p>The rebels remain deadlocked with the Peruvian government over their demand for the release of about 400 jailed comrades.</p>
<p>Peruvian President Alberto Fujimori, who returns to Lima from Washington on Tuesday, has refused to meet the MRTA's demand.</p>
<p>The guerrillas originally seized more than 500 people at the residence during a party but have released most. They are still holding two government ministers, police chiefs, congressmen, judges, about two dozen Japanese businessmen and diplomats, the Japanese and Bolivian ambassadors and Fujimori's younger brother.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
