<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354090" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish parties plan censure of government.</title>
<headline>Turkish parties plan censure of government.</headline>
<byline>Daren Butler</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's main leftist parties said on Tuesday they would file censure motions against the country's Islamist-led government to protect the secular democratic system.</p>
<p>The fresh political tension and a higher-than-expected inflation figure for January sparked a sharp decline on the recently buoyant stock market.</p>
<p>&quot;We decided it was necessary to start the legal process to free the country from this government,&quot; Bulent Ecevit, leader of the Democratic Left Party, told his MPs. He said the motion would focus on problems of the &quot;secular, democratic republic, foreign affairs, economic and social issues and security.&quot;</p>
<p>Turkey's secularists have been enraged by an anti-Israel rally in an Ankara district held by the ruling Islamist Welfare Party last week. In an apparent show of strength by the secular army, a convoy of tanks and military vehicles paraded through the area on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Ecevit said Welfare was the target of the censure motion, adding it would be supported by many members of the junior coalition partner, the conservative True Path Party (DYP).</p>
<p>Sukru Gurel, a senior MP from Ecevit's party, said the motion would be presented to parliament at the latest by Thursday. The coalition holds a narrow majority but the motion would need the support of both leftist parties, DYP's rival the Motherland Party and some other MPs, to pass.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is so urgent, the danger befalling the democratic, secular state is so big, that we must act immediately,&quot; Gurel told Reuters.</p>
<p>Deputies from the other major leftist party, the Republican People's Party, said in a statement they planned to present their own censure motion to the speaker of parliament on Wednesday, state-run Anatolian news agency reported.</p>
<p>Necmettin Erbakan, Turkey's first Islamist prime minister, apparently renounced his radical pro-Islam and anti-Western election pledges after forming the governing coalition last June.</p>
<p>But he has angered members of Deputy Prime Minister Tansu Ciller's DYP and the powerful army in recent weeks with plans to build mosques and other Islamist programmes.</p>
<p>Analysts say the possibility of early polls has forced Welfare to woo the religious and protest votes that gave the party a narrow plurality in general polls in December 1995.</p>
<p>The coalition has been strained recently by Erbakan's pro-Islam proposals.</p>
<p>Erbakan's confidence in pushing the Welfare line has also been boosted by favourable economic news. The stock market has risen over 50 percent this year on hopes for the economy.</p>
<p>But shares fell seven percent on Tuesday after inflation data showing the economy was still far from stable and on concerns about an apparent deterioration in the political outlook.</p>
<p>The European Union added to those concerns with a warning from Dutch Foreign Minister Hans van Mierlo that Europe faced difficulties in fully embracing Turkey, ranging from Ankara's human rights record to the country's Moslem identity.</p>
<p>Ankara has sought full EU membership since 1987 as a central part of its efforts to cement links with the West.</p>
<p>Highlighting secularist sensitivity over Islamist activity, the Interior Ministry has suspended the Islamist mayor of Ankara's Sincan district, Bekir Yildiz, over a &quot;Jerusalem Night&quot; protest, according to state-run Anatolian news agency.</p>
<p>A state security court also investigating the event ordered the detention of Welfare's Yildiz, Anatolian said.</p>
<p>Comments by Yildiz at the rally were criticised in the media as a call to implement the strict Islamic sharia law.</p>
<p>Military officials denied the action was a response to the rally. &quot;This has nothing to do with that. This is training that we do all the time,&quot; an official said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
