<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="35405" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Creditanstalt talks race against time.</title>
<headline>Creditanstalt talks race against time.</headline>
<byline>Knut Engelmann</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Austro-Italian-German group of bidders for privatisation candidate Creditanstalt-Bankverein was locked in hectic negotiations on Thursday to salvage a deal as the clock ticked away towards Friday's government deadline.</p>
<p>Austrian savings bank Die Erste has proposed forming a joint holding with Creditanstalt, but its partners -- including Austro-Italian insurer EA-Generali, Commerzbank of Germany and Banca Commerciale Italiana -- have voiced disagreement with basic aspects of the plan.</p>
<p>The proposal would give Die Erste, which is barely a third of the size of Creditanstalt, majority control of the holding. Commerzbank reportedly has threatened to leave the consortium unless Die Erste  backs down.</p>
<p>&quot;We're talking about the structure, the acceptability of that structure and the way to get there. We are in permanent talks and are getting closer every hour, but some points are still open,&quot; a spokesman for Die Erste said.</p>
<p>He declined to comment on reports in several Austrian newspapers on Thursday saying Die Erste was ready to soften its stance and reconsider its demand for control of the holding.</p>
<p>None of the other partners was willing to comment on the state of the last-ditch negotiations, which must be wrapped up by Friday if the group wants to remain in the race for the state's 70 percent voting stake in Creditanstalt.</p>
<p>&quot;The exact shape of the consortium is unknown to this day,&quot; a source close to the consortium said. &quot;Either there is an offer and we'll have to clarify it or there won't be an offer.&quot;</p>
<p>Finance Minister Viktor Klima earlier this week extended his orginal deadline for a final offer from the group by one week until midnight Friday, threatening to reopen the bidding process if the consortium failed to use its last chance.</p>
<p>The group so far is the only known bidder for Austria's second-largest bank, but Klima, tiring of the group's tortuous squabbles, this week hinted he had already received calls from other potential buyers.</p>
<p>&quot;One has to comply with such deadlines, that's a pretty normal thing,&quot; his spokesman said.</p>
<p>The minister, a member of the ruling Social Democrats, has made little effort to conceal he is running out of patience.</p>
<p>The debate about Austria's number two bank, founded in 1863 by the Rothschilds and one-time banker to the Habsburg empire, has been politically charged since it began six years ago.</p>
<p>The conservative People's Party, the Social Democrat's junior coalition partner, insists the bank should remain under domestic control.</p>
<p>That has annoyed several international bidders, which over the past few years have lost interest in Creditanstalt because of what they felt was a bias against foreigners in Austria.</p>
<p>But the Social Democrats have pressed for a speedy sale, not least to help ease Klima's growing budget woes.</p>
<p>Senior executives of Creditanstalt also have desperately called for a conclusion of the seemingly endless privatisation saga, which they say has damaged the bank's image abroad.</p>
<p>Creditanstalt, with total assets of about 650 billion schillings ($62.38 billion), has become one of the most successful players on the emerging markets of central and eastern Europe. ($1=10.42 Schilling)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
