<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354162" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: WMX to cut 3,000 jobs, divest $1.5 billion in assets.</title>
<headline>WMX to cut 3,000 jobs, divest $1.5 billion in assets.</headline>
<dateline>OAK BROOK, Ill. 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>WMX Technologies Inc., reporting a fourth-quarter loss of more than $460 million, said Tuesday it planned to divest $1.5 billion in assets over the next two years and cut 3,000 jobs, including 1,200 this year.</p>
<p>The announcement disappointed investors, who sent the company's stock plunging $3.375, or 9 percent, to $32.75 on the New York Stock Exchange, where it was one of the most heavily traded issues.</p>
<p>Under fire from dissatisfied shareholders for months, WMX said its restructuring was geared toward meeting several long-standing demands of investors.</p>
<p>A share buyback, sale of non-core assets and certain management changes had been on the agendas of several activist shareholders, including George Soros' hedge-fund group and Lens Inc., an activist shareholder group in Washington.</p>
<p>WMX -- which also announced it was changing its name back to Waste Management Inc. as it refocuses solely on waste management services -- said it was reorganizing its management, buying back shares and cutting capital spending as it tries to get its balance sheet back in order.</p>
<p>&quot;We will add value by concentrating on the basics of the waste management services business,&quot; the nation's largest garbage hauling and handling company said in a statement.</p>
<p>The company said it took a $680 million charge in the fourth quarter, when it lost $461.3 million, or 95 cents a share. That compared with a profit of $49.7 million, or 10 cents a share, a year ago.</p>
<p>Revenues edged up to $2.33 billion from $2.25 billion in the period.</p>
<p>For the full year, net income fell 68 percent to $192.1 million, or 39 cents a share, from $603.9 million, or $1.24 a share. Revenues rose to $9.19 billion from $9.05 billion.</p>
<p>The company, based in Oak Brook, Ill., also predicted that its revenues this year would not improve over last year's.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a lot of disappointment here. There's a feeling that some of these changes are too late,&quot; said Argus Research industry analyst James Kelleher.</p>
<p>Raymond James analyst William Fisher said, &quot;The quarter appeared to be below expectations and core growth appeared lackluster ... You can do all the restructuring you want, but if your core growth isn't there, well.&quot;</p>
<p>WMX said the divestments, to take place in the next 18 to 24 months, were part of a comprehensive change in business strategy that should generate $3 billion in free cash after dividends over the next two years.</p>
<p>It said the reorganization plan also includes cutting its capital budget for 1997 to $900 million from $1.1 billion in 1996.</p>
<p>Under the plan, WMX's Wheelabrator Technologies subsidiary will sell its remaining water services units for $77 million, and its Rust International unit will sell its remaininng engineering and consulting businesses.</p>
<p>WMX also said it would sell about $400 million of non-integrated waste services business in North America and cut its investment in all or parts of its businesses in France, Spain and Austria.</p>
<p>&quot;This seems like WMX is just admitting it made some mistakes ... They went into these markets and got a half a foot in the door and now they're pulling it out. It's acknowledgment of a failed strategy,&quot; Kelleher said.</p>
<p>He added that Wall Street was concerned the asset sales may come on the market at a time when other garbage handlers are also divesting businesses. &quot;Conditions are not ideal for getting a fair value,&quot; Kelleher said.</p>
<p>The company said it will save a total of about $300 million over the next two to three years through initiatives that include cutting 1,200 jobs in 1997 and a total of 3,000 in a two-to-three year period.</p>
<p>The job cuts will be accomplished through attrition, early retirement and staff cuts, it said.</p>
<p>Counting jobs eliminated with discontinued businesses, WMX said it will have fewer than 58,000 employees this year, down from about 73,000 at the beginning of 1996.</p>
<p>The company also said its board had approved a two-year, 50-million share repurchase programme to return free cash to shareholders.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I92110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OAK BROOK, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
