<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354179" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Vail Resorts gets lift in first day on Wall Street.</title>
<headline>Vail Resorts gets lift in first day on Wall Street.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Westhoven</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street gave the stock of Colorado ski resort operator Vail Resorts Inc. a lift in its first day of trading Tuesday.</p>
<p>In heavy trading of more than 4.5 million shares, the stock jumped $2.25 to $24.25 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Vail, which offered 10.5 million shares at $22 per share under the symbol &quot;MTN&quot;, stands to reap $200 million from the initial public offering.</p>
<p>&quot;Vail is very good at bringing in the destination skier,&quot; said Kevin Eldridge, an analyst at Vancouver, British Columbia-based Salman Partners.</p>
<p>Destination skiers are skiers who visit ski resorts for several days usually and tend to be more affluent than local day skiers.</p>
<p>He also cited Vail's plan to reach for revenues beyond the winter season by becoming a year-round resort. Vail also offers golfing, tennis, horseback riding and other activities.</p>
<p>The stock was popular on Wall Street because of its strong brand name, its rank as one of the leading firms in the skiing industry and the prospect of consolidation in the industry, analysts said.</p>
<p>Vail, headquartered in Avon, Colo., is the largest and most popular ski mountain complex in North America, with 1.65-million-skier days in the 1995-1996 winter season, according to the company's prospectus.</p>
<p>Skier days is an industry term that refers to the number of days spent by skiers on the mountain.</p>
<p>Vail Mountain has more than 4,100 acres of ski terrain spanning about 20 square miles. The company operates Vail as well as Beaver Creek, Keystone and Breckenridge in Colorado.</p>
<p>In addition to its image as the mountain where the rich and famous hit the slopes, the prospect of industry consolidation is tantalizing to investors. Acquisitions in the still largely fragmented North American ski industry could benefit Vail, one of the industry's top dogs.</p>
<p>Vail hit a snag recently when its aggressive acquisition strategy in Colorado sparked antitrust concerns at the U.S. Justice Department.</p>
<p>It agreed to sell another resort, Arapahoe, by June 2 as part of a settlement with the Justice Department.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
