<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354123" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ITT board meets, takes no action on Hilton bid.</title>
<headline>ITT board meets, takes no action on Hilton bid.</headline>
<byline>Robin Sidel</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>ITT Corp.'s board of directors met Tuesday to consider a $6.5 billion hostile bid from Hilton Hotels Corp., but took no action on the cash-and-stock offer.</p>
<p>ITT spokesman Jim Gallagher confirmed the meeting but declined to discuss the length of the session or the board's comments about the unsolicited offer.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no public comment about the specifics of the meeting at all,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gallagher also said the board did not set a date for another meeting to consider the Hilton bid.</p>
<p>Los Angeles-based Hilton last week launched a cash-and-stock offer that values ITT at $55 per share. The Hilton offer also calls for the assumption of about $4 billion of ITT debt.</p>
<p>Gallagher reiterated the ITT board has 10 business days to respond to Hilton's offer, which was officially launched Friday. Under that deadline, ITT must respond to the offer by Feb. 14.</p>
<p>The Tuesday meeting had been a regularly scheduled session of the ITT board and no action had been expected.</p>
<p>Sources close to ITT had said the Tuesday meeting would likely be an informational session that would provide a financial analysis of the Hilton bid. The company's financial advisers had not been expected to make any recommendations regarding the offer.</p>
<p>ITT stock, which has risen sharply on views that Hilton would be forced to pay more than $55 for ITT, dipped 25 cents to $56.75 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>On Saturday, ITT Chairman Rand Araskog turned down a request from Hilton Chief Executive Officer Stephen Bollenbach to meet before the board meeting or be permitted to make a presentation to the ITT board.</p>
<p>Hilton said Tuesday it still had not been contacted by ITT or received any information out of the board meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;Our stance is still that we'd very much like to meet with them,&quot; said Marc Grossman, Hilton's senior vice president of corporate affairs.</p>
<p>Hilton's formal bid, at $55 a share for a 50.1 percent stake in ITT, would give Hilton control of the company. After that, Hilton would swap its stock, with a value of $55 a share, for the remaining ITT shares.</p>
<p>The proposed acquisition would create a hotel and gambling giant with 30 casinos and roughly $2.5 billion in annual cash flow, making it three to five times the size of its nearest rival.</p>
<p>The Hilton offer will expire at midnight Feb. 28 unless it is extended.</p>
<p>Hilton, which has said it would launch a proxy fight to replace ITT's board in order to complete the transaction, is preparing a board slate, said sources familiar with the situation. Hilton has retained proxy solicitation firm MacKenzie Partners Inc.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
