<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="35425" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish car sales hit 15-year high at end-August.</title>
<headline>Irish car sales hit 15-year high at end-August.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>New car sales in Ireland exceeded 100,000 for the first eight months of 1996, the highest level in 15 years, the Society of the Irish Motor Industry (SIMI) said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Overall, car sales from January to the end of August 1996 were up 31 percent at 100,770 compared to the same period last year, SIMI president Des Large said.</p>
<p>Large said in a statement that the growth in the economy, continuing low interest rates and a scrappage scheme for old cars contributed to the current car sales boom.  </p>
<p>New car sales figures for the month of August were up 10 percent on last year at 6,436 and the SIMI expects the total figure for 1996 to be around 113,000.</p>
<p>Ford proved the most popular make of passenger car during August when 804 units were purchased. Luxury models like Mercedes and BMW numbered 94 and 84 respectively. Sales of light commercial vehicles in August were up 26 percent at 1,042 compared to August 1995. Heavy commercial vehicle sales rose by 30 percent to 220. Large said the increase in car saleswould create about 1,000 new jobs in the motor industry and government revenue would rise by 120 million Irish pounds in 1996.</p>
<p>	  --Dublin Newsroom +353 1 676 9779</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
