<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="35426" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German DAX ends steady, shrugs off German data.</title>
<headline>German DAX ends steady, shrugs off German data.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares ended bourse trade on Thursday little changed, shrugging off a small rise in German jobless data for August and GDP data amid limited buying interest before Friday's U.S. jobless figures.</p>
<p>The 30-share blue-chip DAX index closed down 2.85 points at 2,529.54 after a rangebound session. The Bundesbank's decision to leave its key rates unchanged, as expected, failed to move the market.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm afraid we're waiting for the U.S. data again,&quot; said one dealer. The jobless data is due at 1230 GMT Friday.</p>
<p>Dealers said news of a 14,000 rise in German unemployment in August compared to the month before had been largely expected.</p>
<p>&quot;A particularly good unemployment figure could have influenced the debt market (and then indirectly share trading) but these figures were already largely discounted,&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>Corporate news was thin. Diversified industrial group Preussag AG dropped 2.50 marks to 347.50 marks after Deutsche Morgan Grenfell downgraded its stock to &quot;underweight&quot; from &quot;neutral&quot;.</p>
<p>The company had reported a fall in sales for the first nine months of the year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
