<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354370" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FCOJ futures settle lower, under key support.</title>
<headline>FCOJ futures settle lower, under key support.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>FCOJ futures continued to back away from recent gains and closed under the 20-day moving average, where analysts had pegged key support basis the March contract.</p>
<p>The spot month settled down 2.25 at 84.15 cents, below support pegged at 84.35 cents. The deferred contracts ended 2.30 lower to 0.20 higher.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at 3,500 lots.</p>
<p>Analysts said today's close sets the stage for additional losses. Major support in March was seen below the contract low of 76.40 cents, at 75.00 cents.</p>
<p>The lingering uncertainty surrounding losses from the Jan 19 freeze has put trade selling on hold, market sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of people in the trade will stand aside until the report comes out,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Agriculture will release its estimate for the 1996/97 Florida crop Feb 12.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the near-term weather outlook calls for mild temperatures through the middle of next week. Although there is a potential for freezing weather by the end of next week, forecasters said it is too soon to predict how low temperatures could fall.</p>
<p>&quot;It will get cooler but it is too early to pinpoint temperatures,&quot; Mike Palmerino of Weather Services Corp, said.</p>
<p>--((Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities 212-859-1646))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
