<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354328" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT corn ends higher on late buying by ADM.</title>
<headline>CBOT corn ends higher on late buying by ADM.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT corn futures closed higher on a late rally again triggered by demand linked to ADM Investor Services, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;ADM bought two million on the close and in the July just like yesterday,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>ADM bought two million bushels of July corn near the close and traders said the ADM purchases Monday in the July on the close totaled three million bushels.</p>
<p>Fundamentals were little changed with news South Korea bought 100,000 tonnes of corn from Argentina largely anticipated, yet it still helped cap March corn gains.</p>
<p>Cargill Inc bought 3.5 million bushels of March on the day with 0.5 million purchased near the close and Rosenthal Collins bought 1.5 million March in late dealings.</p>
<p>&quot;It was not a very exciting day. There wasn't much news to move it,&quot; said Vic Lespinasse of Dean Witter.</p>
<p>Export action was routine with Taiwan overnight buying 54,000 tonnes of U.S. corn and South Korea bought 52,500 tonnes of U.S. corn, export sources said.</p>
<p>Small-lot bear spreading boosted the deferred contracts.</p>
<p>Corn closed one to 3-1/2 cents per bushel higher, with March up one at $2.70-1/2.  </p>
<p>Cargill Inc spread four million bushels of May/July, Tenco Inc did three million July/March and FIMAT Futures spread two million bushels of July/March, traders said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Feed Grains Council Tuesday predicted U.S. corn production will rise modestly to 9.490 billion bushels this year. But the market continued to consolidate awaiting more definite direction from U.S. Midwest spring and summer weather patterns.</p>
<p>Technicians early Tuesday cited first support in March corn at $2.68-1/2 a bushel. The session low was $2.68. First resistance was pegged at $2.70 and second resistance at $2.71-1/2. The session high, set on the close, was $2.71-1/2.</p>
<p>The four- and 20-day moving averages were bullish early Tuesday, chartists reported.</p>
<p>On the day, Rosenthal Collins sold three million March but was a key buyer of at least 1.5 million March on the close, traders said. Tenco Inc sold 3.5 million March and Refco Inc sold two million March, traders said.</p>
<p>Corn futures volume was estimated by the CBOT at 45,000 contracts, above the 44,636 traded Monday.</p>
<p>In corn options, First Options bought 400 May $2.90 calls and sold 400 May $3.10 calls at 1-1/4 cents, Dean Witter sold 400 March $2.70 calls at 3-1/2 cents and sold 500 July $3.40 calls at 16-3/4 to 17 cents, traders said.</p>
<p>Corn options volume was estimated at 15,000 contracts, above the 14,287 traded Monday.</p>
<p>((Sam Nelson 312-408-8721))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
