<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354302" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: State Department contests Helms on chemical treaty.</title>
<headline>State Department contests Helms on chemical treaty.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Worsnip</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The State Department on Tuesday rejected attempts by Republican Sen. Jesse Helms to link ratification of a global chemical weapons ban to other issues such as foreign affairs restructuring and U.N. reform.</p>
<p>Spokesman Nicholas Burns said new Secretary of State Madeleine Albright &quot;strongly disagrees that these issues should be linked to Senate advice and consent to ratification of the Chemical Weapons Convention.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Each is an important issue ... that should be addressed on their own merits,&quot; Burns told a news briefing.</p>
<p>Helms, chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, Monday urged Senate Republican Leader Trent Lott to focus on several other security-related issues before dealing with the treaty and called for a series of conditions to Senate approval.</p>
<p>The Clinton administration wants the Senate to approve the 1993 treaty by April 29. If Washington does not ratify it by then, it will have no say in administration of the ban.</p>
<p>As committee chairman, Helms has the power to prevent the treaty, which he says is deficient, from going to the Senate floor.</p>
<p>In a letter to Lott, the North Carolina Republican listed other priorities that he said should come first, saying that when they had become law, &quot;We can turn our attention to the matter of the CWC.&quot;</p>
<p>On his list were legislation to fold three foreign affairs agencies into the State Department, reforming the United Nations, submitting modifications of two other arms treaties to the Senate and enacting legislation to deploy a national missile defence system.</p>
<p>Burns said Albright agreed with Helms that reorganizing foreign affairs agencies and reforming the United Nations were important issues on which she wanted to pursue a bipartisan approach.</p>
<p>But, he said, U.S. exclusion from administration of the chemical weapons treaty &quot;gets to our credibility and that affects negatively our leadership on a whole range of arms and proliferation issues.&quot;</p>
<p>The treaty bans production, stockpiling and use of chemical weapons. The United States and Russia, which also has not ratified the pact, are the only two countries which admit holding chemical weapons stocks.</p>
<p>Burns said Albright already had visited Congress twice since she was sworn in on Jan. 23 to talk about the treaty and planned to be in touch again with Helms in the next few days on the issue.</p>
<p>Helms returned to the attack on the treaty in a letter Tuesday to National Security Adviser Samuel Berger. In the letter, made public by his office, he said the treaty:</p>
<p>-- Did not cover all types of chemicals used to make chemical weapons.</p>
<p>-- Would not reduce chemical arsenals allegedly held by &quot;rogue states&quot; such as Libya, Syria, Iraq and North Korea, which have not signed the treaty.</p>
<p>-- Was not effectively verifiable.</p>
<p>-- Would impose onerous burdens on up to 8,000 U.S. firms that would be subject to inspections.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
