<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354464" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clintons &quot;very concerned&quot; about Harriman condition.</title>
<headline>Clintons &quot;very concerned&quot; about Harriman condition.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton and his wife Hillary are &quot;very concerned&quot; about Pamela Harriman, the U.S. ambassador to France who suffered a brain haemorrhage on Monday evening, and have asked to be kept informed of her condition, the White House said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The president and the first lady were very concerned to hear about Ambassador Harriman's condition,&quot; White House spokesman Mike McCurry told reporters. &quot;They've asked to be kept updated for any information that comes from our embassy in Paris. Obviously, she is in their thoughts and prayers.&quot;</p>
<p>McCurry declined comment on Harriman's medical codition.</p>
<p>In Paris, a U.S. embassy spokesman said on Tuesday that Harriman was in serious condition in the American Hospital of Paris after suffering a brain haemorrhage on Monday evening.</p>
<p>Harriman, 76, a close supporter of Clinton, was taken ill at the Ritz Hotel where she had gone for a swim and she was taken to hospital by ambulance.</p>
<p>&quot;The initial diagnosis is that the ambassador suffered a cerebral haemorrhage. She remains in serious condition,&quot; a U.S. embassy spokesman said in a brief statement read to reporters outside the hospital in the Paris suburb of Neuilly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
