<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354546" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Shorter Swedish bonds seen a good buy - analysts.</title>
<headline>Shorter Swedish bonds seen a good buy - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Barbara Taltavull</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shorter Swedish bonds are a good buy just now, but longer maturities are less appealing, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now bonds up to two years are worth buying. In addition the crown is relatively cheap,&quot; said Mary Davis, CS First Boston economist, to Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Swedish fundamentals look relatively good. There is a deflationary environment and the government's deviation from tight fiscal policy is acceptable,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Sweden would still probably meet Maastrict treaty criteria, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the goverment would risk not meeting the fundamental targets,&quot; Davis said.</p>
<p>U.S. investment bank PaineWebber also had a buy recommendation on Swedish bonds over Spanish ones on maturities from two to five years.</p>
<p>&quot;We recommend a swap from Spain to Sweden in the shorter end (two to five years). There will be more rate cuts in Sweden but in Spain much has already been discounted in rates,&quot; PaineWebber economist James McKay told Reuters.</p>
<p>Nomura economist Marco Pianelli also said he recommended buying Swedish bonds with maturities of between three to five years because he expected the yield curve to steepen somewhat.</p>
<p>For longer maturities, economists were less optimistic.</p>
<p>This was because of uncertainty regarding the European Union's monetary union and concern the Swedish government would lead a more expansionary fiscal policy ahead of its 1998 general election.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a risk in a pre-election year for popular measures. The risk premium remains high on the longer end because of that,&quot; McKay said.</p>
<p>Deutsche Morgan Grenfell economist Stephanie Pfeiffer said she was negative against Swedish bonds in general.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not go in at all. I believe that the spread between Swedish and German longer yields might increase to 130 basis points in the next few weeks,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think people are selling Swedish bonds, the crown is weakening and the overall environment is negative,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She was particularly concerned about government spending and the financing of its plan to start shutting down Sweden's nuclear programme.</p>
<p>This plan could cause increased clashes between the government and unions as well as higher electricity prices.</p>
<p>Ian Ganna, an economist at U.S. investment bank Chase, said the spread between Swedish and German longer yields would increase to 130 to 135 basis points.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as the crown weakens I would stand aside from Swedish bonds since yields could come up,&quot; Ganna said.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1019</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
