<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354589" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain's Ministry details 1996 public deficit data.</title>
<headline>Spain's Ministry details 1996 public deficit data.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's Economy Ministry gave the following explanation on Tuesday for the difference between the 1996 central government deficit on a national account basis system and on a cash basis:</p>
<p>(figures are in trillion pesetas)</p>
<p>    DEFICIT ON A CASH BASIS			   3.683</p>
<p>     - Adjustments					1.196</p>
<p>	 * Changes in payments/receipts  (1)	0.782</p>
<p>	 * Surprise shortfall		(2)	0.709</p>
<p>	 * Depreciation in debt			-0.226</p>
<p>	 * Interest accrued/paid	   (3)	0.023</p>
<p>	 * Privatisation		     (4)     -0.113</p>
<p>	 * Others					   0.023</p>
<p>    DEFICIT ON A NATIONAL ACCOUNT BASIS	   2.487</p>
<p>    GDP						    74.400</p>
<p>    DEFICIT OVER GDP				    3.3%</p>
<p>NOTE - The central government public deficit on a national account basis is the one considered relevant for the Maastricht Treaty, which sets out the economic requirements for Europe's single currency launch in 1999.</p>
<p>It takes into account accrued revenues and expenditures for a given period, while the deficit on a cash basis records actual money movements during a given month.</p>
<p>The changes in payments and receipts as in (1) are mainly due to the differences in the two accounting systems. In this figure around 450 billion pesetas are due to social security payments which are considered for the purposes of national accounting, but not on a cash basis, the statement said.</p>
<p>This gap (2) is due to the surprise shortfall for a total of 721.2 billion pesetas announced by the government last July.</p>
<p>(3) is due to a change in the way Spanish government accounts for the discounted prices at which the Treasury sells notes and bonds.</p>
<p>From now on it will include the discounted part as interest, accounted for in the same year as the sale.</p>
<p>Privatisation proceeds (4) are not taken into account under Maastricht criteria.</p>
<p>In November, the deficit was 2.156 trillion pesetas on a national account basis, and 2.13 trillion on a cash basis, excluding the effect of the shortfall.</p>
<p>-- Madrid Newsroom, + 341 585 8340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
