<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354572" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU seen set for new bid to cut cereals aid.</title>
<headline>EU seen set for new bid to cut cereals aid.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A further bid is likely to be made for a seven percent cut in EU cereals compensatory payments in order to make savings of more than two billion Ecus necessary to meet EU 1998 farm budget constraints, Commission sources said.</p>
<p>A similar move, which would have saved some 1.3 billion Ecus, was thrown out by farm ministers last autumn. But pressure is growing from EU finance ministers to curb spending to prepare for a single EU currency.</p>
<p>The costs of dealing with the mad cow crisis have also increased calls to make farm spending cuts across the board.</p>
<p>&quot;Cereals payments must be cut,&quot; one source said, noting cereals farmers received nearly 18 billion Ecus, or more than 40 percent of the EU agricultural budget.</p>
<p>The 1997 farm budget was 40.80 billion Ecus, virtually unchanged from 1996 and one billion Ecus less than proposed by the Commission.</p>
<p>Cereals compensatory payments, which absorb about one third of the EU farm budget, were increasingly difficult to justify, a source said.</p>
<p>The payments were agreed in 1992 to offset cuts in intervention prices but world market prices soared to record levels early last year and are still well above official support levels.</p>
<p>It was also hard to defend the payments when 10 percent of the largest cereals farmers received nearly all the aid, the source added.</p>
<p>Commission sources said the envisaged cereals aid cuts would cover only around half the savings needed. They noted last year several hundred million Ecus due to oilseed farmers in 1996 were delayed until 1997 and a similar ploy could be used again.</p>
<p>European Commissioners last week began discussions on the EU 1998 budget, which would normally be adopted by the European Parliament in December.</p>
<p>-Peter Blackburn, Brussels Bureau +322 287 6830</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
