<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354561" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS - Veba offers CW way out of link.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Veba offers CW way out of link.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Veba AG has paved the way for Britain's Cable and Wireless to back out of a strategic alliance with the German group and has begun searching for a new cooperation partner, a senior Veba source said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The source said Veba AG had made an offer to buy back a 45 percent stake in its subsidiary Vebacom from Cable &amp; Wireless.</p>
<p>If the offer, made a week ago, were to be accepted, Veba would turn the stake over to a trustee in the hope of later transferring it to a new partner, the source said.</p>
<p>Veba declined to confirm or deny the source's comments.</p>
<p>The offer to C&amp;W sets the arena for a reshuffle in alliances in the global telecommunications market.</p>
<p>Veba declined to comment on press reports that it had been approached by SBC Communications of the United States. But it confirmed that it was talking to several potential buyers of a stake in its telecoms venture.</p>
<p>Separately, the head of Global One, the joint venture of Deutsche Telekom, France Telecom and Sprint Corp, also declined to comment on speculation the company was in talks with Cable and Wireless.</p>
<p>No comment,&quot; Global One's Viesturs Vucins told reporters in Munich when asked about press reports that C &amp; W was interested in joining the three-way telecommunications alliance.</p>
<p>C&amp;W confirmed it was in talks with Veba about the future of the partnership, but gave no details.</p>
<p>C&amp;W formed the strategic alliance, called Vebacom, in 1995. Last year, the two firms agreed to bring RWE into the fold and final contracts were drawn up two weeks ago.</p>
<p>But C&amp;W has not signed the deal, sparking speculation it is about to pull out amid rumours it was talking to Global One.</p>
<p>The German source said the change of heart had come because C&amp;W was now following a new strategy, which meant it intended to pull out of business in continental Europe and focus more heavily on the British market.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the offer made to Cable and Wireless, Veba would retain its 10.4 percent stake in Cable &amp; Wireless as an investment, the sources said.</p>
<p>The source said that although the stake had been purchased as a means to cement the strategic alliance it had proved to be a good financial investment. Veba paid 2.2 billion marks ($1.3 billion) for the stake, which is now worth around three billion marks.</p>
<p>But even though the stake would be maintained, Veba board chairman Ulrich Hartmann would give up his seat on the British company's board, the source said.</p>
<p>He said the seat was linked to the company's strategic alliance rather than its financial investment in the group.</p>
<p>Veba would also return its stake in joint venture group C&amp;W Europe to the British company, the source said. ($ = 1.640 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
