<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354590" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Montedison 1996 operating profits rise.</title>
<headline>Montedison 1996 operating profits rise.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian agro-industry and chemicals group Montedison on Tuesday reported 1996 net operating profits of 1.995 trillion lire after 1.912 trillion in 1995 on annual sales up at 24.190 trillion lire against 24.176 trillion.</p>
<p>A Montedison statement said net debt at end-1996 fell to 8.386 trillion lire from 10.158 trillion at end-1995. Compart, formerly Ferruzzi Finanziara, which holds around a 31 percent stake in Montedison, said its 1996 net operating profit rose to around 2.0 trillion lire from 1.957 trillion.  </p>
<p>The preliminary Montedison figures for 1996 showed that of the group's four main operating areas, only energy showed an increase in operating profits, while the other areas of agro-industry, chemicals and engineering showed falls.</p>
<p>Revenue at Montedison's energy interests rose nearly 46 percent in 1996 and while agro-industry revenue increased nearly one percent, sales in chemicals and engineering slipped.</p>
<p>Montedison and Compart -- then Ferruzzi -- almost collapsed under a mountain of debt in 1993, and had to be rescued by a group of banks which continue to hold around 70 percent of Compart's shares.</p>
<p>Montedison returned to the black in 1995 with a net consolidated profit of 1.07 trillion lire after a loss of 345 billion lire in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
