<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354698" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Sharif aide doubts IMF deficit target can be met.</title>
<headline>Sharif aide doubts IMF deficit target can be met.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Lyon</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's new government under Nawaz Sharif, thrust to power by a landslide election victory, will promote economic growth, but may not meet a key IMF-agreed target this year, a senior Sharif aide said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The four percent target may take another year or so, rather than June this year,&quot; Sartaj Aziz, secretary-general of Sharif's Pakistan Muslim League and finance minister in the last PML government, told Reuters Financial Television in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;But I think on the whole the IMF package would not be difficult to implement if business confidence is restored and we are able to accelerate the industrial growth and increase exports,&quot; Aziz said.</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund agreed to resume and expand a stalled standby loan in December after the caretaker government promised to cut the budget deficit to four percent of gross domestic product (GDP) by the end of the 1996/97 (July-June) financial year.</p>
<p>The deficit stood at 6.3 percent of GDP in 1995/96.</p>
<p>Aziz, widely expected to serve as finance minister in the new government, declined to say if he would regain that post.</p>
<p>&quot;In a week or 10 days' time when the prime minister takes oath then he will decide the composition of his cabinet and as a member of his team, whatever role he gives me I'll be ready to play,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Results from Monday's national and provincial elections showed the PML sweeping to a landslide victory against ousted prime minister Benazir Bhutto's Pakistan People's Party (PPP).</p>
<p>Aziz said the new government's priority would be to restore business confidence, revive the industrial sector and increase exports to stabilise the balance of payments. It would also seek to accelerate privatisation and economic reform.</p>
<p>&quot;If we create the market economy, remove subsidies and distortions, then along with reduction in the budget deficit, the government will be ready for foreign investment to come in on a substantial scale,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;So I think Pakistan, both in the economic and political fields...is likely to turn the corner and start moving very rapidly upward, both in terms of investment and growth.&quot;</p>
<p>The last Sharif government, which lasted 30 months from 1990 to 1993, gained credit with international lending agencies and investors for starting to liberalise and deregulate the economy and launching a privatisation programme.</p>
<p>But it came under fire for lavish spending on big infrastructure projects and costly popular credit schemes.</p>
<p>Aziz said the new government would have to keep spending under control, but hoped that a revival of growth would increase tax revenue and help to balance the books.</p>
<p>&quot;For the first few months of course we can't afford any expensive projects because we have to contain expenditure,&quot; he said. &quot;But my expectation is that if the economy begins to move up, then we will get more revenue from existing taxes.&quot;</p>
<p>Aziz said it was vital for Pakistan's prospects of recovery to project a stable image and avoid the power struggles of the past between the president and the prime minister.</p>
<p>Asked about last month's creation of a new Council for Defence and National Security by President Farooq Leghari, he said the new parliament would see how the body functioned.</p>
<p>&quot;If the council were to concentrate on security matters and its relationship with the foreign policy and economic policy, to that extent, I do not anticipate any problems,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there are a lot of legitimate functions that can be performed within the existing constitutional framework, in other words, without giving the president executive powers, which the constitution does not give,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The past four governments, including two led by Benazir Bhutto and one by Sharif, have been sacked by presidents, who have controversial powers to dissolve the National Assembly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
