<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="354977" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain, under pressure, demands fair hearing on EMU.</title>
<headline>Spain, under pressure, demands fair hearing on EMU.</headline>
<byline>Sharman Esarey</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain, anxious to silence a debate that has sent its financial markets tumbling, insisted on Tuesday that its economic health would likely secure it a place at the launch of Europe's common currency in 1999.</p>
<p>The peseta tumbled to six-month lows and the benchmark government bond future lost nearly a point on Monday as the markets were hit by talk that Spain, despite its undisputed economic progress, might still be shunned by an exclusive founding club.</p>
<p>Although the markets steadied on Tuesday, top Spanish government officials were quick to downplay talk Spain might be excluded, saying the economic facts should speak for themselves.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Abel Matutes, on a visit to Portugal, reiterated that Spain's economy was sound enough to give it a good chance of being in the first wave of countries to merge their money into a single currency.</p>
<p>&quot;Spain has every probability of joining the first stage of economic and monetary Union,&quot; Matutes said.</p>
<p>&quot;This government is firmly committed to meeting Maastricht criteria, which are the only conditions that will determine which countries will join this union in its first stage and which will not.&quot;</p>
<p>Based on this commitment, Spanish financial markets drove higher for months. A consensus formed that the nation had done its economic homework and would manage to be at the launch.</p>
<p>Inflation tumbled, long-term interest rates fell, the peseta steadied and the government tightened up the budget, narrowed the deficit, and set to work on Spain's debt.</p>
<p>&quot;What really matters is how economic and financial fundamentals are doing,&quot; Budget Secretary Jose Folgado told journalists.</p>
<p>&quot;Entry into European monetary union will not depend on third party opinions but on the targets being met as written in the (Maastricht) Treaty...If these criteria are met, it doesn't matter what certain people say,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But not everyone sees it this way, particularly in northern Europe. For them Spain's economic clean-up remains suspect because of its swiftness. The memory of a series of peseta devaluations that only ended in the spring of 1995 have left a deep impression.</p>
<p>Furthermore, critics contend that politically it would be difficult to allow Spain entry but exclude Italy, which has more political clout but whose economic pulse is weak.</p>
<p>Spain, aware of these fears, has taken the tack that its potential entry should be a cut-and-dried numbers process. But the strategy has not put off the critics.</p>
<p>Last week, Juergen Stark, the number two at Germany's Finance Ministry, said merely fulfilling the economic goals was not good enough to get in at the start.</p>
<p>And on Monday, a top German banker said the debate about Italy and Spain's chances was unsettling markets and it would be better to announce soon that only a small block of countries would go forward.</p>
<p>His comments followed remarks over the weekend by other German bankers that there would be turmoil on financial markets if countries like Italy joined from the start.</p>
<p>--Madrid Newsroom +34 1 585 2167</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
