<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="355010" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - London Evening Standard - Feb 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - London Evening Standard - Feb 4.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>EVENING STANDARD</p>
<p>3,000 HEADS NOT FIT FOR SCHOOLS</p>
<p>Chris Woodhead, the Government's chief inspector of schools, today described the leadership skills of one in seven primary school heads and one in 10 secondary school heads as 'weak', and linked poor performance in schools to to 'poor management and weak leadership by the head'.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>COOK CHIEF READY TO STEP UP BID BATTLE</p>
<p>Andrew Cook, the chairman of William Cook, is believed to be ready to increase his takeover bid for the company, in partnership with venture capital outfit Electra Fleming, if Triplex Lloyd raises its own offer. This latest move in an increasingly bitter struggle for control of the company could see William Cook's value increased to almost 90m pounds stg.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>DOUBLE BOOST HAS THE DOLLAR MARCHING ON</p>
<p>The dollar continued to rise in overnight trading, boosted by heavy buying of D-marks and sterling against the yen, and reports of difficulties for Gajoen Kanko, a major Japanese hotels operator.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>BLUE-CHIP PATH FOR UNION PROTESTORS</p>
<p>100 sacked trade unionists disrupted the annual general meeting of blue-chip kitchen manufacturer Magnet last Thursday, to draw attention to the company's poor performance following the dismissal of 300 skilled workers at the group's Darlington factory last September. Surprised shareholders were regaled with choruses of 'Your shares are going down'.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>CLOTHING OUTFIT FAILS TO SUIT THE CHINESE</p>
<p>Giordano International Holdings, makers of fashionable clothes and once the darling of foreign investors, lost a quarter of its capitalisation on the Hong Kong market last week following news that negotiations to open retail outlets in Shanghai and Beijing had hit problems. While operations on the Chinese mainland constituted only 17 percent of Giordano's last reported profits, their main markets of Taiwan, Hong Kong and Singapore are unlikely to grow much in the future, and China was seen by investors as vital to the company's future.</p>
<p>-- BMC +44 71 377 1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
