<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="355212" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Feb 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Feb 4.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following stories were reported in Tuesday's electronic version of The Wall Street Journal:</p>
<p>* Mercury Finance Chief Executive John Brincat resigned, and agents from the Federal Bureau of Investigation collected records from the company's headquarters.</p>
<p>* Strong Capital Management, a Milwaukee mutual-fund- management firm, bought back from its funds some Mercury Finance commercial paper that Mercury failed to meet a payment on, thereby preventing three of its funds from dropping below the $1 net asset value the funds try to maintain.</p>
<p>* General Motors' U.S. sales of cars and light trucks fell 0.9 percent in January, and Chrysler's sales increased two percent.</p>
<p>* Kmart and Waban are discussing combining their home improvement businesses in a deal that would give investment banking firm Leonard Green a majority stake in the new entity.</p>
<p>* Manufacturing activity grew slightly slower in January than December, which many analysts believe is an indication of the overall trend of the economy for early 1997.</p>
<p>* A White House panel is proposing sweeping air safety measures, but U.S. carriers are opposing the costly plans.</p>
<p>* A food-safety rule issued by the Clinton administration will require poultry inspectors to only check a few birds for contamination on production lines.</p>
<p>* Issuance of 100-year bonds may taper off with a Treasury proposal to limit corporate tax deductions for interest on such securities.</p>
<p>* The car-rental industry is seeking to raise rates as much as 10 percent in major markets, the first significant price increase in five years.</p>
<p>* ITT Corp is expected to keep Hilton Hotels waiting at least another week before presenting an expected rejection of Hilton's hostile offer.</p>
<p>* The Bancroft family issued a statement unanimously in favor of maintaining Dow Jones' independence.</p>
<p>* Baker &amp; Taylor is the target of a suit joined by the Justice Department accusing it of overcharging public schools, libraries and federal agencies $100 to $200 milion.</p>
<p>* Japan auctioned key Tokyo properties for $3.07 billion.</p>
<p>* AT&amp;T Chief Financial Officer Richard Miller plans to resign at the end of this quarter.</p>
<p>* Investors sold off Italian and Spanish bonds amid worries that Germany could block those countries from early participation in a single European currency.</p>
<p>* U.K. cable television and telephone operator stocks fell more than 10 percent after British Sky Broadcasting Plc said it would bid for a digital TV license.</p>
<p>* Thailand's benchmark stock index plunged 3.4 percent.</p>
<p>* WMX Tuesday, as the analysts are calling it, is upon us.</p>
<p>Anticipating big news about WMX Technologies' restructuring plans when the waste management group announces its earnings today, investors have bid the stock up more than 11 percent since January 6 - more than double the gain of the Standard &amp; Poor's 500-stock index. -- Heard on the Street.</p>
<p>* Bonds ran their winning streak to five sessions in a row, helped by a fresh dose of upbeat economic news and renewed optimism that interest rates will remain stable for the foreseeable future. -- Credit Markets.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
