<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="355448" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks end cautious trade slightly lower.</title>
<headline>French stocks end cautious trade slightly lower.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>French stocks ended slightly lower on Tuesday, pressured by early weakness on Wall Street and nervousness ahead of the start of a two-day U.S. Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting.</p>
<p>Traders say caution will also prevail on Wednesday as no news is expected to come from the FOMC meeting on the outlook for U.S. interest rates until late in the day.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index finished down 5.48 points, or 0.22 percent, at 2,503.07, while the CAC-40 February futures contract settled seven points lower at 2,509.</p>
<p>Volume was 7.99 billion francs.</p>
<p>&quot;People are feeling a bit cautious. It makes sense to take profits at these levels,&quot; a trader said. The CAC is not far from its year high of 2,521.88 points.</p>
<p>He said the market was consolidating its recent gains as it awaited fresh direction. &quot;That'll probably be set by the FOMC,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Shares in electrical engineering firm Alcatel Alsthom fell 1.11 percent to 536 francs.</p>
<p>Traders said Morgan Stanley placed 1.2 million Alcatel shares at 536 francs. Alcatel said it did not know who the seller was.</p>
<p>Shares in Generale des Eaux and publishing group Havas extended their gains on Tuesday after confirming newspaper reports on Monday that they were discussing their audiovisual activities, notably Canal Plus.</p>
<p>Newspapers said the operations under discussion would make Havas the biggest shareholder in Canal Plus and Generale des Eaux the key shareholder in Havas.</p>
<p>The Figaro said on Tuesday that bank Societe Generale also planned to swap its stake in Canal Plus for a larger share in Havas. Societe Generale declined comment.</p>
<p>Generale des Eaux shares rose 1.25 percent to 728 francs.</p>
<p>Canal Plus shares ended 0.25 percent lower at 1,174 francs.</p>
<p>Havas shares rose 1.7 percent to 431.20 francs, and Societe Generale's stock closed down 1.72 percent at 628 francs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
