<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="355579" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Morning Update.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Morning Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>POLICE INVESTIGATING SENATOR'S EXPENSES</p>
<p>The Australian Federal Police has confirmed its investigating allegations relating to the use by Liberal Senator Bob Woods of parliamentary expenses.</p>
<p>Senator Woods last night announced he was resigning from the Senate because of personal reasons.</p>
<p>A Federal Police spokesman says officers have been interviewing several people during the investigation, but can't confirm the nature of the allegations involving Senator Woods.</p>
<p>Senator Woods, the Parliamentary Secretary for Health, has been in politics for nearly ten years.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PROSPECTS FOR INTEREST RATES CUT FALLING</p>
<p>Foreign exchange dealers say comments overnight in Switzerland by Finance Minister, John Fahey, make an early cut in official interest rates less likely.</p>
<p>Mr Fahey is being seen as playing down the prospect of an interest rate cut until it beocme clearer where wages are heading.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar strengthened by about a quarter of a cent overnight and foreign exchange dealers say that was prompted by Mr Fahey's remarks.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank, holding its monthly board meeting today, has already expressed unease about the ACTU's safety net wage claim.</p>
<p>But industry wants the bank to go ahead with another interest rate cut.</p>
<p>The ANZ Bank has cut the interest rate on its basic variable rate home loan to six-point-9-5 percent, ahead of today's Reserve Bank meeting.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHARLEVILLE SEEKS COMMONWEALTH HELP</p>
<p>An airflift of emergency supplies for the flood-ravaged Queensland town of Charleville is expected to be made later today.</p>
<p>The State Disaster Coordination Centre has asked for tents, stretchers, cooking equipment and staff, to assist the 250 residents who've been forced to leave their homes.</p>
<p>The residents are camped at the local high school and more evacuations are expected with the flood expected to peak early tonight.</p>
<p>Jack Vintner from the Coordination centre says the supplies will be flown from Brisbane, most likely on a Defence Force aircraft.</p>
<p>Road and rail links to Charleville are cut by flooding.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>NATIVE TITLE TALKS TO CONTINUE TODAY</p>
<p>The Prime Minister will continue discussions on native title today, meeting Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Commission representatives.</p>
<p>Mr Howard has already heard from State and Territory leaders, the National Farmers Federation and the Minerals Council of Australia.</p>
<p>Most States and the Farmers Federation are calling for Commonwealth legislation to extinguish native title rights on pastoral leases.</p>
<p>The Minerals Council doesn't believe that is the best option ... and ATSIC is strongly opposed to it.</p>
<p>Today's meeting with ATSIC is the first of two Mr Howard will be holding with Aboriginal leaders this week.</p>
<p>Mr Howard is also expected to outline Cabinet's proposals for a people's convention and vote on an Australian Republic at today's Coalition party meeting - the first one for the year.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CLAIMS AGREEMENT WILL LEAD TO JOB LOSES</p>
<p>The Federal Opposition says the first regional forest agreement will lead to jobs being lost because it doesn't encourage companies to invest in the local industry.</p>
<p>The East Gippsland regional forest agreement was signed by the Prime Minister and Victorian Premier yesterday.</p>
<p>There will be ten more such agreements across Australia.</p>
<p>Mr Howard says they will create jobs.</p>
<p>But Labor Resoures Spokesman, Neil O'Keefe, says the Federal Government has scrapped the incentive for companies to invest in Australia by allowing increased woodchip exports.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BELL'S SOLICITOR SAYS EXTRADITION EXPECTED</p>
<p>A solicitor representing alleged paedophile Philip Bell says it looks certain that his client will be extradited from South Africa to Australia to stand trial.</p>
<p>The admission came ahead of extradition proceedings which begin in the South African town of Humansdorp today.</p>
<p>Australian authorities are seeking Philip Bell's extradition to face 215 warrants relating to incidents involving underage boys.</p>
<p>Philip Bell has repeatedly claimed he is being persecuted over his lifestyle.</p>
<p>He has compared himself to Oscar Wilde, the nineteenth century Irish poet who was jailed for sodomy.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
