<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="355518" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - Feb 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - Feb 4.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>-- LABOUR WARNS BA OVER SWITCH TO GATWICK</p>
<p>Andrew Smith, the shadow transport secretary, has warned British Airways that a future Labour government would fiercely resist any attempts by the airline to try to release runway slots at Heathrow airport by switching domestic services to Gatwick. BA has announced plans to switch some domestic UK services to Gatwick in order to free up more Heathrow slots for US services. Smith has threatened to use powers under EU regulations to protect Heathrow services for regional flights.</p>
<p>-- KPMG FIRST TO SHOW EXTERNALLY AUDITED ACCOUNTS</p>
<p>Accountancy firm KPMG has published results showing its fee income rose 6 percent last year to 624 million stg, and average profits per partner went up 12 percent to 206,000 stg. It was the first time one of the 'Big Six' UK accountancy firms has published externally audited accounts. KPMG was audited by competitor Grant Thornton, and the two firms plan to press for a new statement of practice to cover non-corporate accounts and introduce standard rules for firms privately reporting.</p>
<p>-- BANK TO LAUNCH PLANS FOR MONEY MARKET REFORMS</p>
<p>The Bank of England is set to introduce far-reaching changes to the way it operates in the money markets and supplies liquidity to clearing banks. A statement is expected Tuesday about the launch, which is likely to start next month. The Bank is also expected to announce a transition period of up to two years to cushion the effect on discount houses.</p>
<p>-- FA SET FOR LONG BATTLE TO STAGE WORLD CUP IN 2006</p>
<p>The English Football Association (FA) is to proceed with an 10 million stg campaign to promote England's bid to stage the soccer World Cup in 2006. The FA has secured the support of Downing Street for the campaign and of the FA's of Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland. The move comes after weekend revelations that Eufa, the governing body of European soccer, is controversially backing the German bid to host the event.</p>
<p>-- EU RAPS 'PREDATORY' GERMAN POST OFFICE</p>
<p>European Commission officials have accused Deutsche Post, the German post office, of engaging in predatory pricing since 1984 in a bid to drive rival parcel services out of business. Deutsche Post, a monopoly, is also accused of abusing its dominant position in the letters market to subsidise its parcel services and offering substantial discounts to big business users. A formal statement by the commission is expected shortly.</p>
<p>-- COURT WIN FOR SCOTTISH POWER</p>
<p>Utility Scottish Power has won a case in the Court of Appeal that could lead to electricity consumers in the south of Scotland paying up to 15 pounds stg in the coming year. The Court upheld a challenge by Scottish Power to a decision by industry regulator Professor Stephen Littlechild over the choice of yardstick for the average of generation costs for the under 100KW market in England and Wales.</p>
<p>-- PREMIER LEAGUE PONDERS PAY-PER-VIEW</p>
<p>The Premier League in England has appointed consultants Oliver &amp; Ohlbaum to advise on the market for pay-per-view soccer. The move comes in advance of the start of negotiations between the Premiership and satellite broadcaster BSkyB, which currently has a 670-million-stg, four-year contract to broadcast Premier League games. The Premiership is thought to be under pressure from some large clubs, many of which have floated on the stock exchange, to introduce pay-per-view.</p>
<p>-- BOOST FOR INDUSTRY EASES RECESSION FEAR</p>
<p>The latest survey from the Chartered Institute of Purchasing and Supply shows an unexpected turnaround in manufacturing activity last month. The survey shows factories took on more staff than at any time since March 1995 as activity accelerated for the first time since October. The turnaround will ease fears that industry could be heading back into recession. Separately, Bank of England figures showed a rapid expansion in January of the amount of cash in circulation, suggesting an upsurge in consumer activity after disappointing Christmas sales figure.</p>
<p>-- ALCATEL MAY LEAD BID FOR THOMSON</p>
<p>French telecoms and engineering group Alcatel Alsthom is reported to be in talks with aircraft companies Aerospatiale and Dassault over a joint bid for French state electronics company Thomson-CSF, which is due to be privatised later this year. If the alliance were to bid for Thomson it would meet fierce resistance from Lagardere, the defence equipment group that appeared to have won control of Thomson last autumn before a government commission intervened.</p>
<p>-- SBC MAY REPLACE C&amp;W IN ALLIANCE</p>
<p>US regional telephone company SBC Communications has become a possible replacement for Cable &amp; Wireless in a telecoms alliance in Germany after reports the UK group has decided to part company with two proposed German partners. Veba and RWE, the German utilities, had planned to link with C&amp;W to attack the German telecoms market from 1998, but C&amp;W is understood to be ready to withdraw from the alliance as new chairman Richard Brown continues to re-evaluate C&amp;W's international strategies.</p>
<p>For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
