<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="355752" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Suba says tax pushes alcohol sales down.</title>
<headline>Suba says tax pushes alcohol sales down.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian trading firm PT Suba Indah said on Tuesday sales of its alcoholic drinks in 1996 fell sharply after the government issued a new tax regulation last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Sales of our alcoholic drinks fell 40 to 50 percent in 1996 compared with 1995 after the government issued a regulation which levied higher taxes on the drinks,&quot; corporate secretary Maurice Pawadi told Reuters.</p>
<p>Pawadi declined to give details on the tax, but said the new tax had forced the firm to raise prices in some cases by more than 100 percent which led to lower demand.  </p>
<p>He said sales of its alcoholic drinks in 1995 reached 14 billion rupiah from total annual sales of some 60 billion rupiah.</p>
<p>Suba Indah briefly rose 175 rupiah to 2,600 rupiah in active trading on Tuesday, but profit-taking cut the gain to 50 rupiah in late trading. It had made strong gains on Monday.</p>
<p>Pawadi denied market speculation that the firm was likely to be acquired by another company. He added that Suba did not plan to make any corporate moves which could have a significant impact on the firm.</p>
<p>Pawadi, however, said the firm's sales of its syrup, other non-alcoholic drinks and snack foods were expected to rise in 1996 compared with 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall our total sales in 1996 may be slightly lower or higher than in 1995 as sales of alcoholic drinks are seen down while sales from other divisions are seen up,&quot; Pawadi said.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
