<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="355757" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine export growth slows but seen positive.</title>
<headline>Philippine export growth slows but seen positive.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippines merchandise exports grew at a slower pace of 17.7 percent in 1996 to $20.531 billion from $17.447 billion in 1995 due to a slackening in electronics and garment exports, the National Statistics Office said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>This compared with a 29 percent expansion in 1995 from $13.484 billion in 1994.</p>
<p>The agency said garments, the country's no. 2 export earner, fell by 4.9 percent to $2.44 billion in 1996 from $2.569 billion as the sector was outpriced by more competitive countries. Garments comprised 12 percent of the merchandise exports for 1996.</p>
<p>Electronics and components, which continued to be the leading earner with a 39.8 percent share of the total for the year, increased by 40 percent to $8.167 billion from $5.834 billion, the agency said. However, exports from the sector had grown 64 percent in 1995 from $3.557 billion in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;The international glut in export economies both in electronics and the garment industries affected our exports,&quot; said Ricky Supangan, an economist of University of Asia and the Pacific.</p>
<p>&quot;The latest figures on exports justified our projections. I was expecting a growth of 17.5 to 18 percent,&quot; said Emma Pante, an economist with Far East Bank and Trust Co.</p>
<p>&quot;1996 showed more realistic growth rates,&quot; said Pante, adding that the 1995 growth had been computed from a very low base.</p>
<p>Analysts pointed out the nation's export performance compared favourably with other countries in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;We're the only ones with double-digit growth rates in the region,&quot; Pante said. South Korea, Singapore and Taiwan were hurt badly by the slowdown in electronics demand worldwide while Thailand's exports suffered from a stronger currency, she said.</p>
<p>Analysts said exports this year would see a steady growth of 19 to 20 percent to about $24.5 billion as foreign investments that came in recent years are expected to go on stream.</p>
<p>An expected slightly weaker peso this year, seen at an average of 26.715/26.80 from 26.215 last year, would also help exports, they said. The weaker peso would be influenced by a projected wider deficit this year from capital equipment and heavy aircraft purchases.</p>
<p>And the United States, which was the Philippines' main market for its exports, is expected to see solid growth in 1997 which would translate to higher exports for the country, analysts said. About 35.7 percent of the country's exports in 1996 went to U.S. markets.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (632) 841-8937</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
