<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="355851" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan private demand strength recognisable -- BOJ.</title>
<headline>Japan private demand strength recognisable -- BOJ.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of Japan governor Yasuo Matsushita told a business symposium on Tuesday that the strength of Japan's private sector demand was becoming recognisable.  </p>
<p>Matsushita said private-sector demand was strengthening despite the fact that public spending was declining, showing that the favourable economic cycle was moving forward.</p>
<p>&quot;It should be noted that we are able to recognise that the economic cycle is moving forward,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Matsushita said recent falls in stock prices and interest rates meant that market participants remained cautious about the outlook for Japan's economy.  </p>
<p>&quot;Looking at the stock market weakness and the decline in long-term interest rates you can reach the conclusion that there is a lingering caution about the outlook for the economy,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Matsushita said the central bank was watching the impact of fiscal consolidation on the economy.</p>
<p>He said the central bank would have to watch fiscal factors such as the decrease in public works spending, the planned increase in the consumption tax, and the planned discontinuation of special income tax cuts.  </p>
<p>Matsushita said pressure from changes in the structure of Japan industry was likely to decrease and this was shown by a rise in capital spending at smaller firms and an improving employment situation.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking at recent movements in capital spending and at improvements in employment, it is safe to say that structural adjustments have progressed significantly.&quot;  </p>
<p>Matsushita said Japan's problem loan issue was being addressed steadily.</p>
<p>However, he said the amount of problem loans that needed to be dealt with remained large and urged banks to increase their assets and strengthen risk management and profitability.</p>
<p>Although banks had been applying stricter standards in making loans, they were eager to increase loans to good borrowers to help speed up their bad loan disposals, he said.</p>
<p>Looking from the point of view of corporations, bank lending rates were at record-low levels and banks were relaxed about making loans.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's difficult to think that financial institutions are becoming stricter about lending and thus obstructing recoveries in companies' capital spending,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Matsushita said the decline in domestic prices was likely to show clear signs of halting as a result of the weak yen and higher oil prices pushing up the price of imports, as well as tightening domestic supply and demand conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;However we see little possibility for now that domestic prices will show a clear rising trend, taking into account a gradual improvement in demand/supply conditions and pressure from global competition,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Matsushita added that the central bank would keep careful watch over price movements after the increase in the consumption tax on April 1. The BOJ will watch to see whether the tax increase will spark inflation worries, he said.  </p>
<p>If the current economic recovery continued, there was a possibility that private demand would strengthen further and this may help absorb the effects of reduced fiscal support, he said.</p>
<p>Matsushita said the speed of economic recovery may decrease in the first half of the next fiscal year but there was a good possibility that the general trend of recovery would continue.  </p>
<p>Matsushita said that looking at production overall, the level of economic activity was nearing levels seen in strong recovery phases of the past.</p>
<p>But he added that the BOJ would continue to conduct its monetary policy with the aim of ensuring a basis for a self-sustainable economic recovery.  </p>
<p>Referring to the foreign exchange markets, Matsushita said that currencies should move in a stable manner and reflect countries' economic fundamentals.</p>
<p>He said recent foreign exchange movements had been rather rapid and the central bank needed to monitor the situation closely.</p>
<p>Matsushita also said that while the BOJ highly regards the government's policy of deregulating the forex market, deregulation in other financial sectors had to be carried out swiftly as well.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless other deregulation measures are carried out quickly, the reform of the foreign exchange laws may invite an outflow of financial transactions and lead to a hollowing out of the Tokyo market,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
