<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="355954" id="root" date="1997-02-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: U.S. ambassador to France ill in hospital.</title>
<headline>U.S. ambassador to France ill in hospital.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Ambassador to France Pamela Harriman fell ill in Paris on Monday evening but the cause has not yet been diagnosed, American embassy spokesman Chris Snow said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In Washington, some U.S. officials said Harriman, 76, had apparently suffered a stroke.</p>
<p>&quot;She is at the American Hospital in Neuilly (outside Paris) where she is being treated and the situation is being evaluated,&quot; Snow told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said Harriman was exercising when she was taken ill.</p>
<p>U.S. State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said Harriman had &quot;fainted and fell ill&quot;. Her son Winston Spencer Churchill was at her bedside, he added.</p>
<p>A senior U.S. official, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said: &quot;I understand she's very, very ill. I heard it was a stroke.&quot;</p>
<p>CNN quoted a senior administration official as saying Harriman was rushed to the hospital, where she remained unconscious. The official said Harriman was &quot;very close to death&quot;.</p>
<p>No immediate comment was available from the hospital.</p>
<p>American newspapers reported last year that Harriman wanted to leave Paris but she issued a statement denying any move was imminent and saying she would follow President Bill Clinton's wishes.</p>
<p>Harriman, whose full name is Pamela Digby Churchill Hayward Harriman, was born in Farnborough, England, and became a naturalised U.S. citizen after marrying her third husband, the late multimillionaire financier and diplomat W. Averell Harriman in 1971.</p>
<p>Her first marriage took place during the Second World War at the age of 19 to Randolph Churchill, son of British leader Winston Churchill. They divorced as the war ended but the marriage produced her only child.</p>
<p>Harriman was national co-chairman of the 1992 Clinton-Al Gore presidential campaign. After Clinton was elected late that year, one of his first stops in Washington was a dinner party at Harriman's smart Georgetown home. For her favours to his party, Clinton named her ambassador to France in 1993, one of the most sought after diplomatic appointments.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
