<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="356240" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Best of times for Intel stock behind it - Prudential.</title>
<headline>Best of times for Intel stock behind it - Prudential.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Intel Corp's spectacular performance both in terms of financial results and stock price appreciation since 1995 may prove difficult to repeat in upcoming years, Prudential analyst Mark Edelstone said.</p>
<p>In comments detailing the move to cut his rating to hold from buy on the world's top computer chip maker, Edelstone wrote that, &quot;We believe 1996 represented the Best of Times for Intel's fundamentals and performance of INTC (the stock).&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;But we expect risk factors to increase in 1997 and 1998,&quot; he said, noting how a historic confluence of strong PC demand, limited competition and the move to Pentium was now behind it.  </p>
<p>Traders said the Prudential analyst's pessimistic comments were behind a sharp selloff in Intel shares that had driven the stock down 8-1/4 to 157-1/4 by Wednesday afternoon.</p>
<p>&quot;Although we believe 1997 willl be another year of strong revenue and earnings growth, we believe Intel's level of earnings risk will increase significantly over last year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While noting that the company's product pipeline for 1997 includes the next generation of its Pentium Pro, code-named Klamath, and a new multimedia version of Pentium, he said he expected minimal software to be ready to harness such power.  </p>
<p>Edelstone cautioned that &quot;the initial transition (to MMX-based Pentiums) could cause some hesitation among PC buyers during the next couple of quarters.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the forthcoming Klamath Pentium Pro chips offer &quot;limited improvement in performance over the current Pentium Pro versions, (which) could lead to a slower-than-expected ramp once demand from early adopters has been satisfied.&quot;</p>
<p>While noting that the risks associated with product transitions are difficult to predict, agressive price cuts and the end of a cycle of manufacturing improvements may have caused Intel's gross profit margins to peak, the analyst said.  </p>
<p>This could cause near-term margin and earnings pressure, he said.</p>
<p>Although the introduction of Advanced Micro Devices Inc's Pentium-rival K6 chip is unlikely to reduce Intel's market share in 1997, Advanced Micro could force Intel to make price cuts and be in position to take meaningful share in 1998, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe investors should recognize that INTC's spectacular advance already discounts much of the strength in the company's fundamentals,&quot; he wrote.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact, we believe 1997 may be a repeat of 1993, when Intel's earnings more than doubled and the stock only advanced six percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;At our $170 (price target), we believe it is fairly valued,&quot; Edelstone said.  &quot;We expect the stock to remain a market perfomer during the remainder of the year.&quot;</p>
<p>Edelstone's office said the analyst was traveling and not immediately available to comment.</p>
<p>((-- E. Auchard, Wall Street bureau, 212-859-1736))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
