<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="356425" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-TAGLIABUE TO REVIEW JETS' DEALS WITH PARCELLS, BELICHICK.</title>
<headline>NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-TAGLIABUE TO REVIEW JETS' DEALS WITH PARCELLS, BELICHICK.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Football League put a hold on Bill Parcells' latest career move Wednesday until Commissioner Paul Tagliabue completes a review of the deals that Parcells and Bill Belichick signed with the New York Jets.</p>
<p>Tagliabue, responding to a formal protest by New England Patriots owner Robert Kraft, asked the Jets to furnish him with copies of agreements announced Tuesday that made former Patriots coach Parcells a Jets consultant and Belichick the temporary head coach.</p>
<p>The commissioner directed that Parcells cannot perform any services for the Jets pending completion of the review, the league said in a statement Wednesday.</p>
<p>Tagliabue ruled last week that Parcells, who coached New England to the Super Bowl last season, could not serve as a head coach in the NFL in 1997 without the Patriots' permission, due to contractual obligations to New England.</p>
<p>Parcells announced last Friday that he would not be returning to coach the Patriots.</p>
<p>The Jets said Tuesday that Parcells would take over from Belichick as head coach and chief of football operations in February 1998.</p>
<p>An NFL spokeswoman said Wednesday the Jets have already advised the league that Parcells will not have any game-day role or perform any other &quot;co-head coach&quot; function during the 1997 season.</p>
<p>The Jets insist that the consultant role for Parcells in 1997 does not violate Tagliabue's ruling.</p>
<p>Kraft, however, labeled the Jets' hirings &quot;a transparent farce.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This 'so-called' consulting agreement is a transparent farce and the latest in a series of actions by the New York Jets and Bill Parcells, which further demonstrates it has been their intention all along to have Bill become head coach of the Jets for the 1997 season,&quot; Kraft said in a statement.</p>
<p>A league spokeswoman said Tagliabue's review of the agreements will be concluded as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>&quot;The Jets were neither denied nor given permission to make a consulting agreement with Parcells for 1997,&quot; the NFL had said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Belichick, who was assistant head coach to Parcells last season and served previously as defensive coordinator for him during the New York Giants' Super Bowl seasons, was signed to a multi-year contract and would become assistant head coach when Parcells takes over in 1998.</p>
<p>Jets president Steve Gutman said Tuesday that negotiations were continuing between Jets owner Leon Hess and Kraft on a possible compensation package for Parcells' services as head coach in 1997.</p>
<p>Kraft has demanded at least the top overall pick in the upcoming college draft to relinquish the coaching rights to Parcells. The Jets have been unwilling to part with the pick.</p>
<p>Although the bitter rift between the teams has grown over the Parcells fiasco, there is no ruling against Belichick coaching the Jets. Belichick was no longer under contract to the Patriots.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
