<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="356493" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London gold fixes barely up in quiet business.</title>
<headline>London gold fixes barely up in quiet business.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold prices were hovering on fresh 3-1/4 year lows on Tuesday despite recovering slightly around midday, dealers said.</p>
<p>Business levels in New York and Europe were light at the afternoon fixing but sufficient to sustain prices above the day's lows which were met early.</p>
<p>Gold was fixed at $343.40 per ounce, 25 cents above the morning fix which was a fresh low since the September 14, 1993 of $342.05.</p>
<p>Dealers said overnight selling in New York and the Far East was prompted by the continuing strong dollar and profit taking after Monday and Tuesday's short-covering rise.</p>
<p>&quot;It is still under pressure. The sentiment is still bearish and the overall downtrend is still intact,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;The very strong dollar isn't helping gold either,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The dealer said that physical support from Hong Kong and Singapore had diminished slightly ahead of the Lunar New Year holidays which will close Hong Kong until February 10.</p>
<p>Hitherto physical support had been prominent. The buying was seen as long term investment interest which would not come back into the market for a 10 or 20 percent profit, dealers said.</p>
<p>Dealers saidthe US Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) policy advisory group which begins its second and final day of debate on the domestic economy today was neutral.</p>
<p>A poll by Reuters of U.S. economists showed most of them did not expect a rise in the fed funds rate at the end of the meeting. But a majority of the sample forecast a 25-basis point rise on the fed fund rate of 5.25 percent some time this year.</p>
<p>The steady policy assumption was based on the absence of inflationary pressures but above-trend growth and some labour market tightness hinted at a possible rise later.</p>
<p>More pressingly, the market was still uncomfortable about the possibility of further central bank selling.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether it has happened or not, it is adding to the bearish tone,&quot; a dealer said referring to a spike in lease rates and heavy sales last Thursday which were immediately interpreted as the work of the central banks.</p>
<p>The other metals were little changed from morning levels and generally below their previous close.</p>
<p>Platinum was down $2.50 at $351.25/$352.25 and palladium off $1.70 at $126.50/$127.50, both reflecting the sector's weakness.</p>
<p>Silver was a cent down at $4.86/$4.88 amid sparse interest after light early buying.</p>
<p>-Brian Spoors London Newsroom +44 171 542 8058</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
