<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="356507" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: North Sea crude steady, Dated holds recent range.</title>
<headline>North Sea crude steady, Dated holds recent range.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea crudes were steady on Wednesday, Dated Brent holding on to substantial premiums to forward paper values amid thin prompt supply and further delays to Ekofisk loadings, traders said.</p>
<p>One of two cargoes turning wet was kept by BP, who sold it to an NWE refiner for Mar Brent +34 cents a barrel, four cents above Tuesday's highest deal. A second Feb 20-22 Brent was clocked to Stasco.</p>
<p>A Feb 12-14 Brent fetched Mar Brent +25 cents in a deal between Wall Street traders, still within a recent range, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is looking pretty stable,&quot; said a major North Sea producer.</p>
<p>Problems commissioning a pipeline tie-in of the U.K. Fulmar field to Norway's Ekofisk stream was compounding week-long delays caused by a shutdown in January, prompting some to look for alternatives to cover February requirements, traders said.</p>
<p>Mar Brent slipped four cents to $22.39 a barrel by 1825 GMT, but intermonth spreads were a couple of cents firmer, Mar/Apr rising to +46/+48 cents.</p>
<p>Other grades were mostly quiet, with little remaining from February programmes to be sold, but 600,000 barrels of Oseberg loading Feb 22-24 fetched a healthy 50-cent premium to Brent.</p>
<p>In the Mediteranean, Urals was still seen under pressure after trade at Dated Brent -79 cents cif Genoa on Tuesday.</p>
<p>West African markets were fairly quiet ahead of the release of the March loading programmes for Nigerian crudes, expected later Wednesday or early Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
