<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="356576" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: FEATURE - Canada and U.S. set for more trade squabbles.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Canada and U.S. set for more trade squabbles.</headline>
<byline>Malina Poshtova Zang</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada and the United States share the world's longest undefended border. They have a long history of good relations and each provides the other with its largest export market.</p>
<p>Yet this year promises another flurry of big and small trade confrontations, ranging from duties on imported cheese to high-level bickering over trade with communist Cuba.</p>
<p>Although both the United States and Canada have sought to play down the impact of bilateral trade disputes, a steady trickle of old and new complaints remains a source of constant tension between Ottawa and Washington.</p>
<p>There is no sign of a relaxation on the horizon. A recent World Trade Organisation (WTO) ruling striking down Canada's protectionist policies against U.S. magazines with Canadian editions, was seen in Canada as a go-ahead for Washington to challenge some other Canadian cultural protection measures.</p>
<p>The decision was not just a blow to Ottawa's protectionist policies. It also revealed the sharp differences in the two countries' perceptions of each other and their relationship.</p>
<p>While Washington views the export of cultural products like magazines, books and films as pure business within the context of free trade, Ottawa sees such exports as an attempt at assimilation, an onslaught on Canada's national identity.</p>
<p>Canada went to great lengths to negotiate a cultural exemption in its free trade agreement with the United States, later superseded by the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA).</p>
<p>Canada has long feared a cultural invasion from its rich and powerful southern neighbour and has guarded against it through protectionist measures -- preferential postal rates, import tariffs on magazines and an 80 percent tax on advertising in U.S. magazines offering Canadian editions.</p>
<p>This month, the WTO rejected most of these measures as violations of world trade rules. The decision sent a chill through Ottawa, which now must weigh its options and either appeal against the ruling or ignore it, thus inviting U.S. retaliation.</p>
<p>U.S. analysts said the effect was largely psychological and the decision was unlikely to lead to a flood of new challenges of Canadian cultural protectionism by Washington.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a huge industry and the ruling will not have a huge impact on U.S.-Canada trade flows, and I don't think Canada is going to be a big target (of U.S. complaints),&quot; said Larry Chimerine, managing director of the Economic Strategy Institute, a Washington research organisation focusing on trade competitiveness.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we will keep picking on Canada. Our big trade problems are much more with the Asian countries than they are with Canada,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But the Clinton administration has hinted that opening Canadian markets further for U.S. exports would be a priority.</p>
<p>One issue expected to top Washington's list is the sky-high tariffs charged by Canada on imports of dairy products, eggs and poultry.</p>
<p>Ottawa imposed the tariffs, up to 355 percent in some cases, to keep imports to a minimum and preserve the livelihood of more than 30,000 Canadian farmers. A NAFTA panel has ruled the import tariffs on dairy and poultry products did not violate the treaty.</p>
<p>But the U.S. dairy industry has complained that it could sell about $1 billion worth of eggs, chickens and dairy products if it had open access to Canadian markets.</p>
<p>&quot;We have stated publicly that notwithstanding the (NAFTA) panel report, we intend to continue to pursue the issue and do everything possible consistent with our trade laws, to ... seek the limitation of those tariffs,&quot; said a U.S. trade official who spoke on condition of anonymity.</p>
<p>Every day about $1 billion worth of goods crosses the 5,525-mile (8,890 km) stretch of land and water between Canada and the United States.</p>
<p>Most of that traffic moves freely and uninterrupted. But occasional spats have often escalated into longstanding trade battles, some of which still simmer long after they have supposedly been resolved.</p>
<p>Last April, Ottawa and Washington finally ended a 13-year dispute over Canadian shipments of softwood lumber by signing a five-year agreement. But the deal has created problems between Ottawa and Canadian lumber producers, unhappy with the export quotas they were assigned under the deal.</p>
<p>Shipments of grain, sugar and steel, as well as the occasional dispute over salmon fishing, are other controversial issues on the back burner.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
