<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="356647" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAfrica business sees reform window of opportunity.</title>
<headline>SAfrica business sees reform window of opportunity.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The buoyant mood sweeping South Africa's markets has presented government with a window of opportunity to implement key facets of its economic plan, the South African Chamber of Business (Sacob) said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Director of economic policy Ben Van Rensburg said the mood reflected expectations that government would take concrete steps on implementing its macro-economic strategy this year and presented it with an ideal opportunity to do just that.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a window of opportunity for government which it must capitalise on to strengthen the foundation from which to launch a better economy for South Africa,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Positive foreign investor sentiment has helped sweep the rand to its strongest level in four months and bond yields to their lowest levels since late September last year.</p>
<p>Local optimism was captured in Sacob's business confidence index, which rose one percentage point to 112.3 in December and January combined to its highest level since last October.</p>
<p>Van Rensburg said that among the objectives set out in government's macro-economic strategy document, business would look primarily to the removal of exchange controls, progress on privatisation and an improvement in labour market flexibility.</p>
<p>&quot;I am talking about freeing up business as far as possible to do with its capital what it needs to do in order to improve its profitability,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Business would look to President Nelson Mandela's opening of Parliament speech on Friday to give direction on economic policy this year, while it was expected that concrete steps would be taken around budget time on March 12, he said.</p>
<p>Van Rensburg said that while business favoured a &quot;big bang&quot; approach to the removal of exchange controls, government was expected to stick to its commitment to adopt a phased approach.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment there is an expectation that government will not go for the big bang approach but that substantial progress will be made in implementation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the danger of that approach is that once you have taken that big step, and there still remain other big steps to be taken, they might be discounted further,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Paul Richardson, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
