<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="356620" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerian shareholders slam privatisation delay.</title>
<headline>Nigerian shareholders slam privatisation delay.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The umbrella organisation of Nigerian shareholders on Wednesday criticised the country's military government for declining to privatise some of the nation's public utilities this year as was widely expected.</p>
<p>The Nigerian Shareholders Solidarity Association (NSSA), an independent body which seeks to protect the interests of shareholders in publicly quoted companies, also criticised the retention of a dual exchange rate for the naira currency.</p>
<p>It said in a statement that it was displeased by the decision not to privatise the companies, including the electricity and telecommunications monopolies as well as state oil firm the Nigerian National Petroleum Corp.</p>
<p>After cabinet ministers last year promised that there would be large scale privatisation, military ruler General Sani Abacha said in his 1997 fiscal budget speech last month that government needed to look at the issue again before going ahead with it.</p>
<p>But NSSA said the government did not need any new study before divesting from inefficient and debt-ridden state firms.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the NSSA) believes that the government has more than enough materials and experience to enable them (to) prosecute privatisation with zeal in 1997,&quot; said the NSSA statement signed by its president, Akintunde Asalu.</p>
<p>Local and multilateral financial institutions have expressed disappointment over the decision to delay programme.</p>
<p>On the exchange rate, NSSA said government should stop operating the official rate of 22 naira to the dollar for a more realistic rate this year.</p>
<p>The official rate is reserved only for some government transactions while other businesses use the market-determined 80 naira to the dollar.</p>
<p>The NSSA, however, praised the decision to raise the paid-up capital of banks nine-fold to 500 million naira and said the central bank should ensure compliance with the policy.</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
