<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="356639" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SUDAN: Egypt opposition says Sudan war harms Egypt.</title>
<headline>Egypt opposition says Sudan war harms Egypt.</headline>
<dateline>KHARTOUM 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egyptian opposition parties have told the Sudanese government that a war between Khartoum and rebels in south and east Sudan also affects Egypt's security.</p>
<p>Labour Party head Ibrahim Shukri and Mahfouz Azzam of the Al-Ahrar party -- both pro-Islamists  -- led the opposition delegation to Sudan, which has cool ties with Egypt since gunmen tried to kill Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak in 1995.</p>
<p>Egypt says Sudan is sheltering the three men while Khartoum denies the charges.</p>
<p>Sudan television showed the delegation late on Tuesday in a meeting with parliament speaker Hassan al-Turabi and Ghazi Salahuddin, secretary general of Sudan's National Congress.</p>
<p>The Sudan News Agency quoted Azzam as saying that although the opposition visit was intended to improve ties between Egypt and Sudan, attacks in south Sudan affected Egypt's security.</p>
<p>&quot;The aggression against eastern Sudan...targets the countries of the Nile Valley,&quot; he was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Egypt is concerned that fighting in the southeast of Sudan could affect Egypt's access to Nile waters.</p>
<p>Egypt's mainstream opposition parties have sided with Sudan's Islamist government and said that Israel and &quot;external powers&quot; are behind the fighting in Sudan's eastern Blue Nile province.</p>
<p>Sudanese President Omar Hassan al-Bashir has said Ethiopian and Eritrean troops, with a little help from Israel, are fighting a battle in the east. He said that both countries are recruiting Sudanese rebels to battle with them.</p>
<p>The Sudanese opposition and President Mubarak have scoffed at Bashir's comments, saying that no foreign troops have entered Sudan. Mubarak also said Egypt would not intervene in what he called an internal issue.</p>
<p>The Egyptian opposition has a minority in parliament and very little influence on matters of state.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KHARTOUM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SUDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
