<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="356717" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Belgium's Amylum suspends Bulgaria production.</title>
<headline>Belgium's Amylum suspends Bulgaria production.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Amylum Bulgaria, a Belgian-Bulgarian corn starch joint venture, suspended production to cut losses caused by an economic crisisin the country, the state agency BTA said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is impossible to trade now and following a dramatic fall in sales, we decided to suspend operation of the plant,&quot; the agency quoted company director Carl Werstraelen as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a difficult decision, but it was taken in view of preserving our long-term position in Bulgaria.&quot;</p>
<p>Amylum N.V. acquired 81 percent of Bulgaria's biggest starch producer, Maize Products Co, for $20 million in 1993, while the remaining 19 percent was bought by the United Bulgarian Bank. The maize processing factory employed 220 and was one of the biggest corn starch producers in the region.</p>
<p>Delayed reform and mismanagement of the economy led Bulgaria to an unprecedented economic crisis. The the lev, plunged to 3,000 per dollar on Wednesday from 600 at the beginning of January and 73 a year ago.</p>
<p>With January inflation expected at more than 50 percent, hyper-inflation has become a factor. Bulgaria suffers from one of the lowest foreign investment levels in the region. Excessive red tape, inconsistantly applied legislation and organised crime has driven investors away.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
