<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="356965" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia to tender for up to 60,OOO tonnes of rice.</title>
<headline>Colombia to tender for up to 60,OOO tonnes of rice.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombia's faces a shortfall of up to 60,000 tonnes of rice this year and the deficit will have to be covered through imports, the head of the National Rice Growers' Association (Fedearroz) said.</p>
<p>The official, Rafael Hernandez, said he would meet senior Agriculture Ministry officials Friday to discuss licensing of the imports, which were likely to begin in April.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear from what country Colombia would import the rice but Hernandez said Fedearroz preferred it to be done in a piecemeal fashion under which Colombian millers would receive multiple shipments of paddy, or rice that has not been hulled.</p>
<p>Hernandez said Colombia, which impo1rted rice from Ecuador last year, was expected to produce about 900,000 tonnes in 1997. But consumption was expected to total 960,000 tonnes, making imports of the staple a strict necessity.</p>
<p>The number of Colombian rice fields has dropped by about 30 percent since 1992 because farmers are increasingly unable to compete with relatively cheap imports, Hernandez said.</p>
<p>A source at the Agriculture Ministry confirmed that Colombia was likely to tender for at least 50,000 tonnes of rice in 1997 but declined further comment.</p>
<p>((-- Juan Guillermo Londono, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
