<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357015" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: FEATURE - Colombia stocks rally just a blip on radar.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Colombia stocks rally just a blip on radar.</headline>
<byline>Tom Brown</byline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A spectacular rally in stocks in early January made Colombia one of the world's best-performing markets and raised fleeting hopes that it was finally getting its act together again after 2-1/2 years of political crisis.</p>
<p>But the rally, which saw a 22 percent gain in share prices over the first 10 trading days of the year, faded quickly. And it now appears to have been little more than a blip on the radar screen of investors in a country whose long tradition of prudent economic policy has come to a screeching halt.</p>
<p>President Ernesto Samper, who has been hit with fresh calls for his resignation since mid-January, insisted in a television address on January 27 that &quot;the economy is looking good&quot; and that Colombians have every reason to be optimistic about the New Year.</p>
<p>But Samper, whose credibility was damaged even before he took office amid a growing drugs scandal in August 1994, has had to bend over backwards to explain why he declared a state of economic emergency on January 13 if things were really looking up. There are many reasons, in a country torn by chaos and general mayhem, to believe he may be overly optimistic.</p>
<p>U.S. CERTIFICATION AND THREAT OF SANCTIONS</p>
<p>A leading cause of uncertainty in Colombia, and what Samper himself has described as &quot;collective hysteria,&quot; is the fact that U.S. President Bill Clinton must decide by March 1 whether it should remain on a list of virtual pariah states that have failed to participate actively enough in the anti-drug fight.</p>
<p>So-called &quot;decertification&quot; for a second consecutive year could trigger punitive economic sanctions that Clinton fell short of imposing last year. In addition to increased tariffs on Colombian exports to the United States, Clinton could invoke the International Emergency Economic Powers Act to impose a wide variety of sanctions, including the suspension of banking services between the United States and Colombia.</p>
<p>Most business leaders consulted by Reuters see decertification as a certainty after a judge's January 17 lenient sentencing of two of the world's most powerful drug lords. The two, the same men accused of pouring millions of drug dollars into Samper's campaign, may walk free in as little as five years.</p>
<p>Businessmen are divided on the prospects of U.S. sanctions on Colombia, but Bogota-based diplomats say Washington may have little choice. &quot;Without sanctions they (the U.S.) will have shown that the whole certification process has no teeth,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>ECONOMIC EMERGENCY</p>
<p>Measures decreed as part of the emergency that Samper surprised the nation with on January 13 include a six percent tax on new foreign loans and a de facto increase in Colombia's capital gains tax -- which could ravage the stock market.</p>
<p>Some economic analysts have said the measures, including a $1.2 billion budget cut and an overall expansion of the tax base, were long overdue and would ultimately gain favour with foreign investors. But they have been widely criticised by importers, who finance much of their business with foreign credits, and prompted the country's leading business group to boycott a new wage-and- price control agreement with the government.</p>
<p>Eighteen of 20 leading economists surveyed by Bogota's El Espectador daily said the emergency measures would do nothing to reactivate the economy and 16 said they were &quot;recessionary&quot;.</p>
<p>The measures are aimed ostensibly at narrowing the central government's yawning budget deficit and pushing Colombia's over valued peso currency lower against the dollar.</p>
<p>EMERGENCY WITHIN THE EMERGENCY?</p>
<p>Adding to uncertainty is that Colombia's constitutional court has 90 days, from the day the emergency measures were announced, to overturn them if it rules they were unjustified.</p>
<p>The government has said a huge increase in the inflow of foreign capital late last year more than warranted the measures. The inflow forced the central bank to buy large amounts of dollars to prevent the peso -- which appreciated by 16 percent against the dollar in real terms (net of inflation) last year -- from crashing through the lower end of its exchange rate band. Exporters led by the powerful National Coffee Growers' Federation insisted on a peso devaluation last year, since its strengthening eroded the real value of export revenues.</p>
<p>Critics argued much of the increase in foreign capital was due to a last-minute flood of privatisation revenues, however, so the government has no one to blame but itself.</p>
<p>If the economic emergency plan is ruled unconstitutional, Samper has warned he may eliminate up to 350,000 state jobs.</p>
<p>LABOUR UNREST LEADS TO STRIKE</p>
<p>Even before the economic emergency was announced, the government said it planned to hold public sector workers to an average wage hike of no more than 13.5 percent this year, despite inflation of more than 21 percent in 1996. This, in turn, led unions representing about 800,000 workers to set a February 11 deadline for a nationwide and indefinite work stoppage.</p>
<p>Some press commentators say the strike could be the worst since September 1977 when public unrest erupted in a violent work stoppage that left 20 people dead in Bogota.</p>
<p>ELECTORAL ENGINES ARE WARMING UP</p>
<p>Further adding to gnawing uncertainty is the fact that 1997 marks Samper's last full year in office and, in his own words, &quot;the electoral engines are warming up now.&quot;</p>
<p>Polls show the front-runner to succeed Samper, when he steps down in August 1998, to be chief prosecutor Alfonso Valdivieso, an anti-drug crusader and key U.S. ally. If Valdivieso doesn't run, Interior Minister Horacio Serpa would be the front-runner.</p>
<p>Serpa, Samper's right-hand man, has had repeated rows with the United States. U.S. officials secretly hope Valdivieso -- who is investigating charges that Serpa knew about and helped cover up illegal campaign financing -- will ultimately send him to jail.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
