<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357013" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Banco de Mexico net assets rise as of Jan 31.</title>
<headline>Banco de Mexico net assets rise as of Jan 31.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-02-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Banco de Mexico said on Tuesday its net international assets as of Jan. 31 were $8.758 billion, up from $8.199 billion on Jan. 24.</p>
<p>The central bank said that its net international reserves as of Jan. 31 were $18.96 billion, compared to $18.147 billion on Jan. 24.  </p>
<p>The central bank said the increase of $559 million in net international assets in the same time period was due to:</p>
<p>-- Net income from the purchase of $537 million from the federal government for the first payment received for the privatization of the Northeast Railway.</p>
<p>-- Net income from operations by the state oil company Pemex worth $149 million.</p>
<p>-- Outflow from the sale to the federal government of $81 million in foreign debt obligations.</p>
<p>-- A net loss of $46 million dollars for a combination of factors including changes in the dollar value of non-dollar assets and liabilities held by the bank; net returns on interest rates and from trading of metals and securities; and net deposits in dollar accounts from commercial banks at the central bank.</p>
<p>Banco de Mexico said that between January 24 and January 31 the monetary base rose by 2.259 billion pesos due to a rise in the seasonal demand of bills and coins at month's end.</p>
<p>In the same period, the federal government's deposits in the central bank rose by 9.618 billion pesos. Some 5.189 billion came from tax receipts while 4.429 billion came from the sale of the railroad.</p>
<p>To compensate for the increase in liquidity resulting from the various operations of the federal government, Banco de Mexico said it had opted to renew 3.503 billion pesos from the balance of deposits that banks had constituted with the central bank. It furthermore allowed those deposits to rise by an additional 1.135 billion.</p>
<p>The following tables detail Banco de Mexico's reserves and net domestic credit. All figures are in billions of pesos, unless otherwise indicated.</p>
<p>			     Jan 24	 Jan 31</p>
<p>International Reserves</p>
<p>   Pesos		   141.920	148.301</p>
<p>   U.S. Dollars	  $18.147 bln  $18.960 bln</p>
<p>Monetary Base	     74.462	 76.721</p>
<p>Net International Assets*</p>
<p>    Pesos		   64.119	 68.499</p>
<p>    U.S. Dollars	  $8.119 bln   $8.758 bln</p>
<p>Net Domestic Credit     10.343	  8.222</p>
<p>*Net International Assets are defined as gross international assets minus central bank liabilities with the IMF and assets of less than a six-month duration from other central banks.</p>
<p>((--Mexico City newsroom +525 728-7902))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
