<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357126" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Some AIDS doctors find assisted suicide common.</title>
<headline>Some AIDS doctors find assisted suicide common.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new survey of more than 100 doctors who regularly care for people with HIV -- the virus that causes AIDS -- has found that more than half have helped patients asking to commit suicide.</p>
<p>The number of doctors going along with the practice seems to be increasing, according to the study in Thursday's editions of the New England Journal of Medicine.</p>
<p>&quot;We found substantial evidence that some physicians are making it possible for their patients with HIV infection to commit suicide and that acceptance of this practice in a consortium of physicians who care for many such patients appears to be increasing,&quot; a five-member research team led by Lee R. Slome of San Francisco said.</p>
<p>The anonymous survey went to each of the 228 doctors in the Community Consortium, which provides treatment to people with HIV in the San Francisco Bay area; 118 responded.</p>
<p>The survey was done between November 1994 and January 1995, but the results are only now being released.</p>
<p>The researchers discovered that 53 percent of the doctors who responded said they had &quot;granted an AIDS patient's request for assistance in committing suicide&quot; at least once. The average number of requests granted was four per physician.</p>
<p>Compared to the findings of a similar study conducted in 1990, the researchers found:</p>
<p>-- When presented with the hypothetical case of a seriously ill HIV patient seeking a lethal dose of narcotics to end his or her life, 48 percent said they would be likely to grant the request, even if the patient was not adamant. In the 1990 survey, only 28 percent were willing.</p>
<p>-- The typical doctor received eight direct requests from patients to help them commit suicide versus four in the earlier study, and the number of indirect requests reported by each doctor had jumped from an average of seven in 1990 to 14 by 1995.</p>
<p>When the Slome team looked at the factors that seemed to influence a doctor's decision, they found those who had seen more AIDS patients die, those who had received several indirect requests from patients to help in their suicide, and physicians who were gay, lesbian or bisexual were the most likely to go along with the request.</p>
<p>The researchers called the number of doctors willing to assist in suicide &quot;surprisingly large,&quot; especially &quot;given the possible legal and ethical repercussions of such an action,&quot; and because other surveys of physician attitudes toward doctor-assisted suicide have reported that only 7 to 9 percent of doctors have complied with such requests from terminally ill patients.</p>
<p>But other surveys have not focused on doctors who treat a lot of people with AIDS, a condition for which there is no cure and where the risk of suicide is higher than in the general population. More than 78 percent of the doctors in this study had treated at least 80 AIDS patients during their careers.</p>
<p>Another reason for the higher number of willing doctors may be California state law, which permits physicians to prescribe large doses of narcotics at one time, the study said. This means patients do not have to hoard drugs to achieve a lethal dose.</p>
<p>The Slome group also stressed the doctors did not necessarily administer the fatal dose. Some patients who are not destined to take their own lives may nonetheless find it comforting to have a fatal dose on hand, &quot;giving them a sense of control over a disease that tends to rob them of control,&quot; the researchers said.</p>
<p>A final caveat to the study was that it was done in the San Francisco Bay area, where AIDS is widespread and &quot;attitudes are generally more liberal.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
