<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357157" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: golf - the club's growing and collectibles prices rising.</title>
<headline>golf - the club's growing and collectibles prices rising.</headline>
<byline>Richard Chang</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Few games capture the imagination as much as golf. So paying $100,000 for a wooden club or $35,650 for a ball that possesses the aura of the sport's 600-year-old history and champions -- while unusual -- hardly shocks lovers of the sport of Scottish kings and queens.</p>
<p>&quot;With golf, you can own the same kind of club that champions used. People like to feel they're in their shoes. There's history behind artifacts like that,&quot; said John Olman, who owns the Old Golf Shop in Cincinnati.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a game you can play by yourself for a lifetime,&quot; he said, unlike baseball or racing cars.</p>
<p>The intensely personal pleasure derived from golf has fuelled the sport's growth from its aristocratic beginnings in Scotland in the 14th century to a popular pastime and spectacle the world over.</p>
<p>But golf became an affordable sport only recently, with equipment and courses within reach of working class incomes.</p>
<p>Scottish aristocrats spent as much gold for each golf ball as they did for a golf club even as late as 1850, said Robert Gowland, golf expert at Phillips Fine Art Auctioneers in New York.</p>
<p>Those hand-made balls of chicken feathers stuffed into a leather casing cost 2 shillings to 5 shillings then, or $150 to $300 in today's terms.</p>
<p>But don't expect to find them in your attic when treasure hunting, even though several hundred feather balls are still in existence. Those flimsy antiques, when wet, exploded into a cloud of feathers when hit with a heavy club.</p>
<p>The discovery of gutta percha, the milky liquid from rubber trees in the mid-1800s resulted in the affordable &quot;gutty&quot; ball and led to modern &quot;balata&quot; balls with an interior made of a long rubber band wrapped around a small sphere.</p>
<p>As ballmakers tried to find ways to make golf balls more distinctive, they created spheres that looked like an atlas globe, the first dimpled ball by Spalding, and balls decorated with waffle, circle crescent and other designs.</p>
<p>For these pre-1920s balls, collectors have paid the equivalent of annual membership fees at premier golf clubs.</p>
<p>Last November, Phillips auctioned an extremely rare Park Royal gutty ball with hexagonal faces, near mint condition, for $35,650, a record for a golf ball. It was expected to fetch only $12,000 to $15,000.</p>
<p>An extremely rare ball designed by &quot;Old Tom Morris,&quot; who won the British Open four times and made golf equipment, sold for $16,675 against an estimate of $12,000 to $15,000.</p>
<p>But early 18th century clubs are the crown jewels of the game. In 1991, the Valderama Golf Club in the southern coast of Spain (which will host this year's Ryder Cup matches) paid about $100,000 for an early 18th century iron club for its private museum, Gowland said.</p>
<p>An H. Philip &quot;longspoon&quot; club fetched $11,500 at Phillips' November auction. A rare Anderson &amp; Sons wood nibblick in brown beechwood with brass sole struck $6,900.</p>
<p>&quot;Collectors tend to be pretty rich, and are very keen golfers all their life. But in their 50s and 60s they tend to get interested in the heritage of the game and interested in all the lovely old clubs used in the 17th to 19th century and even 20th century clubs,&quot; said Gowland.</p>
<p>But just because you inherited your grandfather's wooden shafted golf club doesn't mean you're rich.</p>
<p>There were more than five million American golfers in the 1920s. If each owned 10 clubs -- a very conservative estimate -- this means that more than 50 million &quot;antiques&quot; could be laying around in U.S. attics or basements.</p>
<p>Wooden shafted clubs with faces that have dots or lines are worth $10 to $15 each, Gowland said. Clubs without dots or lines fetch $50 or more.</p>
<p>Pre-1905 clubs whose heads are spliced and bound to the shaft are worth $150 or more. If shaft goes an inch into the head, it is worth $30 to $40.</p>
<p>&quot;In America you're unlikely to find clubs much older than a century unless there were relatives who emigrated from Scotland in the last century and brought over antiques,&quot; Gowland said.</p>
<p>Steel-shafted clubs, which began to appear in the 1940s, are generally too new to be valuable -- unless they have unusual head shapes or were illegal, that is, prohibited because of features that make the game too easy.</p>
<p>Look also for smooth-face irons that are branded Anderson, Army &amp; Navy, Ayers, Carrick, Forgan, Gray, Morris, Park &amp; White, and certain Spalding, MacGregor, Condie, Nicoll, Stewart, Gibson and Wright &amp; Ditson clubs.</p>
<p>If you're an investment minded collector, think fun first.</p>
<p>&quot;Realistically, the only thing people can do is collect something very stylish and different, not use it and maybe their grandchildren will benefit,&quot; Gowland said. ---------------</p>
<p>To comment on the Assets column, write to Richard Chang at richard.chang(at)reuters.com.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
