<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357171" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Metaleurop, Cominco in 1997 zinc treatment charge.</title>
<headline>Metaleurop, Cominco in 1997 zinc treatment charge.</headline>
<byline>Huw Jones</byline>
<dateline>SCOTTSDALE, Ariz. 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Metaleurop SA and Cominco Ltd have settled their benchmark treatment charge for zinc concentrates in 1997 at &quot;mid-point&quot; of $186 per tonne basis an LME cash price of $1,100 per tonne, Metaleurop board member Christian Bue told Reuters.</p>
<p>Cominco of Canada is one of the world's biggest zinc and lead miners, with Metaleurop of France a leading global smelter of zinc metal.</p>
<p>Bue said the deal covers some 110,000 tonnes of zinc concentrates, and included for a first time an escalator of 20 cents per lb, and a de-escalator of 15 cents a lb.</p>
<p>For each dollar rise in zinc price above $1,100 per tonne, the smelter gains 20 cents, while for each dollar dip below this level, the smelter loses 15 cents.</p>
<p>Zinc industry officials are here to attend the American Zinc Association conference where treatment charges are traditionally discussed.</p>
<p>The deal signals a major breakthrough for Cominco in its bid to inject what it sees as a more equitable price exposure between miners and smelters. In the past miners have suffered much more than smelters when prices fell.</p>
<p>The new benchmark deal for 1997 will equate to a downside of $170 per tonne on a base LME cash price of $1,000. Last year's benchmark price was settled at $190 per tonne, basis LME price of $1,000 per tonne. Escalators last year were 13 to 15 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;It was an extremely difficult year to settle because there was an apparent set of circumstances, especially the announcements which took place in November and December about mine closures which is giving a sentiment of shortage of concentrates or at least a tightness,&quot; Bue said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have tried to have a statesmanlike attitude, to limit the extravagant number of dollars anyone can ask for in a buyers or sellers market,&quot; Bue added.</p>
<p>&quot;Secondly we wanted to give a bigger inducement for the smelters to be more clever in their marketing policy which means to try to optimise the margin and not the volume,&quot; Bue said.</p>
<p>Under past TC formulas, the lack of inducement for smelters to cut output in the face of falling prices led to a huge buildup of stocks which further depressed tags.</p>
<p>High cost smelters found it easier to stomach losses for a year or two rather than a much higher price of shutting capacity, analysts said.</p>
<p>Accepting Cominco's price participation proposal represented a &quot;maturing of the smelter industry&quot;, Bue said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have agreed to a concept of much higher price participation,&quot; Bue said. &quot;I feel that certain smelters will find an advantage to reduce their production to optimise their margins.&quot;</p>
<p>With Cominco and Metaleurop having settled their benchmark deal, the rest of the industry was expected to follow suit.</p>
<p>((New York Commodities 212-859-1646))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SCOTTSDALE, Ariz."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
