<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357257" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. doubts Paris security summit will take place.</title>
<headline>U.S. doubts Paris security summit will take place.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. officials said on Wednesday they had &quot;not encouraged&quot; reported French ideas of staging a five-nation summit in Paris to discuss Europe's future security system, and did not believe it would be held.</p>
<p>&quot;We asked the French about the press reports and I don't believe that any such proposal will be forthcoming,&quot; said a senior U.S. official, speaking on condition his name not be published.</p>
<p>Diplomats in Paris said that under the proposal, leaders of the United States, Russia, France, Germany and Britain would meet in April to establish the broad lines of a deal that could enable Moscow to accept the enlargement of NATO.</p>
<p>Asked whether the United States discouraged such ideas, the official said, &quot;I don't believe we encouraged them.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There's a concern among the smaller countries in NATO that this historic decision, which is arguably the most important decision NATO will have made since its creation, not be made in two or three places,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>&quot;We heard that in spades (emphatically) this morning from our visitor, the Belgian Foreign Minister.&quot; The minister, Erick Derycke, met Wednesday with newly appointed Secretary of State Madeleine Albright.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns, asked about the suggestion, said: &quot;We have not received any such proposal from the French government -- no such proposal at all.&quot;</p>
<p>Burns said the U.S. focus was on a full summit of all of NATO's 16 members that will take place in Madrid in July. That summit will issue invitations to so far unspecified East European countries to begin talks on joining NATO.</p>
<p>Russia vehemently opposed the expansion of NATO to include its former Warsaw Pact allies. In an attempt to mollify Moscow, the Western alliance offered the Russians a special charter that would give them the right to close consultations on key security questions.</p>
<p>NATO expansion was expected to be a major issue in talks in Washington this week between Vice President Al Gore and Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
