<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357225" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Edgy session seen ahead for U.S. equities.</title>
<headline>Edgy session seen ahead for U.S. equities.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The sharp, late tumble in U.S. financial markets on Wednesday is likely to leave nerves raw at Wall Street's Thursday open.</p>
<p>Analysts said investors could take some comfort from the market's ability to bounce off its lows in the last minutes of trading, a recovery that saw the Dow recoup about a quarter of the more than 120 points it shed during the most intense phase of the sell-off.</p>
<p>The Dow industrials closed at 6746.90, down 86.58 points and the Nasdaq Composite slid 25.31 points to 1348.44.  </p>
<p>The mild upswing could lend support to a suddenly jittery market in the opening moments, said analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;I would look for something more stable tomorrow, maybe a bounce back in the morning,&quot; said Hugh Johnson, chief investment officer at First Albany.</p>
<p>Johnson added, however, that there seemed to be an &quot;edginess&quot; in the market, a mood that given an earnings disappointment or other bad news &quot;could turn an edgy market into a decline.&quot;  </p>
<p>Analysts were quick to note that stocks, large caps in particular, were due for some form of pullback after enjoying a furious, liquidity-driven January rally.</p>
<p>&quot;Fund inflows are going to be lighter now and it looks like we're going to have a rougher time making money in this market,&quot; said Scott Bleier, chief investment strategist at Prime Charter Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;There's nothing wrong with profit-taking and a lot of these stocks were due for some corrective activity,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Among the stocks hit hardest during Wednesday's late selling were the same top-tier technology names that led the market higher in January.</p>
<p>Intel Corp closed at 157-1/4, down 7-1/2, after dipping as low as 155. Microsoft Corp finished at 98-3/8, down 4-3/4 after a wild day that saw it hit an all-time high 103-1/2 and touch as low as 96-7/8.</p>
<p>Buyers have quickly emerged after every dip in the most recent leg of the bull market, but some analysts said cash could be at least a session slower to re-enter this time around.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors could be on hold for Friday's jobs data,&quot; said Guy Truicko, portfolio manager at Unity Management. &quot;People will want to see the employment number before the market renews its uptrend.&quot;</p>
<p>((-- Wall Street desk, 212-859-1730))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
