<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357396" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Central Power files for $150 million shelf.</title>
<headline>Central Power files for $150 million shelf.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two business trusts formed by Central Power and Light Co said Wednesday it filed a shelf registration with the Securities and Exchange Commission to sell up to $150 million in preferred securities.</p>
<p>The trusts, known as CPL Capital I and CPL Capital II, will the proceeds from the cumulative quarterly income preferred securities, series A offering to invest in junior subordinated deferrable interest debentures of Central Power and Light Co.</p>
<p>The utility will add the proceeds from the sale of the debentures to its general funds and will be used to replace or retire, through redemption, repurchase or otherwise, one or more series of outstanding preferred stock of CPL, or any combination.</p>
<p>Proceeds will also be used to repay all or a portion of CPL's short-term borrowings outstanding and for other general corporate purposes, the utility said.</p>
<p>The offering will be made through Goldman Sachs &amp; Co, Lehman Brothers, Merrill Lynch &amp; Co and Smith Barney Inc.</p>
<p>Central Power and Light Co, based in Corpus Christi, Tx., is a public utility company engaged in the production, purchase, transmission, distribution and sale of electricity in South Texas. Central and South West Corp owns all the stock.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
