<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357350" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. West Coast Lt. crudes fall, no new ANS deals.</title>
<headline>U.S. West Coast Lt. crudes fall, no new ANS deals.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast Alaskan crude prices fell with West Texas Intermediate (WTI) crude early Wednesday, but no new deals were reported following yesterday's sale of a full cargo by BP America, traders said.</p>
<p>The cargo was priced $1.30 a barrel under March WTI for March delivery, BP said.</p>
<p>Some buyers earlier this week said Alaska North Slope (ANS) crude would sell for $1.60, and BP offered cargoes at $1.25 under WTI.</p>
<p>One buyer said a cargo of Oriente crude, an alternative to ANS, was offered at $2.50 a barrel under WTI.  </p>
<p>The buyer said he would consider splitting the half-million-barrel cargo another refiner.</p>
<p>ANS traded 10 cents a barrel lower at $22.50/22.60, as WTI came under pressure from reports of ample heating oil supply.</p>
<p>Four producers of California heavy crude, Mobil, Arco, Texaco, and Monterey Resources, continued to search for ways to lower inventories after Tosco refinery last week turned back two months worth of delivieres, traders said.</p>
<p>One of the producers said they would get rid of supply by sending 250,000 barrels to their Panama refinery.</p>
<p>&quot;We're fine for February. We're just deciding what to do with March,&quot; a company trader said.</p>
<p>The last heavy deal was done Friday at $1.00 under postings, compared with sales of 25 to 50 cents earlier that week.</p>
<p>Confirmed prices for San Joaquin Valley heavies ranged $17 to 17.25 a barrel, flat from Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
