<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357563" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian bonds seen rising if Fed sits on hands.</title>
<headline>Belgian bonds seen rising if Fed sits on hands.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian linear bonds will get a boost with other markets if the U.S. Federal Reserve, as expected, sits on its hands at today's policy-making meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;The probability of a (rate) hike is 25 percent, but then I'm very bullish: I don't see a (U.S.) rate hike this year,&quot; one trader said. &quot;On the other hand I don't expect the U.S. to outperform Germany.&quot;</p>
<p>OLOs ended higher ahead of the end of the U.S. Fed meeting, with the yield on the benchmark 2007 OLO easing to 5.74 percent from 5.76 percent on Tuesday evening.  </p>
<p>The market continued to ignore a bubbling domestic political scandal, with the 10-year yield over Bunds ending unchanged at seven basis points.</p>
<p>Dealers said that was unlikely to change, even ahead of a vote of confidence on Thursday in the government coalition, which has been rocked by allegations one party (the PS, or French-speaking socialist party) accepted bribes during the award of a defence contract in the late 1980s.</p>
<p>In a separate vote, the regional Walloon Parliament agreed on Wednesday its President and PS figurehead Guy Spitaels could be questioned by police leading the bribes probe.  </p>
<p>One trader said volume remained low, but limited buying at the long-end of the curve lent support.</p>
<p>The Belgian franc recovered to above 20.63 to the mark, ending the day at 20.6290/00 from 20.6295/10 at Tuesday's close.</p>
<p>The trader said, however, the spread could move out slightly as convergence trades linked to European economic and monetary union (EMU) were unwound across the continent.</p>
<p>&quot;7-12 (basis points) is fair value,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Nick Antonovics, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6817, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
