<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357507" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Rail strike in France has slight impact on travel.</title>
<headline>Rail strike in France has slight impact on travel.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's second rail strike in a week had only limited impact on traffic on Wednesday as most workers ignored a union bid to force the government to backtrack on plans to reform state railways.</p>
<p>The SNCF state railway company said most high-speed TGV trains operated normally as did high-speed services from Paris to London and Brussels.</p>
<p>Also operating normally were trains bound for the Alps, as many families began ski holidays during the February school break.</p>
<p>Traffic was cut by 30 to 50 percent on main lines to western France. Disruption was worst on regional services in the south, including to Toulouse where urban public transport workers have been on strike for 10 days to demand shorter working hours and the right to retire at 55.</p>
<p>The one-day rail strike  began at midnight (2300 GMT) on Tuesday and was due to end at 9 a.m. (0800 GMT) on Thursday.</p>
<p>A similar strike took place last Thursday, called by the CGT and the Socialist CFDT union. For this week, however, the CFDT chose to stage a protest rally rather than strike a second time.</p>
<p>The latest protest was called by the Communist-led CGT union to coincide with a National Assembly debate on plans to split the heavily-indebted SNCF to restore it to financial health.</p>
<p>Left-wing opposition parties tabled more than 400 amendments to the project and received delegations of protesting rail workers who demonstrated outside the assembly.</p>
<p>The government has proposed setting up a state holding company which would take over the bulk of the SNCF's debts of 208 billion francs ($37 billion) but which would become owner of the network and charge the SNCF rail usage fees.</p>
<p>Most unions back rail reform but the CGT and CFDT fear the plan will lead to a break-up of the SNCF, threatening jobs and deteriorating working conditions.</p>
<p>France has been hit by sporadic labour unrest over the past five months due to near-record unemployment of 12.7 percent and government austerity plans aimed at helping Paris qualify for a single European currency.</p>
<p>Unions fighting for a shorter working week and earlier retirement at tram and urban transit companies in towns outside Paris have called for a strike on Thursday.</p>
<p>And seven civil service unions plan a one-day strike for March 6 by millions of public employees, over a government pay offer they deem inadequate.</p>
<p>The government has offered a 2.8 percent pay rise over 1997 and 1998, rejecting union calls for a bigger hike to compensate for a pay freeze imposed last year.</p>
<p>Civil Service Minister Dominique Perben said a &quot;catch-up&quot; for 1996 would have cost 20 billion francs and that the government was determined to show the financial markets and its European Union partners that France was committed to spending restraint.</p>
<p>($ = 5.555 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
