<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357501" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: 40,000 Rwandan refugees on run in Zaire, says UN.</title>
<headline>40,000 Rwandan refugees on run in Zaire, says UN.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations refugee agency said on Wednesday 40,000 Rwandan refugees had fled camps in east Zaire, where rebels said they were tightening their grip.</p>
<p>The UNHCR said the refugee settlement of Shabunda was now empty after unconfirmed reports that Katshunga, a small town located some 45 km (25 miles) to the northeast, had fallen.</p>
<p>&quot;All refugee sites in Shabunda are empty,&quot; UNHCR quoted Dillah Doumaye, its deputy Zaire representative, as saying.</p>
<p>A small plane bringing in blankets and food was surrounded by a group of 150 people demanding to be flown out. Police fired shots in the air to disperse the crowd, a UNHCR statement said.</p>
<p>The plane took off with all three UNHCR staff members posted in Shabunda on board after they distributed relief supplies originally destined for the Catholic mission of Shabunda.</p>
<p>A UNHCR plane failed to trace refugees on the run because it was low on fuel. Another overflight was planned for Thursday.</p>
<p>The refugees were believed to be heading west, possibly toward Kilima and Kindu, and had been joined by some 7,000 displaced local Zaireans, the UN agency said.</p>
<p>In eastern Zaire's town of Goma bordering northwestern Rwanda, Zairean rebel leader Laurent Kabila said on Wednesday that his army, which has had stunning successes since October, was advancing on Lubutu, home to Rwanda's ousted 40,000-strong army and more than 100,000 Hutu refugees.</p>
<p>The rebel claims could not be confirmed independently, but Kabila said his forces were 19 km (12 miles) from Lubutu after capturing a key bridge in a battle that lasted several days. He said they shot down helicopters trying to reinforce pinned-down government troops and their Rwandan Hutu allies.</p>
<p>Kabila said his forces, now holding a swathe of land over 1,000 km (600 miles) long, were fighting at Shabunda, at Kindu, a major airbase, and outside the town of Watsa captured by his troops five days ago.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
