<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357556" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: U.S. envoy Pamela Harriman dies in Paris.</title>
<headline>U.S. envoy Pamela Harriman dies in Paris.</headline>
<byline>Francois Raitberger</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. ambassador to France Pamela Harriman, a millionaire socialite who became a political heavyweight close to President Bill Clinton, died in Paris on Wednesday two days after suffering a brain haemorrage.</p>
<p>Aged 76, she had been widely expected to retire later this year after four years in her post.</p>
<p>The U.S. embassy said she died in the afternoon at the American Hospital in the Paris suburb of Neuilly. She was rushed there by ambulance after falling ill on Monday evening at Paris' Ritz Hotel where she had gone for a swim.</p>
<p>&quot;She was one of the most unusual and gifted people I ever met,&quot; President Bill Clinton declared on hearing the news. &quot;She was an extaordinary U.S. ambassador...earning the trust of the leaders (of France) and the admiration of the people.&quot;</p>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac, who made her a Commander of the Order of Arts and Letters in 1996 for her patronage of fine arts, hailed her as &quot;a great ambassador of the United States and a grand lady&quot;. Aides said he was deeply saddened.</p>
<p>They said Chirac had telephoned condolences to Harriman's son Winston Churchill, a British MP who had been at her side since she was taken ill. Officials at Chirac's Elysee palace were in touch with her relatives and the U.S. embassy to plan a tribute.</p>
<p>An embassy spokeswoman said funeral plans were not completed but Harriman was not expected to be buried in France.</p>
<p>&quot;She was an inspiring leader, and we will remember her with love and respect,&quot; said her number two at the U.S. embassy, Donald Bandler.</p>
<p>&quot;Ambassador Harriman believed that America must have strong allies in Europe and around the globe. She worked tirelessly during the last four years to strengthen the bonds between the United States and France,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>During Harriman's stint as ambassador, Paris and Washington sparred over alleged U.S. espionage on French soil, the &quot;Europeanisation&quot; of NATO, influence in Middle East peacemaking and power rivalry in Africa.</p>
<p>Her last months in office were marked by a spat over reports that French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette had snubbed former U.S. secretary of state Warren Christopher during a retirement toast in honour of Christopher at NATO headquarters in Brussels.</p>
<p>France and the United States were also at odds over the appointment of Ghanaian Kofi Annan as Secretary General of the United Nations, and Paris' demands that NATO's southern command, based in Naples, be headed by a European rather than an American.</p>
<p>Tributes poured in for the elegant woman who became a respected diplomat after being the wife or companion of some of the world's wealthiest and most powerful men. She was a popular figure in Paris, admired for her fluent French and gracious style.</p>
<p>&quot;Pamela Harriman was a marvellous ambassador, a neighbour and a good friend. Paris will be much the poorer without her,&quot; British Ambassador Sir Michael Jay said.</p>
<p>Harriman, whose full name is Pamela Digby Churchill Hayward Harriman, was born in Farnborough, England, on March 20, 1920, a daughter of aristocracy.</p>
<p>She had been the wife of Randolph Churchill, son of British prime minister Winston Churchill, and of cinema magnate Leyland Hayward.</p>
<p>She became a U.S. citizen after marrying her third husband, the late multimillionaire diplomat Averell Harriman, in 1971.</p>
<p>Her husband's role and her fondness for throwing huge parties for Washington's rich and powerful, led her to become a major Democratic Party figure in her own right, and she grew in prominence following her husband's death.</p>
<p>Clinton chose her in 1993 as Washington's envoy to Paris, one of the juiciest of U.S. political plums, as a reward for raising millions for his first presidential campaign.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
