<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="35759" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NASD says muni whistleblower's charges meritless.</title>
<headline>NASD says muni whistleblower's charges meritless.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>NASD said Thursday that charges by one of its former investigators that she was forced to resign because of her aggressive probe of &quot;pay-to-play&quot; in the municipal bond market are &quot;meritless.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The National Association of Securities Dealers believes that Ms. Carr's claims are meritless and will vigorously defend the lawsuit,&quot; an NASD spokesman said in an interview.</p>
<p>Theresa Carr was a senior compliance examiner in NASD's district 10 office in New York City until June 19, when, according to a complaint she filed in New York Supreme Court Wednesday, she was essentially forced to resign.  </p>
<p>Carr is seeking $20 million in retribution from NASD for &quot;maliciously&quot; discharging her, breach of contract, &quot;tortious interference&quot; with her probe of muni deals, sexual harassment, and sexual discrimination, the complaint states.</p>
<p>NASD's spokesman said the group is &quot;disappointed and surprised&quot; by Carr's action. Carr resigned &quot;of her own accord&quot; in spring 1996, and six weeks ago asked NASD to hire he back, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>He said Carr's lawyer unsuccessfully sought a settlement with NASD. &quot;Her counsel sought a payment from NASD to keep the suit from being filed. NASD declined,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I asked them if they wanted to settle and do the right thing,&quot; Carr lawyer Jacob Zamansky, a partner with Singer Zamansky in New York City, said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;They've ruined this woman's career,&quot; he charged. &quot;Carr is a whistleblower. She's blowing the whistle on NASD's cozy relationship with major financial securities firms.&quot;</p>
<p>Zamansky said Carr was forced to resign for uncovering muni market violations of Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board's rule G-37, which restricts political contributions by bond firms to state and local elected officials with whom they do business.  </p>
<p>Securities and Exchange Commission recently issued a tough report criticizing the NASD for inadequate oversight of the municipal securities market.</p>
<p>Zamansky, meanwhile, said he expects the NASD to file a motion seeking confidentiality of key court documents in the case. &quot;I'm not going to agree to any confidentiality whatsoever,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;I'll go to the court of appeals on that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to lift the lid off the NASD,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
