<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357508" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian parliament tackles reform, League boycotts.</title>
<headline>Italian parliament tackles reform, League boycotts.</headline>
<byline>Paul Holmes</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>An all-party commission of parliament began five months of work on Wednesday to try to draft constitutional reforms intended to give Italy stable government and effective law-making.</p>
<p>In its first act, the 70-member commission elected the leader of the country's biggest party, Massimo D'Alema of the ex-communist Democratic Party of the Left (PDS), as its new chairman with support from at least part of the opposition.</p>
<p>D'Alema said after the vote that Italy was still in the midst of a crisis -- a reference to the incomplete political transition since major corruption scandals broke in 1992 and toppled Italy's old governing class.</p>
<p>&quot;If we have the courage to seek agreement, we will be providing Italy with renewed institutions and will be living up to the task assigned to us of giving our country a stronger, modern democracy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Reform of Italy's 1948 constitution is the most difficult political challenge facing the country, which has had 55 governments since World War Two.</p>
<p>Two previous attempts to change the way Italy works have failed in the past 15 years and deep differences divide the opposing blocs on the best blueprint for reform.</p>
<p>In a swift sign of the problems, the separatist Northern League announced it was withdrawing its six members from the commission just hours after the inaugural meeting because of parliament's refusal to discuss the break-up of the country.</p>
<p>The League, which has declared a symbolic independent northern &quot;republic&quot;, wants the option of a referendum on secession. It said its boycott followed a ruling by parliamentary officials that such a proposal was inadmissible.</p>
<p>D'Alema, who has staked his political reputation on the success of the commission, won 52 votes to six for his only rival, the League's Rolando Fontan.</p>
<p>Twelve ballots were blank, including those of all 10 members of the commission from the hard-right National Alliance party.</p>
<p>The commission is comprised equally of upper house Senators and lower house deputies and includes the leaders of virtually all major parties among its members.</p>
<p>The governing centre-left and opposition centre-right blocs are most openly at odds over how much power to grant the prime minister under an amended constitution.</p>
<p>The commission will also consider streamlining parliament, whose two existing houses duplicate each other's functions, and how far to decentralise the state and move towards federalism.</p>
<p>It must report back to parliament by the end of June. Both houses are then expected to spend a year studying proposals and drawing up a package of changes to put to a referendum.</p>
<p>D'Alema, whose party is the biggest in the government, had called before the vote for broad support for his candidacy, saying he wanted to encourage &quot;a climate of open dialogue and cooperation.&quot;</p>
<p>His non-partisan appeal was welcomed by centre-right opposition leader Silvio Berlusconi, who has also sunk considerable political prestige into the experiment.</p>
<p>His Forza Italia party had intended to abstain in Wednesday's vote but finally decided to back D'Alema.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
