<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357617" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU says Danish shipyard must repay state aid.</title>
<headline>EU says Danish shipyard must repay state aid.</headline>
<byline>Fredrik Dahl</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission ruled on Wednesday that Denmark, whose shipbuilding industry has complained about subsidies in other countries, had handed out too much state aid to one of its own shipyards and that it must be paid back.</p>
<p>The European Union executive demanded that the Odense shipyard, part of Danish shipping and energy group A.P. Moeller, reimburse with interest around one million crowns ($160,000) of aid granted in relation to five shipbuilding contracts in 1992.</p>
<p>The Commission, concluding a broad investigation of Danish shipbuilding aid in the period 1987-1993, said that out of the 58 contracts examined, 53 had been in accordance with EU aid rules while too much support had been granted in five cases.</p>
<p>EU rules allow for aid of up to nine percent of a ship's contract value.</p>
<p>In Copenhagen, Denmark's Trade Ministry said it accepted with reservations the Commissions's ruling.</p>
<p>Trade Minister Jan Troejborg admitted in a statement that the Commission and Denmark had divergent interpretations of the rules, with Brussels declining to accept that interest accrued on subsidy instalments could supplement state support.</p>
<p>&quot;I disagree with the Commission on this point but take note of their assessment and will now contact Odense shipyard with a view to getting the one million crowns refunded,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The accounting practice was in line with ministerial shipbuilding subsidy regulations previously in force and Danish shipyards had acted in good faith, he added.</p>
<p>A.P. Moeller said it had no further comment on the issue.</p>
<p>The Commission's investigation was launched in July following the publication of a critical independent study accusing the Danish government of illegalities.</p>
<p>The study, commissioned by the Danish industry ministry and carried out by accountancy firm Coopers &amp; Lybrand, criticised Danish ministers for subsidising the sector to the tune of four billion crowns over the last decade.</p>
<p>However, Danish Industry Minister Mimi Jacobsen, who resigned in December in a government reshuffle, in September presented a ministry report concluding that the administration of shipbuilding aid from 1986 to 1995 complied with EU rules.</p>
<p>Rejecting the findings of the Coopers &amp; Lybrand study, she said her ministry had studied 308 cases of aid granted to Danish shipyards and found that the report's critical stance was full of errors and misinterpretations of EU rules.</p>
<p>In view of the relatively modest sum of money involved, Wednesday's decision looked set to be more of an embarrassment for Denmark than a heavy financial burden for A.P. Moeller, the country's biggest privately owned group.</p>
<p>In 1995, the group made a net profit of 1.81 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Danish shipbuilders, hit by competition from subsidised yards abroad, have long complained about subsidies elsewhere, notably in Germany.</p>
<p>Last October, they suffered a legal defeat when their challenge to EU approval of aid to a rival east German shipbuilder was rejected. (1$=6.2835 crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
