<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357692" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: FEATURE - Indian film relives Punjab revolt ahead of poll.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Indian film relives Punjab revolt ahead of poll.</headline>
<byline>Clarence Fernandez</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A film portraying a decade-old separatist movement in India's rich northern farming state of Punjab has revived slowly-fading memories of fear and violence as voters prepare to go to the polls on Friday.</p>
<p>Millions of Indians are humming music from &quot;Maachis&quot; (Matchsticks), a film in Hindi about a young man pulled by the police torture of a friend into the vortex of an abortive independence movement which raged in Punjab in the 1980s.</p>
<p>The story revolves around Kirpal, a young Sikh played sensitively by freshman actor Chandrachud Singh.</p>
<p>Kirpal and his childhood friend Jaswant Singh's mundane farming lives are shattered when two police officers come calling in their Punjab village to ask if they are harbouring a Sikh insurgent known as Jimmy.</p>
<p>Jaswant is taken away for questioning, and returns two weeks later, severely wounded by police torture. The trauma drives Kirpal underground into a shadowy group of militants.</p>
<p>The movie is replete with bittersweet ironies.</p>
<p>Sanatan, Hindu leader of a militant hit squad, seeks revenge for a brother killed in anti-Sikh riots in New Delhi in 1984 after former prime minister Indira Gandhi's assassination by two Sikh bodyguards.</p>
<p>Hindu families in Punjab traditionally baptised their eldest sons as Sikhs, underlining close ties between the communities that were strained by the Sikh revolt. The ties have blurred for Sanatan, who plants a bomb in a bus packed with Hindus.</p>
<p>Kapil kills one of the two police officers who tortured Jaswant, but botches a bid to get the other officer, a tough young professional who would rather be a poet than a policeman.</p>
<p>&quot;In virtually every urban centre of Punjab where the film has been released, it's been declared a runaway hit,&quot; the weekly newsmagazine Outlook said recently.</p>
<p>&quot;Highly romanticised, overflowing with lyricism... but in the end benumbingly close-to-the-bone for people who actually lived through the violence, the terrorist strikes and the bloody police encounters, (it) has struck a chord.&quot;</p>
<p>More than 20,000 people were killed as Indian police battled to quell the bloody rebellion by Sikh religious separatists.</p>
<p>Gandhi was killed four months after ordering troops into the holiest Sikh shrine, the Golden Temple, to flush out militants.</p>
<p>State elections were held in 1992 after containing the guerrillas. But violence erupted again in 1995 when a bomb killed the state's chief minister, Beant Singh.</p>
<p>Bombay film producers estimate &quot;Maachis&quot; has earned about 28 million rupees ($782,000) since its release 14 weeks ago. Seven of 15 film prints are being shown in Punjab, where it is being used as a propaganda tool by the pro-separatist Akali Dal party.</p>
<p>But Indian political parties of both the right and the left, who fear &quot;Maachis&quot; will infuse new life into a dying revolt, say it glamorises terrorism. Some have demanded it be banned.</p>
<p>&quot;We wanted it recast because it ends up blaming the police and government on all counts, and exonerates the terrorists, showing them as Robin Hoods,&quot; said K.R. Malkani, a spokesman for the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party -- which, again ironically, is allied with the Akali Dal in the Punjab polls.</p>
<p>Punjab has been sensitised anew before Friday's elections by the film's emotive imagery, he said, adding: &quot;The government has ordered DCs (district commissioners) to step in an ban the film if they perceive it as a law and order problem,&quot; Malkani added.</p>
<p>R.V. Pandit, a maverick 65-year-old publisher whose first foray into film-making has proved a success, said Maachis does not glorify the terrorist, but does just the opposite.</p>
<p>&quot;Terrorism is always self-defeating. The leaders survive, but the foot soldiers lay down their lives. It has happened everywhere in the world -- Palestine, Latin America, Ireland.&quot;</p>
<p>Indeed, towards the end, Maachis portrays the leader of the separatist team escaping scot-free, leaving all the rest dead.</p>
<p>&quot;When I saw it I didn't think it was biased either way,&quot; said Bombay film critic Deepa Gahlot. &quot;It does trivialise the problem a little. It didn't go back into history at all, or offer perspective. I don't blame it, because as a commercial offering, one can't expect all that.&quot;</p>
<p>Law enforcement officials see it with different eyes.</p>
<p>&quot;Whichever film tries to add a little glamour or draw sympathy for a terrorist, is wrong,&quot; said Aftab Khan, who led the Anti-Terrorist Squad of the Bombay police in operations against Sikh separatists working in India's commercial capital.</p>
<p>&quot;I have dealt with many terrorists,&quot; Khan added. &quot;As far as I could see, 99 percent indulge in forms of extortion and violence because they are pure and simple criminals. Few had motivation in terms of cause or ideology.&quot;</p>
<p>Gahlot saw a rising trend among Indian film-makers to cast terrorists as villains.</p>
<p>&quot;Hindi films over a period of time in their own silly way tend to reflect what's happening.At one time, it was all drug dealers and gunrunners, now they're terrorists. In all now the villain is a terorist, selling drugs over the border,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Perspective and ideology apart, for film distributors the bottom line is what matters. &quot;This is a film for the gentry, not the masses,&quot; said one Bombay distributor who did not want to be identified. &quot;It won't earn much, but it will be safe. Distributors will make money on it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
