<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357631" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India stocks end with small losses in dull trade.</title>
<headline>India stocks end with small losses in dull trade.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>**  (1230 GMT) - Stocks at Indian bourses finish lower</p>
<p>	  after lack of follow-up buying wipes out early rally</p>
<p>**  Bombay's 30-share index down 22.91 points, or 0.68</p>
<p>	  percent, to 3,354.72, off 3,426.67</p>
<p>**  Market's roller-coaster ride attributed to heavy</p>
<p>	  speculative action in pivotal stocks</p>
<p>**  Gujarat Ambuja Cement reports 20 pct rise in first half</p>
<p>	  net profit to 489.8 million rupees, share loses 2.72 pct</p>
<p>**  Delhi index falls 0.96 pct to 732.58, Calcutta sheds</p>
<p>	  0.98 pct to 437.02 and Madras 0.26 pct to 3,254.48</p>
<p>**  National bourse index up 4.20 pts, or 0.43 pct to 962.50</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Indian shares closed slightly lower on Wednesday in a session dominated by speculative action, dealers said.</p>
<p>Traders said the slide near the session's close took them by surprise, but attributed no single major factor to the fall.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no reason for the market to have dropped as it did today,&quot; said chief dealer Sanjeev Choithani at brokers Pashupati Advani. &quot;This is a big speculative game going on.&quot;</p>
<p>The Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) 30-share index fell 71.95 points from the day's high of 3,426.67 to end at 3,354.72 -- a net loss of 22.91 points or 0.68 percent over Tuesday's close.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's very difficult to understand the market trend. There's hardly any institutional activity,&quot; said a dealer at a local brokerage.</p>
<p>Positive remarks by Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda helped rally share prices in morning trade.</p>
<p>The Economic Times newspaper said on Wednesday that Deve Gowda had hinted the 1997 budget, due at the end of February, would include a package of measures to boost investor sentiment.</p>
<p>&quot;When we present the budget, there will be more indications for investors to get a further favourable investment message,&quot; the paper quoted Gowda as telling a news conference.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
