<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357716" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Senate panel approves air ticket tax extension.</title>
<headline>Senate panel approves air ticket tax extension.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Senate Finance Committee Wednesday approved a bill to reimpose the 10 percent airline ticket tax through Sept. 30, 1997.</p>
<p>The tax expired at the end of 1996.</p>
<p>The bill, approved by voice vote, now goes to the full Senate.</p>
<p>The legislation also gives the Treasury Department authority to transfer $1.2 billion in tax revenues collected by the airlines last year but not sent to the Treasury until last month after the tax lapsed.</p>
<p>Under current law, the Treasury does not have authority to transfer the money from its general funds to the Airport and Airways Trust Fund. The bill modifies Treasury regulations to prevent airlines from delaying payment of the tax.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't emphasise enough how critical it is that we enact this legislation promptly,&quot; Committee Chairman William Roth, R-Del., said before the vote.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we can agree that the health of our nation's air transportation system deserves our immeidate attention,&quot; House Ways and Means Chairman Bill Archer, R-Texas, said at his committee's hearing on the same bill Wednesday afternoon.</p>
<p>The Finance Committee acted after the Treasury and Transportation departments said the trust fund, which uses money from the ticket tax to pay for airport and air traffic control system improvements, would go broke soon unless the tax was extended.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless Congress acts promptly to reinstate the taxes, the impact on the Federal Aviation Administration, particularly its capital programmes, will be imminent and severe,&quot; Assistant Transportation Secretary Louise Stoll told the committee Tuesday. She said the capital funding programme could run out of money as early as March.</p>
<p>But a coalition of seven major airlines urged Congress to replace the airline ticket tax with user fees. They said the taxes were unfair to airlines and passengers who use congested routes that require the most air traffic control services.</p>
<p>Some airlines have raised fares by the amount of the former taxes rather than pass on the savings to passengers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
