<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="35787" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dallas Fed economist sees few signs of US slowdown.</title>
<headline>Dallas Fed economist sees few signs of US slowdown.</headline>
<byline>Caren Bohan</byline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. economy, which grew at a brisk 4.8 percent clip in the second quarter of this year, has shown few signs of slowing significantly, according to the head of research at the Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas.</p>
<p>&quot;I tend to look at the economy mostly from the point of view of the Eleventh District and here I see no signs of slowing,&quot; said Harvey Rosenblum, senior vice president at the Dallas Fed. He spoke in Dallas Wednesday in an interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>The Eleventh Fed District includes all of Texas, the northern part of Louisiana and southern New Mexico.</p>
<p>Rosenblum said there also seemed to be few signs of slackening activity in other Fed districts. &quot;In talking with my counterparts around the country, I'm not hearing so much in the way of pessimism.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I have the impression that some regions that had not been doing particularly well for several years, such as New England in particular, that they, just like Texas, have run off a lot of the overcapacity that they once had,&quot; he said. &quot;People who might otherwise be on the unemployment rolls have left and buildings are getting fairly fully occupied.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Fed economist did say, however, that there seemed to be some weakness showing up in the housing sector, which he said would help free up resources for commercial construction.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, I see the economy as healthy and well balanced,&quot; Rosenblum said. &quot;There is a healthy churn taking place.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked about inflation in the United States, Rosenblum described it as &quot;modest but possibly tilting in the wrong direction.&quot;</p>
<p>By that Rosenblum was suggesting that after trending downward for several years, inflation &quot;seems to be flattening out and may even be tilting upward,&quot; he explained. &quot;It's definitely not tilting downward.&quot;</p>
<p>Rosenblum said special forces such as sluggish demand in Europe have held down prices despite a rather vigorous U.S. economy and have helped created a favorable inflation scenario.</p>
<p>Yet he stressed that at some point, prices might start to edge up if unemployment stays low and the economy continues to operate at a high rate.  </p>
<p>&quot;If growth goes on at a well above-average pace for a lengthy period of time when the economy is already operating at or close to full employment, eventually pressures are probably going to increase,&quot; Rosenblum said. &quot;The laws of supply and demand have not been repealed.&quot;</p>
<p>Turning to the Fed's longer-term goals, Rosenblum disagreed with some economists attending last weekend's Kansas City Fed conference who argued that central banks should tolerate a very low level of inflation rather than aim for zero inflation because of the risk of deflation.</p>
<p>He said that deflation is certainly a danger but it would be hard for the Fed not to know if it were occurring, even given measurement problems with the Consumer Price Index.</p>
<p>&quot;I fail to see how inflation does the economy any good,&quot; said Rosenblum, who said zero inflation should be a &quot;mission&quot; for monetary policy. &quot;The question is how long it takes to get there.&quot;</p>
<p>Rosenblum said he was not in favor of legislation introduced by Sen. Connie Mack (R-Fla.) that would mandate that the Fed pursue price stability as the sole goal of monetary policy.  </p>
<p>The Fed economist said a more limited mandate might hamper the central bank's flexibility to incorporate other aspects of its charter, such as the health of the banking system and financial markets, into monetary policy decisions when needed.</p>
<p>&quot;We have the best of all worlds in taking a long-run view,&quot; Rosenblum said. &quot;Life is full of tradeoffs.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
