<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="357954" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S., EU officials see breakthrough in meat talks.</title>
<headline>U.S., EU officials see breakthrough in meat talks.</headline>
<byline>Maggie McNeil</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. and European officials reported major progress this week in talks on their respective meat import regulations and said an agreement by April 1 looked very likely.</p>
<p>&quot;We are both dedicated to reaching an agreement ... there is nothing coming out of the last two days that makes me think it is not possible,&quot; said Lars Hoelgaard, who headed the EU delegation.</p>
<p>Hoelgaard briefed reporters on Wednesday after two days of talks with U.S. Agriculture Department officials on a so-called Veterinary Equivalency agreement.</p>
<p>Paul Drazek, senior trade adviser to Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman, said Tuesday that the two sides had made progress in this week's talks, and that he was also optimistic an agreement will be worked out soon.</p>
<p>&quot;We're making headway,&quot; Drazek told Reuters. &quot;We're hopeful we'll reach an agreement by the end of February.&quot;</p>
<p>Washington has been concerned that an estimated $2 billion in meat, poultry, dairy and pet food products trade could be disrupted as the EU harmonises import rules in the 15 member states, resulting in stricter standards.</p>
<p>Hoelgaard said there was an &quot;important breakthrough&quot; in the recent talks. He said the Agriculture Department had agreed to accept Europe's regionalization system in dealing with disease outbreaks in animals. This has been a major sticking point in the talks.</p>
<p>Under Europe's regionalization system, if there is an animal health problem in a certain region of a country, the EU zones off the area and implements measures to restrict trade into and out of the affected area. But there can be free movement in and out of non-affected areas of the same country.</p>
<p>The United States has refused to recognise Europe's system, however, and has banned meat imports from an entire nation if a problem has been cited in any part of the country.</p>
<p>Europe has argued that the &quot;country by country&quot; approach was illogical and has maintained that &quot;what can trade freely within the Community can trade freely with the United States.&quot;</p>
<p>Hoelgaard said the U.S. side has determined that the Agriculture Secretary has the power to recognise Europe's approach, removing a major obstacle in the talks.</p>
<p>Another set of negotiations is planned for the week of Feb. 24, probably in Brussels. Hoelgaard said the U.S. side has identified 13 outstanding unresolved issues, but said he thinks agreement can be reached on the bulk of them.</p>
<p>Remaining issues include procedures used in making pet food, poultry chilling, physical requirements for slaughterhouses and some worker-related issues such as requiring medical examinations upon hiring.</p>
<p>The EU official discounted claims that failure to reach an agreement would mean a massive disruption of at least a billion dollars worth of trade. Hoelgaard estimated that if a deal is not reached -- which he said is unlikely -- only about $100 million worth of trade would be hit. That would involve $50 million to $70 million in pet food, and perhaps some disruptions in the dairy and poultry sectors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
