<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="358019" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British parties clash angrily over EU and jobs.</title>
<headline>British parties clash angrily over EU and jobs.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's opposition Labour Party on Wednesday accused Prime Minister John Major of sacrificing Britain's economic interests by giving in to demands of so-called &quot;eurosceptic&quot; Conservatives.</p>
<p>The charge, by foreign affairs spokesman Robin Cook, followed a speech by Major on Tuesday in which he said signing up to the European Union's social chapter on workplace standards, as Labour wants to do, could cost 500,000 British jobs.</p>
<p>The bitter exchanges between the two parties confirmed that the EU and Britain's relations with it will be a key issue in the upcoming British general election, due by May 22.</p>
<p>In a speech in London, Cook accused the Conservatives of worrying more about patching up their differences over Europe than about promoting good relations with Britain's neighbours.</p>
<p>&quot;John Major and his cabinet colleagues have repeatedly given more priority to pandering to the prejudices of their party than to serving the interests of the British people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Today I make a call to the business community of Britain to join Labour in waking up the British public to the threat which the europhobia of the Tory Party poses to the jobs and prosperity of Britain.&quot;</p>
<p>Cook compared Conservative eurosceptics to the Trotskyist Militant Tendency which infiltrated Labour in the 1980s, pushing it towards policies which made it unelectable.</p>
<p>&quot;The difference between the Labour Party and the Conservative Party is that Labour's leadership took on the Militant Tendency and crushed them. The Tory leadership has surrendered to the eurosceptics without even a fight,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cook said that, although both Britain's main parties had adopted a wait-and-see policy towards the planned single European currency, there was a clear difference between them.</p>
<p>He said a Labour government would take the decision &quot;on the basis of a hard-headed assessment of economic reality&quot;, but the Conservatives would be influenced by &quot;hysteria and prejudice&quot;.</p>
<p>In Tuesday's speech to businessmen in Brussels, Major said making companies comply with scores of government regulations was adding to the unemployment registers in other EU states.</p>
<p>&quot;Over-regulation doesn't work, and as a result nor do millions of Europeans,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He contrasted Britain's success in creating over 900,000 new jobs in recent years with stubbornly high jobless figures in countries like Spain and France, and warned of dire consequences if Britain signed up for the social chapter.</p>
<p>&quot;One signature on the social chapter would mean half a million signatures on the dole...it would become a Trojan horse unloading on Britain the problems which brought us to a low point in the 1970s,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
