<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="358035" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Underwriters change tack, take on rand Eurobonds.</title>
<headline>Underwriters change tack, take on rand Eurobonds.</headline>
<byline>Hayley Pienaar</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>New banks and investors, previously sceptical of the Eurorand bond sector, have crept into the market attracted by the South African currency's recent good run after its crisis in 1996, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The rand has come a long way since the start of its slide in February last year. It surged through 4.50 -- its best levels against the dollar -- on Wednesday, a gain of 20 cents or 4.0 percent since the start of the year.</p>
<p>The South African currency had lost nearly 30 percent of its value against the dollar in 1996.</p>
<p>A total of 550 million rand ($122 million) of Eurobonds were launched by a wide range of underwriters this week.</p>
<p>Hambros Bank and Deutsche Morgan Grenfell have been in the market since its inception in September 1995, but this week newcomers BZW and ABN AMRO Hoare Govett ventured forth.</p>
<p>BZW syndicate manager Richard Mann said the British investment bank had been studying the market for one year.</p>
<p>&quot;The launch was motivated by a combination of fresh money coming to the market and by redemptions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Volumes of expected Eurorand bond redemptions totalled $302 million equivalent in January, $165 million in February and $68 million in March, Capital DATA Bondware showed.</p>
<p>Dealers said there was strong retail demand for the paper from from Benelux, Italy, Germany and Switzerland as investors were keen to lock in double-digit coupons.</p>
<p>Almost 11.0 billion rand ($2.4 billion) has so far been raised in the Eurorand market, Capital DATA Bondware show.</p>
<p>And the supply is not phasing participants. &quot;This is not a one deal market at all,&quot; BZW's Mann said.</p>
<p>Investors have also had the opportunity to reinvest at higher coupon levels. On average, Mann said triple-A paper was being launched 75 to 80 basis points through equivalent government paper.</p>
<p>Some sentiment still remains that amid the &quot;hot game&quot; of Eurorand bonds, demand is not universal but opportunistic.</p>
<p>Retail investors -- although prone to holding on to paper -- have had to sit white-knuckled on their hands while the rand dramatically fell on key currencies.</p>
<p>Last March, spreads on Eurorand bonds (albeit a relatively inactive secondary market) widened and new issues were put on hold as investors were hit by the currency's slide.</p>
<p>Eurorand supply early this year was said to be motivated by investors who did not want to realise losses incurred by the weaker currency but would rather reinvest their money.</p>
<p>But new issues have also been sparked by bullishness in the underlying markets.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot more people appear to be bullish on the prospect of the currency due to the tight monetary policy in South Africa,&quot; Deutsche Bank syndicate manager Roger Bates said.</p>
<p>&quot;The high real rates and what the devaluation of the currency has done for export potential are encouraging.&quot;</p>
<p>West Merchant Bank syndicate manager Martin Hatt agreed.</p>
<p>While there is still concern with institutional investors about the long-awaited abolition of exchange controls, Bates said retail investors were prepared to take the risk.</p>
<p>Markets hope President Nelson Mandela will make a clear statement of intent on the liberalisation of exchange controls at the opening of parliament on February 7, and give further details in the March 12 budget.</p>
<p>Goldman Sachs said today it calculated the real value of the rand at 4.18 to the dollar and forecast that high interest rates would remain in place until the middle of the year.</p>
<p>Up until now borrowers have been limited to triple-A rated banks, corporates and supranationals, but West Merchant's Hatt said he saw a wider-range of credits coming to the fore in future.</p>
<p>&quot;We are prepared to look at the broader spectrum of issuers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7718</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
