<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="358375" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Dollar, EMU talk set to steal the show at Berlin G7.</title>
<headline>Dollar, EMU talk set to steal the show at Berlin G7.</headline>
<byline>Janet Northcote</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Currency issues look set to top the bill when the world's financial leaders meet in Berlin this week, as a surge in the dollar shares the limelight with the thorny issue of who should join Europe's monetary union and when.</p>
<p>Top officials of the Group of Seven nations have made clear last month's surge of some six percent in the dollar against the mark and yen will be high on the agenda at the meeting.</p>
<p>And with Europe's plans to create the euro etched in to the agenda by host Finance Minister Theo Waigel, talk about a brewing row about plans to persuade some countries to stay out of the single currency in the first wave is inevitable.</p>
<p>But any hopes that Saturday's meeting between finance ministers and central bank governors of France, Canada, Britain, Germany, Italy, Japan and the United States will give markets clear trading direction are likely to be disappointed.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a meeting where the ministers will have lots to say to each other but not much to say to the markets,&quot; said Alison Cottrell, international economist at PaineWebber.</p>
<p>&quot;What they clearly want is stability,&quot; she added. &quot;If you want to try and urge that, the only way is not to give markets any excuse to move, which basically means you say we are happy with the situation as it stands.&quot;</p>
<p>A stream of comments made by top officials in advance of the meeting indicate that the most likely outcome of the dollar discussions will be a statement simply supporting a stable dollar or welcoming its normalisation from all-time lows.</p>
<p>While U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin is still rooting for a strong currency, Japan, which has seen the yen slide over 50 percent since it hit a record high on the dollar in 1995, has expressed concern at the rapid gains and called for action.</p>
<p>Within Europe, views also appear divergent.</p>
<p>Germany's Waigel said on Wednesday he was satisfied with dollar rates, although Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer, seemingly concerned by the pace of the rise, warned last week that the normalisation in the currency rates should end soon.</p>
<p>Meanwhile in France, where industry is baying for a lower franc to help boost exports, the current dollar rate of around 1.65 marks is seen as acceptable, but still on the high side.</p>
<p>Chirac said on Wednesday the dollar was &quot;gradually finding its normal level,&quot; implying it could still go higher.</p>
<p>International Monetary Fund director Michel Camdessus, who will also attend the meeting, summed up his views by saying that &quot;we have never had a constellation (of exchange rates) so favourable to economic development&quot;.</p>
<p>But even if a bland dollar provides an easy compromise to smooth over differences in views, tension among the Europeans at the meeting may run high when the subject turns to the euro.</p>
<p>A report in Wednesday's Financial Times, which said Italy would only be offered the chance to join European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) in 2000 or 2001, was dismissed by officials across Europe, including Italian prime minister Romano Prodi and Waigel.</p>
<p>Under the scheme, a &quot;hard core&quot; of EU members would press ahead with EMU in 1999, the paper said.</p>
<p>But confirmation gleaned from a variety of unnamed sources was sufficient to convince financial markets that the report had more than a grain of truth.</p>
<p>&quot;In the next few days we are going to see some serious bargaining here,&quot; said Marco Pianelli of Nomura Research in London, noting that German chancellor Helmut Kohl was also meeting with Prodi on Friday.</p>
<p>Other topics on the agenda for Saturday's meeting include the provision of debt relief for the world's poorest countries, a discussion on world growth and the need for increased cooperation between supervisory bodies.</p>
<p>But analysts see little room for much more than an exchange of views and update on these topics in the brief three-hour meeting. The officials would declare that inflation remained under control but joblessness was a key problem, they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
