<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="358411" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: EU winter grain crop seen barely scathed by frost.</title>
<headline>EU winter grain crop seen barely scathed by frost.</headline>
<byline>Tim Hepher</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union is set to expand its winter grain crop by four to five percent this year after surviving an earlier freeze with very little damage from frost, grain officials and crop analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Bitter cold at the turn of the year, followed by a sudden thaw, raised some concerns over winterkill in northern Europe. But farmers have managed to cling on to most of the extra sowings delivered by looser EU crop rules this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We have hardly any frost damage, virtually none. This has been officially confirmed,&quot; an EU farm official told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been some incidental problems but we look to be four to five percent higher across the EU,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>That is roughly the amount by which farmers are said to have boosted their winter grain sowings after the EU moved last year to halve its mandatory crop set-aside rate to five percent.</p>
<p>Some officials are privately concerned that crops may be progressing too well this year as the EU struggles to export a record 1996 harvest in the face of falling prices.</p>
<p>Recent crop increases have exposed a widening rift between mainly French farmers, who want to export all-out, and other states including Germany, which favour a return to higher stocks.</p>
<p>An EU grain trade source in Brussels said sowings were up in France and Germany, with large producers shifting to wheat. This was despite the halving of wheat prices since last April, when low stocks drove world values to a record $280 per tonne.</p>
<p>But smaller producers, especially in northern countries, are seen likely to switch to other spring-sown crops to avoid traces of winterkill.</p>
<p>In parts of Denmark and eastern Germany, crops failed to get the protective snow they needed when temperatures fell to minus 15 degrees Celsius. Winter yields there are less encouraging.</p>
<p>Unprotected frost can stunt growth just before plants go into dormancy for the winter.</p>
<p>&quot;Farmers don't want to run the risk. They prefer a smaller yield but a certain yield,&quot; the Brussels trade source said.</p>
<p>Europe's grain firms will see their first clear picture of the winter grain area -- sown in autumn and harvested in summer -- when EU trade lobby Coceral produces key figures on Friday.</p>
<p>But in France new estimates already show winter wheat cultivation is up around 4.9 percent -- more than the last official grain office estimate of 4.7 percent.</p>
<p>Barley is also recovering some ground as wheat prices fall, with a 5.3 percent sowing increase after several years in which it had to make way for extra wheat output, analysts said.</p>
<p>Winter grain is the backbone of European cereals production, especially wheat, though much of the continent's barley and oats and all its maize is planted in the spring.</p>
<p>Relatively light winter damage prompted the International Grains Council (IGC) of farm nations to predict total EU wheat output would break through 100 million tonnes in 1997 to reach 100.6 million, up from 99.4 million in 1996.</p>
<p>Yields may not match a 1996 record but the higher sowings will more than make up for this, it said in a report last week.</p>
<p>In Britain, crops started well and shook off the winter with no problem, but a lack of moisture is worrying some experts.</p>
<p>&quot;Let us have some rain in February and March and we could have a good year,&quot; one crop analyst said.</p>
<p>But farmers in Spain, which recovered from drought last year, say their problem is that fields are too wet in the wake of recent floods. Many in the south have had problems entering water-logged fields to sow winter wheat and barley.</p>
<p>In Spain as well as in Italy farmers may turn their attention to spring sowings to recover productivity.</p>
<p>Worldwide, wheat production is set to jump again in 1997 after a strong rebound in 1996 from previous shortfalls. The IGC says global output should reach 580 million tonnes in 1997 from 575 million in 1996 and 541 million the year before that.</p>
<p>-- Compiled in Paris newsroom +331 4221 5146 with contributions from Brussels, Hamburg, London and Madrid.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
