<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="358693" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Sydney air traffic growth boosts new airport plan.</title>
<headline>Sydney air traffic growth boosts new airport plan.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Perrett</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sydney's air traffic growth is far exceeding expectations, reinforcing the new Australian government's plans for a second major airport for the city, a report issued on Wednesday showed.</p>
<p>By the end of the next decade, about 40 million passengers a year would use the airport, compared with the current 20 million a year and the previous forecast of 18 million for 2010 by 1985 estimates, the Transport Department reported.</p>
<p>Booming tourism and industry deregulation, which has driven down airfares, had pushed traffic growth above earlier expectations, Transport Minister John Sharp said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The projected substantial high growth rates in aviation activity in the Sydney basin highlight the need for a second major airport,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Australian international traffic would grow at between seven and nine percent between now and 2010, compared with the worldwide industry's five percent, the minister said.</p>
<p>Sydney's air traffic, essential to business travel and the tourism industry, is a national political problem.</p>
<p>The current airport, in the suburb of Mascot, is just a 20 minute taxi ride from the city centre, which makes it as convenient for travellers as it is unpopular with residents living under the flightpaths.</p>
<p>Sydneysiders have long demanded the airport be replaced, but the former Labor government approved its expansion in the 1980s while developing a distant plan for a new airport in the city's far west, about an hour's drive away from its centre.</p>
<p>Little progress has since been made on the new airport, which in any case would only have taken a small part of the traffic, mainly smaller aircraft and freight, while the main operations stayed at Mascot.</p>
<p>The current Liberal-National government is looking at a closer site for a new airport and insists it should be a full-scale installation, taking much of the load off Mascot.</p>
<p>However, even Sharp does not expect the new airport to replace Mascot.</p>
<p>&quot;For historic and economic reasons, Mascot will still be the major airport, simply because that's where the two major airlines have got their facilities,&quot; he said, referring to Qantas Airways Ltd and Ansett Airlines Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;But the importance and significance of the second airport will grow as the amount of traffic grows and the increase in traffic is steered towards the second airport.&quot;</p>
<p>The new airport would be able to handle 360,000 take-offs and landings a year, compared with Sydney's current 270,000 and the 426,000 projected for the end of the next decade, he said.</p>
<p>The new government came to office last year promising to spread out the air traffic over Sydney, sharing out the noise that Labor had concentrated over a few suburbs.</p>
<p>Flight paths were changed last year but on Wednesday Sharp issued another plan for Sydney airport that would shift more aircraft away from residential areas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
