<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="358719" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Newcrest sees 14 day Telfer scale-back.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Newcrest sees 14 day Telfer scale-back.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Newcrest Mining Ltd said gold mining activities at its Telfer gold mine in the Great Sandy Desert of Western Australia would be scaled-down for at least two weeks due to fuel supply problems caused by heavy rainfall.</p>
<p>&quot;Full mining activities, assuming no further rainfall, will not be capable of resumption in less than 14 days. Until road access is re-established it will not be possible to determine the extent, if any, to which gold production is impacted,&quot; the company said.  </p>
<p>Newcrest said the temporary reduction would allow it to conserve distillate and to continue ore treatment activities.</p>
<p>&quot;This action has become necessary because run-off following persistent rainfall has cut the mine access road for the last five weeks. Heavy duty maintenance, all non-core and some open pit mining activities will cease until road access is re-established.&quot;  </p>
<p>Gold production at Telfer in the 1996/97 second quarter was 95,739 ounces, a fall of three percent on the year ago level and due to lower than expected oxide mill grades.</p>
<p>The company said on January 29 that this problem was a key factor behind its latest forecast that it might achieve only a break-even profit result in the 1996/97 second half.</p>
<p>Newcrest recorded a pre-tax loss of A$4.8 million before abnormal items in the second quarter ended December 31, last year. Its shares were 10 cents higher at A$5.35 at 3.50 p.m. (0450 GMT).</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
