<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="358761" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: ASIAN EXOTICS - Regionals slip on dollar strength.</title>
<headline>ASIAN EXOTICS - Regionals slip on dollar strength.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>* Most regional currencies lower on dollar's renewed surge against majors and dollar short-covering ahead of holiday period.</p>
<p>* Indonesian rupiah relatively steady as market focuses on liquidity conditions.</p>
<p>* Thai baht hit by dollar strength and weak sentiment for local currency, which spurs continued buying of forwards.</p>
<p>* Malaysian ringgit easier, tracking dollar/majors but downside limited by demand from Japanese and U.S. funds.</p>
<p>* Singapore dollar weak and sluggish after overnight fall.</p>
<p>Short-covering of the U.S. dollar ahead of the Chinese and Moslem New Year holidays dominated activity in most Asian regional currency markets, dealers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The dollar's renewed surge to a four-year high of 122.85 yen in early Tokyo trade reinforced the trend. It was quoted at 122.70/80 at o445 GMT.</p>
<p>Only the Indonesian rupiah held relatively steady amid bearish sentiment for the dollar and concerns about money market liquidity.</p>
<p>Dealers in Jakarta said operators were kept from pushing the dollar lower by the central bank's floor rate, but sentiment remained weak for the U.S. unit.</p>
<p>&quot;This is due to the ongoing moves by players to establish short dollar positions to catch weekend premiums when they cover back on Thursday or Friday,&quot; said a local bank dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;The premiums for five days are not bad,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The foreign exchange market will be closed for Eid al-Fitr on February 10 and 11 and reopen on February 12, while the stock market will be closed from February 7 to 11 inclusive.</p>
<p>Spot rupiah was quoted at 2,373.50/74.50 at 0445 GMT, compared with an opening of 2,373.5/74.5.</p>
<p>Dealers said interbank rates were relatively volatile due to fluctuating short-term swap rates. They said people in the region were already in a holiday mood.</p>
<p>The local bank dealer said offshore players seemed to expect a possible rupiah injection from the central bank if the dollar fell out of its band again, thus driving swap rates down.</p>
<p>In Thailand, the baht slid to 25.935-25.945 to the dollar at 0445 GMT against 25.890/25.895 late on Tuesday. The Bank of Thailand fixed the baht/dollar mid-rate at 25.89 against 25.86 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Dollar's bullish mood abroad triggered a new round of buying of the currency here. Most market players took long dollar positions,&quot; said a dealer at a foreign bank in Bangkok.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a lot of buying interest in the spot and forwards out of Tokyo. People are just trying to square out all their carry-trade positions ahead of the New Year holidays,&quot; said a U.S. bank dealer in Singapore.</p>
<p>He said news of a proposed cut of 59 billion baht in government spending did not boost sentiment for Thailand.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market is still very uncomfortable with being short dollars against the baht,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Bangkok dealers said dollar buying was restrained by tight baht liquidity in the local money market.</p>
<p>The overnight interbank rate rose to 14.50-15.00 percent in early trade from 13.00-14.00 late on Tuesday on heavy demand for funds for the Lunar New Year and for bank reserve requirements.</p>
<p>The Malaysian ringgit was easier as players squared their positions ahead of the holidays, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is a bit on neutral ground, but there is more squaring today because tomorrow everybody will go on long holidays,&quot; said a dealer with a European bank in Singapore.</p>
<p>He said the market was still short dollars, but any retreat of the ringgit would be capped at 2.50, where the Malaysian unit had support from Japanese and select U.S. funds.</p>
<p>Malaysian banks are closed from Friday through Tuesday for the Lunar New Year and Moslem Eid al-Fitr festivals.</p>
<p>Further south, the Singapore dollar was also dented by the U.S. unit's bullish stance, but dealers said activity remained very slow.</p>
<p>&quot;Yesterday, people started buying the dollar/Sing because they can earn a little bit more on swap points due to the interest rate play, but there's commercial selling interest at 1.4110,&quot; said the U.S. bank dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;The overnight high was at 1.4099/1.4100 so we're not breaking any new ground today,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Madhav Reddy in Kuala Lumpur (603-230 8911), Mantik Kusjanto in Jakarta (62-21-384-6364), Anuchit Nguyen in Bangkok (662) 652-0642 and Sonali Desai in Singapore (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
