<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="358825" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: South Koreans take anti-Taiwan protests to sea.</title>
<headline>South Koreans take anti-Taiwan protests to sea.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean activists on Wednesday took their anti-Taiwanese protest to sea as Seoul asked a U.N. body to convince Taipei to drop its plan to ship nuclear waste to North Korea.</p>
<p>Witnesses said about 200 activists aboard 40 chartered boats sailed several kilometres (miles) towards Taiwan, flying placards condemning both Taiwan and North Korea for what they called a deal threatening peace and security in northeast Asia.</p>
<p>Under a contract signed by state utility Taiwan Power Co and a North Korean state agency on January 11, Taiwan is due to ship up to 200,000 barrels of nuclear waste to North Korea.</p>
<p>The activists, demonstrating off the western port of Inchon, also carried pickets reading: &quot;Taiwan should scrap the anti-environmental, anti-humane act&quot; and &quot;North Korea, don't pollute the Korean peninsula with radioactive waste&quot;.</p>
<p>Taiwan has flatly rejected the idea of dropping the deal.</p>
<p>Witnesses said no maritime police vessels intervened in the maritime rally that lasted 1-1/2 hours.</p>
<p>In Seoul, riot police stopped nearly 1,000 elderly citizens trying to march on the Taiwanese trade representative office in protest against the waste deal, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Most of them were born in North Korea before the Korean peninsula was divided into the communist North and capitalist South at the end of World War Two.</p>
<p>The two countries are still technically at war after their 1950-53 conflict ended with a truce, not a peace treaty.</p>
<p>The Foreign Ministry said it had asked the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) to block the shipment.</p>
<p>Suh Dae-won, director-general of the ministry's United Nations Systems Bureau, said the director general of the Vienna-based IAEA, Hans Blix, had promised South Korea that it would try to persuade Taiwan to drop the plan.</p>
<p>Seoul says the deal threatens to pollute the peninsula with radioactivity and points out there has been no verification that the impoverished North can store the waste safely.</p>
<p>Taiwan says the plan complies with international regulations and that shipments would be securely packed in steel barrels.</p>
<p>Last week, seven members of the environmentalist group Green Korea were expelled from Taipei after their protest there.</p>
<p>Beijing, which considers Taiwan a renegade province, has condemned Taipei for the nuclear waste deal.</p>
<p>Taiwan has no diplomatic ties with either North or South Korea. Both recognise China.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I15000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
