<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="358831" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Triple-deck stake for Indonesia Citra.</title>
<headline>Triple-deck stake for Indonesia Citra.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian toll road operator and builder PT Citra Marga said on Wednesday it will participate in a 5.82 trillion rupiah ($2.45 billion) triple-deck road and rail project in Jakarta that will begin construction this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We will participate in the project,&quot; Citra Marga's investor relations officer, who declined to identified, told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the firm was considering taking a 19 percent share of the project's total equity but declined to give any further details.</p>
<p>PT Citra Lamtoro Gung Persada, controlled by one of President Suharto's daughters, has said it will launch the road-rail project in April.  </p>
<p>The Citra Marga official said as of December 1996, Citra Lamtoro Gung Persada held a 4.4 percent stake in the listed toll-road company PT Citra Marga.</p>
<p>Citra Group's head of corporate public relations Fariza Y. Irawady said on Wednesday the project would be financed 75 percent by loans and 25 percent from equity.</p>
<p>The loans will come 60 percent from local sources and 40 percent from offshore, he added.</p>
<p>He said the project would be a joint-venture between Citra, state-owned toll road operator Jasa Marga and state-owned rail company Perumka.  </p>
<p>Irawady said that the triple-deck structure would consist of 23.55 km (14.7 mile) toll-road in the upper part, a 21.25 km (13.2 mile) railway in the middle-part and a public road in the lower part to link south Jakarta and downtown Kota in the north.</p>
<p>Citra Lamtoro Gung Persada, controlled by Suharto's eldest daughter Siti Hardijanti Rukmana, focuses mainly on infrastructure projects.</p>
<p>In mid-afternoon, Citra Marga traded unchanged at 2,075 rupiah on a small volume of 13,500 shares.</p>
<p>($1=2,374 rupiah)</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020028">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020041">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I72300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
