<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="359182" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK stocks end up ahead of holiday on rate outlook.</title>
<headline>HK stocks end up ahead of holiday on rate outlook.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks ended higher ahead of the Chinese New Year holiday, buoyed by expectations of a steady, near-term interest rate outlook, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index jumped 112.07 points, or 0.83 percent, to close Wednesday's session at 13,660.50.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe it has a lot to do with the recovery in the U.S. bond market,&quot; said Vickers Ballas director of research Andrew Fernow. &quot;People are not so worried about interest rates.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S. Federal Reserve will end a two-day policy setting meeting later on Wednesday and is widely expected to leave interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>Analysts said investors were already discounting the news. They will be unable to react on Thursday and Friday since the market will be closed for the Lunar New Year.</p>
<p>Peter Lai, associate director at OCBC Securities, said the Hang Seng Index could test 14,000 points next week if rates remain unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;The fundamentals are very strong. After Chinese New Year, people will begin to put energy into the market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wednesday's turnover rose to HK$7.25 billion compared with HK$6.74 billion on Tuesday, boosted by trade in China Eastern Airlines which made its market debut on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The stock opened at HK$1.50 compared with an issue price of HK$1.38 but closed at HK$1.45 on heavy volume of 366 million shares. It is the first overseas listing of a Chinese airline.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that airlines suffer from a lot of risks that other stocks don't have, particularly in China,&quot; said Fernow.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese aviation industry is very heavily regulated. I am not that confident that this particular company can produce a solid performance over the long term. It has competition on the international routes and is also burdened with a lot of debt.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts also pointed to China's move to cut fares for foreigners in 1997.</p>
<p>The China Daily newspaper said on Tuesday that Chinese aviation authorities have slashed domestic air fares for foreigners travelling in China to try to boost tourism.</p>
<p>The banking sector made strong gains on Wednesday with HSBC Holdings finishing at HK$184.00, up HK$2.00, and Hang Seng Bank climbing HK$1.75 to HK$93.25.</p>
<p>Conglomerates were also buoyant. Hutchison rose HK$0.50 to HK$59.75 and Wheelock gained HK$0.40 to HK$21.60.</p>
<p>In the property sector, Sun Hung Kai Properties rose HK$0.75 to HK$93.00 and Henderson Land gained HK$0.75 to HK$73.50.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
