<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="359156" id="root" date="1997-02-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London gold fixes uneasily at fresh 3-1/4 year low.</title>
<headline>London gold fixes uneasily at fresh 3-1/4 year low.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold prics were hovering on fresh 3-1/4 year lows on Tuesday after weakening from London's intraday-high finish on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said selling in New York and the Far East was prompted by the continuing strong dollar and profit taking after Monday and Tuesday's short-covering rise.</p>
<p>Gold was fixed at $343.15 per ounce, down from $345.70 on Tuesday when it closed at $346.05/$346.55. The fix was the lowest since September 14, 1993 when it was set at $342.05. The previous low since then was on February 3 at $343.75.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks as though it has further to go down although you would not like to put a figure on it,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Support from Hong Kong was muted given a softer tone and the pending Lunar New Year holidays. Business there largely featured selling gold in arbitrage deals against the strong U.S. dollar.</p>
<p>Dealers regarded the US Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) policy advisory group which begins its second and final day of debate on the domestic economy today as largely neutral.</p>
<p>A poll by Reuters of U.S. economists showed most of them did not expect a rise in the fed funds rate at the end of the meeting. But a majority of the sample forecast a 25-basis point rise on the fed fund rate of 5.25 percent some time this year.</p>
<p>The steady policy assumption was based on the absence of inflationary pressures but above-trend growth and some labour market tightness hinted at a possible rise later. More pressingly, the market was still uncomfortable about the possibility of further central bank selling.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether it has happened or not, it is adding to the bearish tone,&quot; a dealer said referring to a spike in lease rates and heavy sale last Thursday which was immediately interpreted as the work of the central banks.</p>
<p>But support has come from physical buying described by market players variously as &quot;very good&quot; and &quot;massive&quot; and was particularly prominent in the Far East.</p>
<p>&quot;The Tokyo premium is quietly positive over local London just now whereas a year ago it was negative,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>The buying was seen as long term investment interest which would not come flooding back into the market for a 10 or 20 percent profit, dealers said.</p>
<p>The other metals also slipped off Tuesday's levels. Question marks over Russia's 1997 supply contracts of platinum and more importantly palladium to Japan were still supportive.</p>
<p>Platinum was down $2.25 at $349.50/$350.50 and palladium off $2.20 at $126.00/$127.00, both reflecting the sector's weakness. Silver was two cents down at $4.85/$4.87 amid sparse interest.</p>
<p>-Brian Spoors London Newsroom +344 171 542 8058</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
