<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="359594" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: TENNIS-WAYNE FERREIRA TO TEAM UP WITH BUDDING STAR.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-WAYNE FERREIRA TO TEAM UP WITH BUDDING STAR.</headline>
<dateline>DURBAN 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>World number eight Wayne Ferreira will team up with emerging South African star Jeff Coetzee as a doubles pairing in some international tournaments scheduled for later this year, Ferreira said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Speaking on the eve of his country's world group, first- round Davis Cup tie against Russia at Durban's Westridge Park Stadium, South Africa's number one player said this was his way of helping to perpetuate South Africa's tennis legacy.</p>
<p>&quot;I am proud to be a South African and...I feel it's important to put something back into the game. </p>
<p>&quot;By teaming up with an up-and-coming young South African tennis player, I can hopefully contribute to the development of tennis in this country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The 19-year-old Coetzee, from Okip in the Northern Cape, has only been playing on the satellite and challenge tour for nine months and has already climbed to a world ranking of 597 as a singles player and 370 in the doubles.</p>
<p>&quot;I managed to get to Wimbledon and played guys like Yannick Noah at an early age,&quot; Ferreira said. &quot;While it's very important for someone of Jeff Coetzee's age to play on the satellite tour, I think it is even more important to play at least once or twice against the very best in the world.</p>
<p>&quot;Only then can you realise straight away your potential and where you are as a tennis player against them.&quot;</p>
<p>Ferreira said he and Coetzee would be trying to get into as many tournaments as possible as a wild card entry during the northern hemisphere's summer months.</p>
<p>&quot;Jeff has now got to work on his ranking and, ideally, get it down to 200 in his singles in his first year,&quot; Ferreira said. &quot;Together, we'll be looking to get his doubles ranking down to 100 -- that would be good.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DURBAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
