<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="359673" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIAN OPPOSITION CELEBRATE BUT ECONOMY GRIM.</title>
<headline>BULGARIAN OPPOSITION CELEBRATE BUT ECONOMY GRIM.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Weeks</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's opposition parties have celebrated non-stop since forcing the ruling Socialists to quit and call elections but the euphoria may wear off quickly when the extent of the devastated economy sinks in.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands of Bulgarians partied in the streets on Wednesday after the Socialists, the country's former Communist Party, gave up after 30 days of mass anti-government rallies.</p>
<p>The square in front of Alexander Nevski Cathedral was packed as pop singers belted out tunes, opposition leaders congratulated themselves and the throng chanted &quot;Victory&quot;.</p>
<p>Opposition leader Ivan Kostov sprayed his political allies with champagne on the cathedral steps and then doused chanting supporters who squealed in delight.</p>
<p>Referring to the fall of one-party communist rule in 1989, he said: &quot;For seven years my generation, and the one after it, have gone through the great drama of being unable to guarantee their children a normal life in their own country.&quot;</p>
<p>Since communism fell, the Communist Party -- relabelled as the Socialist Party -- has won six out of seven elections.</p>
<p>&quot;We felt humiliated, cheated and helpless until these 30 days which changed Bulgaria. Thank you for this solidarity, for this support which was for Bulgaria's future,&quot; Kostov said.</p>
<p>An interim government will now be formed by President Petar Stoyanov and elections will be held by April 20, with Kostov and the opposition Union of Democratic Forces (UDF) the strong favourites to win.</p>
<p>A popular uprising in recent months has focused more on the shattered economy than the democratic process. The Socialists were elected to a four-year term in December 1994.</p>
<p>Kostov, 47, is a vegetarian and jogger. He is an associate professor in economics and served twice as finance minister, in a caretaker government in 1990 and again in 1991.</p>
<p>He has promised quick and sweeping economic reforms to try to drag Bulgaria's economy back from chaos but that will be a difficult and painful task for any government.</p>
<p>The national currency, the lev, has dropped from 800 to the dollar 10 days ago to 2,500 to the dollar now. Inflation has hit 50 percent a month and is rising rapidly.</p>
<p>&quot;Political tension has been defused and the threat of violence removed but what remains is a disastrous economy, which will get worse in coming months,&quot; said a diplomat in Sofia.</p>
<p>The collapse of the lev has caused huge losses for the state-owned Neftohim refinery, which lacks the cash to pay suppliers. Many of Bulgaria's 450 petrol stations have closed, with no fuel to sell.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is becoming disastrous. Bulgarians will need bicycles,&quot; Petar Tsanov, deputy director of the state-owned fuel retailer Petrol, said.</p>
<p>Long queues have formed for bread and people with some cash have stockpiled supplies as protection against soaring prices.</p>
<p>In the long run-up to the late April election, the interim government will seek ways to shore up the economy but its hands will be largely tied.</p>
<p>At best, it will prepare such mechanisms as a currency board, which is aimed at stabilising the lev and which should help to slow hyperinflation, economists said.</p>
<p>But the economy may simply keep sinking until the new government is elected and has the power to push economic reforms through the parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;We must celebrate now because we have very hard days ahead,&quot; Kostov said told the final victory rally.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
