<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="359812" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African rand riding high ahead of Mandela speech.</title>
<headline>S.African rand riding high ahead of Mandela speech.</headline>
<byline>Ben Hirschler</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's rand hit a six-month high against a strong dollar on Thursday as a bond buying spree continued and markets looked hopefully to a major speech by President Nelson Mandela.</p>
<p>The currency hit a best level of 4.4570 bid against the dollar at 0830 GMT -- a level last seen on August 5, 1996 -- while long bond yields dipped below 15 percent for the first time since September.</p>
<p>Dealers said they were hoping for news on relaxating exchange controls when Mandela opens the 1997 session of parliament in Cape Town on Friday at 11.00 a.m. (0900 GMT).</p>
<p>Rumours are rife he will use the opportunity of firming markets to make a bold announcement on easing controls and privatisation.</p>
<p>However, few market players are looking for a single &quot;big bang&quot; abolition of all restrictions since this would run counter to previous stated policy of a gradualist approach. Some also say expectations of an announcement on Friday may be premature with the March 12 budget a more realistic date.</p>
<p>Sources close to Mandela say his heir apparent, Deputy President Thabo Mbeki, made a major input into the speech to be delivered on Friday.</p>
<p>Mandela is scheduled to step down at the next election in 1999 and in recent months has delegated more and more responsibilities to Mbeki.</p>
<p>Previous Mandela speeches opening parliamentary sessions have been long on general policy goals but short on specific initiatives or plans.</p>
<p>However, Tony Twine of Econometrix noted that after high- level ANC policy discussions last month Mbeki had signalled that notable speeches would be made during the opening weeks of parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;So it looks as though it's going to be a slightly more important opening of parliament address than we've been used to. That's what the market is now tossing around like a dog plays with a chicken leg,&quot; Twine said.</p>
<p>He said no parliamentary opening speech had yet rivalled in importance that made by F.W. de Klerk in February 1990, when he declared that Mandela would be freed from jail. But Mandela could nevertheless announce major policy changes on Friday.</p>
<p>Currency dealers reported heavy dollar selling by overseas and local players while bond investors once again rushed to buy high-yielding South African debt.</p>
<p>The rand has now advanced nearly five percent against the dollar since the start of the year and some seven percent against a trade-weighted basket of currencies.</p>
<p>Analysts say confidence has been restored to South Africa by expectations of a sharply improving trade balance this year which should cut the current account deficit and boost critically-low foreign exchange reserves.</p>
<p>Against that sound economic backdrop there is a growing consensus that the rand should stabilise in 1997, tempting overseas investors back to rand assets once more.</p>
<p>Foreigners snapped up a net 492 million rands worth ($110 million) of South African bonds on Wednesday, taking net foreign purchases this year to 2.9 billion rand, according to Bond Exchange figures.</p>
<p>($=4.46 rand)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
