<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="359835" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOZAMBIQUE: World Bank chief to see Mozambique's recovery.</title>
<headline>World Bank chief to see Mozambique's recovery.</headline>
<dateline>MAPUTO 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>World Bank President James Wolfensohn visits Mozambique next week where he will find a country transformed into a working democracy after 16 years of civil war and where economic prospects are looking up.</p>
<p>Branded one of the world's poorest countries, the World Bank has projected a growth rate for Mozambique of 15 percent a year in total exports for 1997 to 1999.</p>
<p>Mozambique and South Africa are the two southern African countries Wolfensohn will visit during a nine-day trip of Africa aimed to strengthen relationships with the region.</p>
<p>He will meet government and private sector for round table discussions on Mozambique and regional integration and will see for himself rural projects funded by the Bank.</p>
<p>Mozambique's government began concentrating on rebuilding its economy in 1995 after the massive task of resettling four million Mozambicans who fled their homes during the war and demobilising 80,000 troops.</p>
<p>Democratic elections in 1994 paved the way for a unity government between President Joaquim Chissano's Frelimo party and the former rebel Renamo group.</p>
<p>The economy is unable to survive without foreign aid which finances about two thirds of its national budget, but exports have increased by almost 30 percent and the economy has grown by about six percent in 1995.</p>
<p>A sign of Mozambique's recovery is lower inflation levels which dropped to around 17 percent in 1996 from a high of 70 percent in 1994.</p>
<p>A series of agricultural reforms have doubled the volume of sales of cashew nuts -- a mainstay of the economy -- and the grain harvest has set a 20-year record.</p>
<p>In 1996 the country exported 1.37 million tonnes of cereal and in 1997 this should increase to 1.50 million tonnes, the United Nations said this month.</p>
<p>The country still however faces huge problems of poverty and and heavy foreign debt.</p>
<p>Wolfensohn, who has declared he wants to step up lending to the region, is expected to discuss with Mozambique alternative means of debt relief to help the governnment out of its debt problem.</p>
<p>One of the biggest foreign exchange earners for Mozambique could be the development of its transit corridors to South Africa, Zimbabwe and Malawi which provide vital access to the sea.</p>
<p>The country has also embarked on a privatisation programme and by 1995 it had transferred about 700 of its estimated 1,000 state-owned companies to the private sector.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOZAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAPUTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOZAMBIQUE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
