<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="359871" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - Feb 6.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - Feb 6.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are significant stories in the Nigerian press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY TIMES</p>
<p>- Workers of Texaco Inc Nigeria unit may go on strike over alleged plans to sack 150 of them, union sources say.</p>
<p>- Transport Minister Major-General Ibrahim Gumel says at award of 2.6 billion naira contract to modernise Nigerian Railways' communications that all problems of the company have now been addressed and vibrant rail system should emerge soon.</p>
<p>- Cotton farmers in northeastern Nigeria attribute low prices to over production of the commodity in the area.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>- Nigerian politicians, ruffled by military ruler General Sani Abacha's remarks that he had not addressed his mind on whether or not to contest next year's presidential election, decline to comment on the issue.</p>
<p>- National carrier Nigeria Airways says it is arranging to lease two aircraft to convey to Jerusalem Nigerian Christian pilgrims stranded in Lagos since Tuesday.</p>
<p>THISDAY</p>
<p>- Family of Claude Ake, a prominent social science professor who died in a plane crash last November that killed all 143 on board, may be demanding 99 million naira compensation from the Aviation Development Company, operators of the flight.</p>
<p>- Nigerian Solid Minerals Minister Kaloma Ali visits South Africa to try to attract investors for the mining industry.</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
