<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="359907" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - Feb 6.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - Feb 6.</headline>
<text>
<p>DELO</p>
<p>- Slovenia's prime minister-designate Janez Drnovsek said he expected parliament to approve his new cabinet on Thursday, almost three months after inconclusive November 10 general elections.</p>
<p>- Government coalition comprising centre-left Liberal Democrats, former communists the United List, Desus party representing pensioners and Nationalist Party expects governmental line-up to be approved by parliament in today's vote.</p>
<p>- A civil society group will hold a protest rally in front of parliament, claiming that the government's line-up which is due to be approved today is illegal.</p>
<p>- Slovenian branch of Bank Austria opened a subsidiary in the coastal town of Koper. The bank plans to open subsidiaries in Celje and Maribor.</p>
<p>- The Trbovlje power plant will be closed and replaced by another source of electricity by 2003, the environment ministry said.</p>
<p>DNEVNIK</p>
<p>- Pharmaceutical producer Krka plans to start construction of a factory worth $25 million in Sentjernej, 60 km (37 miles) south of Ljubljana next year. Krka also plans to open factories in Poland, Croatia and Russia.</p>
<p>REPUBLIKA</p>
<p>- Liberal Democrats and United List of Social Democrats, the former communist party, signed a formal coalition agreement on Wednesday.</p>
<p>- The country's privatisation agency said that 1,347 companies have already been privatised, while another 906 are still in the process.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
