<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="359915" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Emboldened Albanian protesters set to return.</title>
<headline>Emboldened Albanian protesters set to return.</headline>
<byline>Benet Koleka</byline>
<dateline>VLORE, Albania 1996-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Impoverished Albanian investors, emboldened by big turnouts in two days of protests, say they will keep marching through this port every day until they get back stakes lost in failed investment schemes.</p>
<p>&quot;Every day to the square!&quot; chanted marchers in Vlore's Independence Square on Thursday after a day of anti-government protests, now unimpeded by police who gave up unsuccessful attempts to contain and disperse demonstrators.</p>
<p>A large fire of cardboard boxes burned into the chilly night as the demonstrators made their way home. Many taking part were residents of hillside villages who also lost life savings in the dubious schemes.</p>
<p>Up to 30,000 protesters surged through the city on Thursday morning denouncing right-wing President Sali Berisha and making a mockery of lines of disheartened riot police.</p>
<p>Some 10,000 pressed on to the main police station demanding the release of demonstrators detained after the previous day's clashes with police on streets strewn with broken glass.</p>
<p>Marchers briefly pelted police with stones in the day's only violence. About 20 people were eventually released.</p>
<p>An evening march through darkened streets to the harbour and back to the square drew an even bigger crowd.</p>
<p>Pyramid schemes offering quick, lucrative returns have flourished in post-Communist Albania. Protesters blame their collapse on Berisha and his ruling Democratic Party, re-elected last year in polls denounced as unfair by Western observers.</p>
<p>&quot;We will march 20 days, 30 days until we get our money,&quot; one well-dressed woman shouted. &quot;They have our money.&quot;</p>
<p>The march was carnival-like, with children and elderly women striding alongside men sporting two-day-old beards. There were no leaders heading columns and not a single government or opposition politician in sight.</p>
<p>The protests were triggered by the collapse of the Gjallica firm, which has its headquarters in Vlore.</p>
<p>Vlore has a tradition of national sentiment and Albanian statehood was proclaimed there in 1912. But it gained notoriety after the fall of communism as a staging point for running drugs and illegal immigrants across the Adriatic Sea to Italy.</p>
<p>Although state television showed lengthy reports of the latest protests, they have so far been confined to the city.</p>
<p>The south was the focal point of protests last month against the collapse of the schemes, but enraged investors set fire to buildings in a whole string of towns.</p>
<p>Would-be protesters have since been deterred by at least 150 arrests and the threat of 15-year jail terms on public order charges. And the country's Socialist-led opposition lacks charismatic leaders to channel discontent.</p>
<p>Berisha has failed to appear in public since chairing a meeting on Tuesday of trade unions and political parties boycotted by the main opposition grouping.</p>
<p>In foreign newspaper interviews this week he admitted the schemes were a bitter lesson for Albanians emerging from Eastern Europe's most repressive communist regime. He also accused his opponents of using protests to try to stir trouble.</p>
<p>Economists believe $2 billion may be tied up in various schemes, some of which have cut interest rates to keep afloat.</p>
<p>Investors in two failed schemes have begun receiving partial refunds on their deposits but demand cash in favour of an offer of government certificates. Banking officials admit that payouts could take more than six months to complete.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VLORE, Albania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
