<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="360028" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovakia approves Exim bank to fight trade deficit.</title>
<headline>Slovakia approves Exim bank to fight trade deficit.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Slovak parliament on Thursday approved a law creating a state Export-Import bank to help boost exports and curb a burgeoning foreign trade deficit.</p>
<p>The bank, expected to begin operation sometime later this year, will be wholly state-owned and start with a basic capital of two billion crowns, all of which will come from the 1997 state budget.</p>
<p>&quot;The Exim bank will be an instrument to solve problems with financing export-import credits, mainly medium and long-term facilities,&quot; the law's preamble said.</p>
<p>The bank's balance sum is expected to eventually reach some 70 billion crowns.</p>
<p>This year's budget will also provide eight billion crowns for the initial stages of financing insurance of export credits by the bank.</p>
<p>According to law, future state budgets should include allocations to serve as the bank's reserve funds.</p>
<p>Slovakia posted a foreign trade shortfall of 64.54 billion crowns for the whole of 1996, compared with a 5.69 billion crown gap for January-December 1995.</p>
<p>The Exim bank's statutes lie outside the current banking law, making it exempt from supervision by the central bank. Instead, cabinet will be the only body with control over the instituion.</p>
<p>The law also states the bank will only support large export projects approved by the government.</p>
<p>The bank will be allowed to operate on domestic and international capital markets.</p>
<p>&quot;The bank's advantage will be that it can obtain cheaper funds since the state guarantee gives it the sovereign risk on foreign financial markets,&quot; the law says.</p>
<p>Slovakia has a sovereign debt rating of BBB- from Standard and Poor's, and a Baa3 from the Moody's agency.</p>
<p>The finance ministry, which drafted the law, says it expects the bank to cover about 30 percent of Slovak exports. The needs of exporters to finance export credits are estimated at around 32 billion crowns.</p>
<p>-- Peter Laca, Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-521-8402</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
