<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="36019" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraq tones down anti-U.S. rhetoric, defiance.</title>
<headline>Iraq tones down anti-U.S. rhetoric, defiance.</headline>
<byline>Leon Barkho</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraqi newspapers on Thursday toned down their defiant rhetoric, a sign that Baghdad may avoid escalating its military confrontation with the United States, at least for the time being.</p>
<p>The newspapers avoided fiery comments or editorials. Their front pages were splashed with pictures of President Saddam Hussein's Wednesday meetings with air defence commanders and chiefs of staff.</p>
<p>In their inside pages they published pictures of &quot;the victims of the criminal American bombing on Wednesday&quot;.</p>
<p>The papers shifted focus to world reaction to the U.S. missile strikes, highlighting Russia's condemnation of the attacks, which were prompted by Iraqi military moves in the Kurdish north.</p>
<p>The U.S. fired a total of 44 cruise missiles on Iraq on Tuesday and Wednesday on air defence targets in southern Iraq to minimise Iraqi resistance to its warplanes policing an expanded no-fly zone in southern Iraq.</p>
<p>An Iraqi military communique late on Wednesday spoke of further U.S. strikes on both military and residential targets in and around Baghdad.</p>
<p>Large explosions rocked the Iraqi capital and heavy anti- aircraft fire burst over the city, litting up the night-sky.</p>
<p>The Pentagon denied it had launched any attacks in and around Baghdad. Iraqi officials took Western reporters to a residential area where they saw small craters and an apartment littered with glass and furniture.</p>
<p>Iraq has vowed to defy U.S. and allied air-exclusion zones over its territory. It has urged its pilots and anti-aircraft gunners to shoot down any foreign plane violating its air space.</p>
<p>U.S. warplanes on Wednesday patrolled the new areas which President Bill Clinton added to the former no-fly zone in southern Iraq.</p>
<p>On Wednesday a U.S. warplane fired at an Iraqi radar outside the zone closed to Iraqi aircraft. No other incident has been reported so far.</p>
<p>Iraq's neighbour Turkey showed its readiness to protect its interests in the region. A foreign ministry spokesman said on Wednesday Ankara planned to create a security cordon inside northern Iraq to curb increasing Kurdish separatist activity along the porous border between the two countries.</p>
<p>Turkish troops, backed by air power, could attack Kurdish separatist rebels in northern Iraq at any time, a high-ranking Turksih military official said.</p>
<p>On Thursday Iraq's state-run radio and television were slowly switching to normal programmes after a three-day continuous broadcast of patriotic songs and commentaries urging Iraqi armed forces and people to rise against &quot;criminal (U.S. President) Bill Clinton and his vicious aggression.&quot;</p>
<p>The government newspaper al-Jumhouriya in a front-page editorial thanked Russia, France and China for what it described as their pro-Iraq attitudes on Baghdad's latest row with Washington.</p>
<p>The editorial in the official al-Qadissiya called on U.N. Security members not to remain silent on &quot;America's humiliating aggression&quot; on Iraq. So did Babel, the newspaper of Saddam 's eldest son Uday. The official al-Iraq had no comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
