<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="36020" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS - German economy expands strongly in 2nd QTR.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - German economy expands strongly in 2nd QTR.</headline>
<byline>Terence Gallagher</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German government said on Thursday the economy rebounded a strong 1.5 percent in the second quarter from the weak previous quarter, at the upper end of economists' expectations.</p>
<p>The economy had shrunk 0.5 percent in the first quarter.</p>
<p>Measured against the year-earlier quarter, gross domestic product (GDP) grew 1.2 percent in the second quarter, up from 0.2 percent year-on-year growth in the first quarter.</p>
<p>Uwe Angenendt of BHF Bank told Reuters Financial Television the second-quarter growth figures were &quot;on the upper end of expecations. It is quite good news for the German economy&quot;.</p>
<p>Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt said 1996 growth could be stronger than the government's previous projection of 0.75 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;An increasing number of economic indicators speak for a continuation of the economic revival,&quot; Rexrodt said.</p>
<p>Low interest rates, moderate wage agreements, stable prices and a retreat in the mark's overvaluation all contributed to a recovery of business confidence.</p>
<p>Growth in the first half of the year was 0.7 percent from the year-earlier half, he said.</p>
<p>Juergen Stanowsky of Dresdner Bank was even more bullish. &quot;For all of 1996, we still expect a growth rate of 1.5 percent. The inflation perspective is quite good. There is no reason for the Bundesbank to cut rates,&quot; Stanowsky told Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>Economist Mathias Hafner of BZW took a more sceptical view. &quot;The numbers are good but we believe that growth will normalise in the second half of the year and give the Bundesbank little reason to do anything else on interest rates. For the second half we expect more moderate growth, around 0.5 percent on the quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>West Germany showed growth of 1.0 percent in the second quarter from the previous quarter, according to the Economics Ministry, and 1.1 percent from the year-earlier quarter.</p>
<p>The east German economy grew a vigorous 5.0 percent from the previous quarter, and 2.6 percent from the year-earlier period.</p>
<p>Private consumption gained 1.2 percent from a year earlier, while public consumption gained 3.6 percent. Capital investment gained 0.5 percent, but construction fell 1.4 percent.</p>
<p>Exports gained 2.5 percent and imports fell 0.7 percent.</p>
<p>Rexrodt said the second-quarter rebound was due to core growth as well as seasonal recovery from the unusually severe winter.</p>
<p>Incoming orders expanded, boosting industrial production and capacity utilisation. Construction demand remained weak, but the economy is back on course for growth in the medium term, Rexrodt said.</p>
<p>Labour market conditions remained unsatisfactory, and no near-term relief was visible, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;More effort at flexibility and an accelerated economic development are indispensable fro an improvement in the labour market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The services sector continued its expansion, which had been uninterrupted by the weak phase in the broader economy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
