<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="360412" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Progress seen toward Parkinson's gene therapy.</title>
<headline>Progress seen toward Parkinson's gene therapy.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kenen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>In a development that could one day lead to new therapies for Parkinson's disease, U.S. scientists said on Thursday they have used gene therapy in rat brains to protect nerve cells that make a crucial chemical.</p>
<p>A University of Rochester team used a modified version of the common cold virus to deliver into rat brains a gene that produces a protein messenger needed to protect nerve cells that make dopamine.</p>
<p>Parkinson's patients lack of dopamine, a neurotransmitter, leads to gradual deterioration of motor abilities, including tremors and difficulty in moving.</p>
<p>Rochester neurobiologist Martha Bohn said rat experiments, reported in Friday's edition of the journal Science, did not hold out any immediate hopes for human patients but were a step toward gene therapy.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an excellent first step,&quot; she said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Bohn is now working on other versions of viral delivery systems, and will also test the approach in monkeys, who provide a better model of Parkinson's.</p>
<p>Parkinson's targets a tiny area deep in the brain stem, where nerve cells produce dopamine.</p>
<p>The virus served as a shuttle, called a vector, to introduce into the brain a gene that controls glial cell-derived neurotrophic factor, known as GDNF.</p>
<p>Introducing this gene enabled damaged brain cells to start producing GDNF. Nerve cells need GDNF to stay healthy and produce dopamine.</p>
<p>Lab rats with a condition like Parkinson's given this treatment lived significantly longer than those that did not.</p>
<p>&quot;The exciting part of this finding is that we know you can put the gene into the right part of the brain and get GDNF secreted continuously at low levels,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>If the gene therapy approach works in humans -- and many experiments with gene therapy have failed -- it would provide a way of getting a very small amount of this growth factor into precisely the right place in the brain.</p>
<p>Other experimental treatments with GDNF under development require larger doses, which could cause side effects, she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
