<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="360433" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RTRS-INSIGHT-Copper seen in uptrend, GSCI return.</title>
<headline>RTRS-INSIGHT-Copper seen in uptrend, GSCI return.</headline>
<byline>Clive McKeef</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Base metals prices, including copper, are likely to continue to move higher in 1997, as world economic growth picks up and inventories remain low, analysts said.</p>
<p>In the past month, base metals prices have already made the biggest contribution to returns on commodities as an investment class, as measured by the Goldman Sachs Commodity Index (GSCI) Total Returns Index, analysts noted.</p>
<p>&quot;Following two years of volatile but generally declining prices, base metals have rebounded from the late 1996 lows and appear poised to move higher, not unlike the 1994 bull market,&quot; E.D. &amp; F. Man's New York analyst Fred Demler said.</p>
<p>&quot;The common threads among the base metals include an improving global economy, a shift from consumer destocking to restocking, a slowdown in primary production growth, an improved East-to-West trade balance, and generally low or declining inventories,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Physical premiums have increased, the futures markets forward spreads have tightened and discretionary institution fund managers have turned friendly to the industrial metals complex,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In New York COMEX March copper prices were down 1.45 cents a pound at $107.30 cents early Thursday, after rallying to fresh six month highs Wednesday.</p>
<p>But the nearby spreads remained in sharp backwardation, with the London Metal Exchange (LME) cash-to-three month spread around $207 a tonne, from $180 a tonne at Wednesday's close, and up from a low around $111.00 a tonne Tuesday.</p>
<p>The COMEX March/May spread edged up to 4.05 cents early Thursday, from 3.70 cents at Wednesday's close.</p>
<p>In the past three months copper prices have been recovering steadily from two year lows seen in mid-1996, when, after the Sumitomo scandal, prices fell to levels that restricted the supply of scrap onto the prompt market.</p>
<p>After Wednesday's jump in COMEX March copper to six month highs, the contract's standard five-day (weekly) simple moving-average was turning higher again, and its 21-day (monthly) average remained above its 55-day (quarterly) average, as it has done since October 1996, analysts noted.</p>
<p>With copper, aluminium, zinc and nickel prices all in uptrends in recent months in LME trading, industrial metals have seen a 1.54 percent return as a sector in the past month in the GSCI Total Returns index, and a 13.64 pct return in the past three months, with copper alone returning 21.35 pct. The GSCI Total Returns Index measures gains on investments in commodities as an asset class, based on buying nearby active month futures and rolling them forward near expiry.</p>
<p>The GSCI index itself was down 0.66 points at 203.49 early Thursday, from 215.26 on December 31. The other US benchmark commodity index, the CRB Index, was down 0.45 points at 238.86, little changed from the 239.61 on December 31.</p>
<p>Copper mine capacity builds, largely in Chile, Peru, Australia and the US, will lead to primary production increases of about 6.0 pct in 1997 and 1998, Demler said.</p>
<p>But copper consumption is expected to rise 4.1 percent in 1997 and remain strong in 1998, after eleven consecutive years of demand growth, he said.</p>
<p>And combined LME and COMEX exchange inventories are relatively low, despite a recent recovery, and the stocks/consumption ratio fell to only 2.5 weeks usage in 1996.</p>
<p>In addition, the Chinese may return to the copper market as buyers in late February or early March, said Ted Arnold, analyst at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>&quot;This buying interest will coincide with some Japanese buying for GSP (preferential tariff purchases) and a seasonal pick up in construction activity.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;So whatever happens, do not short the market as a big backwardation could reappear in the next few months.&quot;</p>
<p>Clive McKeef, New York Commodities, +1-212-859-1641</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
