<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="360638" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Portugal's Navigator bonds seen booming in 1997.</title>
<headline>Portugal's Navigator bonds seen booming in 1997.</headline>
<byline>Sergio Goncalves</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Portugal's Navigator bond market is steering towards a buoyant 1997 as domestic investors with few investment alternatives seek to capitalise on a sharp fall in local interest rates, analysts said.</p>
<p>Some said volume this year in the new Navigator eurobond issues could reach 1.0 trillion escudos ($6 billion), up from 550 billion in 1996. In January of this year, 100 billion escudos of new Navigator bonds have already been issued.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has been very frisky since the start of the year, which makes me think that we could see 1997 volume of 800 to 900 billion escudos. It might even reach 1.0 trillion,&quot; said Luis Feria, syndication director at Banco Cisf.</p>
<p>Unlike Spain, where foreign demand is strong for the equivalent Matador bonds, demand for Navigators has remained almost solely domestic.</p>
<p>&quot;Domestic investors want to diversify but with the security of a credit rating. This is the main reason for the strong growth,&quot; said Leonardo Mathias of Banco Essi.</p>
<p>There are no restrictions on who can issue the bonds, but most issuers tend to be foreign financial institutions and some supranationals, such as the European Investment Bank (EIB). EIB is the leading issuer and last year, began issuing 20-year Navigators.</p>
<p>Though Navigators are issued in escudos, most issuers include a simultaneous swap deal for dollars or marks.</p>
<p>Navigators also attract domestic insurers and funds who do not wish to get involved in foreign currency trading or take risks on a domestic issuer without a credit rating.</p>
<p>Declining rates has also helped fuel volume. Since January 1996, the Bank of Portugal's repo rate has fallen 200 basis points (bps) to its current 6.50 percent, and Treasury bond yields have dropped 300 basis points to 6.68 percent. The Treasuries' spread over Bunds has fallen from 370 to 100 bps on Thursday, after hitting a low of 85 bp.</p>
<p>&quot;Against this background of lower interest rates, there is going to be demand for extra yield,&quot; Luis Nogueira of Banco Finantia said. &quot;As a result, people are going to be looking for alternatives with different risks that will yield more.&quot;</p>
<p>That demand for higher yields should also lead to greater sophistication in the relatively young market.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to see innovations in credit risk, and we'll have new names issuing in this market,&quot; Feria said.</p>
<p>One analyst said appetite for 10-year, fixed-rate bonds was waning and that investors would hunger for shorter maturities at variable rates.</p>
<p>&quot;We could also see issues linked to interest rate spreads and exchange rates against the mark, with maturities of up to two years (January 1999), with an optimial period of one year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another analyst expected to &quot;see more securitised structures, which offer higher yields than non-securitised structures and besides, many issues with cap, floor and collar -- the issue of more sophisticated structures such as swaptions.&quot;</p>
<p>While last year, most financial institutions banked on Portugal's joining Europe's Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) at its launch, recent doubts could mean investors might hold back before deciding which fixed-rate investment to opt for, pushing them toward Navigators.</p>
<p>-- Lisbon newsroom +351-1-3538254 ($ = 165.7 Portugese Escudos)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
