<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="360661" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital markets closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital markets closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>French bond futures ended the MATIF session off the lows touched after German unemployment data and a weak-demand OAT auction, but the 10-year future could test its contract high if US non-farm payrolls are favourable on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;If they're good, the notionnel should get back to 131.16, and why not further,&quot; said one trader. The outlook was basically positive and the very high German unemployment number gave new life to hopes of further rate cuts, the trader added.</p>
<p>Analysts said it was hard to measure when the Bundesbank might make a further cut in interest rates but it now looked like it would at least be under more pressure to do so.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think the Bundesbank is more sensitive to unemployment than in the past, in the run up to monetary union,&quot; said an analyst at Credit Lyonnais. &quot;It wants growth under good conditions.&quot;</p>
<p>Speaking of the possibility of a Bundesbank rate cut, the analyst said, &quot;There could be a window in the next four to six weeks.&quot;</p>
<p>On the other hand, the Bundesbank might be tempted to wait until the export lift from a stronger dollar wore off before moving, but in any case the feeling was the market had not seen the end of the cutting, the analyst added.  </p>
<p>U.S. non-farm payrolls are expected to fall to 237,000 for January from 262,000 previously, with the unemployment rate expected to come down to 5.2 percent from 5.3 previously.</p>
<p>The 10-year future settled at 130.90 but off a low of 130.66 hit earlier in the day after a high German unemployment figure foot-faulted a curve-steepening play that has dominated the French market for a couple of weeks.</p>
<p>The dip was accentuated after demand at Thursday's OAT auction came in far weaker than expectations, but buying back at lower levels lifted it back later in the day.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 42 21 53 63</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
