<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="360612" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek farmers seize roads as police look on.</title>
<headline>Greek farmers seize roads as police look on.</headline>
<byline>Costas Paris</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek farmers scored again in their row with the government on Friday after seizing national roads with thousands of tractors and embarrassing police who stood by, powerless to react.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Costas Simitis refused to meet farmers' representatives on Thursday to discuss their demands and the farmers answered with a mass parade of 2,000 tractors on the main north-south highway.</p>
<p>Simitis, now facing critisism for taking no action when the farmers occupied highways for 25 days in December, sent 5,000 police, many in riot gear, into the central Thessaly region with strict orders to keep roads open.</p>
<p>But in a show of force, the farmers eluded police on Thursday night, driving their tractors for five hours through cotton fields and across rivers before emerging on the national highway outside the central Almiros village.</p>
<p>Television showed the convoy of tractors -- an endless line of headlights coming in from the mountains -- rattling down the highway as police units watched from a distance with orders from Athens to let them through.</p>
<p>&quot;We may stay the night on the highway or pull over later on. We are in full control and Mr Simitis will now understand that his authoritarian methods can't stop us,&quot; Manolis Sotirakis, a cotton grower said.</p>
<p>Simitis had earlier turned down the farmers' request to meet him, saying no meeting was possible with the roads under siege.</p>
<p>&quot;All forms of mobilisation and threats to close off the roads must clearly stop for such a meeting to be possible,&quot; government spokesman Dimitris Reppas told reporters.</p>
<p>The farmers have been playing a cat-and-mouse game with police for the past four days, driving their tractors off the roads and accross vast farmlands or under bridges whenever riot squads and police helicopters confronted them.</p>
<p>They blocked smaller roads at will in a bid to show that police could not stop them from repeating their December action.</p>
<p>Simitis waited out that 25-day blockade, saying the country could not afford to satisfy the farmers' demands, which include cheaper fuel, lower taxes and more subsidies.</p>
<p>The farmers gave up the December blockade because of the Christmas holidays but vowed to bring their tractors back to highways if their demands were not met.</p>
<p>They are among a long list of groups protesting or striking against a 1997 budget described as the toughest in 15 years, and strict incomes and tax policies.</p>
<p>Teachers are on strike for a third week while labour confederations have staged repeated walkouts against the government. Protest rallies almost daily congest traffic in the Greek capital.</p>
<p>Simitis has turned down all labour demands, saying giving in would risk Greece's efforts to catch up with its European Union partners.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
