<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="360724" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France's Juppe sees no intervention in Algeria.</title>
<headline>France's Juppe sees no intervention in Algeria.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Prime Minister Alain Juppe voiced horror on Thursday at Algeria's civil war but reiterated that Paris would not intervene in the former French colony.</p>
<p>&quot;We are agreed on a feeling of horror in the face of so much barbarity and on expressing our sympathy to the Algerian people because they suffer in their flesh, in their culture and in their spirit,&quot; Juppe said during Senate questions.</p>
<p>But he immediately added that &quot;Algeria's fate is not decided in Paris. Perhaps we should break with habits which belong to the past.&quot;</p>
<p>The only party that France stood by, Juppe said, was the party of democracy. Elections should be as transparent and as unquestionable as possible, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We mustn't leave the Algerian people isolated, because that would add other difficulties, including economic ones, to the tragedy they are living.</p>
<p>&quot;To go beyond that, to get involved in the choice of those who must participate in these elections, would mean confusing our moral responsibility with interference which is no longer on the agenda,&quot; Juppe said.</p>
<p>In an implicit reference to French ex-president Valery Giscard d'Estaing's call last week for Islamists to be allowed to take part in forthcoming Algerian general elections, Juppe said he did not want to step into a row on the issue.</p>
<p>Juppe had said on Monday that Algeria's proposed parliamentary elections should be open to all legal parties, effectively ruling out the outlawed Islamic Salvation Front (FIS).</p>
<p>Socialist opposition leader Lionel Jospin has urged France to consult its European partners on a joint initiative on Algeria.</p>
<p>Jospin said no one dared to discuss the conflict while Paris stayed silent about Algeria, which won independence from France in 1962 after a bloody war.</p>
<p>An estimated 60,000 people have died in Algeria in fighting since military-backed authorities cancelled a general election in January 1992 which the FIS was poised to win.</p>
<p>Paris is especially attuned to events across the Mediterranean because of the presence in France of more than two million people of Algerian origin.</p>
<p>Algerian-based Islamic fundamentalist groups claimed responsibilty for several bloody bombings in France in 1995 and authorities suspect them of a similar attack in Paris in December which killed four people.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
