<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="361176" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Frankfurt, Paris stocks close at new highs.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Frankfurt, Paris stocks close at new highs.</headline>
<byline>Leonard Santorelli</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Frankfurt and Paris stocks clawed back losses to close at record highs on Thursday but London finished down, rattled by Wall Street's uncertain opening.</p>
<p>On currency markets, the dollar was strong in late European trade, rising against the mark on weak German jobs data and hitting a new four-year high of 124 yen at one point.</p>
<p>In Frankfurt, stocks recovered their poise to reach a new peak at the close as the firm dollar and interest in chemical and engineering shares enouraged a bullish mood.</p>
<p>The DAX finished at 3104.14, a modest increase on the day, but eclipsing the previous best set on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;With people constantly taking up chances to come into the market, I think we are O.K. at these levels,&quot; said another, adding that he saw 3,150 points as an attainable short-term goal for the DAX.</p>
<p>The dollar -- a crucial factor for German exporters' income -- was buoyed all day after a report showing a sharp rise in German unemployment, which rose to 4.66 million in January, the highest level since the 1930s.</p>
<p>London, Europe's biggest bourse, was the worst performer, showing a 0.36 percent loss at the close as recent volatility on Wall Street prompted a small pull-back from Wednesday's all-time highs.</p>
<p>Continued fears that the Dow could be on the verge of a substantial downward correction weighed on investor sentiment but steady British and U.S. interest rates helped calm but not eradicate jittery market nerves.</p>
<p>&quot;It wasn't a bad day considering Wall Street's slide yesterday,&quot; the head of trading at a large investment bank said. &quot;But the market is still on edge.&quot;</p>
<p>The FTSE 100 index closed 15.6 points down at 4,265.9.</p>
<p>The Dow Industrials, which plunged 86 points on Wednesday, started a dozen or so points firmer in the opening minutes of U.S. trade but was virtually unchanged by the close of London business.</p>
<p>In Paris, shares clawed back early losses to show a 0.68 percent gain at the close. They had opened sharply lower following Wall Street's overnight drop.</p>
<p>On the foreign exchange front, the dollar remained buoyant against the mark and yen as economic problems in Germany and Japan stayed at the forefront of traders' minds, suggesting no objection to recent currency trends from the Group of Seven industrial nations this weekend.</p>
<p>Persistent rumours that Japan's Nippon Credit Bank is in deep financial difficulty were denied by the bank later but proved enough to help dollar to a fresh four-year high at 124.00 yen at one point.</p>
<p>And the dollar hovered just shy of 31-month highs against the mark as the German currency was dented by yet another dire German jobless report.</p>
<p>Seasonally-adjusted German unemployment rose a massive 160,000 in January, dragging the unadjusted unemployment rate to 12.2 percent from 10.8 percent in December.</p>
<p>&quot;There's really been no change in the fundamentals that have driven the dollar this far and it's highly unlikely anyone in the G7 has an interest to reverse the trend,&quot; said Peter Wood, currency trader at Bank of Boston.</p>
<p>&quot;Quietly the Germans must be happy with a weaker mark when you see unemployment data like this.&quot;</p>
<p>CURRENCIES</p>
<p>The dollar was quoted at 1.6520 marks and 123.83 yen compared with 1.6479 marks and 123.54 yen in late European trading on Wednesday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS</p>
<p>LONDON - The FTSE-100 index closed down 15.6 points down at 4265.9.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - The 30-share DAX index closed up 6.14 at 3104.14.</p>
<p>PARIS - The CAC-40 finished up 17.18 at 2,558.43.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold closed at $343.30 an ounce, compared with $342.95 at the close on Wednesday. Silver finished down two cents at $4.83.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
