<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="36129" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Christopher hopes French will support Iraq plan.</title>
<headline>Christopher hopes French will support Iraq plan.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher said on Thursday he hoped France, cool towards two U.S. missile strikes on Iraq this week, would support any future action against Baghdad.</p>
<p>After meeting British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind, Christopher told reporters that Iraqi leader Saddam Hussein should realise further &quot;repressive&quot; actions against Kurds in the north of Iraq would be punished.</p>
<p>Christopher flies to Paris after his one-hour meeting with Rifkind.&quot;I hope that after our conversations this afternoon the French will go forward with the operations as we have had in the past,&quot; Christopher said.</p>
<p>The U.S. fired a total of 44 cruise missiles on Iraq on Tuesday and Wednesday on air defence targets in southern Iraq to minimise Iraqi resistance to its warplanes policing an expanded no-fly zone in southern Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we have brought home to Saddam Hussein that there is a very high price for the kind of repressive conduct that he has taken in northern Iraq and that will continue to be the standard by which we measure our actions,&quot; Christopher said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
