<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="361425" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton sets budget that reaches surplus in 2002.</title>
<headline>Clinton sets budget that reaches surplus in 2002.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton on Thursday presented a $1.69 trillion budget that would cut $98.4 billion in taxes over five years, raise $76 billion in various taxes and fees, yet still reaches balance by 2002.</p>
<p>The fiscal 1998 budget, which covers the year beginning on Oct. 1, was formally released on Thursday after being widely leaked Wednesday. It forecast a 1998 deficit of $120.6 billion against 1997's $125.6 billion, gradually shrinking over the next three years and becoming a $17 billion surplus in 2002.  </p>
<p>The budget forecast steady economic growth of 2.0 percent for 1997 and 1998, rising to 2.3 percent from 1999 through 2002. It would increase revenues by a mix of closing corporate tax loopholes, restoring some expired excise taxes and selling $36.1 billion worth of broadcast spectrum over five years.</p>
<p>As previously reported, the budget would trim $100 billion over five years from projected spending on the popular, and politically sensitive, Medicare health care programme for the elderly.</p>
<p>In putting forward the proposal, Clinton, a Democrat, was essentially presenting his opening offer in the annual budget negotiations between the president and Congress. Republicans hold a majority in both the Senate and House of Representatives.</p>
<p>In a message accompanying the budget, Clinton noted that the budget deficit has been cut by more than 60 percent since he took office in 1993. &quot;I want to work with Congress to achieve the final increment of deficit cutting and bring the budget into balance for the first time since 1969,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
