<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="361515" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German debt, futures underpinned by German data.</title>
<headline>German debt, futures underpinned by German data.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Bunds and futures were slightly lower in afternoon dealings on Thursday, hurt by profit-taking but underpinned by support from ongoing sluggish German economic conditions, traders said.</p>
<p>At 1445 GMT, DTB March Bund futures were down two basis points at 102.11 points after reaching a new contract high at 102.34 after German unemployment in January reached a new post-war record at 4.66 million.</p>
<p>The 10-year benchmark cash Bund due January 2007 was at 102.29, yielding 5.69 percent and below Wednesday's closing level of 102.38 points.  </p>
<p>Traders expected range trade on Friday as the market consolidated recent gains tied to the weak economic outlook and for March futures to remain between 101.80 and 102.35.</p>
<p>&quot;We could see some more gains if the unemployment reports keep coming in so poorly,&quot; said one trader. &quot;But for now the lack of new impulses will keep the market relatively quiet.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders saw 101.92 points as a critical level for March Bund futures, with a close below that level likely prompting more profit-taking, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's shaping up to be a decisive level for the market,&quot; said one Frankfurt trader.  </p>
<p>Despite falling German debt yields, traders said the market generally did not expect a Bundesbank rate cut in the near-term. The German central bank opted to keep rates steady at a council meeting on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank lowering German interest rates is not going to wipe away unemployment nor will it help the mark against the dollar,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>On a technical basis, traders looked for March futures to find support at 101.72 and 101.53, while resistance is evident at the contract high of 102.34.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
