<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="361727" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oasis singer Liam Gallagher set to marry next week.</title>
<headline>Oasis singer Liam Gallagher set to marry next week.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's bad boy of rock, Oasis lead singer Liam Gallagher, plans to marry British actress Patsy Kensit in a secret ceremony on Monday, newspapers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;They've been engaged since the summer, so it's no surprise they're getting married,&quot; Oasis manager Johnny Hopkins told the Daily Star after news of the impending nupitals leaked out.</p>
<p>It will be the first marriage for Gallagher, 24, and the third for Kensit, 28, who was previously wed to singer Jim Kerr of the rock group Simple Minds, the father of her four-year-old son James.</p>
<p>Thirty couples have been invited to the reception which will be held at a London hotel and followed by a church blessing on St Valentine's day.</p>
<p>Oasis is Britain's most successful rock group since the Beatles in the 1960s. Their first two albums sold 20 million copies and led to a &quot;Britpop&quot; revival.</p>
<p>Gallagher and his song-writing brother Noel have made frequent headlines for their bad behaviour and foul language since their Manchester-based band burst on to the rock scene in 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
