<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="361959" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: RFM says may hit one bln peso net in 1997.</title>
<headline>RFM says may hit one bln peso net in 1997.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Food and beverage company RFM Corp said on Thursday it hopes to earn 880 million pesos in profits this year but improvement in the performance of its poultry subsidiary may take the earnings to one billion pesos.</p>
<p>&quot;This (880 million pesos) does not even include a substantial upside from Swift, which we have not factored in yet... If Swift does well in the first quarter, and we do expect better performance because of lower corn prices and a better industry supply situation, RFM might even hit the billion mark this year,&quot; RFM president Jose Concepcion III said in a statement.</p>
<p>Swift Foods Inc, the poultry unit of RFM Corp, was hit by an oversupply of chicken in the local market last year.</p>
<p>RFM Corp said it posted 503 million pesos in net income last year. Although no comparative figures were disclosed, the comparny earlier reported a 620.6 million peso net income in 1995.</p>
<p>Concepcion said lower costs of skimmed milk powder and sugar are expected to boost the earnings of its milk, juice and ice cream businesses.</p>
<p>Aside from lower cost of sugar, the sustained sales volumes growth of RFM's ice cream subsidiary, Selecta Dairy Products, is expected to boost RFM's earnings in 1997.</p>
<p>Cosmos Bottling Corp, the beverage arm, is expected to make 480 million pesos in earnings this year, making the unit RFM's biggest source of income for 1997. The company made 310 million pesos in net income last year.</p>
<p>Wheat prices are also expected to drop this year benefitting RFM's noodles, flour-based mixes, baked goods, snacks, breads and cakes business, Concepcion added. - Manila newsroom 63 2 8418939 fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
