<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="36194" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: PRESS DIGEST - Lebanon -  Sept 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Lebanon -  Sept 5.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Beirut press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AN-NAHAR</p>
<p>-A coalition between Amal and Hizbollah in south Lebanon polls has been cooked in secret.</p>
<p>-Beirut relieved after Oslo assures it that the hijacker of the Bulgarian plane was not armed.</p>
<p>-The Council of Maronite Bishops: &quot;The elections showed that our democracy is retreating&quot;.</p>
<p>-Economy Minister Jaber promised to lower the price of bread as the price of wheat has begun to fall.</p>
<p>AS-SAFIR</p>
<p>-More that 522,000 voters to choose 23 south Lebanon representatives to parliament in the polls on Sunday.</p>
<p>-Islamist MP Yakan says: &quot;The elections are unconstitutional and illegal&quot;.</p>
<p>AL-ANWAR</p>
<p>-Israeli jets stage mock raids over south Lebanon.</p>
<p>-A poll on the south Lebanon elections shows that 48 percent will stick to choosing the announced lists of candidates.</p>
<p>AD-DIYAR</p>
<p>-Lebanon bought $170 million worth of industrial machinery from Germany in the first seven months of 1996.</p>
<p>NIDA'A AL-WATAN</p>
<p>-Sheikh Fadlallah, spiritual leader of Lebanon's pro-Iranian Moslem militants, calls for a coalition between Hizbollah and Amal in the south Lebanon polls.</p>
<p>-State Minister al-Khalil urges the residents of Israel's south Lebanon occupation zone to vote in the polls.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
