<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="362254" id="root" date="1997-02-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton's budget wipes out deficit by 2002.</title>
<headline>Clinton's budget wipes out deficit by 2002.</headline>
<byline>Tabassum Zakaria</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton, honouring his pledge to balance the U.S. budget in five years, will unveil a $1.69 trillion spending plan that achieves a $17 billion surplus in 2002, according to a budget summary obtained on Wednesday.</p>
<p>If Congress approved Clinton's budget, spending through 2002 would be $252 billion less than it would be if current spending and tax policies continued.</p>
<p>Clinton's budget, which will be formally unveiled on Thursday, is just the first step in the budget process. Republicans in Congress have said they would keep an open mind so that the president's budget would be &quot;alive on arrival.&quot;</p>
<p>The document projected the deficit would rise in 1997, ending a four-year deficit decline. For the year starting on Oct. 1, 1996, the government will run red ink of $125.6 billion, up from the $107.3 billion deficit posted in the previous year. It will begin a five-year decline next year with a $120.6 billion deficit.</p>
<p>Clinton said in his State of the Union address on Tuesday that balancing the budget was a priority. &quot;Let this Congress be the Congress that finally balances the budget,&quot; he said to cheers from Republicans and Democrats.</p>
<p>House of Representatives Speaker Newt Gingrich, a Republican from Georgia, said earlier on Wednesday: &quot;I think it's very clear that Democrats and Republicans alike by vast majorities favour getting to a balance budget.&quot;</p>
<p>To help reach that goal, Clinton proposed cuts in the Medicare health programme for the elderly, increased fees for use of government services, sales of the broadcast spectrum and a range of changes in government programmes from agriculture to job training.</p>
<p>As expected, his budget asked Congress to cut $100 billion over five years from Medicare.</p>
<p>Clinton proposed tax relief aimed at low income and middle class families worth $98.4 billion over five years, while Republicans in Congress have said they want tax cuts nearly double that amount.</p>
<p>The centrepiece of Clinton's tax plan is a $500 per child tax credit, which would save families $46.0 billion through 2002. If approved by Congress, taxpayers would see a $5.5 billion tax break over five years through expanded Individual Retirement Accounts and a $36 billion tax break for education and training.</p>
<p>The much-touted capital gains tax break for sales of homes would be worth $1.4 billion to taxpayers over the five years.</p>
<p>Clinton's budget forecast the economy on a steady growth path of 2.0 percent for 1997 and 1998 and projected it to strenghten to 2.3 percent from 1999 through 2002. Unemployment was expected to reach 5.3 percent in 1997 and then was seen rising to 5.5 percent in 1998. Inflation was forecast at 2.6 percent this year and at 2.7 percent in 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not an optimistic scenario or a rosy scenario,&quot; Burson-Marsteller budget analyst Stan Collender said of the economic forecasts. &quot;This is probably right in the middle of the consensus range.&quot;</p>
<p>To pay for his policies, Clinton proposed to close corporate and investor tax loopholes worth $34.3 billion through 2002 and to extend expiring excise and other taxes worth $41.7 billion through 2002.</p>
<p>While government spending will continue to rise each year through 2002, the White House projects revenues will also increase, to $1.90 trillion in fiscal 2002 from $1.57 trillion expected in fiscal 1998. The government is expected to receive $1.51 trillion in the current 1997 fiscal year.</p>
<p>Clinton, who has made education a priority, proposed increasing spending for the Education Department to $32.1 billion for fiscal 1998 from $28.3 billion in 1997.</p>
<p>Clinton also proposed increasing new spending programmes for military programmes in the defence budget to $251.6 billion in fiscal 1998 from $250.9 billion in fiscal 1997, and proposed cutting the Department of Energy spending to $14.6 billion from $15.4 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
