<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="362545" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: TENNIS-SWISS TAKE DAVIS CUP LEAD OVER SWEDES.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-SWISS TAKE DAVIS CUP LEAD OVER SWEDES.</headline>
<dateline>LULEA, Sweden 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss number one Marc Rosset won a marathon over Swede Magnus Larsson to give his country a 1-0 lead over in their Davis Cup world group first-round tie on Friday.</p>
<p>Rosset, 26, outfought Larsson 7-6 3-6 6-4 4-6 13-11  on the slow plexi-pave surface at Lulea's Pontus Hall near the Arctic circle, probably the most northerly location for a Davis Cup match.</p>
<p>The lanky, faired-haired Swiss, world ranked 24th,  took the first set in a tie-break. But the 26-year-old Larsson held his own throughout the marathon three hours and 52 minutes of play which only saw four breaks of serve.</p>
<p>Rosset spearheads the Swiss team and because of his strong and precise serve is considered the only real competition to the favoured Swedes.</p>
<p>Although Larsson, ranked 46th, also served well and played more imaginatively when both players were visibly exhausted, Rosset's serves were unfaltering.</p>
<p>Rosset, in bright orange shoes, eventually broke Larsson's serve in a 24-game final set to take the match.</p>
<p>&quot;I played as well as I could,&quot; Larsson said. &quot;He serves well and is a tough competitor.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It was a pretty good start wearing him out for the weekend but it's the win that counts.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LULEA, Sweden"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
