<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="362596" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: TENNIS-ONDRUSKA GIVES S.AFRICA EDGE OVER RUSSIA.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-ONDRUSKA GIVES S.AFRICA EDGE OVER RUSSIA.</headline>
<byline>Mark Stokes</byline>
<dateline>DURBAN 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa opened up a significant early lead over Russia before rain interrupted the opening singles matches of their Davis Cup World Group first round tie on Friday.</p>
<p>South Africa's number two player Marcus Ondruska gave his country the perfect start when he upset Russian number one Andrei Chesnokov 7-6 6-3 3-6 4-6 7-5 in a five-set marathon in the first match of the day.</p>
<p>The 24-year-old Ondruska, the world number 103, overcame his higher-ranked opponent after almost four hours of intense battle in extreme heat and humidity at the Westridge Park Stadium.</p>
<p>&quot;That's one of the toughest matches I've ever played - it was incredibly humid out there,&quot; Ondruska said.</p>
<p>&quot;The first two sets were pretty intense and I think I put in a lot more effort than he did. By the third set, I felt dead tired - and not at all healthy.&quot;</p>
<p>In the second rubber of the day, world number eight Wayne Ferreira was locked at five-games all in his opening set against Russian number two Andre Cherkasov when persistent rain finally ended play for the day.</p>
<p>Ferreira, ranked 112 places higher than Cherkasov, was 15-0 up on his own service game when the players were driven from the court by the second rain stoppage of the day. Their unfinished match continues on Saturday morning.</p>
<p>With on-court temperatures reaching 41 degrees celsius, Ondruska took the first two sets against Chesnokov in the opening rubber.</p>
<p>But the Russian, ranked 73 in the world, then clawed his way back into the match with some good passes and consistent serving to take the third anmd fourth sets 6-3, 6-4.</p>
<p>The fifth and final set began with both players exchanging a break of serve apiece before holding their respective serves to remain locked at five-all.</p>
<p>Chesnokov then double-faulted when 30-40 down in the 11th game to present Ondruska with a crucial 6-5 lead and the South African, playing with increased confidence, promptly held his serve to take the set 7-5 and the match.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt like dead meat on the court - the heat was terrible,&quot; Chesnokov said. &quot;Only once before, in Singapore, have I experienced heat as bad. I don't think I was in good shape today and he played much better than me over the last three games.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DURBAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
