<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="36266" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Staples seen gaining approval on merger.</title>
<headline>Staples seen gaining approval on merger.</headline>
<byline>Michael Ellis</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Staples Inc and Office Depot Inc have surprisingly little geographical overlap and small market shares, and should face only minor regulatory hurdles in their planned merger, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The overlap isn't that great, and I think the possiblility of this going through is pretty high,&quot; said Thomas Kully, an analyst with William Blair &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Boston-based Staples and the South Florida-based Office Depot only overlap significantly in Los Angeles, Baltimore, Washington and, to a lesser extent, in Detroit, Kully said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't see any major hurdles. They don't overlap,&quot; said John Lyons, an analyst with Chicago Corp.</p>
<p>Staples Chief Executive Tom Stemberg said the two national office superstores together cover 96 percent of the metropolitan areas in North America but only overlap in 21 percent of those markets.</p>
<p>Stemberg said the combined company, to be called Staples the Office Depot, had only a 10 percent share of the retail market for office products, a six percent share of contract orders and a five percent share of mail orders.  </p>
<p>&quot;The things we sell today...is a $185 billion market. The market as a whole is growing in high single-digits or low double-digits,&quot; Stemberg told reporters and analysts during a conference call on Wednesday.</p>
<p>When asked if Staples faced any regulatory problems, Stemberg replied: &quot;One would hope that when you look at a merger between two companies whose entire livelihood has been generated by cutting prices, that they would see through any potential problems to see the tremendous consumer benefits this merger represents.&quot;</p>
<p>Analsyts said Stemberg's estimate of $185 billion market seemed too high, but they agreed the combined company would account for only a small part of the office products market.</p>
<p>&quot;The office products market, as we estimate it, is a $100 billion market,&quot; said Linda Farquhar, an associate analyst with Alex Brown. &quot;You have the office product superstores, you have the contract stationers...and you also have the Wal-Marts and K-Marts.&quot;</p>
<p>Farquhar said Staples was ready to do &quot;whatever it takes&quot; to make sure the acquisition gained regulatory approval, including selling some retail outlets if necessary.</p>
<p>Stemberg said Staples would close some stores as a result of the merger while continuing to expand.</p>
<p>-- Boston bureau, (617) 367-4176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
