<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="362873" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ETHIOPIA: Ethiopian premier rules out war with Sudan.</title>
<headline>Ethiopian premier rules out war with Sudan.</headline>
<dateline>ADDIS ABABA 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ethiopian Prime Minister Meles Zenawi ruled out the possibility of war with neighbouring Sudan despite charges of aggression from Khartoum's Islamist-backed government, the national news agency said on Friday.</p>
<p>The agency said Meles told parliament on Thursday that Sudan and Ethiopia would not go to war &quot;in spite of the massive military propaganda from the other side&quot;.</p>
<p>Sudan has accused Ethiopia, along with Eritrea and Uganda, of direct military involvement in a rebel offensive launched a month ago from the south and east by the Sudan People's Liberation Army and allied opposition forces.</p>
<p>&quot;Ethiopians have had more than their fair share of war, bloodletting and sufferings and its earnest desire now is for the prevalence of peace between the two neighbouring countries,&quot; Meles said.</p>
<p>He added that Sudan was incapable of military confrontation with Ethiopia.</p>
<p>Relations between the two neighbours have been chilly since Addis Ababa accused Khartoum of harbouring gunmen who attempted to assassinate Egypt's President Hosni Mubarak in the Ethiopian capital in 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ETHPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADDIS ABABA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ETHIOPIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
