<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="362833" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa stocks end up, but bullion woes hit golds.</title>
<headline>S.Africa stocks end up, but bullion woes hit golds.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African shares closed up, despite a slide in the gold index, as positive sentiment continued to support the market, dealers said on Friday.</p>
<p>President Nelson Mandela's speech at the opening of parliament in Cape Town contained no surprises and was seen underpinning a recent upsurge in confidence -- without triggering off a major rally.</p>
<p>The all-share index ended up 16.0 points to 6,879.6 as the industrial index put on 22.6 points to 8,203.0. But the gold index took a hammering as the bullion price dropped to its lowest levels for nearly four years.</p>
<p>The index shed 30.0 points, or 2.16 percent, to 1,357.5. Some analysts have speculated that the gold price may try and test levels in the low $330s an ounce range, spelling more gloom for South African gold shares.</p>
<p>Compounding the woes the rand gold price fell to its lowest level in eleven months on Friday on the dollar gold price and as the rand continued its rally against the U.S. unit.</p>
<p>Analysts said the falling price held dire prospects for South African gold mines in the first quarter of this year.</p>
<p>However, the surging rand, strong bond market and good outlook for interest rates are still underpinning the positive mood in the rest of the market.</p>
<p>South African blue chips are still attracting good overseas and foreign institutional interest and got a late boost from market pleasing U.S. jobless figures.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
