<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="362991" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary bourse growth delays continuous BUX launch.</title>
<headline>Hungary bourse growth delays continuous BUX launch.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The launch of the continuous calculation of Hungary's BUX share index will be delayed by enlargement work on the Budapest Stock Exchange's (BSE) dealing system, needed due to soaring turnover, the BSE said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a few weeks' delay as we concentrate all our efforts on increasing (the system's) capacity,&quot; BSE Managing Director Jozsef Rotyis told a news conference on Friday.</p>
<p>The BSE's BUX index is currently calculated at the end of each trading session. The BSE had earlier said that continuous calculation was likely to begin at the end of January.</p>
<p>But the BSE has to focus on upgrading its trading system, which works at almost full capacity as investors' interest in deals on the Hungarian bourse has substantially increased since 1995, Rotyis said.</p>
<p>The BSE's total duplicated spot turnover rose to 1,845.4 billion forints in 1996 from 1,145.4 billion in 1995. Futures turnover soared to 200.6 billion forints from 10.2 billion.</p>
<p>Share and futures turnover rose dynamically, Rotyis said, adding that January's 130 billion forint stock turnover was five times more than in the first month of 1995, while BUX index futures soared to 34 billion forints from less than 0.5 billion.</p>
<p>The BSE plans to double the capacity of its trading system, in which currently average 2,000 deals are concluded at one session, up from 600 to 700 in May 1996, Rotyis said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has been expanding more rapidly than we expected,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The BSE plans to further expand its trading capacity next year, replacing the old trading system with a new one, as the bourse expects its turnover continue to increase and also plans to launch a standardized options market this year, Rotyis said.</p>
<p>-- Sandor Peto, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
