<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="362914" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Poland - Feb 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Poland - Feb 7.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- Poland's production of video cassette recorders (VCR) grew by 200 percent and the chemical batteries' output skyrocketed by 600 percent in 1996. Truck and special purpose vehicle production plunged by 500 percent, the Central Statistical Office (GUS) s aid.</p>
<p>- Powszechny Bank Kredytowy (PBK) bank will acquire a controlling stake in the Szczecin-based Bank Morski from the Polish Development Bank (PBR). Prior to that PBR will buy a 22.6 percent stake in Morski from the Westdeutsche Landesba nk and resell it to PBK. The transaction will improve PBR's results and facilitate a planned share issue, PBR said.</p>
<p>- Denmark's Agriculture Minister Henrik Dam Kristensen supported Poland's efforts to join the EU during his current visit to Poland. He said Denmark did not fear competition by Polish farmers, as new markets for Danish-made foods opened in Japan and South Korea in the last few years.</p>
<p>- Ciech foreign trade company is planning to form a joint venture with one or more international chemical concerns to take part in the privatisation of the Polfa Krakow and Polfa Poznan pharmaceutical plants, Ciech's president Zdzislaw Matkiewicz said following talks with a major western pharmaceutical concern at the Davos conference.</p>
<p>- The listed Optimus computer maker's subsidaries operating in the most dynamic areas of the industry will increase profits by several hundred percent this year, Optimus financial director Stefan Mroczek said. In 1997 the company will invest extensively in multimedia development and the mass production of Microsoft Optimus computers.</p>
<p>- Rabo BRP Bank, controlled by the Dutch Rabobank,  will concentrate on agro-business investments, the bank's president Dariusz Ledworowski said. He said that Rabo BRP will further increase its capital through a new share issue to be taken over by the mother bank.</p>
<p>NOWA EUROPA</p>
<p>- The Polish Securities Commission (KPW) has approved for public trading of the H, I and J-series shares of the ComputerLand software firm, Tomasz Sielicki said.</p>
<p>- Polkomtel, one of Poland's three cellular telephones operators, is planning a new share issue to increase capital by 200 million zlotys, Polkomtel's spokesman Leszek Kaminski said.</p>
<p>- Poland's textile industry needs $2.5 billion in investment by 2000 to be able to compete on international markets, the Polish Textile Industry Chamber (PIPT) president Jerzy Wojtkowski said.</p>
<p>- Finland's Nokia telcom equipment maker has a 70 percent share in Poland's mobile phone market, the concern's deputy president Stefan S. Wiadomski said.</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>- Three foreign investors are planning to take over a controlling stake in the Elektrocieplownia Krakow heating and power plant, according to sources requesting anonymity.</p>
<p>- Poland's Finance Minister Marek Belka has doubts about Bank Gdanski' request for a government guarantee for a loan, which would enable the Gdansk shipyard to construct five vessels contracted by Germany's Scholler Holdings. Belka will soon discuss legal inadequacies of the motionr with the Gdanski's president Wojciech Hasse.</p>
<p>ZYCIE</p>
<p>- Over 200 hundred firms from Poland and Lithuania are exhibiting their products at the Suwalki Border Area international fair.</p>
<p>- The Lublin-based Bank Depozytowo Kredytowy (BDKL) bank's net profit in 1996 was 109 million zlotys, 50 percent more than the year before, BDKL said.</p>
<p>PARKIET</p>
<p>- The listed Relpol electrical engineering firm has set up Polish-Belarus joint venture in Minsk to trade Relpol's products in Belarus, which signals the company's expansion eastward, Relpol's president Krzysztof Prucnal said.</p>
<p>- The listed Swarzedz furniture maker's revenues will grow 60 percent this year, compared with 1995 results, the company forecast said.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
