<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="363006" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: Kazakh deputies urge closure of Russian test sites.</title>
<headline>Kazakh deputies urge closure of Russian test sites.</headline>
<byline>Dmitry Solovyov</byline>
<dateline>ALMATY 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A harrowing exhibition of photographs showing disabled children and dying nature opened on Friday in the Kazakh parliament, part of a drive by deputies to close Russian weapons test sites in their country.</p>
<p>The pictures, including a small girl with ugly stumps instead of arms and a skinny camel chewing thistles amid used missiles scattered across the steppe, are meant to shock.</p>
<p>Last October, the Russian and Kazakh governments agreed Moscow would continue to use four test sites for conventional weapons in the vast Central Asian state's central steppe until 2006. Kazakhstan would receive $26.5 million a year for use of the sites.</p>
<p>But Kazakh law-makers want the former Soviet republic's government to review the accord and sent a demand to that effect to Kazakh President Nursultan Nazarbayev on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The agreement will never be ratified by either of the two houses of the Kazakh parliament,&quot; Kazakh deputy Engels Gabbasov, the organiser of the exhibition, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Intensive weapons tests have lead to births of mentally ill and crippled children and destroy nature.&quot;</p>
<p>Kazakhstan, whose vast territory was chosen by the Kremlin 50 years ago to carry out atomic tests in its race with the West for nuclear supremacy, was the first former Soviet republic to ship its nuclear missiles back to Russia.</p>
<p>Some of the country's 16.9 million population are still suffering the after-effects of decades of nuclear tests at its Semipalatinsk test site in the northeast.</p>
<p>&quot;Kazakhstan already needs at least $2 billion to clear up the ecological damage caused by earlier tests,&quot; Gabbasov said. &quot;But current tests of missiles, aircraft and fuel in upper layers of the atmosphere continue killing children and nature.&quot;</p>
<p>About eight million people live in the four Kazakh regions where the sites, used to test non-nuclear weapons, are located. The sites sprawl over 2,000 km (1,250 miles) from the country's east to the centre.</p>
<p>&quot;Burning parts of missiles and poisonous clouds of tested fuels often fall onto nearby villages and towns,&quot; one of the deputies said, adding that Russia has not told Kazakhstan how it plans to use the sites.</p>
<p>Kazakh deputies are now preparing a letter to both houses of the Russian parliament asking them to block ratification of the October agreement but realise their appeal may be ignored in Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia's reaction may be difficult for us -- its set of testing sites in Kazakhstan is the largest in the world.</p>
<p>&quot;But those living in Kazakhstan are human beings and not rabbits for medical experiments,&quot; Gabbasov said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
