<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="363194" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Orinoco key to Venezuela oil future - PDVSA.</title>
<headline>Orinoco key to Venezuela oil future - PDVSA.</headline>
<byline>Tom Ashby</byline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-02-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Venezuela's state oil firm PDVSA has already topped U.S. rivals Exxon and Texaco as the biggest gasoline retailer in the United States, but this is only the beginning of a long-term strategy which could put Venezuela on a par with Saudi Arabia as a world oil power.</p>
<p>Massive deposits of heavy oil and bitumen on the northern flanks of the Orinoco River form the basis of Venezuela's planned assault on the world energy market, David Escojido, PDVSA's planning coordinator, told Reuters in an interview.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Orinoco Belt has 1.2 trillion barrels of heavy oil in place. Of these, very little are in the (proven reserves) books right now,&quot; Escojido said. &quot;If we don't do anything and somebody discovers something to replace oil, everyone will be crying about all those reserves down there that we didn't do anything about.&quot;</p>
<p>Currently, some 66 billion barrels of proven oil reserves rank Venezuela fifth in the world.</p>
<p>But modern technology and private finance mean that it is getting closer to adding another 244 billion barrels from the Orinoco Tar Belt to its &quot;proven reserve&quot; books.  </p>
<p>This would put Venezuela above Saudi Arabia as the biggest oil province in the world, if the Saudi figure stayed at its current 261.4 billion barrels.</p>
<p>&quot;We know that in western Venezuela on the eastern shore of lake Maracaibo there are heavy oilfields that were developed in 1950... In that area we have proved that we can recover up to 45 percent of the reserves,&quot; Escojido said.  </p>
<p>&quot;If, of the 1.2 trillion, we only apply 22 percent which are not proven yet, we could have 300 billion barrels in proven reserves,&quot; he said. &quot;The trick is to do it economically. You need a huge investment up front and the returns are going to come in the long term.&quot;</p>
<p>Most of the Orinoco Belt is not counted as proven reserves because not enough exploration work has taken place, but Escojido says PDVSA has already organized five joint ventures in the area worth a total of $12-13 billion in investments over the next three to five years.  </p>
<p>&quot;The way we are developing the Orinoco Belt is with horizontal wells and submergible pumps, so the economics have improved quite a bit. Now there is a rush of everybody who wants to go into that.&quot;</p>
<p>It is still in its infancy, but the Orinoco has so far attracted the attention of U.S. giants Phillips Petroleum Co, Exxon, Mobil Corp, Atlantic Richfield Co and DuPont Co's Conoco; Norway's Norsk Hydro and Statoil France's Total Petroleum SA and Germany's Veba Oil.  </p>
<p>In the next ten years, PDVSA hopes oil production from the Orinoco will reach 665,000 bpd, part of a planned doubling of Venezuela's oil production capacity to 6.2 million bpd by 2006.</p>
<p>Private finance, in addition to improved technology, is proving to be a key driver in Venezuela's ambitions.</p>
<p>&quot;Of the three million bpd increase (in oil production by 2006), two million bpd would be produced with the participation of private capital,&quot; Escojido said. Currently, private capital in involved in just 130,000 bpd.  </p>
<p>PDVSA says the world will be able to absorb Venezuelan production easily. It forecasts two percent demand growth over the next ten years, translating into 1.5 million bpd more oil every year.</p>
<p>&quot;We have the resources, we have the demand, so what are we going to do? We are going to double our capacity in the next ten years,&quot; Escojido said.</p>
<p>((-- Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
