<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="363253" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GMC to offer new luxury sport/utility.</title>
<headline>GMC to offer new luxury sport/utility.</headline>
<byline>David Lawder</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO</dateline>
<text>
<p>In a bid to attract more luxury-oriented buyers to its GMC truck brand, General Motors Corp. ( ) said Friday it will launch a new upscale sport/utility vehicle in 1998 and may junk its venerable Jimmy nameplate.</p>
<p>GMC officials said the new Envoy vehicle will essentially be a more luxurious version of the current GMC Jimmy compact sport/utility vehicle. A concept version of the Envoy, loaded with leather seats, real wood trim, chrome wheels and GM's OnStar satellite navigation and communications system, was unveiled at the Chicago Auto Show Friday.</p>
<p>It is expected to sell for more than the Jimmy's $29,900 top-end price. But to gain that kind of premium, GMC officials said they had to change the name.</p>
<p>&quot;Jimmy was not prestigious and premium enough&quot; in consumers eyes, said Jeff Cohen, GMC brand manager for compact sport/utility vehicles.</p>
<p>The Jimmy name dates back to World War II, when soldiers gave it to GM-built military trucks, much in the same way the Jeep name was coined for the army's &quot;General Purpose Vehicle.&quot;</p>
<p>GMC's Envoy will debut in mid-1998 as a 1999 model, joining the Jimmy and two other similar GM sport utility vehicles, including the Chevrolet Blazer and the Oldsmobile Bravada. GMC said last month it will offer a luxury version of its full-size Yukon sport/utility -- the Denali -- in the 1998 model year.</p>
<p>GMC will offer both the Envoy and the Jimmy initially, but since GM is trying to position GMC as its luxury truck brand, Cohen said the Jimmy name may be dropped. That decision will be based on customer response, he said.</p>
<p>The Envoy is one of an unprecedented number of luxury sport/utility vehicles slated to hit the market in the next two years, including Mercedes-Benz' U.S.-built M-Class vehicle and a new car-based sport/utility vehicle from Toyota Motor Corp.'s Lexus that was unveiled Thursday at the Chicago show.</p>
<p>GM also is mulling future entries in that market. GM marketing chief Ronald Zarrella said the automaker may produce a &quot;hybrid&quot; car-based utility vehicle for its Buick Division. However, such a vehicle would be more than two years away, Zarrella said.</p>
<p>Buick has traditionally sold only conservatively styled cars, but last year discontinued its Roadmaster wagon, which had a small but loyal following for its towing and hauling capabilities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
