<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="363219" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: U.S. Beirut envoy explains controversial remarks.</title>
<headline>U.S. Beirut envoy explains controversial remarks.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Ambassador Richard Jones said on Friday remarks he made on 73 Israeli troops killed in mid-air helicopters crash while flying to an occupation zone in south Lebanon were meant to be humanitarian rather than political.</p>
<p>Lebanon's foreign ministry summoned Jones on Friday to explain his statement on Wednesday which angered some Lebanese officials, deputies, religious clerics and newspaper columnists, some of whom demanded the ambassador's expulsion.</p>
<p>Asked after the meeting whether the issue was resolved, Foreign Minister Faris Bouez told reporters &quot;yes&quot;.</p>
<p>Jones has said that the 73 Israelis killed in the crash on Tuesday were soldiers carrying out the orders of their political leaders and that nobody should rejoice over the deaths. The helicopters were carrying the troops to a border zone that Israel occupies in south Lebanon.</p>
<p>&quot;The remarks I made...should be understood in a humanitarian context. The United States is a peace-loving country, we grieve for the loss of life anywhere in the world whether in south Lebanon, Israel or any country,&quot; Jones told reporters after meeting Foreign Minister Faris Bouez.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sorry if they were understood by some to be a change in the policy of the United States,&quot; added Jones, who made a similar statement after meeting Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri earlier.</p>
<p>In his remarks made at the presidential palace on Wednesday, Jones said: &quot;Certainly those soldiers were doing their duty for their country and they are not the ones responsible for the policies.</p>
<p>&quot;They are victims as much as anyone else, and I think that our hearts should go out to the families and to the people that suffered because of an accident,&quot; Jones said.</p>
<p>Sheikh Hassan Nasrallah, chief of the pro-Iranian Hizbollah fighting to oust the Israeli forces from south Lebanon, said on Friday that the Lebanese government must take a tough stand with Washington over Jones' remarks and &quot;if the Americans don't like that..let them take their ambassador and leave our country.&quot;</p>
<p>Hizbollah (Party of God) said on Wednesday the helicopters crash was an act of God and it was overjoyed over it.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
