<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="363327" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ecuador's $300 mln bond seen on hold indefinitely.</title>
<headline>Ecuador's $300 mln bond seen on hold indefinitely.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ecuador, which had planned to issue $300 million in debt in the international capital markets via Chase Securities, is not expected to come to market anytime soon given the country's current political crisis, said syndicate and emerging market debt sources.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is pretty clear that the environment has deteriorated. The Eurobond is very much at risk,&quot; said one emerging market debt source at a U.S. investment firm.</p>
<p>The deal, which was announced in December, was originally planned to come to market this month, sources said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think it would be premature for us to make any comments until we see what happens in Ecuador over the next few days and certainly we haven't had discussions with them yet about that. It really is a wait-and see situation,&quot; said one debt syndicate manager close to the deal.</p>
<p>&quot;With the political situation like this, people aren't thinking about when the bond will get done,&quot; the syndicate source added.</p>
<p>The political crisis, which resulted in the ouster of President Abdala Bucaram by Ecuador's Congress late Thursday, mounted after he refused to step down.  </p>
<p>Fabian Alarcon, the congressional leader, was sworn in to replace Bucaram as interim head of state.</p>
<p>According to news reports from Reuters in Quito, a state of emergency was declared to try to restore peace as protests and mayhem gripped the nation.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, three emerging market debt sources, all of whom requested anonymity, said Chase had provided bridge financing for Ecuador in the amount of $300 million.</p>
<p>One of the three sources said that ING Barings also had a hand in the bridge loan. Neither Chase nor ING were immediately available for comment.  </p>
<p>&quot;Chase gave a bridge financing for Ecuador of $300 million,&quot; said one emerging market source at a U.S. bank.</p>
<p>According to the analyst, half of the funds were transferred to Ecuador last year, and the rest were transferred a few days ago.</p>
<p>&quot;This was tied to the issuance of a $300 million bond, probably a 144A issue. The present circumstance is they will have to wait for the new government, and I suppose this is not going to happen in the short term. I don't know how much this is going to cost Ecuador,&quot; the analyst added.  </p>
<p>The first source agreed that the bridge financing was provided in advance of the expected $300 million bond issue to finance the fiscal deficit and build reserves.</p>
<p>&quot;From what I hear, some of the bridge financing went to plug up (Ecuador's) fiscal accounts at the end of last year and to prop up reserves in the first month of this year and so that money has probably already been spent so it may end up becoming a longer-term commercial bank loan,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A third source at a European bank in New York said the loan was really for fiscal needs rather than external balance of payment needs but the source noted that the fiscal needs have not gone away.</p>
<p>(( --Diane Craft, 212-859-1946 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
