<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="363336" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - CVS sees Revco deal accretive.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - CVS sees Revco deal accretive.</headline>
<byline>Robin Sidel</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>CVS Corp on Friday said it expected its proposed $2.8 billion acquisition of Revco D.S. Inc to be slightly accretive in 1997 and add 10 to 15 cents to earnings per share in 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;What we're trying to be is more than just a growth company -- a world-class health-care retailer. And that's what I think this combination will do,&quot; Chief Operating Officer Thomas Ryan told Reuters in a telephone interview.  </p>
<p>Ryan said that CVS had also considered an acquisition of Eckerd Corp but the transaction with Revco was determined to be a better fit. J.C. Penney Co Inc announced a $3.3 billion acquisition of Eckerd in November.</p>
<p>He said CVS and Revco had held talks since early October, adding that key criteria for strategic acquisitions pursued by CVS included leadership in new markets, growth potential in pharmacy operations and earnings accretion.</p>
<p>&quot;We think combining these two entities across the largest retail store base in the country positions us pretty well for the managed-care environment going forward,&quot; Ryan said.  </p>
<p>&quot;This will make us a stronger company on the retail side, and it also will strengthen us as a health-care player,&quot; he said, referring to CVS' patient benefit management company and Revco's mail-order operations.</p>
<p>The planned acquisition of Revco is expected to result in about 1,000 layoffs at the company's Twinsburg, Ohio, headquaters. CVS and Revco did not specifically cite those figures but did not dispute the estimates.</p>
<p>&quot;It's unfortunate, but I like to think about the 98 percent of the people that we are employing at Revco,&quot; he said, adding that CVS would honor Revco severance packages.</p>
<p>Ryan said CVS might consider other acquisitions, although most of its attention was likely to be focused on Revco in the near term.</p>
<p>&quot;We're always looking for the right opportunity, but obviously our focus is on maintaining the productivity and the customer service we've established at CVS and to begin to work on the transition at Revco,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
