<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="363406" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American Airlines seeks new $1 billion credit line.</title>
<headline>American Airlines seeks new $1 billion credit line.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>American Airlines, facing the possibility of strike by its pilots, said Friday it was borrowing $1 billion from a credit line and has arranged to borrow another $1 billion under a new credit agreement.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Florida Sens. Bob Graham and Connie Mack asked President Clinton to help the airline and the pilots reach an agreement to avoid a walkout that would cripple their state's winter tourism business.</p>
<p>The carrier based outside Fort Worth, Texas gave notice it was drawing $1 billion under the existing credit line, which expires in 2001, in a filing with the federal Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
<p>It said it had not yet borrowed from the new line of credit and did not say how it would use the funds.</p>
<p>American, a unit of AMR Corp., is the dominant air carrier at Miami International Airport, a key gateway for passengers and cargo to Latin America.</p>
<p>In a letter to the president, Graham and Mack said a strike beginning Feb. 15 would be &quot;costly&quot; and &quot;painful.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If a settlement is not reached, a mid-February holiday weekend airline strike would disrupt passengers and the flow of freight across our nation and overseas, particularly in our hemisphere,&quot; the letter said. &quot;Nowhere would the harm be more acute than in Florida.&quot;</p>
<p>Pilots' leaders have said they want to win a new contract now, even if it involves a strike, rather than risk lengthy arbitration. Earlier this week, a senior union leader predicted a 50 percent possibility of a strike, and that it could last up to 60 days.</p>
<p>Starting Monday, the two sides are to begin five days of &quot;supermediation&quot; in a last-gasp effort to reach a new four-year labour contract. Those negotiations will take place in Washington with the help of the National Mediation Board.</p>
<p>Pilots are demanding pay raises of more than 11 percent over the life of the contract, improved stock options and a guarantee that American will not use its American Eagle commuter carrier, which employs pilots of another union, to fly 50-passenger regional jets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
