<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="363428" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Republican leader &quot;depressed&quot; by Clinton budget.</title>
<headline>Republican leader &quot;depressed&quot; by Clinton budget.</headline>
<byline>Jackie Frank</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senate Republican Leader Trent Lott, signalling tough negotiations ahead on balancing the U.S. budget, on Friday criticised President Bill Clinton's new plan as full of &quot;shell games&quot; and &quot;recooked from last year.&quot;</p>
<p>After taking 24 hours to review Clinton's blueprint, Lott expressed his disappointment directly to the president in a telephone call on Wednesday morning and found him &quot;a little bit taken aback&quot; by the depth of the lawmaker's concerns.</p>
<p>&quot;I am gravely depressed about what I have seen ... This is a disappointment. So much of the budget is recooked from last year,&quot; he said, using some of the strongest language heard so far from the majority Republicans against Clinton's plan.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks more like a political document to me than a serious budget document,&quot; the Mississippi Republican said as he appeared at a formal news conference in shirt sleeves, symbolic of his determination to go to work on the budget.</p>
<p>&quot;I think (he was) maybe a little taken aback that I felt as strongly as I did,&quot; he responded when asked how Clinton received the criticisms.</p>
<p>Clinton later told reporters he took no offence at Lott's remarks and knew it would be difficult to reach a compromise.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the differences between us and you look at how close we are to a balanced budget, we can do it and I'm convinced we will do it,&quot; he said at the White House.</p>
<p>Clinton will go to the capitol on Tuesday for an unusual meeting with leaders of both the majority Republicans and his Democrats. This will be followed by months of talks on budget nuts-and-bolts between White House analysts and lawmakers.</p>
<p>Republicans acknowledged that last year's budget showdown cost them politically. &quot;We want to work with you. We can't afford to have the impasse we had in the past,&quot; Senate Republican Whip Don Nickles of Oklahoma told Clinton's budget director Frank Raines at Friday's Budget Committee hearing.</p>
<p>After the White House budget was submitted on Thursday, Republicans initially took pains to stress that this one was not dead on arrival, a marked departure from the past two years when Clinton's budgets were dismissed out of hand.</p>
<p>Republicans now charged the White House used overly optimistic assumptions about growth of the nation's economy to avoid making $187 billion worth of spending cuts congressional analysts say are needed to bring the deficit to zero by 2002.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition to optimistic assumptions and shell games and triggers it also adds a significant amount of new entitlement spending,&quot; Lott told reporters.</p>
<p>Clinton's plan envisions the deficit will turn in to a $17 billion surplus in five years. But before this happens the administration predicted the deficit will be higher for two years and only drop below this year's $107 billion in 2000. The deficit has fallen for the last four years.</p>
<p>Central to the White House game plan was their expectation that good economic circumstances for the next five years would bring businesses and families more income, lead to higher tax revenues and enable slower growth in welfare and unemployment.</p>
<p>Republicans charged that Clinton put off deep spending cuts until he will be out of the White House. And they were puzzled by his request for $60 billion in new entitlement programmes -- new programmes to be permanently paid for.</p>
<p>Republicans also were angered that buried in the budget was cryptic reference to triggers that would cancel tax cuts and automatically cut spending if the favourable economic forecast proves untrue.</p>
<p>The White House proposed $98 billion of tax relief mainly aimed to help families and those with children in college -- a 0.3 percent reduction in government revenue over five years. Republicans want to reduce taxes nearly double that amount for a broader group of people and to make the cuts permanent.</p>
<p>To help pay for this, Clinton asked for a $76 billion tax increase on corporations and investors and an extension of expiring excise taxes. And he recommended new user fees for government services and sales of broadcast spectrum to raise $36 billion. That magnitude of revenue from spectrum sales was impossible, Lott said.</p>
<p>Medicare was one area where Republicans said Clinton moved in their direction with $100 billion in Medicare health care reductions for the elderly over five years. Clinton's plan held other spending virtually level for the next five years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
