<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="363424" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT corn options -- Commercials target $2.70 puts.</title>
<headline>CBOT corn options -- Commercials target $2.70 puts.</headline>
<byline>Emily Kaiser</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Recent action in Chicago Board of Trade corn options suggests commercial interests are building short positions in the July and December contracts near $2.70 per bushel, market sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;Both commercials and commission houses are positioning themselves towards large short corn positions in the options,&quot; said Chris Manns, corn options trader with CDM Traders Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;This suggests the trade is willing to be a cautious bear at this moment, barring any South American (crop) problems,&quot; Manns said. </p>
<p>The latest Commodity Futures Trading Commission Commitment of Traders data confirmed that commercials were getting short.</p>
<p>Monday's report on combined futures/options positions indicated that commercials were short roughly 144 million bushels in exercizable corn options, up 21 million bushels from two weeks earlier. Commercials were long about 106 million bushels in exercisable options, CFTC data showed.</p>
<p>&quot;This year, a lot of commercials are using options as a backstop,&quot; said Steve Freed, analyst with ADM Investor Services. &quot;If they're bearish, they can come in and buy calls and that gives them the flexibility to trade (sell) futures.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said trade has been centered on the July because that contract can protect against volatility in case of spring planting problems. The December contract reflects new crop corn and allows traders to lock in a price before harvest.</p>
<p>Open interest in July put options has nearly doubled since January 10. According to CBOT data, open interest in July puts was at 12,487 contracts as of January 10. By February 6, that figure had jumped to 23,657 contracts.</p>
<p>Volume for all corn options climbed from 322,189 contracts as of January 10 to 391,971 contracts by February 6. July puts alone accounted for 16 percent of that increase.  </p>
<p>Most of the action has been at strike prices between $2.60 and $2.80 per bushel, within about 10 cents of the spot March futures which closed Thursday at $2.69 per bushel.</p>
<p>July futures closed at $2.67-1/2 a bushel on Thursday.</p>
<p>Open interest in July call and put options was 71,297 contracts at Thursday's close, of which $2.70 strikes alone accounted for about 18 percent, according to CBOT data.</p>
<p>&quot;When you look at the fundamentals, it's difficult to get the market to trade much below $2.50 until we know more about the planting,&quot; ADM's Freed said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Unless beans explode, it's difficult to see the (corn) market trading above $2.80 and getting into the next level of farmer selling,&quot; Freed added.</p>
<p>The active trade reflects in part, a bearish fundamental outlook based on projections for a large U.S. corn harvest and competition from South American crops, said John Zanutto, head of the commercial grain division at LFG Futures.</p>
<p>&quot;The overriding fundamentals of the corn market are extremely bearish,&quot; Zanutto said.</p>
<p>July $2.70 calls and puts have been trading at relatively cheap premiums for the last two weeks. According to CBOT data, the premium for July $2.70 puts closed at 11-1/2 cents on January 24, against Thursday's close at 12-3/4 cents.</p>
<p>Calls also closed at 11-1/2 cents on January 24, compared with 10 cents as of the close on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;When the options get relatively cheap and you can get large control for a small amount of risk money, that is extremely attractive to anyone who might have business or is involved in making deliveries,&quot; Zanutto said.</p>
<p>((Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8749))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
