<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="363557" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Record price paid for Portuguese painting.</title>
<headline>Record price paid for Portuguese painting.</headline>
<byline>David Brough</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>An anonymous buyer has paid a record price of 42 million escudos ($253,000) for a Portuguese painting, a 1910 oil canvas by renowned local artist Jose Malhoa depicting a drunk.</p>
<p>&quot;This work, 'Enough, My Father!', is a record price paid in Portugal. This is one of the best works of Malhoa,&quot; Clara Ferreira Marques, partner of auctioneers Leiria &amp; Nascimento, told Reuters after the auction on Thursday night.</p>
<p>The painting, rich in colour, shows a young woman pleading to her drunken father in a bar to stop drinking.</p>
<p>Malhoa (1855-1933), who painted scenes of villagers and farmhands, was a leading Portuguese impressionist and was hailed in his time as one of Portugal's greatest artists. Many of his works are displayed in national museums and galleries today.</p>
<p>Another Malhoa oil painting, 'Give a Drink to the Thirsty', dated 1921, which shows a young woman watering a plant, was sold at the same auction for 26 million escudos ($157,000), a record price before 'Enough, My Father' was sold in the next lot.</p>
<p>A third, small oil painting by Malhoa, 'A couple of Birds', dated 1920, sold for 7.4 million escudos ($45,000) at the packed auction, where porcelain tableware, sculptures, antique clocks and paintings by other artists also came up for sale.</p>
<p>The previous record price for a Portuguese painting was 25 million escudos ($150,000), paid last year for another Malhoa painting, Ferreira Marques said.</p>
<p>A painting by Maria Helena Vieira da Silva, perhaps the best known Portuguese artist who has a museum dedicated to her work in Lisbon, has sold for 24 million escudos ($145,000), she said.</p>
<p>Ferreira Marques said the record price was paid because one of Malhoa's best works had come to the market, rather than because an art boom was starting in Portugal.</p>
<p>&quot;Just as the best Van Gogh paintings sell for very high prices and his less impressive works sell for much less, the same is true of Malhoa's paintings,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The Portuguese have more money to spend on paintings as disposable income has risen sharply in recent years. The economy is showing a robust performance as it strives to pass the tough entry test for joining a European single currency.</p>
<p>The Malhoa paintings had belonged to a wealthy Portuguese private collector, Agostinho Fernandes. ($1=165.79 escudos)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
