<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="363736" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Blue chips end sharply higher; concern over dollar trims gain.</title>
<headline>Blue chips end sharply higher; concern over dollar trims gain.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue-chip stocks ended up sharply Friday on a positive jobs report for January, though concern over a possible shift in the United States' view on the strong dollar brought the market off its high.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average closed up 82.74 points, or 1.22 percent, at 6,855.80 after an early run-up of more than 95 points. The rally put the blue-chip index within striking distance of its record closing high of 6,883.90 set on Jan. 21. For the week, the Dow rose 42.71 points.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks and the New York Stock Exchange Composite index both closed at new highs.</p>
<p>In the broader market, advances beat declines 1,627 to 930 on active volume of 538 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Sparking the rally was the employment report for January that showed stronger-than-expected job growth but only slight wage increases. The data muted fears of wage-driven inflation and eased fears of interest rate tightening any time soon by the Federal Reserve.</p>
<p>Non-farm payrolls came in with an increase of 271,000 compared with a revised 261,000 the previous month. But analysts said the number had been inflated due to seasonal factors. More importantly, average hourly earnings rose by a mere 1 cent after a sharper rise over the previous two months.</p>
<p>The tame inflation implications of the report sent bonds higher and stocks quickly followed suit.</p>
<p>In the bond market, the bellwether 30-year Treasury bond was up 23/23, lowering its yield to 6.70 percent from 6.76 percent on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The market got what it wanted, particularly from the hourly earnings number which was very encouraging on inflation,&quot; said Guy Truicko, portfolio manager at Unity Management.</p>
<p>The ferocity of the move suggested to analysts that some of January's mutual fund inflows may still be sitting on the sidelines, waiting for an opportunity to enter the market.</p>
<p>&quot;What I see is a lot of cash waiting in the background,&quot; said Peggy Farley, chief executive at Amas Securities. &quot;Every time we've seen good news, the market has shot up.&quot;</p>
<p>But recently, with every step higher, the stock market has also exhibited increasing wariness.</p>
<p>That skittishness was most apparent during the session's frenzied afternoon, which saw dollar-related comments by Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin send markets gyrating wildly.</p>
<p>Rubin signalled that he would not be unhappy with some weakening of the dollar, but he stopped well short of advocating a decline in the U.S. currency.</p>
<p>His comments, however, helped bring one about, driving the greenback sharply lower in the New York foreign exchange market as speculators scrambled to dump dollars. The dollar slumped to 123 Japanese yen from 123.75 on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the bullish props, particularly for bonds, was the strong dollar,&quot; said Anthony O'Bryan, an analyst at A.G. Edwards. &quot;When the dollar gave back gains, that hit bonds and triggered futures-related sell programmes.&quot;</p>
<p>As bonds recovered, however, programmes quickly ensued on the buy side, producing a choppy finish that saw the Dow index ultimately surge nearly all the way back to its morning peak.</p>
<p>Financial stocks were broadly higher, benefiting from the improved interest rate climate. Citicorp jumped 4-1/8 to 120-3/4 and BankAmerica Corp. rose 3-5/8 to 118-7/8.</p>
<p>American Express Corp. gained 3-3/8 to 65-3/8 on news that U.S. Justice Department staff attorneys are considering an anti-trust suit against Visa and MasterCard.</p>
<p>The suit, if filed, would challenge Visa and MasterCard's practice of prohibiting their U.S. member banks from issuing American Express cards.</p>
<p>Drug store chain Revco D.S. Inc. climbed 3-3/8 to 41-3/8 after agreeing to a $2.8 billion stock acquisition by CVS Corp. CVS shares rose 3-1/8 to 47-1/8.</p>
<p>Physician Support Systems Inc. plunged 8-3/4 to 7-1/2 after warning of disappointing fourth-quarter earnings.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index rose 11.31 points to 1,357.71.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks gained 9.41 to 789.56, a new high. The American Stock Exchange index rose 1.59 to 586.62.</p>
<p>The NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks rose 3.91 to 413.80, a new high. The average share was up 41 cents.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 7,582.919, up 71.043, or 0.95 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
