<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="36428" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Accord may be close for Cr Lyonnais salvage plan.</title>
<headline>Accord may be close for Cr Lyonnais salvage plan.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>State-owned Credit Lyonnais would not comment on Thursday on a report its chairman had threatened to quit unless agreement was reached by Friday on a new rescue plan for the ailing French bank.</p>
<p>But a source close to talks involving the bank and the government said the letter was written by bank chairman Jean Peyrelevade in July and a solution to the bank's problems was close.</p>
<p>&quot;I doubt he will resign because he knows things are coming to a solution,&quot; he said. &quot;Things are going quite quickly.&quot;</p>
<p>A &quot;consensus was developing&quot; in government circles to help the bank, he said. The solution was said to centre around Peyrelevade's favoured option that would free the bank of the financial burden of financing its own rescue.</p>
<p>Financial analysts have said unless the rescue terms are revised, the bank could plunge back into the red this year.</p>
<p>A finance ministry spokeswoman would not confirm reports of progress. She would only say the two sides were &quot;working every day&quot; to reach a solution &quot;because one must be found&quot;.</p>
<p>The bank and the government have been in a race against time to come up with a plan before Credit Lyonnais' board meets on September 26 to approve its half-year results.</p>
<p>Credit Lyonnais accumulated losses of 21 billion francs (currently $4.1 billion) between 1992 and 1994 as a result of a reckless expansion spree. It eked out a 13 million franc profit in 1995, helped by a massive state rescue package, the second in two years.</p>
<p>($ = 5.078 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
