<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="364498" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Finnish MPs see security rows in multi-core Europe.</title>
<headline>Finnish MPs see security rows in multi-core Europe.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Divisions within the European Union generated by the drive to launch a single currency could lead to security policy conflicts, the Finnish parliament's foreign affairs committee warned on Friday.</p>
<p>The birth of a multi-core union, where  groups of EU members made different rates of progress on various issues, looked set to become a reality, the committee said.</p>
<p>&quot;The creation of several cores could become very problematic when dealing with security policy issues. Differing views on how to run security policy could in the worst case lead even to serious differences of opinion between Union member countries,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>It seemed likely that the European Union's way forward would be largely dictated by big member countries, mainly Germany and France, the committee added.</p>
<p>A multi-core, or multi-speed, EU was one scenario portrayed by the Finnish government last autumn in a report to parliament titled &quot;Finland and the Future of Europe&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The report gives the impression that the government is ready to accept a multi-core nature for the union especially in connection with the third stage of EMU,&quot; the committee said in its review of the report.</p>
<p>The committee said a single currency must not have such a high political value that problems marrying convergence criteria and the EMU timetable lead to legal objections or ignore the economic impact and the effects on society.</p>
<p>The Finnish government wants Finland to be in the first group of countries setting up the single currency in 1999. It also supports enlargement of the EU to include the Baltic republics and the countries of central and eastern Europe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
