<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="364473" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Ryanair unveils new low-price European flights.</title>
<headline>Ryanair unveils new low-price European flights.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish cut-price airline Ryanair unveiled details of new services to Paris and Brussels on Friday which it said undercut competition by 50 percent.</p>
<p>The airline said it would start the new services on May 1 with up to six flights a day between Dublin and Beauvais, near Paris, and Dublin and Charleroi, near Brussels.</p>
<p>It said in a statement that the lowest prices for both destinations would be 79 Irish pounds return which it said undercut tariffs charged by state carrier Aer Lingus by half.  </p>
<p>It said it had won special reduced bus and taxi rates to and from the airports in Brussels and Paris and that by avoiding the main terminuses of Paris's Charles De Gaulle and Brussels' Zaventem it would get passengers to the capitals quicker.</p>
<p>&quot;For years now passengers have been complaining about the high cost of air travel to and from continental Europe. There is absolutely no reason why it should cost almost 500 pounds for a business trip to Paris and Brussels and we in Ryanair hope to change this for ever,&quot; Chief Executive Michael O'Leary said.  </p>
<p>Speaking on behalf of Paris Beauvais airport, Marketing Director Guy Monnehay said, &quot;Ryanair and Paris Beauvais airport will be a great partnership. The French market has been denied access to low air fares for too long and we look forward to a huge increase in French traffic to Ireland resulting directly from the introduction of this service.&quot;</p>
<p>Ireland's transport minister Alan Dukes welcomed the new service.</p>
<p>&quot;Competition is good for travellers, customers and the people competed with,&quot; he said at the launch. &quot;The more we see of this new competition the better.&quot;</p>
<p>The service was also warmly greeted by Irish Tourist Board chairman Mark Mortell who said it should increase tourism to and from continental Europe.</p>
<p>Ryanair, which bills itself as a no-frills low-fare airline, says it is the fastest growing scheduled airline in Europe and carried more than three million passengers in 1966.</p>
<p>It operates a fleet of 12 Boeing 737 aircraft on a network of 14 routes to British destinations to and from Dublin.</p>
<p>-- Dublin Newsroom +353-1-6613377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
