<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="364525" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-German coffee roasters raise retail prices.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-German coffee roasters raise retail prices.</headline>
<byline>Vera Eckert</byline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>German coffee roasters are seeking to offset sharp increases in futures prices and the dollar by increasing retail prices of coffee, they said on Friday.</p>
<p>The desired increase is two marks per kilo of roasted coffee for which average prices currently stand at 14 marks.</p>
<p>Market leader Kraft Jacobs Suchard (KJS), part of Philip Morris Cos Inc took the lead with an announcement it would raise its prices by two marks with effect from March 10.</p>
<p>Most rivalling roasters said they had similar plans.</p>
<p>Traders said the move was much needed in an underpriced roasted coffee market, the world's second largest, where green coffee equivalent use in 1996 was just above 564,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>But only time would tell to what degree higher ex-plant prices would work their way through the wholesale and grocery chain to reach the consumer, the traders added.</p>
<p>KJS said arabica prices had risen sharply since December and the dollar had also gained 10 percent at 1.65 marks.</p>
<p>Stocks at origin and in consumer countries were low and reduced crop expectations in leading producer country Brazil -- together with omnipresent Brazilian frost fears -- made higher green coffee prices look likely over a long period.</p>
<p>Spokesman Rolf Sauerbier said the company was confident it would achieve the higher prices as consumers were turning to KJS's new range of mild-flavoured and single origin products.</p>
<p>The Bremen-based company was aiming to reach and maintain a 30 percent market share after 28.5 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>German coffee consumption had been picking up slightly in the second half of 1996 after losses in both 1994 and 1995.</p>
<p>A spokesman for premium roaster Alois Dallmayr Kaffee oHG in Munich said his firm had chosen a similar course of action.</p>
<p>&quot;Coffee prices applying to our blends have nearly risen by 50 percent over the last two months and with the dollar higher as well it is inevitable for us to raise prices,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're in the process of informing our customers.&quot;</p>
<p>Dallmayr had an eight percent market share in 1996 when it bought some 750,000 60 kg bags of green coffee.</p>
<p>A fierce competitor of the two, Melitta Kaffee GmbH in Minden said it would also follow the KJS move.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman put Melitta's December market share at 12.3 percent.</p>
<p>At Hamburg's J. J. Darboven, the head of raw materials purchasing Guenther Fude said there were plans to move along the same lines, but final details could not yet be announced.</p>
<p>Darboven accounts for roughly seven percent of the market.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman at Tchibo Frisch-Roest Kaffee GmbH in Hamburg said prices would be raised modestly, most likely at the end of February, but she would not say by what amount.</p>
<p>&quot;We need especially good qualities which are tight and where we have to pay premiums over futures,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Eduscho GmbH &amp; Co KG said it had raised the price of one of its key brands, Milde Natur, by two marks on Jan 23 and would await market developments before taking this further.</p>
<p>Tied-outlet roasters Tchibo and Eduscho, who together represent some 30 percent of the market, act more cautiously than other roasters, where the success of price moves depends on competitive wholesale and grocery policies.</p>
<p>They can immediately implement price hikes in their shops.</p>
<p>An analyst said he expected a certain amount of trade and consumer hoarding ahead of the German price adjustments.</p>
<p>-Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
