<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="364699" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian wool prices said firm this week.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian wool prices said firm this week.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian wool prices remained surprisingly firm at sales in Goulburn, Melbourne and Fremantle this week, Wesfarmers Dalgety Ltd said on Friday.</p>
<p>The eastern market indicator fell by six cents to 592 cents a kg clean while the western indicator rose one cent to 573 cents a kg clean.</p>
<p>A total of 104,048 bales were offered, of which the trade bought 91.1 percent. The pass-in rate was 8.9 percent.</p>
<p>Wesfarmers said there was evidence of active Chinese business, new orders from India and hesitant but improving European enquiry.  </p>
<p>&quot;The very best quality fine wools continued to be in strong demand, but for the bulk of the offerings, there was quite an irregular pattern in price movements, particularly early in the week. However, the market overall does appear to be stabilising around an eastern market indicator of 600 cents a kg clean,&quot; the Australian Council of Wool Exporters said.</p>
<p>Wool International said its stockpile of unsold wool totalled 1,880,662 bales as at February 6.</p>
<p>In the futures market, a total of 70 contracts were traded in the 21 micron contract in the week ended February 6.</p>
<p>Open interest decreased by 31 contracts to close at 838.  </p>
<p>The February 1997 contract closed two cents down at 689 cents a kg clean and the April 1997 contract closed 10 cents down at 709 cents a kg clean.</p>
<p>Sales next week are in Sydney, Geelong and Fremantle with a total of 88,700 bales rostered for sale.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
