<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="364622" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Truce collapse puts N.Irish police in front line.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Truce collapse puts N.Irish police in front line.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most police give photos of their passing out parades pride of place in their homes. Not in Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>Here they are hidden in drawers so that no unannounced visitor will ever know that there is a member of the Royal Ulster Constabulary (RUC) in the house.</p>
<p>Every day they they peer under their cars for booby-trap bombs. Only close neighbours know what their occupation is. The tell-tale green police shirts are rarely on the washing line.</p>
<p>A year after Irish Republican Army (IRA) bombs blew holes in a peace process, Northern Ireland's police are back on the front-line of a growing guerrilla war.</p>
<p>&quot;We're back to where we were,&quot; a veteran officer said ruefully about the collapse of an IRA ceasefire on February 9, 1996, and violence that could dump war on his doorstep.</p>
<p>POLICE THE MAIN TARGET OF IRA</p>
<p>The IRA bombing of London's Canary Wharf complex one year ago heralded the end of a 17-month truce and the start of a new campaign to drive Britain from the province.</p>
<p>Bomb attacks in the northern English city of Manchester and a British army base in Germany followed quickly but since October last year the IRA has concentrated on Northern Ireland and the RUC in particular.</p>
<p>&quot;When the Canary Wharf bomb went off in London this time last year, my heart sank. I thought to myself we're on a slide. It's starting again',&quot; recalled the officer, who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>He had seen at first hand the depths of the 1969-1994 IRA guerrilla war that erupted in daylight on street corners or along dark country lanes in a conflict that killed 3,200.</p>
<p>Officers torn apart by guerrilla rockets. Bewildered parents being led into hospitals to identify loved ones found bound, gagged and shot, victims of sectarian murder gangs.</p>
<p>A senior British security source said IRA &quot;volunteers&quot; have been told by their commanders to attack Northern Ireland soldiers and police officers, preferably while on duty and in uniform, in an escalation of a war to end British rule. &quot;The threat is high against security forces right across the province,&quot; the source told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The IRA is quite well supplied. Alongside all their commercially-produced weaponry, they have also always relied heavily on home-made weapons which are just as effective.&quot;</p>
<p>CANARY WHARF WRECKS PEACE DREAM</p>
<p>The Canary Wharf explosion killed two civilians and caused millions of pounds worth of destruction in the heart of one of the British capital's key financial districts.</p>
<p>It wrecked an Anglo-Irish peace process, ended the longest truce the IRA has ever called, and set the province back on the slippery slope towards renewed sectarian war as a way of life.</p>
<p>In 25 years the RUC lost 297 officers and hundreds more were badly wounded, largely at the hands of IRA bombers and gunmen.</p>
<p>The truce by the IRA, which draws support from Northern Ireland's 40 percent Catholic minority, was followed by one from pro-British Protestant Loyalists, which threw the troubled province a lifeline.</p>
<p>The 92 percent Protestant RUC turned to &quot;normal policing&quot; and got on with passing out speeding tickets but simmering tensions led to sectarian clashes last summer.</p>
<p>Many in the Catholic minority accused the RUC of bias and of using heavy-handed tactics to ensure the passage through Catholic districts of several contentious Protestant parades.</p>
<p>Distrusted by sections of Catholics and regarded by many Protestants as a bulwark for preserving treasured British links, RUC officers say they have been pitched into a no-win position in the middle of age-old rivalries.</p>
<p>They say they help the whole community preserve order and defeat crime but IRA guerrillas, and a growing Loyalist menace, are forcing them into a high profile counter-insurgency role they hoped had been left behind.</p>
<p>TRUCE MEANT &quot;FALSE SENSE OF SECURITY&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We were lulled into a false sense of security,&quot; said a policewoman in a country station. &quot;Now it's slipping back.&quot;</p>
<p>The IRA staged its first attack for two years in the province in October, killing one soldier and wounding 30 with a car bomb at British Army headquarters in Lisburn near Belfast.</p>
<p>Since December the guerrillas have stepped up mortar and grenade attacks on both police and British soldiers. To date they have killed no one, but police say it is a matter of time. The main threat is at security patrols or bases, but police officers are stepping up personal and domestic safety measures.</p>
<p>Cadet graduation pictures are locked in drawers for fear of unexpected callers. Children are reminded not to leave doors open and not to talk too much about &quot;what dad does&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;You try to strike a balance between not being careless and being alive to the fact that there are people who would maybe go to your house and plant a bomb under your car or shoot at your home,&quot; a long-serving officer said.</p>
<p>In the past, RUC men and women have been ambushed on and off-duty, in their homes, in security bases, in bars and on their way to church.</p>
<p>When the IRA called its truce the RUC shed their bulky flak jackets and high calibre arms. For the first time in a quarter of a century they patrolled without army support in areas that had been war zones. Now they are back on alert.</p>
<p>Gingerly they patrol hostile Irish republican strongholds on foot or in in bleak grey bullet-proof vehicles. Military armour backs them up, helmeted soldiers riding shotgun.</p>
<p>The onset of a potentially explosive Protestant &quot;marching season&quot;, which saw Loyalist hardliners attack them last summer, will see them in riot gear again this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We had let ourselves become a lot more relaxed during the ceasefire,&quot; a middle-rank officer said wistfully.</p>
<p>&quot;It was like having a weight lifted off our sholders. The prospect of facing back into a war situation - well, its really dreary and depressing.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
