<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="364655" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-OPINION-Russell Barton's Canberra Closeup-Woods on Block.</title>
<headline>RTRS-OPINION-Russell Barton's Canberra Closeup-Woods on Block.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Russell Barton (ABC TV Political Editor)</p>
<p>Higher standards, family values, codes of conduct, motherhood even. All terrific planks in a platform for getting elected.</p>
<p>Having achieved victory, then comes the unpleasant reality. Some of the boys on the bus have streaks of naughtiness which sit uneasily with the pre-election pledges.</p>
<p>The former parliamentary secretary for health, the retiring Senator Bob Woods, has not been charged with any offences relating to his handling of parliamentary allowances. He's still under federal police investigation on that score.</p>
<p>But he has confirmed the myriad reports that he formed a relationship with Roxanne Cameron, who works in the office of the Liberal member for North Sydney, Joe Hockey.</p>
<p>This was common knowledge around the Liberal Party last year. In itself, it was neither remarkable nor newsworthy.</p>
<p>Woods is not the only MP to have marital difficulties. But suddenly Woods and his friend are marking the break-up of their liaison with a public slanging match.</p>
<p>It's been marked by Woods' claim that he had called for police special branch investigation of her, a claim now denied by the special branch itself.</p>
<p>Then she applied for an apprehended violence order against Woods, which will be heard next Wednesday.</p>
<p>The matter shifted from a sleazy curiosity to a political issue when its tentacles reached the prime minister revealing John Howard doesn't necessarily remember everything he's told.</p>
<p>He told the public through a television current affairs show on Tuesday that he didn't know about the police investigation into Woods' use of his parliamentary travel allowances until late January when Woods told him about the execution of search warrants.</p>
<p>Then on Wednesday night, Government Senate Leader Robert Hill was left with the task of correcting the record -- Attorney-General Daryl Williams had remembered what the Prime Minister had forgotten. He had told Howard of the Woods investigation in September.</p>
<p>Howard dealt effectively with the predictable parliamentary attack yesterday. His account did stack up to be a simple case of faulty memory.</p>
<p>It is arguable, however, whether he should have moved to suspend Woods earlier, particularly when Liberal Party director Andrew Robb for some time had been expressing concern about the senator's private life and its potential for political embarrassment.</p>
<p>While Howard does seem to have avoided major strife, for now, the whole affair does leave a number of questions and issues for this government.</p>
<p>Already there have been mutterings of dissatisfaction from the ministry and the backbench about the prime minister's office way of working. It seems plenty goes on in Howard's office which is not recorded or diarised -- as others have discovered before that's a very dangerous practice.</p>
<p>The same could be said for Daryl Williams, whose memory of just when he told Howard, and just what he said, has escaped him. Why, for instance, did the attorney-general not correct Howard's account of when he knew of the Woods matter soon after the prime minister's television appearance. This lack of attention to detail can be fatal in politics.</p>
<p>As for Senator Woods himself, his behaviour has followed the usual linear pattern for politicians in trouble. It goes like this: denial, resistance, revelation, resignation.</p>
<p>Woods will be gone by the end of March. But behind him he will leave another smudge on that part of the Howard platform which had such play in the 1996 campaign -- the promise of higher standards.</p>
<p>It's already tarnished by the ministerial casualties over the shares affair which Howard concluded simply by drawing the line -- refusing to countenance any further protests about Industry Minister John Moore's shareholdings and apparent conflicts of interest.</p>
<p>Anyone who regularly observes the parliament would also be struck by the inconsistency of the conduct of Speaker Bob Halverson with Howard's pre-election promise of an independent speaker who would repair parliamentary standards after Paul Keating had rent them asunder.</p>
<p>The general consensus is that Halverson has a long way to go to pull himself off the bottom of the Speakers' league table.</p>
<p>As for the opposition, any reasonable person would expect that Labor would have handled the Woods affair with political aplomb and, as a result, severely dented the government.</p>
<p>But deputy leader Gareth Evans managed to put the opposition on the back foot at the outset with his comment that there was an element of sleaze in this government.</p>
<p>Kim Beazley had words with his deputy, who then tried to spin his way out of trouble by arguing he was talking about Woods' money irregularities, not his love life.</p>
<p>The opposition also failed to inspire confidence when the ABC's 7.30 Report tried to set up a debate on the political aspects of the controversy on Thursday night.</p>
<p>Peter Reith was prepared to front for the government as Leader of the House, but his Labor counterpart Simon Crean declined, saying it was too forensic for television.</p>
<p>The affair failed to bring out the best in our national leaders.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
