<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="364688" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Wheat Board mulls float on ASX.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Wheat Board mulls float on ASX.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian Wheat Board (AWB) is considering floating a corporate vehicle on the Australian Stock Exchange (ASX) as part of looming restructuring, AWB chairman Trevor Flugge said.</p>
<p>Assets of the new company would be the grower levy-funded Wheat Industry Fund (WIF), wheat held in the AWB's pool, other businesses which might be built up, plus the goodwill of an organisation more than 55 years old, AWB spokesman Alex Nichol told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Any listing of the AWB's corporate vehicle was likely by about 2001, Flugge said while speaking to reporters at the Australian Bureau of Agricultural and Resource Economics (ABARE) Outlook conference in Canberra this week.</p>
<p>The WIF contained A$360 million before the current record harvest and levy contributions from the harvest would provide the fund with a &quot;considerable fillip&quot;, Nichol said.</p>
<p>The WIF, a levy-based pool of finance being built up to underpin AWB borrowings when the Australian government removes its guarantee on the organisation's borrowings in 1999, is expected to contain about A$550 million by 2000.  </p>
<p>The size of the possible float had not been decided, nor had it been decided that the float would proceed, Nichol said.</p>
<p>A range of possible names for the new company had been registered, with no decision taken yet, he said.</p>
<p>The Grains Council of Australia, representing graingrowers, and other sectors of the trade favour a trust arrangement to house the A$550 million grower funds that will have accumulated by July 1, 1999.</p>
<p>Flugge said a trust would confuse matters and that he strongly supported a dual-class share structure and stock exchange listing of the privatised body.  </p>
<p>Under the AWB model, every wheat grower will receive one A class share, which will control the privatised body.</p>
<p>B class shares also will be issued in proportion to the amount of funds growers have invested in the WIF.</p>
<p>Listing of the WIF after the government's competition review of the AWB's export monopoly would involve a probable ceiling of five percent on any single shareholding, Flugge said.</p>
<p>Flugge said the listing arrangement would be required to show that shares were &quot;locked up and not vulnerable to takeover&quot;.  </p>
<p>International customers of Australian wheat, including Japan and Egypt, now wished to strengthen their linkages with the AWB export system to ensure that they became &quot;part of the chain&quot; as privatisation loomed, he said.</p>
<p>But this would not involve them becoming shareholders in the listed company, Flugge said.</p>
<p>The AWB chairman also strongly supported the AWB's single desk monopoly on export sales of Australia's annual wheat crop and said that a listed company would provide the best vehicle to raise the A$3.0 billion or so each year required in advance payments to growers for wheat delivered to the pool.  </p>
<p>Inefficient financing of the pool, through a trust arrangement, could threaten the basis for the single export desk, he said.</p>
<p>As an example of the effectiveness of the AWB's single desk export powers, Flugge said the U.S. could no longer compete with Australia and was in danger of becoming a &quot;residual player on the world market.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 610-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
