<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="364710" id="root" date="1997-02-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGB futures end higher following stocks' plunge.</title>
<headline>JGB futures end higher following stocks' plunge.</headline>
<text>
<p>*Japanese government bond futures end higher in dealer-led buying following Tokyo stocks' fall, but capped by dollar's rise above 124.00 yen.</p>
<p>*Players cautious ahead of weekend G7 meeting.  </p>
<p>However, buying waned following the dollar's rise to a fresh 48-month high against the yen, traders said. The dollar rose as high as 124.30 yen in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Market participants were cautious ahead of the release of U.S. employment data later Friday and the Group of Seven (G7) meeting, which starts on Saturday.</p>
<p>Any negative impact from further yen weakness on JGBs is likely to be limited unless the dollar rises sharply above 125 yen after the G7 meeting, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;JGBs have already factored in a possible dollar rise to 125 yen,&quot; said a trader at a city bank's securities unit.  </p>
<p>&quot;If the dollar/yen stabilises after the G7, March JGB futures could test record highs next week,&quot; said the brokerage house trader.</p>
<p>The all-time high for any benchmark futures contract is 126.83 set on January 27.</p>
<p>In coming weeks, short-covering pressure on the March contract is likely to intensify ahead of the expected change in the benchmark, traders said. The June contract is expected to take over as the benchmark later this month.</p>
<p>Investors' demand for cash JGBs could also help limit the downside risk, traders said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Investors were still keen to buy 193rd JGBs and some unlisted bonds on dips,&quot; said the brokerage house trader.</p>
<p>The yield of the benchmark cash 182nd JGB stood at 2.375 percent in late Tokyo, down from 2.385 percent on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Japanese government's monthly economic report released earlier in the day was virtually ignored by the bond market as it did not contain anything fresh, traders said.</p>
<p>The Economic Planning Agency (EPA) said in its overall assessment that the economy was recovering on the back of strong capital spending and housing starts, though the tempo remained slow.  </p>
<p>Players could be discouraged from trading actively next Monday as Japanese financial markets will be closed on Tuesday for a national holiday, traders said.</p>
<p>-- Kanta Watanabe, Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-3432-9780</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
