<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="36488" id="root" date="1996-09-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Borotra hopes for French buyer for Valeo.</title>
<headline>Borotra hopes for French buyer for Valeo.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Industry Minister Franck Borotra said he was hoping for a deal this month that would enable a French buyer to acquire a stake up for sale in car parts manufacturer Valeo.</p>
<p>The stake is owned by Italian industrialist Carlo De Benedetti's French holding company Cerus, which has been seeking to sell it since February.</p>
<p>&quot;We could see a French offer materialise in September. I hope so,&quot; Borotra told Les Echos in an interview published on Thursday. The matter is politically sensitive as French carmakers oppose any deal that would put Valeo in the hands of a foreign group or rival.</p>
<p>A Cerus spokesman said on Wednesday that De Benedetti's resignation as chairman of Olivetti did not alter Cerus's stance on Valeo. The company has said it would entertain offers at the right price which it estimated at around 400 francs per share.</p>
<p>Valeo closed at 270 francs on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Analysts say only a big automotive concern would be willing to pay the kind of premium Cerus is seeking and that such a buyer would probably be aiming for control of Valeo.</p>
<p>Valeo is due to unveil its first-half results at a news conference later on Thursday after the stockmarket closes.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
