<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365176" id="root" date="1997-02-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Coffee prices rise, drinkers seen paying up.</title>
<headline>Coffee prices rise, drinkers seen paying up.</headline>
<byline>Jalil Hamid</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coffee prices resumed their climb on Friday, raising prospects of dearer cups of coffee as European roasters hiked retail prices to make up for soaring bean costs.</p>
<p>Bean prices are already up by 32 percent since the start of the New Year and traders said the market looked poised for further gains after recent consolidation.</p>
<p>London March robusta coffee futures prices surged to a high of $1,628 a tonne on Friday, just short of five-month peaks of $1,630 set on January 23, on fresh investor short-covering.</p>
<p>But the contract's rally was shortlived, falling back to $1,540 by the close for a $14 loss. Traders however said the short-term uptrend remained intact.</p>
<p>Fundamentally, the market remained firm boosted by worries of lower central American supplies and amid forecasts of lower 1997/98 Brazilian harvest.</p>
<p>Coffee stocks in both producing and origin countries are also low. Western manufacturers had been running down on stocks since the Brazilian frosts in 1994 pushed prices to 10-year highs.</p>
<p>Coffee drinkers will now have to pay for roasters' stock-keeping policy.</p>
<p>Roasters, caught by the sudden hike in bean prices, scrambled to rebuild their supplies. But with the 32 percent hike in raw material costs, many would have no choice but to pass some of the costs to consumers.</p>
<p>Large German roaster Kraft Jacobs Suchard is the latest firm to announce a retail price hike, announcing on Friday that it would have to offset the surge in futures prices and the dollar.</p>
<p>Dutch roaster Douwe Egberts also toook a similar action earlier this week but Nestle UK, part of the Swiss food conglomerate, reiterated on Friday it had no immediate plans to raise retail prices but was watching the situation very closely.</p>
<p>Despite the hike in bean prices, major producers said they would not like to see prices rising to levels that would deter consumer demand.</p>
<p>The head of the Association of Coffee Producing Countries Rubens Barbosa said that the group would like to maintain a policy of stabilising prices at renumerative levels.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as the ACPC is concerned we are not looking for sky-high prices,&quot; Barbosa said. &quot;It is neither in the interest of the consumers nor the producers to have boom and bust cycles agains,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>ACPC countries agreed additional cuts in exports of robusta and arabica coffee totalling 1.3 million bags in the first six months of 1997, aiming to narrow the premium of New York-traded arabica over London's robusta.</p>
<p>Barbosa denied comments that ACPC's export retention programme may have backfired, threatening consumer demand, saying the price spike was a result of changes in fundamental conditions.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 4985</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
