<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365270" id="root" date="1997-02-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: India to allow foreign-owned atomic plants - report.</title>
<headline>India to allow foreign-owned atomic plants - report.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>India will allow 100 percent foreign ownership of nuclear power plants in order to develop its infrastructure, Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda was quoted as saying in a Japanese business newspaper report on Saturday.</p>
<p>Gowda, in an interview in New Delhi on Friday with the Nihon Keizai Shimbun business daily, said full foreign ownership of a nuclear power plant in India would present no problem.</p>
<p>The Japanese translation of his statement quoted him as saying that &quot;the 100 percent participation of foreign capital in nuclear power plants will be recognised... there is no problem whatsoever&quot;.</p>
<p>The front-page article provided no details on specific projects or schedules, however.</p>
<p>A decision to allow full foreign ownership of a nuclear power plant represents a sharp departure from the go-it-alone approach India has taken in building the nine atomic plants it now operates, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>However, India's refusal to join the Nuclear Non-proliferation Treaty and other international protocols aimed at curbing the spread of nuclear weapons would likely pose a barrier to the introduction of foreign nuclear technology in the country, the report said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I1610109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
