<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365226" id="root" date="1997-02-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAJIKISTAN: Tajik security minister held in hostage crisis.</title>
<headline>Tajik security minister held in hostage crisis.</headline>
<byline>Yuri Kushko</byline>
<dateline>DUSHANBE 1997-02-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tajikistan's hostage crisis worsened on Saturday when the government said its security minister, Saidamir Zukhurov, was kidnapped by rebels already holding a group of United Nations workers.</p>
<p>&quot;Saidamir Zukhurov has been taken hostage,&quot; Zafar Saidov, spokesman for Tajik President Imomali Rakhmonov, told Reuters in the Tajik capital Dushanbe.</p>
<p>He said Zukhurov was taken hostage late on Friday.</p>
<p>The president held an emergency meeting of the government on Saturday to discuss ways of tackling the crisis but Rakhmonov ruled out the use of force.</p>
<p>&quot;The government will not use force, this can only be solved through negotiations,&quot; said Saidov.</p>
<p>The minister was part of a government team trying to negotiate the release of four employees of the United Nations refugee agency (UNHCR), including a Nigerian, four U.N. military observers from Austria, Switzerland and Ukraine -- and four Russian reporters abducted last week.</p>
<p>The hostages are being held near the town of Obigarm in mountainous territory 80 km (50 miles) east of Dushanbe.</p>
<p>The hostage-takers are part of a group commanded by Rizvon Sadirov, which once fought for the country's armed Islamic opposition but whose loyalties are now unclear.</p>
<p>The kidnappers, led by Rizvon's brother Bakhrom Sadirov, are demanding free passage for colleagues based in neighbouring Afghanistan to return to Tajikistan.</p>
<p>Russia's Itar-Tass news agency said on Saturday that all border crossings between the two countries had been closed because of the crisis.</p>
<p>It quoted the commander of Russian border guards based in Tajikstan Lieutenant-General Pavel Tarasenko as saying that there were more than 10 armed Tajik opposition groups close to the border in Afghanistan but that the situation was calm.</p>
<p>Earlier, the Tajik government said the remaining hostages could be released on Friday after two Red Cross employees captured by the same group were released the same day.</p>
<p>&quot;An agreement was reached in Obigarm for the release of all the hostages without preconditions,&quot; said Saidov.</p>
<p>But a helicopter sent tentatively to collect the remaining hostages returned empty on Friday evening.</p>
<p>U.N. personnel began leaving the republic on Saturday after the world body decided on Friday to withdraw all non-essential personnel. A U.N. spokesman said around 40 employees had left for neighbouring Uzbekistan by road.</p>
<p>&quot;In view of the serious security situation in Dushanbe and danger to the lives of United Nations personnel, United Nations special representative Gerd Merrem...has decided to relocate UNMOT (military observers) and all other U.N. agencies from Tajikistan to Uzbekistan,&quot; said a statement given to journalists in the Tajik capital Dushanbe on Friday.</p>
<p>The Red Cross also suspended operations in the former Soviet republic, after two of its workers were abducted by the same group. They were subsequently released on Friday and returned to the capital Dushanbe.</p>
<p>The international agencies have been based in the region to bring badly needed aid to the remote, mountainous country bordering China which has been devastated by a four-year civil war. A ceasefire agreed between the government and Islamist guerrillas last December appears to be holding.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TADZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUSHANBE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAJIKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
