<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365239" id="root" date="1997-02-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia oil workers set contract talks deadline.</title>
<headline>Colombia oil workers set contract talks deadline.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-02-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombia's main oil union said it would go out on strike if the state oil company Ecopetrol did not meet its demands on a new collective contract by February 17.</p>
<p>One of the USO union leaders, Gustavo Triana, said the decision taken at a meeting in Bogota late Friday did not mean the all-out strike would begin on the day the deadline expired but on an unspecified date thereafter.</p>
<p>The strike call, which was approved in principle in December but put on hold pending talks with Ecopetrol, may be academic, however, since Triana said the USO would join an indefinite, national public sector strike due to start February 11.</p>
<p>The USO has been demanding a 30 percent wage hike and a deal for at least 10 members arrested in December accused of links with the National Liberation Army (ELN), Colombia's secopnd largest guerrilla force.</p>
<p>Union leaders and government ministers, meanwhile, resumed talks Friday afternoon aimed at hammering out an 11th hour deal to avert the stoppage by state workers, which could affect 800,000 employees and paralyze key sectors such as oil, telecommunications, health and public administration.</p>
<p>State workers are protesting at below-inflation wage rises and the growing clampdown on labor rights.</p>
<p>-- Karl Penhaul, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
