<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365358" id="root" date="1997-02-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Crew of 20 feared dead as ship sinks off Norway.</title>
<headline>Crew of 20 feared dead as ship sinks off Norway.</headline>
<byline>Rolf Soderlind</byline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-02-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Greek cargo ship with a Polish crew of 20 sank with all hands in a storm off southwestern Norway on Saturday, apparently as the captain was calling the Norwegian rescue service for help.</p>
<p>Rescue officials said the ship, the Leros Strength, went down about 30 miles west of the Norwegian North Sea port of Stavanger in waves six metres (20 feet) high.</p>
<p>A helicopter using a heat-seeking camera and seven ships were searching for survivors following the sinking, which officials said probably happened shortly after the captain radioed for help at 7.50 a.m. (0650GMT).</p>
<p>&quot;We are not optimistic (of finding anyone alive),&quot; rescue service spokesman Anders Bang-Andersen told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We were on the spot quickly. The helicopter pilot saw bubbles and diesel oil on the surface. Life vests and two empty lift rafts were floating in the sea. A plate with the ship's name on it was observed, too.</p>
<p>&quot;The captain was calm,&quot; Bang-Andersen said. &quot;But he knew they were in a serious situation and he asked for assistance, asked for help to save the crew and himself.&quot;</p>
<p>The captain was identified by the Polish Ship Rescue service in Gdynia as Eugeniusz Arciszewski. Norwegian officials said he reported a hole in the bow of the 21-year-old ship, which was said by Norwegian authorities to have been in a poor condition.</p>
<p>&quot;He said he had problems navigating because of the hole in the bow. When we asked for a weather report the communication was broken. One theory is that the ship then suddenly sank,&quot; Bang-Andersen said.</p>
<p>Rescue official Svein Solberg, who spoke with Arciszewski for three minutes before the line went dead, said the captain must have been taken by surprise at the speed with which the ship went under.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible that the ship had been taking in more water during the night than the captain was aware of,&quot; he was quoted as saying by the Norwegian news agency NTB. &quot;The ship must have gone down very quickly.&quot;</p>
<p>The ship, a 22,000 tonne bulk carrier, was carrying apatite, a crystalline mineral used in the manufacture of fertilisers, from Murmansk, Russia, to Poland.</p>
<p>Built in 1976, it was registered  in Cyprus but owned by Greek shipping company Leros Management, officials said.</p>
<p>NTB quoted the Norwegian Maritime Directorate as saying the ship was held in the Dutch port of Rotterdam on August 13 last year because of 11 complaints about its condition. They included everything from insufficient rescue gear to faults in the navigational system, NTB said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is obvious that the ship was in a very poor state six months ago,&quot; maritime directorate official Odd Vollene told NTB. &quot;The check-up uncovered a lot of faults and shortcomings, much more than is normal.&quot;</p>
<p>It was the worst ship disaster off Norway for years.</p>
<p>In December 1995, 10 fishermen drowned when the Russian trawler Novgorodets sank in a storm off the Arctic province of Troms.</p>
<p>In October 1993, the Norwegian fishing boat Bordanes went down off the Arctic port of Hammerfest, killing nine seamen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
