<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365405" id="root" date="1997-02-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Police detain two protesters at Berlin G7 meeting.</title>
<headline>Police detain two protesters at Berlin G7 meeting.</headline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1997-02-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police detained two people on Saturday as 300 anarchists staged an anti-capitalist protest in Berlin outside a meeting of financial leaders from the world's seven most industrialised nations, the G7.</p>
<p>About 300 anarchists and punks donning rainbow-coloured hair and black ragged clothes marched through the centre of Berlin and stopped outside the Kronprinzenpalais (Crown Prince Palace), where the G7 meeting was taking place.</p>
<p>Some carried banners with anti-capitalist slogans, such as: &quot;They tread on corpses to give money to the rich&quot;. Scuffles broke out between protesters and police but noone was injured.</p>
<p>Police detained the two because they had broken a law requiring demonstrators to make themselves clearly identifiable. Police did not say how they were disguised, but some protesters had covered their heads with scarves.</p>
<p>The demonstration later broke up and a large contingent marched on to west Berlin to join an anti-nuclear protest there.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
