<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365568" id="root" date="1997-02-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: WEEK AHEAD-US supply, G7 meeting overhang markets.</title>
<headline>WEEK AHEAD-US supply, G7 meeting overhang markets.</headline>
<byline>Catherine Bremer</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. quarterly refunding and questions about the dollar's direction are likely to dominate financial markets in the coming week, analysts said.</p>
<p>First on the agenda will be the market's reaction to a Group of Seven (G7) meeting in Berlin on Saturday, where finance ministers and central bankers said major currency misalignments of nearly two years ago had been corrected.</p>
<p>Although there had been speculation before the meeting that the G7 might want to send the dollar lower, analysts said the market was likely to keep favouring the upside.  </p>
<p>&quot;They're not saying the dollar is over-extended and has to go down,&quot; said Graham McDevitt, senior analyst at Paribas Capital Markets in London.</p>
<p>In terms of scheduled events in the coming days, analysts said the sale of U.S. Treasury debt is likely to overshadow some of the various economic reports.</p>
<p>&quot;The main talking point will be the U.S. refunding,&quot; said David Hewitt, bond strategist at Tokyo Mitsubishi International. &quot;The feeling is that it should go fairly well.&quot;  </p>
<p>The U.S. Treasury last week said it would sell three-, 10- and 30-year Treasuries worth a total of $39.75 billion. Wall Street analysts had expected around $37.5 billion.</p>
<p>On Tuesday the Treasury auctions $17.75 billion of three-year notes, on Wednesday $12.0 billion of 10-year notes and on Thursday $10.0 billion of 30-year bonds.</p>
<p>Analysts said they expected aggressive bidding for the new issues, after U.S. payroll data on Friday calmed worries over inflationary pressure and caused Treasuries to rally.  </p>
<p>Hewitt said he expected Treasuries to go up rather than down after the auction, given an improvement in market tone.</p>
<p>&quot;The traditional response is that the market backs off ahead of (an auction) then goes running after it,&quot; said Dick Howard, senior economist at Julius Baer Investments.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a case of nerves ahead of supply then a rally when it's absorbed.&quot;</p>
<p>He said recent gains could be given up on Monday and early Tuesday if the market was seen as overbought. But after that short term cap, he expected a rally out of the auctions.  </p>
<p>Howard said U.S. producer price figues due Friday were not generally expected to hold any surprises. Retail sales figures could be more buoyant, he said, but the two together were likely to paint the now familiar picture of healthy growth but restrained inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;Friday's figures will certainly be positive for the supply,&quot; he said. &quot;There's nothing there to show that inflation is going to rear its ugly head.&quot;  </p>
<p>Economists surveyed by Reuters forecast January retail sales on Thursday will show a 0.7 percent increase,  while producer price growth is expected to be 0.3 percent in the month.</p>
<p>In Europe, Britain has one of the heaviest weeks in terms of data.</p>
<p>British producer price figures are due on Monday, followed by employment and earnings data on Wednesday and retail price figures on Thursday.</p>
<p>The jobs numbers will be closely scrutinised for any signs of wage pressures. Analysts expect the average earnings growth rate in December to hold at four percent while January unemployment is forecast to drop by 30,000.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Italian production figures are due on Thursday.</p>
<p>((--International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6320))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GSEVEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
