<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365672" id="root" date="1997-02-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ECUADOR: Chronology of Ecuador's political crisis.</title>
<headline>Chronology of Ecuador's political crisis.</headline>
<dateline>QUITO 1997-02-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following is a brief chronology of events in Ecuador's political crisis that led to the ouster of democratically elected President Abdala Bucaram.</p>
<p>Jan. 8 - The administration of President Abdala Bucaram launches austerity package, including stiff increases in electricity, gas and public transport.</p>
<p>Feb. 5 - First day of a 48-hour general strike to protest the government's austerity measures. Protesters calling for Bucaram's resignation clash with police near presidential palace.</p>
<p>Feb. 6 - Trade unions extend walkout indefinitely or until Bucaram is dismissed.</p>
<p>- Army troops clash with demonstrators outside the presidential place.</p>
<p>- Congress votes by 44-34 to oust Bucaram on grounds of mental incompetence, then swears in its leader Fabian Alarcon. Bucaram rejects the vote as &quot;judicial barbarity,&quot; suggesting bid to depose him was engineered by economic elite.</p>
<p>Feb. 7 - Vice President Rosalia Arteaga declares her own right to the presidency as Ecuador wakes up with three &quot;presidents.&quot;</p>
<p>- Defence minister declares state of emergency, which suspends the right to stage public demonstrations and other individual guarantees.</p>
<p>- One person killed, scores injured in disturbances outside presidential palace as up to 4,000 protesters move to take the palace by force.</p>
<p>- Bucaram leaves presidential palace to spend four-day carnival weekend in his home in the Pacific coast city of Guayaquil.</p>
<p>Feb. 8 - Defence Minister Gen. Victor Bayas announces his resignation.</p>
<p>- Bucaram says he would rather die than step down in disgrace.</p>
<p>- Leading regional army chief Gen. Jose Grijalva says the military is not taking orders from Bucaram &quot;since he is no longer in charge and was destituted by Congress.&quot;</p>
<p>Feb. 9 - Legislators and military leaders agree on a plan allowing Vice President Arteaga to take over as interim president for a few days until Congress passes new legislation to reappoint Alarcon as president until August 1998, following elections in May or June.</p>
<p>- Bucaram concedes defeat, saying he was deposed in a military-backed &quot;congressional coup&quot; but vows to make a political comeback.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="QUITO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ECUADOR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
