<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365750" id="root" date="1997-02-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila to finish talks with rebels by June.</title>
<headline>Manila to finish talks with rebels by June.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-02-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Government and communist rebel negotiators may complete their talks on ending a 28-year Marxist insurgency in the Philippines by June, President Fidel Ramos said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Ramos expressed hope in a statement that &quot;the momentum of talks ... would be sustained until a final peace settlement is attained&quot;.</p>
<p>Ramos issued the statement after a government panel and the National Democratic Front (NDF) on Saturday ended an eight-day meeting in the Dutch city of Utrecht, which is hosting the negotiations.</p>
<p>Many of the leaders of the NDF, a communist-led umbrella group of 13 leftist organisations, live in exile in the Netherlands.</p>
<p>Ramos said the government panel informed him the talks would resume in March &quot;with the end in view of targeting completion of the negotiations by June 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>During the February 1 to 8 talks in Utrecht, the two sides reached several preliminary agreements, including the mode for releasing leftist leader Danilo Borjal who is currently held in a Philippine prison, Ramos said.</p>
<p>They also agreed to set up four working committees to speed up the negotiations, he said.</p>
<p>More than 40,000 people have died in the insurgency war.</p>
<p>The government in June signed a peace accord with the mainstream Moro National Liberation Front (MNLF) ending a 24-year revolt for Moslem autonomy in the southern Philippines.</p>
<p>It is currently holding preliminary talks with the breakaway Moro Islamic Liberation Front (MILF) on a separate peace deal. The MILF is fighting for an Islamic state in the southern islands.</p>
<p>The government in October 1995 signed a peace deal with right-wing army rebels involved in six failed coup attempts from 1986 to 1989 against then president Corazon Aquino.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
