<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365797" id="root" date="1997-02-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel Treasury director-general to leave March 31.</title>
<headline>Israel Treasury director-general to leave March 31.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-02-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's Finance Ministry director-general David Brodet will be leaving his post March 31 to be replaced by an official at the country's lottery organisation.</p>
<p>Shmuel Slavin, Brodet's designated successor, was former prime minster Yitzhak Shamir's economics adviser and is an activist in the ruling Likud party. He has been a deputy managing director at Mifal Hapayis, the state lottery organisation, since 1994.</p>
<p>Brodet served in senior Treasury positions under two Likud governments and one Labour government. He had been budget director since 1991 and moved up to director-general in 1995.</p>
<p>He has refused to comment on his plans after leaving the Treasury.</p>
<p>As director-general, Brodet chaired a number of key committees, among them the panel that recommended forcing the commercial banks to reduce their stakes in non-bank companies. He also led the Israeli delegation to economic negotiations with the Palestinians as part of the Oslo peace accords.</p>
<p>Brodet presided at the Treasury as the government's deficit ballooned in 1996. But he stayed on to help achieve the 1997 budget cuts aimed at reining in overspending this year.</p>
<p>- Jerusalem newsroom, 972-2-537-0502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
