<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365779" id="root" date="1997-02-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Netanyahu urges end to Lebanon pullout debate.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu urges end to Lebanon pullout debate.</headline>
<byline>Howard Goller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-02-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu called on Sunday for an end to a growing public debate on a unilateral Israeli troop pullout from south Lebanon, saying the talk could encourage attacks on Israeli soldiers.</p>
<p>He made the appeal only hours after seven Israeli soldiers were wounded in a clash with pro-Iranian Hizbollah guerrillas in Israel's occupation zone. On Tuesday, 73 troops were killed in a collision of two helicopters heading there.</p>
<p>&quot;This talk, during days of mourning and emotional upheaval, might encourage the terrorists in Lebanon to step up their attacks on Israeli soldiers,&quot; said a statement issued by Netanyahu's spokesman.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime minister calls on all members of parliament and public officials to stop dealing at this time with the possibility of unilateral withdrawal from Lebanon,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>A group of Israeli lawmakers and veteran security men met on Saturday to formulate what one participant described as &quot;new thinking&quot; on Lebanon. They said they intended to present their ideas to Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai.</p>
<p>Netanyahu, who ruled out a one-sided pullout in a television interview on Friday, was not pleased.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not in Lebanon to rule it but to ensure security for Israel's northern settlements. As long as this aim obliges us to remain in Lebanon, that is the way we will continue to act.&quot;</p>
<p>The helicopter crash on Tuesday, the worst military air disaster in Israeli history, set the stage for renewed debate over the soldiers' destination: the anti-guerrilla occupation zone which Israel carved out in south Lebanon 12 years ago.</p>
<p>Netanyahu said on Friday a unilateral Israeli withdrawal from the 15 km (nine-mile)-wide occupation zone would bring Hizbollah &quot;terrorists&quot; closer to Israel's northern Galilee.</p>
<p>Israel, he said, would have to stabilise its northern border before it could leave and that would be difficult without agreement from Syria, Israel's arch-foe and the main power broker in Lebanon.</p>
<p>Netanyahu said in the television interview he would have pulled Israeli troops out of Lebanon if he believed there was a &quot;high probability&quot; that fighters from Hizbollah -- the Party of God -- would not deploy in the vacated areas.</p>
<p>The group that met to discuss options in Lebanon was led by former Shin Bet security service man Gideon Ezra, now a member of parliament from Netanyahu's ruling Likud. It included parliament members from four political parties, former generals and other former Shin Bet men.</p>
<p>&quot;We wanted to raise various ideas about the continuation of the process in Lebanon,&quot; Ezra told Israel Radio.</p>
<p>&quot;We are speaking of things that must be done from tomorrow morning,&quot; he told army radio in another interview.</p>
<p>None of the participants would go into specifics about the proposals. Ezra said they wanted to speak first to Mordechai.</p>
<p>Another participant, former West Bank settlers leader Yisrael Harel, said he believed it was time to come up with a new military-political initiative after years of stagnation in Lebanon that had been costly to Israel.</p>
<p>The soldiers were flying to avoid Hizbollah roadside bombs that have claimed the lives of dozens of Israelis. Nearly 200 soldiers have died fighting guerrillas in Lebanon since Israel set up the occupation zone in mid-1985.</p>
<p>&quot;Israeli army soldiers are working today in impossible conditions that don't add substantially to the peace of the Galilee in my assessment or their own personal security,&quot; Harel told army radio.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
