<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365885" id="root" date="1997-02-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Basques seek united voice amid escalating violence.</title>
<headline>Basques seek united voice amid escalating violence.</headline>
<byline>Tracey Ober</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-02-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Political leaders in Spain's troubled northern Basque region scrambled to rebuild a unified front on Sunday to combat escalating violence after a serious split last week appeared to derail peace efforts.</p>
<p>Basque Nationalist Party (PNV) leader Xabier Arzalluz, who last week unleashed a storm of Basque protests with a call for talks with separatist ETA rebels, promptly rowed back, saying dialogue was impossible while the group was still killing.</p>
<p>On January 30, a gunman shot and killed a bicycle vendor in an attack in San Sebastian that the government blamed on ETA.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't think a negotiation (with ETA) will be possible when there are deaths on the agenda,&quot; Arzalluz said in an opinion column published in the newspaper Deia on Sunday. &quot;But an initial phase of contacts and gestures is almost inevitable.&quot;</p>
<p>Arzalluz admitted that his party was divided with some viewpoints &quot;diametrically opposed&quot; on how to handle ETA (Basque Homeland and Freedom), which has killed some 800 people since starting a drive for independence in 1968.</p>
<p>Some members favour starting talks with the rebels without setting conditions, while others insist that ETA first give up its arms and call a truce.</p>
<p>Sixty percent of Spaniards polled in a survey published on Sunday said the government should not negotiate with ETA.</p>
<p>The separatist rebels had been relatively quiet in 1996 -- killing only five people, a record yearly low -- leading officials both in Madrid and the Basque region to express cautious optimism about the prospects for peace.</p>
<p>But street violence by groups of young people supporting ETA has risen dramatically in the past few months and officials said it has led to a climate of fear and intimidation.</p>
<p>&quot;The Basque people are living in a time of desperation, worry and pessimism such as they have never seen,&quot; Ramon Jauregui, the Socialist leader in the region, said.</p>
<p>&quot;Basque politicians are responding with division and confusion...The only possible response to this situation is with a great political pact for unity and with democratic conviction.&quot;</p>
<p>Police attempts at a crackdown have only worsened the violence, in which hooded gangs attack and burn property associated with symbols of authority.</p>
<p>Dozens of people were injured and property was damaged in protests and demonstrations scattered throughout the Basque region late on Saturday after an alleged ETA prisoner was found hanged in his cell.</p>
<p>An autopsy report revealed that the prisoner had been depressed for several weeks and had killed himself, but hundreds of Basques took to the streets claiming it was murder.</p>
<p>They carried banners and chanted slogans: &quot;The people will not forgive&quot; and &quot;Assassins, you have killed another prisoner&quot;.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, members of ETA's political arm Herri Batasuna (HB) called a news conference on Saturday to announce a fresh series of demonstrations and strikes to protest at the jailing of its leaders.</p>
<p>Five HB leaders were sent to prison last week for refusing to appear in Spain's Supreme Court to answer charges they promoted violence.</p>
<p>PNV spokesman Jose Antonio Ardanza, who is to meet conservative Prime Minister Jose Maria Aznar on Monday to discuss the central government's policy toward the region, said he would try to bring a message of unity to the encounter.</p>
<p>But Spain's interior minister doubted one could be found.</p>
<p>&quot;The PNV finds itself at a crossroads because it doesn't know what part to play in the peace process,&quot; the minister, Jaime Mayor Oreja, said in an interview published on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;The one thing I have no doubt about is that the conditions are not right now for a negotiated end to the violence.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
