<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365886" id="root" date="1997-02-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek farmers hold mass rally against police action.</title>
<headline>Greek farmers hold mass rally against police action.</headline>
<byline>Costas Paris</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-02-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Protesting Greek farmers held a mass rally in central Greece on Sunday against police action which immobilised their tractors, while top government ministers toured the area in an effort to ease tension.</p>
<p>Riot police units on Friday deflated the tyres of thousands of tractors lining the main north-south highway to prevent a fresh blockade. The farmers accused police of damaging the tractors, despite a denial by the government.</p>
<p>Some 5,000 farmers gathered outside the central village of Almyros and then headed towards the highway to continue repairs on the tractors.</p>
<p>&quot;They pulled off the radio from the dashboard. They cut electrical cables and threw sugar in the petrol tank to destroy the engine. They then slashed two tyres with knives,&quot; said onion grower Antonis Anagnostopoulos.</p>
<p>Other farmers showed reporters smashed windshields, headlights and cut ventilator belts.</p>
<p>They said they would sue the police and the government, but the public order ministry issued a statement saying police deflated the tractors' tyres and did nothing else.</p>
<p>The farmers, pushing for state subsidies and cheaper fuel and equipment, began a second round of protests last Tuesday after blocking national roads for 25 days in December.</p>
<p>They paraded on major roads with 2,000 tractors on Thursday after Prime Minister Costas Simitis refused to meet them and discuss their demands.</p>
<p>Simitis, determined to push through his tough economic policies, sent 5,000 police, many in riot gear, with orders to keep the roads open at all costs.</p>
<p>On Saturday he sent five of his top ministers on a tour of central Greece to meet residents and explain the government's policy on farming.</p>
<p>He has said the farmers' demands can't be met as they violate the European Union common agriculture policy, and that in any case the state budget can't spare a single drachma for any particular group.</p>
<p>The farmers said at Sunday's rally they would continue their protests but did not say how. Their leaders said the priority was to repair the tractors and pull them off the highway.</p>
<p>They have been inventive in eluding police during their protests, driving their tractors through vast cotton fields and across rivers to reach key points of the national highway.</p>
<p>But many of their tractors are now immobilised and the government hopes the protests will ease as farmers will have to return to their fields in two weeks for seasonal work.</p>
<p>The farmers are among a long list of groups protesting or striking against a 1997 budget described as the toughest in 15 years, and against strict incomes and tax policies.</p>
<p>Teachers are on strike for a  month while labour confederations have staged repeated walkouts against the government. Protest rallies clog traffic almost daily in the Greek capital.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
