<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="36583" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Dow-led Australian stocks end down but off lows.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Dow-led Australian stocks end down but off lows.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian shares ended mostly weaker on Friday, the market bruised by Thursday's nervous Dow ahead of the release of U.S. payroll data later today, although selective bargain hunting helped restrict the market's fall.</p>
<p>Major resources issues suffered the most after being hit by the triple whammy of the Dow dip, weaker base metals prices and a stronger Australian dollar</p>
<p>The key share barometer, the All Ordinaries index closed 20.4 points lower at 2,237.0, off its intra-day low of 2,232.9.</p>
<p>The September share price index futures ended 22 points down at 2,230 and at a seven point discount to the underlying index.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the kind of market that could bounce back very easily if U.S. payrolls is not as strong as feared,&quot; a dealer from a Sydney-based brokerage said.</p>
<p>The dealer pointed to a number of stocks that bucked the negative trend as indicating an underlying positive tone to the market as its nears the end of the reporting season.</p>
<p>&quot;Although earnings have been weaker, they generally have been at or above expectations which has pleased a number of investors I have spoken to,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>Stocks that found support today included transport groups TNT and Brambles, Comonwealth Bank and retailer Coles Myer.</p>
<p>The only major company to report today was property and financial services group Lend Lease Corp whose year net profit rose 7.7 percent to A$280 million (US$222 million)</p>
<p>The most speculative issues on the day were mining entrepreneur Joseph Gutnick's Centaur Mining and Exploration and gold and minerals explorer Forrestania Gold following its announcement of a promising nickel find on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
