<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365808" id="root" date="1997-02-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Universal plans blitz for Jurassic Park sequel.</title>
<headline>Universal plans blitz for Jurassic Park sequel.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES</dateline>
<text>
<p>Universal Studios, eager to cash in on the long-awaited sequel to &quot;Jurassic Park&quot;, will announce Monday a series of licensing agreements and promotional deals with a number of leading companies.</p>
<p>The announcement, which coincides with the start of the annual New York International Toy Fair, is aimed at building interest in the Steven Spielberg film &quot;The Lost World: Jurassic Park&quot; and tapping into the rich merchandise market for everything from toy dinosaurs to children's T-Rex underwear.</p>
<p>Judging by the windfall generated by the first film, which sold more than $1 billion in merchandise worldwide, Universal officials are optimistic about the sequel.</p>
<p>&quot;We are extremely excited about the program's strategic alliances,&quot; said Cynthia Cleveland, president of merchandising and licensing for Universal. &quot;This comprehensive licensing programme and its unique new products will reinvigorate the already record breaking Jurassic Park franchise.&quot;</p>
<p>To make sure Universal hits all of its target audiences, the studio formed partnerships with fast-food giant Burger King, toy-maker Tyco Toys Inc. and a variety of clothing companies. It also signed deals with cereal giant General Mills Inc., Tropicana, owned by Universal's parent company Seagram Co. Ltd. and Eastman Kodak Co..</p>
<p>The studio even signed a licensing pact with German auto giant Mercedes- Benz to coincide with the launch of the carmaker's new sport utility vehicle later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Jurassic Park&quot; is one of Hollywood's most successful movies, grossing more than $900 million at the box office and more than $1 billion in merchandise. The film, which used dazzling special effects to tell a story about what goes wrong when scientists try to bring dinosaurs back from extinction, triggered an instant demand for dinosaur products, clothing and books.</p>
<p>The sequel, directed by Spielberg, is scheduled for release on Memorial Day.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32840">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37330">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I49410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
