<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365816" id="root" date="1997-02-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Enthusiasm down, volatility up on Wall Street.</title>
<headline>Enthusiasm down, volatility up on Wall Street.</headline>
<byline>Andrej Gustincic</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>As a January employment report that drove stocks and bonds higher Friday fades into memory, Wall Street will embrace volatility and concerns about the dollar and its effect on 1997 corporate earnings.</p>
<p>Analysts said that bonds and the dollar will map out the course for stocks and that the equity market is likely to change directions many times in the coming weeks and make little progress overall.</p>
<p>The employment report showed non-farm payrolls grew by a higher-than-forecast 271,000 new jobs in January after December growth of 261,000 new jobs.</p>
<p>Analysts said that the figure may have been inflated due to seasonal factors. More importantly, average hourly earnings rose by a mere $0.01 after two consecutive months of much sharper increases.</p>
<p>The Dow industrials jumped 83 points Friday, closing at 6856, just 27 points under their all-time closing high. The Dow finished the week up 43 points.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt that the employment report was good and that it gave stocks and bonds an initial lift,&quot; said First Albany Corp. chief investment officer Hugh Johnson. &quot;But it is also clear that the euphoria from that report is fading and the market is going back to being worried about something.&quot;</p>
<p>Johnson said he believes the worries are about 1997 earnings. The dollar has become an important issue for investors, raising real concerns about the corporate profits, he said. A stronger dollar makes exports from U.S. companies more expensive and also shrinks their sales in dollar terms.</p>
<p>&quot;Multinationals are reporting losing business because of the strong dollar and we all know it will hurt earnings because of the translation profits,&quot; Johnson said.</p>
<p>The dollar hit new highs in Tokyo and Europe Friday but had retreated in Europe by the close of trading on some mild profit-taking before Saturday's Group of Seven meeting.</p>
<p>Johnson said that this strength would affect large capitalisation companies like International Business Machines Corp., Intel Corp. and Microsoft Corp.</p>
<p>Scott Bleier, chief investment strategist at Prime Charter Ltd, said the stock market had segued from being a momentum market to a trading range market.</p>
<p>&quot;A trading range market is subject to big volatile swings,&quot; he said. &quot;We have already stretched the upper boundaries of valuations and now the market has to digest its gains.&quot;</p>
<p>Bleier set the trading range between 6650 and 6850 on the Dow.</p>
<p>He said the market would continue to see &quot;rolling corrective activity&quot; such as the battering of the high techs throughout much of last week, this time probably affecting bank and drug stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;The banks and the drugs are due for some correcting. They have come up a long way and need to take a rest,&quot; he said. &quot;The oils have corrected, techs are correcting. The cyclicals corrected and are coming back.&quot;</p>
<p>Not everyone is quite so cautious.</p>
<p>Joseph Barthel, chief investment strategist at financial at Fahnestock &amp; Co, said that Friday's solid bond market could set the stage for even lower yields and a rally that will take the Dow Industrials to 7,000 in the next one or two weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't be surprised to see the long bond yield decline to 6.40 percent, and that will set the stage for the market to continue its advance,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we will go through 7,000, but I think we can reach it in the next week or two. We have a decent oversold condition, the bond market is in our favour and you can make a case for higher prices directly in front of us.&quot;</p>
<p>Data this week include Thursday's January retail sales, and Friday's producer price index, industrial production and capacity utilization for January.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
