<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365838" id="root" date="1997-02-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Financial services seen in global realignment.</title>
<headline>Financial services seen in global realignment.</headline>
<byline>Cal Mankowski</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The financial services industry is heading for a global realignment that is likely to be speeded up by the stunning news of the merger of Dean Witter Discover &amp; Co and Morgan Stanley Group Inc.</p>
<p>Navtej Nandra, a vice president at the global management consulting firm Booz Allen Hamilton, said one reason there has not been more cross-border consolidation may be that U.S. firms have found it easy to just ride the long-running bull market.  </p>
<p>&quot;Wall Street is historically not known for thinking five years out, and as long as the going was good they sat back and enjoyed life,&quot; Nandra said. &quot;I think this deal is going to be a call to arms.&quot;</p>
<p>The combination of Dean Witter's retail brokerage business with Morgan Stanley's global presence was among other things a recognition that small investors are looking for avenues to invest globally, analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;When something like this occurs it puts pressure on the more domestic U.S. firms to find alliances,&quot; said Eli Ofek, professor of corporate finance at New York University. He noted that stocks of several domestic firms jumped Wednesday after the Morgan Stanley-Dean Witter news on speculation that they would be the next merger targets.</p>
<p>Among the U.S. retail brokers considered by analysts to be potential acquisition candidates are PaineWebber Group Inc, the Prudential Securities unit of  Prudential Insurance Co of America, A.G. Edwards Inc and  Edward D. Jones &amp; Co.  </p>
<p>But there are questions about which foreign buyers, if any, would step forward for any of the U.S. brokers. &quot;I don't see any Japanese firms coming in here and buying U.S. firms per se,&quot; said Perrin Long, an independent securities analyst. &quot;I don't think they quite understand the retail side of the (U.S.) business.&quot;</p>
<p>Still, Gilbert Clark, senior vice president at Daiwa Securities America Inc, said there is recognition that the appetite for foreign securities is increasing in the U.S.  </p>
<p>Some of the more notable recent cross-border deals include Merrill Lynch and Co Inc's acquisition of U.K. firm Smith New Court, and Dutch banking giant ABN AMRO Holdings NV's purchase of Chicago Corp, a U.S. broker.</p>
<p>U.S. firms concentrating in the capital markets part of the business could also be swept up in cross-border consolidaton. Two possible candidates are Salomon Inc and Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc.  </p>
<p>Ofek noted that U.S. broker Smith Barney &amp; Co, part of the Travelers Group Inc insurance-financial services empire, has been shopping for investment firms to buy in Europe.</p>
<p>Long said one way in which Morgan Stanley and Dean Witter will benefit from the merger is through syndications of debt and equity. The firm can take a bigger share for its own clients thanks to the added distribution, and as a result collect more fees. Long said there will probably still be selling groups but the membership will be smaller.  </p>
<p>Scott Pardee, senior adviser, Yamiachi International (America) Inc, observed that international finance has opened up substatially in recent years. &quot;There are fewer exchange controls and capital controls,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Pardee noted that in the emerging markets the trend has been to raise money in the financial markets and not to seek government subsidies.</p>
<p>At the same time there has been an explosion of foreign companies seeking to list shares in the U.S.</p>
<p>&quot;The international financial arena is a busy place and will continue to be busy,&quot; Pardee said. &quot;The question is how to capture a leading share and be a survivor from the shakeout that is taking place.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
