<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365922" id="root" date="1997-02-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India needs $10 bln for deep water oil exploration.</title>
<headline>India needs $10 bln for deep water oil exploration.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-02-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>India will need $10.0 billion to develop its deep water oil and natural gas reserves, the chairman of state-run Oil and Natural Gas Corporation (ONGC) says.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on estimates, the exploration programme and development of identified structures may cost approximately $10.0 billion,&quot; ONGC chairman Bikash Bora told a seminar on deep water oil and gas exploration.</p>
<p>India could tap between five to nine billion tonnes of oil and oil-equivalent gas reserves, Bora said in a speech which was read out on Saturday by A.S. Soni, ONGC's director of operations.</p>
<p>He said ONGC had worked out the cost of developing economic field size ranging from 50 to 200 million barrels per day at water depths of 200 to 600 metres.</p>
<p>&quot;Considering the cost of oil at $20 per barrel, the rate of returns fall in the range of 19 to 30 percent, suggesting that deep water exploration programme is very much viable and commercially attractive,&quot; Soni said.</p>
<p>He said ONGC looked forward to oil firms from the United States, Britain, Norway and Brazil to contribute to development of India's deep water hydrocarbon resources.  </p>
<p>Between 20 to 35 percent of hydrocarbon potential in India is expected to be in deep waters beyond 200 metres, Soni said.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on the seismic and other available data which is not very exhaustive at the moment, resources of the order of five to nine billion tonnes of oil and oil equivalent gas are estimated in deep water areas between 200 to 2,000 metres.&quot;</p>
<p>ONGC, which accounts for almost 90 percent of India's oil and gas production, has taken up four locations for drilling, covering about 1.4 million square metres in the Arabian Sea and the Bay of Bengal, Soni told the conference.</p>
<p>ONGC has been increasingly looking to deep waters as India's indigenous oil production has been stagnating around 30 million tonnes a year and domestic demand growing by about eight percent.</p>
<p>Local crude accounts for less than half of India's petroleum product requirements.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
