<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="365916" id="root" date="1997-02-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Japan investors wake up to India but face barriers.</title>
<headline>Japan investors wake up to India but face barriers.</headline>
<byline>Narayanan Madhavan</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-02-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese investors led by powerful car makers have plunged into India's alluring market but face daunting challenges ahead, analysts said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Car makers were at the head of the pack as a delegation representing Japan's influential business association, Keidanren, descended on the Indian capital last week.</p>
<p>Japanese executives praised India's five-year-old economic reforms, a change in tack from two years ago when Keidanren complained about India's labour laws which they claimed prevent firms from closing loss-making plants.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the employment situation in India, I don't think this is an issue that can be easily resolved,&quot; said Keidanren director-general Masaya Miyoshi. &quot;I do not believe that this issue remains a big problem for potential Japanese investors.&quot;</p>
<p>But analysts said Japanese investors still have to cope with bureaucratic barriers and cumbersome legal procedures.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a need for elimination and relaxation of regulations so that we can enhance free competition,&quot; said Shoichiro Toyoda, chairman of Toyota Motor Corp</p>
<p>Japan is India's biggest aid donor but has lagged far behind Europe and the United States in foreign investment. Still, Japan appears to be warming up to the Indian market.</p>
<p>Some 135 Japanese firms displayed their wares on Saturday as Japan and India joined hands at the India Engineering Trade Fair in New Delhi.</p>
<p>On Friday, Honda Motor Corp announced the launch of its City model, while Toyota's Toyoda said he would meet India's Kirloskar group to consider a car venture.</p>
<p>But on the same day, Industry Minister Murasoli Maran said New Delhi would not allow Suzuki Motor to increase its 50 percent stake in car maker Maruti Udyog Ltd. The Indian government shares the rest of Maruti's equity.</p>
<p>Maruti holds 70 percent of the Indian car market, thanks to the Suzuki's foray into a sheltered market in the early 1980s.</p>
<p>But Suzuki is finding it difficult to impose its will on Maruti so it can compete in India with other big car makers including Ford Motor Co and General Motors Corp of the United States, South Korea's Daewoo Motor and France's Peugeot SA.</p>
<p>Analysts said Suzuki, which needs to expand to retain its market share, may be forced to borrow, increasing its costs, if it cannot expand its equity stake.</p>
<p>&quot;The (Indian) government is not in a position to pump in more equity,&quot; said analyst K.N. Sreenivasan of fund manager Jardine Fleming. &quot;The only option out is the debt route.&quot;</p>
<p>Since 1991, more than 70 Japanese firms have set up shop in India but the investment flow has been modest.</p>
<p>Actual Japanese investment in the 1995/96 period ended last March 31 stood at $61 million, down from $95 million in the previous year.</p>
<p>But Japan's interest in India has been growing. More than 100 Japanese trade delegations visited India between November 1995 and March 1996.</p>
<p>In 1995, India approved $436 million worth of Japanese investments, up sharply from $112 million in 1994. The amount of investment which is approved usually exceeds actual investment as some projects never materialise.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I31000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
