<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="36606" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hicks Muse to buy American Home food unit.</title>
<headline>Hicks Muse to buy American Home food unit.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hicks, Muse, Tate &amp; Furst Inc., a private investment firm, said Friday it has signed a definitive agreement to acquire the food business of American Home Products Corp. for about $1.3 billion.</p>
<p>The business, which will be renamed American Home Food Products, sells packaged convenience foods primarily in the United States, with projected sales of about $1 billion in 1996.</p>
<p>Its products include Chef Boyardee prepared pasta products, pizza mixes, and dinner kits; PAM cooking spray, Franklin Crunch 'n Munch glazed popcorn; Polaner fruit spreads and spices; Gulden's mustard; Ranch Style Brand beans; Dennison's chili; Luck's beans; Ro*Tel tomato and chilies products; Jiffy Pop popcorn; Maypo and Wheatena hot cereals; and G. Washington broth. It also has strong foodservice and private label businesses.</p>
<p>American Home Products will receive about $1.2 billion in cash and will retain 20 percent of the common stock of its food unit, Hicks Muse said.</p>
<p>&quot;Consistent with our proven approach of acquiring and building quality companies with exceptional management teams, this transaction provides a superb platform to execute a buy-and-build strategy in the branded food products business,&quot; said Michael J. Levitt, managing director of Hicks Muse.</p>
<p>Hicks Muse said Chase Securities Inc. and Bankers Trust Company will arrange financing for the transaction.</p>
<p>The transaction is subject to governmental approvals.</p>
<p>The acquisition is Hicks Muse's largest since the Dallas-based investment firm was formed in 1989. It will form a company with its food industry management affiliate, C. Dean Metropoulos &amp; Co., to make the acquisition.</p>
<p>Metropoulos manages three Hicks Muse portfolio companies, The Morningstar Group Inc.; Heritage Brands, Inc., which includes Campfire marshmallows and marshmallow crisp rice bars; and Ghirardelli Chocolate Co.</p>
<p>Over the past six years, Hicks Muse has completed, or currently has pending, more than 55 transactions worth more than $9 billion. The firm also has offices in New York City, St. Louis, and Mexico City.</p>
<p>American Home Products' stock rose 37.5 cents to $59.375 on the New York Stock Exchange at mid-morning.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
