<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="36600" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: First Union sets Keystone acquisition.</title>
<headline>First Union sets Keystone acquisition.</headline>
<dateline>CHARLOTTE, N.C. 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>First Union Corp. said Friday it agreed to acquire privately held Keystone Investments Inc. for about $186 million in stock.</p>
<p>First Union, which will also assume some $106 million of Keystone debt, said it was offering 2.9 million shares to acquire the Boston-based investment management and mutual fund company, which has $11.6 billion in assets under management.</p>
<p>Based on First Union's stock price of $64 late Friday, the shares to be issued are valued at about $185.6 million, the Charlotte, N.C.-based bank holding company said. First Union stock was up $1.125 at $64 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>First Union, which manages the Evergreen family of mutual funds, said its Keystone acquisition will create a mutual fund complex consisting of 69 individual funds with almost $27 billion in assets under management.</p>
<p>&quot;First Union is committed to building the premier money management organisation in America and the acquisition of Keystone will accelerate our strategy for growing mutual fund assets under management and building non-interest income for the corporation,&quot; First Union Executive Vice President Donald McMullen said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;This acquisition offers First Union new market opportunities, solid operating structure and a stronger family of mutual funds that will complement the existing Evergreen product line.&quot;</p>
<p>Keystone, one of the nation's oldest investment management firms, manages 33 retail, three institutional and nine foreign mutual fund portfolios, with equity and fixed income funds accounting for more than 96 percent of assets under management.</p>
<p>It has a distribution system of some 27,000 brokers and more than 3,500 broker/dealers in the United States as well as a significant global distribution network. It currently ranks as the top foreign mutual fund manager in Japan, based on mutual fund assets under management.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an extremely attractive fit for both institutions,&quot; Keystone Chairman Albert Elfner said. &quot;Keystone will gain access to First Union's substantial retail network while the Evergreen funds will benefit from our well-established broker/dealer relationships throughout the country and the world.&quot;</p>
<p>Following the acquisition, Elfner will remain president, chairman and chief executive officer of Keystone Investments, reporting to McMullen.</p>
<p>William Ennis, president of Evergreen Investment Services, will become president of distribution for Keystone and Evergreen Investment Services and assume responsibility for distribution, service, sales, marketing and fund administration for both organisations.</p>
<p>With the acquisition, First Union said, it will become the nation's third-largest bank-advised mutual fund organisation, the second-largest bank manager of equity mutual fund assets, and the 27th-largest mutual fund manager, based on mutual fund assets under management.</p>
<p>First Union said the acquisition, scheduled to close in late 1996 or early 1997, is expected to add to earnings by 1998. Closing is subject to approval by Keystone shareholders and regulatory officials as well as other conditions, First Union said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHARLOTTE, N.C."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
