<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="366014" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wolff ups copper price forecast but still bearish.</title>
<headline>Wolff ups copper price forecast but still bearish.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Copper has been unexpectedly strong in recent months, causing an upward revision in the price forecast, although the longer-term outlook remains bearish, London Metal Exchange (LME) broker Rudolf Wolff said.</p>
<p>In a presentation here Wolff analyst William Adams said stocks are low, so upside spikes cannot be ruled out, although the market is swinging into a supply surplus, and prices will fall and the backwardation return to a contango.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the unexpected strength of copper in the last few months we would revise up our forecast price for 1997 from $1,750/tonne, which we made in October 1996, to around $1,900/tonne,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At present, stocks are low at around 3.3 weeks of consumption, which is well below the 4.5 to five weeks supply traders view as a critical level to maintain.</p>
<p>&quot;Historically with stocks this low, it would not be surprising to see prices anywhere between $2,500 and $3,000,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But if such a move happened it would be short-lived, and seen as an ideal time for producers to hedge forward sales.</p>
<p>Copper's scenario in coming years is bearish, because supply is set to overtake demand. Mine production is forecast rising by around 160,000 tonnes in 1997 and 325,000 tonnes in 1998.</p>
<p>Also, solvent-extraction electrowon (SX-EW) output is seen rising by 300,000 tonnes this year and 460,000 tonnes in 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;Western supply is therefore expected to rise by 570,000 tonnes in 1997 and 550,000 tonnes in 1998. This would require demand to rise by over five percent in both years, which seems unlikely,&quot; Adams added.</p>
<p>To some extent the effect of the surplus will be lessened by falling net exports to the West from the former Eastern countries.</p>
<p>Chinese imports of refined copper will rise, and new legislation controlling scrap will cut the amount of scrap being imported into China.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, internal consumption should stabilise and start to recover in the former Soviet Union, so net exports to the West should fall.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the outlook for consumption is extremely good, as there are many new applications that use copper.</p>
<p>&quot;If you imagine all the copper needed for electrification of towns and cities in the developing world, plus all the potential demand for consumer goods, then the outlook can only be strong,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But the problem that copper faces is on the production side, and when the price declines trading activity and volumes will fall as well.</p>
<p>&quot;The copper price is then likely to suffer a few years of subdued sideways trading in a band $100 either side of $1,700 a tonne or around 77 cents/lb,&quot; Adams said.</p>
<p>((--Martin Hayes, New York Commodities 212-859-1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
