<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="366046" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Marvel bondholder hearing continued.</title>
<headline>Marvel bondholder hearing continued.</headline>
<dateline>WILLMINGTON, Del. 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Helen Balick said she would not decide on Monday whether to allow bondholders of Marvel Entertainment Group Inc's parent company to foreclose on the common stock that collateralizes their bonds.</p>
<p>After opening arguements and some testimony from Marvel and the bondholders, Balick said she would continue the hearing on Feburary 25, when she expected testimony to be completed.  </p>
<p>Bondholders, led by investor Carl Icahn, have asked Balick to lift an automatic stay that shields debtors under Chapter 11 protection from the claims of creditors until the debtors reorganize. Lifting the automatic stay would allow bondholders to foreclose on shares of common stock.</p>
<p>The bondholders object to a restructuring proposed by Perelman that would dilute the common stock of Marvel Entertainment which collateralizes their bonds from 78.8 percent to 17.2 percent. The bonds have a face value of $558.5 million and a maturity value of $894.1 million.</p>
<p>Court papers filed by the bondholders allege the reorganization plan is &quot;an inside deal rammed through without consideration of any other alternatives that severely dilutes ... collateral ... (with) a loss of mammoth proportions.&quot;</p>
<p>At Monday's hearing, Marvel said it would be irreparably harmed if the automatic stay were lifted allowing bondholders to foreclose on the Marvel stock.</p>
<p>The bondholders &quot;have not established cause to justify the draconian effects that would result from a modification of the automatic stay&quot; and the interests of other creditors &quot;should not be sacrificed to parochial demands of distressed debt traders,&quot; according to court papers filed by Marvel.</p>
<p>Balick has set March 7 for a hearing on whether Perelman's reorganization plan should be confirmed.</p>
<p>The reorganization plan is based on a series of interdependent deals which begin with an infusion of $365 million from Perelman's wholly-owned Andrews Group Inc.  The money would be earmarked to buy the Toy Biz Inc stock not already owned by Marvel.</p>
<p>Marvel Entertainment Group and several affiliates filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy on December 27.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I49410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WILLMINGTON, Del."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
