<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="366010" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. toy sales grew 3.6 pct in 1996-trade group.</title>
<headline>U.S. toy sales grew 3.6 pct in 1996-trade group.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The toy industry experienced one of its worst holiday shopping seasons in a decade this past year, but sales still grew about 3.6 percent, the industry group Toy Manufacturers of America said Monday.</p>
<p>American toy sales increased to $20.7 billion retail, the trade group said at a news conference opening the 94th annual American International Toy Fair.</p>
<p>A similar increase among the industry was posted in 1995. And the industry is projecting about the same increase for the 1997 season, said David Miller, president of the Toy Manufacturers of America.  </p>
<p>A year marked by &quot;overall modest growth&quot; was helped in part by sales from Tyco Toys Inc's Tickle Me Elmo, said George Volanakis, the president and chief executive of Ertl Co Inc and chairman of the Toy Manufacturers of America.</p>
<p>&quot;The public and the media went crazy over Elmo, which helped generate a burst of excitement for the toy industry during the holiday season,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>About one million units of Tickle Me Elmo were sold last year. So far, an additional 600,000 units have been shipped out this year, Tyco U.S. President Michael Lyden said.</p>
<p>The best-selling toys last year were dolls, vehicles and plush toys, which each increased by more than eight percent, the industry group said.</p>
<p>Top performers last year included Barbie Pet Doctor, Melanie's Mall, Easy Bake Oven Snack Center, Take Care of Me Twins and Space Jam Tune Squad.</p>
<p>Toy manufacturers and retails have described this past holiday season as one of the industry's worst, in part because the shopping season was about a week shorter than usual.</p>
<p>((-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I49410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
