<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="366193" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ecuador debt continues strong in N.Y. session.</title>
<headline>Ecuador debt continues strong in N.Y. session.</headline>
<byline>Nancy Leinfuss</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ecuadorean Brady bonds added to recent gains in New York trade on Monday, advancing on news of the appointment of interim president Rosalia Arteaga over the weekend.</p>
<p>President Abdala Bucaram -- popularly known as &quot;El Loco,&quot; or &quot;madman,&quot; for his sometimes bizarre behavior -- was voted out of office last Thursday night on grounds of mental incompetence by Ecuador's congress but refused to step down.</p>
<p>Bucaram, in power for only six months, finally conceded on Sunday and stepped down from the presidency.  </p>
<p>Ecuador debt spiraled upward, Ecuador's PDIs  ECPDI=RR gaining 2-7/8 points to trade at 61-1/4 following Friday's close at 58-3/8. PDI bonds had tumbled to a low of 58 bid last week.</p>
<p>Ecuador's discount bonds  ECDISC=RR were also up 1-1/2 points on the news, trading at a 69 bid, off Friday's lows of 66-1/2 bid.</p>
<p>Traders said recent political and social unrest in Ecuador had taken a toll on the country's debt.</p>
<p>&quot;The bonds bounced on renewed optimism behind this new presidential fill-in,&quot; said one Brady trader.  </p>
<p>&quot;More importantly than the person (Arteaga), is the fact that the situation was immediatly addressed over the weekend bringing some sort of order,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Last week, unions and opposition groups held a general strike to demand Bucaram's resignation and protest the government's austerity policies.</p>
<p>Other players said the news triggerd more buying, sending volume higher.</p>
<p>&quot;We did see some shortcovering and we did have some better buyers with volume at more substantial levels than in previous weeks,&quot; another debt trader said.  </p>
<p>Analysts said, however, that despite news of Bucaram's ouster and the appointment of an interim president, a more permanent longer-term solution is needed.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's taking this surprisingly optimistically but the governemental situation is still in a holding pattern and while this is a good interim solution, we still don't know what it means longer-term,&quot; said Richard Segal, head of fixed income research at Santander Investments.</p>
<p>&quot;A key issue for the financial markets is whether the Eurobond that was mandated not too long ago goes through,&quot; Segal added.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Eurobond is required to pay back some bridge financing and if the financing doesn't come through then they're going to need to repay it somehow,&quot; Segal said. &quot;If they've already used the money they've raised it could be quite difficult.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said the crisis spells bad news for the Ecuadorean economy, noting that it may cost the country a half-percentage point in its Gross Domestic Product (GDP) growth for this year or thereabouts.</p>
<p>&quot;Not only is that bearish, but it implies that the budget situation is going to be that much more tough,&quot; Segal said.  </p>
<p>Recent tax hikes were designed to bring the budget back into balance, Segal said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, congress is expected to meet on Tuesday to pass legislation allowing it to reappoint its leader, Fabian Alarcon, as president, with Arteaga assuming her original role as vice president.</p>
<p>Alarcon would serve as interim head of state until August 10, 1998, then hand over power to a new president to be chosen in general elections to be held in May or June next year.</p>
<p>Analysts said Arteaga was seen as a weak vice president, while Alarcon has been viewed as a much stronger candidate with better name recognition.</p>
<p>Ecuador's financial markets were closed on Monday in observance of the Carnival holiday.</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1660 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
