<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="366239" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: TENNIS-MOYA GIVES SPAIN DAVIS CUP VICTORY OVER GERMANY.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-MOYA GIVES SPAIN DAVIS CUP VICTORY OVER GERMANY.</headline>
<byline>John Mehaffey</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Open finalist Carlos Moya cruised to a straight-sets victory over Hendrik Dreekman on Sunday to give Spain an unbeatable 3-1 lead over 1993 champions Germany in their Davis Cup world group first round match.</p>
<p>Moya broke Dreekman's serve in the opening games of the first two sets to win 6-4 6-4 7-5 on clay in Mallorca.</p>
<p>Jim Courier overcame a spirited challenge from Gustavo Kuerten to give 1995 champions United States a decisive 3-1 lead over Brazil in Ribeirao, winning 6-3 6-2 5-7 7-6. Alex O'Brien won the final singles against Fernando Meligeni.</p>
<p>Kuerten, ranked 60 places below Courier, saved four match points in the fourth set when the American twice volleyed into the net.</p>
<p>But Courier, who needed treatment for dehydration afterwards, held on to wrap up an awkward tie against a team who had not been beaten at home for 10 years.</p>
<p>Courier later made light of the noisy crowd, an informal samba band and a light aircraft which zoomed low over the arena during the first set.</p>
<p>&quot;The crowd are very supportive of their team,&quot; he said</p>
<p>&quot;I like the drum section, the horns are a bit much, a bit loud on the ears, but my favourite was the guy who flew the plane over the court. I'd like to meet him.&quot;</p>
<p>Sweden, runners-up to France in last year's final and now without the retired Stefan Edberg, crushed Switzerland 4-1 in Lulea, Sweden, to book a quarter-final against South Africa in April.</p>
<p>Thomas Enqvist clinched the rubber with a 6-3 6-2 3-6 6-2 win over Marc Rosset who was clearly feeling the effects of 10 hard sets over the previous two days.</p>
<p>&quot;We are eager to bring the Cup to Sweden,&quot; said team captain Carl-Axel Hageskog. &quot;With the team spirit and the very good players I have, I think it's possible. We have to go for it.&quot;</p>
<p>France were ousted from the Cup on Saturday by Australia, who completed the formality of a 4-1 win on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Netherlands, trailing 2-0 after the opening singles, completed a remarkable comeback by beating Romania in Bucharest.</p>
<p>Paul Haarhuis clinched the tie by beating Andrei Pavel 6-3 6-1 6-2 after team mate Jan Siemerink defeated Adrian Voinea 7-6 5-7 6-7 7-6 6-4.</p>
<p>&quot;It was like winning the lottery,&quot; Siemerink remarked.</p>
<p>In Durban, South African doubles pair Ellis Ferreira and Grant Stafford defeated Russia's Andrei Olhovsky and Andrei Cherkasov 6-2 3-6 6-0 6-2 in a match carried over from Saturday to secure their quarter-final spot.</p>
<p>&quot;We were expected to win but the first three matches were all tough,&quot; said South African captain Danie Visser. &quot;This victory is very satisfying.&quot;</p>
<p>Jiri Novak sealed a 3-2 victory for the Czech Republic over India with an easy 6-1 6-4 6-3 after the Czech number one Petr Korda had levelled the tie in his final Davis Cup appearance.</p>
<p>Korda defeated Leander Paes 5-7 6-3 6-4 6-1 then announced he was retiring from Davis Cup tennis.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a very tiring, draining experience and I think you should leave at the top,&quot; Korda said. &quot;Now is the right time.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
