<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="366395" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Trial gives insight into soccer lifestyle.</title>
<headline>Trial gives insight into soccer lifestyle.</headline>
<byline>Helen Smith</byline>
<dateline>WINCHESTER, England 1996-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Wimbledon goalkeeper Hans Segers, on trial on match-rigging charges, has given an intriguing insight into the lifestyle of a soccer player.</p>
<p>Segers told on Monday of a life of extra-marital affairs, tax dodging and financial deals although he denies that he accepted bribes to throw matches in England's premier league.</p>
<p>He said he had told police a concocted tale that he made money from stealing and selling luxury cars, rather than have them discover he had been forecasting the outcome of soccer matches.</p>
<p>Although match-forecasting is not illegal, it contravenes English Football Association rules and the Dutchman said he feared being suspended.</p>
<p>&quot;To come to play football in England was a dream come true and to put that in jeopardy...&quot; Segers, 35, said.</p>
<p>Segers is on trial for match-rigging along with former Liverpool goalie Bruce Grobbelaar, former Aston Villa striker John Fashanu and a Malaysian businessman, Heng Suan Lim.</p>
<p>All deny the charges and say that they were merely forecasting the outcome of games for a group of wealthy Asian gamblers.</p>
<p>Segers said he had declined the offer to have a lawyer present when police interviewed him after his arrest last year, leaving his lawyer in court to unravel what he described as the &quot;absolute rubbish&quot; he had told police.</p>
<p>He said he had denied to police that he knew Fashanu well, even though Fashanu was Wimbledon's team captain when Segers was vice captain.</p>
<p>But Segers said he and Fashanu had been in constant telephone contact because they were covering for one another's extra-marital affairs and he didn't want his wife to find out about his infidelity.</p>
<p>Segers' wife already knew of an earlier affair and he feared he would lose his family. He has a daughter aged 11 and a son aged eight.</p>
<p>&quot;I was booked (after the previous affair),&quot; Segers said. &quot;We managed to scrape through though and hang in there,&quot; he added, sounding, as on many occasions during his evidence, as if he were describing a soccer match.</p>
<p>Like other top class footballers, Segers earned a huge amount from his club. As well as his 1,000 pounds ($1,634) a week wages, he got an annual 30,000 pound signing-on fee and a 50,000 pound annual loyalty bonus.</p>
<p>Segers branched out into a business venture, manufacturing ties and scarves with a fellow Dutchman, and he said he was engaged in property speculation with Fashanu.</p>
<p>Segers said Fashanu, himself an extremely wealthy businessman, had introduced him to a bank where he could open a tax-evading Swiss account.</p>
<p>But the 100,000 pounds he paid in were the proceeds of his business ventures, not, as the prosecution alleges, bribes for throwing matches.</p>
<p>Fearing he would be caught for tax evasion, Segers had told police that the money in his Swiss account had been transferred from Jersey, another tax haven. But he decided to reveal all to the court to try to save himself a maximum seven-year prison sentence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINCHESTER, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
