<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="366510" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: Zambian reporter denies contempt in electoral case.</title>
<headline>Zambian reporter denies contempt in electoral case.</headline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Zambian supreme court on Monday charged a reporter on an independent daily with contempt in a case in which four opposition parties are challenging the outcome of the country's general elections last year.</p>
<p>Masausto Phiri, editor of special projects on The Post, appeared before the court to answer charges resulting from a report in which he alleged that seven Supreme Court judges had been bribed by the state to rule in favour of the ruling Movement for Multiparty Democracy (MMD).</p>
<p>In his report Phiri alleged that the government would give the judges a total of 14 billion kwacha ($10.6 million) to dismiss election petitions.</p>
<p>Four opposition parties are challenging the legitimacy of the elections, which they claim was rigged by the MMD by manipulating the voters register.</p>
<p>They are also challenging President Frederick Chiluba's credentials, and claim that he lied about his nationality and parentage in filing his electoral nomination papers.</p>
<p>Seven opposition parties boycotted the elections that were won in landslide by Chiluba last November.</p>
<p>Phiri denied on Monday that he had deliberately libelled the judges.</p>
<p>&quot;What I wrote was not intended to demean or ridicule this court,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The court is scheduled to rule on his case on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Chiluba could face up to seven years imprisonment if the court rules against him. $1 = 1,320 kwacha.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
