<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="366515" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African political killings drop to year low.</title>
<headline>S.African political killings drop to year low.</headline>
<dateline>DURBAN, South Africa 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The number of South Africans killed in political violence dropped to its lowest level in a year, the independent Human Rights Committee said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Fifty-seven people were killed in political violence (in January), the lowest monthly total since January 1996,&quot; the HRC said in its monthly report. The previous lowest figure was 55.</p>
<p>The 18 politically related killings in the volatile KwaZulu-Natal province, which is home to nine million Zulus, had dropped far below the provincial monthly average of 41, the report said.</p>
<p>The HRC attributed the drop to a heavy security presence in the Indian Ocean coastal province, concerted probes into political massacres and a fragile peace agreement between President Nelson Mandela's African National Congress and the Zulu-based Inkatha Freedom Party.</p>
<p>Fighting in the multi-billion dollar taxi industry accounted for 15 of the 57 deaths, the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;This marks a decrease for the fourth consecutive month,&quot; the HRC said. It warned the drop could be a temporary lull in an industry where drivers and owners fight for limited routes and passengers.</p>
<p>Two people were killed in northern KwaZulu-Natal on Monday when rival groups armed with AK-47 semi-automatic assault rifles and handguns attacked each other at a taxi rank in Kranskop, police said.</p>
<p>One of those killed was believed to be an innocent bystander, the police said.</p>
<p>The HRC figures show 981 people were killed in political violence across South Africa last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DURBAN, South Africa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
