<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="366634" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croat Eurobond paves way for munis, corporates.</title>
<headline>Croat Eurobond paves way for munis, corporates.</headline>
<byline>Kolumbina Bencevic</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatia said on Monday its first $300 million five-year Eurobond, launched last week, had paved the way for direct foreign investment and new debt issues to finance the country's post-war development.</p>
<p>&quot;It was very important for the debut to be successful. But now we know that we can easily borrow money at favourable terms and where we can borrow it when there is a need,&quot; Deputy Prime Miniser Borislav Skegro told a news conference.</p>
<p>Some 50 percent of the maiden Eurobond issue was sold to European institutional investors, 35 percent to Americans and 15 percent to Asian investors, officials said.</p>
<p>They put the amount raised at roughly one third of the country's planned gross foreign borrowing this year. It will fund investment like rebuilding of war-damaged infrastructure and help pay back part of the matured sovereign debt.</p>
<p>The interest among investors was said to be very strong, allowing Croatia to tighten the spread of 80 basis points above U.S. treasuries, if it wanted to.</p>
<p>The bonds were rated BBB- by Standard and Poors. They pay a seven-percent annual interest and mature on February 27, 2002.</p>
<p>Another Eurobond issue, probably denominated in German marks, is due later this year. But government officials declined to give any time frame just yet.</p>
<p>They also hoped to launch longer maturities from now on.</p>
<p>Croatia is toying with the idea of refinancing part of the debt incurred at higher prices before getting the investment grade rating, said Finance Minister Bozo Prka.</p>
<p>He said the seven percent paid on Eurodollar would provide a benchmark for other Croatian issuers, government and private.</p>
<p>&quot;This will enable units of local administration to borrow (money) for capital investment projects,&quot; Prka said.</p>
<p>He mentioned among other likely candidates corporations buying new equipment or seeking to expand their production capacities.</p>
<p>Internationally arranged deals involving state-owned shipyards were already said to be in the making.</p>
<p>The government would no longer guarantee any more corporate loans at rates exceeding the benchmark, Prka added.</p>
<p>&quot;In this way the sovereign exposure will be reduced and other borrowers will be able to get financing at more favourable terms.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Croatia would open a tender for an international consultant to help it manage the public debt and slash budget costs. The 1997 budget gap is estimated at 2.8 billion kuna ($474 million) or 2.5 percent of gross domestic product (GDP).</p>
<p>The country has significantly reduced the internal debt inherited from the former Yugoslavia, and has got favourable rescheduling terms for liabilities to foreign creditors.</p>
<p>Its foreign debt now stands at a relatively low 26 percent of GDP, leaving room for future borrowing to prop up the economic recovery and open new jobs.</p>
<p>Unemployment ran at just under 16 percent in 1996.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
