<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="366665" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: German and two Russians blast off to Mir.</title>
<headline>German and two Russians blast off to Mir.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two Russians and a German cosmonaut blasted off for Russia's Mir space station at 5.09 p.m. (1409 GMT) on Monday, a spokeswoman for mission control in Kaliningrad outside Moscow said.</p>
<p>The spokeswoman said the launch, from the Baikonur cosmodrome in Kazakhstan, was successful.  </p>
<p>German cosmonaut Reinhold Ewald, 40, is due to stay aboard Mir for 20 days before returning to Earth with the station's current crew, Valery Korzun and Alexander Koleri. The two have been aboard the station for the last six months.</p>
<p>Russians Vasily Tsibliyev, 42, and Alexander Lazutkin, 39, are scheduled to remain in space along with U.S. astronaut Jerry Linenger, who began to work at the station on January 15. They are due to return to Earth in June.</p>
<p>Ewald is flying under an agreement between Germany and Russia in which Germany will pay millions of dollars for the ride -- a welcome fillip for the cash-strapped Russian space programme.</p>
<p>Funding problems have delayed several missions in recent months, forcing cosmonauts to stay aboard Mir longer than planned. Russia has nevertheless promised to go ahead with its contribution to the next generation Alpha space station.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
