<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="366706" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Handlowy maintains Mostostal W &quot;buy&quot;.</title>
<headline>Handlowy maintains Mostostal W &quot;buy&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The brokerage unit of Poland's Bank Handlowy SA has kept its January 1996 buy rating for Polish construction firm Mostostal Warszawa SA, which has managed good cost control in segments with good prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;The company achieves a higher net sales profitability than the sector due to better cost controls, the realisation of orders with a high degree of complexity as well as high quality services,&quot; the report dated January 10 said.</p>
<p>On that day Mostostal Warsawa closed at 18 zlotys. It closed at 22.2 zlotys on Friday.</p>
<p>Handlowy said Mostostal would also continue to benefit from the development prospects of the construction services market in which it operates and its realised investment programme.</p>
<p>Handlowy sees Mostostal investing a total of 33 million zlotys from 1996 to 1998.</p>
<p>It said another good sign was that Mostostal was increasing its share of projects in which it acts as general contractor.</p>
<p>Handlowy estimated that Mostostal would lift net profit to 4.1 million zlotys in 1996 and 5.6 million zlotys in 1997 from 2.7 million zlotys in 1998.</p>
<p>It said sales would increase to 107 million zlotys in 1996 and 155 million in 1997 from 90.9 million in 1995.</p>
<p>Preliminary results show that Mostostal netted 4.4 million zlotys in 1996 on 114.4 million zlotys in sales.</p>
<p>Handlowy saw Mostostal's price-earnings ratio dropping to 19.3 based on forecast 1997 earnings from 26.3 at the time of the report.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
