<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="366842" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: FEATURE - Brazilian president lives up to princely nickname.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Brazilian president lives up to princely nickname.</headline>
<byline>William Schomberg</byline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian President Fernando Henrique Cardoso is living up to his new nickname, The Prince.</p>
<p>Shortly after the Chamber of Deputies approved a constitutional amendment that reverses a founding tenet of the 1889 republic by allowing re-election, Cardoso took up temporary residence in the summer palace of the country's former emperors.</p>
<p>Cartoonists rose to the bait, bedecking the president in ermine robes and surrounding him with fawning courtiers, a reminder of how sensitive this country still is to the prospect of perpetual power once enjoyed by the Portuguese colonists.</p>
<p>&quot;People joke about Cardoso becoming Emperor Fernando I,&quot; said politics professor Alexandre Barros. &quot;But what's really important here is that his government has proven once and for all that it is a strong one.&quot;</p>
<p>Cardoso pulled off the biggest victory of his two years in office in late January when the Chamber of Deputies approved a constitutional amendment allowing sitting presidents, state governors and mayors to run for a second, consecutive term.</p>
<p>Not even opposition leaders believe Congress will reject the re-election bill in further voting in either the Chamber of Deputies or the Senate. And, as long as his popular inflation-slashing policies stay on track, everyone thinks Cardoso has next year's presidential race in the bag.</p>
<p>&quot;People will say everything I do is for re-election,&quot; the president told a crowd of cheering dockworkers at a port modernisation ceremony in Rio.</p>
<p>&quot;Well, let's do more for re-election! And after that there'll be someone who can carry on. Let's hope there is, so I can have a rest.&quot; The following day, newspapers declared the presidential race on.</p>
<p>THE PRINCE EMBOLDENED</p>
<p>Typically, a Brazilian president's power begins to wane once he is halfway through his four-year term as would-be successors emerge from the shadows, jostling for power.</p>
<p>By way of contrast, Cardoso, in his first two years, tamed Brazil's once rampant inflation but roundly failed to overcome entrenched resistance to reforms of the pensions and tax systems and the civil service. They are vital to the long-term success of Brazil's economic plan, but none has so far passed Congress.</p>
<p>Congress in 1995 approved reforms opening up Brazil's energy and telecommunications monopolies to private capital, but the government has dithered in drawing up enabling legislation that would actually put the changes into effect.</p>
<p>&quot;This government has been decisive on the macro level, but has hesitated on the details,&quot; politics professor Barros said. &quot;Now Cardoso's got a golden opportunity to stop trying to please everyone and to assume leadership.&quot;</p>
<p>LAWMAKERS FLOCK TO CARDOSO'S SIDE</p>
<p>The prospect of Cardoso retaining his grip on the budget and the choicest government jobs for another six years, as opposed to the two left in his current term, is an attractive one for lawmakers who are now expected to rally around the president.</p>
<p>The day after the Chamber of Deputies gave re-election its first approval, three deputies joined Cardoso's Brazilian Social Democratic Party (PSDB).</p>
<p>It remains only the fourth largest in Congress, forcing the president to rely on the support of several unpredictable allies in Congress. But the PSDB is expected to grow fast.</p>
<p>&quot;There's going to be an avalanche of deputies heading the PSDB's way. They'll be the biggest party in Congress by March or April,&quot; said Senator Pedro Simon from the rival Brazilian Democratic Movement Party (PMDB).</p>
<p>Cardoso humiliated opponents in Congress by snatching re-election votes from within the parties they considered their own personal fiefdoms, leaving them isolated and reluctant to risk running against the president next year.</p>
<p>Communications Minister Sergio Motta, considered the loose cannon in the cabinet for his aggressive style, boasted the PSDB was building a dynasty that would last 30 years.</p>
<p>But PSDB officials insisted they will be selective when admitting new members to the party. They do not want to start a divisive power battle in Congress just as the government prepares to resume its reform drive.</p>
<p>&quot;We want our party to grow via the ballot box and not at the expense of our allies,&quot; said PSDB president Teotonio Vilela.</p>
<p>OPPOSITION TO REFORMS STILL LIKELY</p>
<p>In a first sign it still faced opposition to its reforms, the government proposed exempting lawmakers from a $10,300 ceiling on monthly pay and benefits included in its civil service reform.</p>
<p>The Chamber of Deputies, which was due to vote on the bill, had been up in arms about the ceiling which would have denied members income from special pensions awarded after short spells in the civil service.</p>
<p>In the Senate, the government has to persuade senators to approve an unpopular pension reform bill that mainly seeks to end public sector pension perks, just when many of them were preparing to run as state governors in next year's elections.</p>
<p>Financial analysts, frustrated by the snail's pace of reform in Brazil, were sceptical about how much Cardoso might acheive in his remaining two years in power.</p>
<p>&quot;Cardoso will definitely have some momentum now. But how much? This is not going to solve all the reform problems,&quot; said Gene Frieda, an analyst with New York consultants I.D.E.A.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
