<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="367077" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MSRB reaches no decision on new underwriting rules.</title>
<headline>MSRB reaches no decision on new underwriting rules.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board reached no decisions at its quarterly meeting in Hawaii last week on how or whether to tighten regulation of bond underwriting, including deals involving swaps and other &quot;collateral&quot; transactions, the board's chairman said.</p>
<p>&quot;We came to (no decisions) that I can announce at this time,&quot; Roger Hayes said in a telephone press conference. &quot;The staff has a number of things to look into and get back to us on at the May board meeting. We may have a position to announce after that meeting.&quot;  </p>
<p>In addition, said Hayes, managing director of municipal finance for NationsBanc Capital Markets Inc., the board opted not to finalize a rule it proposed last September that would require dealers to send official statements to customers much sooner than currently required.</p>
<p>&quot;The board will issue a notice indicating that the (rule) will not be adopted at this time,&quot; Hayes said.</p>
<p>But he said, &quot;It is absolutely important to get OSs to investors&quot; under the timetable required under current MSRB rules.</p>
<p>&quot;There is some evidence that this is not happening as it should,&quot; Hayes said. &quot;The dealer community would be well advised to review their procedures to see what's needed to comply with existing rules.&quot;</p>
<p>The draft rule would have amended MSRB's rule G-32, which sets disclosure standards for new issues of municipal bonds.</p>
<p>The draft rule would have moved up the time that a customer receives a final official state from the date of settlement to the date the final money confirmation is sent by the dealer to the customer.</p>
<p>The board's review of the muni underwriting process comes amid mounting federal enforcement actions against top financial advisers in the market, including former Lazard Freres &amp; Co. executive Mark Ferber.</p>
<p>Also, the Securities and Exchange Commission and other federal regulators are examining allegations of massive &quot;yield burning&quot; in the muni market.</p>
<p>Yield burning refers to charges that dealers in the early 1990s overcharged issuers for U.S. Treasury securities purchased in the open market and used in bond refinancing transactions.</p>
<p>Hayes said that while the 15-member board reached no decisions on whether to tighten regulation of bond underwriting, &quot;This was one of the most intense board meetings I have ever attended.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the board does not want to &quot;rush into anything&quot; because of industry concerns that it is being &quot;regulated to death&quot; already.</p>
<p>&quot;The discussion has begun,&quot; Christopher Taylor, the board's executive director said. He said the board will meet with other market groups on the issue before its May meeting.</p>
<p>Taylor said he would not release an options memo on the issue that was prepared by MSRB staff and circulated at the quarterly meeting.</p>
<p>Among MSRB's options are adopting tighter rules, setting new policies, setting up pacts with other industry groups, seeking new legislation, or taking no action, MSRB watchers say.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
