<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="367094" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Western retains previous earnings outlook.</title>
<headline>Western retains previous earnings outlook.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo. 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Western Resources Inc said Monday that if its proposed $2 billion merger with Kansas City Power and Light Co succeeds, overall earnings will meet or possibly exceed earlier projections.</p>
<p>Speaking to analysts in a teleconference, Western Chairman and CEO John Hayes Jr. said earnings would be comparable to the forecast the company made in a document filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission on July 3, 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;(Including) information from KCPL, and using a conservative approach, we find that the projections are better in some respects than expected,&quot; Hayes said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The effect on earnings in the first full year after the close of the merger should be flat on a normalized basis and accretive thereafter as compared to that July 1996 S-4 document,&quot; Hayes said.</p>
<p>In the S-4 document, Western said it expected combined company post-merger earnings to be $1.71 per share during the first full year after the merger takes place. The estimate assumed the merger would be completed on January 1, 1998, and that it would be accounted for as a pooling of interests.</p>
<p>Hayes also said he expected Western's senior debt credit rating to be virtually unchanged after the merger is complete.  </p>
<p>Hayes said he anticipated a credit rating of between single-A'-minus and triple-B'-plus. In January, Standard &amp; Poor's lowered its rating on Western's senior secured debt to triple-B'-plus from single-A'-minus.</p>
<p>Hayes said dividends for KCPL shareholders could increase by up to 40 percent over current KCPL dividends as a result of the proposed merger, which was announced Friday.</p>
<p>Under the proposed deal, KCPL shareholders would receive $32 of Western stock per KCPL share, subject to a maximum of 1.1 shares and a minimum of 0.917 shares of Western stock for each share of KCPL.  </p>
<p>Based on Friday's closing price of Western stock, the exchange ratio would be 1.049.</p>
<p>Hayes said he expects the merger to be completed by the end of 1997, assuming shareholders and regulators approve it.</p>
<p>Regulatory approval of the deal will have to come from the Kansas Corporation Commission, the Missouri Public Service Commission, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</p>
<p>&quot;We anticipate no undue delays in obtaining these regulatory approvals and we will begin filing the applications with these agencies as early as April,&quot; Hayes said.  </p>
<p>The deal must be approved by holders of a majority of Western Resources' outstanding common and preferred stock, and by two-thirds of KCPL's outstanding common stock.</p>
<p>KCPL Chairman Drue Jennings, who also participated in the conference call, said KCPL would pay termination fees to UtiliCorp United Inc &quot;in the near future.&quot; The payment, which UtiliCorp said totals $53 million, is due under the terms of KCPL's previous merger agreement with UtiliCorp.</p>
<p>That merger was scuttled after Western's hostile takeover bid prevented KCPL from receiving enough votes to approve the merger last year.</p>
<p>Western Resources President David Wittig told analysts that a Florida court had not yet ruled on Western's request that security giant ADT Ltd hold a special shareholders' meeting no later than March 20, 1997.</p>
<p>In December, Western launched a $3.5 billion hostile bid for ADT, which has called the bid &quot;inadequate&quot; and high-risk.</p>
<p>&quot;As we have said, we're going to have a meeting of the ADT shareholders between March and July of this year. We are in court in Florida to determine when the date of that meeting will be. Other than that, there's really nothing to add,&quot; Wittig said.</p>
<p>((--Greg Frost, 816 561-8671))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
