<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="367087" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ADT sues Chase over hostile bid.</title>
<headline>ADT sues Chase over hostile bid.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>ADT Operations Inc filed suit Monday against former banker and financial adviser Chase Manhattan Corp, charging it with breach of fiduciary duty for assisting Western Resources Inc in a hostile bid for the security company.</p>
<p>The lawsuit, filed in New York State Supreme Court, seeks $50 million in punitive damages from Chase and requests that Chase be prohibited from involvement in Western's bid.</p>
<p>ADT contends that Chase, which was its banker and financial adviser since at least 1993, had agreed not to participate in a hostile takeover of the company.  </p>
<p>ADT Operations is a subsidiary of ADT Ltd.</p>
<p>Western Resources launched a $3.5 billion hostile bid for ADT Ltd in December.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on the special relationship between ADT Operations and Chase, Chase had a duty to disclose to ADT Operations that it was advising and assisting Western in a hostile takeover attempt of the ADT companies,&quot; according to the ADT lawsuit.</p>
<p>&quot;Had ADT Operations been advised of Chase's conduct with respect to Western, ADT Operations would have ceased providing confidential and proprietary information to Chase and would have terminated their relationship,&quot; the suit continued.  </p>
<p>Officials from Chase and Western Resources could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>The lawsuit said that Chase had access to sensitive confidential financial information about ADT and also held discussions with ADT senior management about the company's strategic programs and long-term plans.</p>
<p>The lawsuit also said that, when confronted about its relationship with Western, Chase said it believed the agreement not to assist in a hostile bid was no longer effective because ADT's previous planned merger with Repubic Industries Inc had put the company &quot;in play.&quot;</p>
<p>Western Resources launched its bid for ADT after the planned merger with Republic collapsed.</p>
<p>ADT rejected Chase's argument, saying &quot;there was a substantial difference between a consensual merger between two companies and a hostile effort by one company to take control of another company.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Robin Sidel, 212/859-1723))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BERM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
