<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="367116" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX spot heat bucks declines on short covering.</title>
<headline>NYMEX spot heat bucks declines on short covering.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX prompt heating oil remained firm Monday afternoon on short covering, bucking declines in the oil prices which fell for the fifth session.</p>
<p>&quot;You ahd a lot traders who were short the heat crack who are now covering, so crude is being sold for heating oil,&quot; said a New York crude trader.</p>
<p>At 1422 EST, March heating oil was up 0.02 cent a gallon at 60.55 cents a gallon. The March gasoline-to-crude rose to $3.53 a barrel from $3.19 on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Buying in the March and selling April seems to be the feature of the day,&quot; said a New York heating oil dealer.  </p>
<p>&quot;Buying in the March and selling April seems to be the feature of the day,&quot; said a New York heating oil dealer, noting there was short covering in outright heat as well.</p>
<p>Crude and gasoline continued to be buffeted by fund selling, with March open interest declining sharply in crude.</p>
<p>March crude was off one cent a barrel at $22.22 after falling to $21.62 earlier in the session. Strength in heating oil was supportive to crude, dealers said. March gasoline was off 0.26 cent at 62.80 cents a gallon.  </p>
<p>A seasonal downturn in oil prices amid weak refined product demand have sent prices into a tailspin since early last week. March crude has lost close to $2.00 a barrel, March heating oil has lost about five cents a gallon and gasoline has lost more than five cents a gallon since last Monday.</p>
<p>There has been some talk that the March/April crude spread could slip into contango, but most dealers said the year-over-year crude inventory deficit would keep prices backwardated.</p>
<p>The American Petroleum Institute (API) said crude stocks were 9.6 million barrels below a year ago as of January 31.</p>
<p>The March/April crude spread expanded to 22 cents from 16 cents on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Harry Milling, New York Energy Desk, 212-859-1761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
