<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="36754" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: ACQUISITIONS DRIVE NBM-AMSTELLAND PROFIT SURGE.</title>
<headline>ACQUISITIONS DRIVE NBM-AMSTELLAND PROFIT SURGE.</headline>
<dateline>THE HAGUE 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch builder NBM-Amstelland said on Thursday that recent acquisitions had been the main engine behind a surge in 1996 first-half net and operating profits.</p>
<p>The company earlier reported first-half net profits more than doubled to 33.6 million gulders from a year-earlier 16.3 million, while operating profits also doubled to 55.6 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Particularly the acquisition of Cementbouw Beheer in December 1995, but also Alvon Bouwsystemen (pre-fabricated flooring) taken over early this year contributed to this favourable development,&quot; NBM Amstelland said in a statement.</p>
<p>It said poor weather conditions early in the year had braked growth in turnover independent of acquisitions, affecting not only construction activities but also spilling over into its industrial and trading business -- including building materials trader Cementbouw Beheer.</p>
<p>&quot;In the first few months of the year major backlogs were built up, which were however eliminated to a large extent in the second quarter,&quot; NBM said.</p>
<p>The builder said general construction activities had turned in a satisfactory performance, with order books steady at around the level at the beginning of the year (1.474 billion guilders).</p>
<p>Housing construction, which was loss-making last year, had been restructured and was seen contributing to group profits again in 1997, NBM Amstelland said.</p>
<p>The unit's contribution was currently &quot;neutral&quot;, a company spokesman said.</p>
<p>NBM said its environmental business continued below par. Its soil decontamination unit had gained too few orders and prices were under pressure, it said, adding it planned a reorientation of its environment arm in the second half.</p>
<p>Project development generated substantial organic growth, while NBM also upped its 10 percent stake in German project developer Gesellschaft Fur Grundbesitz to 50 percent.</p>
<p>Industrial and trading activities developed satisfactorily after a difficult start, NBM said. These activities, which generated some 25 percent of group sales in 1995, are expected to account for more than 40 percent of total turnover in 1996.</p>
<p>By contrast construction's share of total sales is seen falling to under 50 percent from more than 60 percent.</p>
<p>-- Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000, Fax +31 20 504 5040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="THE HAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
