<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="367646" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Labour urge Clarke to come clean on UK finances.</title>
<headline>Labour urge Clarke to come clean on UK finances.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Opposition Labour leader Tony Blair on Monday called on Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke to make it clear whether there was a &quot;black hole&quot; in Britain's public finances.</p>
<p>Blair was reacting to a press report that an independent think-tank had calculated that the next government would inherit a financial headache which would force it to raise taxes or cut public spending by up to 14 billion pounds ($22.96 billion).</p>
<p>&quot;What this indicate yet again is a great black hole in the public finances,&quot; Blair told a news conference.</p>
<p>Blair said he had only read the report in the Independent newspaper of the National Institute of Economic and Social Research's findings.</p>
<p>But he said they showed that economics spokesman Gordon Brown was right to say that an incoming Labour government would need to work within tough cash spending limits.</p>
<p>&quot;What I would like to know is what the Chancellor of the Exchequer says to this,&quot; Blair added. &quot;Is this true or not? Does this deficit exist or not? We should be told.&quot;</p>
<p>Blair's news conference was called to launch a new document on Labour's policies towards small businesses.</p>
<p>He said Labour's determination to follow clear rules on public spending and introduce greater certainty and ie openness in decision-making about interest rates would help small firms to plan ahead. ($1=.6097 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
