<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="367929" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austria's &quot;black widow&quot; murder trial opens.</title>
<headline>Austria's &quot;black widow&quot; murder trial opens.</headline>
<byline>Alexandra Zawadil</byline>
<dateline>KREMS, Austria 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The trial of  a woman suspected by police of a murder spree spanning more than a decade opened on Monday in Krems, 50 km (30 miles) west of Vienna.</p>
<p>Elfriede Blauensteiner, 66,  dubbed the &quot;black widow&quot; by the Austrian press, is charged with poisoning pensioner Alois Pichler with fatal doses of medication. Police are still investigating three other deaths possibly relating to the woman.</p>
<p>Blauensteiner arrived at the court wearing a beige suit and clutching a metal crucifix. &quot;My hands are clean. I've nothing to hide,&quot; she told reporters, smiling.</p>
<p>Asked if she would plead guilty, she said: &quot;I would never kill. I believe in my innocence.&quot;</p>
<p>Police said Blauensteiner confessed to five murders during the initial investigation but later withdrew the confession.</p>
<p>&quot;I confessed because the police questioned me for so long. I would have confessed to anything,&quot; she told journalists.</p>
<p>Police suspect she killed for money to finance a gambling addiction.</p>
<p>A bespectacled pensioner of matronly appearance, Blauensteiner told reporters she enjoyed nursing older men and that it was a coincidence some of those she nursed had died.</p>
<p>&quot;I like nursing people. If I picked younger men they would have wanted my body and I prefer older men as they are more grateful,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The woman's former lawyer is also on trial, charged with falsifying the victim's will.</p>
<p>Prosecutor Friedrich Kutschera alleged in court on Monday that Blauensteiner and her former lawyer had placed advertisements in newspapers enabling her to meet elderly men, with the aim of obtaining their money.</p>
<p>Kutschera said the accused gave Pichler anti-depressant tablets, left him in a room with the windows open all night and then put him under a hot shower, causing his fatal heart attack.</p>
<p>Karl Bernhauser, one of three lawyers representing the widow, said Blauensteiner wanted to meet wealthy men, but denied she had intended to murder Pichler. She had given him medicine to make him sick and show him he needed her, but not to kill him, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KREMS, Austria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
