<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="367956" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: PRESS DIGEST - Norway - Feb 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Norway - Feb 10.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in Norwegian papers this morning:</p>
<p>AFTENPOSTEN</p>
<p>-Immigrants from non-western countries have lower income and lower living standards than Norwegians in general. Thirty percent of immigrant families receive salaries that are below EU's minimum income levels, a study shows.</p>
<p>-The Polish crew on board the Leros Strength bulk carrier reported to family members already last Wednesday that there was water in a cargo hold. The ship sank on Saturday off Norway with all 20 sailors.</p>
<p>-An increasing number of Norwegians buy services at private hospitals. However profits have fallen considerably in the last year for most private hospitals.</p>
<p>DAGENS NAERINGSLIV</p>
<p>-Finance minister Jens Stoltenberg wants more efficient laws for share and bond markets. A new law will be introduced to parliament this spring.</p>
<p>-Norway's oil and gas recoverable reserves continue to be upgraded. Over the last two years reserve estimates have been upgraded by 15 percent.</p>
<p>-Manager Einar Forsbak at Norway's Union Bank Association sees no need for a merger between Norway's two largest commercial banks. Leading bankers have suggested to merge Christiania Bank and Den Norske Bank in order to meet increased competition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
