<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="367971" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britons start to insure against costs of long-term care.</title>
<headline>Britons start to insure against costs of long-term care.</headline>
<byline>Pratima Desai</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Though people are living longer, medical science has failed to cure the ailments of old age. This has created a new niche in the U.K. insurance market -- insurance against the costs of long-term care.</p>
<p>&quot;The philosophy behind long-term care policies is simple. The state will not be able to provide for future care needs. There is no support for people with financial means,&quot; said Sandy Johnstone, marketing manager at insurance company Commercial Union Plc.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect a bigger uptake of long-term care policies this year, it's a better alternative than using savings.&quot;</p>
<p>Association of British Insurers (ABI) figures show that by 2010, one person in 20 will be aged over 80 compared to one in 33 now. The chances of reaching 100 are 15 times greater now than they were 40 years ago.</p>
<p>One man in four and one woman in three currently needs long-term care. One person in six ends up in a retirement or nursing home.</p>
<p>This can cost up to 30,000 sterling ($45,000) a year. Basic nursing care at home costs around 10 pounds ($15) an hour. Many Britons have had to sell their homes to meet bills.</p>
<p>The National Health Service (NHS), the major, public medical services provider, can no longer cope with demand and has been slowly withdrawing from long term care.</p>
<p>Local health authorities will only pay for residential care once assets have fallen below 16,000 stg ($25,600).</p>
<p>Long-term care policies pay out if a person cannot perform at least two of the basic functions of life -- the so-called activities of daily living (ADLs) which include washing, dressing, toileting and mobility.</p>
<p>Premiums can be paid monthly or in a lump sum and depending on the policy, benefits may be deferred for one or more months.</p>
<p>&quot;Clients who are buying tend to be retired and they tend to prefer lump sum payments,&quot; said Steven Ingledew, development director at Frizzell Life and Financial Planning.</p>
<p>Most policies offer home help first. Places in nursing homes are normally reserved for those who fail all ADLs.</p>
<p>Costs of policies vary from company to company and depend on specifications made in the policy.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no standardisation of policies and it is difficult for consumers to compare directly,&quot; Ingledew said.</p>
<p>Long-term care insurance has not yet caught on in Britain, with the number of policies sold estimated at only 10,000.</p>
<p>The Association of British Insurers (ABI) suggest that there was still an assumption that the NHS, or immediate relatives, would cope with the demands of the elderly.</p>
<p>Young people were reluctant to channel cash into policies to provide for the distant prospect of care in old age, the ABI said.</p>
<p>Potential buyers were also unwilling to invest money into policies which might yield nothing -- if the insured dies without claiming, the estate does not benefit.</p>
<p>Two companies, PPP Healthcare and Commercial Union, have addressed this by either passing ownership of the fund to heirs or repaying some of the premiums if no benefits are claimed.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got around 120 applications so far with the premium averaging around 20,000 sterling ($30,000), but as with any new product there is a learning process,&quot; said Mike Whittaker, product development manager at PPP Healthcare.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect business to start accelerating as the product becomes better known and people start understanding it&quot;.</p>
<p>To promote long term care insurance, the government has proposed a scheme which would allow policy holders to keep more assets than non-holders when they are means-tested for residential care.</p>
<p>The insurance industry is also calling for tax incentives -- long-term care policies are not excluded from insurance premium tax (IPT) of four percent.</p>
<p>In December the Treasury (Finance Ministry) announced a consultation paper on the regulation of long-term care insurance.</p>
<p>&quot;It's only clear that they've decided to legislate to bring long-term care under the Financial Services Act. It will be regulated by the Personal Investment Authority,&quot; Ingledew said.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of the competition aspects regulation is still very much on hold.&quot;</p>
<p>The ABI has been lobbying for regulation and a supervisory body to ensure that policies match requirements.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that such a step is necessary to give consumers sufficient confidence to buy these products,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
