<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="367977" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: FOCUS-Japanese FIRMS detail India investment plans.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Japanese FIRMS detail India investment plans.</headline>
<byline>Sonali Verma</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Mitsubishi Corp is discussing a clutch of high-profile investments in India topped by a $2.0 billion telecommunications joint venture, a senior Mitsubishi official said on Monday.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi was one of several Japanese investors that unveiled plans for India on Monday. A record 132 Japanese firms are represented at an engineering trade fair in New Delhi.</p>
<p>The surge in interest was in contrast with warnings at a seminar elsewhere in the Indian capital on Monday that the country must quickly tear down barriers to trade and investment.</p>
<p>K. Yoshizawa, deputy president of the Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi Ltd, told the seminar that India attracted a meagre $2.5 billion of foreign direct investment in 1996 compared with China's $40 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The big gap does suggest no time should be lost in removing the factors that stand in the way of capital inflows,&quot; he said. &quot;The amount of red tape is so appalling that it is critically eroding India's competitiveness in attracting foreign capital.&quot;</p>
<p>Parvesh Gulati, manager of Mitsubishi Corp's New Delhi liaison office, told Reuters the proposed telecom project would involve basic telephone services.</p>
<p>The Japanese company was in talks with the Tata group, India's largest private-sector group, and RPG Telecom Ltd, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If we get a good proposal in telecom, we are definitely thinking of a new joint venture,&quot; Gulati said.</p>
<p>Separately, Marubeni Corp said it had earmarked $100 million for investment in India over the next three years in textiles, automobiles, metals and petrochemicals.</p>
<p>Liquefied petroleum gas distributor Iwatani International Corp said it was in talks with state-controlled Indian Oil Corp Ltd (IOC) to build an LPG import terminal in India, a project that could involve investment of up to $10 million.</p>
<p>&quot;We'd like to cooperate with an Indian company in this, and we are already in contact with IOC,&quot; a company official said. He said the two firms were planning to establish a joint venture with equal equity stakes.</p>
<p>And financial information services group Nihon Keizai Shimbun Inc (Nikkei) said it wanted to sell on-line information in English in India.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking for an agent in India to sell our service, but we are ready to provide it from today,&quot; Hideto Onishi of Nikkei's information system department told Reuters.</p>
<p>Japan is India's biggest donor, offering 133.7 billion yen ($1.1 billion) in overseas development assistance (ODA), or aid, in the 1996/97 fiscal year which will end on March 31.</p>
<p>But it is only the fourth largest investor in India, ranked behind the United States, Germany and Britain.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi said it was also in talks with India's Essar Steel Ltd and Tata Iron and Steel Co Ltd to set up a joint venture company that would make construction, steel and port equipment.</p>
<p>&quot;That will involve $10 million minimum, but it could mean up to $50 million -- that depends on the project,&quot; Mitsubishi's Gulati said.</p>
<p>The firm was also discussing building India's first methyl methacrylate (MMA) plant with Indian Petrochemicals Corp Ltd and the Aditya Birla group, he said.</p>
<p>A decision on the project, which would entail investment of $150 million to $250 million, was due by year-end, he said.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi was scheduled later this week to a sign a $10 million joint venture agreement with India's JBM Group to produce metal parts for Hyundai Motor Co Ltd.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi Chemical Corp, a subsidiary of Mitsubishi Corp, was in the process of negotiating a $350 million contract for a turn-key petrochemicals plant in Haldia town, in the eastern state of West Bengal, Gulati said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
