<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="368233" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysian youth may have to do national service.</title>
<headline>Malaysian youth may have to do national service.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A proposed non-military national service programme may be made mandatory for all Malaysian secondary school graduates as well as those pursuing tertiary courses, a local newspaper reported on Monday.</p>
<p>A national service programme was proposed last week as one way to combat social problems among the country's Moslem population.</p>
<p>&quot;With so much concentration on the academic aspect, the moral and civic aspects were neglected during their school years,&quot; the Star newspaper quoted Deputy Education Minister Fong Chan Onn as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, we are looking at conducting the programme in the students' respective schools, but we have not finalised it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Malaysia does not have military conscription. so the proposed scheme would be the first compulsory national service for young people.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad last Wednesday led Moslem religious leaders, some Moslem cabinet ministers and state chief ministers in launching a campaign against drug abuse, incest and crime besetting the Moslem community in Malaysia, which makes up more than half of the country's 21 million population.</p>
<p>Fong said that a working paper on national service is being prepared by the Youth and Sports Ministry. The non-military service could be modelled along the lines of summer camps in the United States, Fong was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>The programme would focus on good moral and civic values and include a &quot;character-building plan&quot; for youths leaving school, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The main thing is to have a programme to strengthen the moral fibre and promote self-reliance and perseverance among the youth,&quot; he was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603 201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
