<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="368243" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Four Indonesian rioters face subversion charges.</title>
<headline>Four Indonesian rioters face subversion charges.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four men are facing subversion charges following an ethnic and religious riot in Tasikmalaya in Indonesia's West Java province last last year, the official Antara news agency reported on Monday.</p>
<p>The report quoted M. Adenan, head of the West Java prosecutor's office, as saying the four men, aged between 24 and 25 and identified only by their initials, were now officially suspects in the case of the Tasikmalaya riots on December 26.</p>
<p>&quot;One of them has been held for examination since 10 days ago while the arrest warrants for the other three will come immediately,&quot; Adenan said after attending Moslem prayers on Sunday in the West Java capital of Bandung.</p>
<p>Four people died when a mostly Moslem mob went on the rampage burning shops, police stations, houses and churches after Tasikmalaya police beat an Islamic religious teacher and two of his students during interrogation.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on information from witnesses the four youths meet the conditions for being processed under the subversion law and tried,&quot; Adenan was quoted as saying. Subversion carries a maximum penalty of death.</p>
<p>Adenan said it was possible the number of suspects would increase and that the &quot;intellectual actor&quot; -- the phrase used by authorities to describe an alleged provocateur or mastermind behind the riots -- would appear after the four suspects had been questioned.</p>
<p>The government has blamed a number of recent ethnic and religious riots on unnamed intellectual actors or remmants of the banned Indonesian Communist Party (PKI). No &quot;intellectual actor&quot; has been brought to trial so far.</p>
<p>&quot;(The suspects) have used the organisation where they are members and even chairman,&quot; Adenan said without giving any further details. He added all would be revealed in court.</p>
<p>Promiment Moslem leaders have claimed a number of small and more extreme Moslem ogranisations incited members of larger and more moderate groups, particularly their younger members, to take part in the violence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
