<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="368331" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>LAOS: FEATURE - Change comes quietly to old Vientiane.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Change comes quietly to old Vientiane.</headline>
<byline>Katya Robinson</byline>
<dateline>VIENTIANE 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>In the dim hall of the Russian Centre for International Scientific and Cultural Cooperation, yellowed photos of farm equipment and other machines hang forlornly and the only person around is a Lao staff member eating a bowl of soup.</p>
<p>There is not much more activity on a movie night, says centre director Evgueny Vnoukov.</p>
<p>Vnoukov stretches his meagre funds to provide Russian language classes, concerts and films for the Lao people, but he recognises his country's ability to spend money in this communist nation dwindles with each passing year.</p>
<p>&quot;In (Russia's) transition period to a market economy, there are a lot of financial difficulties,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>As evinced by the empty centre, many Laotians are turning elsewhere for entertainment and education, and that shift holds the key to the changing face of modern Vientiane, say analysts.</p>
<p>Faced with waning financial aid from Moscow since the 1980s, this sleepy capital of some 530,000 people has had to wake up to the outside world, encouraging foreign investment, allowing free enterprise and opening itself to new influences, they say.</p>
<p>Vientiane, the place where time once stood still, is being transformed at an uncharacteristically hurried pace.</p>
<p>&quot;It's changing so fast,&quot; said one diplomat. &quot;People who visit come back six months later and notice the changes.&quot;</p>
<p>FOREIGN INFLUENCES ABOUND</p>
<p>Officials and foreigners, most of whom are diplomats or work for aid agencies, point to pervasive Thai influences ranging from the free use of the baht alongside U.S. dollars and the Lao kip, to the hundreds of Thai products in the markets and stores.</p>
<p>They laud the preservation of many historic buildings, even as new hotels and office complexes spring up, and they note the growing morning market (open all day) as well as improvements to the airport and telephone system.</p>
<p>Restaurants, which serve Indian, Italian, Thai and French fare, are on every corner. And there is access to foreign media even in the countryside, where satellite dishes powered by car batteries beam CNN and Thai television into Lao homes.</p>
<p>Some bemoan the negatives of Vientiane's awakening, such as increased traffic -- including the proliferation of noisy tuk-tuks, the local motorbike taxis -- and loud discos.</p>
<p>Foreigners in particular mourn the loss of the French colonial-era avenues of trees and quiet streets, including the recent levelling of the Khou Vieng promenade of rain trees that led into the city.</p>
<p>&quot;There's an attitude that this is the last of old Asia, we should enjoy it while it lasts,&quot; said one international aid worker.</p>
<p>Economic growth, meanwhile, is likely to accelerate.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect good growth,&quot; said Leuane Sambounkhan, vice-chairman of the Committee for Planning and Cooperation, which licenses foreign investments, when asked about 1997.</p>
<p>But for those attracted to the historic charms of old Vientiane there is not yet cause for panic.</p>
<p>There are still rice fields within the main streets of the city, and traffic is light compared to most other capitals.</p>
<p>&quot;There's not much to do here,&quot; said one diplomat. &quot;I have a lot of free time.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LAOS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENTIANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LAOS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
