<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="368358" id="root" date="1997-02-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Crescent Petroleum in talks with foreign firms.</title>
<headline>Crescent Petroleum in talks with foreign firms.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crescent Petroleum Company International Ltd on Monday confirmed it was in talks with several foreign firms on future strategic alliances and a possible equity sale in the Sharjah-based private oil firm.</p>
<p>&quot;The company has been in discussions with several international companies seeking strategic alliances,&quot; a spokeman for Crescent said.</p>
<p>Crescent had been approached with offers of entering partnerships in &quot;areas of mutal interest&quot; and the possible sale of a minority equity stake in the firm.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition to companies from the Far East, including Taiwan and South Korea, discussions have been held with European as well as Canadian oil firms,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Taiwan's state-owned Chinese Petroleum Corp was in talks with Crescent to buy a 40 percent stake in a Crescent affiliate, a statement released by the Taipei economics ministry said on Monday.</p>
<p>Crescent's spokesman said that they had not been approached with the offer and that a deal was not imminent.</p>
<p>&quot;No agreement has been concluded with any entity...No offers have been given to or received from Taiwan's CPC,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Taiwan's Central News Agency also reported on Monday that CPC had offered $80 million to secure the 40 percent stake.</p>
<p>The Sharjah-based firm has oil and gas producing assets in the gulf and interests in a Pakistan refinery project and a planned gas project to transport and sell gas from Qatar to Pakistan.</p>
<p>Crescent's Buttes Gas and Oil and exploration firm Enterprise Oil Plc signed a $70 million venture in July 1996 to fund exploration and production activities offshore Sharjah.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SHAJH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
