<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="368474" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>India: Bombay stocks end shade lower in moribund trade.</title>
<headline>Bombay stocks end shade lower in moribund trade.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>**  (1000 GMT) - Shares at Bombay Stock Exchange close with</p>
<p>	  small losses in a day of little action</p>
<p>**  Bombay's top 30-share index down 11.99 points, or 0.32</p>
<p>	  percent at a provisional close of 3,750.38, off 3,780.16</p>
<p>**  Market stuck in consolidation phase as players seek</p>
<p>	  clues to judge trend, say traders</p>
<p>**  Foreign funds stay quiet, hesitant to pick up stocks</p>
<p>	  in a big way--traders</p>
<p>**  National Stock Exchange 50-stock index loses 7.80</p>
<p>	  points, or 0.73 percent, to 1,066.40 just before close</p>
<p>Blue chips edged lower in lacklustre trade at the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) on Thursday as lack of buying support weighed on the market, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets have been pretty dull. Essentialy, there is only trading activity,&quot; said Vetri Subramaniam, equity trader at institutional brokerage SSKI Securities Pvt Ltd.</p>
<p>The BSE's benchmark 30-share index drifted in a narrow band, ending 11.99 points lower at a provisional 3,750.38, off the intra-day high of 3,780.16.</p>
<p>&quot;There seems to be some sort of consolidation-phase taking place,&quot; said SSKI's Subramaniam.  </p>
<p>The Bombay index rallied nearly 16 percent to hit an eight-month high of 4,029.56 last week, as participants welcomed a market-friendly budget announced by the government.</p>
<p>The proposals in the 1997/98 (April-March) budget unveiled on February 28 included a cut in corporate and personal income tax rates, raised foreign portfolio limit in domestic firms and allowed companies to buy back their shares.</p>
<p>But, profit-booking at higher levels capped the post-budget gains, dealers said. &quot;Foreign funds and local institutions sold pivotals when the market was at the 4,000 level,&quot; said Neeraj Batra, president at Hinduja Finance.  </p>
<p>Batra was confident about investment buying stepping in at lower levels. &quot;A reaction of about 100-150 points, to the 3,600 levels will see fresh buying coming in.&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Shares of Castrol India surged 25.25 rupees, or 5.16 percent to close at 515.0 at the Bombay bourse with a sharp rise seen in trading volumes. About 496,094 shares were traded.</p>
<p>Dealers did not attribute any particular factor behind the price surge despite some foreign fund buying seen in the stock.</p>
<p>The National Stock Exchange 50-stock index ended 9.15 points, or 0.85 percent, down at a provisional 1,065.05.</p>
<p>-- Anshuman Daga, Bombay equities desk +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
