<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="368608" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US blue chips stage late rally to close higher.</title>
<headline>US blue chips stage late rally to close higher.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. blue chips closed higher on Tuesday, shaking off an extended sell-off in the technology sector to rally sharply in the final minutes of the session.</p>
<p>The Dow industrials rose 52 points to close unofficially at 6858, with all the gains coming in a program-dominated last half-hour of trading.</p>
<p>The late rally saw funds flock to many of the selected large cap names that have driven the market higher in recent months. Oil shares in particular found support after a weak performance on Monday.  </p>
<p>Chevron Corp, Exxon Corp and Texaco Inc were all among the Dow's strongest performers.</p>
<p>But the market's real test of confidence took place among technology stocks, which faced stiff selling pressure most of the day.</p>
<p>Late in the day, however, some top names in the sector, notably Intel Corp, finally began to rise, and traders said the buying interest seemed to spark a rapid-fire turnaround by large caps.  </p>
<p>&quot;A lot of people were watching Intel today,&quot; said Mike Rothberg, director of portfolio trading at Cantor Fitzgerald.</p>
<p>Intel is considered a tech bellwether, and many analysts use the stock to gauge investor sentiment toward the sector.</p>
<p>Early on, that was bad news for the market, because Intel fell below a key level at 150 and then &quot;dropped like a stone&quot; to 146-1/2, he said. But suddenly, the tide turned.</p>
<p>&quot;Buyers seemed to step in at 146 for Intel, and it looked like that flushed out buyers for other large-cap stocks,&quot; Rothberg said. &quot;Before long, we saw buy programs starting to kick in, and those really helped us at the end.&quot;  </p>
<p>The late surge saw other top-tier tech companies such as Microsoft Corp and International Business Machines Corp reverse earlier losses.</p>
<p>By the end, Intel finished at 151-3/4, up 1/8 for the day, while Microsoft rose 3/4 to 98-1/2, recouping losses that took it as low as 95-1/8. IBM gained 2-1/2 to 145-1/4 after falling as low as 141-1/8.</p>
<p>Despite the rebound, investors clearly remained leery of smaller-cap tech stocks as well as shares in companies whose growth prospects appeared to be in doubt.  </p>
<p>Motorola Inc was one such stock, falling four points to 63-1/2 after Swedish cellular telephone competitor LM Ericsson said it expected continued pressure on prices of its telecommunications products in 1997.</p>
<p>Motorola made similar comments just a month ago, but even so, investors beat a hasty retreat from the group.</p>
<p>&quot;With the market as nervous as it is, stocks are getting knocked down every time there's bad news,&quot; said Barbara Marcin, vice president at Citibank Global Asset Management.  </p>
<p>&quot;For companies trading at very high price-to-earnings ratios, taking even a little off the earnings can really do a lot of damage,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Nasdaq-listed shares in Ericsson fell 1-7/8 to 32-5/8 and shares in Finnish company Nokia AB fell 1-1/2 to 65-3/8 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Centennial Technologies Inc failed to open for trading on the NYSE after the company announced it had dismissed several top executives and was examining past earnings reports for possible misstatements.  </p>
<p>The shares, which closed on Monday at 16-1/2, have fallen steadily since December 11, 1996, when they closed at 55-1/2.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite fell 3.83 to 1331.51.</p>
<p>The S&amp;P 500 index rose 4.16 to 789.59, a record.</p>
<p>((-- Wall Street desk, 212-859-1730))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
