<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="368791" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: SNOWBOARDING-REVOLUTION ON THE SLOPES.</title>
<headline>SNOWBOARDING-REVOLUTION ON THE SLOPES.</headline>
<byline>Belinda Goldsmith</byline>
<dateline>ARE, Sweden 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>What started as a fad on snow is revolutionising life on ski slopes across the world.</p>
<p>Snowboarding has joined the mainstream in the past three winter seasons, becoming the biggest craze on the piste since people began skiing, and its rise in popularity shows no sign of slowing down.</p>
<p>An estimated eight percent of people who go to the snow are now snowboarding rather than skiing and industry groups project this could surge to 40 percent by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Its popularity is expected to receive a further boost when the sport makes its debut in the winter Olympics in Nagano in Japan in February 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not just a sport, it's a lifestyle, complete with the fashion, the music, the attitude and even a language,&quot; said Stefan Cederberg, the co-founder of a snowboard manufacturing company in Sweden, one of several European countries caught up in the snowboarding boom.</p>
<p>&quot;It really exploded in 1993 and the sport is continuing to increase by about 15-20 percent a year. Young people don't start to ski anymore. They want to snowboard.&quot;</p>
<p>Snowboarding began in the United States in the late 1970s when surfers looking for a similar buzz on snow threw away one ski and widened the remaining one, surfing down moguls instead of riding waves.</p>
<p>The first crude snowboards had only one foot binding and were made of wood. Others had a split, V-shaped tail and were called winter sticks.</p>
<p>But over the years, as other snow crazes like monoskiing melted away, the equipment has become more sophisticated with today's boards made of fibreglass and wood, with two bindings and shaped symmetrically for easier movement.</p>
<p>What started as a garage industry has turned into a lucrative new area for sports equipment manufacturers.</p>
<p>Lennart Edner, who opened one of Sweden's first snowboarding shops in Stockholm in 1992, said it costs at least 7,000 crowns ($950) to get kitted out for snowboarding.</p>
<p>&quot;The price of the equipment has not been low enough for the sport to really go mainstream but we are now starting to go in that direction,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact the market is now just about saturated with snowboard manufacturers with most big name brands getting in there too. At least it's bringing prices down.&quot;</p>
<p>But it is not just the snowboard and shoes that cost. An essential part of snowboarding is wearing the right gear -- baggy trousers, oversized jackets and trendy hats.</p>
<p>Functional snowboarding garments have moved across into mainstream fashion and, coupled with music by bands with names like Mind Jive and Offspring, have created a distinctive image for the sport.</p>
<p>Snowboarders, like surfers, even have their own terminology, describing good snow as &quot;pow pow&quot; and creating their own phrases for snowboarding manoeuvres.</p>
<p>&quot;The image and fashion is very important,&quot; Edner said. &quot;You can't snowboard without the attitude.&quot;</p>
<p>Ulla Vikland, information manager at Are in central Sweden, one of Scandinavia's largest ski resorts, said eight percent of the 1.7 million Swedes who went to the snow last season were snowboarders.</p>
<p>Figures from the Swedish Lift Companies Organisation showed popularity in snowboarding has risen steadily, accounting for five percent of snow activity in the 1994/95 season.</p>
<p>The seventh annual Snowboarding Industry Conference in Aspen in December heard this could grow to 40 percent by 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;All Swedish resorts are putting in half pipes (ramps) for snowboarders and building special activity areas on the slopes,&quot; Vikland said in a interview in Are, 600 kms (370 miles) northwest of Stockholm.</p>
<p>&quot;Young people are always looking for something new and snowboarding has become a trend over the whole world of skiing. But this year we are also starting to see older people trying snowboard, parents who have seen their kids on boards.</p>
<p>&quot;What is good is that snowboarding is bringing people to the snow who would never have come skiing, a new group.&quot;</p>
<p>But with a new sport comes its problems. Medical centres at ski resorts in Sweden have reported a large number of snowboarders needing treatment for wrist injuries.</p>
<p>&quot;With any new sport you will always get this kind of negative publicity,&quot; Cederberg said. &quot;You really don't get any more injuries snowboarding than you get skiing. It's just wrists rather than legs.&quot;</p>
<p>The relationship between the newcomers to the piste and more traditional skiers, however, does have its rocky patches.</p>
<p>&quot;It's rather like raceboats and sail boats,&quot; Edner said. &quot;Snowboarders are much more laid back, like skateboarders and surfers. Skiers seem to run everywhere.&quot;</p>
<p>Vikland said skiers often get annoyed with snowboarders sitting on the slopes or taking up too much of the piste.</p>
<p>&quot;It is something that we are aware of and we try to find solutions to ensure relations are kept smooth,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Cederberg was blunter. &quot;Snowboarders hate skiers and we hate them,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ARE, Sweden"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
