<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="368899" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reuters historical calendar - February 18.</title>
<headline>Reuters historical calendar - February 18.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the major events to have occurred in February 18 in history.</p>
<p>1248 - Imperial forces under Frederick II were defeated at Parma in Italy.</p>
<p>1455 - Fra Angelico (Guido di Pietro), Dominican Friar and Italian painter of many religious works, died. Famed for his &quot;Last Judgement&quot; at Orvieto as well as his contemplative frescoes in Florence.</p>
<p>1478 - George, Duke of Clarence, convicted of treason against his brother Edward IV, was murdered in the Tower of London. He was drowned in a wine butt.</p>
<p>1516 - Mary I, Queen of England, born, the  daughter of Henry VIII and his first wife Catherine of Aragon. Queen from 1553, she became known as &quot;Bloody Mary&quot; after her campaign against Protestants in England.</p>
<p>1546 - Martin Luther, German Augustinian Friar and leader of the 16th century Protestant reformation, died.</p>
<p>1564 - Michelangelo Buonarotti, Italian painter, sculptor and architect, died. Described as the most brilliant representative of the Italian Renaissance,he was famed for his work on the Sistine Chapel, his painting of &quot;The Last Judgement&quot; and his statue of &quot;David&quot;.</p>
<p>1745 - Count Alessandro Volta, Italian physicist, born. He gave his name to a unit of electricity and invented the electric battery in 1800.</p>
<p>1861 - In Italy, the first parliament met and proclaimed Victor Emmanuel as King.</p>
<p>1865 - After being besieged, the Unionist fleet took the town of Charleston in South Carolina in the U.S. Civil War.</p>
<p>1884 - British General Charles Gordon arrived at Khartoum in the Sudan in an attempt to end to the rebellion by the Mahdi.</p>
<p>1900 - The battle of Paardeberg began in the second Boer War. The Boers under Piet Cronje eventually surrendered (Feb 27) under the weight of British artillery led by Lord Roberts.</p>
<p>1915 - In World War One, Germany began a blockade of England using submarines.</p>
<p>1916 - In Cameroon, the last German soldiers surrendered to the Allies thus ending German control of the colony.</p>
<p>1918 - German Army launched an offensive against Russia and within a week had occupied the Baltic States.</p>
<p>1919 - Jack Palance, U.S. film actor, born as Walter Palahnuik.</p>
<p>1932 - Milos Forman, U.S. film director, born in Czechoslovakia. His film &quot;One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest&quot; (1975) won five Oscars.</p>
<p>1944 - In World War Two, RAF Mosquitoes bombed Amiens prison in France, allowing 100 prisoners to escape.</p>
<p>1951 - In Vietnam, Prime Minister Tran Van Huu announced the formation of a new government.</p>
<p>1951 - In Nepal, a new Council of Ministers was sworn in thus ending century-old Rana domination and starting a new democracy.</p>
<p>1954 - John Travolta, U.S. film actor, born. Star of &quot;Saturday Night Fever&quot;, &quot;Grease&quot; and &quot;Pulp Fiction&quot;.</p>
<p>1960 - Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Mexico, Paraguay, Peru and Uruguay agreed to set up a Latin American Free Trade Association.</p>
<p>1965 - Gambia became an independent state within the Commonwealth.</p>
<p>1967 - Robert Oppenheimer, U.S. physicist and father of the atomic bomb, died.</p>
<p>1980 - In Canada, Pierre Trudeau, leader of the Liberal Party, returned to office as prime minister.</p>
<p>1981 - U.S. President Reagan's first budget proposed the largest tax cuts and spending curbs ever for an administration, including $90,000 million dollars increase in defence spending over four years.</p>
<p>1991 - An IRA bomb in exploded in London's Victoria Railway station, killing one and injuring at least 40 people.</p>
<p>1994 - Delegates from 130 countries agreed at a United Nations conference that there must be new cuts in greenhouse gas emissions to halt if global warming.</p>
<p>1996 - An IRA explosion ripped apart a bus in Londons, killing one person and injuring nine others.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
