<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="368839" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAFRICAN RIGHTWINGERS BAIL PLEA POSTPONED.</title>
<headline>SAFRICAN RIGHTWINGERS BAIL PLEA POSTPONED.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A bail application by a notorious South African right-winger and eleven other people was postponed on Tuesday in court proceedings marred by the spraying of a tear gas-like spray.</p>
<p>Willem Ratte and 11 others, including a 16-year old boy, people were arrested on Monday, after breaking into the Pomfret military base, allegedly to steal arms, in the country's North West region.</p>
<p>A police spokesman said a female supporter of the right-wingers sprayed the gas into the court chamber. She was charged with contempt of court.</p>
<p>&quot;Court proceedings were disrupted for about fifteen minutes and then things carried on,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The day's hearings were also disturbed when Ratte and his co-accused received a verbal warning for singing &quot;Die Stem&quot; -- the anthem of the old racist aparthied state.</p>
<p>State prosecutor Sophia Meyer said the state asked for the postponement of the bail applications to March 17 to allow further investigations to take place. The suspects will remain in custody in different places.</p>
<p>Before being arrested Ratte had been out on bail pending his appeal against a five-year sentence for his participation in the seizure of an old fort in Pretoria three years ago.</p>
<p>He won his release on bail after being on a hunger strike which lasted for 54 days last year. The ruling ANC however has attacked the hunger strike as &quot;phony&quot;, saying Ratte had taken nourishing fluids.</p>
<p>Ratte also clashed with police in 1995 when he holed himself up at a farm outside Pretoria to guard the transmitter for a right-wing radio station, which had been broadcasting illegally for nine months.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
