<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="368987" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Gendis sees loss from unit bankruptcy.</title>
<headline>Gendis sees loss from unit bankruptcy.</headline>
<byline>Lydia Zajc</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gendis Inc will post &quot;extensive&quot; losses in fiscal 1998 after its Greenberg Stores Ltd unit was forced into bankruptcy with almost 1,500 layoffs, President Allan MacKenzie said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Asked in an interview what impact Gendis would feel for the year ending in late January 1998, MacKenzie told Reuters: &quot;Extensive. Multi-millions.&quot; He declined to elaborate.</p>
<p>MacKenzie said that the losses from the bankruptcy would be reported separately from ongoing operating results.</p>
<p>Winnipeg-based Gendis said on Tuesday that Greenberg, one of its two wholly owned retail arms, declared bankruptcy and sold 89 of its 169 stores to the other unit SAAN Stores Ltd, resulting in the closing of 80 stores and about 1,500 layoffs.</p>
<p>MacKenzie added that Gendis would take the largest loss among Greenberg's creditors after acting as its chief banker.</p>
<p>Greenberg's Montreal headquarters would be shuttered and 60 of its 322 staff members offered jobs at SAAN's head office in Winnipeg, MacKenzie said.</p>
<p>Deacon Capital analyst Bill Chisholm said Gendis would need to write off Greenberg's assets before recouping some of the losses. &quot;It'll be a big charge for the current year, probably around C$65 million,&quot; Chisholm said.</p>
<p>In its fiscal 1997 third quarter ended October 26, Gendis earned C$1.7 million or C$0.10 a share versus year earlier C$847,000 or C$$0.05 a share.</p>
<p>Greenberg stores, scattered across Quebec and Canada's Atlantic provinces, lost ground after Wal-Mart Stores Inc came to Canada in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;We, I don't think there's any doubt, got caught in what I would call the crossfire,&quot; MacKenzie said.</p>
<p>Chisholm added SAAN was a largely profitable operation and would &quot;hopefully&quot; remain in the black.</p>
<p>Gendis shares slipped 0.30 to 10.70 in light turnover on the Toronto Stock Exchange today.</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau 416-941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
