<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="368988" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada bonds close firmer, outperform U.S. issues.</title>
<headline>Canada bonds close firmer, outperform U.S. issues.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian bonds closed firmer on Tuesday, boosted by domestic buying interest in quiet trade, with investors focusing on Wednesday's auction of both Canadian and U.S. bonds, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Generally we've seen buyers, but we've had fairly light activity,&quot; said a bond trader at one bank-owned brokerage. &quot;It's just enough to move the market, but nothing decisive. Generally we've seen better domestic buying.&quot;</p>
<p>Canada's 30-year bond rose C$0.20 to C$112.05 to yield 6.991 percent. The U.S. 30-year benchmark bond traded unchanged to yield 6.70 percent.  </p>
<p>The spread between the benchmark bonds narrowed to 29 basis points from  30 basis points at the close of trading on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. certainly was kept behind by the auctions they had today and also the next couple of days,&quot; said David Yu, a fixed-income portfolio manager with Perigee Investment Counsel Inc. &quot;There appear to be some term extension trades today. That would explain why our long end is doing much better today than the U.S.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S. government today held the first of three auctions this week to sell almost US$40 billion in bonds.  </p>
<p>While results were fairly good for the first auction this afternoon of US$17.75 billion of three-year bonds, U.S. investors were seen as cautious ahead of the two remaining auctions.</p>
<p>In Canada, the Government of Canada tomorrow will auction C$2.3 billion of 10-year bonds.</p>
<p>In other prices, the Government of Canada's 7.0 percent bond due 2006 rose C$0.17 to C$104.95 to yield 6.313 percent. The U.S. 10-year bond fell 1/32 to yield 6.41 percent. The negative spread between the bonds widened to 10 basis points from eight basis points at Monday's close.  </p>
<p>The three-month cash T-bill traded with a yield of 2.86 percent against the U.S. bill which yielded 5.15 percent.</p>
<p>((Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
