<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="368993" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Goodale says more locomotives to move wheat.</title>
<headline>Goodale says more locomotives to move wheat.</headline>
<dateline>WINNIPEG 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian Agriculture Minister Ralph Goodale told Parliament railway companies took steps to add more locomotives to move wheat to export ports.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm glad to see the railways have taken some steps to bring more locomotive power to the situation,&quot; Goodale said to Parliament.  </p>
<p>Goodale's spokesman, Vern Greenshields, in a phone interview from Ottawa with Reuters, played a tape recording of the remarks made in the House of Commons.</p>
<p>Forty-two vessels waited to load on Canada's Pacific coast on Monday as demurrage fines against the Canadian Wheat Board for delayed delivery exceeded C$15 million, the CWB said.</p>
<p>Shipment of more than 1.5 million tonnes of grain has been deferred so far since early January, the CWB said.</p>
<p>&quot;I've had the opportunity to discuss the situation with some of the players on the shipping and grain side and plan to speak with more in the coming days,&quot; Goodale told Parliament.  </p>
<p>Officials at Canadian National Railway Co and at Canadian Pacific unit CP Rail System were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Saskatchewan Wheat Pool earlier Tuesday asked Goodale to call an emergency meeting to expedite grain shipment.</p>
<p>&quot;This situation is critical,&quot; Goodale told Parliament.</p>
<p>The shipping delays forced the CWB to pass up wheat sales for February and March and may now threaten April delivery, CWB chief commissioner Lorne Hehn told Reuters earlier Tuesday.</p>
<p>((Gilbert Le Gras 204 947 3548))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINNIPEG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
