<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369007" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GHANA: Ghana president names nine ministers, more to come.</title>
<headline>Ghana president names nine ministers, more to come.</headline>
<dateline>ACCRA 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ghana's president, Jerry Rawlings, has named nine members of his new government, seven of them members of the outgoing administration, state-run Ghana News Agency reported.</p>
<p>The list, in a presidential statement read to parliament by speaker Justice D.F. Annan on Tuesday, included outgoing Finance Minister Richard Kwame Peprah but the statement said further nominations would be announced in due course.</p>
<p>Rawlings won a second and final elected term in December. His new team is widely expected to be smaller than the outgoing government of 33 ministers and 50 deputy ministers.</p>
<p>Joseph Owusu-Acheampong at parliamentary affairs, Eunice Brookman-Amissah at health, Edward Salia at transport and communications, Vida Yeboah at tourism, Kwabena Adjei at lands and forestry and Upper East regional minister Cletus Avoka all retain their jobs.</p>
<p>Rawlings nominated Nii Okaidja Adamafio to the interior ministry and Kojo Yankah as central region minister. Parliament has to consider these nominations, the agency said.</p>
<p>Parliament refused to let Peprah present the 1997 budget last week, arguing that the new government had not been announced.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GHANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ACCRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GHANA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
