<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369032" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>LIBERIA: After a long war, Liberia looks headed for elections.</title>
<headline>After a long war, Liberia looks headed for elections.</headline>
<byline>John Chiahemen</byline>
<dateline>MONROVIA 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>After numerous dashed hopes for an end to Liberia's seven-year civil war, even skeptical Liberians and foreign watchers now believe elections will be held as scheduled in May to usher in peace.</p>
<p>Diplomats and peacekeepers say disarmament of guerrillas under a peace accord signed in Abuja, Nigeria, last August had practically cleared the biggest obstacle to free elections.</p>
<p>&quot;I think security is better than it has been and it keeps improving everyday,&quot; said U.S. Ambassador William Milam, whose country is the most influential Western power in Liberia. &quot;We have gone further along than we were in April 1996.&quot;</p>
<p>Ironically it is the seven-week orgy of ethnic militia warfare that exploded in Monrovia last April 6 that appeared to give momentum to the on-off Liberia peace process.</p>
<p>&quot;April 6 was a bad thing but it may have finally convinced the faction leaders that none of them can win individually and that the war had to be settled by other means than conflict,&quot; Milam told Reuters.</p>
<p>Milam was the diplomat in charge of a massive U.S. military operation to evacuate foreigners fleeing the flareup in April. Liberia was founded by freed American slaves in 1847 and Liberians still look up to the United States.</p>
<p>Milam oversees expanded U.S. logistics and material aid for the regional peacekeeping force ECOMOG, in Liberia since 1990.</p>
<p>Regional army chiefs who met in Monrovia this week to assess security arrangements for elections, lauded U.S. and other Western support for the Nigerian-led ECOMOG since it received a new mandate last August to disarm guerrillas.</p>
<p>U.S. helicopters and communications equipment, Dutch and German trucks and other foreign government support have vastly improved the mobility and confidence of ECOMOG, which in April abandoned central Monrovia to gangs of armed looters.</p>
<p>ECOMOG's new commander, tough-minded Nigerian General Victor Malu, is singled out for praise by faction leaders, ordinary Liberians and diplomats for the force's new credibility and effectiveness on the ground.</p>
<p>&quot;Today I believe there will be trouble in Liberia if there is any attempt to move Malu from the command of ECOMOG at this stage,&quot; chief warlord Charles Taylor told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Every guerrilla knows that if General Malu says he is coming for your gun he means it,&quot; Milam said, adding: &quot;I have  a great amount of admiration and confidence in General Malu and the ability of ECOMOG forces here to provide security.&quot;</p>
<p>Taylor who launched civil war with an invasion from neighbouring Ivory Coast in December 1989 says he is confident of winning presidential elections in May.</p>
<p>One of three main faction leaders expected to contest the presidency, Taylor has put in motion a massive electioneering machinery -- and issued a veiled threat if the poll is delayed because of U.N. concerns over arrangements.</p>
<p>While campaigning has yet to start officially, elections have replaced tales of war and suffering as the talking point in Monrovia's mushrooming bars and fast food restaurants.</p>
<p>In another sign of the changed situation, the remnant of Liberia's national army decimated by war, staged the first Army Day parade since the war on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Liberians of all tribes packed the pavilions to watch the parade of unarmed soldiers. The AFL was disarmed under accords but is recognised as the nucleus of a new national army.</p>
<p>While warlords like Taylor have the advantage of name recognition notably among teenagers with little memory of politics before the war, the ordeal of the conflict has tainted their image in the eyes of most Liberians outside the ranks of tribal militias.</p>
<p>After receiving a tumultuous welcome in September 1995 on his first visit to Monrovia since war erupted, Taylor appears to have alienated many Liberians for the leading role of his National Patriotic Front of Liberia guerrillas in the devastation of the capital last year.</p>
<p>But encouraged by the growing signs of peace, many international organisations that closed their offices last year have reopened. Monrovia's leading hotel is again swarming with foreigners trying to see if it is safe to do business.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONROVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LIBERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
