<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369020" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Stanbic sees better interest margins in '97.</title>
<headline>Stanbic sees better interest margins in '97.</headline>
<byline>Vera von Lieres</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard Bank Investment Corp said on Tuesday it was optimistic that a continuous improvement in money market conditions would see a normalisation in interest margins during the year.</p>
<p>&quot;We've seen a progressive improvement in the money market situation since the second week in January and there is a sense that we will see more normal (interest) margins this year,&quot; Stanbic group Chief Executive Mike Vosloo said at the group's annual results presentation on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not quite where we would like to be but the signs are positive,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the year ended December 31 the banking group -- South Africa's second largest in terms of assets -- showed headline earnings per share rising to 1,311 cents from 1,053 cents previously, while the dividend climbed to 407 cents compared with 327 cents.</p>
<p>Vosloo said there were indications that government's fiscal policy was coming in line with monetary policy.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking ahead, underpinning economic fundamentals are becoming more attractive for our kind of industry,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The group's interest margins came under pressure for the year to December due to difficult conditions in the domestic money market in the second half of 1996 -- particularly in the last quarter -- which saw short-term interest rates soar and a continuous squeeze in the daily money market shortage.</p>
<p>Vosloo said extremely tight money market conditions and continued downward pressure on the rand restricted growth in net interest income -- the bugbear of the year -- to 10 per cent for the year.</p>
<p>He said growing trade-related offshore lending balances at low margins combined with strong growth in domestic high quality low margin assets also added to lower group margins.</p>
<p>Growth in home loans picked up during the year and mortgages were becoming an important focus area, Vosloo said.</p>
<p>&quot;We took our eye off home loans earlier last year but the situation has now turned around and mortgages are becoming an important aspect of our business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Income from associates was 222 million rand -- significantly higher than in 1995 -- due to a change by associate Liberty Life Association of Africa Ltd to the valuation of its life fund.</p>
<p>Group assets grew by 26 percent and loans and advances by 19 percent, recording strong growth in corporate loans, instalment sale finance, card debtors and home loans, Vosloo said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
