<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369153" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: Kazakhstan names buyer to revive copper plant.</title>
<headline>Kazakhstan names buyer to revive copper plant.</headline>
<byline>Larisa Kokovinets</byline>
<dateline>ALMATY 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kazakhstan hoped to breathe new life into its troubled copper industry on Tuesday by naming the winner of a tender for control of the Balkhashmys copper plant.</p>
<p>A statement from the State Privatisation Committee confirmed Russian press reports late on Monday that South Korea's Samsung won the tender to buy the assets of Kazakhstan's Balkhashmys copper company.</p>
<p>But this is already the third time the government has offered up the ailing plant to foreign investors, and underlines the Central Asian state's often bumpy ride on the road to privatising its assets.</p>
<p>The need for investment is clear. Balkhashmys' ore reserves are largely exhausted, and debts amount to over $200 million.</p>
<p>Output at the plant, which produces 40 percent of Kazakhstan's copper, slumped to 80,000 tonnes last year from 135,000 tonnes in 1995.</p>
<p>Samsung has undertaken to invest up to $700 million by the year 2000 to boost output, improve metallurgical equipment, develop ore basins and take steps to protect the environment.</p>
<p>Samsung will this year allot $80 million for the measures, and another $80 million to replenish the plant's capital base.</p>
<p>Through its investments Samsung aims to boost copper production to 100,000 tonnes in 1997 and to 200,000 tonnes by the year 2000.</p>
<p>The government has repeatedly held auctions for the right to own companies in its potentially multi-billion dollar oil, energy and metals sectors, but many later fell through.</p>
<p>In December 1995 Cam Finance S.A. of Switzerland won a tender for the right to own 29 percent of shares in Balkhashmys. It also had the right to buy another 10 percent of shares by the year 2000.</p>
<p>But the contract was never signed because the Swiss side demanded that its investment should be guaranteed by a deposit of Kazakh precious metals into a Swiss bank.</p>
<p>The second tender held in September 1996 was won by a consortium grouping Glencore AG of Switzerland, Phelps Dodge Corp. of the United States and Kazkommertsbank, a local commercial bank.</p>
<p>But later the consortium refused to take on the responsibility for Balkhashmys' $200 million debt because the Kazakh government had originally said the debt was only $90 million.</p>
<p>In January this year the government offered its 85 percent stake in the charter capital of Balkhashmys in return for its assets, which it put up for tender without including the company's main debt as part of the deal.</p>
<p>&quot;This is more favourable for a strategic investor because it frees him from the need to pay the debts of the enterprise,&quot; Erkinbek Shombinov, named temporary manager of Balkhashmys by the government, told Reuters.</p>
<p>According to the conditions of the third tender, Samsung will only have to pay debts on salaries to 14,000 Balkhashmys workers.</p>
<p>But whether Samsung's bold step pays off is still far from clear. A recent company audit showed that Balkhashmys' two mines -- Kounrad and Sayak -- are already nearly exhausted and will only provide enough ore to last until the year 2000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
