<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369137" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Feb 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Feb 11.</headline>
<text>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - Officials of Russian Gazexport yesterday did not confirm or deny information concerning documents prepared together with Czech state-owned Transgas, in which Gazexport apparently offered the Czech cabinet 1,000 cubic metres of natural gas at the extremely low price of $85 if a 20 year contract is signed.</p>
<p>- Rodinny Penzijni Fond is completely liquidated and prepared to fulfill its obligation to clients. This is according to Tomas Vicherek, director of the fund, who also characterised the Finance Ministry's decision to revoke the fund's licence as severe.</p>
<p>- Total losses from the railway strike are estimated at around one billion crowns, and the management of Czech Railways does not plan to pay damages, despite requests from many businesses.</p>
<p>MLADA FRONTA DNES - Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus shocked the coalition politicians by announcing his intention to help Milos Zeman, chairman of the Social Democratic Party, prepare an accompanying document to the Czech-German Declaration. The coalition has repeatedly expressed disapproval for the Social Democrats' plan for parliament to add such a document to the declaration.</p>
<p>PRAVO - According to the Czech Statistical Bureau, consumer prices in January increased over December by 1.2 percent, and in comparison to January of 1996 by 7.4 percent. CSU predicts a whole-year inflation rate this year of 7.5 to 8 percent.</p>
<p>- Union Group, the main shareholder of Union Bank in Ostrava, bought 27 percent of the independent Polish Bank Przemyslowy and would like to obtain a majority share of the bank.</p>
<p>- According to a spokeswoman for the Transport Ministry, Judita Stuchlikova, a working group was established on Monday, which will administer a complete inspection of the accounts of Czech Railways and an analysis of restructuring which has so far taken place.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom 42-2-24-23-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
