<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369115" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbian parliament reinstates opposition victories.</title>
<headline>Serbian parliament reinstates opposition victories.</headline>
<byline>Gordana Kukic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Serbian parliament approved a special law on Tuesday reinstating opposition victories in local elections whose annulment touched off three months of civil unrest.</p>
<p>The Serbian deputies voted 128 in favour of the bill, one abstained and one refrained, the speaker of the parliament said.</p>
<p>The ruling Socialists had annulled November's opposition victories by the Zajedno (Together) coalition in 14 cities, including Belgrade, on grounds of &quot;irregularities&quot;.</p>
<p>The action attracted an international outcry and prompted three months of huge protests that at times threatened to erupt into violence.</p>
<p>A week ago President Slobodan Milosevic, facing his biggest challenge in his 10 years in power, announced he was asking parliament to approve a bill recognising the opposition gains.</p>
<p>The Serbian parliament also approved a new cabinet as Milosevic sought to shore up his power base after months of civil unrest.</p>
<p>A deputy prime minister and six other ministers were ousted. Among key changes was the appointment of Milan Beko to head a new ministry that will begin the privatisation of the huge and financially ailing state sector of the economy.</p>
<p>Radmila Milentijevic, a hard-line Milosevic loyalist, was appointed to the information ministry and immediately said the majority of students were not protesting in the streets.</p>
<p>For the past 12 weeks tens of thousands of students have protested against the elections fraud.</p>
<p>Political and economic analysts and members of the Zajedno (Together) coalition, which forced Milosevic to concede opposition victories in November municipal elections, dismissed the appointments as a smoke screen.</p>
<p>&quot;The privatisation ministry is planned to create an illusion that privatisation in Serbia is going ahead since the regime lacks $110 million per month to pay wages, salaries and cover its costs,&quot; a senior economic expert said.</p>
<p>&quot;I cannot explain this choice but nothing the regime has been doing, especially after November 17, makes much sense,&quot; Kosta Obradovic, a Zajedno spokesman, said.</p>
<p>The new appointees were sworn in immediately after the 250-member parliament, with 157 present, voted 130 for and 25 against, with two abstentions.</p>
<p>Ultra-nationalist Radicals held up passage of the special bill reinstating the electoral victories for hours, saying that it allowed the international community to use parliament to legalise decrees imposed from above.</p>
<p>&quot;Absolutely there was an obstruction of parliament by the Radical Party,&quot; federal trade minister Djordje Siradovic told reporters. &quot;I don't understand what they are really after.&quot;</p>
<p>Zajedno saw Milosevic's introduction of a special law as a climb down, and a triumph for the huge protests in Belgrade and other cities.</p>
<p>But suspecting subterfuge on the part of the Socialists, opposition politicians say they plan to keep up the pressure by continuing the street rallies.</p>
<p>Zajedno has said it fears that even with the special bill, Milosevic will remove the already limited powers of local councils with legislation stripping them of their sources of revenue.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright issued a personal appeal to Milosevic, urging him to ensure the election results were reinstated and open a dialogue with his opponents.</p>
<p>Milentijevic accused the United States and Germany of meddling in Serbia's internal affairs:</p>
<p>&quot;The influence by the United States and Germany in Serbia's internal affairs is big and that is not such a good thing.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
