<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369298" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: China unrest sparked by executions, say exiles.</title>
<headline>China unrest sparked by executions, say exiles.</headline>
<dateline>ALMATY 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leader of an exiled nationalist Uighur group in Kazakhstan said on Tuesday riots in China's predominantly Moslem northwest were sparked by the execution of 30 Uighurs by the Chinese authorities last week.</p>
<p>&quot;We have heard that 30 people, Uighurs, were executed by a firing squad,&quot; Yusupbek Mukhlisi, leader of the United National Revolutionary Front of East Turkestan, told Reuters in the capital Almaty. He said the executions took place on February 7.  </p>
<p>Chinese residents in Yining in northwestern Xinjiang province, about 50 km (30 miles) from the Kazakh border, have said the town has been sealed off by Chinese police and that a curfew is in place following riots by separatists of the Uighur minority last week.</p>
<p>Mukhlisi said hundreds of Uighurs had been arrested following the rioting. &quot;They have run out of room at the prisons and are putting people in cellars,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Information from the remote region is difficult to verify. Mukhlisi said telephone lines to the region from Kazakhstan had been cut, with most information arriving in Almaty from Uighur travellers.</p>
<p>Xinjiang authorities last year cracked down on Uighur separatists, Turkic-speaking Moslems who make up the majority of the region's population, after a series of violent clashes, bombings and assassination attempts on officials and Moslem leaders regarded as pro-Beijing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
