<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369264" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Richter eases on market sentiment, not on results.</title>
<headline>Richter eases on market sentiment, not on results.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Hungarian pharmaceuticals company Richter Gedeon Rt opened a little weaker on Tuesday following the release of the company's preliminary 1996 results.</p>
<p>But traders said Richter's price fall stemmed from the market's general trend and not from the results.</p>
<p>&quot;The price fall has nothing to do with the results, it reflects a general market sentiment,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Richter shares opened at 11,800 forints, below Monday's closing price of 11,900 and at 1104 GMT they traded at 11,850. Many of the leading issues of the market drifted lower.</p>
<p>In its earnings reports released this morning Richter said it boosted its IAS operating profit to 9.072 billion forints in 1996 from 5.716 billion in 1995, while its sales grew to 36.764 billion forints from 27.394 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Operating profit growth shows that) the company continues to regard strict cost control one of its main priorities, if not the top priority,&quot; Richter's CEO Erik Bogsch told a news conference. &quot;Of course this is beside an aggressive marketing and promotion policy.&quot;</p>
<p>Richter's operating margin rose to 24.7 percent from 20.9 percent. &quot;The company achieved its aim of keeping the operating margin between 20 and 25 percent,&quot; Bogsch said.</p>
<p>The company's earnings report said the board intended to recommend a 1996 dividend of an amount equivalent to 25 percent of audited 1996 distributable earnings (according to Hungarian Accounting Standard).</p>
<p>Bogsch declined to give forecast for 1997, but said the company will do its best to please the market.</p>
<p>&quot;We try to do our best,&quot; Bogsch said. &quot;We know that expectations towards us are to increase from last year,&quot; he said, adding that &quot;we try to do everything to succeed in reaching this.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
