<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369220" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish Amica Wronki plans 2.2-mln-share IPO in Q2.</title>
<headline>Polish Amica Wronki plans 2.2-mln-share IPO in Q2.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish white goods producer  Amica Wronki SA plans an initial public offering of 2,184,500 shares in late April or early May, the deputy president of BMT SA brokerage offering the issue said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Amica Wronki plans to issue 2,184,500 shares which will be fully undewritten and the issue price would be set later through book-building,&quot; Maciej Wandzel told a news conference.</p>
<p>The company, which currently has 6,553,000 shares on issue, has about 60 percent of the domestic cooker market and 10 percent of the refrigerator market. It wants to enter the main market of the Warsaw bourse.</p>
<p>Wandzel said 50 million zlotys of the new issue would be earmarked for paying back an investment loan and the remaining funds would be used for investments.</p>
<p>The president of Amica Wronki, Wojciech Kaszynski, confirmed estimates that if the issue were priced at a similar level as January's non-public issue of 728,000 shares, it could bring the company about 60 million zlotys.</p>
<p>Amica Wronki, 47.1-percent controlled by Polish bank  Bank Handlowy SA and 46.6-percent controlled by  Holding Wronki SA, had a net profit of about 20 million zlotys last year and expects it to stay flat in 1997.</p>
<p>Four foreign funds took 11.1 percent of shares in the company or 5.9 percent of votes in the January issue, and the remainder are held by the company's management and employees.</p>
<p>The firm, whose sales amounted to 366 million zlotys in 1996, specialises in producing gas and electric cookers, but also wants to expand its refrigerator factory and enter new areas such as dishwashers.</p>
<p>-- Malgorzata Rzepka +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I31000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
