<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="36926" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Details of South African constitutional failings.</title>
<headline>Details of South African constitutional failings.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's top court on Friday declined to certify a final post-apartheid constitution, mainly because it would give too much power to a majority party and its national government.</p>
<p>Court President Arthur Chaskalson hailed the 140-page document thrashed out during the first two years of democracy, but told its drafters to try again on several key points.</p>
<p>The court ruled that the new text failed to meet the minimum requirements set out in 34 principles appended to the interim constitution guiding South Africa from the first all-race election in 1994 to the second one in 1999.</p>
<p>The court said a provision entrenching employer rights to bargain with labour only through employer organisations did not meet the guaranteed rights of individual employers.</p>
<p>It also threw out an attempt to make the provisions of a Labour Relations Act (LRA), which redefined labour law after the transition to democracy, immune to any challenge under the new constitution.</p>
<p>It said that conflicted with the fourth principle entrenched in the interim constitution, which states: &quot;The constitution shall be the supreme law of the land. It shall be binding on all organs of state at all levels of government.&quot;</p>
<p>The ruling affects a last-minute trade-off between business and labour in which they agreed that the labour act would protect employers' right to lock out strikers while the new constitution would protect workers' right to strike.</p>
<p>The court said constitutional guarantees of independence for the watchdog public protector, to whom citizens can appeal against government actions, and the auditor-general, who monitors government spending, were inadequate.</p>
<p>The new constitution proposes that a committee of the National Assembly, which would automatically be dominated by the majority party, should have the power to decide whether either official is incompetent or guilty of misconduct.</p>
<p>The committee's sacking of either official would be subject to ratification by a simple majority of parliament.</p>
<p>The new constitution's allocation of powers to the nine provincial governments drew the most criticism. The court ruled &quot;that such powers and functions are substantially less than and inferior to the powers and functions of the provinces in the interim constitution&quot;.</p>
<p>The court also rejected the new constitution's chapter dealing with the powers of municipal governments. It was judged to have failed to meet the requirements of three principles requiring defined powers, procedures and financial resources for local councils.</p>
<p>The judgment also rejected a clause setting up an independent body to monitor the civil service, saying its powers were not well-defined.</p>
<p>The court rejected a clause seeking to make the amnesty provisions of the National Unity and Reconciliation Act, which sets up Archbishop Desmond Tutu's &quot;Truth Commission&quot;, immune from constitutional challenge.</p>
<p>The act allows Tutu's panel to grant amnesty to agents of the former government and liberation forces that fought it for gross human rights violations committed in the course of the struggle over apartheid.</p>
<p>The court's ruling means that the amnesty provision will have to be written into the constitution, or left vulnerable to challenge by survivors of the conflict.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
