<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369321" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONDURAS: Labor unrest against government grows in Honduras.</title>
<headline>Labor unrest against government grows in Honduras.</headline>
<dateline>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Honduran health workers shut down hospitals for six hours on Tuesday to demand higher wages from the government in a prelude to what was expected to be a day of widespread labour unrest on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Fired by the success of Ecuadoran unions in bringing down President Abdala Bucaram, representatives of some 14,000 government health workers planned to hold an indefinite strike from Wednesday onwards, coinciding with a day of marches by the country's three main labour confederations.</p>
<p>&quot;What happened in Ecuador should serve as a warning to our rulers, particularly (President Carlos Roberto) Reina,&quot; said Mauro Gonzalez, head of the Honduran National Workers Union.</p>
<p>He said so-called &quot;neoliberal&quot; policies of privatisation, balanced budgets and public spending caps were failing throughout Latin America, putting their heaviest burden on the poor who were fed up with shouldering it.</p>
<p>Reina faced demands for wage hikes from some 70,000 government workers, who have staged a variety of street protests in recent weeks, including the seizing of government offices. They have also pressed for an end to rises in the cost of public services, and tighter control of inflation.</p>
<p>Reina's government approved a general wage increase of 13 percent for government workers, which it said implied additional public spending of $20.6 million. It said the workers' demands would mean shelling out some $70.5 million, a cost it said it could not afford.</p>
<p>Unions said the offered pay hike was insufficient.</p>
<p>Reina on Tuesday was due to meet with the country's security chiefs to discuss the militant state of the country's workers, a government source said. On Sunday Defence Minister Col. Jose Nunez warned that the army was prepared to act against the protests.</p>
<p>But Foreign Minister Delmer Panting denied there was any crisis brewing like that in Ecuador, where two days of paralysing strikes over harsh austerity measures last week led to a congressional vote in which Bucaram was ousted.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONDURAS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
