<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369360" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Anheuser, Modelo deal not dead - analysts.</title>
<headline>Anheuser, Modelo deal not dead - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Martin Roberts</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Analysts were surprised on Tuesday by Anheuser-Busch's announcement that it could not finalize a deal to increase its stake in Mexico's Grupo Modelo, but they said they expected the two companies to reach an agreement eventually.</p>
<p>&quot;It will get resolved at some point in the future. They do have until the end of 1997,&quot; said Marla Marron of ING Barings in New York.  </p>
<p>A source at Grupo Modelo in Mexico City told Reuters the deal stalled because of differences between the Mexican brewer's majority shareholders and Anheuser-Busch over the price per share to be paid in the transaction. The deal was set out in an investment agreement signed in 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;They are holding talks to reach agreement on the price per share,&quot; said a source at Grupo Modelo in Mexico City, who wished to remain anonymous.</p>
<p>&quot;It may go to arbitration as a last resort, which is provided for in the original 1993 agreement, but attempts will be made to reach mutual agreement first,&quot; the source said.  </p>
<p>The source stressed that the 1993 agreement provided for Anheuser-Busch to acquire the shares directly from controlling shareholders in Grupo Modelo.</p>
<p>In 1993, Anheuser-Busch purchased a 17.7 percent direct and indirect interest in Grupo Modelo and its Diblo subsidiary and secured options to purchase an equity position of up to 50.2 percent. These options could be exercised between mid-1995 and the end of 1997.  </p>
<p>In December, Anheuser-Busch's board quietly approved the purchase of an additional 25 percent of Grupo Modelo. On Tuesday the U.S.-based brewer said it was unable to complete the deal.</p>
<p>Marron of ING Barings said she thought the talk of arbitration did not necessarily signal a breakdown in relations between the two companies.</p>
<p>&quot;It could come to that, but I think it's a negotiating stance by Modelo's controlling shareholders,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>Carlos Laboy, an equity analyst with Bear Stearns in New York, said a reference price per share was not inked into the 1993 agreement. Still, he added, the share price in dollar terms had changed little despite the December 1994 devaluation of the peso.</p>
<p>Laboy said news that the deal had been delayed made &quot;it slightly more difficult for the Street to discern what is the strategic role of A-B in Modelo going forward.&quot;</p>
<p>In contrast, Laboy pointed to an agreement between Canadian brewer John Labatt Ltd and Modelo's Mexican competitor Fomento Economico Mexicano SA (Femsa).</p>
<p>&quot;Labatt clearly helps Femsa to sell more Mexican beer in Mexico, and that translates into more earnings per share,&quot; Laboy said.</p>
<p>((--Mexico City newsroom +525 728-7907))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
