<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369333" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: BAESA says reversed operating problems.</title>
<headline>BAESA says reversed operating problems.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's Buenos Aires Embotelladora SA (BAESA) reversed operating difficulties that had caused it losses but is still in a &quot;delicate situation,&quot; President and CEO Luis Suarez said Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The initial 100-day plan launched in July 1996 has been fruitful in reversing the operational difficulties that generated great losses, basically due to the performance in Brazil,&quot; he said in announcing a reduction in first quarter net losses to $16.7 million from $22.9 million the previous year.  </p>
<p>He said financial support from Pepsico, which has operating control over BAESA, and an agreement with its leading creditors to defer until March 31 repayments of capital of about $520 million in debts, gave BAESA the necessary time and resources to improve the operating performance.</p>
<p>Those trends &quot;should allow us the ability to start our process of restructuring our debt,&quot; Suarez added.</p>
<p>However, he cautioned BAESA is still &quot;in a delicate situation, as the cash flow needs, affected by high indebtedness, are still affecting the operations.&quot;  </p>
<p>Suarez said the strengthening of equity structure is a main challenge for the company in the long run.</p>
<p>Executive Vice-President Osvaldo Banos said the company is working to finish a proposed debt restructuring plan to be presented soon to BAESA creditors.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe improvements in operating performance will lay the foundations to implement a global restructuring plan.&quot;  </p>
<p>BAESA, the biggest Pepsi Co bottler outside the United States, has the exclusive Pepsi and Seven-Up franchises for the Buenos Aires metropolitan area and other regions in Argentina, as well as Chile, Uruguay and Costa Rica and certain Southern Brazilian states, including the metropolitan areas of Sao Paulo and Rio de Janeiro.</p>
<p>In September 1996 shareholders of BAESA filed a class action suit in Manhattan federal court against both BAESA and PEPSI alleging they hid the bottler's problems.</p>
<p>In fiscal 1996 BAESA said it lost $452.4 million versus a $44.8 million gain in 1995.</p>
<p>((-Guillermo Haskel, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 541 318-0650))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
