<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369399" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Morning Update.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Morning Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>CONSUMERS UNHAPPY ABOUT DIRECTORY ASSISTANCE CHARGES</p>
<p>A group representing phone users says Telstra needs to realise its free Directory Assistance service helps it make money from phone calls.</p>
<p>The Consumer Telecommunications Network says it won't support Telstra's proposal to charge 50-cents for calls to Directory Assistance.</p>
<p>Telstra wants to encourage people to look up the number themselves, saying Directory Assistance is overused.</p>
<p>The consumer group's Helen Campbell, says a department store will tell you where their shoe department is because they hope you'll make a purchase, and Telstra should take the same approach.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TIGER WOODS WORRIED BY ADMIRATION</p>
<p>American golfing sensation Tiger Woods says the huge public admiration he's receiving worries him.</p>
<p>In Melbourne for the Australian Masters which starts at Huntingdale tomorrow, Woods says when he gets mobbed he fears for his safety.</p>
<p>And he admits he also fears for his wholesome image at such times, because he becomes less than obliging.</p>
<p>Woods says he finds the adoration strange, because all he does is chase a little white ball around.</p>
<p>In world rankings released overnight, Woods is 14th, well behind Greg Norman who is listed as the world's best golfer, with a two point lead over Tom Lehman, from the United States.</p>
<p>Lehman is closely followed by Scotland's Colin Montgomerie, and Ernie Els from South Africa.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>DEADLINE FOR AGREEMENT ON CENTURY ZINC MINE</p>
<p>The company wanting to develop the one-billion dollar Century Zinc mine in north-west Queensland, says it's hopeful the dispute over the project will be resolved today.</p>
<p>Today is the deadline for an agreement on native title issues that have surrounded the project for eight years.</p>
<p>Century Zinc last year withdrew a request for the Queensland Government to pass special legislation to allow the project to proceed.</p>
<p>The company has since been negotiating with Gulf of Carpentaria aborigines under the Native Title Act.</p>
<p>The matter will go to abitration before the Native Title Tribunal if the parties fail to reach agreement today.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SOUTH AUSTRALIAN MINISTER UNDER INVESTIGATION</p>
<p>South Australia's Finance and Mines Minister Dale Baker says he's pleased allegations against him will be brought to a head with inquiries now underway.</p>
<p>Mr Baker will return to the backbench while the police anti-corruption branch investigates allegations about land deals in 1994.</p>
<p>The Government may also have to support an inquiry into allegations Mr Baker had a conflict of interest.</p>
<p>He's been back in Cabinet only two months, following the change of Liberal leadership in South Australia, after being sacked by the former Premier, Dean Brown a year ago.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>NINE TAKING ABA TO COURT</p>
<p>The Nine television Network is taking the Australian Broadcasting Authority to court to test its interpretation of anti-siphoning provisions.</p>
<p>Nine's Chief Executive Officer, David Leckie, says the court action is in response to public outrage at the absence of free live-to-air coverage of the South African cricket tour.</p>
<p>Tour matches will be shown live on pay television.</p>
<p>Mr Leckie says Nine made a generous bid for the live rights, and will ask the federal court to consider whether the ABA erred in its decision to endorse Channel Seven's acquisition of delayed rights.</p>
<p>A Nine network spokesman says the anti-siphoning provisions were introduced to ensure that Australian viewers would have access to sporting events traditionally shown on free to air TV. The touring Australian team is already in South Africa, with its first test match to start on February the 28th.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61- 29373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
