<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369406" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia budget bill due in Senate Wednesday.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia budget bill due in Senate Wednesday.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian government said a key budget bill, to limit migrants' welfare entitlements, was due to be voted on early on Wednesday in the upper house of parliament, the Senate.</p>
<p>&quot;It will probably be voted on in about an hour or an hour and a half,&quot; a spokesman for Social Security Minister Jocelyn Newman told Reuters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The substantial part of our amendments were accepted on Tuesday by the independents,&quot; the spokesman said.  </p>
<p>&quot;By approving that they have basically approved the vast bulk of what we were intending in the bill, and that was the A$200 million worth of savings over four years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Independents Mal Colston and Brian Harradine, who hold the balance of power in the Senate, voted against the bill late last year.</p>
<p>According to government estimates last year's amendments would cost savings of A$130 million in 1997/98, rising to A$400 million over four years.  </p>
<p>Under the Social Security (Newly Arrived Residents' Waiting Periods) Bill, 1996, the government wants to exclude migrants from social security payments for two years after arrival.</p>
<p>A government gains the constitutional option of an early Senate election if the Senate fails to pass a bill in the form demanded by the House of Representatives and then does so again after three months.</p>
<p>This bill was last considered by the Senate less than two months ago.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
