<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369431" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FOCUS-Australia's RBA awaits wages decision.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FOCUS-Australia's RBA awaits wages decision.</headline>
<byline>Bernard Hickey</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reserve Bank of Australia Governor Ian Macfarlane said on Tuesday last year's rate cuts were starting to improve the outlook for employment and investment, comments that economists said indicated rates were now on hold.</p>
<p>Macfarlane said the RBA now would wait for a key decision on wages for the lower paid before changing its assessment on the economy and monetary policy.</p>
<p>Economists had until now generally thought a fourth rate cut in less than a year was possible in the next couple of months.  </p>
<p>But they said Macfarlane's latest comments meant rates were now likely to be put on hold until a key wages decision was made in March or April at least.</p>
<p>&quot;The current feeling is that some of the (rate cut) effects are coming through,&quot; Macfarlane said in answer to a question about future interest rates after an address to the Sydney Institute, a conservative think-tank.</p>
<p>&quot;Our feeling is that the sort of information that we have received over the last couple of months is better than the sort of information we were receiving during the second half of 1996 when we were making those (interest rate) easings,&quot; he  </p>
<p>said, referring to improved investment and housing data.</p>
<p>&quot;The near term outlook for inflation is very good and we think the 1997 outlook for economic activity is also good -- stronger through 1997 than it was through 1996,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The RBA eased monetary policy three times during the second half of 1996, cutting the official cash rate to six percent from 7.5 percent.</p>
<p>Economists had generally thought another rate cut was certain until stronger than expected wages data last week convinced some that the bank would wait.  </p>
<p>Macfarlane said that the bank watched wages data closely for an indication of what inflation would do over the longer term.</p>
<p>&quot;So if you have some important information on this (wages), either from the market sector or the administered sector then it would be only logical to wait until you saw what the results were,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Macfarlane was seen when talking about the administered sector to be referring to the Industrial Relations Court's (IRC) coming decision on a claim by the Australian Council of Trade Unions (ACTU) to increase wages for the low paid.  </p>
<p>The ACTU's 'living wage' claim proposes low paid workers receive an 8.75 percent increase to their standard pay rates and three A$20 a week increases to the minimum wage over three years.</p>
<p>The government has branded the claim as irresponsible and the RBA has said the full claim would imply a marked acceleration in wages growth.</p>
<p>That decision is expected to be delivered in March or April.</p>
<p>Economists said Macfarlane's comments indicated rates were on hold until then at least.  </p>
<p>The Australian dollar, which has been weak against the U.S. dollar early this year in expectation of further rate cuts, rallied to US$0.7615/20 from US$0.7570/75 before the comments.</p>
<p>Ten year bond futures also sold off slightly in overnight trade in disappointment that an imminent rate cut was less likely.</p>
<p>&quot;These points are consistent with the view ... that the RBA was prepared now to delay any action on monetary policy, being encouraged by some early positive signs on growth,&quot; Westpac economist Bill Evans said.</p>
<p>&quot;Macfarlane's latest comments are further support for our view that it is unlikely that the bank will change interest rates throughout the course of 1997,&quot; Evans said.</p>
<p>The financial markets also judged the comments as a sign of no more rate cuts in the near future.</p>
<p>-- Bernard Hickey 61-2 9373-1812</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
