<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369451" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thailand cuts spending to improve current account.</title>
<headline>Thailand cuts spending to improve current account.</headline>
<byline>Vithoon Amorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand unveiled a broad package of budget and public spending cuts on Tuesday designed to rein in the country's high current-account deficit.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Amnuay Viravan won cabinet approval to cut the 1996/1997 national budget by six percent and order 24 state enterprises to tighten their belts by deferring or scaling back utility and infrastructure projects.</p>
<p>&quot;The measures are in line with the tradition of deficit-free fiscal budgets that the government has followed in the past nine years,&quot; Amnuay told reporters.</p>
<p>Central bank governor Rerngchai Marakanond said the package -- which would reduce public spending by at least 99 billion baht ($3.8 billion) -- would help narrow the 1997 Thai current-account deficit to 7.4 percent of gross domestic product from an earlier projected 7.9 percent.</p>
<p>Market analysts saw Amnuay's package as a test of the resolve of Prime Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh's government to improve Thailand's deteriorating economic outlook.</p>
<p>The Thai economy grew 6.7 percent in 1996, its smallest growth in 10 years.</p>
<p>Amnuay sought to convince analysts that the budget cuts fulfilled his earlier pledge to tackle economic problems with fiscal discipline.</p>
<p>Central bank governor Rerngchai said the spending cuts should cause the Thai economy to expand at a slower 6.8 percent rate this year against an earlier targeted 7.1 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The budget cuts confirm Thailand's policy of putting top priority on economic stability. Lately we have achieved stability especially in the CPI...now we have to sacrifice some aspects of growth as a tradeoff for current account stability,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Transport and Communications Minister Suwat Liptapallop told reporters after a cabinet meeting that the government would also curb spending by replacing a 96 billion baht plan to build a second Bangkok airport with an 11.9 billion baht expansion of the city's existing Don Muang airport.</p>
<p>He said expanding the existing airport would prepare it to cope with expected higher air traffic, which is expected to grow to about 45 million passengers annually by the year 2007.</p>
<p>Amnuay said the 59 billion baht to be cut from the 984 billion baht budget in the fiscal year ending September 30 would make up for an expected government tax revenue shortfall of the same amount caused by the slowing of the Thai economy.</p>
<p>He said the National Economic and Social Development Board (NESDB), a Thai think-tank, would work with state enterprises on details of specific spending cuts.</p>
<p>A government spokesman said state enterprises would cut spending by at least 40 billion baht but the cuts could reach 62 billion baht.</p>
<p>He said 16 billion baht could come from delayed or scaled back projects in energy production, 39 billion from highways and transport services, and 6.7 billion from other infrastructure projects.</p>
<p>The minister said state-owned bodies would face lower ceilings under which they could commit fresh foreign loans this year.</p>
<p>(US$1 = 26 baht)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
