<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369548" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US senators warn poor CRP rules will imperil funds.</title>
<headline>US senators warn poor CRP rules will imperil funds.</headline>
<byline>Charles Abbott</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Funding for the Conservation Reserve will be in jeopardy, key U.S. senators warned, if new operating rules to be unveiled Wednesday squander the program's potential to arrest soil erosion and protect water purity.</p>
<p>With their warning, leaders of the Senate Agriculture and Budget committees joined environmentalists and grain groups in concern the new rules would make too much land -- perhaps more than half of U.S. cropland -- eligible for the reserve.</p>
<p>Created in 1985, the reserve pays farmers an annual rent to idle fragile land for 10 years. Annual cost is $1.9 billion.</p>
<p>The Agriculture Department scheduled a news conference for 1100 EST/1600 GMT to announce the new rules, mandated by Congress when it reauthorized the program last year.</p>
<p>About 32 million acres were enrolled in the reserve at present with a maximum of 34.6 million allowed. Contracts on 24 million acres expire this fall. About eight million would not be eligible for re-entry under regulations proposed last fall.  </p>
<p>At that time, the department said land would need an erodibility index of eight or higher to qualify. About 108 million acres potentially could be offered under that rule.</p>
<p>Concern has risen over potential broadening of the rules.</p>
<p>The prairie pothole region of the Northern Plains has been declared a priority area, which could give preferential treatment to land from that three-state region.</p>
<p>Senator Pat Roberts, Kansas Republican, has expressed confidence of &quot;uniformity&quot; in conservation rules. An entire field should be eligible for the reserve, he has argued, if it is required to have an anti-erosion plan. Farmers now must write the &quot;conservation compliance&quot; plans if one-third of a field is subject to high erosion.</p>
<p>Concern also has been raised about possible abuse of rules that allow higher rents to achieve environmental benefits.</p>
<p>Congress has directed that Conservation Reserve rents be based on local cash rental rates.</p>
<p>Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman has tried to dampen concern about the pool of land that might be eligible.</p>
<p>&quot;The proof in the pudding in this is how we implement the program,&quot; Glickman said Tuesday. &quot;The role is to protect the most sensitive, most highly erodible lands in the country.&quot;  </p>
<p>He also said the amount of land to be considered for the reserve was not materially larger than initially proposed.</p>
<p>In a pair of letters, the Republican and Democratic leaders of the Senate Agriculture and Budget committees warned they would be ready to shift funding to other uses if the new operating rules were lax.</p>
<p>The Agriculture Committee leaders said it appeared more than half of U.S. acreage would be eligible, at odds with congressional expectations that U.S. conservation programs to be &quot;more highly targeted and economical in the future.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We ... will not be reluctant to suggest that CRP funds be used for other purposes if our expectations are not met,&quot; the Budget Committee leaders wrote.</p>
<p>Last fall, Glickman said the reserve would be retooled to keep top-quality land in crop production while sheltering fragile land.</p>
<p>&quot;Gone will be the days of retiring productive farmland,&quot; he said, but added he did not expect the reserve to shrink much.  </p>
<p>The reserve includes 10.8 million acres of wheat land, 4.3 million acres of corn land, 2.5 million of sorghum land, 2.8 million of barley land, 1.4 million of oat land and 1.4 million of cotton land.</p>
<p>The Food and Agricultural Policy Research Institute has forecast enrollment would drop to 29 to 30 million acres in coming years. The U.S. Feed Grains Council, in a report last week, forecast enrollment would drop to 28.7 million acres in 1998/99 and then rise steadily to nearly 32 million acres by 2005.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
