<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369749" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - New Omniview chief sees more ventures.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - New Omniview chief sees more ventures.</headline>
<byline>Chris Scott</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The new chief of  Omniview Inc, which makes systems that create 360-degree photo images, said the company is setting up joint ventures aimed at taking its patented process further onto the Internet and beyond.</p>
<p>&quot;(Omniview) has many companies that are setting up strategic alliances,&quot; James Phillips told Reuters, including automakers, publishers and medical research firms.</p>
<p>Earlier, Phillips, former general manager of Motorola Inc's Multimedia Marketing Division, became chairman, president and chief executive officer of Omniview.  </p>
<p>Motorola, which first invested in Omniview in 1994, said Tuesday it is boosting its stake to an undisclosed amount.</p>
<p>Partners of Omniview strategic alliances currently include Toyota Motor Corp, Honda Motor Co Ltd, New York Times Co, Tribune Co and  Discovery Communications Inc, which also bought an undisclosed stake in Omniview.</p>
<p>Omniview's system transforms photographs and videos into 360-degree environments that can be navigated in real-time, Phillips said.  </p>
<p>The Knoxville, Tennessee-based company's products are being used to create sites on the World Wide Web as well as for interactive CD-ROMs, Phillips said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is as close to teleportation as you get,&quot; Phillips said. &quot;It takes you to whatever that location is, whether it's to view a piece of real estate or inside a museum.&quot;</p>
<p>The system uses off-the-shelf cameras with fisheye lenses that Phillips said are currently available to consumers, photojournalists and general photographers.  </p>
<p>The film is sent to Omniview for development into either CD-ROMs or what Phillips described as a &quot;photo bubble&quot; that gives the 360-degree effect for the Web.</p>
<p>Omniview is currently profitable, but it is in &quot;an investment stage,&quot; Phillips said.</p>
<p>Discovery plans to use the software to show 360-degree photographs from various locations around the globe on its Website and has signed a contract for Omniview to create a line of CD-ROM titles, said Phillips, a member of Omniview's board since 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the only system that gives you the full 360-degree view, either recorded or live -- everything from the ceiling to the floor,&quot; Phillips explained.</p>
<p>He added the company's products have applications beyond touring cyberspace, including military and medical products.</p>
<p>&quot;If you're in a tank,&quot; Phillips said, &quot;the idea is that you can put on a photo bubble headset and you've got a 360-degree view if someone is coming up behind you.&quot;</p>
<p>Phillips said doctors will also eventually be able to put a tiny camera on a probe to obtain real-time, 360-degree views from inside parts of the human body.</p>
<p>((Chicago newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
