<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="36974" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - Sept 6.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - Sept 6.</headline>
<text>
<p>DELO</p>
<p>- Slovenian President Milan Kucan sets the general elections for November 10.</p>
<p>- Government resists demands from electricity companies to increase the price of electricity by 9.7 percent.</p>
<p>- Retired ex-Yugoslav general Milan Aksentijevic, who must leave Slovenia by midnight after the Interior Ministry denied his request for residence in Slovenia, said he hoped to come back for New Year celebrations with his family.</p>
<p>- Slovenia has 26 registered political parties, according to statistics from the Interior Ministry.</p>
<p>DNEVNIK</p>
<p>- Opinion poll shows 59.3 percent of Slovenians are satisfied with Kucan's decision to set the election date at November 10, while 8.3 percent say the date is too early.</p>
<p>REPUBLIKA</p>
<p>- August monthly inflation rate at 0.1 percent, which is well below the July rate of 0.5 percent, is expected to push down interest rates of tolar savings accounts.</p>
<p>FINANCE</p>
<p>- Several companies are facing financial problems due to the July liquidation of Komercialna banka Triglav.</p>
<p>- The shares of pharmaceutical trading company Lek rose ahead of the expected listing next week of additional shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
