<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="369889" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss shares close above 4,400 SMI points.</title>
<headline>Swiss shares close above 4,400 SMI points.</headline>
<text>
<p>1540 GMT - Swiss shares overcame a midday dip to end above the 4,400 point mark in the blue-chip Swiss Market Index (SMI) for the first time.</p>
<p>The closing level of 4,408.4 points was also an all-time high and the ninth consecutive record close on the Swiss bourse. After an early correction, which put shares under pressure, bargain hunting and heavy buying of Novartis lifted shares to new highs, dealers said.</p>
<p>* SMI ended up 24.1 points, or 0.55 percent, at 4,408.4.</p>
<p>* The broad Swiss Performance Index (SPI) also hit a new high, adding 11.91 points, or 0.43 percent, to 2,808.04.  </p>
<p>Results of Alusuisse, which announced an eight percent rise in 1996 net profit to 417 million francs, may have disappointed some investors, one dealer said. Alusuisse fell eight francs to 1,201.</p>
<p>* Shares of watchmaker SMH were reportedly pressured by declining Swiss watch exports in 1996. SMH bearers shed 11 francs to 952.</p>
<p>* Among banks, UBS bearers added four to 1,243, SBC lost 1.50 to 275 and Credit Suisse Group was steady.</p>
<p>* Nestle was up seven francs to 1,584.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
