<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="370049" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India sugar firm after govt hikes prices to public.</title>
<headline>India sugar firm after govt hikes prices to public.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian sugar prices firmed on the local market on Tuesday following a government decision to raise selling prices to the public, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Higher consumer demand as well as speculative buying on the back of hike in the sugar prices supplied through the public distribution system dragged prices upward in the open market,&quot; dealers said.</p>
<p>The Indian government on Monday hiked selling prices of sugar supplied through public distribution system from 9.05 rupees per kg to 10.50 rupees per kg.</p>
<p>Ready delivery sugar S-30 rose by 10/20 rupees to 1,270/1,300 rupees per quintal while M-30 moved up by 10/15 rupees to 1,315/1,390 rupees per quintal. Sugar mill delivery was up by 15 rupees at 1,215/1,230 rupees per quintal.</p>
<p>The price of sugar supplied through public distribution system was 6.90 rupees per kg in 1992, 8.30 rupees per kg in 1993, and 9.05 rupees per kg in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;Since 1994 government had not revised prices and burden of the subsidy on government was heavy,&quot; said Shantilal Dedhiya, secretary to Bombay Sugar Merchant Association.</p>
<p>&quot;The hike was overdue and came at last,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Indians consume about 400,000 tonnes of sugar supplied through public distribution system per month.</p>
<p>--Bombay Commodities +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
