<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="370000" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Local buying spurs India shares to higher close.</title>
<headline>Local buying spurs India shares to higher close.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>**  Expectations high ahead of month-end 1997/98 budget</p>
<p>**  National bourse 50-stock index ends 11.30 pts, or 1.15</p>
<p>	  pct higher, at 992.75</p>
<p>**  Delhi share index gains 9.88 pts to 749.16, Calcutta</p>
<p>	  3.84 pts to 454.94 and Madras 47.01 pts to 3,382.89</p>
<p>Indian shares notched smart gains on Tuesday as renewed local operator buying ahead of the federal budget helped pivotals end higher, dealers said.</p>
<p>Participants said speculation that the 1997/98 budget due on February 28 will contain market friendly measures prompted buying.</p>
<p>&quot;With growing expectations about the budget, more players are entering the market,&quot; said chief dealer Ketan Jhaveri at brokerage Kotak Securities.</p>
<p>Some funds were keen buyers in cement stocks in anticipation of incentives likely to be given to the industry, traders said.  </p>
<p>Cement maker ACC jumped 78.0 rupees, or 5.63 percent, to 1,462.25 in volumes of 129,786. Gujarat Ambuja Cement which last week announced a 20 percent rise in net profit for the first half ending December 1996 rose 9.0 rupees, or 3.68 percent, to 253.0 with 435,159 shares traded.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has shown a steady rise today. It is more due to operators building up positions ahead of the budget,&quot; said Ravi Chadha, institutional dealer at brokers Motilal Oswal.</p>
<p>Kotak's Jhaveri said, &quot;The nominal arbitrage opportunities between Bombay bourses indicates that operators are taking delivery based positions.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;This is pre-budget euphoria that we are seeing. A short-term rally is likely to prompt fence-sitters to build up fresh positions,&quot; said a dealer at a foreign brokerage.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign funds however, are not aggressive buyers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the list of pivotal stocks, SBI gained 11.50 rupees to 282.75, TELCO 13.20 to 333.0, L&amp;T 7.0 to 247.50, ITC 8.0 to 409.0 and Reliance 4.50 to 278.0.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has turned volatile and is likely to show two-way movements until the budget,&quot; said Suresh Aggarwal of Delhi brokers Jai Mata Securities.</p>
<p>-- Anshuman Daga, Bombay equities desk +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
