<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37019" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Nomura sees Polish banking sector staying strong.</title>
<headline>Nomura sees Polish banking sector staying strong.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rising demand for credit from retail and small businesses, reflected in real volume growth over the past 18 months, should continue to buoy Polish banks this year and next, Nomura Equity Research said in a report.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that far from being over -- bearing in mind the recent decline in GDP growth estimates and the slackening of export demand -- the Polish banking boom is only just beginning,&quot; the report, dated August 29, said.</p>
<p>Nomura said the Polish banking sector was one of the few in the region which could be relied on for real earnings growth over the next two to three years.</p>
<p>It said the sector had &quot;outstanding growth prospects&quot; with bank lending at 18 percent of gross domestic product compared to 80 percent in the Czech Republic and 40 percent in Hungary.</p>
<p>Nomura said retail loans, which make up 12 percent of Polish bank lending, were generally safe because of Poland's rapid economic growth and had a delinquency rate below one percent.</p>
<p>The report said investors should buy shares of BIG, Bank Gdanski, WBK, Bank Slaski and PPABank, and hold shares of BPH and BRE.</p>
<p>It said BIG had mended a past weakness by gaining a retail base after its 32-percent purchase of Bank Gdanski late last year, and said the three BIG members in Gdanski's management board should help Gdanski.</p>
<p>It said that among Polish banks Slaski best combined retail and regional strength, profitablity, aggressive management and a quality strategic investor in Dutch ING Bank.</p>
<p>Nomura also said Poznan-based WBK should continue to benefit from western Poland's many small and mid-sized firms and from its 36-percent owner Allied Irish Banks Plc.</p>
<p>PPABank should benefit from its portfolio entirely filled by small- and mid-sized business loans.</p>
<p>Nomura said BPH was no longer cheap, after having risen 119 percent, but was not hurt by confusion on whether it would be included in Poland's bank consolidation programme.</p>
<p>It said that though BRE's core market of trade financing was becoming more competitive, it had long-term attractions to foreign investors.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
