<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="370214" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Centennial probing reported results.</title>
<headline>Centennial probing reported results.</headline>
<dateline>BILLERICA, Mass. 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Centennial Technologies Inc said Tuesday it was checking the accuracy of earnings it reported for the quarter ended December 31 and financial statements for prior periods.</p>
<p>Preliminary information has raised significant questions as to whether reported results contained material misstatements, the company said.</p>
<p>The board has appointed a special committee comprised of four directors to oversee the inquiry, it said.  </p>
<p>Centennial said Emanuel Pinez had been removed as chairman, chief executive and secretary, and his employment by the company had been terminated.</p>
<p>Also, James Murphy is being relieved of his duties as chief financial officer until further notice and is assisting the company in its inquiry, it said.</p>
<p>John Shields, vice-chairman of the board, will chair the special committee conducting the inquiry. The panel has engaged independent legal counsel to assist with the probe. The company said independent auditors are also assisting.</p>
<p>The committee will also start a search for a CEO and an interim CFO.</p>
<p>Effective today, J.P. Luc Beaubien and William Kinch, two directors, will assist President John McDonald with the executive management of the company, Centennial said.</p>
<p>Beaubian has served as a director since January 1994 and Kinch has served as a director since July 1995.</p>
<p>The stock closed Monday at 16-3/8.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BILLERICA, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
