<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="370394" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Bottomley rules out BBC privatisation.</title>
<headline>UK's Bottomley rules out BBC privatisation.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's ruling Conservative party would not privatise the BBC if it wins re-election, National Heritage Secretary Virginia Bottomley said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Bottomley told parliament's National Heritage Select Committee that selling off the BBC could jeopardise the standards of broadcasting in Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;To privatise the BBC would seem absolute folly unless there were a host of regulations on offer which are not yet in place,&quot; she said. &quot;In broadcasting we need diversity and we have diversity unequalled anywhere in the world.&quot;</p>
<p>The ruling Conservatives face an election within 3-1/2 months and trail the opposition Labour Party by between 15 and 25 points in opinion polls.</p>
<p>Bottomley said the government's broadcasting policies were aimed at ensuring &quot;variety, choice and quality&quot;.</p>
<p>A memorandum from her department to the select committee highlighted the government's commitment that the BBC should remain Britain's main public service broadcaster.</p>
<p>Bottomley said it was likely the licence fee would remain the BBC's main source of revenue although she welcomed its attempts to branch out into new areas of income.</p>
<p>In December, Bottomley unveiled a five-year formula that will leave the licence fee fractionally lower in real terms at the end of the five years. The fee stands at 89.50 stg for a colour set, rising to 91.50 from April.</p>
<p>The committee was concerned that a flood of new television channels through the advent of digital television would threaten the quality of broadcasting.</p>
<p>Last week, British pay television operator BSkyB said it would press ahead with plans to launch a 200-channel digital satellite service later this year.</p>
<p>The week before, a collection of heavyweight TV companies teamed up to form two new digital terrestrial companies offering about 30 channels initially.</p>
<p>But that is just a drop in the ocean. The Cable Communications Association says digital cable television will offer up to 1,000 channels.</p>
<p>Bottomley said her National Heritage department would be watching the quality issue &quot;like hawks&quot;.</p>
<p>She said the BBC's obligations in terms of high-quality public service broadcasting were enshrined in its Charter and overseen by its board of governors.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't conceive of circumstances where the governors would go against those principles,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>And programming from Channel Four would also get a boost. The government is expected to discuss later this year reducing the levy C4 pays to independent television companies as part of its funding formula. C4 is a non-profit making corporation with a remit to cater for minority tastes.</p>
<p>But Bottomley conceded that the same levels of quality would not be demanded of new broadcasters on digital channels. &quot;Let them fly first, let them be successful and then additional requirements can be imposed later if necessary,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>-- Mike Peacock, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
