<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="370344" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Segers denies match-fixing, says behaved foolishly.</title>
<headline>Segers denies match-fixing, says behaved foolishly.</headline>
<byline>Gideon Long</byline>
<dateline>WINCHESTER, England 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A tearful Hans Segers denied on Tuesday he had thrown a vital soccer match between Everton and his side Wimbledon in 1994 and said football was everything he had in life.</p>
<p>But under cross examination the Dutch-born goalkeeper, charged with fixing matches for an Asian betting syndicate, admitted he had evaded income tax payments, lied to police and twice cheated on his wife by having affairs with other women.</p>
<p>He denies the charge of match-fixing.</p>
<p>The court in the southern English town of Winchester was shown video evidence of the Everton versus Wimbledon match of May 7 1994 -- the last match of the 1993-94 season.</p>
<p>Wimbledon lost 3-2 after taking a 2-0 lead. The result meant Everton retained their place in the premier league and another club, Sheffield United, were relegated.</p>
<p>Segers, questioned by his lawyer Desmond Da Silva, commented on Everton's three goals.</p>
<p>The first was a penalty. Segers dived to his left but the shot went into the net to his right.</p>
<p>&quot;I tried to anticipate the shot,&quot; Segers, 35, explained. &quot;At that time I just guessed the wrong side.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he could do little to save Everton's powerfully struck second goal and had been deceived by the bounce of the ball in the dramatic 81st minute third goal. The third goal was repeatedly shown as it bounced over Seger's hands.</p>
<p>&quot;The pitch at the end of the match is quite rough,&quot; he said. &quot;It's all bits and bobs all over the place. He hit a shot, I dived and had it covered all the way and it just hit a divot and popped up and changed direction.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if he had ever tried to influence a result by deliberately conceding goals, Segers said: &quot;I've never thrown a match, I've never been asked to throw a match.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;At the time the article came out (in which the allegations became public in November 1994) I was really worried. I thought everything was going to be taken away from me, my livelihood... Football was everything I've got. I wake up with football and I go to bed with football.&quot;</p>
<p>His voice quaking with emotion, Segers admitted he had lied to police after his arrest in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sorry for that, I'm sorry I've done that, It's been really hard, really hard,&quot; he said, wiping a tear from his eye.</p>
<p>Later, under cross examination from chief prosecutor David Calvert Smith, Segers admitted he had withheld information from tax inspectors. &quot;You have lied about your income, you now tell us, to the income tax people,&quot; Calvert Smith said.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't lie. I just didn't tell them everything,&quot; Segers replied. &quot;It was very foolish of me.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;You deceived them,&quot; Calvert Smith insisted.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at it that way,&quot; Segers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Have you not looked at it that way?&quot; Calvert Smith asked.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes,&quot; Segers replied.</p>
<p>Calvert Smith asked the former Nottingham Forest and PSV Eindhoven goalkeeper if he had had an extra-marital affair.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a difficult time, yes,&quot; Segers replied.  &quot;I'm sorry Mr Segers, but we're going to have to establish how truthful you are. You cheated on her?,&quot; the prosecutor insisted.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes,&quot; Segers said.</p>
<p>Calvert Smith then asked the Dutchman if he had had a second affair, again without telling his wife.</p>
<p>&quot;That's correct,&quot; Segers said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINCHESTER, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
