<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="370484" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel evicts bedouin to expand Jewish settlement.</title>
<headline>Israel evicts bedouin to expand Jewish settlement.</headline>
<byline>Sami Aboudi</byline>
<dateline>MAALEH ADUMIM, West Bank 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli bulldozers levelled the tin shacks of 11 Palestinian families on Tuesday, sweeping away a bedouin encampment to make room for the expansion of a Jewish settlement in the West Bank.</p>
<p>At least two Palestinians were hurt, including a 13-year-old boy, as police officers carried and dragged members of the Jahalin tribe who sat on the ground arm-in-arm refusing to budge.</p>
<p>&quot;They are throwing us out like donkeys,&quot; one of the bedouin shouted.</p>
<p>African and Thai workers hired by Israeli occupation authorities to help in the evacuation hauled mattresses, pillows and clothes on trucks while bulldozers ploughed through the tin shacks of the 11 families forced out of the site.</p>
<p>Peter Lerner, a spokesman for the Israeli military authorities' Civil Administration, said the land had been reserved for the expansion of the adjacent Jewish settlement of Maaleh Adumim.</p>
<p>The evacuation came as Israel announced it was releasing 31 Palestinian women prisoners under a peace deal with the PLO.</p>
<p>&quot;It is like a front line. What can we do? They are evicting us by force,&quot; said 25-year-old Mousa Mohammed al-Hiresh moments before Israeli soldiers pulled him away by his shirt collar as he stood next to his wife and three children.</p>
<p>&quot;Is this a state? Is this a civilised action? They are evicting us to build for Jews from Ethiopia and Russia,&quot; complained 60-year-old Mohammed Rashid as a bulldozer knocked down his tin shack.</p>
<p>Chief Palestinian negotiator Saeb Erekat condemned the evacuation and said he had filed a complaint with the Israeli government.</p>
<p>&quot;We demanded that Israel stop such measures and to abide by the agreements signed,&quot; Erekat told Reuters.</p>
<p>It was the third wave of evictions this year by Israel of members of the Jahalin tribe, who are scattered across the wilderness east of Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Lerner said the bedouin were squatters on land that was declared state property in 1981, 14 years after Israel captured the West Bank in the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
<p>He said the bedouin would be moved to an alternative site near the Palestinian village of Abu Dees, where each family would be allocated a small land plot on a 25-year-lease.</p>
<p>But members of the tribe said they had been living at the disputed site since Israel forced them to leave their homes in the Negev desert in 1950 and drove them across the demarcation line to the then Jordanian-controlled West Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;I knew the bedouin even before I knew the (Jewish) residents here. They have been living here since before Maaleh Adumim was built,&quot; said Yossi Hasson, 49, an Israeli truck driver from Maaleh Adumim.</p>
<p>&quot;I came here to tell them that I am sorry about what they are doing to them.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAALEH ADUMIM, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
