<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="370563" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Daily Variety - February 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Daily Variety - February 11.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following stories appeared in Tuesday's Daily Variety:</p>
<p>* CBS parent Westinghouse Electric will acquire Gaylord Entertainment's The Nashville Network and Country Music Television cable networks for $1.55 billion in stock.</p>
<p>* The TV arm of Brian Grazer and Ron Howard's Imagine Entertainment has signed an exclusive, multiyear production deal with Walt Disney Television. Although the terms were not disclosed, sources estimated it was worth $10-12 million. Grazer and Howard are known for their films &quot;Ransom,&quot; &quot;The Nutty Professor&quot; and &quot;Apollo 13.&quot;</p>
<p>* TNT and TBS are close to finalizing a network-bypassing output deal for a small film package that includes likely Oscar nominees &quot;Evita,&quot; &quot;The English Patient&quot; and &quot;Shine,&quot; sources said. The deal is part of Time Warner Vice Chairman Ted Turner's quest to land theatricals for his basic cable services.</p>
<p>* George Clooney is being sighted by Jersey Films and Seagram's Universal to star in &quot;Out of Sight,&quot; the adaptation of Elmore Leonard's bestselling novel. Clooney gets $10 million for the role, sources said.</p>
<p>* Andrew Lloyd Webber has cancelled the already delayed June 15 opening of his $10 million musical, &quot;Whistle Down the Wind,&quot; and a new date has not been scheduled.</p>
<p>* Frank Cicha, the senior vice president of research and marketing at Twentieth TV, is expected Tuesday to be named VP of programming at News Corp's Fox TV Stations, in charge of all program buying and scheduling for the 22-station Fox group, sources say.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
