<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="370578" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Alaska governor proposes education endowment.</title>
<headline>Alaska governor proposes education endowment.</headline>
<byline>Yereth Rosen</byline>
<dateline>ANCHORAGE, Alaska 1997-02-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>With Alaska's resource-based economy on the upswing and plenty of money in savings accounts, the state should consider setting up an endowment for long-term education funding, Gov. Tony Knowles said Monday.</p>
<p>The Democratic governor said he wanted a plan for long-term education funding to be put before voters in the 1998 general election.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Alaska, more than any other state in America, has the chance to build a long-term, stable plan, and what a great legacy,&quot; Knowles said in a speech to the Anchorage Chamber of Commerce.</p>
<p>An education endowment could become a &quot;second permanent fund,&quot; he said, referring to a state trust fund established in 1977 when North Slope oil began flowing through the trans-Alaska pipline.</p>
<p>The Alaska Permanent Fund has accumulated assets of $20.5 billion from the state's oil wealth and pays each state resident an annual dividend.</p>
<p>Establishing an endowment to fund education in advance would help Alaska cope with a growing population while insulating school budgets from oil-price volatility, Knowles said.</p>
<p>Education spending accounts for about a third of Alaska's annual operating budget. Knowles has introduced a fiscal 1998 budget of $2.4 billion.</p>
<p>Also Monday, Knowles introduced a bill that he said would simplify and make fairer the formula for disbursing state funds to school districts.</p>
<p>His revised formula includes a $12.3 million addition to be used for rewards to school districts that improve their programs.</p>
<p>&quot;If we're going to put more money into it, we have to get more quality,&quot; Knowles said.</p>
<p>That incentive funding would be only the second addition to state education spending in the past decade, with the exception of adjustments for inflation, Knowles said.</p>
<p>Knowles proposed the incentive funding come from a $1-a-pack tobacco tax increase being considered by the state legislature. The increase, added to the state's current 29 cent-per-pack tax rate, would give Alaska the nation's largest tobacco tax and would raise an estimated $42 million a year for the state.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANCHORAGE, Alaska"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
