<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="370727" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: UPM LWC news signals turnaround - analysts.</title>
<headline>UPM LWC news signals turnaround - analysts.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish forest industry group UPM-Kymmene's announcement that it will raise prices of light-weight coated paper signals an earlier than expected turnaround in product prices, industry analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We expected price hikes at the earliest in the summer -- this is a really positive surprise,&quot; said Jaakko Niemela, chief analyst at Opstock.</p>
<p>&quot;We have now seen the bottom of the price cycle in LWC,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>UPM-Kymmene -- the world's leading manufacturer of coated magazine paper -- said on Tuesday it will raise prices of LWC paper by 5-8 percent during the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>LWC paper is used for magazines and direct mail order catalogues, among others.</p>
<p>Last year, the price of LWC paper fell about 20 percent and it has been over 18 months since UPM announced any price hikes in LWC, analysts said.</p>
<p>Brisker than forecast economic growth in UPM's main markets such as the United Kingdom and the Benelux countries has clearly boosted demand for paper, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Positive economic growth has created demand for paper,&quot; said Jukka Huuskonen, senior investment analyst at Arctos Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;And demand has clearly surpassed expectations,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>UPM's share jumped 1.50 markka to 99.00 on the news, pulling the whole sector sub-index up 1.38 percent. Turnover in UPM's shares was lively at over 16 million markka.</p>
<p>Analysts saw scope for further gains in UPM and other forestry shares, providing that the price increases hold and that there will more increases down the line.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect the stock to gain about 10-20 percent in the near-term,&quot; said one analyst requesting anonymity.</p>
<p>Another Finnish forest industry group, Metsa-Serla Oy, said on Monday that prices of coated papers had turned into a rise but that prices of other paper grades were still in decline.</p>
<p>-- Veera Heinonen, Helsinki newsroom +358-9-680 50 240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
