<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="370915" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ govt concerned by petrol, diesel import margins.</title>
<headline>NZ govt concerned by petrol, diesel import margins.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Energy Minister Max Bradford on Tuesday said he was concerned about rising petrol and diesel importer margins and wanted to encourage competition in the sector.</p>
<p>&quot;There is some evidence of rising petrol and diesel importer margins which is of concern to the government.</p>
<p>&quot;I am keen to see more vigorous competition in the New Zealand petrol and diesel markets than there perhaps is now. This competition should extend to price and not just service,&quot; Bradford told the launch of the private sector energy umbrella group, the Energy Federation.  </p>
<p>Bradford said rising margins were likely to encourage new entry into petrol retailing.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to see supermarket chains and the proposed new supermalls take up the challenge of retailing petrol,&quot; Bradford said, adding that this would put pressure on prices and wholesaler margins.</p>
<p>&quot;I intend to ensure any barriers which may prevent the emergence of competitive retailing by supermarkets are removed.&quot; Bradford said he had a prefence, but not a dogmatic one, for light-handed regulation to address issues of market power and natural monopoly.  </p>
<p>&quot;Information disclosure in particular should, but is not guaranteed to, allow industry players to monitor each other and facilitiate the use of general competition law against each other.&quot;</p>
<p>He said domestic electricity consumers had not yet seen the benefits of reform, and he expected the industry to take &quot;a good hard look&quot; at its domestic contracts.</p>
<p>Industry disclosure requirements would be tightened this year to separate and ring-fence the natural monopoly components from contestible activities.  </p>
<p>&quot;Line businesses will have to operate in a goldfish bowl where their activities, charging systems and contracts are more transparent than at present,&quot; Bradford said.</p>
<p>He said the government was reviewing progress on pricing the Cook Strait cable &quot;and may be faced with having to take further steps to resolve the current inmpasse soon.&quot;</p>
<p>He said New Zealand should not penalise itself by getting ahead of its trading partners in adopting environmental hurdles which would place an extra cost on industry.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
