<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="370944" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian farmers look for rain from cyclone.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian farmers look for rain from cyclone.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A tropical cyclone building off the Queensland coast could do more good than harm to Australia's cotton and sorghum crops but could pose a slight threat to part of the new sugarcane crop, growers' groups said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The impact of the cyclone could be some good rain ... this could blow some sugar cane down but it's early enough in the season that the cane could survive,&quot; Ian Ballantyne, general manager of the Canegrowers group, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Tropical cyclone Gillian is expected to gather strength and head towards the north Queensland coast later on Tuesday, the Bureau of Meteorology said.  </p>
<p>At about 1000 GMT (12 noon local time) Gillian was about 370 km east-northeast of Cairns and had shown little sign of development over the last 18 hours.</p>
<p>It was travelling south-southwest at 10 km an hour, the Bureau said.</p>
<p>Gillian has been rated as a category one cyclone, the least damaging on a scale of one to five.</p>
<p>Ballantyne said there was more concern if the cyclone remained offshore for a prolonged duration, causing it to draw water from the cane fields, currently in mid-growing season.  </p>
<p>The Bundaberg cane-growing would be hardest hit, given particularly dry conditions in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;We've had pretty good rain, except for Bundaberg, where there has been no recharge of water storages,&quot; Ballantyne said.</p>
<p>Australia's 1997 cane crush will not begin until June. The crush normally runs until December.</p>
<p>Rain from cyclone Gillian could assist Australia's cotton crop, now approaching early picking stage, and its sorghum crop, now in planting phase, growers and merchants said.  </p>
<p>Early picking of Australia's northernmost cotton crop, at Emerald in south east Queensland, is due to begin in four to eight weeks, an officer with Cotton Trading Corp said.</p>
<p>Rain would help. It would take a substantial cyclone to affect yields at this stage, he said.</p>
<p>Last week's heat had been good for the cotton crop, he added.</p>
<p>An officer with Queensland grain co-operative Grainco Ltd said Gillian would be of real benefit to the present sorghum crop if it crossed the coast between Bowen and Mackay and worked its way down Queensland's central highlands.  </p>
<p>The northern highlands were also looking for a good two-to-three inches of rain, he said.</p>
<p>If cyclonic rain fell to that extent in central Queensland it could cause a switch to additional sorghum planting from sunflower, he said.</p>
<p>Sorghum crops were looking good south of Emerald but north of Emerald were looking for further rain, he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
