<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="371124" id="root" date="1997-02-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: FEATURE - Settlement bankroller still backs Israel's Netanyahu.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Settlement bankroller still backs Israel's Netanyahu.</headline>
<byline>Colleen Siegel</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aside from gold mines, Australian billionaire Joseph Gutnick says his advantage over Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu when it comes to promoting Jewish settlement on Arab land is that he is not a politician.</p>
<p>Gutnick, faithful to the Habad sect of ultra-Orthodox Judaism which opposes Israel's handing to Arabs lands it deems Jewish by biblical right, is one of a few wealthy individuals who privately fund building Jewish settlements in the Israeli-occupied West Bank and Gaza.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that if he wouldn't have had the pressures that were on him, he wouldn't have made that agreement,&quot; the mining entrepreneur told Reuters on a visit to Israel after the Jewish state withdrew from 80 percent of Hebron in the West Bank under a deal between Netanyahu and the PLO.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't have those pressures, I'm not in the government, I'm an individual who represents a movement, an ideology, which we believe is in the best interests of the State of Israel.&quot;</p>
<p>Netanyahu took office in June opposed to handing occupied land to Arabs. It took seven months for him to implement the Hebron deal reached by the previous government.</p>
<p>The non-Israeli moneymen have an impact in a part of the world periodically teetering on the brink of war over land.</p>
<p>According to Israel's Peace Now movement, all 3,949 homes built in 1995-1996 on the settlements the Palestine Liberation Organisation (PLO) and the U.S. government label obstacles to peace were privately funded.</p>
<p>Peace Now head Mosi Raz said private money was behind about half of some 20,000 homes built since 1992. Israel's Housing Ministry says it does not have figures on privately funded construction in lands the Jewish state captured in the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
<p>LAND BOUGHT FROM ARABS</p>
<p>&quot;I've helped in building a settlement in Efrat...in Shiloh (settlement) and I'm helping building in Hebron,&quot; Gutnick said.</p>
<p>The moneymen, who can do through back channels what Israeli governments might want to do but find awkward diplomatically, do not restrict themselves to building. They also buy land from Arabs in the territories, including Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>And sometimes they help politicians get elected.</p>
<p>&quot;I certainly was behind the concept and encouraged people on this concept 'Netanyahu is good for the Jews',&quot; said Gutnick, 44, citing a campaign slogan from last May's elections.</p>
<p>Habad sources say Gutnick bankrolled their 11th-hour push for Netanyahu, who beat dovish Prime Minister Shimon Peres by less than a percentage point.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no question about it that we believe that we put Prime Minister Netanyahu into office...There's no question about the teamwork between myself and Rabbi Gutnick,&quot; Israel Habad head Rabbi Yosef Aronov told Reuters.</p>
<p>Ironically, Aronov said he and Gutnick were making themselves available to the media because they wanted to dispel accusations that Habad, which has never run a candidate for Israel's parliament, was a political movement.</p>
<p>An Israeli journalist, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said of Habad's claim that it handed Netanyahu victory: &quot;I think it's been overstated (but) the feeling in the public is that it did.&quot;</p>
<p>READY ACCESS TO NETANYAHU</p>
<p>Whether Gutnick and Habad's efforts put Netanyahu over the top, they definitely have easy access to the Israeli leader. Netanyahu's office confirmed that Gutnick and he met on January 22.</p>
<p>It refused to give details. Gutnick was not so shy.</p>
<p>&quot;He found it very difficult to withdraw from Hebron and he's very disappointed about it,&quot; Gutnick said the prime minister told him. He said that while he did not agree with handing back Hebron, he still supported Netanyahu.</p>
<p>&quot;He was very encouraging to me and thanked me for my help to the settlers in Hebron. He wants me to help them...he will definitely give permission to build and expand on land that is already under the control of Jews in Hebron.&quot;</p>
<p>Gutnick's stable of companies is led by Great Central Mines NL, major gold producers in Australia. They recently acquired diamond exploration rights covering one-sixth of mainland China.</p>
<p>But at his marble-walled home-cum-office deep in an ultra-Orthodox section of Jerusalem, the bearded Gutnick, in traditional Jewish skullcap, was planning building for Jews in Hebron.</p>
<p>He said he wanted to add storeys to the Gutnick centre which stands in front of Hebron's Tomb of the Patriarchs, revered by both Moslems and Jews as burial place of their mutual forefather Abraham, and had &quot;five or six projects&quot; in mind.</p>
<p>&quot;Purchasing of Arab land, that may be at a later stage, but this stage is not to aggravate the situation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gutnick is buying breathing room for Netanyahu, whom many have accused of betraying the right-wing ideology that got him elected, in hopes of stiffening his spine to hold onto the rest of the West Bank -- where 130,000 settlers live amid some two million Palestinians -- in final peace talks set to end in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;When we talk about protecting the interests of the settlers, we're talking about a lasting peace that will protect all Jews...He's got a difficult job ahead of him and he'll have the support of myself and whoever I can influence,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
