<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37123" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Colombia signs deal to buy Cuban vaccines.</title>
<headline>Colombia signs deal to buy Cuban vaccines.</headline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cuba and Colombia on Friday signed a health cooperation agreement that foresees Colombian purchases of $5.8 million worth of Cuban medicines, mainly anti-meningitis and anti-hepatitis vaccines, the Cuban news agency Prensa Latina said.</p>
<p>The deal was signed by Cuban Health Minister Carlos Dotres and his Colombian counterpart, Maria Teresa Forero de Saade, who began a visit to the Communist-ruled island on Friday.</p>
<p>Prensa Latina quoted the Colombian minister as saying her country would buy vaccines against Type B meningococcal meningitis and against Hepatitis B produced by Cuba's health industry. The approximate total value of the planned purchases was $5.8 million.</p>
<p>Colombia also hoped to receive specialised training for its health workers from Cuba, Forero de Saade added.</p>
<p>Despite a five-year economic crisis triggered by the collapse of trade and aid ties with the former Soviet bloc, the Cuban government has invested considerable state funds in a bid to develop an international export industry in medicines and pharmaceutical products.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
