<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="371317" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TWA names Gitner as chairman, CEO.</title>
<headline>TWA names Gitner as chairman, CEO.</headline>
<dateline>ST. LOUIS 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trans World Airlines Inc said Wednesday its board elected Gerald (Gerry) Gitner as chairman and chief executive officer. Gitner had been vice chairman and acting chief executive officer since December 1996.</p>
<p>The carrier said Thomas Meagher, formerly non-executive chairman of the board, remains chairman of the board's executive committee and will be the lead director on the board.  </p>
<p>Gitner had been one of three interim senior executives of TWA. He said the two other members of the interim management team -- acting executive vice president and chief operating officer David Kennedy and acting executive vice president- operations Bill Compton -- continue in their present interim roles.</p>
<p>In addition to serving full time as chairman and CEO of TWA, Gitner is chairman of Avalon Group Ltd, a New York investment bank. He has held senior management positions at several major airlines, including vice chairman of Pan American World Airways and chief executive officer of Pan American World Services.</p>
<p>Gitner previously was employed at TWA from 1968 to 1974.</p>
<p>&quot;The board has been impressed with our interim management team's focus on improving the basics of on-time performance and customer service,&quot; said Meagher in a statement, adding he expects to see great progress in these areas under Gitner's direction.</p>
<p>((Chicago newsdesk 312 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
