<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="371354" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hawkins Chemical sees FY97 EPS at $0.64.</title>
<headline>Hawkins Chemical sees FY97 EPS at $0.64.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hawkins Chemical Inc chief executive officer Dean Hahn said on Wednesday the company's earnings per share for the fiscal year ending in Septebmer will &quot;possibly&quot; be $0.64.</p>
<p>&quot;Earnings per share were at $0.59 (in fiscal 1996). With the five percent stock dividend, we'll pro rate that back to about $0.55. In fiscal 1997 we'll possibly be $0.64, and that's with the increase in shares,&quot; Hahn told Reuters after the company's annual shareholders meeting.  </p>
<p>Hahn credited much of the anticipated rise in earnings to the chemical supplier's increased reliance upon Cheese-Phos, a proprietary liquid emulsifier used in cheese processing.</p>
<p>The executive said he expected both sales and profits on Cheese-Phos to double in 1997. &quot;We're expecting our Cheese-Phos business to double in both sales and profits (in fiscal 1997). Sales will be around $3.5 million and profits, $1.6 million,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hahn said by May the company will have installed capital equipment which will reduce the manufacturing time of Cheese-Phos by 80 percent.</p>
<p>He said the company's capital expenditures would decrease this year to about $3 million from $4.3 million in fiscal 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Capital expenditures this year are going to be down to about $3 million and next year they'll drop off more because we've got all the expansion done at our (storage) terminals.&quot;</p>
<p>The company has been expanding its terminal base on the Mississippi River, adding a tank for the storage of caustic soda used in the manufacture of Cheese-Phos.</p>
<p>	 ((Chicago newsdesk 312 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
