<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="371514" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tenet Health at ease with 1997 estimates.</title>
<headline>Tenet Health at ease with 1997 estimates.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tenet Healthcare Corp Chief Financial Officer Trevor Fetter said Wednesday he was comfortable with earnings per share estimates of $1.46 for the fiscal year ending May 31.  </p>
<p>Speaking to Reuters after a company presentation at the Smith Barney Health Care Services Conference in New York, he also said the company was at ease with analysts' EBITDA (earnings before interest, tax, depreciation and amortization) projections of about $1.6 billion for the year and expected to meet or beat those projections.</p>
<p>Speaking of Medicare and the impact of any potential legislation on the company, Fetter said the &quot;effect will be relatively small in relation to earnings.&quot;  </p>
<p>During the presentation, Chairman and Chief Executive Jeffrey Barbakow said the company targeted $55 million of operating savings from its merger with OrNda HealthCorp, much of which was slated for the first year.</p>
<p>Rationalization of facilities would be carried out in Orange County and Los Angeles County, Calif., over the year, but Barbakow declined to be more specific.</p>
<p>Barbakow said Tenet would continue its strategy of acquisition-led growth and currently had about $700 million worth of acquisitions pending in the pipeline. He said the company was also looking at joint ventures.  </p>
<p>In a response to an analyst's question about acquisition strategies, Barbakow suggested the company had been approached by the Dallas-based non-profit hospital network Baylor Health Care System for possible combinations, but declined to elaborate.</p>
<p>Fetter said Tenet had over $2 billion left under its credit facility and would use part of it to fund acquisitions.  </p>
<p>Last month, Tenet announced it issued $2 billion of debt in the high yield markets and had also established a new revolving credit facility of $2.8 billion. Part of the proceeds were used to repurchase substantially all of OrNda's public debt and to repay both companies' previously outstanding bank debt.</p>
<p>According to Fetter, the company's debt currently stood at about $5.3 billion.</p>
<p>He said an investment grade rating was achievable in two to three years, depending on the level of acquisitions.</p>
<p>The company carries a rating of BB/Ba1, just below investment grade, from Standard &amp; Poor's and Moody's Investors Service.</p>
<p>Tenet's merger with OrNda, valued at $3.5 billion in stock and debt, was completed at the end of January and gives the combined entity about $8.8 billion in pro forma revenues. ---Kamalakshi Mehta, New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
