<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="371662" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-BETIS SHAKE UP SPANISH HIERARCHY.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-BETIS SHAKE UP SPANISH HIERARCHY.</headline>
<dateline>SEVILLE, Spain 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>In the past the Real Madrid-Real Betis fixture scheduled for Saturday used to be a David and Goliath-style clash in which the only question really in doubt was the number of goals by which the home side would win.</p>
<p>But in the last few years Betis, together with Deportivo Coruna, have shaken up the hierarchy of the Spanish game and are no longer to be taken so lightly.</p>
<p>Betis have emerged perhaps not as kings, but at least as pretenders to the throne in this year's Spanish title race.</p>
<p>It is an unlikely role for the Seville-based side that for many years had to play second fiddle not just to the Madrid and Barcelona sides, but also to neighbours Sevilla.</p>
<p>Whereas the name of Real Madrid is almost synonymous in Spain with wealth, success and power, that of Real Betis is more readily identified with frustation and heroic failure.</p>
<p>Not that it bothered Betis' flamboyant following. They continued to pack the Benito Villamarin stadium even when the side were in the third division.</p>
<p>Whereas Sevilla traditionally monopolise the support of the city's wealthier classes, Betis tend to find their fans amongst the poorer sections of the community, amongst them Seville's famous gypsy clans.</p>
<p>Betis is also the favourite side of many flamenco musicians and bullfighters.</p>
<p>But all too often Betis's performance on the field would have been enough to inspire a 'cante jondo', or 'deep song', a wailing flamenco lament.</p>
<p>But after several years in the second division in which Betis looked likely to disappear under a sea of debt, the club has hit a more up-beat rhythm.</p>
<p>Conducted by owner Manuel Ruiz de Lopera and Serra Ferrer, who after over 100 games in charge is the Spanish first division's longest serving manager, Betis have reappeared with a vengeance.</p>
<p>A self-made multi-millionaire who once sold caps and scarves at Betis matches, Lopera has given the club the financial backing it never had in the past.</p>
<p>He spent over 3 billion pesetas ($21.1 million) over the summer in players, amongst them former Real Madrid striker Alfonso Perez.</p>
<p>Lopera's next signing, Ajax winger Finidi George, was widely interpreted as a snub to the Madrid side because of the problems they had caused in the Alfonso transfer.</p>
<p>Just this week Lopera has confirmed that he doesn't like taking a back seat in dealing with Spain's big two.</p>
<p>&quot;If they're not good enough for Barcelona, they're not good enough for Betis,&quot; he said in response to reports that Barcelona may offer reserve players in exchange for the much-coveted Alfonso.</p>
<p>And he has big ideas for the future.</p>
<p>Lopera is reluctant to join Sevilla in plans for a new athletics stadium which would form the centrepiece of Seville's bid for the 2004 Olympics.</p>
<p>Instead he has asked architects for proposals for a new 70,000 all-seater venue of his own.</p>
<p>And while financially-troubled Sevilla are nose-diving toward the second division, Lopera's Betis could yet open their new stadium with a European Champions' League game.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEVILLE, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
