<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="371652" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-ALBERT BELLE ADMITS TO GAMBLING LOSSES.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-ALBERT BELLE ADMITS TO GAMBLING LOSSES.</headline>
<dateline>CLEVELAND 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Cleveland Indians home run basher Albert Belle admitted under oath in a legal deposition that he lost up to $40,000 gambling on pro football and college basketball games, a newspaper reported Wednesday.</p>
<p>Belle, who left the Indians this offseason to sign a $55 million free agent contract with the Chicago White Sox, made the admission Tuesday in a lawsuit filed over a 1995 incident in which he chased a group of boys that threw eggs at his house, the Cleveland Plain-Dealer reported Wednesday.</p>
<p>Belle's attorney, Jose Feliciano, told the newspaper that his client bet only on football and basketball and not on baseball games.</p>
<p>&quot;Albert, like many other players, does bet on games outside of his own sport,&quot; Feliciano said.</p>
<p>Baseball personnel are strictly prohibited from betting on Major League games and could be banned for life if bets were placed on games involving their own team.</p>
<p>A Major League Baseball spokesman declined to comment on the report.</p>
<p>White Sox vice president of major league operations Ron Schueler issued a statement saying: &quot;We do not have any information at this time so we are not in a position to comment.&quot;</p>
<p>Belle made the gambling admission while being questioned by an attorney for one of the boys in the egg throwing incident, the Plain-Dealer reported.</p>
<p>A local court found the four boys delinquent of criminal mischief last year. But Sandra Abdul-Razzaaq, a guardian of one of the boys, is suing Belle for $850,000 in damages, saying the boy was injured while being chased by Belle in his Ford Explorer.</p>
<p>Cleveland lawyer Richard Lillie, representing the boy, told the Plain-Dealer he was questioning Belle about gambling and other issues as &quot;another way of impeaching his credibility.&quot;</p>
<p>Lillie said he also questioned Belle about his well documented temper outbursts, alcoholism treatment and numerous suspensions from baseball.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CLEVELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
