<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37168" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Analysts approve of Brazil's CVRD sale plan.</title>
<headline>Analysts approve of Brazil's CVRD sale plan.</headline>
<byline>William Schomberg</byline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>A plan outlining the sale of Brazil's mining giant Companhia Vale do Rio Doce (CVRD) meets with market expectations and represents another step towards Latin America's biggest privatization to date, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're heading into the final phase,&quot; said an analyst in Sao Paulo who asked not to be named.  &quot;The risks of Vale not being privatized are now minimal.&quot;  </p>
<p>Brazil's National Privatization Council (CND) approved Thursday a plan to sell off a 40-45 percent chunk of CVRD's voting shares -- which would constitute a holding dubbed Valecom -- in a cash-only auction, probably in February 1997.</p>
<p>Employees would then be offered 4.45 percent of CVRD's voting stock and six percent of non-voting shares, followed by the sale of remaining voting shares via domestic and international public offerings, probably in June.  </p>
<p>The Brazilian government currently owns 76 percent of CVRD's voting stock and about six percent of its non-voting stock, jointly equivalent to 51 percent of its total capital. CVRD's privatization is expected to raise about $6.0 billion.</p>
<p>The CND also decided:</p>
<p>-- to allow big producers, consumers and traders of iron ore to buy up to 45 percent of Valecom;</p>
<p>-- to require Valecom have at least three owners;  </p>
<p>-- to give the government two &quot;golden shares,&quot; one to ensure its rules for the make-up of Valecom are observed for an initial five years, the second giving it veto powers over any attempt to spin off CVRD's iron ore, railway and port operations.</p>
<p>Marcello Mesquita, an analyst with Banco Garantia in Sao Paulo, said the golden share rules appeared to open the door for CVRD's future owners to sell other big areas of the company's business, principally its paper, aluminum and steel operations.  </p>
<p>&quot;That kind of thing had been hoped for because it will allow the new investors to sell areas with less synergies and invest the cash in the railways and gold sectors, which are the most profitable,&quot; Mesquita said.</p>
<p>He also welcomed the decision to allow CVRD competitors and clients into the 40-45 percent block sale, albeit in restricted form, because the greater the number of bidders, the better the chances of high bids in the auction.</p>
<p>But there were still question marks over how minority shareholders would be allowed to offer their shares during the auction of Valecom.</p>
<p>And the CND appeared not to have touched on a plan to issue the government and existing minority shareholders  &quot;mineral debentures&quot; entitling them to royalties from future development of areas to which CVRD has exploration rights.</p>
<p>-- William Schomberg, Brasilia newsroom 5561 2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
