<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="371721" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: HUNGARY'S HORN TO TESTIFY IN &quot;TOCSIK-AFFAIR&quot;.</title>
<headline>HUNGARY'S HORN TO TESTIFY IN &quot;TOCSIK-AFFAIR&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian Prime Minister Gyula Horn and Ivan Peto, head of ruling coalition partner Free Democrats will be asked to testify before Parliament's committee looking into an 1996 privatisation scandal dubbed the &quot;Tocsik-affair&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The hearings will take place next Monday, Tuesday or Wednesday, depending on when it is convenient (for the two party leaders),&quot; Tamas Deutsch told committee members Tuesday evening.</p>
<p>A special parliamentary committee was formed last December to look into the Tocsik affair, in which an adviser to state privatisation agency APV Marta Tocsik received 800 million forints for negotiating land deals with municipalities on APV's behalf.</p>
<p>Revelations of the payments led Horn to dismiss last October the entire APV board and the minister in charge of privatisation, Tamas Suchman.</p>
<p>Horn told Parliament on Monday he is ready to appear before the Parliament's committee.</p>
<p>Horn also told Parliament neither the government, nor the Socialist Party is involved in the privatisation scandal.</p>
<p>At today's hearing only two of the six persons called to testify appeared, among them Socialist Party treasurer Laszlo Boldvai, who only said he refuses to participate in what he called the committee's biased activity.</p>
<p>&quot;A number of opposition members of the committee do not display the required impartiality,&quot; Boldvai said and left without giving the committee the chance to ask their questions.</p>
<p>A Budapest court has started proceedings in the Tocsik-case in January, and at the request of Chief Prosecutor Kalman Gyorgyi, Parliament last week lifted the immunity of Boldvai, following evidence that may implicate him in the affair.</p>
<p>($=171.23 Hungarian forints)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
