<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="371824" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PRESS DIGEST-Australian Sports News - Feb 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-Australian Sports News - Feb 13.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>The Australian Rugby League wants the clubs playing in its competition this year to sign contracts committing them to a 1998 season with the organisation. The documents have been mailed to the clubs. The move follows suspicion that some of the league's stronger clubs are planning to defect to the rebel competition, Super League. Page 36.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Zoran Matic, the coach of a major Australian soccer team, Collingwood, claims that the Australian national soccer league could collapse within four years if a salary cap is not introduced. The claim follows reports that Club Carlton is planning to pay hundreds of thousands of dollars for new players. Page 35.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Noted Australian jockey, Jim Cassidy, will made his comeback at the Sydney racecourse, Flemington on Saturday. It will be the first time in two years that Cassidy has competed in a professional competition. He was banned by the Australian Jockey Club in1994 for his participation in the controversial Sydney jockey tapes affair. Page 35.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Australia's chances for swimming gold at the 2000 Olympics are already being determined by the athletes coaches. The spotlight is being shined on Gennadi Touretski whose methods have been criticised by some but who is very popular with his swimmers, in prticular World Cup champions Australian's Michaell Klim and Matthew Dunn. Page 52.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian cricket team has their first practice session in South Africa yesterday, but were driven off the field by a thunderstorm. Australia will play its first match in South Africa this weekend at Randjesfontein, near Johannesburg, with the first Test match occurring in two week's time. Page 54.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In the opening match of this year's Rugby Union competition the New Zealand team, Waikato's defeated the New South Wales A team, the Waratahs by 25 to 13. The match was a close fought one, with the Waikato's failing to take control of the match until well into the second half. Page 54</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>The Australian athletics championship, the Nike Track Classic, is to see Roger Kingdom and Jack Pierce, two of the best hurdlers in the world, will compete against Australian champion Kyle Vander-Kuyp. Vander-Kuyp was a finalist in the 1995 world champioship and last year's Olympic Games. Page B6.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian Rugby League is to decide later this month whether a Melbourne based team is a viable proposition. Sources say the proposal is being considered seriously with the possibility of a Sydney team being relocated. Page B8.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>American superstar golfer Tiger Woods, yesterday praised the abilities of Australian golfer Robert Allenby. He first saw him play at the 1995 Scottish Open and is not underestimating the threat Allenby poses to him in the upcoming Australian Masters Open Woods said he believed that Allenby could win the tournament. Page B8.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE HERALD SUN</p>
<p>Former West Indies cricket captain Richie Richardson has warned Australian cricket captain Mark Taylor of premature burnout. He has warned that Taylor needs to be more sparing of his time in order to cope with the rigours of the modern season scheduling. Page 94</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian golf player Robert Allenby is the local favourite to win the Australian Masters, the opening round of which is held today. He is confident of his chances and does not appear intimidated by golfing superstar American Tiger Woods. Allenby last on the championship in 1994. Page 90</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The ninety ninth Austral Wheelrace will by held on Saturday night at Northcote Velodrome, Melbourne. It is one of the premier events in Australian cycling history with most of Australia's major cyclists having competed in it. Page 88.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>The Brisbane Broncos a team in the rebel Australian rugby competition, Super League, have launched an major publicity campaign to retain its old fan base and recruit a new one. This includes store and school appearances, sponsorship deals and autograph sgning sessions. Page 83.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian commentators have called for closer scrutiny of the Australian cricket team when it tours South Africa later this year, with those who misbehave by verbally abusing players from the opposite team being sent home, no matter their professional status. Page 85.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Linford Christie, former Olympic and world champion, will make his professional debut at the Botany Bay Gift athletics carnival in Australia, later this month. He will be the first Olympic 100m gold medals to run in an Australian gift race. Page 86.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
