<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="371876" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Burundi fighting reported after U.N. says it quiet.</title>
<headline>Burundi fighting reported after U.N. says it quiet.</headline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Heavy fighting has been heard near the capital in recent days, residents said on Wednesday, a day after the head of the U.N. refugee agency reported there was almost total security in Burundi.</p>
<p>Burundi's army also said there had been clashes with rebels in the northwest following its major offensive against them.</p>
<p>U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees Sadako Ogata had told reporters it was hard to know for certain in a one-day visit but &quot;I have the impression that security is almost total.&quot;</p>
<p>The comments -- although she also said it was still not safe for refugees to be repatriated -- contrasted with the reports of continuing fighting.</p>
<p>More than 150,000 people have died in massacres and civil war between the Tutsi-dominated army and Hutu rebels since the 1993 assassination of its first freely elected Hutu president.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been skirmishes in Cibitoke province,&quot; said army spokesman Lieutenant-Colonel Isaie Nibizi. &quot;These correspond with the end of our operations in the Kibira forest, where we have dismantled rebel bases and seized lots of military equipment.&quot;</p>
<p>Army officers from Cibitoke province, who declined to be identified, said the army had taken losses in recent encounters with the rebels, especially around Murwi commune. Cibitoke is considered the most dangerous province in Burundi.</p>
<p>In addition, Bujumbura residents said over the last few days and nights they heard regular, heavy fighting around the capital, including mortar fire.</p>
<p>Hitoshi Mise, the U.N. refugee agency representative in Burundi, told Reuters that Ogata had gained her impression through talks using interpreters.</p>
<p>&quot;What we can do is say that generally the security situation is improving, not in the entire 15 provinces, but in several of them,&quot; said Mise, who accompanied Ogata during her visit.</p>
<p>&quot;Since July 25 last year, the security situation has improved. As an expatriate I would say that incidents involving expatriates have significantly dimished, but we cannot deny allegations about other security incidents,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The civilian government was overthrown in an army coup last July 25. Military ruler Pierre Buyoya, hit by regional sanctions against his government, has promised peace talks with Hutu rebel groups but they have failed to start.</p>
<p>The U.N. human rights office said on January 29 the army had killed at least 1,000 people in the seven weeks to January 21 in a new escalation of violence in the three-year civil war.</p>
<p>Prison officers said Augustin Nzogibwani, secretary general of the Frodebu party that was in power until the July coup, was arrested on Tuesday and taken to prison.</p>
<p>His wife said police gave her a statement accusing him of distributing anti-government tracts, inciting civil war and making false statements that could create panic. Nzogibwani has compared camps where the army puts Hutu peasants, officially for their protection against rebels, to concentration camps.</p>
<p>In Nairobi, a Burundian government minister complained on Wednesday that Burundi had lost more than $200 million because of regional sanctions that block exports of Burundi's main foreign revenue earner coffee and halted imports.</p>
<p>Environment Minister Bernard Barandereka was allowed to bypass a travel ban on Burundian government officials to attend a U.N. Environment Programme conference in Nairobi last week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
