<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372059" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares set high, seen losing steam.</title>
<headline>Polish shares set high, seen losing steam.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares set a 34-month high after Tuesday's dip but analysts said the stronger selling after price-fixing signalled the bourse was losing steam after having gained about 32 percent since mid-December.</p>
<p>They said the main market, currently at 17,700.4 points after apparent heightened foreign buying, could pierce 18,000 later this month before a deeper profit-taking correction hit.</p>
<p>&quot;Ratios for some stocks seem pretty overheated, almost asking for the stocks to be sold,&quot; said Pawel Dmytryk, a trader at Bank Staropolski brokerage, who saw the market flat or slightly down on Thursday.  </p>
<p>The main market's all-share WIG index rose 0.9 percent to 17,700.4 points and turnover rose 4.9 percent to 254.2 million zlotys on both markets.</p>
<p>Some analysts said Wednesday's continued high trade and lower number of orders meant growth was possible on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we're yet at the point of the growth trend where lots of small investors start joining and then there are falls,&quot; said Janusz Oleksak of Bank Slaski brokerage.</p>
<p>Analysts said the next major signal for the market would be January earnings data due early next week, which could be good after last week's news that the month's industrial climate improved.  </p>
<p>Analysts said top gainer Budimex, up 6.4 percent in heavy trade to 26.6 zlotys, was enjoying an upturn after consolidating at just below 23 zlotys.</p>
<p>They said Prochnik, up 5.9 percent, benefited from a Tuesday bourse kerb transaction after a National Investment Fund said it would buy 9.99 percent of the firm.</p>
<p>They said Olawa fell 5.3 percent after revising down its 1996 earnings due to additional income tax.</p>
<p>NFI units were flat at 165 zlotys in the regular session and at 163 zlotys in live trade where stocks were mixed in 17.8-million-zloty trade.</p>
<p>-- Steven Silber +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
