<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372068" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Evicted Mostar Moslems not returned - U.N..</title>
<headline>Evicted Mostar Moslems not returned - U.N..</headline>
<byline>Samir Koric</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Moslem residents expelled from the Croat dominated west Mostar in the last wave of evictions have yet not returned to their homes despite claims by authorities otherwise, a U.N. spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody of the people evicted since the incident had been reinstated to their homes,&quot; U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) spokesman Kris Janowski told Reuters.</p>
<p>He denied earlier claims by a senior Bosnian Croat official that all expellees had returned to their homes.</p>
<p>A Croat member of Bosnia's collective Presidency and President of its Moslem-Croat Federation Kresimir Zubak, speaking at a news conference in Sarajevo on Wednesday confirmed evictions of Moslem families from west Mostar over the last few days.</p>
<p>But he said that they were all allowed to go back.</p>
<p>&quot;Our attitude on that is firm and all those families were returned, as far as I know,&quot; Zubak told reporters.</p>
<p>NATO-led peacekeeping troops and Western envoys struggled to defuse tensions in the divided Bosnian city after Croats shot and stabbed Moslems who had sought to mourn their dead in Liska cemetary in the Croat-held western quarter on Monday.</p>
<p>As international police monitors investigated the violence that killed one Moslem and wounded at least 20, U.N. human rights workers reported an alarming upsurge in expulsions and intimidation of up to 5,000 Moslems remaining in west Mostar.</p>
<p>Bosnian Croat media claimed a number of their policemen were wounded in the incident but this could not be confirmed by international organisations in Bosnia.</p>
<p>Zubak said there were reports of four Bosnian Croat policemen stabbed with knives during the incident.</p>
<p>Michael Maclay, spokesman for the International High Representative for Bosnia, told a news briefing that Croat leaders in Mostar started action on Wednesday morning to undo the latest wave of ethnic evictions.</p>
<p>Maclay was unable to give details of the action involved.</p>
<p>But Alexander Ivanko, spokesman for the international police monitors, said six more people were evicted from west Mostar overnight.</p>
<p>Until Monday, 82 cases of evictions from west Mostar had been recorded since December 1995, when the Dayton peace agreement halted 43 months of fighting in Bosnia.</p>
<p>Relief workers said on Tuesday Croat police were blocking Moslems trying to cross back into west Mostar after day trips to the east in what amounted to de facto evictions.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is quite tense, freedom of movement is hampered and we are very worried about the fate of the Moslem minority remaining in west Mostar,&quot; Kris Janowski said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
