<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372004" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine parliament votes foreign credit suspension.</title>
<headline>Ukraine parliament votes foreign credit suspension.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukraine's parliament voted on Wednesday to stop the government from borrowing money abroad until it passes a new law on foreign debt in March.</p>
<p>Deputies voted 239 in favour and five against the suspension of foreign credits, which also ordered parliament's Finance and Banking Committee to guarantee deputies a say in Ukraine's borrowing when it drafts the law.</p>
<p>&quot;The role of deputies in substantiating the need for foreign credits, the conditions for their enlargement, and future control of effective disbursement should be recognised,&quot; the motion stated.</p>
<p>The government can ignore the motion, passed a day after deputy finance minister Serhiy Makatsaria told parliament that Ukraine's foreign debt had grown to $8.84 billion on January 1 from $8.04 billion a year ago.</p>
<p>The government was asked to demonstrate to deputies in March how it had used foreign credits, and deputies ordered money to be used to boost sagging industrial production and help the flagging agricultural sector.</p>
<p>About $4.205 billion of Ukraine's debt is owed to the former Soviet republics of Russia and Turkmenistan for energy.</p>
<p>The IMF will decide whether to approve a three-year, $2.5-3.0 billion Extended Fund Facility (EFF) once Ukraine passes the 1997 budget, probably in March.</p>
<p>--Yuri Kulikov, Kiev Newsroom +380 44 229 2264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
