<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372174" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>ECUADOR: Ecuador's Congress to appoint new president.</title>
<headline>Ecuador's Congress to appoint new president.</headline>
<byline>Gilles Trequesser</byline>
<dateline>QUITO, Ecuador 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ecuador's Congress met on Tuesday to appoint its leader, Fabian Alarcon, as the country's new president for the second time in five days, capping a turbulent week in Ecuadorean politics.</p>
<p>The vote, which political sources said was a foregone conclusion, was expected to end a bizarre political crisis triggered by last week's ouster of populist leader Abdala Bucaram.</p>
<p>At a news conference shortly after the start of the extraordinary session of Congress, interim president Rosalia Arteaga said she would step aside and return to the vice presidency if Congress elected a president.</p>
<p>The week's political turmoil, which at one point saw three people claiming the presidency, began on Thursday with the dismissal by a divided Congress of Bucaram, a quirky populist whose antics earned him the nickname &quot;El Loco&quot; (The Madman). The 49-year-old Alarcon was swiftly sworn in as the new president.</p>
<p>Carnival-like confusion ensued, with the defiant Bucaram initially refusing to step down, doing so only after the military withdrew its support. In turn, Vice President Arteaga claimed transitional power under what she said were constitutional rules.</p>
<p>But under the new accord, Alarcon, Ecuador's 41st president in the country's 167-year history, is to hand over power on Aug. 10, 1998, to a democratically elected head of state. General elections are tentatively scheduled for May next year.</p>
<p>Ecuador's shaky transition process, which many bemused observers saw as another surreal episode in Latin America's unpredictable politics, remained clouded until the end by Arteaga's insistence on respecting the Constitution and not stepping down.</p>
<p>Arteaga said nobody could assume the presidency until a constitutional reform was passed empowering Congress to appoint presidents. Such a reform had to be approved by a two-thirds majority of the 82-member Congress.</p>
<p>If Congress appointed Alarcon, Ecuador &quot;will enter a period of congressional dictatorship,&quot; she told reporters before the vote.</p>
<p>At her news conference, she called for a referendum within three months to solve what she called the country's &quot;constitutional void.&quot;</p>
<p>But amid accusations she was clinging to power, Arteaga, Ecuador's first woman president, if only for two days, apparently bowed to pressure to step aside.</p>
<p>Some analysts said the &quot;irrational&quot; episode, which unfolded over carnival holidays, might leave deep scars on the small Andean nation's political scene.</p>
<p>&quot;Politicians have shown an amazing lack of maturity,&quot; said Santiago Nieto, of the consulting firm Informe Confidencial. &quot;They allowed everybody to see how power-hungry they were and how little they cared about the country's interests.&quot;</p>
<p>Another analyst, who requested anonymity, said Bucaram's swift dismissal on grounds of &quot;mental incompetence&quot; could set a dangerous precedent.</p>
<p>&quot;Sane leaders could be given the boot for the same crazy reasons ... if the Constitution is not reformed, it will happen again,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The accord paving the way for Alarcon to take over as president specified that he could be appointed by a simple majority of Congress, without any constitutional reforms.</p>
<p>Bucaram dismissed the vote as a sham and a &quot;national disgrace&quot; and said Ecuador had fallen into the hands of &quot;a traitor, a Judas.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Some countries won't see kindly that Ecuador has a president (who is the) product of a dictatorship,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bucaram left the country on Tuesday for Panama on a tour to tell regional leaders that he was deposed in what he called a military-backed &quot;congressional coup.&quot;</p>
<p>He told reporters at Guayaquil airport that he would denounce that &quot;corruption has taken over in Ecuador.&quot; From Panama, he said he would go on to Argentina to meet President Carlos Menem and then to Colombia and Haiti and &quot;other Latin American countries.&quot;</p>
<p>Bucaram said he would return to Ecuador next Tuesday but rumours immediately circulated that he would stay abroad, possibly in Panama, where he fled to a few years ago when he was mayor of Guayaquil after he was charged with corruption.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="QUITO, Ecuador"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ECUADOR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
