<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372169" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia strike holds; talks restart Thursday.</title>
<headline>Colombia strike holds; talks restart Thursday.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Union leaders said a nationwide strike by Colombia's 800,000 state employees, in its second day on Wednesday, would not be lifted until the government gave firm guarantees to meet labour demands.</p>
<p>Hernando Hernandez, head of the main oil union, said talks with government ministers would restart at 7 a.m. Thursday (1200 GMT) but doubted there would be any quick deal to end the indefinite work stoppage.</p>
<p>Workers continued to man picket lines outside public offices and hospitals around the capital and in other major provincial cities. Armed forces chiefs said they remained on maximum alert to counteract street violence or a threatened wave of guerrilla attacks timed to coincide with the strike.</p>
<p>No marches were planned for Wednesday but labour leaders said thousands of demonstrators would be bused in from the provinces to Colombia's five main cities for the biggest protest rallies of the strike so far on Thursday -- regardless of the planned renewal of negotiations.</p>
<p>A demonstration in downtown Bogota on Tuesday ended in running battles between riot police and a 200-strong group of protesters, hurling bricks and bottles. There were no reports of injuries, however, and police said there were no other major outbreaks of violence elsewhere in the country.</p>
<p>&quot;Negotiations will restart Thursday morning. We want the presence of ministers with economic and political portfolios. But the government has already said it doesn't have much room for manoeuvre and we will not budge on our demands,&quot; Hernandez said.</p>
<p>State workers called the strike to press for a 21.5 percent pay hike, compared to the government's weighted 13.5 percent offer, and are protesting a series of planned privatisations and what they claim is a repressive labour code.</p>
<p>&quot;We have said that the strike will not be lifted until there's a concrete agreement with the government and guarantees that these will be fulfilled,&quot; said Eberto Lopez, head of the state phone company (Telecom) union.</p>
<p>Union and government officials continued to issue conflicting reports on the strike's effects. In comments late Tuesday, President Ernesto Samper branded the industrial action a virtual failure, saying only 10 percent of state workers heeded the strike call.</p>
<p>Workers' representatives said the strike was &quot;total&quot; and had severely disrupted key economic and social services, including oil, telecommunications, education and all but emergency health care.</p>
<p>Transport associations, though not directly involved in the strike, said road freight had dropped by as much as 30 percent, as truck drivers stayed off the roads for fear of guerrilla attacks. A truck drivers' spokesman said he believed flowers, coffee and banana cargoes had been hardest hit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
