<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37223" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo cool to anti-Japan sentiment over island row.</title>
<headline>Tokyo cool to anti-Japan sentiment over island row.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo reacted coolly on Friday to anti-Japanese sentiment brewing in Hong Kong and Taiwan over a territorial dispute regarding a group of South China Sea islands.</p>
<p>&quot;I think you are well aware of the Japanese position regarding the Senkaku (Diaoyu) Islands and I will not repeat it here,&quot; Foreign Ministry spokesman Ken Shimanouchi told a regular news conference.</p>
<p>Tokyo has said the tiny uninhabited islands are Japanese and that their sovereignty is not negotiable. The islands, which are thought to have significant untapped oil reserves, lie about 300 km (190 miles) west of Okinawa and 200 km (125 miles) east of Taiwan. They are claimed by Tokyo, Beijing and Taipei.</p>
<p>Japan's moves to assert sovereignty over the islands have angered Chinese in Taiwan, Hong Kong and mainland China.</p>
<p>On Friday, Taiwan's foreign ministry angrily protested Japan's use of coast guard vessels to force a private Taiwanese ship away from the islands.</p>
<p>&quot;The Ministry of Foreign Affairs expresses its serious regret over the Japanese government's action,&quot; the ministry said in the latest twist in the simmering sovereignty row.</p>
<p>&quot;It hereby reiterates the Diaoyu islands are part of our existing territory. This position is unquestionable,&quot; the statement said. &quot;The (Taiwan) government's determination to protect our territory will never change.&quot;</p>
<p>Activists and World War Two survivors with bitter memories of atrocities committed by Japan have staged a spate of anti-Japanese protests over the past month in Hong Kong. The British colony reverts to Chinese sovereignty next July 1.</p>
<p>Shimanouchi said he hoped the long-running row over the islands would not sour Japanese ties with Beijing and Taipei.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's important not to lose sight of the big picture,&quot; Shimanouchi said, referring to the importance of stable ties between the three neighbours.</p>
<p>The latest dispute over the uninhabited islands broke out in July when a rightist Japanese pressure group built a lighthouse on one of the islands.</p>
<p>On Thursday, a group of pro-Beijing activists marched to the Japanese consulate in Hong Kong and presented a petition to protest Japan's claim to the islands.</p>
<p>Taiwanese television said on Friday that a second private fishing boat that left for the islands before dawn was escorted away by Japanese patrol boats, but not before an old Japanese imperial flag was burned aboard their vessel.</p>
<p>Taiwan has no diplomatic ties with Japan, which recognises only Beijing's communist government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
