<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372269" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru rebels and government agree on further talks.</title>
<headline>Peru rebels and government agree on further talks.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Peruvian government and Marxist rebels holding 72 hostages at the Japanese ambassador's home in Lima agreed at talks on Tuesday to hold further negotiations to end the 56-day-old crisis, mediators said.</p>
<p>The mediators from the Vatican and Canada told reporters that both sides had agreed on the procedures for future negotiations to be held at a date yet to be set.  </p>
<p>After four hours of talks between government negotiator Domingo Palermo and the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement's (MRTA) second-in-command Rolly Rojas, the mediators, Bishop Juan Luis Cipriani of the Vatican and Ambassador Anthony Vincent of Canada, read a short statement to reporters in Spanish then in English.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we began the preliminary conversations. We have agreed the procedures to follow in future conversations and we have agreed to continue the conversations at a date yet to be set,&quot; said the statement.</p>
<p>The meeting was the first time the guerrillas and the government had met face-to-face since Palermo talked with MRTA leader Nestor Cerpa Cartolini on Dec. 28.</p>
<p>The crisis began when 15 heavily-armed MRTA rebels stormed the residence during a cocktail party on Dec. 17 and seized over 500 guests. They later freed most of hostages but kept 72, including two Peruvian ministers, the Japanese and Bolivian ambassadors, about two dozen Japanese businessmen and the brother of Peru's president.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
