<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372294" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: INTERVIEW - ANZ Funds bullish on New Zealand economy.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - ANZ Funds bullish on New Zealand economy.</headline>
<byline>Catherine McCaw</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>ANZ Funds Management general manager Anthony Quirk said on Thursday his firm had a very positive view on the long-term prospects for New Zealand's economy, one which he thought foreign investors would share.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no doubt there is a little bit of a dip at the moment in the economy, and that the high exchange rate is hurting some sectors. But one has to take a longer term view, and no country ever got rich by having a weaker currency,&quot; Quirk said.  </p>
<p>He said a speech by new Treasurer Winston Peters at a business breakfast on Tuesday will have soothed a few fears among offshore investors about the controversial New Zealand First party leader's plans for the economy.</p>
<p>In the lead-up to October's general election Peters argued the New Zealand dollar was too high and was hurting exporters.</p>
<p>On Tuesday he said the National/NZ First coalition government would not react to &quot;short-term crises&quot; in the exchange rate and would let the market respond as it saw fit.  </p>
<p>&quot;Winston Peters' speech was very dry and very orthodox, and I think that's very positive for the economy and for the financial markets longer term,&quot; Quirk said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think he realises you can't talk down currencies.&quot;</p>
<p>Quirk said some investors had recently exited large stocks such as Telecom and Carter Holt Harvey, fearing the companies were experiencing a dip in fortunes due to the strong dollar and competitive pressures.</p>
<p>But he described the current softness in the economy as an &quot;aberration&quot;.  </p>
<p>&quot;Long term we're very positive about the New Zealand economy...it's still relatively robust.</p>
<p>&quot;Interest rates have come down reasonably dramatically and that's going to help some segments. The only concern would have to be those sectors that are adjusting to the firm currency.&quot;</p>
<p>ANZ Funds Management expects economic growth to pick up in the second half of this year.</p>
<p>Quirk said total inflows in the retail managed funds industry were a paltry NZ$23 million in the December quarter, which suggested they were being influenced by factors other than the economy.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think there's a more endemic problem in the industry. I think the December quarter really should have been an improving quarter. Rates were coming down, the election was over -- two aspects which actually should have started to put money in but haven't.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a basic problem in the industry of convincing people of the merits of managed funds.&quot;</p>
<p>Quirk said ANZ was pleased with its own inflow performance in a relative sense but could have done better if the industry had been &quot;burning&quot;.  </p>
<p>&quot;People still don't seem to have a mentality that they can lock away funds for the longer term...awareness is starting to improve, but the industry seems to be missing that link from people understanding they have to save for their retirement, and actually how they do that.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of it comes back to the industry to actually make our products a lot simpler,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Quirk said lower interest rates in the March quarter could prompt a pick-up in retail managed funds, and said lengthy political coalition negotiations may have dampened December quarter data.  </p>
<p>&quot;I'll be interested to see the March quarter figures for the industry. I know in our case there hasn't suddenly been a wave of inflows...it's just carried on pretty much the same as last year.&quot;</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
