<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372241" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico Cetes rate tilts upward on soft peso.</title>
<headline>Mexico Cetes rate tilts upward on soft peso.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Like a puppy chasing its tail, Mexican Cetes rates rose slightly on Wednesday in an initial response to a soft peso -- which fell on a dramatic plummet in primary interest rates last night, traders said.</p>
<p>The benchmark overnight rate rose 44 basis points to 20.14 percent this morning. Nonetheless, traders said rates could fall to Tuesday's levels as the market is liquid and peso weakness was being reined in by dollars pouring into the stock market.  </p>
<p>&quot;Rates will stay down. Some felt the primary rate fall was excessive, but the market is still liquid and the peso has stood up well,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Primary rates on bellwether 28-day Cetes dropped 176 basis points to 19.69 percent at Tuesday night's central bank auction, their eighth consecutive fall and lowest level since the December 1994 peso crisis.</p>
<p>Some traders added that recent flows of capital into the Mexican markets were not sufficient to explain such a sharp fall in primary rates as the one seen Tuesday night.  </p>
<p>&quot;Although capital is flowing in, bids at the primary auction took a real dive and we don't expect primary rates to fall further in the coming months,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Benchmark 48-hour peso contracts were 0.65 of a centavo weaker in earlier trade at 7.7975/7.8000 per dollar.</p>
<p>The peso's fall was broken by the continuing tide of dollars entering Mexico's stock market. The bolsa's leading IPC index was up 1.18 percent to 3,794.22 points in early trade.</p>
<p>Overnight rates on bank paper meanwhile opened down five basis points at 21.65 percent.  </p>
<p>Liquidity of 311 million pesos was expected to re-enter to the system during the session from prior central bank money market intervention.</p>
<p>((-- Patricia Lezama, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9554))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
