<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372337" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>LAOS: Laotian silk firm revives lost art.</title>
<headline>Laotian silk firm revives lost art.</headline>
<byline>Katya Robinson</byline>
<dateline>VIENTIANE, Laos</dateline>
<text>
<p>In a stately French colonial mansion in the Laotian capital, a group of women spin silk threads, work looms and revive an ancient tradition.</p>
<p>&quot;The handicraft sector has become the priority of the government, and now it's on the mental map of visitors,&quot; said weaver and designer Carol Cassidy.</p>
<p>Cassidy, the first American to register a business in Laos, started Lao Textiles in 1990 after discovering that most local weavers were using polyester rather than silk fibers.</p>
<p>&quot;Handwoven silk wasn't available then,&quot; the 40-year-old Connecticut native said. &quot;Now we're setting a new standard for what people expect for textiles from Laos.&quot;</p>
<p>In the impoverished communist nation of 4.5 million people, Cassidy's fabrics are fast becoming a new benchmark for foreign entrepreneurs while exposing an old tradition to global markets.</p>
<p>Her rectangular-shaped works are used mainly as scarves or wall-hangings, finding demand from New York to Hong Kong and costing from $85 for shawls to several thousand dollars for pieces that take six months to weave, she said.</p>
<p>The company's staff of 35 workers produce about 30 to 50 pieces a month depending on the complexity of the design, she said, adding that an expansion is being considered.</p>
<p>The products of Lao Textiles have travelled far from quiet Vientiane. They are displayed at New York's prestigious Fashion Institute of Technology and in Hong Kong and Sydney, Australia, Cassidy said.</p>
<p>Some foreign customers consider her the Jim Thompson of Laos -- a nod to the American who helped develop Thailand's silk industry.</p>
<p>After training weavers for the United Nations, Cassidy started the business in Laos, spurring the socialist government to preserve the country's silk-weaving tradition.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is taking on a more dynamic, active role. They are sending Lao entrepreneurs to workshops. There is a real emphasis on small business devlopment,&quot; said Cassidy. Her business, for example, receives a government tax exemption.</p>
<p>Textiles have been central to Laotian culture for hundreds of years, dating back to the 14th century. Woven patterns, incorporating a rich mix of mythical and religious symbols, revealed a woman's family origins, village, ethnic group and marital status.</p>
<p>Women who were accomplished weavers were respected in their communities and sought after by prospective husbands.</p>
<p>But the disruptions of French colonialism, Japanese occuption during World War II and American bombings in the 1960s and 1970s dealt the industry a near-fatal blow.</p>
<p>Weavers began spending less time on their work and when Cassidy arrived in 1989, polyester and cotton were the threads of choice, rather than labour-intensive, hand-raised silk.</p>
<p>But despite the country's attempts to woo investment through its 1993 investment law and its growing support for entrepreneurs, there remained a lack of educated Laotian managers and absence of copyright laws, Cassidy said.</p>
<p>She said she found no legal recourse after a customer recently copied one of her designs in Chinese silk.</p>
<p>Despite that, most customers were loyal and tended to choose her work for important occasions, she said. &quot;I recently did the designs for a Lao-Scottish American wedding in San Francisco.&quot;</p>
<p>Cassidy, married with two children, said she developed a passion for silk fabrics during a trip to Mexico at age 12. She studied textiles in Norway and Michigan and taught mohair weaving in African villages for seven years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LAOS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENTIANE, Laos"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LAOS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
