<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37249" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Mobil chief seeks business in Vietnam.</title>
<headline>Mobil chief seeks business in Vietnam.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mobil Corp Chairman Lucio Noto told Vietnam's leaders that his firm was hoping to be included in oil exploration ventures now under consideration by the Hanoi government, a senior Mobil executive said on Friday.</p>
<p>However, he said Noto did not mention specific projects during meetings in Hanoi with Communist Party Secretary General Do Muoi and Prime Minister Vo Van Kiet on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The discussion didn't get into specifics,&quot; Robert Haines, President of International Government Relations, told Reuters by telephone from Ho Chi Minh City.</p>
<p>He said Noto's meetings in Hanoi, including one with the head of Vietnam's state oil and gas firm Petrovietnam, were &quot;courtesy visits&quot; rather than negotiating sessions.</p>
<p>Mobil is one of four candidates which have been shortlisted for an exploration licence at block 15-1, one of Vietnam's most promising offshore areas.</p>
<p>Industry sources have named the other contenders for the block, which is believed to have reserves of oil and associated gas, as:</p>
<p>- a consortium led by the Dupont Co unit Conoco Inc with South Korea's Petroleum Development Company and Yukong Oil</p>
<p>- Geopetrol of France</p>
<p>- a consortium of Exxon Corp, British Petroleum Co Plc, Norway's Statoil and Mitsubishi Oil.</p>
<p>Haines said there were four other outstanding concessions in Vietnam in which Mobil hoped to have a share.</p>
<p>Speaking more generally of Mobil's business in Asia, Haines said the company had a very good position in a market which it believed was one of the most dynamic in the world.</p>
<p>&quot;That said, there have been some challenges in the Asian market recently. But over the long haul, the future looks bright and we are well positioned,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the same applied to the global picture.</p>
<p>&quot;Round the world things may not be looking as good right now as they have in the past, but they will improve. You can't take the oil business one quarter at a time.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
