<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372555" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX Hub natgas ends down, then sinks on AGAs.</title>
<headline>NYMEX Hub natgas ends down, then sinks on AGAs.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub gas futures, hit by technical selling on forecasts for mild weather next week, sold off sharply Wednesday, then sank further after a bearish weekly gas inventory report, industry sources said.</p>
<p>March tumbled 13.4 cents to close at $2.09 per million British thermal units, then skidded on ACCESS to $2.01 after the AGA data. April settled 9.5 cents lower at $2.052. Other deferreds ended down by 2.5 to 8.1 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;What else can you say? It's (the AGA number) pretty bearish, but some of it may have been factored into today's selloff,&quot; said one East Coast trader.  </p>
<p>AGA said late Wednesday that U.S. gas stocks fell last week by 60 bcf, well-below expectations, with overall stocks now 212 bcf, or 20 percent above year-ago. Eastern stocks are now 261 bcf, or 50 percent, over last year, a factor likely to keep the Gulf cash on the defensive, particularly with mostly moderate weather expected next week.</p>
<p>Despite brief cold snaps in Texas, the Midwest and Northeast this week, most forecasters were looking for seasonal to above-seasonal U.S. temperatures next week.</p>
<p>While the AGA draw was in line with heating degree day calculations, most were surprised that eastern operators did not cash in on the steep backwardation in prices and trim inventories.</p>
<p>While the market may be oversold and due for a bounce, most technical traders said any rally was likely a selling opportunity. They said a break of psychological support at $2 should lead to a move to the $1.90 area and then a possible test of the contract low at $1.749. Resistance was seen in the $2.25-2.30 area and then in the low-$2.50s.</p>
<p>In the cash, Gulf Coast prices firmed Wednesday by more than a nickel to about $2.40. Midcon pipes held relatively steady in the low-$2.30s. New York city gate gas firmed by 10-15 cents to about $3 on expectations for one or two more days of cold.</p>
<p>The 12-month Henry Hub strip slipped 5.5 cents to $2.106. NYMEX said an estimated 44,436 Hub contracts traded, up from Tuesday's revised tally of 32,491.</p>
<p>NYMEX Alberta and Permian natgas did not trade Wednesday.</p>
<p>On KCBT, March finished 14.2 cents lower at $1.848, while deferreds ended down by 1.5 to 9.5 cents. The East/West spread widened by 0.8 cent to 24.2 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>((J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
