<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372643" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT wheat closes lower as export ideas dashed.</title>
<headline>CBOT wheat closes lower as export ideas dashed.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT wheat futures closed lower as hopes faded for an increase in wheat exports due to transportation problems in Canada, traders said.</p>
<p>Wheat rallied sharply late Tuesday on fund short covering tied to the traffic tie ups in Canada that led to ideas for a hike in quick shipments of U.S. wheat, mainly spring wheat.</p>
<p>But Asian customers overnight indicated there probably would not be a noticable increase in U.S. wheat exports.</p>
<p>Japan's Food Agency said it has no immediate plans to buy more U.S. wheat despite serious shipping delays at Canadian ports.</p>
<p>Mickey Luth, director of research for the Chicago-based LaiFa Group said the Canadian problem may have given the market a boost but the rally was temporary and wheat futures will go back to test contract lows.</p>
<p>Traders said the wheat market gave a pacing glance to USDA's February supply/demand report.</p>
<p>USDA said 1996-97 U.S. wheat carryout would total 474 million bushels, slightly above the 469 million bushel carryout forecast by USDA in its January report.</p>
<p>Wheat closed unchanged to 4-3/4 cents per bushel lower, with March down 4-3/4 at $3.57-1/4 a bushel.  </p>
<p>Traders said the KCBT hard red winter wheat futures market gained roughly two to three cents per bushel on spreads with CBOT soft red on USDA's ending stocks projection.</p>
<p>USDA said total 1996-97 U.S. ending stocks would be 474 million bushels, above the 469 million projected in January. The government increased to 43 million bushels its outlook for soft red winter ending stocks from the previous 28 million bushels. But the hard red winter ending stocks figure was trimmed to 144 million bushels from the previous 159 million bushels.</p>
<p>Traders said Cargill Inc and R.J. O'Brien each sold two million bushels of March. Refco Inc, Iowa Grain and LIT America each sold one million bushels of March, traders said.</p>
<p>Chartists said first support in the March was $3.54-1/4 and second support was at $3.42-1/4. The session low for March was $3.54. First resistance was at $3.66-1/4 and second resistance was at $3.78-1/4. The session high for March was $3.62.</p>
<p>The nine day relative strength index (RSI) for March closed at 38 percent. The market generally considers an RSI of 30 or less as an oversold market.</p>
<p>Wheat futures volume was estimated at 24,000 contracts, above the 23,392 traded Tuesday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>In wheat options, Tradelink Futures bought 250 May $3.70 calls at 7-1/2 cents, Cargill Investor Services bought 200 March $3.60 calls at three cents and sold 200 March $3.70 calls at one cent.</p>
<p>Wheat options volume was estimated at 3,500 contracts, below the 3,799 traded Tuesday.</p>
<p>((Sam Nelson 312-408-8721))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
