<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372666" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Boston kids surf on-line porn in library - report.</title>
<headline>Boston kids surf on-line porn in library - report.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Children are using the Boston Public Library's access to the Internet to view pornography, the Boston Herald reported Wednesday.</p>
<p>Parent John Hunt told the newspaper he was furious to learn that his 11-year-old daughter was able to view pornography at the library while she was working on a school essay.</p>
<p>&quot;She said all the boys were around the computer and they were laughing and called the girls over to look at pictures of naked people,&quot; Hunt told the newspaper. &quot;I want to find out from these library officials what is going on.&quot;</p>
<p>Library spokesman Arthur Dunphy, who could not be immediately reached for comment, told the Herald, &quot;We do have children's librarians, but we don't have Internet police.&quot;</p>
<p>Dunphy told the newspaper that a Philadelphia federal court decision last year banned the government from forcing libraries to censor materials on the Internet for children because it violated their First Admendment rights.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Boston's City Council is expected to hold a meeting Wednesday to demand action.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm a believer in early learning, but not this kind of early learning,&quot; City Councilor Peggy Davis-Mullen told the Herald.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
