<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372614" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. West spot power extends gains on outages.</title>
<headline>U.S. West spot power extends gains on outages.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>News of another power plant outage in the western U.S. Wednesday helped spot electricity prices extend yesterday's gains, market sources said.</p>
<p>A 750 megawatt (MW) unit at the coal-fired Navajo generating station in Page, Ariz., was reportedly shut Tuesday for boiler tube repairs.</p>
<p>That outage followed Sunday's shutdown of a 755 MW unit at the Four Corners coal-fired plant, also due to a tube leak.</p>
<p>There has also been talk of a 330 MW unit at the Colstrip coal-fired power plant in central Montana, that has been down since Monday, but its status could not be confirmed.</p>
<p>Outages of the three units tightened short-term power supplies, and forced some players in the Northwest and Southwest to cover their day-ahead schedulings, traders said.</p>
<p>Firm, peak electricity at the California-Oregon border (COB) for Thursday widened to $12.00-$13.50 a megawatt hour (MWh) from $12.50-13.50 Tuesday.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak COB deliveries for Thursday were quoted at $7.00-7.50, a slightly tighter range than the $6.50-7.50 heard for Wednesday deliveries.</p>
<p>Firm, peak electricity at Mid-Columbia (Mid-C) for Thursday rose to $11.00-11.75 from $10.50-11.50 Tuesday, while off-peak Mid-C for day-ahead delivery stayed at $6.00-7.00.</p>
<p>Firm, peak Palo Verde (PV) electricity climbed to $14.00-15.00 from Tuesday's $13.50-14.00, while off-peak deliveries held at $7.00-9.00.</p>
<p>Next-day firm, peak power at Four Corners was quoted at $14.00-15.00 from $13.00-14.00 Tuesday, while off-peak remained at $7.00-9.00.</p>
<p>Forward COB and PV values held steady from Tuesday's levels. &quot;They are still in the same narrow ranges,&quot; a Northwest trader said.</p>
<p>Firm, peak COB power for the second quarter was quoted at $10.35-10.60 and third quarter $16.55-16.75.</p>
<p>Firm, peak PV electricity for Q2 delivery was assessed at $13.90-14.10 and Q3 at $22.35-22.50.</p>
<p>Temperatures in the Northwest were forecast to average 3 to 6 degrees F above normal through Friday with peak readings in the 30s-40s. Showers are expected to continue across the coast while valley rain and mountain snow were called for in the interior regions.</p>
<p>In the Southwest, temperatures will likely remain 2 to 4 degrees F below normal ahead of the weekend, with day readings reaching the 50-60 degree range. Low pressure in the southeastern part of the region could cause precipitation through early Thursday.</p>
<p>Separately, swing gas prices at the Sumas export point on the U.S.-Canada border firmed 25 cents to the $2.15 per million British thermal unit level and those at the Permain Basin area in the Southwest held at $2.24-$2.28.</p>
<p>((--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
