<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372630" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cohen wants to limit U.S. peace missions abroad.</title>
<headline>Cohen wants to limit U.S. peace missions abroad.</headline>
<byline>Jim Adams</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Defence Secretary William Cohen said on Wednesday he would be more selective about committing U.S troops to peace missions around the world and would avoid diverting funds from regular military tasks.</p>
<p>&quot;We should not be the world's policeman. We can't be a prisoner of world events and we may be required to respond to some cases which do not involve our vital interest,&quot; Cohen told congressional hearing.</p>
<p>&quot;But we have to be much more selective, much more restrained in (committing) our men and women to areas which are going to ... drain what needs to be done as far as keeping our readiness up and also funding the (weapons) modernisation account,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He was speaking before the House of Representatives National Security Committee at the start of congressional hearings on President Bill Clinton's proposed $265 billion defence budget for the year beginning next October.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we have to look very carefully at how many operations we commit our troops to,&quot; Cohen told the panel.</p>
<p>Cohen, who took over the defence post from William Perry last month, has already said he will strictly adhere to a June, 1998 deadline for pulling U.S. troops out of Bosnia, where they are part of the international force.</p>
<p>He repeated that pledge on Wednesday, saying: &quot;I plan to work hard to help ensure that the participation of U.S. ground troops in Bosnia will indeed end by June of 1998, as planned.&quot;</p>
<p>According to NATO plans, the 8,500-member American contingent in the international force of some 31,000 is supposed to be reduced gradually, along with others, and the status of the force is to be reviewed every 6 months.</p>
<p>Cohen said U.S. participation in the Bosnia mission will cost about $6 billion at a time when U.S. military readiness programmes need funding.</p>
<p>Republicans who control Congress want at least $7 billion more for defence next year than the $265 billion Clinton has requested. One top Republican said the level of the Clinton proposal would lead the nation on a road &quot;fraught with peril.&quot;</p>
<p>Representative Floyd Spence, the Republican chairman of the committee, told Cohen what he considered a low budget request would mean a smaller military force, spread thinner to meet U.S. commitments around the world.</p>
<p>Spence said he feared U.S. military services would eventually have to choose between paying for combat readiness and training they need or buying weapons they need because they will not be able to afford both.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a road fraught with peril and one, unfortunately, that this nation has already been down with disastrous consequences several times this century,&quot; Spence said.</p>
<p>Cohen disagreed, saying the new request would pay for readiness, weapons and a military able to meet U.S. global commitments. But he pledged to work hard for cooperation between the administration and Congress on defence spending where possible.</p>
<p>Cohen, the first Republican in Democrat Clinton's Cabinet, told the Republican-controlled committee that &quot;on matters of national defence, bipartisanship and cooperation are essential.&quot;</p>
<p>Most of the questioning at the initial hearing was on details of the defence budget request and parochial issues such as base closings and whether Air Force maintenance depots should be privatised or consolidated to save money.</p>
<p>In many cases, Cohen did not spell out hard administration positions but instead promised to meet with the members of Congress to try to work out agreements on those problems.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
