<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372779" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Albright may visit India, Pakistan. [CORRECTED 22:30 GMT]</title>
<headline>Albright may visit India, Pakistan. [CORRECTED 22:30 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Carol Giacomo</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Secretary of State Madeleine Albright is considering a trip to India and Pakistan, which would be the first substantive visit to those countries by a U.S. secretary of state in 14 years, U.S. officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Albright, in office since Jan. 23, has talked about making such a trip with senior aides, and specialists in the State Department's South Asia bureau are strongly encouraging it. But no decision has been made, officials told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone in the bureau has tried to get their hooks into her for an early commitment but we have nothing definite,&quot; one official said.</p>
<p>&quot;We'd like to raise the profile of South Asia in the foreign policy arena. Also, these visits are very useful for getting cooperation on a broad range of issues,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another official said: &quot;Albright would like to make a trip there. She's talked about it. She's interested in that part of the world.&quot;</p>
<p>This year marks the 50th year of independence of both India and Pakistan and officials say for that reason it would be an especially auspicious time for the secretary of state to travel there.</p>
<p>The last U.S. secretary of state in Pakistan was George Shultz, who made a lightening visit in 1988 (corrects year) for the funeral of President Zia ul-Haq, who was killed in a plane crash with the U.S. ambassador Arnold Rafael.</p>
<p>The last substantive trip to India and Pakistan was also by Shultz, in June-July 1983.</p>
<p>The Clinton administration in recent years has tried to strengthen ties with both countries, which are considered by Washington to be threshold nuclear states which could quickly produce atomic arms if they wanted to.</p>
<p>To that end, Deputy Secretary of State Strobe Talbott went the area in March 1994.</p>
<p>Although Washington has traditionally had close ties to Pakistan, there have been tensions over arms sales and nuclear cooperation between Islamabad and Beijing. And while relations with India have improved, there are differences over Russia's proposed sale of nuclear reactors to New Delhi as well India's refusal to sign the Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty.</p>
<p>Testifying before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee recently as part of her confirmation process, Albright said during her tenure she would again &quot;consider the prospects for reducing the tensions that have long existed&quot; between India and Pakistan.</p>
<p>Albright embarks on her first overseas trip as secretary of state on Saturday when she leaves on an 11-day tour of major European and Asian capitals.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
