<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372756" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MGM unveils partnership for Detroit casino.</title>
<headline>MGM unveils partnership for Detroit casino.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>MGM Grand Inc, the hotel and gambling company based in Las Vegas, on Wednesday unveiled plans to partner with a group of Detroit community and business leaders to pursue a casino license in that city.</p>
<p>MGM Grand also said its bankers have agreed to boost the company's credit line to $1.0 billion from the current $600 million, giving it the ability to finance a hotel/casino in Detroit and continue expansion in Las Vegas and Atlantic City.</p>
<p>The local group partnering with MGM Grand is currently comprised of nine business, civic and community leaders.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are prepared to bring to the people of Detroit and to the State of Michigan an emotionally engaging facility that will attract tourists from the Midwest region, Canada, and from throughout the world,&quot; MGM Chief Executive Officer Terrence Lanni said in a statment.</p>
<p>MGM will not finalize its project plans until after requests for proposals (RFPs) have been issued by the city.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be premature at this time to propose specific plans for the project,&quot; Lanni said.  </p>
<p>The local investment group includes:</p>
<p>-- William Pickard, a business executive who also is acting as the group's spokesman.</p>
<p>-- Joseph Davis, director of the National United Auto Workers Civil Rights Department and national board member of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference</p>
<p>-- Jane C. Garcia, community awareness specialist, U.S. Census Bureau, and VP of United Way for Southeastern Michigan</p>
<p>-- Anthony Grainer, president and CEO of Malan Realty Investors Inc ; and major contributor, Helping Hands</p>
<p>-- Dr. Arthur Johnson, retired Wayne State University vice president and vice chairman of New Detroit, Inc.</p>
<p>-- Dr. Edward Littlejohn, professor of law emeritus, Wayne State University Law School and former chairman of the Detroit Board of Ethics</p>
<p>-- Roy S. Roberts, vice president and general manager, Pontiac-GMC division, General Motors Corp ; and board of directors, United Negro College Fund</p>
<p>-- Myzell Sowell, senior partner, Sowell and Evelyn, attorneys at law; and life member, board of directors, NAACP</p>
<p>-- Dr. Lorna Thomas, medical staff member of the Detroit Medical Center; board of trustees, Detroit Receiving Hospital.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
