<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372894" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India shares close shade lower in dull trade.</title>
<headline>India shares close shade lower in dull trade.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares at Indian bourses drifted lower in lacklustre trade on Wednesday, with market action focused on pivotal stocks, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market opened firm, but showed signs of weakness towards close on little buying support,&quot; said a dealer at an institutional brokerage in Bombay. &quot;Select bidding by foreign funds helped some stocks close with small gains.&quot;</p>
<p>The 30-share index of the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) ended 18.79 points, or 0.54 percent, down to 3,483.48 after rallying to 3,525.34 at mid-session.  </p>
<p>Funds were bidders in blue chips such as Glaxo, Oriental Bank, Hindustan Petroleum, Indian Rayon, BSES and Hindalco, market sources said.</p>
<p>At the National Stock Exchange (NSE), tobacco conglomerate ITC was the top stock traded in volumes of over 14.67 million shares. The share jumped 12.50 rupees, or 3.07 percent, to end at 418.90, off the day's high of 426.50.</p>
<p>There was no single major factor behind the ITC price surge, dealers said. Bull operators were pushing up the stock, they added. ITC rose 7.75 rupees, or 1.89 percent, to 416.76 at the BSE with over 4.24 million shares traded.  </p>
<p>&quot;Foreign funds are looking at non-cyclicals -- telecoms, power, banks and a few auto firms that cater to the rural markets,&quot; Subra Subramanian, Indian research director at securities firm HG Asia, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Analysts said the low price-earnings ratios of Indian stocks, compared to other Asian markets, meant that there was a lot of potential for &quot;good&quot; price appreciations.</p>
<p>Among pivotal stocks, SBI lost 5.50 rupees to 277.25, Reliance 6.75 to 271.25, TISCO 4.25 to 194.50, L&amp;T 3.50 to 244.0 and TELCO 2.25 to 331.0.</p>
<p>-- Anshuman Daga, Bombay equities desk +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
