<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372897" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: African students in Bangladesh protest attack.</title>
<headline>African students in Bangladesh protest attack.</headline>
<byline>Shakeel Anwar</byline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>African students at a technical institute near Dhaka marched to the office of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina on Wednesday to protest against what they called racially motivated attacks by Bangladeshi villagers.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel deeply hurt and disappointed that we face such problems in a country that claims brotherhood among Moslems, and has won the sympathy of all African countries,&quot; the protesters said in a memorandum handed to the prime minister's office.</p>
<p>When told that Hasina was not in her office, the students squatted outside and chanted: &quot;Where is Islamic brotherhood?&quot; and &quot;We want justice and protection.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier the Africans marched to embassies of Moslem countries in the Bangladesh capital and handed out copies of the memorandum, police said.</p>
<p>African students at the Islamic Institute of Technology at Tongi, 25 km (15 miles) from Dhaka, began boycotting classes on Wednesday after two colleagues were injured in an assault.</p>
<p>Ibrahim Bande, chairman of the African Students Union at the institute, said the Africans felt insecure following the attack by villagers on two Senegalese students on Tuesday night.</p>
<p>Abdoulie Gieng and Usman (one name) suffered severe head injuries, Bande said. Both were admitted to hospital.</p>
<p>&quot;They faced a racial attack by local people as they ventured to a market outside the campus,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the sixth case of this nature,&quot; said the memorandum, adding that Bangladeshi authorities had done nothing about the incidents.</p>
<p>Professor Abdul Matin Patwari, director general of the institute, confirmed that &quot;minor clashes&quot; between students and outsiders had occurred, but dismissed allegations that they were racially motivated.</p>
<p>&quot;The information I got was that the clashes occurred over price-bargaining during shopping, not that people were attacked only because they are black,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;They are from totally different cultures. So there might be some misunderstanding and suspicion,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Patwari said he had spoken to community leaders in an attempt to prevent further incidents. He also said he had called in police to guard the campus.</p>
<p>The 70 Africans are the biggest group among 350 students of the institute, which is funded by member countries of the Organisation of Islamic Conference.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
