<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372988" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Parts strike could hurt GM truck output, spin-offs.</title>
<headline>Parts strike could hurt GM truck output, spin-offs.</headline>
<byline>David Lawder</byline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A threatened strike at a key General Motors Corp. parts supplier not only would halt GM truck production, it also could hamper the automaker's efforts to divest unprofitable plants, industry observers said Wednesday.</p>
<p>American Axle &amp; Manufacturing Inc., a company made up of former GM operations, faces a strike deadline set by the United Auto Workers union for 11:59 p.m. EST Friday.</p>
<p>A strike at the company's five plants in Detroit, Three Rivers, Mich., and the Buffalo, N.Y., area would quickly force GM to shut down production at its 11 North American truck assembly plants. American Axle is GM's sole source for rear-drive truck axles and other components.</p>
<p>In a separate parts supplier labor dispute, Ford Motor Co. Wednesday resumed assembly of Expedition sport utility vehicles after shifting rear seat production from a strikebound Johnson Controls Inc. plant to a rival seat-maker, Lear Corp.</p>
<p>No new talks were scheduled Wednesday in Johnson Controls' 16-day struggle with the UAW over an initial contract for newly organized plants in Plymouth, Mich., and Oberlin, Ohio.</p>
<p>The American Axle talks also mark the first time that a GM spin-off operation has had to negotiate a new contract with the UAW. When former Chrysler Corp. manufacturing chief Richard Dauch and other investors bought the plants in 1994, they assumed GM's 1993 labor agreement.</p>
<p>The UAW has demanded that American Axle meet the same terms agreed to last fall by GM, which include job guarantees and generous wage and pension benefit increases.</p>
<p>American Axle maintains that it can't afford to give its 7,500 workers the Big Three pattern -- it needs a contract that allows it to be competitive with other parts suppliers, many of whom have non-union plants.</p>
<p>&quot;Dana, TRW, Eaton, Rockwell -- they're out here to eat our lunch,&quot; said a spokesman for American Axle. &quot;We don't make anywhere near the profit on axles that Ford makes on an Expedition.&quot;</p>
<p>The spokesman, who asked not be identified, said American Axle wants a &quot;modern operating agreement,&quot; which allows more flexibility in work rules and job assignments.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking for a partnership with the union,&quot; he said, adding that profit-sharing would be a major component of any new agreement.</p>
<p>American Axle workers averaged $1,049 in profit sharing payments for their 1995 performance, compared to about $800 for GM workers. The spokesman added that the 1996 payout will likely be about $800 vs. $300 for GM workers.</p>
<p>For the UAW, the aggressive stance in negotiations with parts suppliers markes a major push into that end of the auto industry.</p>
<p>With the UAW workforce expected to shrink at GM, Ford and Chrysler Corp., and foreign automakers' U.S. plants staunchly non-union, the UAW is turning to parts suppliers to replenish its ranks.</p>
<p>GM, which sold four interior parts and hardware plants late last year, has said it may divest more parts plants in the future. A strike at American Axle could hamper those efforts, because buyers would inherit UAW workforces that will want to keep their generous GM benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;An aggressive UAW would make potential buyers think twice,&quot; said Burnham Securities David Healy. &quot;It may not actually prevent spinoffs by GM, but it will make the process A parts supplier executive agreed, saying American Axle would take a &quot;step backwards&quot; if it were forced to accept the GM pattern. &quot;It would hamstring your ability to make that place competitive,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
