<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="372991" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar ends higher despite threats of intervention.</title>
<headline>Dollar ends higher despite threats of intervention.</headline>
<byline>Chris Stetkiewicz</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar ended higher Wednesday but failed to hold its sharp early gains after global economic leaders raised the prospect of market intervention to slow the currency's recent rally.</p>
<p>The dollar hit a fresh four-year high against the Japanese yen and a 34-month peak against the German mark in early trading, supported by a New York Times article citing American exporters' relative comfort with an extended rally that has powered the U.S. currency higher.</p>
<p>A stronger dollar makes U.S. exports relatively more expensive on world markets, but American firms have minimised the impact by cost-cutting and shifting production overseas, the article said.</p>
<p>&quot;That was very supportive for the dollar. Those companies are not complaining like they did during the dollar rally of the 1980s,&quot; said Francois Akl, chief currency dealer at Gulf International Bank.</p>
<p>The dollar ended at 1.6871 marks, up from 1.6773 late Tuesday, and at 124.25 yen, up from 123.28. The dollar climbed to 1.4515 Swiss francs, a 34-month high, from 1.4375 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The British pound fell to $1.6310 from $1.6370. The dollar rose to Canadian $1.3553 from C$1.3552.</p>
<p>After the dollar climbed to 1.6935 marks and 124.48 yen overnight, Japanese Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka told a news conference the world's central banks would watch the markets carefully and &quot;take appropriate measures to tackle any excessive moves.&quot;</p>
<p>A short while later a Bundesbank spokesman chimed in with a statement suggesting leaders of the Group of Seven industrial nations had selected 1.65 marks per dollar as an appropriate level at their meeting in Berlin last Saturday.</p>
<p>While traders expressed doubt that the G7 would intervene at current levels, they said the mere possibility of official dollar-selling convinced many investors to unload dollars and book profits from the current rally.</p>
<p>&quot;Those statements from Japan and Germany spooked the market. The intervention threat does overhang the market,&quot; said Ben Strauss, foreign exchange trader at Bank Julius Baer and Co. Ltd.</p>
<p>Yet investors will likely keep pushing the dollar higher in coming sessions, with a target range seen at 1.70 to 1.75 marks, dealers said.</p>
<p>Analysts said solid U.S. economic growth, which contrasts with Japan's slumping economy and record German unemployment, continues to draw investors to U.S. stocks and bonds, which could bolster the dollar indefinitely.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not yet reached a significant high, though the market can't just snub the central banks,&quot; said Marc Chandler, senior foreign exchange analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
