<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37301" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore rubber futures close lower across board.</title>
<headline>Singapore rubber futures close lower across board.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rubber futures closed lower across the board on Friday in line with lower Japanese prices, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said prices in Tokyo and Kobe were down on continued long liqudation, as an increase in Japanese rubber stocks announced late on Thursday fuelled concerns over near-term oversupply trends.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was quiet and featureless in the morning on a lack of fresh factors. But prices were marked down slightly in the afternoon following weaker prices in Tokyo and Kobe. Volume was moderate,&quot; a local broker said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Prices might continue to fall if expectations of oversupply continue to plague the nearby months in the Japanese market. But on the other hand, if China comes into the market to do some purchases, then price might stabliise a little bit,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am expecting the (local) market to go up slighty next week on some technical adjustments because prices have marked down quite a lot over the last few days,&quot; another trader added.</p>
<p>At around 0945 GMT, October RSS3 fell 1.75 cents to 127.00 U.S. cents a kg. November RSS1 fell 1.75 cents to 186.75 Singapore cents (US$1.33) a kg. July/September fell 1.50 cents to 184.00 Singapore cents (US$1.31) a kg. (US$1-S$1.40)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
