<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37316" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey sees need for security cordon in Iraq.</title>
<headline>Turkey sees need for security cordon in Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Elif Unal</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish Foreign Minister Tansu Ciller said on Friday renewed upheaval in northern Iraq made necessary Turkey's planned creation of a security zone there.</p>
<p>She said the cordon would deter infiltration by guerrillas of the Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK), which is fighting to establish self-rule in Turkey's mainly Kurdish southeast.</p>
<p>Interviewed by BBC World Television, Ciller called the zone a &quot;must&quot;.</p>
<p>But echoing other officials who spelled out limited Turkish military goals, Ciller insisted: &quot;It is going to be temporary kind of activity&quot;.</p>
<p>President Suleyman Demirel late on Friday called a security summit on northern Iraq, meeting with the chief of staff and the head of intelligence as well as Ciller and the interior and defence ministers.</p>
<p>Iraq has already expressed its displeasure with Ankara's military build-up at the border with Kurdish-held northern Iraq. At midnight on Thursday, Iraq summoned a senior Turkish diplomat in Baghdad to complain about the concentration of force.</p>
<p>But despite a surge of Turkish troop movements and air patrols near the border on Thursday, Ankara and U.N. officials said the Turkish army had yet to make a move.</p>
<p>&quot;There is nothing happening,&quot; Ahmet Erturk, deputy governor of Turkey's southeastern provinces, told reporters.</p>
<p>After clashes flared this week in northern Iraq between two Iraqi Kurdish factions, Ankara revived the long-standing idea of a security zone to repel the PKK, which uses the Iraqi terrain as a springboard for its attacks on Turkey.</p>
<p>More than 20,000 people have died in 12 years of fighting between the rebels and the Turkish army.</p>
<p>The governor's office for Turkey's southeastern provinces under emergency rule said on Friday that Turkish troops killed 26 PKK rebels in clashes in the area.</p>
<p>The promise of only a temporary security cordon is key to securing the support of Washington, Turkey's closest ally.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not raising any particular objections based on what the Turks have told us,&quot; State Department spokesman Glyn Davies told a news briefing on Thursday.</p>
<p>The United States, leading an anti-Iraqi alliance, fired two volleys of cruise missiles at southern Iraqi military targets this week in retaliation for Iraqi intervention in the Kurdish fighting last week.</p>
<p>But France on Friday came out against a buffer zone, saying the international community had reaffirmed its commitment to Iraq's sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>
<p>&quot;We have security problems at our borders,&quot; Ciller said. &quot;Each time this kind of military action happens, the terrorists build up on our borders and then try to infiltrate. So we need this security zone there.&quot;</p>
<p>Foreign ministry officials said &quot;conditions&quot; would determine how long the cordon would remain and how many troops would patrol the zone, set to extend up to 10 km (six miles) deep into northern Iraq.</p>
<p>In Baghdad, Iraqi Foreign Minister Saeed al-Sahaf summoned the Turkish acting charge d'affaires to complain the Turkish military measures &quot;constituted a totally unjustified conduct and a violation of Iraq's sovereignty,&quot; Baghdad newspapers said.</p>
<p>On Friday Ciller hosted consultations with Deputy Chief of Staff General Cevik Bir, the defence and interior ministers, Under-Secretary of the Foreign Ministry Onur Oymen and the secretary of the Turkish secret service.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
