<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="373206" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Applebee's sees more expansion in 1997.</title>
<headline>Applebee's sees more expansion in 1997.</headline>
<dateline>OVERLAND PARK, Kan. 1997-02-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Applebee's International Inc, which franchises and operates casual dining restaurants, said Tuesday it expects aggressive system-wide restaurant expansion to continue in 1997.</p>
<p>The company anticipates that at least 135 Applebee's restaurants will open during the year. It said it anticipates opening about 35 company-owned Applebee's, including two expected to open as part of the recently announced acquisition of the St. Louis market area.</p>
<p>In addition, at least 100 franchise restaurants are expected to open in 1997.</p>
<p>At December 29, 1996, there were 819 Applebee's restaurants open systemwide, including 148 company-owned or operated and 671 franchise operated.</p>
<p>During 1996, a total of 163 new Applebee's restaurants were opened including 29 company-owned and 134 franchise restaurants, of which five were international openings. As present there are 834 restaurants open systemwide, reflecting the opening of 15 restaurants during the first six weeks of 1997.</p>
<p>Earlier, the company reported fourth-quarter earnings of $0.29 a share, up from $0.26. Results for the December 29 fourth quarter included an after-tax charge of $0.05 a share, mostly from the intended disposition of two California restaurants.</p>
<p>In the fourth quarter of 1996, comparable sales of company-owned and operated Applebee's restaurants increased 0.3 percent, while comparable sales for franchise Applebee's restaurants decreased 0.9 percent. Systemwide comparable sales for the fourth quarter decreased 0.7 percent.</p>
<p>	     ((Chicago newsdesk 312 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OVERLAND PARK, Kan."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
