<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="373245" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - London Evening Standard - Feb 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - London Evening Standard - Feb 12.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>EVENING STANDARD</p>
<p>20 MILLION CALL 10 STG CONCORDE</p>
<p>British Airways 'World's Fastest Offer' promotion offering a 'once in a lifetime' opportunity to fly to the United States on concorde for 10 pounds stg, saw an amazing 20mn people jam telephone switchboards in an attempt to win tickets.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>POUND AND DOLLAR KEEP MARCHING ON</p>
<p>The pound was on the increase again today along with the dollar. Sterling's long term rise against the Deutschmark and yen is linked to the sluggish economic recoveries taking place in Germany and Japan.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>HERON IN 200 MLN STG SOUTH WALES DEVELOPMENT</p>
<p>Property company, Heron International is undertaking its first significant British land development scheme since being rescued by U.S. investors two years ago. The group is planning a 200 million stg development programme in South Wales.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>OIL PRICE SLIDE PUTS CLYDE AT MERCY OF GULF CANADA</p>
<p>With oil's dramatic slide on world markets, British oil independent Clyde Petroleum attempts to fight off Gulf Canada's attempts at a takeover look doomed to failure.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>C&amp;W'S OPTUS FLOAT HITS HITCH</p>
<p>In a legal case that is also threatening its telecoms asset, Cable &amp; Wireless risks losing more than 50 percent of its investment in an 1.3 billion Australian dollars (604 million stg) Australian pay TV venture. The A$2 billion float of Optus Communications in which Cable &amp; Wireless has a 24.5 percent stake has been stalled by legal action among shareholders in pay-TV subsidiary Optus Vision.</p>
<p>-- BMC +44 171 377 1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
