<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="373308" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NatWest, interactive investor launch fund website.</title>
<headline>NatWest, interactive investor launch fund website.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>NatWest Securities and UK financial services company interactive investor (iii) have launched a fund information service on the Internet covering nearly 400 UK investment trusts.</p>
<p>In a presentation to investors, NatWest said performance statistics, market information and asset allocation changes about 395 investment trusts (60 of them split capital trusts) will be updated daily at http://www.iii.co.uk.</p>
<p>Hamish Buchan, chairman of NatWest Securities Scotland, said the service was targeted at sophisticated investors, institutional analysts and intermediaries.</p>
<p>Readers will be able to search for any trust they are interested in and sort trusts according to preference such as performance, yield, discount and many other variables.</p>
<p>Information about unit trusts, personal equity plans and offshore funds will be added to the site in the near future.</p>
<p>The database is maintained and managed by the NatWest Securities Investment team working with the Association of Investment Trust Companies (AITC). NatWest will supply daily net asset values, as it has in printed form since 1968.</p>
<p>Buchan said investors will be able to construct a personal portfolio of trusts to monitor, obtain e-mail notification of any major changes to portfolio holdings and visit key websites of other investment managers.</p>
<p>More than 100 investment trust companies have indicated they will join the site, including Baillie Gifford, Flemings, Framlington, Gartmore, John Govett, Invesco, Martin Currie, Mercury Asset Management and Scottish Value. There is an annual charge of 450 pounds per investment trust featured onsite.</p>
<p>Interactive investor has already set up 85 financial services sites across 10 countries. It brings its links with the Association of Unit Trust Investment Funds (AUTIF), fund data company Micropal and the Financial Times Magazines to the deal.</p>
<p>NatWest Stockbrokers, which handles one in 10 of the private transactions on the London Stock exchange, will operate a share dealing service on the site.</p>
<p>Sherry Coutu, managing director of interactive investor said the package gave investors free access to information that until now had only been available to internal employees of securities houses and their clients.</p>
<p>She said the site had grown at a compound monthly rate of 40 percent, with hits jumping from 140,000 in January 1996 to over 1.4 million in December 1996. The current number of UK readers per month is around 100,000.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 6414</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
