<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37346" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dlr ends mostly up in US, jobs point to rate rise.</title>
<headline>Dlr ends mostly up in US, jobs point to rate rise.</headline>
<text>
<p>*Dlr ends up vs mark and Swiss franc, flat vs yen. Late sales of dollar/yen boost yen vs mark, drag dollar/mark off highs. *Stronger-than-expected August U.S. jobs data, broad mark sell-off and rallies in U.S. stocks and bonds buoy dollar. *But dollar faces tough resistance at 109.50 yen, 1.4960 marks. *Mark/Paris, most other mark/European crosses also lower.  </p>
<p>The U.S. unit rose after the release of August U.S. jobs data, led by gains in dollar/Swiss.</p>
<p>The dollar climbed as high as 1.4935 marks, 1.2200 Swiss francs and 109.42 yen before a late round of selling in dollar/yen triggered stops in mark/yen at 73.20, pressuring the U.S. currency to close off its highs, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a very thin Friday afternoon market and it just drifted lower,&quot; said Peter Wadkins, vice president at Standard Chartered Bank.</p>
<p>The dollar ended at 1.4920/30 marks and 1.2185/95 Swiss francs against openings of 1.4848/53 and 1.2052/59.  </p>
<p>The U.S. currency ended little changed against the yen at 109.15/18 compared with 109.17/22.</p>
<p>Long-awaited U.S. employment data for August showed the economy expanding at a brisk pace and increased the odds the Federal Reserve will increase interest rates this month, giving the dollar an early boost, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;What you've got here is a pretty strong bias for a rate hike right now,&quot; said Kevin Harris, international economist at MCM CurrencyWatch.</p>
<p>The Labor Department reported the economy created 250,000 non-farm jobs in August aganist a revised 228,000 in July.  </p>
<p>The jobless rate slumped to a seven-year low of 5.1 percent from a previous 5.4 percent, the government reported.</p>
<p>Economists on average had expected non-farm payrolls to rise by 224,000 in August, and the unemployment rate to edge lower to 5.3 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The (jobs) numbers lead us to think that the Federal Reserve will move in September, raising rates by 25 basis points,&quot; said Phoenix said.</p>
<p>Despite the good news on the interest rate front, many expect the dollar to have a difficult time surmounting resistance at 109.50 yen and 1.4960 marks next week.  </p>
<p>&quot;I can't see 110 dollar/yen next week. There's a lot of pressure on the topside for dollar/yen approaching the Japanese fiscal half-year (on September 30),&quot; Wadkins said.</p>
<p>The mark was again broadly sold, against the yen and against European currencies.</p>
<p>Mark/yen closed at 73.13 after opening at 73.48.</p>
<p>Late in the day, mark/French franc was trading around 3.4146/50 compared with 3.4190/95 near the opening.</p>
<p>&quot;The market seemed to be a little long of marks going into the end of the week. That precipitated a lot of selling of marks on the crosses,&quot; said Harris at MCM CurrencyWatch.  </p>
<p>In other trade, sterling finished down at $1.5590/00 compared with $1.5656/63.</p>
<p>The dollar was Canadian $1.3732/37, up from C$1.3710/15.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar was $0.7990/95.</p>
<p>-- Daniel Rosenblum, 212-8559-1662</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
