<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37344" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Parry says low US jobless rate linked to inflation.</title>
<headline>Parry says low US jobless rate linked to inflation.</headline>
<dateline>BEND, Ore. 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. unemployment is currently at a level that &quot;generally&quot; has been associated with rising inflation,&quot; Robert Parry, president of the Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco, said Friday.</p>
<p>The Labor Department reported earlier that the jobless rate slid to 5.1 percent in August from 5.4 percent in July, while nonfarm payrolls grew by 250,000 in August.  </p>
<p>Parry, who addressed a luncheon held as part of a joint meeting of Fed branch officials in the Northwest, was asked by a member of the audience his view of the likelihood of a recession sometime during the next four years.</p>
<p>He replied that, barring any unforeseen external shocks, it was unlikely provided the Fed pursues the correct policies to keep the economy on a steady course.</p>
<p>Describing the policies the Fed should pursue, Parry said, &quot;We've got to make sure that this economy doesn't grow too fast or too slow.&quot;</p>
<p>He added, &quot;If it grows much too slow you are in a recession. If it grows much too fast -- as we learned very painfully in periods in the late '60s and '70s and even to some exent a little bit in the '80s -- you cause inflationary pressures that cause the Fed to have to step on the brake hard.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEND, Ore."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
