<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="373546" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: FORECAST - Danish KFX index to steady after records.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Danish KFX index to steady after records.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Copenhagen Stock Exchange's top-20 KFX index has peaked after hitting record highs and rising 12 percent since the New Year and stay around current levels for the rest of 1997, according to a poll released by Reuters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Twelve analysts saw the KFX index rising on average to 154 by end-March, to slip back to 152 at end-June and 151 by end-December 1997.</p>
<p>The KFX index closed at 152.86 on Wednesday, just short of its February 7 all-time closing high of 152.90.</p>
<p>Estimates table:</p>
<p> (KFX index) Date	  31/3	  30/6	31/12/97</p>
<p> Average		     154	   152	   151</p>
<p> Lowest			145	   140	   130</p>
<p> Highest		     160	   170	   162</p>
<p>Share turnover hit a monthly all-time high on Copenhagen Stock Exchange in January, 63 percent up on the same month last year, according to bourse data.</p>
<p>Trading totalled 33.1 billion crowns in market value, an increase of 78 percent on the previous month, with average daily trading volume at 1.5 billion crowns, it said.</p>
<p>The previous monthly record of 28.6 billion crowns was set in January 1994.</p>
<p>Copenhagen Stock Exchange said industrial shares were the most traded during January 1997 with turnover of 11.6 billion crowns, followed by trade and services at 8.7 billion crowns and banks at 6.7 billion crowns.</p>
<p>It said share prices rocketed, with the top-20 KFX index hitting 10 all-time record highs in the month to peak at 147.88 at end-January, 8.5 percent up on the beginning of the year.</p>
<p>--Stig Pedersen, Copenhagen newsroom +45-33969652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
