<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="373648" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: BAA to take 65 pct stake in Naples airport.</title>
<headline>BAA to take 65 pct stake in Naples airport.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>British airport operator BAA Plc  is set to take a 65 percent stake in Capodichino airport in Naples, the third biggest airport in Italy, a spokeswoman for the airport operator said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>She said the deal was expected to be signed in early March.  </p>
<p>&quot;Everything leads us to expect that the deal will go through,&quot; the spokeswoman for Gesac, the company which operates Capodichino told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;The deal should be signed at the start of March,&quot; she said, adding that it would then be presented to Naples regional authorities for final approval.</p>
<p>In London, BAA said in a statement that negotiations to buy the controlling equity interest were &quot;well-advanced&quot; but it declined to confirm it was about to take a 65 percent stake.</p>
<p>BAA signed a non-binding letter of intent with Gesac last January. &quot;If the signing of a conditional contract now goes ahead, completion will be subject to ohbtaining the relevant local approvals -- a process which could take up to 70 days,&quot; the statement said.  </p>
<p>Under the new ownership structure, BAA would have a 65 percent stake and Naples local and provincial authorities would hold 20 percent plus a golden share, the Gesac spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>She said Italian flag carrier Alitalia would seek to keep its five percent share in Capodichino, Gesac staff would take a further five percent and private investors the balance.</p>
<p>The spokeswoman said she could not comment on the amount BAA was expected to pay but said that under a law on airport recapitalisation that linked investment to passenger numbers, Gesac's capital would be increased from 2.5 billion lire ($1.5 million) at present to some 25 billion lire ($15 million).</p>
<p>&quot;BAA will take part in the capital increase,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She said that a five-year &quot;masterplan&quot; for Capodichino, drawn up jointly by BAA and Gesac, foresaw investment of 240 billion lire ($145 million).  </p>
<p>Naples airport handled nearly 2.9 million passengers in 1996 and is the third biggest airport in Italy behind Rome's Fiumicino and Milan's Linate, the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Aeroporti di Roma, the company which operates Rome's two airports, said it had sent a letter to Naples city officials saying it too was ready to take a stake in Gesac.</p>
<p>&quot;ADR is ready to begin immediate talks to take a significant share stake in Gesac,&quot; the group said in a statement.</p>
<p>ADR said that as Italy's biggest airport operator, it had the professional, technical and financial resources to compete for a stake in Gesac but had not been contacted to see whether it would be willing to take part in the development plan.</p>
<p>It said such a move would be in line with its stated aim of extending its management activities to other airports.</p>
<p>The Gesac spokeswoman said ADR had expressed an interest in Naples when the BAA letter of intent was signed a year ago but &quot;nothing came of it&quot;.</p>
<p>-- Rome newsroom +396 678 2501</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
