<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="373798" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK Talk Radio asked to remove poster ad.</title>
<headline>UK Talk Radio asked to remove poster ad.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A British advertising watchdog on Wednesday said it asked Talk Radio to withdraw a poster advertisement that used sexually graphic imagery.</p>
<p>The poster ad, designed by Walsh Trott Chick Smith, was headlined &quot;15 million pounds for Shearer.&quot; It showed two hands, one in a thumbs-up gesture headlined &quot;good buy&quot; and the other with the hand gripped in an O-shape headlined &quot;good bye.&quot;</p>
<p>The Advertising Standards Authority (ASA) said it upheld complaints objecting to the second gesture as &quot;an obscene one denoting masturbation.&quot;</p>
<p>Talk Radio said the ad, which referred to the Newcastle United football club signing English striker Alan Shearer for 15 million pounds, was part of a campaign designed to stimulate debate. Talk Radio said the precise interpretation of the images was up to the viewer.</p>
<p>The ASA, which received 33 complaints against the ad, said the complainants had understood the imagery and had been offended.</p>
<p>The ASA also upheld complaints against two advertisements in PC Zone magazine for computer games, one of which used sexually graphic and bloody imagery and the other which was found to condone drug use.</p>
<p>The ad for 3DO Co's computer game Strife pictured a pair of testicles on a blood-stained sheet of paper and a brain on a larger blood-stained piece of paper. The ad read: &quot;Strife (for eight people). Ingredients: 1 brain (medium). 1 pair of balls (large) Blend until smooth. Sip during game play.&quot;</p>
<p>The ASA said it concluded the ad was &quot;likely to offend some readers seriously.&quot; The ASA asked that the ad -- designed by the Butterfield, Day, DeVito, Hockney agency -- be withdrawn.</p>
<p>The ASA upheld a complaint filed against an ad for a GameTek computer game that also ran in PC Zone. The ad was headlined, &quot;Are You The Crack Pilot The Population Is Dying For?&quot; The ad showed a man holding a hypodermic needle and sitting on a pile of human skeletons.</p>
<p>The ASA said it found that &quot;...although it was unlikely to cause serious or widespread offence, the advertisement condoned a light-hearted attitude to the use of illegal drugs.&quot; The ASA asked GameTek to withdraw the ad and to get copy advice before advertising again. It was the second time in the last 12 months that the ASA upheld a complaint against GameTek.</p>
<p>An advertisement in LAN Magazine for Advanced Logic Research that showed the top half of naked woman and was headlined, &quot;Spend Your Wad On This,&quot; was found offensive by the ASA. The ASA asked that the ad, designed by TMMA, not be repeated.</p>
<p>An ad in Church Music quarterly offering &quot;The New Climax Series of Organ Music&quot; and featuring books with titles such as &quot;What a Swell organ you have,&quot; &quot;Coxon,&quot; &quot;Soft Organ,&quot; &quot;Hard Organ&quot; and &quot;Big Organ&quot; was also found offensive by the ASA. The ASA asked the advertiser, Oecumuse, not to use the same approach in the future.</p>
<p>-- Leslie Adler, London Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 2815</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
