<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="373784" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU set to issue economic report for 1996.</title>
<headline>EU set to issue economic report for 1996.</headline>
<byline>Henry Engler</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission will offer on Thursday a sweeping annual review of the European Union economy in 1996 and an assessment of the challenges ahead.</p>
<p>The 130-page document will not, however, include new forecasts for growth in the EU or the expected pace of budget consolidation in the 15-nation bloc in 1997.</p>
<p>The current year is critical for countries wishing to qualify for a planned single European currency and the EU executive's yearly update is certain to be scrutinised more closely than usual.</p>
<p>Countries must bring their deficits, inflation and interest rates in line with the Maastricht treaty this year if they hope to qualify for monetary union, expected to start in 1999.</p>
<p>Fresh economic outlooks for all 15 nations will be forthcoming towards the end of April, incorporating the most recent data from late last year.</p>
<p>As a result, the Commission will reiterate its expectation of a 2.3 percent rise in the EU's gross domestic product this year and a further increase to 2.8 percent in 1998.</p>
<p>Regarding Germany, still Europe's main economic engine, officials said it was still too early to tell whether they will have to alter their previous estimates for 1997.</p>
<p>Two important influences are at work: the first is the dampening effects of a somewhat harsher winter and the second the strong dollar, which at a pinch should allow Germany more opportunities for export growth.</p>
<p>During its last round of forecasts in October, the Commission confidently predicted that Germany would bring its 1997 budget deficit down to three percent of GDP, the Maastricht treaty's requirement.</p>
<p>But weaker than expected growth in recent weeks combined with record joblessness have sown doubts among independent analysts on whether Bonn can meet the Maastricht target without further budget cuts.</p>
<p>A Reuter poll of economists suggested on Wednesday that Germany's deficit ratio would be 3.5 percent of GDP this year.</p>
<p>In its annual economic report last month Bonn forecast a deficit ratio of 2.9 percent. A German finance ministry official told Reuters on Wednesday that the rosier estimate still stood.</p>
<p>The Commission's document will also highlight some of the key structural problems facing the EU, such as the competitive effects from an increasingly integrated and globalised world economy.</p>
<p>It will also include an analysis which adjusts the budgetary performance of all 15 nations for the ups and downs in their economies. The upshot of this evaluation is that their budgetary situation may look better than currently forecast.</p>
<p>Officials warned, however, that such an exercise is meant to demonstrate &quot;the need for serious structural reform,&quot; and would not pre-judge the decision in early 1998 on which countries will qualify for EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no question of this report being an evaluation of who participates in 1999,&quot; said a Commission official.</p>
<p>There will also be an investigation into why budgetary restraint is needed apart from the preconditions of a common currency as well as a review of EU monetary policies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
