<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="373777" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Kohl answers critics but remains under pressure.</title>
<headline>Kohl answers critics but remains under pressure.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Liffey</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl defended his policies on Wednesday and rejected suggestions of poor health, but remained under pressure from allies seeking more leadership and a commitment to stand for election again.</p>
<p>Kohl reaffirmed the need for budget austerity which has spawned controversial plans to reform tax and pensions systems and said it was not only necessary to qualify for his cherished project of European economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>&quot;The unemployed would gain nothing if we tried to stoke up the economy by going further into debt,&quot; he told the mass-circulation daily Bild. &quot;Currency union will give the European economy a strong boost. That will create new jobs,&quot;</p>
<p>The conservative chancellor urged those in work to content themselves with small or zero real pay rises over the next few years to make it easier for companies to create new jobs.</p>
<p>Kohl, 66, also angrily dismissed speculation by the news weekly Der Spiegel that he had prostate problems and that this might have influenced his decision to wait before deciding whether to stand in the 1998 general election.</p>
<p>It was Kohl's most robust riposte yet to a wave of speculation that he may have no answers to soaring unemployment and an apparent lack of direction in his centre-right coalition.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the conservative daily Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung (FAZ) became the latest paper to point to pressure within the centre-right coalition for Kohl to commit himself soon to stand in the 1998 elections.</p>
<p>It said many of Kohl's own Christian Democrat (CDU) members of parliament wanted him to decide now, to dispel the impression he might already have written off the October 1998 election.</p>
<p>But this would also require him quickly to settle internal rows about the two projects which were intended to win the election for the coalition -- tax and pensions reform, the deputies said.</p>
<p>Another conservative daily, Die Welt, said in a front-page editorial the coalition was increasingly edgy and Kohl must act by declaring within two months that he will stand again.</p>
<p>&quot;There is whispering in backrooms...Some of the young CDU members are starting to think about what comes after the party patriarch.&quot;</p>
<p>Die Welt referred to comments Kohl made on Sunday in an interview on French television.</p>
<p>&quot;Someone who says, in an interview from France in the middle of a heated reform debate, that he is not really sure if he wants to be chancellor again is not showing he has the constancy (to get reforms passed).&quot;</p>
<p>Even the austerity budgets Kohl's government produced last year have failed to convince analysts Germany will get its deficit under the limit required for EMU, as record unemployment squeezes tax revenue and pushes up welfare spending.</p>
<p>Already Finance Minister Theo Waigel is considering an emergency spending freeze.</p>
<p>On Wednesday there was further bad news in the shape of a report in the Frankfurter Rundschau daily which said Bonn faced an explosion in pension payments for civil servants in the postal service which could create an unexpected deficit of 7.4 billion marks by 1999.</p>
<p>And there was a predictable reaction from unions and the opposition Social Democrats (SPD) to Kohl's idea of voluntary wage restraint.</p>
<p>SPD leader Oskar Lafontaine told a party meeting the government was to blame for record unemployment and was suffering from &quot;paralysis of brain, thought and action&quot;.</p>
<p>And Ursula Engelen-Kefer, deputy leader of the DGB trade union federation, said workers had anyway not seen real wage rises for years because of tax rises and welfare cuts.</p>
<p>&quot;One has to stop trying to politically destroy the workforce,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
