<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="373812" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS - FEB 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS - FEB 12.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek financial press:</p>
<p>KATHIMERINI</p>
<p>--A new wave of strike action is coming the country's way, this time from civil servants protesting the government's proposed uniform wage scale. The new front is led by forestry officials who struck for 24 hours yesterday to claim an allowance granted in July 1996 and abolished under the new wage scale. Also to follow are workers in the computer departments at the finance ministry and civil personnel at the defence ministry.</p>
<p>--The government's draft bill on the insurance sector foresees wide-ranging changes, including compulsory third party insurance for drivers. The bill was submitted to Parliament yesterday. </p>
<p>--Prime Minister Costas Simitis returns to his old stomping ground tomorrow to jointly announce the government's policy on industry, energy , research-technology and trade with Development Minister Vasso Papandreou. (Separate announcements on tourism will be made in a month's time.) Simitis's appearance at Papandreou's side is construed as a show of support following recent tension between Papandreou and others over the Floisvos casino, currently being examined by a parliamentary fact-finding commission. </p>
<p>--1997 got off to a bad start for the retail foodstuffs sector, with January turnover figures for supermarkets showing a reduction for the first time in years. </p>
<p>IMERISIA</p>
<p>--The alarm bells are ringing for the 2,800 Greek firms active in Balkan countries, as the political and economic crises show no signs of abating, forcing a reconsideration of their investment plans. The problem also affects hundreds of small and medium-size enterprises in northern Greece.</p>
<p>--Simitis will discuss the government's efforts at &quot;social dialogue&quot; today with his national economy and labour ministers.</p>
<p>KERDOS</p>
<p>--The Athens bourse saw a number of orders to sell or buy unfilled yesterday after demand exceeded the ability of borkerage firms' transaction levels. The problem was acute among those with foreign and domestic institutional clients. </p>
<p>--The market has reacted badly to the finance ministry's plans for a tax on financial derviatives. Sources say investors from abroad have led the complaints, claiming that the tax has effectively levied retroactive taxes on these derivatives.</p>
<p>--Industrialists yesterday took their grievances to National Bank of Greece Governor Theodoros Karatzas. Industrialists called for banks to simplify procedures and develop products for the business customer. </p>
<p>--Simitis and Papandreou are expected to announce important moves in energy policies, growth and the strengthening of investments and privatisation tomorrow.</p>
<p>EXPRESS</p>
<p>--Procedures for the privatisation of state-run firms and mergers of bank subsidiaries or banks are time-consuming and difficult, Simitis is told.</p>
<p>--Industrial production was up by 0.6 percent in the January-November 1996 period.</p>
<p>NAFTEMBORIKI</p>
<p>--Harmonising energy taxes in the European Union - to be adopted by the Commission today - will mean a gradual increase in the cost of all fuel for Greeks. The reforms will be phased in from 1998 until 2002.</p>
<p>--The continuing 'hard drachma' policy, an agressive marketing policy by some banks to promote new financial forex products, and the significant difference in the cost of servicing loans, have led consumers to forex loans, which have increased by 50 percent over the last three months, and particularly in the last two weeks.</p>
<p>--Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
