<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="373864" id="root" date="1997-02-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dollar strong in Europe, intervention fears grow.</title>
<headline>Dollar strong in Europe, intervention fears grow.</headline>
<byline>Abigail Levene</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar extended its relentless bull run in morning Europe, hitting fresh 34-month highs against the mark and Swiss franc, but fears grew that central bank intervention would emerge.</p>
<p>&quot;The central banks are probably thinking about intervening at some point soon,&quot; said Stephen King, deputy chief economist at HSBC James Capel. &quot;It's almost as if they're seeing how far the markets can push the dollar before they take some intervention themselves.&quot;  </p>
<p>The dollar surged to 1.6910 marks and 1.4493 Swiss francs in early trade, way up from late Tuesday's European levels of 1.6715/25 and 1.4330/50. It had settled at 1.6885/90 marks and 1.4475/80 francs by 0848 GMT.</p>
<p>The dollar was lifted overnight by reports quoting German finance officials as saying they would welcome a rally to 1.70-1.75 marks to lower German export prices and boost the economy.</p>
<p>The German finance ministry later said it had nothing to add to the statement released after the recent Group of Seven meeting, which said currency &quot;misalignments&quot; had been corrected. But the ministry fell short of denying the reports.  </p>
<p>That had combined with a New York Times report, saying the number of U.S. companies expressing concern over the rise of the dollar had been surprisingly small, to dilute the impact of the G7 statement to almost nothing, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;People are still anxious about intervention, and that could keep a bit of a top on it...but the market is still very gung-ho, it's become more so -- almost to a dangerous point,&quot; said Tim Fox, treasury economist at Standard Chartered here.</p>
<p>The dollar stood at 124.15/25 yen at 0907 GMT, up from 122.75 in late Europe on Tuesday. A break of last Friday's 124.72 high would take it to its best level in four years.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're pretty close to levels where the Bank of Japan would be looking to intervene,&quot; said Chris Turner, currency strategist at BZW in London.</p>
<p>&quot;The weak yen has had its beneficial effect on (Japan's) economy. Exports are very profitable again, but import costs are rising quite strongly, dampening down the profitability of other sectors of the economy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Japan had the strongest case for intervention among the G3, Turner believed. A sluggish economy and doubts over monetary union made German dollar-selling unlikely, while the U.S. was insistent a strong currency was in its interests, he said.  </p>
<p>The data slate is thin today, and traders saw little reason to go against the dollar-positive flow. Indeed, the second leg of the U.S. Treasury's quarterly refunding -- the sale of $12 billion of 10-year notes -- is likely to go well and provide yet more support for the currency, analysts said.</p>
<p>The market absorbed yesterday's $17.75 billion of three-year notes with relative ease. Thirty-year bonds go on sale Thursday.</p>
<p>Players are looking ahead to tomorrow's release of U.S. retail sales data for January, expected to show a 0.7 percent rise. Friday brings U.S. producer prices for last month, seen up 0.3 percent on the month and 3.0 percent on the year.  </p>
<p>New signs of U.S. economic strength should provide yet more fuel for the dollar's rally as they point up the contrast with the struggling economies of Germany and Japan, analysts said.</p>
<p>Sterling continued to rocket, scoring new 52-month highs on the mark as it continued to benefit from upbeat UK economic data, safe-haven flows amid EMU jitters and dollar strength.</p>
<p>The pound was fuelled by a 67,800-plunge in UK January unemployment, more than double the drop forecast by economists. Sterling stood at 2.7632/42 marks and $1.6370/80 at 0947 GMT versus 2.7438/48 and $1.6430/40 late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44-171-542-8968</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
