<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="374483" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AMR strike could cost Dade Cty, Fla millions - mayor.</title>
<headline>AMR strike could cost Dade Cty, Fla millions - mayor.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A strike by pilots of AMR Corp could wreak havoc on Dade County, Fla.'s economy, costing it about $400 million over 30 days, county mayor Alex Penelas said Thursday on cable television station CNBC.</p>
<p>Penelas in an interview described this weekend as one of the busiest of the year. The threatened strike would come during two major tourist events in Miami -- the annual boat show and the Coconut Grove Art Festival.</p>
<p>&quot;It is already having an impact,&quot; Penelas said.  </p>
<p>Economists have estimated that American Airlines generates nearly $4 billion a year in the south Florida economy and some 114,000 jobs are indirectly tied to the carrier.</p>
<p>American employs 9,000 people in Miami with a payroll of $33 million a month.</p>
<p>The airline accounts for 52 percent of the flights and 47 percent of the passengers at Miami International Airport.</p>
<p>Additionally, the threat of a strike is forcing Miami's cruise companies to re-route passengers sailing from the busy Port of  Miami. Royal Caribbean alone has had to rebook 10,000 passengers on flights to Miami to catch their cruises.</p>
<p>As many as 25,000 cruise ship passengers leave Miami on a typical weekend day, and most of them travel by air to Miami.</p>
<p>Penelas and other mayors of cities that depend on American Airlines were in Washington, D.C., on Wednesday to request President Clinton intervene and prevent the strike.</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
