<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37458" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oregon tax court ruling to benefit schools - S&amp;P.</title>
<headline>Oregon tax court ruling to benefit schools - S&amp;P.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Oregon tax court ruling that permits the use of general obligation bond proceeds to finance school building repairs and technology will benefit school districts in the state, Standard &amp; Poor's Corp said.</p>
<p>The court, which ruled in favor of the Beaverton School District in a suit filed by a group of local taxpayers, was &quot;welcome news for school districts throughout the state,&quot; S&amp;P said in its CreditWeek Municipal, set for release Monday.</p>
<p>The suit questioned the validity of a portion of a $151 million general obligation bond authorization approved by voters earlier this year, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>The taxpayer group contested the validity of bonds earmarked for school repairs and the purchase of computers and other equipment, alleging that using tax dollars to pay debt service on such bonds would violate the state Constitution.</p>
<p>By enabling districts to issue bonds to finance school building repairs and technology, the ruling allows them to use their limited property tax revenues to fund other needs, S&amp;P said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
