<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37464" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. corporate bonds fall from highs, end stronger.</title>
<headline>U.S. corporate bonds fall from highs, end stronger.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. high-grade corporate bonds retreated from midday highs but held on to some gains by the close after turbulent early trade ignited by the U.S. August payrolls report, dealers said.</p>
<p>Investment-grade corporates road the coattails of U.S. Treasuries which dove in a lightening-quick sell-off and recovery immediately following the release of the in-line payrolls report.</p>
<p>The 30-year long bond rose from over a point off to close up 17/32 at 95-18/32 to yield 7.11 percent.</p>
<p>Wall Street stocks tracked the rally in Treasuries.  </p>
<p>The Dow Jones Industrial Average ended up 52.90 to 5659.86, fueling junk bonds which closed up 1/8 to 1/4, dealers said.</p>
<p>Trade volume was light in both high-grade and high-yield arenas. Dealers said the recent drought of new issuance along with Friday's volatile underlying markets has dampened secondary trade activity.</p>
<p>But post payrolls, new issuance is seen picking up as long as currnet interest rate levels hold, dealers said.  </p>
<p>Numerous finance and bank names are circulating around the new issue market include Wells Fargo, Signet Bank, Nationsbank, Key Bank, Australia/New Zealand Bank, and Argentaria Bank with a $250 million yankee offering, sources said.</p>
<p>No new issues priced on Friday.</p>
<p>In spot trade, Mellon Bank's 11-year paper, which debued on Thursday, closed issue-bid, dealers said.</p>
<p>Ralphs Grocery 10.45 percent paper was quoted up 7/8, while the company's 11 percent paper was up 5/8, traders said.</p>
<p>Pathmark 9.625 percent debt also traded up 1/2 at 95 bid.  </p>
<p>The Labor Department reported a sharp decline to 5.1 percent in the nation's unemployment rate, the lowest since March, 1989. August nonfarm payrolls were up 250,000 while the average hourly earnings component was up a stronger-than-expected 0.5 percent.</p>
<p>-- Roanne Daniels, 212-859-1677</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
