<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="374875" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE white sugar mixed before expiry, trading calm.</title>
<headline>LIFFE white sugar mixed before expiry, trading calm.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Price movements were tight on London's white sugar futures market on Thursday as players juggled positions before the spot March contract goes off the board at close of trading.</p>
<p>Activity was calmer than in recent sessions, reflected in a more modest volume after last week's all-time record.</p>
<p>One leading trade house was reported to be active on both sides on the market and some light commission house dealings were also noted.</p>
<p>The March/May spread edged out slightly but remained clear of the levels seen in early trade on Wednesday, when it widened to more than $6.00.</p>
<p>Traders said the hefty volumes seen over the last week or so suggested that between one and two cargoes at most were likely to be delivered against the March contract at expiry.</p>
<p>Origins would be the European Union and possibly Poland, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's bits and pieces today...I think the whites will go off pretty tamely,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>At 1305 GMT March was up just 50 cents at $305.40 and May down 20 cents at $301.30. Volume totalled 546 lots.</p>
<p>The March arbitrage is likely to be a focus of trading interest when the New York market opens as it narrowed back to around $70 in late trading on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It all gets a bit out of line nearer to expiry,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>Technically, the second-month May contract, about to take over the limelight of spot position, continued to trade above a bear trendline dating from the September high, while moving along a three-week upward channel.</p>
<p>In physical news, Taiwan Sugar said it had completed a contract to buy 30,000 tonnes of sugar from Czarnikow at a private tender in New York.</p>
<p>Pricing is to remain confidential by mutual agreement and shipment is scheduled from April 20 to May 5.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's agriculture ministry said 8,000 hectares would be planted with sugar beet in 1997 and forecast output of 120,000 tonnes compared to 53,000 in 1996.</p>
<p>Activity was subdued on the Paris market where just 138 lots were posted on the board.</p>
<p>March was untraded and May down 90 cents at $300.60.</p>
<p>-- Jeremy Smith, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8064</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
