<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="374934" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Sports News - Feb 14.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Sports News - Feb 14.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Lucas Parsons fired an equal course record nine-under-par 64 to lead on the first day of the Australian Masters at Huntingdale in Melbourne yesterday. He leads fellow New South Welshman Peter O'Malley who shot a 65 whilst tournament draw-card and crowd favourite Tiger Woods hit an impressive 68 to be four stokes off the pace. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Leading Melbourne horse trainer Lee Freedman was found guilty yesterday of not taking proper precautions in ensuring two of his horses were not administered a prohibited substance and was fined A$3000. Stewards found that persons entered Freedmans's stable without his knowledge with the intent of nobbling two of his horses. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Cricketer Matthew Elliott made an encouraging comeback in South Africa yesterday, scoring 91 against Nicky Oppenheimer's XI. He joined with Matthew Hayden to put on 124 for the opening wicket, and is tipped to take over the number three role from test newcomer Justin Langer. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Super League chief executive John Ribot has confirmed he is continuing negotiations with Queensland Events Corporation in preparation to hold the first Super League grand final at Brisbane's ANZ stadium. Ribot said ANZ's ability to hold more than 50,000 pectators and its strong record of holding major events were the major factors for its favouritism for the grand final. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Brisbane Broncos Super League coach Wayne Bennett has accepted the position of Queensland coach for the upcoming triangular series against New South Wales and New Zealand, but not before he was promised by Super League chief executive John Ribot there wold be no politics in team selections. Page 43.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The row intensified between rival Super League and Australian Rugby League teams in Newcastle yesterday as the Newcastle Knights were ordered to pay A$138,000 in back rent for the use of Marathon stadium. Knights chief executive Ian Bonnette believes the City Council was influenced by the Knight's Super League rivals, the Hunter Mariners in the decision. Page 43.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Sydney Swans chief executive Kevin Templeton says the team's A$74,000 profit last year is unlikely to hasten the arrival of a second Australian Football League (AFL) team to Sydney, saying the AFL will only bring another team to the city if it considers te Swans to be secure and a second team will be viable. Page 43.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Towering Wallaby back-rower Daniel Manu is keen to cement a spot in the New South Wales Super 12 side after being selected to replace the injured Fili Finau for the Warratah's trial match against Waikato in Sydney tomorrow night. Manu was a stand-out performer in the New South Wales 'A' 49-0 win against Western Samoa on Wednesday night. Page 43.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Following the Socceroos wins against Norway, New Zealand and South Korea in the recent four nations tournament in Australia, it has been moved up 17 places in the FIFA world rankings from 47 last month to 33, the biggest move from any country within the top 50. Page C6.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Former Olympic 100 metres Olympic champion Linford Christie will run in Australia for the first time in five years when he competes at an athletics meet in Melbourne next Thursday. Christie will race many of the country's up-and-coming sprinters, which follows the recent visit to Australia by American record gold-medalist Carl Lewis. Page C6.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Former Australian Wimbledon champion Pat Cash has scored a surprise victory over Spaniard Carlos Costa in the first round of the Dubai open. Cash, a wild card into the event, won 7-6 (7-4), 7-7 (8-6) to advance into the second round. Australian Sandon Solle also won in straight sets. Page C6.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE HERALD SUN</p>
<p>The Australian Football League (AFL) has urged clubs to support the move to Docklands stadium, as ticket prices for the new stadium were revealed yesterday. AFL chief executive Wayne Jackson has informed all clubs that fans will have to pay between $20.8 and $31.80 for premium tickets at the new stadium. Page 134.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A Commonwealth Games and world championship medalist has informed the Australian Institute of Sport he is likely to return a positive drug test. The cyclist is understood to have informed officials of the positive test after inadvertently taking a banned stimulant during competition in New Zealand three weeks ago. Page 134.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>South Australia holds a 266 run lead against Tasmania in their Sheffield Shield match in Hobart. At stumps, South Australia was 3-127 in its second innings after Tasmania struggled to reach 248 with the only bright point a 126 from test discard Ricky Ponting. Page 126.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The future of Ericsson Cup soccer team the Collingwood Warriors looks in doubt after two key businessmen withdrew their support from the battling club. A club spokesman said the team could be $A400,000 off budget by the end of the season after poor crowd attendences during the year. Page 128.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
