<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375068" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAJIKISTAN: U.N. hostage reported killed in Tajikistan.</title>
<headline>U.N. hostage reported killed in Tajikistan.</headline>
<byline>Yuri Kushko</byline>
<dateline>DUSHANBE 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tajik rebels holding more than a dozen Western and Russian hostages killed a U.N. military observer among the captives after an expected hostage-for-rebel swap did not take place, Itar-Tass news agency reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>United Nations sources in the Tajik capital Dushanbe declined to make any comment and Western diplomats expressed caution about the report, which was also carried by Interfax news agency.</p>
<p>An Itar-Tass correspondent, herself one of the hostages being held near Obigarm, 80 km (50 miles) east of Dushanbe, reported the fatal shooting of the U.N. military observer by satellite phone to her office in Moscow.</p>
<p>An Interfax journalist, another of the hostages, also rang to confirm the shooting. Neither journalist named the observer who had been shot.</p>
<p>It was not clear why the captive Tass and Interfax reporters were allowed to telephone from the rebel base, nor how freely they could describe the situation there.</p>
<p>The hostages include three U.N. military observers -- two Swiss and a Ukrainian -- four Russian reporters and four workers with the U.N. refugee agency. The rebels also seized Tajikistan's security minister on Saturday when he flew in to negotiate the captives' release.</p>
<p>In Switzerland, a defence ministry spokesman called the Tass report of the hostage killing &quot;not credible&quot; and said the Swiss government was still seeking information from Tajikistan and from United Nations.</p>
<p>The Tajik government earlier on Thursday flew in 40 rebels from Afghanistan ahead of a deadline set by the rebels, but their release was delayed by haggling over details.</p>
<p>Government spokesman Zafar Saidov said helicopters carrying the fighters had landed near Obigarm, where fighters Rizvon and Bakhron Sadirov are holding their captives.</p>
<p>But their release was delayed as the two sides could not agree on a procedure for the hostages-for-rebels swap, he said.</p>
<p>Interfax said the rebels had killed the U.N. military observer after the Tajik authorities failed to meet the conditions they had set.</p>
<p>&quot;The hostages held by the Sadirov brothers ask the government of Russia and Tajikistan to take all measures for the exchange of the hostages,&quot; Interfax correspondent Suraiye Sobirova told her agency. &quot;Otherwise all the hostages will be killed.&quot;</p>
<p>In Moscow, Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin was informed of the situation on Thursday evening while chairing a cabinet meeting, Tass said. He was expected to telephone the Tajik president on Thursday night.</p>
<p>Russia's deputy foreign minister Igor Ivanov was quoted by Interfax as condeming the reported killing &quot;in the most decisive way.&quot;</p>
<p>The United Nations Mission of Observers in Tajikistan has about 45 military personnel in the republic in an operation aimed at ending a four-year civil war between the secular government and Islamist opposition forces.</p>
<p>In December, Sadirov's group took 23 people hostage, including seven U.N. observers. All the hostages were later released.</p>
<p>On Tuesday the rebels released one of their current hostages, an Austrian U.N. observer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TADZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUSHANBE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAJIKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
