<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375099" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Buying side cautious on Budapest grains market.</title>
<headline>Buying side cautious on Budapest grains market.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trade in grains futures on the Budapest Commodity Exchange (BCE) dropped to a meagre 190.75 million forints on Thursday due to a very cautious buying side, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sales for new (1997) crop milling wheat and old (1996) crop maize were so far euphoric, but most of it was speculative&quot; said Istvan Markus of Swap brokerage. &quot;It is natural that any sign of a price rise prompts the closing of positions.&quot;</p>
<p>New crop wheat maturities opened lower but firmed by the close, he said.</p>
<p>March maturity milling wheat prices rose 100 forints to 25,100 forints per tonne, as some speculators sought to close their positions.</p>
<p>Markus added that most of the remaining open March contracts for milling wheat and maize were probably backed up by actual deliveries.</p>
<p>There are 2,735 open contracts for March maize and 1,016 for milling wheat.</p>
<p>Despite a shortage of barley, feed barley prices dropped by the daily 400 forints limit for all maturities from May to September and Markus said barley prices remain highly unpredictable.</p>
<p>&quot;Feed barley now follows earlier drops in other commodities with a phase delay, but seems to have a mind of its own,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that this year's planted area is the smallest in the last 10 years but the dramatic drop in sow livestock also means a reduced feed demand.</p>
<p>&quot;Also, Hungarian feed mixes traditionally contain only a small percentage of barley, thus its price is not so critical,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Total turnover on Thursday was 495 contracts of which 248 were for milling wheat.</p>
<p>Lot size is 20,000 kgs for all contracts.</p>
<p>($=174.02 Hungarian forints)</p>
<p>-- Denes Albert, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
