<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375172" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albanian police officer's home bombed, no one hurt.</title>
<headline>Albanian police officer's home bombed, no one hurt.</headline>
<dateline>VLORE, Albania 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Masked assailants have bombed the home of an Albanian police officer widely accused of scattering anti-government protesters last week by racing his car through the town of Vlore, according to the Interior Ministry.</p>
<p>An Interior Ministry statement said masked persons threw explosives into the apartment of Limoz Sallani on Wednesday night, causing damage but no injuries. The family was not in the apartment at the time.</p>
<p>Sallani is accused by many protesters of being behind the wheel of a white Volkswagen car which sped through Vlore's streets last Thursday, sending hundreds of anti-government protesters scrambling for safety.</p>
<p>One demonstrator hurled a stone at the car, shattering its windscreen. No one was injured but the incident raised tensions in the town.</p>
<p>Thousands of people have demonstrated in Vlore for the past nine days after a local get-rich-quick investment scheme failed, owing investors $500 million.</p>
<p>One person was shot dead and two others died from heart attacks during clashes between anti-government protesters and riot police earlier this week. Some 150 people were injured.</p>
<p>Another police officer was shot dead on Wednesday in an attack near his home in a Vlore suburb. He was identified as Shezai Zani, 30.</p>
<p>Police said the case appeared to be criminal and not linked to the recent clashes. Random violence has risen in Vlore since police virtually pulled out after being stoned by protesters this week.</p>
<p>More than 100 impounded speedboats, often used to smuggle illegal refugees across the Adriatic to Italy, were seized from a Vlore compound by their owners this week after police left.</p>
<p>Police also said an 18-year-old girl was kidnapped from her Vlore home on Wednesday night. Her father was shot while trying to save her.</p>
<p>The father, Hamid Dule, was in critical condition in the hospital. He told police three masked kidnappers said they were going to sell the girl to a prostitution ring in Italy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VLORE, Albania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
