<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37512" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs, pork bellies end higher, cash supportive.</title>
<headline>CME hogs, pork bellies end higher, cash supportive.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME hog and pork belly futures closed higher in reaction to a slowdown in hog marketings late this week, traders said.</p>
<p>The slowdown in hog runs resulted in higher cash hog prices Thursday and Friday at Midwest markets. Also, CME traders said cash hogs may trade steady to higher Monday.</p>
<p>Pork bellies settled with steep gains largely on continued short covering from Thursday, but some new longs joined the buying amid ideas cash prices may firm.</p>
<p>Analysts said seasonally, cash hog supplies gradually decline from now through the fall and prices increase.</p>
<p>Some traders agreed the long-term trend may be higher in hogs, but cautioned that a seasonal rolling of longs from October to December contracts should begin next week which would pressure October.  </p>
<p>USDA reported actual interior Iowa/southern Minnesota hog marketings for Thursday were 98,000 head, under its 105,000 estimate. USDA estimated Friday's marketings at 100,000 head versus 106,000 a week ago.</p>
<p>Also, USDA reported Friday's hog slaughter at 305,000 head, below 345,000 a week ago, but much of this decline was linked to east coast packing plants being down Friday because of Hurricane Fran.</p>
<p>A Smithfield Foods official said its Tar Heel, N.C., hog plant will operate two shifts Saturday if employees can get to the plant.</p>
<p>Hogs closed up 0.025 to 0.300 cent with October up 0.125 at 53.775 cents per lb and December up 0.275 at 54.900 cents. Pork bellies closed up 1.650 to 0.425 cent with February up the most at 78.575.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
