<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375159" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary's BUX firms one percent after results.</title>
<headline>Hungary's BUX firms one percent after results.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian share prices closed mixed with upward sentiment on Thursday, traders said.</p>
<p>A strong gain on Wall Street overnight and corporate results had a positive impact on the market but many investors remained on the sidelines awaiting 1996 results, most of which are expected on Friday, they said.</p>
<p>The BUX index closed at 5,635.99 points, up 57.41.</p>
<p>&quot;In theory Wall Street's rise helps,&quot; said Balazs Szabo of Eastbrokers. &quot;If it went downwards, we'd go downwards, too,&quot; he added. &quot;The market was cautiously optimistic.</p>
<p>Traders said the market opened higher benefiting from good corporate results but later oil company MOL shares took over the trend-setter role.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result of the company reports most shares opened higher,&quot; said Tamas Revesz of Wintrust. &quot;Later definitely MOL showed trend for the market.&quot;</p>
<p>MOL opened at 3,150 forints, up from Wednesday's close of 3,115 forints, but when a seller emerged on the market, all shares began to come down to close below the day's peaks, traders said.</p>
<p>Of the bout of corporate results released this morning, gas distributor Primagaz which boosted its operating profit to 2.37 billion forints in 1996 from 1.28 billion in 1995, firmed over four percent to close at 10,490, up 440.</p>
<p>Pharmaceuticals Human which reported after-tax consolidated profit of 712.1 million forints in 1996 against 469.3 million, advanced 55 forints to end at 3,245.</p>
<p>Elsewhere on the market, pharmaceuticals Richter fell from a day's high of 12,400 forints to 12,000 on what Revesz explained by news that Hungary's privatisation agency APV Rt said it would sell further stakes in Richter.</p>
<p>The share later recovered to close at 12,350, down 100, in demand by foreigners.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
