<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375307" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Cuba says U.S. news bureaus will be Cuban decision.</title>
<headline>Cuba says U.S. news bureaus will be Cuban decision.</headline>
<byline>Pascal Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cuba alone will decide, in accordance with its national interests, whether or not to allow more than one U.S. news organisation to open reporting offices on the island, Cuban Foreign Ministry officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry spokeswoman Marianela Ferriol told a news conference in Havana the Cuban government stood by its decision, announced in November, to allow Cable News Network to have a reporting bureau in Cuba.</p>
<p>CNN will be the first U.S. news organisation to open an office on the communist-ruled island since 1969.</p>
<p>Ferriol described a U.S. government decision on Wednesday to grant licenses to 10 U.S. media organisations, including CNN, to open news bureaus in Cuba as an &quot;internal policy&quot; decision by the United States that would not influence Cuba's policy.</p>
<p>&quot;Decisions concerning our country are the sole responsibility of our government and our people,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Frank Gonzalez, director of the Cuban Foreign Ministry's International Press Centre, added that the entry of foreign journalists to Cuba was decided by the Cuban authorities &quot;in accordance with national interests.&quot; This covered both the individual concerned and the organisation he or she represented.</p>
<p>Ferriol was reluctant to be drawn on whether the Cuban government would consider the authorisation of news bureaus on the island for the nine organisations, apart from CNN, mentioned in Wednesday's announcement in Washington.</p>
<p>&quot;When we take a decision, we announce it. This has nothing to do with decisions taken by the United States,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The organisations granted licenses for Cuba by the United States were CNN, ABC, Univision and CBS television networks; the Miami Herald, Chicago Tribune and Fort Lauderdale Sun-Sentinel newspapers; the Associated Press and Dow Jones news agencies and the Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies, which publishes information on Cuba.</p>
<p>Ferriol was asked what criteria the Cuban authorities would employ when deciding whether or not to allow other U.S. media, apart from CNN, to have a presence in Cuba. &quot;We want the reality of our country to be known,&quot; she said, but added that coverage should be objective and respectful.</p>
<p>&quot;Any media organisation which lends itself to projecting the U.S. government's policy of hostility against Cuba is disqualified,&quot; Ferriol said. She cited no specific cases but was clearly referring to U.S. government-funded media like Radio and TV Marti, which broadcast to the island and are hostile to President Fidel Castro's one-party communist rule.</p>
<p>Ferriol made clear Cuba would continue its current policy of granting temporary entry visas to U.S. journalists. &quot;They have been coming and will keep on coming,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Negotiations with CNN were taking place to establish the terms and details of the network's presence in Cuba.</p>
<p>The Foreign Ministry spokeswoman's response was less strident than an article published on Thursday by the Communist Party daily Granma which rejected the U.S. government announcement as a &quot;new act of interference by Washington.&quot;</p>
<p>Condemning what it called U.S. &quot;arrogance,&quot; Granma said the U.S. approval of licenses for Cuba for U.S. media was part of a gradual implementation of the U.S. Helms-Burton law, which seeks to force political change on the island by tightening longstanding U.S. economic sanctions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
