<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375497" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American, pilots talk as strike deadline looms.</title>
<headline>American, pilots talk as strike deadline looms.</headline>
<byline>Robert Trautman</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>American Airlines' pilots' union said on Thursday it would present a broad offer aimed at averting a strike, but the mediator shuttling between the union and company officials said talks were slow and difficult.</p>
<p>With time running out before a midnight Friday (0500 GMT Saturday) strike deadline, the nation's second-largest carrier and its pilots' union continued marathon negotiations with a government mediator on hand.</p>
<p>&quot;This afternoon we will make a complete proposal on competitive costs, either face-to-face or through the mediator,&quot; Allied Pilots Association President James Sovich told a news conference.</p>
<p>American said it would not comment on the new offer until it saw the details.</p>
<p>A strike would disrupt plans for hundreds of thousands of travelers. The Fort Worth, Texas-based airline is trying to rebook passengers on other carriers and has already cancelled nearly all international flights scheduled for Friday night.</p>
<p>A Transportation Department official said a strike could cost the U.S. economy up to $200 million a day.</p>
<p>The official, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the figure was contained in a government report sent to the National Mediation Board and the White House.</p>
<p>At the negotiations, the union said its proposal dealt with two of the key disputes with American -- pay for pilots on American's regular flights and whether its union pilots should fly smaller jets for the airline's American Eagle unit and their level of pay.</p>
<p>American wants to use lower-paid pilots from another union on the American Eagle regional flights, which the Allied Pilots Association opposes. The airline, a unit of AMR Corp., wants lower costs to compete with other major airlines' regional commuter services.</p>
<p>The pilots said a possible compromise would be for members of their union to fly regional jets, but at lower pay.</p>
<p>The union's chief negotiator, Brian Mayhew, said the pilots also offered a new proposal on pay -- presumably less than the 11.5 percent pay increase over four years sought earlier -- but he gave no details.</p>
<p>The latest offer on pay from American was a 6 percent raise over four years.</p>
<p>The union said the two sides were not that far apart and said American could afford to bridge the gap without losing its competitive position in the industry.</p>
<p>But the government mediator trying to bring the two sides together played down prospects for a breakthrough in the bitter dispute.</p>
<p>&quot;I would characterise the pace (of the negotiations) as going still very slowly and with great difficulty. However, we are hopeful that this comprehensive proposal (from the union) will provide a means for resolution,&quot; said the National Mediation Board's Kenneth Hipp.</p>
<p>Separately, American Airlines Chairman Robert Crandall called for binding government arbitration of the dispute, a proposal the pilots have repeatedly rejected.</p>
<p>&quot;I think mandatory binding arbitration should be required&quot; to prevent airline strikes, Crandall told a congressional subcommittee.</p>
<p>&quot;I seriously doubt we could accept that,&quot; union spokesman Wally Pitts said.</p>
<p>The two sides were already negotiating with a mediator present but binding arbitration would mean both parties agreed to abide by the decision of an arbitrator.</p>
<p>Crandall told a hearing of a House of Representatives Transportation subcommittee he was unsure if a strike could be avoided.</p>
<p>&quot;We have two choices: we can either cave in or take a strike. A strike of 90 days will destroy this airline,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>As the talks entered their fourth day of intensive bargaining, President Bill Clinton was keeping a close watch.</p>
<p>Clinton could intervene and name an emergency board to try to resolve the issues. Creation of a board would prevent any work stoppages for 60 days while the board and the two parties again tried to mend their differences.</p>
<p>But at an unrelated news conference on Thursday, Clinton repeated that the parties should use the government mediator to reach an agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;It cannot be a good thing for the people of the United States, and indeed people coming to the United States from other parts of the world, for a significant interruption to occur in the operations of this airline,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
