<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375513" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American General to acquire USLife for $1.8 billion.</title>
<headline>American General to acquire USLife for $1.8 billion.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Vowinkel</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>American General Corp. will acquire USLife Corp., a rival financial services company with major life insurance operations, for $1.8 billion in stock, the companies said Thursday.</p>
<p>The acquisition comes amid a major consolidation in the life insurance industry and follows weeks of speculation that USLife might be a takeover candidate.</p>
<p>American General said it will pay $49 worth of its own common stock for each share of New York-based USLife.</p>
<p>American General's shares edged up 37.5 cents to $41.875, and USLife soared $5.25 to $47, both on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;This merger represents the largest transaction in American General's history and is an outstanding strategic fit which offers a unique opportunity to combine two of the premier providers of life insurance and financial services in the nation,&quot; said American General Chief Executive Rober M. Devlin said in a statement.</p>
<p>USLIFE Chairman Gordon Crosby told investors on a tense conference call he does not expect any jobs to be eliminated as a result of the merger. &quot;We don't anticipate any at the moment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said there would be cost savings, that decisions about senior management of the combined company had not yet been made, and that the deal included a $48 million break up fee.</p>
<p>But Crosby declined to elaborate, infuriating investors and Wall Street analysts who found him was surprisingly uncooperative.</p>
<p>&quot;I never heard one like that,&quot; one analyst said. &quot;I give up on what the intention of this conference call was. If you're not at liberty to speak, why be there?&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Speculation about USLife had grown in recent weeks as Crosby, its chairman for 30 years, neared the end of his term with no chance for re-election unless the board approved an extension in the age limit for directors.</p>
<p>Crosby, 76, who had been known for his steadfast opposition to a takeover of the company, said Thursday, &quot;This is truly an outstanding result for both organisations.&quot;</p>
<p>American General is a diversified financial services company that provides retirement services, consumer loans and life insurance to nine million customers. It had 1996 sales of $10.9 billion. The company has about 15,300 employees.</p>
<p>USLife, also a holding company, has operations in life and health insurance and other financial services. It had 1996 sales of $1.6 billion. The company has about 2,140 employees.</p>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's Corp. said its ratings on USLIFE's debt remain under review, since Wednesday, amid concerns about the company's limited financial flexibility and surprisingly low life insurance sales in 1996.</p>
<p>However, the credit agency revised its implications to &quot;developing&quot; from negative after news of the merger.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
