<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375657" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton makes pitch for embattled CIA nominee.</title>
<headline>Clinton makes pitch for embattled CIA nominee.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton on Thursday made a strong and emotional plea for the Senate to stop delaying action on his nomination of Anthony Lake to be CIA director, praising Lake's service to the country and saying he deserved a hearing.</p>
<p>&quot;His service to this country deserves a hearing and a vote on the floor of the Senate and I hope he will get it,&quot; Clinton said at a news conference, thumping the lectern with his fist for emphasis.  </p>
<p>The Republican-led Senate Intelligence Committee is delaying confirmation hearings on Lake, who was Clinton's first-term national security adviser, because of questions both about his involvement in some U.S. policy decisions and his failure to divest himself of some energy stock.</p>
<p>This has clearly nettled Clinton to the point that, when no one asked about it during a joint news conference with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, he brought it up himself and launched into praise of Lake.</p>
<p>&quot;We've now answered all the questions that we've been asked (about Lake's qualifications),&quot; he said. &quot;... I think he ought to be given a hearing and a vote.</p>
<p>&quot;And I'd like to remind everybody it was Tony Lake who came up with the strategy that we implemented to end the bloodiest war in Europe since World War II (in Bosnia),&quot; he said. &quot;He was a terrific success as the national security adviser to the president ... He fully understands intelligence operations. He is superbly qualified. If someone has some reason to oppose him let them oppose him in a hearing and in a vote on the floor.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
