<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375691" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Congressman queries Chicago Fed operations.</title>
<headline>Congressman queries Chicago Fed operations.</headline>
<byline>Isabelle Clary</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Operations at the Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago are the object of an inquiry by a senior member of the House of Representatives' banking committee, according to a document obtained by Reuters.</p>
<p>The office of Congressman Henry Gonzalez, ranking member of the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services, D-Texas, sent a two-page memo dated Jan. 14 to the Chicago Fed requesting information.</p>
<p>Gonzalez has repeatedly criticised the Fed, in the past, for not giving minorities sufficient representation in senior positions and for a lack of openess.</p>
<p>The memo, addressed to William Gram, secretary and general counsel at the Chicago Fed, cited complaints that had been made to the congressman's office about the bank's operations and an alleged incident of harassment.</p>
<p>Gonzalez's office confirmed being in contact with the Chicago Fed, but declined to elaborate. &quot;I really can't comment at the moment,&quot; said Robert Auerbach, an economist on Gonzalez's staff.</p>
<p>According to the memo, Auerbach was the staff member requesting the information from the bank.</p>
<p>The Chicago Fed confirmed having received a request for information from Gonzalez's office and said the allegations that triggered the inquiry were contained in an anonymous letter sent to both the bank and Gonzalez's office.</p>
<p>&quot;We acknowlege that an anonymous letter was received by the Chicago Fed and by Mr. Gonzalez's office which did, indeed, contact us regarding that matter,&quot; a spokeswoman for the bank said.</p>
<p>&quot;An anonymous letter would not be dismissed at hand,&quot; the spokeswoman added, pointing out that the author's desire for anonymity raised the issue of motivation.</p>
<p>In its memo, Gonzalez's office requested that the Chicago Fed produce, among other things:</p>
<p>-- A list of employees earning more than $100,000 a year in 1990 and 1996;</p>
<p>-- the number of bank examinations in 1990 and 1996;</p>
<p>-- 1994-1996 travel expenses for employees earning more than $100,000 a year, and a statement about whether they were accompanied by relatives on any trips;</p>
<p>-- the itemised cost of conferences held by the Chicago Fed in the past three years;</p>
<p>-- a list of outside consultants employed by the Chicago Fed in the past three years.</p>
<p>The memo also showed that Gonzalez's office requested information about how any harassment cases at the bank over the last three years had been settled. It asked for a breakdown of employees &quot;by race, sex, disability, and age.&quot;</p>
<p>The inquiry comes as the Fed is reconsidering the financial services it provides to the public.</p>
<p>Technological changes, new banking regulations and competition from the private sector led Fed Chairman Alan Greenspan to appoint a special commission, headed by Vice Chairwoman Alice Rivlin, to look into the future role of the Fed in the world's largest payments system.</p>
<p>The Chicago Tribune reported on Feb. 5 that the Chicago Fed eliminated six officer positions in three departments at the end of January. The paper cited a late January internal memo to Chicago Fed staff that was made available to the newspaper.</p>
<p>The memo was from Chicago Fed President Michael Moskow and First Vice President Bill Conrad. It cited concern that the &quot;traditional management structure continues to be too hierarchical and top-heavy,&quot; the newspaper said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
