<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375688" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NW gas pipeline at reduced capacity through Friday.</title>
<headline>NW gas pipeline at reduced capacity through Friday.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Northwest Pipeline Corp officials hope to complete a survey of their natural gas system Friday and could restore it to full capacity soon afterward, a company spokesman said Thursday.</p>
<p>John Nicksich, spokesman for the pipeline operator owned by Williams Cos Inc, said capacity of the high-pressure system at the Canadian border town of Sumas, Wash., had been reduced to about 700 million cubic feet daily from 1,066 million cubic feet.</p>
<p>He said capacity would be increased to 800 million cubic feet Friday but could not estimate when full capacity would be restored, saying that would depend on results of the survey of the 260-mile pipeline section.</p>
<p>Northwest Pipeline decided to shut down one of two paired north-south lines it runs through western Washington state late Wednesday after discovering a new land movement near Everson, Wash., where the line ruptured and exploded Saturday, apparently due to shifting land.</p>
<p>The next day, 220 miles to the south near Kalama, Wash., another land shift caused the same 26-inch pipeline to rupture and explode in a towering fireball.</p>
<p>Gas was diverted around the affected sites to the parallel 30-inch line until the 26-inch line was repaired, but then consulting geologists saw signs of more land movement.</p>
<p>&quot;They saw that and at that point they said, let's survey the entire thing,&quot; Nicksich said. &quot;This was completely voluntary on the part of Northwest Pipeline.&quot;</p>
<p>He said despite the capacity reduction, customers are getting the gas they need by going to alternative suppliers in Wyoming or Colorado rather than to Canadian suppliers or by turning to an interconnected Pacific Gas Transmission line, owned by PG&amp;E Corp.</p>
<p>Nicksich said there also was some gas remaining in the 26-inch line and some stored gas available.</p>
<p>The survey began Thursday with crews checking the line visually by helicopter and sending in ground crews to inspect spots where land movement is suspected.</p>
<p>Washington state has been pounded this winter by unusually heavy snow and rain, saturating the ground.</p>
<p>((-- Reuters Seattle bureau 206-386-4848))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
