<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375629" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ITT asset sales expected to take months.</title>
<headline>ITT asset sales expected to take months.</headline>
<byline>Robin Sidel</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>ITT Corp expects the sale of its non-core assets to take up to six months, although the Madison Square Garden properties are likely to be sold more quickly, according to sources close to the company.</p>
<p>The hotel, casino and entertainment company has held high-level talks with Cablevision Systems Corp about acquiring its 50 percent stake in Madison Square Garden, but no deal has been struck, the sources said.</p>
<p>Cablevision is &quot;the primary potential acquirer,&quot; said one source close to ITT who declined to be identified.  </p>
<p>Although ITT has held discussions with potential buyers about the other properties, which include its profitable international telephone directories business, those talks are not in advanced stages, the sources said.</p>
<p>Sources also said on Thursday that ITT has hired Morgan Stanley to assist with the asset sales. ITT also is being advised by Lazard Freres and Chase Securities.</p>
<p>ITT declined to comment on the potential sales or the hiring of Morgan Stanely. A Morgan Stanley spokeswoman also declined to comment.  </p>
<p>ITT rejected a $6.5 billion hostile takeover bid from Hilton Hotels Corp on Wednesday and said it would consider selling non-core assets to boost shareholder value.</p>
<p>ITT partnered with Cablevision in 1995 to buy the Madison Square Garden properties, which include the world-famous arena, the New York Knicks professional basketball team and the New York Rangers professional hockey team.</p>
<p>Cablevision declined to comment again today, referring to a Wednesday statement in which it said it does not comment on rumored deals and also noted it has a good relationship with ITT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
