<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375662" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. warns cigarette butts a danger to infants.</title>
<headline>U.S. warns cigarette butts a danger to infants.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Small children risk becoming sick from swallowing cigarettes and butts that adults leave around the house, federal health officials warned Thursday.</p>
<p>The U.S. Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) reviewed 90 cases in Rhode Island where children between six months and two years swallowed cigarettes or cigarette butts. One-third of them became sick. Most of them vomited, while others suffered nausea, lethargy or gagging.</p>
<p>&quot;Children in households where cigarettes were smoked in their presence were four times as likely to ingest cigarettes or cigarette butts as children in households where smoking does not occur around children,&quot; the CDC said.</p>
<p>&quot;This study points out another potentially dangerous scenario associated with the use of tobacco around children,&quot; CDC epidemiologist Ann Malarcher said.</p>
<p>&quot;Second-hand smoke has been linked to as much as 300,000 respiratory infections among infants and young children in the United States,&quot; she said. &quot;It's known to cause chronic coughing, wheezing and phlegm in these children.&quot;</p>
<p>The American Association of Poison Control Centres said it received 7,917 reports of potentially toxic exposures to tobacco products among children aged 6 and under in 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
