<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375669" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MWRA proposes average 8.9 pct rate hike for FY '98.</title>
<headline>MWRA proposes average 8.9 pct rate hike for FY '98.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Massachusetts Water Resources Authority (MWRA) proposed an average of 8.9 percent rate hike in wholesale water and sewer charges to the communities it serves to fund a $410 million expense budget for fiscal year 1998 that begins July 1.</p>
<p>MWRA spokeswoman Shelia McGann said in a telephone interview Thursday that debt service on bonds issued to finance construction of new facilities including the Deer Island Sewage Treatment Plant makes up 50.4 percent of the proposed budget.</p>
<p>MWRA said in a statement that the final cost of the Deer Island plant remains $3.6 billion and that debt service represents the largest increase in the new budget, up by $28 million over last year.</p>
<p>The plant &quot;is now 90 percent complete,&quot; MWRA Executive Director Doug MacDonald said in a statement, adding, &quot;New operating costs are under tight rein, but paying for the new plant and our other needed system improvements makes a budget increase unavoidable...&quot;</p>
<p>Public hearings on the budget will be held in the Spring. A final budget is expected to be adopted in June.</p>
<p>MWRA's debt is rated single-A by both Moody's Investors and Standard &amp; Poor's.</p>
<p>((--Leslie Gevirtz, 617-367-4142))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I92120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
