<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37571" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Simpson faked look of surprise at verdict - author.</title>
<headline>Simpson faked look of surprise at verdict - author.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>O.J. Simpson knew he would be cleared of killing his ex-wife the night before the verdict was announced and faked his look of surprise in court, according to the author of a new book on the criminal trial.</p>
<p>New Yorker magazine writer Jeffrey Toobin told a television interviewer Simpson learned in advance from a jail guard of the jury's decision to find him not guilty.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the things I've learned since the trial is that one of the most famous moments in television history, which is that shot of O.J., is fundamentally a fraud,&quot; Toobin said in excerpts of an interview released before broadcast on NBC News' &quot;Dateline Sunday&quot; on Sept. 8.</p>
<p>A Los Angeles jury found Simpson not guilty on Oct. 3, 1995 of stabbing to death his ex-wife Nicole Brown Simpson and her friend Ronald Goldman in June 1994 but he still faces a wrongful death civil trial starting Sept. 17. The former football star is being sued by the families of the murder victims, who allege he is responsible for their deaths.</p>
<p>Toobin, whose book is called &quot;The Run of His Life,&quot; said the jurors reached their verdict on the night of Oct. 2 and had a party during which they told Los Angeles sheriffs guarding them that the verdict was not guilty. One of the sheriffs called a friend who was guarding Simpson and told him, Toobin said in the interview.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the sheriffs came up to him (Simpson) and said 'I want your autograph tonight because you're going home tomorrow.' Simpson said 'what?',&quot; Toobin said. He quoted the sheriff as saying &quot;We know. Jury voted to acquit.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
