<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375703" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American Airlines pilots say to make new proposal.</title>
<headline>American Airlines pilots say to make new proposal.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pilots of AMR Corp.'s American Airlines will make a comprehensive proposal later Thursday to try to end a dispute with the company and head off a strike, a union leader said.</p>
<p>&quot;This afternoon we will make a complete proposal on competitive costs, either face to face or through the mediator,&quot; Allied Pilots Association President James Sovich told a news conference. The airline has said the pilots' pay and other demands would make it uncompetitive.  </p>
<p>Sovich said that although talks this week through a mediator had been &quot;incredibly difficult and not very fruitful,&quot; he believed a solution was possible.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a constructive solution to this problem. We believe our two sides should sit down together and bargain over competitive costs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the union's board would vote Friday on whether to authorise a strike that same night, adding &quot;I believe the board will vote to authorise the strike.&quot; He also said that President Clinton should not step in to avert the strike.</p>
<p>Clinton is &quot;seriously considering&quot; becoming involved in the dispute, Representative Martin Frost, D-Texas, said, adding he had spoken to administration representatives at the &quot;high level&quot; who have told him that Clinton is monitoring the dispute carefully.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
