<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375993" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Helsinki at life-high but profit-takers dent Nokia.</title>
<headline>Helsinki at life-high but profit-takers dent Nokia.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares managed a new life high in bumper volumes after a result-packed session led by Nokia on Thursday. But brokers were wary and, as profit-takers moved in late on the telecoms stock, saw room for a correction.</p>
<p>The HEX general index ended at the 2,855.97 point session low, up 0.73 percent, clearly below the 2,887.75 life-high set earlier but still its highest close ever. Volume was a massive 1.4 billion markka.</p>
<p>A 21 percent profit drop in 1996 plus a dividend hike from Nokia initially seemed to satisfy investors, and the stock held pre-result gains. But some profit-taking had been seen on the cards and by the close, Nokia was off four markka at 319.00.</p>
<p>&quot;In money terms, the result was exactly what was expected, but it wasn't any more than that, so these expectations have already been priced in,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Stockholm market sources also cited rumours Goldman Sachs had downgraded Nokia, which it denied. Analyst Richard Kramer said Goldman had Nokia as &quot;outperform&quot;.</p>
<p>One broker said Nokia had presented a very encouraging picture in its conference call with analysts: &quot;They had good things to say about all their lines of business. The outlook is really good,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another saw Nokia sticking around 300-330 markka near term.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Rautaruukki saw plenty of action and picked up 2.30 markka or over five percent to 44.50 after sounding upbeat on prospects and with results in line with the market's view.</p>
<p>Kesko put on 1.80 markka to 72.50 markka after its report beat expectations and Raisio rose nearly four percent to 440.00 -- but in fairly thin volumes -- after its report came in at the high end of market forecasts.</p>
<p>Amer fell 2.00 markka to 102.00 after reporting a wider-than-expected loss for 1996: &quot;The share could have fallen more than it did.&quot; said one broker. &quot;Evidently some foreign investors still think Amer is a good investment.&quot;</p>
<p>After rallies in other forestry stocks, Metsa-Serla attracted unusually heavy interest, adding 2.10 markka to 40.50, but brokers could identify no special reason.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
