<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375975" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Veba, BT meet as industry churns.</title>
<headline>Veba, BT meet as industry churns.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The global telecommunications industry seems to be an unending game of musical chairs, with the world's major players sure of only one thing: the market is a moving target and loyalty ends at the bottom line.</p>
<p>In the run-up to no-holds-barred competition in European telecommunications beginning in January, the German market, expected to be worth some 100 billion marks ($59.4 billion) by the year 2000, has become a microcosm for the entire industry.</p>
<p>In Germany, engineering group Mannesmann AG has teamed up with AT&amp;T Corp and the European Unisource NV alliance to run the telecommunications operations of the national railway.</p>
<p>In France, Mannesmann is doing the same thing. But this time not with AT&amp;T, but rather the U.S. phone giant's archrival British Telecom Plc, which is about to merge with AT&amp;T's U.S. competitor MCI Communications.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, German utility Veba AG, Mannesmann's most potent competitor among a host of newcomers to the German telecoms scene, confirmed on Thursday that its chairman Ulrich Hartmann met BT chairman Ian Vallance this week.</p>
<p>Last week, British Telecom and German utility Viag AG celebrated winning Germany's fourth digital mobile phone licence by welcoming Norway's Telenor Ltd into their telecoms alliance.</p>
<p>Now, Veba -- which last year lured away Viag and BT's partner RWE AG, another German utility, is seeking to play down any thoughts that the meeting between Hartmann and Vallance could mean BT was about to switch alliances.</p>
<p>&quot;Such speculation is complete nonsense,&quot; said Veba spokeswoman Marie-Luise Wolff.</p>
<p>But then again, Veba is still looking for an international partner for its telecommunications business after Cable and Wireless, BT's main competitor on its home market, defected from its alliance with Veba and RWE last week.</p>
<p>The daily Berliner Zeitung also reported on Thursday that BT was &quot;more than dissatisfied&quot; with its alliance with Viag.</p>
<p>BT would be a stronger partner for Veba, which is now looking a bit pale compared to Mannesmann.</p>
<p>Mannesmann appears to be building a counterweight to the powerful alliance of Deutsche Telekom and France Telecom by tying up with the national railways of Germany and France, which form the core of Europe's biggest telecoms markets.</p>
<p>But at this early stage in the game, it is just as hard for investors to weed out the losers as it is to say which of the aspirants are going to repeat the success of companies like MCI and Sprint Corp, who became the winners of the deregulation of the huge U.S. telecoms market 12 years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing that is certain is that there is going to be a lot of shifting around for some time to come,&quot; said one London-based telecoms analyst.</p>
<p>Industry officials say that there is nothing unusual about forming a partnership in one country with companies that they are competing against elsewhere.</p>
<p>Unlike any other industry perhaps, telecommunications firms must cooperate daily, carrying communications traffic from competitors over their own networks in order to complete calls.</p>
<p>But this should not smooth over the fact that the making and breaking of alliances today is evidence of an ongoing process of concentration that has been brought about by the unparalleled liberalisation of global telecoms markets.</p>
<p>In the end, industry observers expect a small handful of global telecommunications operators providing everything from basic telephone services to Internet access and cable television services.</p>
<p>($ = 1.684 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
