<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="375909" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German sex scandal isolated incident - U.S. army.</title>
<headline>German sex scandal isolated incident - U.S. army.</headline>
<byline>John Gilardi</byline>
<dateline>DARMSTADT, Germany 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. army commanders said on Thursday that allegations of sexual harassment at a base in Germany did not mean that there was a systematic problem there.</p>
<p>The army, embarrassed by a growing scandal at home, said on Wednesday it was probing allegations by 11 women soldiers that they were harassed or raped by male instructors at a Darmstadt training centre.</p>
<p>A statement by the training centre said complaints by some of the women also included forcible sodomy. Three male instructors , two of whom were in custody, had been relieved of duty pending an end to the investigation, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not know of any inappropriate conduct in a systematic pattern over time at Darmstadt,&quot; said Colonel Michael Sullivan, the chief spokesman for the army in Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;What we are dealing with here is an incident, or a series of incidents, involving the instructors at this academy over a relatively short period of time.&quot;</p>
<p>Army officials have not said how the instructors reacted to the allegations against them.</p>
<p>The scandal is the latest to hit the army, which has been investigating cases at training bases in the United States in which a number of male drill sergeants were charged with wrongdoing ranging from harassment to rape and sodomy of young women recruits.</p>
<p>The army has suspended its top enlisted man, Army Sergeant Major Gene McKinney, from duty in Washington pending resolution of sexual harassment charges against him by a retired woman soldier and at least two other women soldiers.</p>
<p>The Darmstadt inquiry arose from a complaint made by a woman assigned to a signal brigade near the town who had attended a two-week orientation and training programme at the centre before joining her new unit.</p>
<p>Her official complaint was turned over to criminal investigators last week after more victims were identified, the army said. Sullivan said the woman was still in the army and with her unit in the Darmstadt area.</p>
<p>Military officials, citing evidence from the 70 people questioned so far, said the incidents occurred between mid-November and mid-January and involved sergeants from Darmstadt units assigned to the centre on six-month rotations.</p>
<p>&quot;The allegations are that these men took advantage of women in a very vulnerable situation, many of them at lower ranks in the army, who were likely away from home for the first time,&quot; one military commander said.</p>
<p>The facility, the Individual Training Centre, is attended by all soldiers arriving for duty with the base support battalion and other units in the immediate area.</p>
<p>About 30 enlisted soliders, non-commissioned officers and commissioned offcers go through the centre each month, with single or unaccompanied married soldiers staying there along with the instructors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DARMSTADT, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
