<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37602" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. wage gains could push inflation toward 4 pct.</title>
<headline>U.S. wage gains could push inflation toward 4 pct.</headline>
<byline>Chris Stetkiewicz</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rising U.S. wages threaten to shatter the tranquil U.S. inflation picture, with some analysts predicting inflation near 4.0 percent by early 1997.</p>
<p>Consistent U.S. job growth and a steadily shrinking supply of available workers will soon end a six-year run of official inflation near 3.0 percent, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;You do have a serious problem. We'll potentially have as much as a one-percent runup in inflation before all is said and done,&quot; said Cary Leahey, senior financial markets economist at Lehman Government Securities Inc.  </p>
<p>Fresh signs of labor market tightness emerged from the August employment report released Friday morning. The economy created 250,000 new jobs, while the unemployment rate fell to 5.1 percent, a six-and-a-half-year low.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, average hourly earnings rose 0.5 percent, pushing the 12-month gain to 3.6 percent and sparking warnings of rising price inflation in the near future.</p>
<p>&quot;Does this mean we're going to see higher price inflation? In the context of a strong economy, if sustained, it will eventually show through,&quot; said Richard Berner, chief economist at Mellon Bank Corp in Pittsburgh.  </p>
<p>The U.S. consumer price index has hovered near 3.0 percent since 1991 even as the economy has enjoyed steady, if modest growth in gross domestic product.</p>
<p>Analysts have marveled at the economy's sparkling performance and readily admit they have issued several false alarms over inflation in recent months.</p>
<p>&quot;Skepticism should be well-founded. Other indicators, like rising capacity utilization, suggest we should have seen inflation pick up three months ago,&quot; Leahey conceded.</p>
<p>But wages are clearly rising, with hourly earnings up nearly five percent annualized over the last three months.  </p>
<p>&quot;This pushes deep into the inflation threshold,&quot; said Dan Seto, senior economist at Nikko Securities Co International Inc. &quot;You're looking at a significant bulge in earnings.&quot;</p>
<p>The current expansion has forced many analysts to rethink the relationship between the unemployment rate and inflation.</p>
<p>Analysts traditionally expected rising wage growth when official joblessness holds below 6.0 percent. But the jobless rate has held below 6.0 percent since June 1994 and wage growth is just now picking up.</p>
<p>But the drop in joblessness to 5.1 percent has inflation hawks beating the drums once again.  </p>
<p>&quot;Only recently the job market has gone from tight to really tight,&quot; Leahey said.</p>
<p>&quot;It will only take monthly job creation of 125,000 to keep unemployment where it is. Anything above 150,000 is great for people looking for jobs, but bad for people paid to worry about inflation,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The nation's official inflation-fighter, the Federal Reserve, is clearly concerned about the potential for job-related inflation. Friday's report raises the odds the panel will raise short-term interest rates at its September 24 policy-making meeting, analysts said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
