<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="376219" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMF gives Sudan last chance to deal with arrears.</title>
<headline>IMF gives Sudan last chance to deal with arrears.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Monetary Fund executive Board on Thursday gave Sudan a last chance to come to deal with arrears on its loan payments or face the threat of expulsion.</p>
<p>In a statement, the IMF board said it found that Sudan had persistently failed to meet its obligations but it would stop short of withdrawing its membership if Sudan took steps including making scheduled payments by March 3.</p>
<p>&quot;If Sudan fails to meet any of these conditions, the Board will meet promptly, to review the situation and recommend compulsory withdrawal to the Board of Governors,&quot; the statement said.  </p>
<p>Besides making its loan repayments, the IMF board said Sudan needed to agree and implement a program of economic and financial reform that warrants monthly monitoring by IMF staff.</p>
<p>The board said such a program would be negotiated with the Sudanese authorities but it added that Sudan was ineligible to use IMF financial resources.  </p>
<p>The IMF estimates Sudan is $1.7 billion in arrears on its loans, and Khartoum has shown little interest in rescheduling or other measures to solve the problem, monetary sources said.</p>
<p>The 24-member executive board could have recommended immediate expulsion, an action that would have thrown the matter to a vote by the IMF's 181 member countries and required a voting approval of 85 percent to achieve.</p>
<p>The monetary sources said many developing countries felt some sympathy for Sudan's plight and it would be difficult to convince them to go along with expulsion of Sudan.  </p>
<p>Membership of the IMF, formed in the last days of the Second World War, has risen substantially in recent years to 181 countries as the independent states of the former Soviet Union and others have signed on.</p>
<p>While some countries have chosen to leave the lending institution voluntarily, IMF records show only one country -- Czechoslovakia -- was compelled to withdraw because it refused to provide required economic data in the early 1950s.</p>
<p>Jose Pedro de Morais, an IMF alternate executive director, said in Khartoum last month that Sudan's case was also being hurt by perceptions the country was an Islamic fundamentalist state.</p>
<p>He said Washington in particular had argued in the past that Sudan should be expelled if it did not make some arrangement to repay its arrears.</p>
<p>The United States has also taken the view that Sudan is one of seven countries supporting terrorism and has cut off some trade, including arms sales.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
