<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="376531" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli January CPI seen rising 0.5 percent.</title>
<headline>Israeli January CPI seen rising 0.5 percent.</headline>
<byline>David Rosenberg</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's January consumer price index (CPI), due to be published on Friday, is expected to show a rise of about 0.5 percent, producing  a 10.3 percent year-on-year increase, economists said on Thursday.</p>
<p>But they warned of impending upward pressure on prices that could cause inflation to edge higher in the next few months. They said it was unlikely interest rates would be lowered this month.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bank of Israel has not given any signal that it will lower rates at this stage,&quot; said Irit Oren, economist at the Federation of Chambers of Commerce.</p>
<p>She said the relatively low increase in the index in January would be influenced by a sharp seasonal drop in clothing prices. The dollar's strong rise against the shekel, which began in mid-January, had not yet affected consumer prices, Oren added.</p>
<p>Since the start of the year the dollar has risen some 2.8 percent to 3.34 shekels, reflecting the strengthening of the U.S. currency in world markets.</p>
<p>Consumer prices rose 10.6 percent last year, but the rate fell sharply in the second half of the year to an annualised 6.8 percent from an annualised 14.6 percent in the first half.</p>
<p>Jonathan Katz, chief economist at Solid Financial Markets, said the key indicator in the January index would be housing prices. Housing prices have been on a moderating trend but rose an unexpected sharp 1.9 percent in December, compared with an overall CPI rise of 0.8 percent.</p>
<p>Katz said he expected inflation to edge higher starting in February.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like I'm revising my February forecast to 0.8 percent from 0.6 percent,&quot; he said. &quot;That's due both to the strengthening of the dollar...and the rise in vegetable prices due to the weather.&quot;</p>
<p>Katz said, he was raising his full-year forecast to 9.3 percent from 9.0 percent, while Oren said she was looking for a 9.2 percent rise. That would still be within the government's target of 7-10 percent, but economists said they doubted the Bank of Israel would lower rates.</p>
<p>Bank of Israel Governor Jacob Frenkel has expressed concern about the budget deficit, which reached 1.28 billion shekels in January. On Thursday, he told the parliamentary finance committee that the bank would maintain its cautionary stance.</p>
<p>Economists also said the bank was concerned about the sharp rise in M1 money supply in January. Sources at the Bank of Israel estimated M1 grew 3.5-4 percent.</p>
<p>Katz said the Bank of Israel believed that the economy was not heading into a recession and could therefore maintain high interest rates. He said the fourth-quarter GDP, which grew at a 2.7 percent annualised rate, indicated the economy was making a &quot;soft landing&quot; from its fast-paced growth of the early 1990s.</p>
<p>-- 972-2-537-0502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
