<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="376590" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NOTICE OF SALE - County Wake, N.C..</title>
<headline>NOTICE OF SALE - County Wake, N.C..</headline>
<text>
<p>SUMMARY NOTICE OF SALE</p>
<p>				 $100,000,000</p>
<p>				County of  Wake</p>
<p>				North Carolina</p>
<p>	   General Obligation School Bonds, Series 1997</p>
<p>Sealed bids for the above-captioned bonds will be received by the Local Government Commission of North Carolina at  its office in  the  Albemarle  Building,  Room  411,  325  North Salisbury Street, Raleigh,  North Carolina 27603-1385  until 11 o'clock A.M., North Carolina Time, on:</p>
<p>			     February 25, 1997</p>
<p>such bids to be opened in  public at said time and place  on said day  for the  purchase of  the following  bonds of  the County of  Wake, North  Carolina dated  March 1,  1997,  and maturing (subject  to  the  right of  prior  redemption)  in annual installments on March 1 as follows:</p>
<p>   Year   Amount  Year   Amount   Year   Amount</p>
<p>   1998  $5,000,000     2004	$5,000,000  2009 $5,000,000</p>
<p>   1999   5,000,000	2005     5,000,000   2010 5,000,000</p>
<p>   2000   5,000,000	2006     5,000,000   2011 5,000,000</p>
<p>   2001   5,000,000	2007     5,000,000   2012 15,000,000</p>
<p>   2002   5,000,000	2008     5,000,000   2013 15,000,000</p>
<p>   2003   5,000,000</p>
<p>all as described in the detailed Notice of Sale.</p>
<p>The bonds  will  be  general  obligations  of the  County, secured by  a  pledge of  its  full faith  and  credit.  The approving opinions of  Hunton &amp;  Williams and  Bode, Call  &amp;  Stroupe,  L.L.P.  of  Raleigh,   North  Carolina,  will   be</p>
<p>furnished to the  successful bidder  at the  expense of  the County.</p>
<p>Copies of the  Official Statement  and the Notice  of Sale and Bid Form relating to the bonds may be obtained from  the Local Government  Commission  (919-733-3064).  The  sale  is subject to  standard  North  Carolina  conditions  of  sale, including a  required  deposit,  all  as  described  in  the detailed Notice of Sale. Each bid must be submitted on a bid form contained in the Notice of Sale and Bid Form. The bonds will be  delivered  on  or about  March  11,  1997,  against payment therefor in Federal Reserve Funds at The  Depository Trust Company.</p>
<p>			Local Government Commission</p>
<p>			  Raleigh, North Carolina</p>
<p>			     By Robert M. High</p>
<p>			Secretary of the Commission</p>
<p>			  (From The Bond Buyer)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
