<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="376679" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Albright presses funds for Africa force.</title>
<headline>Albright presses funds for Africa force.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Secretary of State Madeleine Albright on Wednesday urged Congress to approve funds for a new African Crisis Response Force, $70 million for NATO's Partnership for Peace programme and $535 million to &quot;cement&quot; reforms in the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Her appearance before a key House of Representatives Appropriations subcommittee was part of a campaign to win a nearly 7 percent increase in foreign affairs spending in 1998 to $19.5 billion.</p>
<p>The Clinton administration launched last year a campaign to create an all-African force that could respond to crises on the continent. Then-Secretary of State Warren Christopher heard mixed reactions when he discussed it with regional leaders on a trip to sub-Saharan Africa in October.</p>
<p>But although the administration initially wanted to launch the new force by April, not much has been heard about it until Albright raised it on Wednesday in her testimony.</p>
<p>&quot;We are placing a priority on our efforts to increase the peacekeeping capacities of African nations through an African Crisis Response Force,&quot; Albright said.</p>
<p>Her written testimony said the administration was seeking $90 million for a voluntary peacekeeping account that would include unspecified &quot;modest support to projects such as the ACRF that strengthen states' ability to deter or respond to conflicts in their own backyards.&quot;</p>
<p>She gave no further details but Christopher's plan was to create a 10,000-member force that would be sent to countries where civil war, insurrection or campaigns of genocide threatened mass civilian casualties.</p>
<p>The United Nations was to control and order peacekeeping missions in which the crisis force would take part.</p>
<p>The administration is also seeking $70 million in military assistance for countries that are members of NATO's Partnership for Peace programme under which former communist states cooperate with the alliance on European security.</p>
<p>This is up $10 million from 1997 and will help some partnership members prepare for full membership in NATO, a decision the alliance plans to make at a summit in July. Poland, the Czech Republic and Hungary are the top contenders.</p>
<p>The new Partnership for Freedom programme, costing $535 million out of a total $900 million sought for former Soviet republics, would help Russia and other newly independent states promote business, trade, investment and activities that strengthen democracy and the rule of law.</p>
<p>&quot;This reflects an evolution in our approach to the region. For years, we have been providing technical advice on how to achieve political and economic reform. Our focus will now be on cementing the irreversible nature of those reforms,&quot; Albright said.</p>
<p>Representative Sonny Callahan of Alabama, the subcommittee's Republican chairman, said winning the overall foreign affairs spending increase sought by the administration would be difficult because of pressures to cut the budget. But other members, like Republican Representative John Porter of Illinois, said the proposed rise was much needed and they would support it.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
