<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="376650" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Feb 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Feb 13.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following stories were reported in Thursday's electronic version of The Wall Street Journal:</p>
<p>* The Dow industrials surged 103.52 points to a record 6,961.63, with a resurgance in technology stocks leading the way and pushing the Nasdaq up 27.45 to 1,358.96. The dollar continued to rise.</p>
<p>* American General is expected to announce a pact to pay up to $1.8 billion for USLife, plus the assumption of $600 million in debt.</p>
<p>* Pilots of AMR's American Airlines rejected a new contract proposal that raised the company's pay offer by one percentage point but cut stock options.</p>
<p>* ITT Corp rebuffed Hilton Hotels' hostile $6.5 billion bid and said it would sell its non-core assets. The company also filed a suit saying Hilton misused confidential information and failed to reveal all facts to shareholders.</p>
<p>* AT&amp;T is offering an unadvertised special that would give customers an unlimited dime-a-minute long-distance rate.</p>
<p>* Investors put about $24 billion of new money into stock mutual funds in January, almost double December's inflow.</p>
<p>* Japan's trade surplus is likely to rise this year because of the weak yen.</p>
<p>* B.A.T Industries has indicated it might consider an industrywide pact to end U.S. tobacco litigation under certain conditions.</p>
<p>* Prescription drug prices rose 4.1 percent last year, above the 3.2 percent overall consumer inflation rate.</p>
<p>* A racial discrimination suit against S C Johnson &amp; Son could make employers reconsider using worker teams without supervisors.</p>
<p>* Former U.S. Labor Secretery Lynn Martin made a number of recommendations for improving the workplace of Mitsubishi's U.S. auto plant, which was the subject of a federal sexual harassment suit.</p>
<p>* Bell Atlantic said one of its executives will take over the daily operations of the new company to be created after the merger with NYNEX.</p>
<p>* TWA named acting chief executive Gerald Gittner chairman and chief executive.</p>
<p>* With American Airlines pilots threatening to strike Saturday, the risks for investors in parent AMR Corp could hardly be more stark. While a quick settlement would boost the stock, a long walkout could trigger a steady fall. -- Heard on the Street.</p>
<p>* The jury is still out on whether inflation-indexed bonds will prove to be a home run with investors - or just a solid base hit. -- Credit Markets.</p>
<p>--New York newsdesk 212-859-1610.))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
