<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="376632" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S jobless claims point to labor market tightness.</title>
<headline>U.S jobless claims point to labor market tightness.</headline>
<byline>Jeff Coelho</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A sharp drop in initial claims for state unemployment insurance undershot expectations of Wall Street economists, pointing to further evidence of labor market tightness, experts said.</p>
<p>Claims for the week ended February 8 fell to 309,000 from a revised 324,000 the prior week, the lowest since July 27. Economists in a Reuters poll had forecast 339,000 new claims.</p>
<p>&quot;The only way you can read it is we have a very strong labor market,&quot; said Astrid Adolfson, first vice president and an economist at consulting firm MCM MoneWatch Inc.  </p>
<p>This week's reading might still be distorted by weather effects since the numbers are reaching such low levels, Adolfson said. &quot;Even if you assume 15,000 to 20,000 incorrect seasonals, you would still have a very strong labor market.&quot;</p>
<p>Claims have been volatile over the past few weeks, as they normally are in January, said Donald Maude, chief U.S. economist at Scotia Capital Markets Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;But we've had two consecutive weeks of 325,000 or below,&quot; Maude said, adding that it &quot;probably bodes for pretty decent February non-farm payrolls.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Labor Department said the four-week moving average for initial claims slipped to 327,750 from a revised 330,750.</p>
<p>&quot;The four-week average has come down and is continuing to come down,&quot; said Marilyn Schaja, money market economist at Donaldson Lufkin &amp; Jenrette Securities Corp.</p>
<p>Looking forward, however, Schaja projected jobless claims would eventually drift upward because of an eventual slowdown in the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the expectation of a slowdown in economic activity, it should weaken the labor market,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the 0830 EST/1330 GMT report on retail sales and the upcoming Treasury auction later in the day may have muted the government bond market's reaction to jobless claims.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm encouraged that the bond market is stable, we haven't lost any ground since retail sales were released ... and don't forget you've got an auction today,&quot; said Hugh Johnson, chief investment officer at First Albany Corp.</p>
<p>By 0945 EST/1445 GMT, the 30-year U.S. Treasury bond rose 5/32 to 97-16/32 bid, to yield 6.69 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm a little more moved by the claims number (than retail sales), which are coming down,&quot; Johnson said.</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1562 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
