<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="376719" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: DASA keen to develop new Airbus models.</title>
<headline>DASA keen to develop new Airbus models.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Busvine</byline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Daimler-Benz Aerospace AG (DASA) said on Thursday it was keen to press ahead with developing two new, larger models of the Airbus passenger jet and bring in new partners for the projects.</p>
<p>Chief executive Manfred Bischoff said the four-country European Airbus consortium should should continue work on the super-large A3XX model in addition to the twin A340-500 and A340-600 versions -- even if costs proved prohibitive.</p>
<p>&quot;Developments will not and cannot take place at the same time due to technical and financial questions,&quot; Bischoff told DASA's annual news conference. &quot;But we will do all possible to realise both.&quot;</p>
<p>Airbus links DASA -- a Daimler-Benz AG unit -- with British Aerospace, France's Aerospatiale and CASA of Spain.</p>
<p>Bischoff said the recent decision by newly merged U.S. rival Boeing -McDonnell Douglas to drop plans for a stretch version of the 747 Jumbo did not necessarily mean there was no market for the A3XX.</p>
<p>The only way for airlines operating out of crowded airports -- like British Airways or Singapore Airlines -- to boost passenger capacity would be to fly larger jets, he added.</p>
<p>The A3XX, which would have twin decks and carry over 550 passengers, would cost an estimated $10 billion to develop, DASA executives said. Airbus has said it would cost $8 billion.</p>
<p>Italy's Alenia has said it would take a 10 percent stake in the A3XX project, and Sweden's Saab has also expressed a strong interest. Bischoff said Airbus was also seeking other partners.</p>
<p>DASA executives said that a decision to make the A3XX would need to be taken by 1999, with the first flight planned in 2003.</p>
<p>Bischoff also said the development of the 375-seat A340-600 and the long-range A340-500 -- capable of flying non-stop from the U.S. to Hong Kong -- would boost Airbus's competitive position in the larger capacity market against Boeing.</p>
<p>&quot;We want and will improve our competitiveness against our main competition,&quot; he said. Airbus said on Tuesday that the new A340 models could fly by 2001.</p>
<p>But, Bischoff warned, with massive concentration going on in the U.S. aircraft industry and Washington pursuing a supportive industrial policy, Europe would not be able to develop the new aircraft without state aid.</p>
<p>He also said that political leaders in Europe would need to help Airbus realise its goal, agreed in January, of restructuring into a single operating company by 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;Airbus will not become a united European company if the politicians do not want it,&quot; Bischoff said.</p>
<p>--Bonn newsroom +49 228 26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
