<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="376814" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Rights group rejects Burmese government criticism.</title>
<headline>Rights group rejects Burmese government criticism.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The London-based human rights group Amnesty International on Thursday dismissed Burmese criticism of its latest report on the country and reiterated a call for Asian nations to isolate Rangoon.</p>
<p>&quot;The Burmese government's strong reaction to our report shows just how sensitive the authorities are to criticism of their human rights record,&quot; the group said in a statement from its European Union office in Brussels.</p>
<p>&quot;This shows the importance of the members of ASEAN (Association of Southeast Asian Nations) and other governments continuing to put pressure on the Burmese authorities.&quot;</p>
<p>Rangoon on Wednesday dismissed an Amnesty report on human rights in Burma as &quot;ridiculous&quot;, accusing the group of being a propaganda machine for anti-government organisations.</p>
<p>In its report, Amnesty said political repression and human rights violations in Burma last year reached their highest levels since the violent state suppression of a popular uprising in 1988.</p>
<p>The group said more than 2,000 people were arrested in 1996 simply for calling for human rights reforms and that opposition party members were attacked by organised mobs.</p>
<p>Amnesty has been lobbying hard to get a meeting of the European Union and ASEAN currently being held in Singapore to come out with a strong statement on Burma, but the issue has split Asian and European nations.</p>
<p>Burma is likely soon to be made a member of ASEAN -- possibly before the end of this year -- despite EU leaders warning that this could &quot;complicate&quot; relations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
