<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37692" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Axa buys Generali's 11 percent stake.</title>
<headline>Axa buys Generali's 11 percent stake.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS</dateline>
<text>
<p>Insurer Axa said Friday it bought Italian insurer Generali's 11 percent stake in the French company for 5.9 billion francs ($1.16 billion), bringing down the curtain on their co-operation efforts.</p>
<p>Generali, Italy's largest insurer, sold its Axa stake as it no longer saw it as a strategic holding and Axa exercised its preemptive right to buy the stock, the two companies said.</p>
<p>Generali had long been unhappy over its Axa stake, last year threatening to sell if it did not become a more active partner.</p>
<p>In February, Axa announced a restructuring under which Generali transformed its indirect holding in Axa into a direct holding, making it more liquid. In March, the two signed a shareholder cooperation pact to run unto the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;It's true we didn't expect them to sell so quickly,&quot; an Axa official said.</p>
<p>The two groups had intended to cooperate internationally with Generali expressing keen interest in developing mutual ventures in Asia where Axa has built a strong foothold.</p>
<p>But these never materialised. &quot;There were no opportunities,&quot; said an Axa spokeswoman. Generali said it had nothing to add to the companies' joint statement.</p>
<p>Axa said the purchase eliminated the risk of big amounts of its stock coming onto the market and weighing on the price.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
