<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37696" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: FOCUS-Generali makes last-minute Creditanstalt bid.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Generali makes last-minute Creditanstalt bid.</headline>
<byline>Knut Engelmann</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austro-Italian insurer EA-Generali said on Friday it would together with its partners make a fresh offer for privatisation candidate Creditanstalt hours before a government deadline was to expire.</p>
<p>It said it would update a proposal orginally made last October, when the group offered to pay nine billion schillings for about two-thirds of the government's 70 percent voting stake in Creditanstalt and sell the remaining shares in a secondary offering.</p>
<p>The eleventh-hour bid came shortly after savings bank Die Erste  said it had left the consortium, which also includes Germany's Commerzbank and Banca Commerciale Italiana, as frantic negotiations in the group failed to help bridge a growing rift between the partners.</p>
<p>The consortium members have been at loggerheads over a proposal by Die Erste to form a holding with Creditanstalt which it would control even though it is barely a third of the size of Austria's second-biggest commercial bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The consortium regrets that Die Erste did not see itself able at this point in time to be part of the updated offer,&quot; EA-Generali said in a statement.</p>
<p>The insurer, majority-owned by Italy's Assicurazioni Generali SpA, said it would submit its bid to investment house JP Morgan, the Austrian government's adviser in the privatisation process.</p>
<p>Details of the offer were not made available.</p>
<p>Die Erste issued a tightly-worded statement confirming it had left the consortium, but made scant attempts to hide its disappointment with its erstwhile partners.</p>
<p>&quot;Die Erste regrets that no agreement could be found after all. It was surprising that the other partners in the consortium have ended the negotiations even though substantial progress had been made,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The Austrian government had given the group, so far the only known bidder for the flagship bank, until midnight Friday to come up with a final and binding offer.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Viktor Klima threatened to reopen the six-year long privatisation saga on Monday and invite new offers from potential bidders if the consortium failed to come up with a last-minute bid.</p>
<p>Klima has been pressing for a speedy conclusion to what has become Austria's longest-running privatisation, eager for as much as 18 billion schillings in potential revenue to help plug his ballooning budget deficit.</p>
<p>A host of international bidders, among them Germany's Allianz and CS Holding of Switzerland, has over the past years lost interest in Creditanstalt, put off by what they felt was a bias against foreigners in Austria.</p>
<p>Creditanstalt, founded in 1863 by the Rothschild family and one-time banker to the Austro-Hungarian empire, has in recent years become one of the most successful players on the emerging markets of central and eastern Europe.</p>
<p>Before suspension, Creditanstalt's ordinary shares were down eight schillings at 661 on the Vienna bourse, while its preference shares were down 6.10 schillings at 477.90.</p>
<p>The preferred shares have fallen by as much as 23 percent over the past six months and are now hovering near their year-low of 470.30 schillings, hit at the end of August.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
