<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="376929" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Feb 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Feb 13.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company.</p>
<p>DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>SCOTAM DEMANDS BIDDER SECRECY</p>
<p>Scottish Amicable is to prevent potential bidders that sign confidentiality agreements, in order to gain access to the life assurance company's financial information, from making a hostile bid. The agreement prevents bidders from publicly disclosing any details of their offers. This also means they must accept that ScotAm's decision is final. The agreement prevents bidders from disseminating any financial information relating to ScotAm.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>SIEBE SNAPS UP STRUGGLING WHESSOE WITH AGREED 46 MILLION STG</p>
<p>The controls and electronic power supplies group, Siebe, has bought the specialist instrumentation maker, Whessoe, which slashed its dividend in December after a profits setback, for 46 million stg. A spokesman for Siebe said Whessoe would be integrated into its one billion stg control systems division and Whessoe's range will take the company into new areas, complementing Triconex, the safety shutdown systems company it acquired two years ago.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>POLYGRAM FORTUNES SLUMP AFTER TAKING EYES OFF STARS</p>
<p>Film and music giant, PolyGram, which is owned 75 per cent by Philips, has admitted that it had not produced the big hits required to offset difficult trading conditions. President Alain Levy said that in retrospect the company had not spent enough time with some of its stars to ensure their albums were really &quot;up to scratch&quot;. However, he was more upbeat about sales growth in the music industry for 1997.</p>
<p>THE TIMES</p>
<p>_________</p>
<p>BRITISH GAS JOB CUTS OUT OF CONTROL</p>
<p>British Gas claims that job losses at the company have run out of control and revealed that by the end of this month it will have cut 35,000 jobs since 1993. This is 10,000 over an original target from four years ago and is 5,000 more than a revised plan outlined 18 months ago. Chairman Richard Giordano detailed the losses at a meeting designed to approve the demerger of British Gas into two companies, Centrica, the gas supply business, and BG, the TransCo and international activities business.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>FINANCIAL SERVICES IN STORE AT TESCO</p>
<p>Tesco is set to launch an instore service to provide both a credit card and a range of financial services, including mortgages, in a joint venture with the Royal Bank of Scotland. Customers will be able to obtain online insurance and other financial products at special outlets in selected stores at the same time as they shop. The Royal Bank's Direct Line insurance subsidy is at the heart of the scheme.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>MILLENNIUM EXHIBITION JOB FOR MUIRHEAD</p>
<p>One of the founders of advertising company M&amp;C Saatchi, Bill Muirhead, has been brought in to help the Millennium Exhibition at Greenwich as director of communications. He will go on secondment from M&amp;C, but will be paid by a new company being set up to run the exhibition, Millennium Central. The role has been created by chief executive of British Airways, Bob Ayling, who is also chairman of Millennium Central.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>____________</p>
<p>LABOUR PROMISES &quot;THRIFT FOR ALL'</p>
<p>The Labour Party's Treasury spokesman, Mike O'Brian, has said the party will implement a &quot;thrift for all' policy that will roll back the financial industry's retreat from poorer areas. He said the party would be asking big investment houses to help its drive to take savings products back into the inner-cities and poor housing estates. He claimed that Labour is to undertake a year-long consultation with the industry regarding greater access to financial products for women, ethnic minorities and members of low-income groups.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>UNEMPLOYMENT FIGURES PLUNGE TO SIX-YEAR LOW</p>
<p>Figures from the Office for National Statistics show that the number of people out of work and claiming benefit has fallen to a six-year low of 1,815,000. The Labour Party have accused ministers of fiddling the figures to make the economy appear more stable in the run-up to the forthcoming General Election. The Conservative Party claim the drop is due to Britain's flexible labour market, adding that Labour's support for the Social Chapter and the minimum wage would add 1,500,000 to the unemployment count.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>GULF CANADA TIGHTENS GRIP ON 495 MILLION STG CLYDE TAKEOVER FIGHT</p>
<p>The oil and gas explore, Clyde Petroleum, looks likely to be taken over by Gulf Canada, which has put in a bid for 495 million stg, after it emerged that fund manager PDFM, the group's second biggest shareholder, sold its 14.7 per cent stake in the group to Gulf. Analysts in the City claim that Clyde's only hope for survival depends on it persuading all of its other big shareholders, including Capital Group and Norwich Union, to support it.</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>_______________</p>
<p>BANK TELLS CLARKE TO ACT NOW</p>
<p>Official figures reveal another big fall in the number of people claiming unemployment benefit and a faster pace of average earnings growth, leading the Bank of England to issue another warning that interest rates should rise. This comes just hours after Chancellor Kenneth Clarke insisted no increase in rates was necessary. The Bank has revised down its short-term inflation forecast because of the strong pound, but revised up the outlook two years ahead. It puts the target measure at three per cent and rising in 1998.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>WATER COMPANIES FACE SWINGEING PRICE CUTS</p>
<p>Water regulator, Ian Byatt, has unveiled proposals, as part of a new price-cap regime from the year 2000, for a big one-off cut in bills for the privatised water companies, a move which has already take effect in the electricity and gas industries. The plans will also pile further pressure on water shareholders by pledging that bills will not increase in real terms in the years that follow the initial price reduction. Byatt said that the next set of price controls would have to make up for efficiency gains made by companies in the current price regime.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>BA CLAIMS TIE-UP WILL BENEFIT RIVALS BY 613 MILLION STG</p>
<p>Chief executive of British Airways, Bob Ayling, has defended the group's planned alliance with American Airlines. He claims that rival carriers would see benefits in revenue growth worth 613 million stg. He claims if the partners had to give up some of their runway slots, under proposals from the Office of Fair Trading, services between Heathrow and the USA would grow by a fifth. The OFT says that the tie up may not be referred to the Monopolies and Mergers Commission if the partners had to divest 168 slots.</p>
<p>--BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
