<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="376935" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Living thermometer turns blue with the heat.</title>
<headline>Living thermometer turns blue with the heat.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Scientists have discovered a living thermometer in the Arizona desert in the form of a lizard which changes colour as the temperature rises and falls, the New Scientist magazine reported.</p>
<p>The male striped tree lizard (Urosaurus ornatus) paradoxically turns bright blue in the heat, but is green when it is cold.</p>
<p>The lizard was already known to change colour, but it took scientists from Hood College, Maryland to realise that its hue changes were linked to temperature.</p>
<p>They found that at a comparatively cool 28 degrees Celsius (82F) the lizard was a dull green, but as the heat increased it turned turquoise at first and was cobalt blue by the time the thermometer hit 36 degrees Celsius (96F).</p>
<p>Randall Morrison from Hood College believes the lizard develops its garish blue to attract mates and ward off rivals, while its green incarnation helps to disguise it from predators when it is cold and sluggish.</p>
<p>&quot;When it's cool, these animals can barely move at all and the green patches help them remain inconspicuous,&quot; said Morrison.</p>
<p>In the heat of the day &quot;the lizards are displaying like crazy, but because it's hot they can run away fast if danger threatens,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
