<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="377047" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: CBA steps up Asian expansion.</title>
<headline>CBA steps up Asian expansion.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Commonwealth Bank of Australia (CBA) managing director David Murray said on Thursday the bank had decided to expand its Asian activities and would seek out new joint ventures in Indo-China, Vietnam and India.  </p>
<p>&quot;We've already expanded our presence in Asia and we're about to start our joint venture bank in Indonesia, but I think there's more up there for us to do and we've decided to seek out some fresh opportunities,&quot; Murray told reporters after addressing a Securities Institute function.</p>
<p>&quot;Our focus has been Indonesia, China, Vietnam and India because they are countries whose financial systems are still evolving because the Australian system, which is one we know very well, is quite mature,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking in each of those countries for joint venture opportunities.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;The other area which we would like to focus on is development of more skilled work such as structured finance and investment banking opportunities,&quot; Murray added.</p>
<p>Murray said such an expansion would not need a great amount of capital.</p>
<p>&quot;The only way that we would need a lot more capital would be if we looked at acquisition, which has not to date been on our agenda,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier Murray said the CBA was also looking to expand and diversify in New Zealand, where it currently has only the ASB Bank.  </p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
