<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="377185" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: First Holdings unit says in $669 mln loan.</title>
<headline>First Holdings unit says in $669 mln loan.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>First Gas Power Corp, a unit of First Gas Holdings Corp, said on Thursday it has appointed ABN-Amro Bank, Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi and Westdeutsche Landesbank as lead arrangers for a $669 million loan.</p>
<p>First Gas Holdings is a joint venture of First Philippine Holdings and British Gas.</p>
<p>First Gas in a statement said it will require $669 million to finance in part its 1,000-megawatt power plant in Batangas, south of Manila.  </p>
<p>Peter Garrucho, First Gas Holdings president, said in the statement that financial closing of the loan is expected by the second quarter of this year.</p>
<p>The power project will cost a total of $880 million of which $669 million will be financed through loans and the rest from equity.</p>
<p>Garrucho said PCI Capital Corp will arrange for working capital loans from local banks. Commonwealth Development Corp and Kreditanstalt fuer Wiederaufbau (KfW) will also provide financing for the project.</p>
<p>The company will also source loans from export credit agencies which include the U.S. Export-Import Bank, the Malaysia Eximbank and the Malaysia Export Credit Insurance.</p>
<p>First Gas Holdings treasurer Federico Lopez added in the same statement that about 20 European, American and Japanese banks submitted bids for the financing.</p>
<p>The power plant which will run on condensate fuel is expected to be completed by 1999.</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom 63 2 8418939 fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
