<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="377138" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korean won ends lower despite BOK intervention.</title>
<headline>S.Korean won ends lower despite BOK intervention.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The won closed lower against the U.S. dollar despite a series of interventions by the central bank on Thursday, dealers said.</p>
<p>The won closed value-tomorrow trading at 874.40 after opening at 870.00. It hit a low of 874.90.</p>
<p>The Bank of Korea (BOK) offered to sell $20 million each at 887.00 in three-month and 899.00 in six-month forward trading in the early morning session. This failed to boost the won.</p>
<p>Just before the lunch break, the BOK sold dollars in value-spot trading after the won fell to an 84-month low of 875.30.  </p>
<p>A BOK official said the central bank would neither confirm nor deny its interventions in the market.</p>
<p>South Korea's won/dollar trading is divided into value-spot and value-tomorrow based on the method of cash settlement. In value-tomorrow, cash settlements are made the day after the transaction and after two business days in value-spot. The value-tomorrow rate is regarded as the representative rate.</p>
<p>Without signs of improvement in the won's demand and supply, the local unit will continue to fall in line with the dollar's strength on world markets, dealers said. Friday's mid-rate is expected to be pegged at 874.00 against Thursday's 868.70.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
