<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="377113" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: PRESS DIGEST - Chinese newspapers - Feb 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Chinese newspapers - Feb 13.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Chinese political and business stories in leading newspapers, prepared by Reuters in Beijing. Reuters has not checked the stories and does not guarantee their accuracy. Telephone: (8610) 6532-1921. Fax: (8610) 6532-4978.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PEOPLE'S DAILY</p>
<p>- With reform of the grain circulation system, state-run grain enterprises in Shanghai, and Shandong and Hunan provinces have increased profits</p>
<p>- Front-pate commentary calls on state-run grain enterprises to eliminate losses and increase profits.</p>
<p>- State Statistical Bureau report shows 40 percent of production capacity in 28 sectors lies idle</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>XINHUA DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>- Shanghai industrial sector showed improved efficiency last year and turned out more high-quality products.</p>
<p>- Commentary praises Fu Wei, a deceased regimental commander who dedicated his life to national defence.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>FINANCIAL NEWS</p>
<p>- Minister of Internal Trade Chen Bangzhu urges large stores to boost management and halt falling profits</p>
<p>- State Development Bank recalls total of 31.524 billion yuan in loan interest in 1996</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ECONOMIC DAILY</p>
<p>- Editorial says planned cut in bank reserve requirements will not lead to loosening of monetary policy</p>
<p>- China makes provincial governments responsible for supplying rice and rice flour to the army</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA DAILY</p>
<p>- All central government administrative departments must hire all low-ranking civil servants based on open examinations and merit appraisals starting this year.</p>
<p>- The state will draft several national regulations this year to standardise management of floating population and improve reproductive services for women.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
