<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="377441" id="root" date="1997-02-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Giscard d'Estaing urges Spain, Italy be in Euro.</title>
<headline>Giscard d'Estaing urges Spain, Italy be in Euro.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former French president Valery Giscard d'Estaing says it might be possible for European leaders to grant &quot;conditional acceptance&quot; to Italy and Spain so they can be in the first wave of countries in Europe's single currency in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;It is highly important that Italy and Spain be members of the first wave of countries launching the euro,&quot; the International Herald Tribune newspaper on Thursday quoted him as saying, &quot;because their participation will give a truly European flavour.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If we are just restricted to those countries centred around the Rhine, it will simply look like an enlargement of the deutschemark zone and not a genuinely European endeavour.&quot;</p>
<p>He said &quot;naturally Italy and Spain can only be admitted if they meet the criteria contained in the Maastricht treaty.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said European leaders who will meet in early 1998 could agree on a &quot;solution&quot; to pave the way for these countries to join the first wave.</p>
<p>That solution could involve agreeing to a plan for Italy and Spain to join the single currency launch even if they fail to meet the 1997 target, but as soon as they meet the criteria, whether that is in January 1999 or a few months later.</p>
<p>Last year, Giscard d'Estaing stirred controversy when he called for a &quot;lower level&quot; for the franc. The newspaper quoted him as saying he notified President Jacques Chirac before he made his call last November for the franc to depreciate against the dollar to boost France's sluggish economy.</p>
<p>The newspaper said he told it that at a time of high joblessness and fiscal austerity there was a lack of political leadership in the European Union &quot;with the notable exception of Helmut Kohl.&quot;</p>
<p>Giscard d'Estaing called for a &quot;more active monetary policy&quot; in France that was not afraid to cut short-term interest rates to German levels to help spur growth.</p>
<p>Giscard d'Estaing stressed the Maastricht treaty was clear in saying countries must meet deficit and other criteria before January 1999. But he said &quot;it was only for practical purposes that we have to decide in the spring of 1998 on who joins and that it is in order to create a European central bank.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The difficulty will be those countries that in 1997 will not meet the criteria but that obviously will meet them by January 1999. The trend will have to be very clear, and the numbers solid, but at that point we may have a solution.&quot; He urged talks among government chiefs in the spring of 1998 &quot;about the trend and then a decision in principle could be made.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It could be a conditional acceptance,&quot; he said, &quot;with the implementation delayed until they meet the criteria and that could be January 1999 or a few months later.&quot;</p>
<p>Giscard d'Estaing added he believed there was insufficient political leadership in western Europe at present, apart from Kohl &quot;who has a definitive vision of the future of Europe.</p>
<p>Today's European political leaders, he said, &quot;are addressing the problems as they come.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;They are all embattled,&quot; he said, &quot;and the public perceives this.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
