<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="377610" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: GM Canada plants vulnerable to axle strike.</title>
<headline>GM Canada plants vulnerable to axle strike.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Motors Corp's Canadian unit said on Friday that two of its plants could be affected by a possible strike at American Axle and Manufacturing Inc in the United States.</p>
<p>GM Canada spokesman Greg Gibson said American Axle was the main supplier of axles to GM Canada's truck plant in Oshawa, Ontario and its sports car plant in Ste. Therese, Quebec.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not going to speculate on that at this point in time because we're hopeful that there won't be a disruption, but they do supply to both our Ste. Therese plant and to our truck plant in Oshawa,&quot; said Gibson.</p>
<p>He said GM would need to take stock of its inventory if a strike stopped production at American Axle's five plants in Detroit; Three Rivers, Michigan and Buffalo, New York. The UAW has set a strike deadline of 2359 EST on Friday.</p>
<p>Gibson would not specify how long it would take for a strike at American Axle to interrupt production in Oshawa or Ste. Therese, but said GM managers were keeping a close eye on the proceedings.</p>
<p>&quot;Our policy is that we don't get out and project how long we're good for,&quot; Gibson said. &quot;What we'll do is we'll keep monitoring the situation and if we are we will announce that.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if GM Canada felt obliged by its labor contract to review its relationship with American Axle and Manufacturing Inc because of the supplier's labor relations, Gibson said he was unsure of GM Canada's responsibilities.</p>
<p>&quot;I think I'd have to go back and look at what the wording actually says on that.&quot;</p>
<p>A new labor relations clause in the labor agreement that GM Canada signed with the Canadian Auto Workers (CAW) union last autumn gave the union the right to call for a review of GM Canada's relationship with its suppliers if the CAW objected to the supplier's labor practices.</p>
<p>A furor arose in the U.S. auto industry this month after Ford Motor Co switched seat suppliers to honor similar obligations to which it agreed in its labor contract with the United Auto Workers union in the United States.</p>
<p>Ford resumed assembly of Expedition sport utility vehicles after shifting rear seat production to Lear Corp. from a strikebound Johnson Controls Inc plant.</p>
<p>((Paul Casciato, Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100 or email: paul.casciato@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
