<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="377766" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIA BEEFS UP CONTROL AGAINST FUEL SMUGGLING.</title>
<headline>BULGARIA BEEFS UP CONTROL AGAINST FUEL SMUGGLING.</headline>
<byline>Liliana Semerdjieva</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria, heavily hit by fuel shortages, beefs up border control from Friday to prevent speculative exports of fuel, said interim prime minister.</p>
<p>&quot;From today we ban any fuel exports and if necessary we will have troops on borders but we must stop speculations with fuel,&quot; Stefan Sofianski told reporters on Friday.</p>
<p>The ban of fuel exports does not affect the contracted volumes by the country's biggest oil refinery Neftohim, Sofianski said.</p>
<p>Local media say cars and motorists smuggle cans full of petrol or diesel to neighbouring Yugoslavia and Macedonia, where prices are higher while fuel shortages threaten to paralyse Bulgaria due to a lack of cash for crude supplies.</p>
<p>Most petrol stations in the country are closed due to a lack of fuel and municipalities are distributing petrol and diesel for ambulances, bread and food trucks, police, the army and other social activities, officials said.</p>
<p>Bus transport in towns has been strongly reduced causing problems for production, transport ministry officials said.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's new interim cabinet on Thursday sacked the board of directors of Neftohim. Within two weeks the new board is due to prepare a stabilisation programme for the refinery.</p>
<p>Neftohim, which supplies almost the whole domestic market, has debts worth millions of dollars due to low domestic prices and suppliers refuse to deliver crude to a bankrupt refinery.</p>
<p>Sofianski, who visited Neftohim, located in the Black Sea port of Bourgas, late on Thursday, said the interim government would seek financial stabilisation of the plant.</p>
<p>Neftohim, which needs huge investments for modernisation, is pending partial privatisation, Sofianski said. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>&quot;A drastic hike of fuel prices is urgent and the interim cabinet will discuss it on Monday,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Neftohim officials say regular government revisions of fuel prices have not kept up with a recent drastic fall of the lev against the dollar. A litre of gasoline now costs 10 cents, as the price has been based on a rate of 660 levs per dollar.</p>
<p>The Bulgarian lev traded 3,020-3,050 per dollar on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will take steps by Sunday for opening new credit lines for Neftohim and for rescheduling the plant's debts to the banks,&quot; Sofianski said.</p>
<p>Earlier this week Neftohim agreed a 50-million credit with France's Paribas Bank branch in Geneva after Russia's state-owned Rosneft oil company guaranteed half of the credit line. Rosneft holds a 50-pecent stake in a joint venture with Neftohim.</p>
<p>The refinery is distributing limited volumes of 680 tonnes of petrol and 680 tonnes of diesel per day. It has been refining 8,500 tonnes of crude per day since Tuesday, while its daily capacity is 25,000.</p>
<p>A 66,300-tonne tanker from Russia's Rosbulneft arrived on Wednesday at the Bourgas port under its February contract for crude deliveries to Neftohim.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
