<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="377733" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: RUGBY UNION-DEPLETED FRENCH WARY OF 'DANGEROUS' WALES.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-DEPLETED FRENCH WARY OF 'DANGEROUS' WALES.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Vignal</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>France are confident they can shrug off the massive disruption to their Five Nations preparations and prolong Wales's dismal record at Parc des Princes when the two countries meet on Saturday.</p>
<p>Despite losing five key players through injury and a sixth through suspension since his side's convincing 32-15 over Ireland in Dublin on January 18, French team boss Jean-Claude Skrela remains in upbeat mood.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the circumstances, we've put together the best possible team and it has been a pleasure to watch the players train,&quot; he said. &quot;They want to win badly, you can see that.&quot;</p>
<p>Emile Ntamack, Thomas Castaignede, Alain Penaud, Fabien Galthie and Philippe Benetton have all withdrawn with various injuries in the build-up to the game, with prop Franck Tournaire already banned for violent conduct in the Irish clash, but flanker and captain Abdel Benazzi remains unconcerned, at least in public.</p>
<p>&quot;All those injuries have brought us even more closely together,&quot; he said at France's training camp in a forest outside Paris. &quot;The guys will give their all, there's no doubt.&quot;</p>
<p>Unlike some of their Five Nations rivals, France are lucky to have impresive strength in depth, with the likes of winger Laurent Leflamand, scrum-half Philippe Carbonneau and flanker Richard Castel eager to prove they are more than mere substitutes.</p>
<p>&quot;They are talented players and it's up to them now to show us that we were right to pick them,&quot; Skrela said.</p>
<p>Powerful centre Richard Dourthe, who missed the match at Lansdowne Road through injury and whose goalkicking duel with Neil Jenkins could be a key area, said he feared the Welsh more than the English.</p>
<p>&quot;Wales are a fine combination of power and talent,&quot; he said. &quot;I watched England against Scotland and I wasn't at all impressed. I think Wales are more dangerous than England this year.&quot;</p>
<p>Skrela is also wary of looking too far ahead, particularly to his side's visit to Twickenham on March 1 which will make or break France's grand slam ambitions.</p>
<p>&quot;One match at a time, please,&quot; said Skrela. &quot; If you start calculating, you can't beat a team like Wales.</p>
<p>&quot;We must not drop as many balls as we did in Dublin and we must also show more initiative in running the ball.</p>
<p>&quot;Against Ireland, the Welsh used the wrong tactics. But they are an exciting team with strong forwards and gifted backs, a bit like us actually. It should be a great match to watch.&quot;</p>
<p>Wales have not won in Paris since 1975, but scored three tries against their opponents in a 40-33 friendly defeat in Cardiff in September and believe they can score the sort of upset which contributes so much to the magic of the Five Nations.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we've got a great chance,&quot; said lock Gareth Llewellyn. &quot;Several of their key players are injured and it doesn't matter how good a side you are, that is bound to have an effect.&quot;</p>
<p>Even so, eleven of the Welsh side have never played at the Parc before, and British Lions manager Fran Cotton will be in Paris to study how many should be earmarked for the similarly tough mission to South Africa later this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
