<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="37772" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France under fire over summer time.</title>
<headline>France under fire over summer time.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>France came under fire from European neighbours on Friday for its decision to stop changing the clocks twice a year between winter and summer time.</p>
<p>Citing public opposition to the disruptive time changes, Prime Minister Alain Juppe said in a letter on Wednesday he had decided France would keep the same time all year and asked a member of parliament to recommend how to implement the decision and to put the French position to European Union partners.</p>
<p>EU diplomats said the announcement had come as a complete surprise. There was no prior consultation and it was unclear how the French move would work.</p>
<p>&quot;Are people going to reset their watches when they cross the border with Belgium or Germany half of the year? Think of the disruption to business,&quot; one European envoy said.</p>
<p>In Britain, which is one hour adrift from continental Europe and only recently agreed to switch from summer to winter time on the same day as its EU partners, the Times newspaper thundered that &quot;French ministers meddle with the clocks at their peril&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;To outsiders, it might seem a little perverse for France to be opting out of single European time when its government is doggedly insistent that it will be at the rendezvous for the single European currency,&quot; the paper said.</p>
<p>Germany's mass circulation Bild Zeitung called in an editorial for summer time to be retained, saying it gave Germans longer light evenings on their balconies or gardens.</p>
<p>France originally introduced summer time in 1976 as an energy-saving measure during the oil crisis. But it no longer faces an energy shortage, drawing most of its electricity from nuclear power, and economists say the twice-annual time change costs more than it saves. Farmers have long opposed it.</p>
<p>Juppe's office said the prime minister's office had simply decided to reopen the debate and asked deputy Francois-Michel Gonnot to report within six months on the pros and cons. An official said there would be plenty of time to consult France's EU partners before a final decision was taken.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
