<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="377738" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FORECAST - RAND SEEN BUOYING TRENCOR H1 SHR.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - RAND SEEN BUOYING TRENCOR H1 SHR.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Transport and container firm Trencor Ltd was expected to report a healthy rise in earnings for the six months to December 31, but a continued surge in the rand could cut into second half profits, analysts said Friday.</p>
<p>Analysts polled by Reuters forecast earnings rising to between 51.9 and 72 cents, with consensus at 60.3 compared with 51.9 at the halfway stage in 1995 -- a rise of over 16 percent.</p>
<p>Trencor is due to report results on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Analysts said the 29 percent depreciation of the rand against the dollar last year could put a sparkle in Trencor's earnings since about 80 percent of profits came from its container unit Textainer which earns mainly foreign currency.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Trencor) are a company which is positively favoured by the weakness in the rand,&quot; said an analyst who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>However, other analysts were less upbeat predicting a flat performance. </p>
<p>Profits in the second half to end June 1997 were seen curbed if the rand, which has recovered almost six percent since the beginning of the year, continued its rally.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook for the future is good but at the moment with the rand continuing to strengthen things could be tough for their second half,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>The half year dividend was forecast at between 12 and 14 cents a share, compared with 12 at the last interim.  </p>
<p>-- Ellis Mnyandu, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
