<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="377819" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE white sugar firms but trade thin after expiry.</title>
<headline>LIFFE white sugar firms but trade thin after expiry.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nearby white sugar futures pushed higher in light volume as commission houses bought the May contract, now spot position after the recent March expiry, to keep pace with a strong New York market.</p>
<p>Commission house activity was reported on both the May/August spread and on May outright, offset by some light trade selling.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a bit of activity in the May -- but overall it's quiet after the expiry and it's holding up,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Traders said activity was light as few players wanted to take up new positions directly after the March expiry with New York closed on Monday for President's Day.</p>
<p>At 1720 GMT May was up $3.10 at an intraday high of $304.50 and August up $2.80 at $304.40. Volume amounted to 590 lots, nearly all of which was in the spot month.</p>
<p>A total 423 lots of white sugar, equivalent to 21,150 tonnes, was delivered against the March contract, with E D &amp; F Man buying everything from commission houses Prudential Bache and Refco.</p>
<p>The ports specified were Rostock, Eemshaven and Immingham.</p>
<p>In other news, the Indian government authorised the export of 250,000 tonnes of sugar in 1996/97, with 20,000 tonnes to be exported by the ISGIEC to the EU and US under an existing preferential arrangement.</p>
<p>Cuba has produced its first one million tonnes of sugar in the current 1996/97 harvest, in which the island is hoping to improve on the 4.45 million tonnes it produced last season, a state newspaper said on Friday.</p>
<p>The official newspaper Granma said the first one million tonnes, reached on February 10, was produced with less sugar cane than last year, which indicated some improvement in efficiency at the island's sugar mills.</p>
<p>Paris trading followed a similar pattern to London with just 433 lots on the board. May was up $2.80 at $304.00 and August up $1.80 at $303.50.</p>
<p>-- Jeremy Smith, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8064</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
