<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="378099" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia govt acts on Moscow oil firm creation.</title>
<headline>Russia govt acts on Moscow oil firm creation.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Russian government has carried out President Boris Yeltsin's decree of January 22 to create a new oil company called the Central Fuel Company, Interfax news agency said on Friday.</p>
<p>Interfax said that a government decree dated February 10 had ordered the State Property Committee to transfer to the Moscow city government 38 percent stakes in oil products trader Mosnefteprodukt and in the Moscow Oil Refinery.</p>
<p>The original decree freed Mosnefteprodukt and the Moscow Oil Refinery from inclusion on a government list of strategically significant firms whose state stakes cannot be sold near-term.</p>
<p>The new company would work to ensure supplies to the capital and to surrounding regions, the presidential press service said in January.</p>
<p>Interfax said the new company would rely heavily on oil producing companies, because it has no production capacity of its own.</p>
<p>The Moscow city government was therefore considering options for attracting vertically-integrated oil firms into working in the new holding company, Interfax said.</p>
<p>So far only LUKoil  LKOH.RTS  0#LKOH.RUO, Russia's biggest oil company by output, has officially shown interest in working with the Central Fuel Company.</p>
<p>LUKoil President Vagit Alekperov said in January that his company wanted an active role in the new firm, but added that LUKoil was not looking to take full control of it.</p>
<p>LUKoil owns more than 20 percent of voting shares in Mosnefteprodukt, a distributor of petroleum products.</p>
<p>The Moscow Oil Refinery is managed by Rosneft, the state oil company which is being privatised.</p>
<p>--Moscow Newsroom +095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
