<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="378113" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish Plock refinery raises petrol, diesel 5-8 pc.</title>
<headline>Polish Plock refinery raises petrol, diesel 5-8 pc.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's Plock refinery on Friday raised the prices of its petrol and diesel by five to eight percent at its filling stations and by 5.8 to 11.3 percent wholesale, the refinery said in a statement.</p>
<p>The rise follows the finance ministry's Thursday decision to free all fuel prices and remove administrative limits on distributors' margins.</p>
<p>Plock, Poland's largest refinery, said wholesale prices of the leaded 94 octane and 98 octane petrol would rise 5.8 and 6.3 percent respectively to 1,553 and 1,662 zlotys per tonne while the price of unleaded 95 octane petrol would rise seven percent to 1,485 zlotys.</p>
<p>It said wholesale diesel prices would rise by 10 percent and 11.3 percent to 1,181 zlotys and 1,201 zlotys per tonne respectively for the EDP type and EDZ type respectively.</p>
<p>For retail the size of the rises is smaller at five and six percent for the 94 and 98 octane leaded petrol, which now cost 1.59 and 1.71 zlotys per litre respectively and six percent for the 95 octane unleaded, now at 1.55 zlotys.</p>
<p>It raised EDZ diesel by eight percent to 1.41 zlotys per litre.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
