<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="378151" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenian PM to present cabinet on Monday - sources.</title>
<headline>Slovenian PM to present cabinet on Monday - sources.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenia's prime minister-designate Janez Drnovsek is expected to present a new cabinet on Monday, the last day available, after his first cabinet failed to win parliamentary approval , sources close to Drnovsek said on Friday.</p>
<p>Drnovsek of the centre-left Liberal Democrats, failed eight days ago to win parliamentary support for his first cabinet, formed in January after an inconclusive November 10 general election.</p>
<p>Throughout the week, Drnovsek, who has been prime minister since April 1992, has held talks with all parliamentary parties, but has not yet managed to win over any of the rightist groups that comprise the so-called &quot;Spring&quot; alliance.</p>
<p>The rightist alliance holds 44 out of 90 seats.</p>
<p>The alliance, composed of the conservative People's Party, the centre-right Social Democrats and the Christian Democrats last week managed to persuade parliament to reject Drnovsek's leftist cabinet.</p>
<p>Parliament refused the cabinet by an evenly split result of 45 votes against 45, thus forcing Drnovsek to present a new cabinet in 10 days.</p>
<p>If the parliament fails to confirm at least two thirds of the second line-up, President Milan Kucan will have to nominate a new prime minister.</p>
<p>Analysts said on Friday Drnovsek's chances of forming a coalition with the People's Party were increasing.</p>
<p>&quot;According to recent statements of the People's Party, the party is considering entering a coalition. If that does not happen, Drnovsek will have to try to gain a slim majority for a line-up that will be similar to the last one,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to try to find a solution to form a government that would solve current matters at least until (possible) early elections,&quot; Marjan Podobnik, head of the People's Party, told Radio Slovenia earlier.</p>
<p>The People's Party is the second largest in parliament with 19 seats, trailing the Liberal Democrats who have 25 seats.</p>
<p>The new government would be the third after Slovenia's independence from the former Yugoslavia in 1991.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
