<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="378199" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru hammers out details for rebel hostage talks.</title>
<headline>Peru hammers out details for rebel hostage talks.</headline>
<byline>Saul Hudson</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Peruvian government and mediators hammered out details on Friday for talks with Marxist rebels aimed at freeing 72 hostages held at the Japanese ambassador's home for nearly two months.</p>
<p>Peru's negotiator, Domingo Palermo, coordinated plans for a second round of face-to-face talks with the peace commission overseeing the dialogue. He said on Thursday he hoped to meet by Saturday afternoon with the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement's (MRTA) No. 2 leader, Rolly Rojas.</p>
<p>After weeks of deadlock, this week's resumption of talks in a safe house across the street from the ambassador's residence was a breakthrough in attempts to end a hostage crisis that began on Dec. 17 when the MRTA stormed a cocktail party.</p>
<p>But with the rebels refusing to give up their demand for the release of over 400 jailed comrades, and the government flatly rejecting that, a peaceful end was not expected soon.</p>
<p>The all-male, mainly middle-aged hostages have already spent Christmas and New Year in the compound and on Friday had to pass Valentine's Day away from their loved ones.</p>
<p>A few miles from the siege in the &quot;Park of Love&quot; on the Pacific coast, 72 couples were married at a mass wedding to show solidarity with the 72 captives.</p>
<p>&quot;We are here to tell them (hostages) they are not alone,&quot; said Mayor Oscar Barron at the end of the ceremony held beneath a huge statue of two lovers embracing, called &quot;The Kiss.&quot;</p>
<p>Wives and girlfriends also sent chocolates in to the captives as a gift to mark the special day.</p>
<p>Some hostages, however, probably did not indulge in the chocolate as they have taken to dieting and jogging to lose weight, according to a doctor and former captive who now treats the capitives.</p>
<p>&quot;Although some of them go jogging on the second floor, because of the lack of physical exercise some have put on weight and have decided to go on a diet,&quot; said Dr. Miguel Sanchez, who was among the first batches of hostages to be released. &quot;Some of them have lost 13 to 18 pounds (six to eight kg).&quot;</p>
<p>A heart specialist, Sanchez told Peruvian television that on his latest visit on Thursday he found the hostages calm and in generally good health.</p>
<p>Meanwhile the Vatican's representative on the peace commission, Bishop Juan Luis Cipriani, was believed to be arranging the agenda for the talks. The Red Cross and Canadian government are also mediating in the 59-day crisis and Tokyo has a talks' observer.</p>
<p>&quot;It is now a question of him meeting with the guarantors to prepare for the conversations. They are channelling information from the MRTA,&quot; a government source close to the negotiations said.</p>
<p>The first formal meeting on Tuesday between Palermo and Rojas produced a pledge for further talks but little more apparent progress in the aim for a peaceful solution.</p>
<p>Speaking publicly about Tuesday's meeting for the first time late on Thursday, Palermo described it as &quot;absolutely normal&quot; and &quot;quite positive.&quot; He added, &quot;we are going to continue our work, and then we hope to have results,&quot; but also warned &quot;we are very worried&quot; about the situation in general.</p>
<p>The MRTA freed most of their 500-plus captives in the first weeks of the siege but have held on to those they consider the most useful bargaining chips to win freedom for their jailed comrades.</p>
<p>The remaining hostages include President Alberto Fujimori's brother, two government ministers, top security and judicial officials, the ambassadors of Japan and Bolivia and about two dozen Japanese businessmen and diplomats.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
