<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="378212" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuela businesses question social security plan.</title>
<headline>Venezuela businesses question social security plan.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Proposed changes in Venezuela's social security system got a lukewarm reception from business leaders on Friday when union leaders formally presented their reform plans to the tripartite commission.</p>
<p>The commission gathers private sector leaders, union and government officials in an attempt to break a long-standing impasse over social security reform -- seen as a prerequisite for a long awaited restructuring of the 1.2 million strong Venezuelan public sector.  </p>
<p>&quot;There are some matters in their proposal that worry us,&quot; leading business chamber Fedecamaras president Jorge Serrano told reporters.</p>
<p>Under current rules, fired workers are paid twice their monthly salary for each year worked while retiring workers are paid once. Government and private sector leaders say such a scheme prevents increases in worker salaries. Take home pay is boosted instead, when needed, with monthly bonds.</p>
<p>Under changes proposed by Venezuela's largest union, the Confederation of Venezuelan Workers (CTV), workers would be paid severance payments according to a sliding scale.</p>
<p>Workers on salaries less than 53,000 bolivars a month would receive three months salary for each year worked, while those with salaries over 500,000 bolivars would receive one month's pay.</p>
<p>CTV president Federico Ramirez Leon said the scale favored those who are paid less &quot;which are most is this country&quot;.</p>
<p>But Serrano said he favored moving towards a new system of social security payments rather than a tinkering of the current method.</p>
<p>((-- Oscar Galvis, Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
