<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="378273" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: INTERVIEW-Dissident fosters split in Mexican labor.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Dissident fosters split in Mexican labor.</headline>
<byline>Veronica Galan</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shaken by growing dissent within its ranks, Mexico's official labor movement faces its biggest challenge in decades as more than two dozen unions consider defecting from the pro-government Labor Congress (CT).</p>
<p>A dissident faction of the monolithic CT will decide whether to form a separate labor confederation at a meeting recently scheduled for July 31.  </p>
<p>&quot;Each union must bring its proposals on whether or not we establish this new organization,&quot; said Francisco Hernandez Juarez, head of the influential Telephone Workers' Union.</p>
<p>Hernandez, who is spearheading the drive to push Mexican labor in a fresh direction, made his remarks in an interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>Some 25 unions will meet to vote on whether to split from the CT, launching a direct challenge to Fidel Velazquez, the nonagenarian union leader who has kept Mexican labor firmly in the camp of the ruling Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI) since 1928.  </p>
<p>Real wages in Mexico have fallen sharply during the past two decades as the country weathered a series of economic crises, but labor unrest has been virtually non-existent.</p>
<p>&quot;Unionism is supposed to be accommodating enough to represent all workers and defend their interests despite their political color,&quot; Hernandez said.</p>
<p>The CT &quot;has shown clearly that it is incapable of defending the Mexican worker,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Forum so far has no defined political stripe.  </p>
<p>The CT embraces more than 40 unions, including the huge Confederation of Mexican Labor, led by Velazquez. It represents about five million workers, or about half of those claimed by the CT.</p>
<p>The dissident unions, known as collectively as the Forum, include the Telephone Workers' Union, the Electricity Workers' Union, the Automotive Industry Union and the Social Security (IMSS) Union. Together they claim to represent three million workers, though the CT says their ranks are closer to a half million.  </p>
<p>Hernandez said his telephone union was committed to leaving the CT and hoped to be joined by others.</p>
<p>&quot;We know we want to leave, but we don't want to do it alone. If just the telephone workers were independent, it would open us up to all sorts of aggression,&quot; Hernandez said.</p>
<p>Signs of trouble in the official labor movement surfaced last year, when a handful of unions belonging to the CT marched in the May Day parade despite an official ban, imposed out of concern over potential unrest.</p>
<p>When the peso crashed more than two years ago, inflation again skyrocketed and real wages fell sharply. This year, economists forecast little change in real wages.</p>
<p>Velazquez has lashed out at Hernandez for threatening to drive a wedge in the CT's ranks. Hernandez said the 96-year-old Velazquez was striking out because he did not believe the 25 unions would agree on a congress to discuss a split with the CT.</p>
<p>Velazquez recently said workers would be allowed to march in this year's May Day parade. Hernandez said that move was designed to convince workers their situation was improving ahead of key mid-term elections in early July.</p>
<p>((-- Mexico City newsroom, +525 728-9500))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
