<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="378307" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Alarcon says Ecuador was on point of collapse.</title>
<headline>Alarcon says Ecuador was on point of collapse.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ecuador's newly appointed President Fabian Alarcon told a Mexican television programme on Thursday that Ecuador had been on the point of collapse before former president Abdala Bucaram was dismissed by Congress.</p>
<p>In an interview with the news programme 24 Horas, Alarcon said that his new government was preparing a series of constitutional reforms and would tackle the country's large budget shortfall.</p>
<p>Alarcon was sworn in on Tuesday following a period of political turmoil after Bucaram was dismissed by Congress on the grounds of &quot;mental incompetence.&quot; That followed widespread popular protests against austerity measures.</p>
<p>&quot;Our political circumstances were extremely difficult. The country was on the point of collapse in every respect,&quot; Alarcon told the news programme.</p>
<p>Alarcon will act as president until August 1998.</p>
<p>During that time he said the government's primary aims will be to stabilise the economy, reform the political system and restore Ecuador's international credibility.</p>
<p>&quot;In the next few days we will announce a large-scale reactivation of the economy of Ecuador that will firstly allow us to correct the budget deficit, which is about five percent (of GDP), to fight inflation, unemployment, high interest rates and to reactivate the nation's productive capabilities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bucaram's unpopular austerity measures, which included steep hikes in the cost of public services, have been suspended and his plan to tie the sucre currency to the dollar was scrapped.</p>
<p>Alarcon also said his government will bring in constitutional amendments.</p>
<p>&quot;We are preparing a series of constitutional reforms,&quot; he told the news programme. One of those will aim to clarify who should replace a president who is permanently removed from office, he said.</p>
<p>At one point during the crisis, there were three people claiming the right to be president.</p>
<p>When asked if Bucaram might returned as president, Alarcon answered, &quot;There is no way.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The only president that there is in Ecudaor is called Fabian Alarcon, supported by the legislature, by the courts, by the armed forces ...,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
