<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="378319" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Ecuador's Bucaram begins tour to get presidency back.</title>
<headline>Ecuador's Bucaram begins tour to get presidency back.</headline>
<byline>Daniel Helft</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ecuador's ousted former president Abdala Bucaram arrived in Argentina on Thursday and vowed to regain his country's presidency.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that I will be holding the presidency once again this month or next month,&quot; Bucaram told reporters at a news conference at his Buenos Aires hotel after lunch with Argentine President Carlos Menem.</p>
<p>&quot;But you have to give me time. I'm not Superman and I can't just get things from one day to the next,&quot; he said. &quot;I'm working on it.&quot;</p>
<p>Flanked by his son and his former Housing Minister Victor Sicouret, Bucaram declared he would tour Latin America and lobby the Organisation of American States.</p>
<p>Bucaram also said he intended to visit Colombian President Ernesto Samper, Peru's President Alberto Fujimori and Brazil's President Fernando Henrique Cardoso to seek support.</p>
<p>He said that at lunch, Menem had promised to &quot;make the voice of protest heard&quot; over his plight.</p>
<p>Bucaram said that Menem told him he feared that recent events in Ecuador would serve as &quot;a Pandora's Box&quot; threatening the democratic stability of other Latin American countries.</p>
<p>Bucaram was dismissed as president last week by Congress on grounds of &quot;mental incompetency&quot; after a storm of protest over tough austerity measures. His opponents were also irritated by his eccentric style.</p>
<p>Bucaram blasted former Congress speaker Fabian Alarcon, who took over as president on Tuesday. &quot;He is a traitor who betrayed the government and is playing at a coup d'etat.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that Ecuador's rich and powerful financial interests had pushed for his ousting.</p>
<p>Bucaram said that despite the lunch with Menem, his visit to Argentina was personal and he had not been invited by the government. He was scheduled to stay until Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
