<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="378318" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine ruling affirms telecom rates - agency.</title>
<headline>Argentine ruling affirms telecom rates - agency.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-02-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Argentine federal judge on Thursday ordered the government not to alter telecommunications rates it approved in late January, the private DyN news agency reported.</p>
<p>The government's Communications Secretariat said the ruling by Judge Ricardo Bustos made certain the tariffs would take effect, according to DyN</p>
<p>The judge's ruling &quot;ends the state of uncertainty about the tariff question,&quot; the secretariat said in a statement, according to DyN.  </p>
<p>It was not immediately possible to contact the secretariat or the judge's office.</p>
<p>The ruling came after another judge earlier Thursday suspended the increases in local telephone rates included in the new rate structure after a court action presented by a consumer group.</p>
<p>The decisions on Thursday were the latest in a series of court rulings on the tariff changes, which have become a legal football since authorized by decree in late January.  </p>
<p>A federal judge last week suspended the new tariff structure pending a ruling brought by the nation's Ombudsman on a court case to have the changes reversed. But the tariffs came back into force Wednesday after the government presented an appeal.</p>
<p>The changes increased the cost of local calls and telephone rentals but slashed the rates for national and international long-distance calls.</p>
<p>Telefonica de Argentina and Telecom Argentina had waged a long lobbying campaign for the tariff changes, which they said would make charges fairer for provincial businesses.</p>
<p>The companies also hoped it would make them more competitive when the Argentine phone market is thrown open to all competition, probably in the year 2000.</p>
<p>Consumer groups and opposition parties fought hard against the charges and argued in public hearings ending in December 1996 that private users' telephone bills would rise and the phone companies pocket the difference.</p>
<p>The companies argued the new charges would not increase their profits. Telefonica is controlled by Telefonica de Espana, and Telecom by France Telecom.</p>
<p>((--Jason Webb, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0655))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
