<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="378796" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Travelers fret as American nears strike.</title>
<headline>Travelers fret as American nears strike.</headline>
<byline>Kieran Murray</byline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tens of thousands of air travelers braced for traffic chaos as pilots prepared to shut down American Airlines on Friday, with the potential of causing huge economic losses across the United States.</p>
<p>With a strike deadline set for midnight EST Friday (0500 GMT on Saturday), big U.S. airports were jammed as passengers scrambled to rearrange their plans and get on a flight while the airline was still running.</p>
<p>Others started out on long U.S. Presidents Day weekend vacations worried they would be left stranded.</p>
<p>&quot;If this thing blows, I could be in deep trouble,&quot; said Dan Cummins, a 27-year-old salesman who flew to visit his girlfriend in Chicago for a Valentine's Day celebration but said he expected serious problems in getting a return flight to Dallas on Sunday. &quot;My boss is going to be mad as hell if I don't get back on time.&quot;</p>
<p>American's management and pilots' union leaders met for a fifth straight day of negotiations in Washington on Friday in a last-ditch effort to cut a new four-year labour contract.</p>
<p>The leading federal mediator said some progress had been made but there were &quot;major points that have to be resolved between now and midnight.&quot; Pilots' leaders said they were determined to strike if no deal was reached by midnight, although talks could continue even with the airline shut down.</p>
<p>American is the second largest U.S. airline, accounting for 20 percent of domestic flights and carrying about 200,000 passengers on 2,200 daily flights.</p>
<p>It has already cancelled almost all of its international flights scheduled for Friday because it does not want any planes stranded abroad in the event of a strike. A handful of domestic flights were also cut.</p>
<p>Travel agents said any strike would batter the tourist industry in the Caribbean, which is in its peak winter holiday season, and could cause havoc at American's home base of Dallas-Fort Worth as well as airports in Chicago, Miami, New York, Los Angeles and San Juan, Puerto Rico.</p>
<p>Caribbean tour operators and hotels planned extraordinary measures to ensure that vacationers kept coming, and that those already there could get home.</p>
<p>The Doubletree Sapphire Beach Resort on St. Thomas said it has lined up several boats to transport guests to Puerto Rico, where they would stand a better chance of making an airline connection home. &quot;I figure I could have up to 300 guests that I have to figure a way to get off-island,&quot; general manager Mark Kaiser said.</p>
<p>A pilots' strike would cost American's parent company AMR Corp. upwards of $30 million per day and federal government officials said it could cost the U.S. economy between $100 million and $200 million per day.</p>
<p>Most of AMR's 90,000 employees will be placed on unpaid emergency leave as soon as a strike kicks in and tens of thousands more workers would be laid off by tourism firms and businesses which supply the giant airline.</p>
<p>American has said it will try to rebook all stranded passengers on other airlines, but there are few guarantees on the routes where American has a strong share of the market.</p>
<p>&quot;They have told me they'll get us back, but we have nothing in writing,&quot; passenger Phillip McCrory said as he and his wife Debbie waited to leave Dallas for their 25th wedding anniversary vacation to Honolulu on Friday.</p>
<p>McCrory said his loyalty to the airline would be strained if they are unable to return home on time. &quot;Going on strike is one thing but if they leave people stranded, they will lose face and people are going to look at other airlines.&quot;</p>
<p>American Airlines executives, senators and business leaders from around the country have urged President Bill Clinton to step in and push the two sides into binding arbitration, but pilots' union leaders say they do not want Clinton involved and White House officials refused on Friday to discuss any possible intervention.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
