<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="378864" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: FOCUS-Trade partners press US to back telecom pact.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Trade partners press US to back telecom pact.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Major trading powers piled pressure on the United States on Friday to agree to what they said was a potentially powerful pact to open up the booming telecommunications industry to worldwide competition.</p>
<p>But U.S. officials close to the World Trade Organisation (WTO) talks in Geneva declined all comment on prospects for an accord by the Saturday deadline, indicating that a decision was in the works and could be announced later in Washington.</p>
<p>&quot;What is on the table amounts to a massive liberalisation of the world telecommunication market that it would be crazy not to grab with both hands,&quot; European Union Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;I see no conceivable justification on the basis of what is on the table for failing to clinch the deal,&quot; he declared.</p>
<p>A senior negotiator from Canada, which has been strongly targetted by the U.S. for offering to allow only 46.7 per cent foreign ownership of domestic telecoms companies, said he could not believe the United States would walk away now.</p>
<p>Such action, he said, would ignore &quot;economic and commercial good sense&quot;, adding: &quot;I think that at the end of the day, rationality will prevail and we will all sign.&quot;</p>
<p>The long-negotiated pact is billed by WTO analysts as holding the prospect of bringing telephone charges for ordinary users and business tumbling around the globe and boosting markets for new telecoms equipment and services.</p>
<p>In a report issued on Friday, the International Telecommunications Union (ITU) predicted global revenues for the industry would jump from $800 billion last year to $1.2 trillion at the turn of the century -- if the deal goes through.</p>
<p>But the United States is vital for a meaningful pact since it is the world's largest single telecoms market, accounting for just under one third of the annual total.</p>
<p>Last April, Washington sunk an earlier bid to get a pact when it walked away just before a previous deadline saying offers from other countries, primarily emerging economies, were not good enough.</p>
<p>U.S. officials say that to ensure strong public and Congressional backing for a deal at home, it has to be clearly &quot;equitable&quot; with wide enough openings from other countries to match their own offer.</p>
<p>Throughout this week, these officials have insisted that improvements in openings currently on the table were needed to finalise a pact. The United States package proposes a full opening of its domestic market to all comers.</p>
<p>Britain, sometimes more attuned to U.S. thinking on economic matters than to that of its EU partners, on Friday joined the chorus of appeals to Washington to line up behind the deal -- which would link a total of 61 countries.</p>
<p>&quot;I would certainly urge the Americans to live up to their rhetoric....and sign up to an accord,&quot; Minister for Science and Technology Ian Taylor told another Geneva news conference as the word from Washington was anxiously awaited.</p>
<p>Japanese officials have also said the market opening offers now on the table, which include many from small and major emerging economies who did not join the last round of talks, made a good deal and should be sealed in a pact.</p>
<p>The EU's Brittan had an hour-long meeting with WTO Director-General Renato Ruggiero who has called on all countries in the talks to make their best efforts for a pact, saying failure could undermine the two-year-old body's authority.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
