<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="378955" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German government agrees on tax talks with opposition.</title>
<headline>German government agrees on tax talks with opposition.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl will meet Oskar Lafontaine, head of the opposition Social Democrats (SPD), on February 24 to try and break a deadlock over sweeping government tax reforms, officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>Chancellery Minister Friedrich Bohl said after a meeting of Kohl's three-party coalition that the Chancellor had called Lafontaine and arranged the meeting to try and win SPD backing for government tax cuts.</p>
<p>The news raised hopes the two sides can reach a tax deal without a drawn-out parliamentary battle, creating conditions to boost investment and fight unemployment which has spiralled to the highest since the 1930s Great Depression.</p>
<p>But the meeting may also put renewed strain on worn ties between Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU), the Christian Social Union (CSU) and junior partners Free Democrats (FDP). The FDP has advocated radical tax cuts to help business and investment.</p>
<p>Guido Westerwelle, FDP general secretary, shrugged off any suggestion the larger alliance of CDU/CSU could work out a deal with the SPD at the expense of his party's liberal position.</p>
<p>&quot;One should never go into negotiations and rule certain things out ahead of time,&quot; he told ZDF television.</p>
<p>&quot;But we as the FDP have a clear idea of how we will go into these talks, and that means seeking cuts across the whole range of tax rates and above all simplifying the tax system.&quot;</p>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel's tax plan, agreed by the three coalition parties, proposes net tax cuts of 30 billion marks. It would cut the entry rate of income tax to 15 percent and the top rate to 39 percent from 1999. Some corporate taxes would be cut in 1998.</p>
<p>The cuts would be partly offset by scrapping tax write offs, raising in indirect taxes like value-added tax, and upping taxes on work at night, and on Sundays and holidays.</p>
<p>The SPD has demanded the government bring forward the tax cuts by one year to 1998 and rejected raising VAT. They have also said it would be unfair to cut the top tax rate of 53 percent as a present to the wealthy. But there have been signs this week that the two side were drawing closer.</p>
<p>While accusing the SPD of blocking sorely-needed reforms, Waigel opened the door for a compromise on Wednesday when he suggested the government could bring forward some of its tax plan to 1998 if financing were secured.</p>
<p>SPD leaders, who seized on Waigel's offer, were delighted the talks will go ahead. &quot;We will steer the government onto the right course,&quot; parliamentary leader Rudolf Scharping said.</p>
<p>A leading SPD member also raised hopes of a quick deal when he told the Handelsblatt daily on Friday the SPD might not be dead-set against cutting the top tax rate.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as I am concerned, the top tax rate of 53 percent for non-commercial income is not written in stone,&quot; said Gerhard Schroeder, SPD premier in the state of Lower Saxony.</p>
<p>&quot;I also do not believe that this tax rate is a matter of doctrine for Oskar Lafontaine. If one wants an agreement, and we do, then both sides will have to step back a little from their original positions.&quot;</p>
<p>The SPD also won support from an unusual corner on Friday as it became clear that German industry was not fully satisfied with some of the government's tax proposals.</p>
<p>Dieter Hundt, president of the Federation of German Employers, said plans to raise taxes on overtime and Sunday work &quot;a step in the wrong direction&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;This type of tax, of course, has the negative consequence that labour costs rise through higher social security costs,&quot; Hundt said.</p>
<p>This view seemed to be widespread among German industry, as reflected by a poll of German companies -- including utility Veba AG, chemical giant Bayer AG and electronics group Siemens AG -- published in Handelsblatt on Friday.</p>
<p>While companies saw the income tax reform as a &quot;positive signal&quot;, particularly to attract foreign investment, they took issue with plans to raise taxes on overtime and Sunday work.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
