<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="378930" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: EU grain export commitments near 20 mln tonnes.</title>
<headline>EU grain export commitments near 20 mln tonnes.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union grain export commitments are up 43 percent on an annual basis, official figures showed on Friday.</p>
<p>The EU, which had a record crop above 200 million tonnes last year, earmarked 19.659 million tonnes for export through licences between July 1 and the beginning of this week, up from 13.78 million over the same period one year ago.</p>
<p>This week's grain export decisions issued on Thursday raised the figure to just short of 20 million tonnes, officials said.</p>
<p>Last year's exports were hampered by low stocks and a rare export tax to fight abnormally high domestic prices.  </p>
<p>The figures supplied by member-state officials are for grain and derived products like flour and malt as well as food aid.</p>
<p>For key categories of commercial grain, soft wheat export commitments up to February 11 were 6.95 million tonnes, up 54 percent from the same point last year. Barley grain was up more than threefold at 4.08 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Exports of rye, however, fell to 56 percent of their year-ago level at 699,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>On Thursday the EU awarded exports of 115,500 tonnes of soft wheat, 180,000 tonnes of barley, 5,500 tonnes of durum, 1,000 tonnes of rye and 10,000 tonnes of maize -- bringing the seasonal total to 19.97 million tonnes, plus whatever extra has been exported in the way of secondary products.</p>
<p>Traders believe the EU can export 26 million tonnes of grain and products in the whole crop year that ends on June 30.</p>
<p>The grain trade association Coceral said before Thursday's export announcement this week that it saw scope for another four million tonnes of soft wheat grain exports by June 30.</p>
<p>It did not give an estimate for flour.</p>
<p>--Paris newsroom +331 4221 5146</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
