<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="378924" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Nazi-hunter urges Portugal to speed gold probe.</title>
<headline>Nazi-hunter urges Portugal to speed gold probe.</headline>
<byline>Richard Waddington</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Nazi-hunting Simon Wiesenthal Centre urged Portugal on Friday to speed a probe into the tonnes of gold it received from Nazi Germany during World War Two, warning delay could stir suspicions.</p>
<p>European director Shimon Samuels said after meeting central bank officials in Lisbon that Portugal had still to start serious work on investigating the wartime flow of gold totalling between 44 and 55 tonnes and worth over $500 million at today's prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Portugal cannot afford to be the odd man out. That would just stoke suspicions,&quot; he told Reuters. Other countries, notably Switzerland, were more advanced in seeking to pin down the truth about their relations with Nazi Germany.</p>
<p>Portugal, then under right-wing dictatorship, was neutral during World War Two and as such legally allowed to trade with both sides.</p>
<p>The official line both then and now is that the gold was received in return for exports because Germany had no other way of paying for them. Nevertheless, after years of negotiations, Lisbon agreed in the early 1950s to hand back some four tonnes.</p>
<p>But in the face of a growing international storm over the fate of gold looted by Nazi Germany, both from countries it invaded and individuals, mainly Jews, who died in concentration camps, the Bank of Portugal announced two months ago it was launching an internal probe into its dealings.</p>
<p>It appointed economic historian Joaquim Costa Leite to report on the bank's transactions during the 1939-45 war.</p>
<p>It set no deadline and the investigations must respect Portugal's bank secrecy laws. The government has said that it will take no action until it has seen the findings.</p>
<p>While welcoming the launch of the study, Samuels said he believed that the probe would have gained additional credibility from the inclusion of independent researchers, perhaps from the Wiesenthal Centre or the World Jewish Congress.</p>
<p>&quot;For the reputation of the study, there should be some outside element working with it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Samuels said Portugal, which records show received more gold than any neutral country other than Switzerland, had acted as an important staging post for the shipping of gold to South America, where many leading Nazis fled after 1945.</p>
<p>In just 12 months between 1942 and 1943, around 3.5 tonnes of gold left Portugal for Argentina alone, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The lion's share of gold to Argentina came from the central bank of Portugal. The total amount may not be very dramatic but what is startling is the regularity of the shipments,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Samuels said that he would also like to see the probe widened to include the activities of companies and certain banks -- some still in business -- which could have been used as a channel for money and assets being secreted out of Nazi Germany.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
