<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="379009" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian rupee rallies after dlr demand peters out.</title>
<headline>Indian rupee rallies after dlr demand peters out.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indian rupee rallied to close firmer against the dollar at 35.920/925 on Friday after weakening to an intra-day low of 35.985, dealers said.</p>
<p>Spot dollar opened steady at 35.945/965 on Friday.</p>
<p>The rupee edged up to the 35.94/95 level in early trade on speculative dollar selling by Bombay banks, dealers said.</p>
<p>Late in the morning session, dollar demand from eastern India emerged, pulling down the rupee to 35.97/98 level.</p>
<p>&quot;There were some dollar buyers at 35.9850 today,&quot; said a dealer.</p>
<p>Plentiful dollar selling at this level combined with retreating dollar demand helped push up the rupee to 35.920/925 by the close, firming from 35.94/96 on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) continued to be active in the swap segment, buying spot September dollars and dragging down forward premia, dealers said.</p>
<p>The six month forward dollar premium closed the day at 6.79 percent compared with the previous close of 7.01 percent.</p>
<p>Dealers said the RBI would have bought over $700 million in recent weeks through its purchases in the spot and swap markets.</p>
<p>They said the RBI was shoring up its dollar reserves ahead of Saturday's redemption of India Development Bonds which is expected to result in an outflow of about $1.0 billion.</p>
<p>Many dealers expect spot dollar to stabilise around 35.90 next week. &quot;We could see more depreciation coinciding with the budget (scheduled for the month-end),&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>A dealer at a French bank in Bombay said the rupee was crying out for a sharper correction in the light of dollar's recent gains against leading global currencies.</p>
<p>&quot;Indian exporters have to compete in a sluggish international market at an exchange rate dating back to 1994/95 level,&quot; the bank said in a foreign exchange commentary.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
