<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="379372" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: OPTIONS - BTP players dump vols as futures repelled.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - BTP players dump vols as futures repelled.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>BTP futures' inability to make new medium-term progress on the upside has led many in the options market to dump volatility amid expectations of protracted range-trading, dealers said on Friday.</p>
<p>March options only had six days to go before expiry so many were focusing on June. &quot;The biggest trade is paper selling of the 124.00-134.00 strangle in June,&quot; said a French broker here.</p>
<p>&quot;If you sell a strangle like that you're saying two things --  one that the futures are going to come down to the midpoint and two that the market is not going to move around. The seller thinks the market is going to calm down,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>March BTP futures at 1307 GMT were at 130.71, up 22 basis points from the prior close. Since setting a record high of 132.38 on January 23, BTPs came off a little more than two full points, then recovered, and are now in a short-term downdraft.</p>
<p>The broker said there was some trade in March 129.50 puts, but he added that given the proximity of the expiry such trades were more of a lottery than anything else.</p>
<p>&quot;If you're trading something in March you're no longer trading volatility,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A dealer at an Italian house in Milan said people were selling both puts and calls. &quot;Everybody's selling volatility,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He quoted 10-year volatility was around 7.75 percent, which he said was down about one point from a few days ago.</p>
<p>The French broker said the June 124.00-134.00 strangle went for volatility of 8.77 percent in the puts and 6.69 percent in the calls.</p>
<p>--Adam Cox, International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6784</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
