<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="379384" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Williams' Chubb bid seen as plus, but pricey.</title>
<headline>Williams' Chubb bid seen as plus, but pricey.</headline>
<byline>Jeff Daeschner</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Williams Holdings Plc's lock-up with Chubb Security Plc should make a good fit, but some analysts argued that the British manufacturer may have paid too much for the acquisition.</p>
<p>Conglomerate analysts said Williams' recommended 1.3 billion stg bid, unveiled on Friday, offered a steep premium to Chubb's shareholders, valuing the firm at 450p per share.</p>
<p>&quot;The fit is excellent for Williams, but the issue is the price. People think they overpaid. They should have paid maybe 15-16 times earnings, not 21 times,&quot; said one analyst.  </p>
<p>But other analysts defended the offer price, arguing that the strengthening of Williams' security and fire protection operations would unlock long-term strategic benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the price they had to pay to improve the quality of Williams. They will make it pay, but it will take a little longer than perhaps we would have preferred,&quot; said Geoff Allum, diversified industrials analyst at Henderson Crosthwaite.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be some dilution in the first year, whilst they bring the two companies together but thereafter, then the benefits really begin to come through,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Williams' shares dropped more than 11 percent, falling 38p to 300 by 1305 GMT to rank among the top percentage losers on the London Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Allum attributed some of the fall to possible concerns about the dilutive effect of the deal, which was made up of about 50 percent cash and 50 percent in Williams shares.</p>
<p>&quot;There might be a fair amount of shares sloshing around for a little while until things settle down,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Chubb's shares rose 5.5p to 425.5 in heavy trade.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chubb shareholders have done extremely well,&quot; another analyst said.</p>
<p>The deal, which would combine major brand names in security and fire protection, was widely expected to be cleared by British regulatory authorities.</p>
<p>&quot;There may be one or two little bits Williams have to dispose of, but it won't change the overall tenor of the deal,&quot; Allum said, adding that he doubted a rival bidder would emerge.</p>
<p>&quot;I doubt anyone gets near the synergies that Williams does (from Chubb),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34330">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
