<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="379435" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish Islamists back down on headscarf plan.</title>
<headline>Turkish Islamists back down on headscarf plan.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's ruling Islamists have backed down from a bid to lift a ban on the wearing of Islamic headscarves under pressure from their government allies, the justice minister said in comments published on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Our coalition partner is not ready at the moment for the lifting of the ban on headscarves in public organisations,&quot; the ruling Welfare Party's newspaper Milli Gazete quoted minister Sevket Kazan as saying.</p>
<p>A justice ministry spokesman confirmed that Kazan, a close aide of Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan, made the comments earlier this week.</p>
<p>The abolition of a ban on female civil servants wearing the headscarf was among a series of Islamist proposals by Welfare during the recent Moslem holy month of Ramadan that upset the secularist establishment.</p>
<p>Ministers from the secularist True Path Party (DYP) of Foreign Minister Tansu Ciller publicly opposed the Islamist plans, which included building big mosques in traditionally secularist neighbourhoods and providing for overland pilgrimages to the Moslem holy city of Mecca in Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>But Kazan said both coalition parties had reached agreement on lifting a ban on female university students wearing headscarves.</p>
<p>At the moment, rectors have the power to forbid students from wearing the headscarf but many universities allow it.</p>
<p>Turkey's secular media has also attacked a Welfare move to set up a bodyguard team dressed in militia-style uniforms in the central Turkish province of Kayseri.</p>
<p>Welfare's Kayseri chairman, Serafettin Elmastas, and 39 of his colleagues resigned this week after a court demand they be sacked over the bodyguards, a Welfare official told Reuters on Friday.</p>
<p>The court had ruled that the establishment of the team was against a law on political parties.</p>
<p>Turkey's two main leftist parties have filed censure motions against the government for allegedly threatening Turkey's constititutional secularism. The motions are to be debated on February 25.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
