<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="379679" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Global union group to back striking Swazi workers.</title>
<headline>Global union group to back striking Swazi workers.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU), a global trade union group, said on Friday it would send a high-level delegation to Swaziland to express its support for striking Swazi workers.</p>
<p>The Brussels-based group said the delegation would arrive in Swaziland on Monday &quot;in a show of solidarity with Swazi workers who have been on strike since February 3 to support Swazi trade union demands for democratic reforms and negotiations on economic and social issues&quot;.</p>
<p>A national strike began 10 days ago in the small southern African state, where trade unions seeking democratic change have crippled the country's vital sugar and timber export industries.</p>
<p>Police have fired on strikers, wounding several people, and the government headed by King Mswati III has arrested trade union leaders.</p>
<p>ICFTU said in a statement that the initial two-day strike was turned into an indefinite action after police arrested the four top leaders of the 80,000 strong Swaziland Federation of Trade Unions (SFTU), an ICFTU affiliate.</p>
<p>Police picked up remaining members of SFTU's executive committee for interrogation and beat them up, ICFTU said.</p>
<p>The ICFTU delegation, which will include senior trade union officials from South Africa, Zambia, Zimbabwe, Britain and the United States, will press for the release of the detained SFTU leaders and urge authorities to resume dialogue, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWAZD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100136">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
