<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="379780" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: ESA thinks universe bigger, younger than thought.</title>
<headline>ESA thinks universe bigger, younger than thought.</headline>
<byline>Bernard Edinger</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The yardstick by which generations of astronomers have judged the size of the universe may be wrong, according to European Space Agency scientists</p>
<p>Results from the ESA's Hipparcos satellite indicate the observable universe may be 10 percent larger than previously thought.</p>
<p>And the oldest  stars may be billions of years younger than previous calculations -- which would rescue astronomers from the paradox that some stars seemed older than the estimated age of the Universe.</p>
<p>The conclusions were being presented to a conference in London on Friday.</p>
<p>The revised measuring stick &quot;drastically reduces the age of the oldest stars to about 11 billion years. By a tentative interpretation, the Universe is perhaps 12 billion years old,&quot; the Paris-based agency said.</p>
<p>Some previous estimates had put the age of the oldest stars at 14.6 billion years.</p>
<p>Hipparcos circled the earth from 1989 to 1993, using telescopes and computers to map the positions of stars.</p>
<p>Some of its key observations were of winking stars called Cepheids.</p>
<p>Their brightnesses, which are related to the speeds at which they blink, have been used since 1912 to compare remote stellar distances. But before Hipparcos Earth-based measurements gave only a rough estimate of how far away the closest of them are.</p>
<p>Having concluded that the nearest Cepheids are further than previously thought, and therefore brighter, the ESA astronomers are ready to add 10 percent to the ranges of similar stars that have been measured by comparison.</p>
<p>That would also make the oldest stars in the universe younger than previously thought, and bring their ages within range of the nine to 12 billion years estimated by astronomers using the Hubble Space Telescope, the agency said.</p>
<p>The ESA conclusions were reached by Michael Feast of the University of Cape Town, South Africa, one of the first speakers at Friday's London meeting of the Royal Astronomical Society devoted to Cepheids and the Hipparcos findings.</p>
<p>The space agency described the Hipparcos programme as &quot;the largest computations in the history of astronomy&quot; and said it had increased a hundred-fold the accuracy of star positions.</p>
<p>&quot;Until Hipparcos, the cosmic distance scale rested on well-informed guesses,&quot; said Hipparcos project scientist Michael Perryman.</p>
<p>&quot;The distances we now have, for stars of many kinds, provide for the first time a firm foundation from which to gauge the distances of galaxies. &quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
