<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="379881" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK watchdog halts ads over epileptic seizure risk.</title>
<headline>UK watchdog halts ads over epileptic seizure risk.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Independent Television Commission (ITC) said on Friday it had ordered two separate advertising campaigns to be withdrawn because they failed to meet guidelines designed to reduce the risk of epileptic seizures.</p>
<p>Three ads for Boots Co Plc's No. 7 Cosmetics failed to meet the guidelines related to lowering the risk of epileptic seizures triggered by flickering or intermittent lights and certain types of repetitive visual patterns, the ITC said.</p>
<p>A commercial for a Marmite Cube featuring vertical, black and white lines which formed a psychedelic moving background was also ordered to be withdrawn, as was a second Marmite ad that featured a background of white specks moving on a black background.</p>
<p>The ITC did not uphold complaints from 15 viewers over an ad for a Peugeot 306 car, who objected to the ad as too explicit for early evenng showing, as well as objecting to the use of water pistols in the ad.</p>
<p>The ad featured a couple on their second honeymoon interspersed with shots of their two children staying with their grandparents.</p>
<p>It showed the couple in a hotel bedroom, including having a pillow fight, the woman being squirted by her husband with a water pistol, and in a novelty shop where the woman plays with a mannequin in ladies underwear.</p>
<p>The ITC said all five versions of the ad that were broadcast were excluded from being shown during or around children's programming.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the light-hearted and non-explicit nature of the scenes and since the offence did not seem to be widespread, ... (it) did not consider any further restrictions would be justified,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The ITC upheld complaints against an ad for Texaco Clean System 3 that featured a car as a medical &quot;patient&quot; requiring an &quot;operation&quot; on the motorway.</p>
<p>Although the ad was meant to be lighthearted, the ITC said the advertiser &quot;underestimated the potential of material of this kind to cause gratuitous distress to people recently exposed to life-threatening situations&quot;.</p>
<p>Separately, the ITC said that since its ruling last April that there was no justification for continuing to regard the Church of Scientology as disqualified from television advertising, it has received 56 objections to the decision and 33 letters or phone calls in support.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
