<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="379948" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-OPINION-Jim Middleton's Canberra Close-Up-In the hot seat.</title>
<headline>RTRS-OPINION-Jim Middleton's Canberra Close-Up-In the hot seat.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>the hot seat</p>
<p>By Jim Middleton (ABC TV Political Correspondent)</p>
<p>&quot;The most important thing that any government can do is to build a sense of trust, a sense of integrity, a sense of honesty ...&quot; -- John Howard, Liberal campaign launch February 18, 1996.</p>
<p>Honest John -- it's a reputation John Howard's been trading on for fully two decades. However, events of the last fortnight have started to knock a few chips off the old block.</p>
<p>On which score the decade-long saga of the Old Speaker's Chair -- or Howard's folly, as the opposition is keen to dub it -- is highly instructive as to the distinctions between the prime minister's claims about his behaviour and his subsequent actions.</p>
<p>It also provides telltales as to the tactics Howard is using to try to ride out the cavalcade of unsavoury behaviour on the part of his frontbench.</p>
<p>Back in 1987 when the Labor-dominated parliament rejected moving the old chair up the hill (partly on the grounds of cost) then opposition leader Howard went feral. He cited the desirability of maintaining a link between the Australian parliament and the British House of Commons.</p>
<p>No one, he fulminated, &quot;... should start advancing expense as one of the reasons why you have taken this decision.&quot; In other words, hang the cost.</p>
<p>It was just such an attitude which 10 years later led Prime Minister Howard to revive his old push to get the old chair into the new House -- an exercise which had already been costed at a cool half a million dollars.</p>
<p>Only when it became brutally clear to Liberal strategists that such expense would be the height of self indulgence at a time of renewed budget cuts that Howard was finally persuaded he should retreat.</p>
<p>The prime minister frequently admonishes us to have pride in our history and to respect tradition. Parliamentary history and tradition appear to be another matter, despite what he's said about rebuilding respect for the institution and its inhabitants.</p>
<p>For instance, the prime minister does not appear to take seriously two of the most important parliamentary conventions inherited from the House of Commons -- cabinet responsibility and misleading the parliament.</p>
<p>On Sunday, Howard announced his work-for-the-dole scheme. On Monday, he was asked in parliament how that sat with a pre-election press release from then opposition employment spokesman David Kemp that &quot;claims that the coalition would force Australians to work for the dole are completely false.&quot;</p>
<p>The prime minister's response: &quot;That press release you refer to was not made by me ...&quot; In other words, a member of his shadow cabinet was not speaking for him. Bye bye cabinet responsibility -- one of the central pillars of the Westminster system.</p>
<p>But there's more.</p>
<p>In the same answer, Howard went on to say this: &quot;... during the course of the election campaign I at no stage ruled out introducing a work-for-the-dole scheme.&quot;</p>
<p>How, then, to explain the following statement in the Herald-Sun newspaper just two weeks before the election -- and under his name? &quot;We do not support the introduction of a work-for-the-dole scheme.&quot;</p>
<p>Easy.</p>
<p>He'd never seen it, Mr Howard said. The Liberal campaign had done it without reference to him but in consultation with the relevant shadow minister. And who would that be? Why, none other than David Kemp.</p>
<p>The prime minister now admits coalition policy was &quot;silent&quot; as he put it on work-for-the-dole.</p>
<p>So silent that when asked why such a popular idea hadn't been revealed at the election, there was an awkward pause of fully four seconds before Mr Howard could come up with any words to defend his surreptitiousness.</p>
<p>That's what you get when you come up with &quot;virtual&quot; policy on the spur of the moment designed merely to get you out of a spot on a weekend talk show.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, this is all part of what the prime minister calls his &quot;commonsense&quot; approach to policy designed to appeal directly to the voters (or &quot;the mob&quot; as he called them in parliament yesterday) ignoring the nitpicking of the opposition and the media.</p>
<p>Funny that &quot;commonsense&quot; goes out of the window in the case of Senator Mal Colston and the timely A$75,000 boost to spending on his staff. Just before he voted for the Telstra sell-off, it was.</p>
<p>Mr Howard is adamant that Senate president Margaret Reid backed the application when correspondence with Senator Colston clearly shows she opposed it and was still only lukewarm about the idea when prevailed upon by the prime minister's office.</p>
<p>That's not a &quot;commonsense&quot; approach, at best it's being economical with the truth.</p>
<p>But &quot;commonsense&quot; is the watchword for the prime minister's defence of John Sharp and John Herron -- that it's about air safety, not about ministerial standards.</p>
<p>That may work when you're dealing with your shopworn political opponents, but Saint Gabi Hollows is an altogether more dangerous proposition. The mainstream may not take kindly to an attack on a person the tabloids treat as the name of perfection -- Australia's sweetheart.</p>
<p>Mr Howard may not have the speaker's chair he wants, but he still wants Bob Menzies' desk as a consolation prize.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
