<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="379991" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ Act reviewing support for compulsory super.</title>
<headline>NZ Act reviewing support for compulsory super.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Free market Act New Zealand is reviewing its support for compulsory superannuation to distance itself from the government's stance, Act leader Richard Prebble said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking at superannuation right at the top of our policy reviews. It has been confirmed this week the government will go ahead with a referendum on the subject so I think superannuation will by the end of this year be a major issue,&quot; Prebble said in a telephone interview.  </p>
<p>The centre-right National-New Zealand First coalition government agreed to a referendum on compulsory superannuation following the 1996 election.</p>
<p>&quot;We think (NZ First leader Winston) Peters' proposals are fundamentally flawed and our concern is that the way we package our policy may mean we are caught up in the mess over his.&quot;</p>
<p>New Zealand First campaigned for a compulsory scheme as a means to improve the level of savings, address the lack of domestic investment capital, and as a &quot;sovereignty&quot; issue by improving New Zealanders' ability to own their own assets.  </p>
<p>Act also campaigned for compulsory superannuation, but Prebble told Reuters it was concerned now about being &quot;typecast&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I think his (scheme) is nuts. It will mean the richest man in New Zealand will still have to put aside eight percent of his income for a superannuation proposal when he clearly doesn't need it,&quot; Preeble said.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't like the thought (Peters) will give government guarantees, to direct where the money is going. All those matters are statism, whereas what we had in mind was a proposal to make sure those that can save, but choose not to, don't  </p>
<p>become a burden on the state.</p>
<p>&quot;We are doing another review to see whether, among other things, there is a way of achieving a savings-based superannuation scheme.&quot;</p>
<p>The government is yet to define the exact question to be asked at the referendum, but has said it will treat the result as binding.</p>
<p>Asked if the upshot of the Act review would see a move away from compulsion, Prebble said: &quot;I don't know. We are basically looking at how we package a proposal. Now we are trying to anticipate how the government will put forward the referendum  </p>
<p>... but doing a review of how we want it put.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the party's conference in March would be the time to discuss the matter.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
