<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="380032" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: PRESS DIGEST-Hong Kong Newspaper Headlines-Feb 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-Hong Kong Newspaper Headlines-Feb 14.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Hong Kong press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- MING PAO -- Chief Executive-designate Tung Chee-hwa criticised the leader of the Democratic Party, Martin Lee, accusing him of &quot;bad-mouthing&quot; Hong Kong, which could damage overseas confidence in the territory.</p>
<p>-- In Taiwan, 1,000 lovers would take part in a &quot;kissing competition&quot; to celebrate the Valentine's Day. The award would go to the couple whose kissing was the longest and most impressive.</p>
<p>-- APPLE DAILY -- Democratic Party leader Yeung Sum said Tung's attack on the Party showed that Tung was trying to adopt paternalistic rule and suppress freedom of speech.</p>
<p>-- TA KUNG PAO -- Chief Executive-designate Tung Chee-hwa said he would take steady measures to ensure a peaceful handover.</p>
<p>-- China strongly demanded that the British government solve the issue of the Vietnamese boat people, and criticised the Hong Kong Supreme Court's decision to release 11 Vietnamese boat people in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>-- SOUTH CHINA MORNING POST -- Officials in London said they had made no decisions about the eligibility of Indians and Pakistanis in Hong Kong who wish to gain British citizenship.</p>
<p>-- According to official figures and economists, growth in China's industrial output slowed sharply last month, with many factories shutting down as much as three quarters of their production capacity to reduce inventories.</p>
<p>-- Speculation was growing that limited direct air links would soon be restored between China and Taiwan in the wake of the signing of a shipping accord between the two parties late last month.</p>
<p>-- HONGKONG STANDARD -- The Government was hoping to block a sudden influx of low-skilled British workers before the handover by rushing in new visa conditions by April 1.</p>
<p>-- Leading fund managers yesterday rushed to the defence of the territory's embattled Mandatory Provident Fund amid growing signs the scheme might be shelved.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843-6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
