<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="380390" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: GAN warns on share price, in talks with govt.</title>
<headline>GAN warns on share price, in talks with govt.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>French state-controlled insurer GAN warned investors on Friday that a recent sharp rise in its share price was not justified by the group's basic situation and said that it was in talks with the government on defining solutions to the insurer's financial problems.</p>
<p>It also said in a statement that the first results from an audit into its exposure to bad property risks confirmed that these would have a negative impact on its 1996 accounts.  </p>
<p>&quot;In the belief that the recent development of its share price is not justified by the group's intrinsic data, GAN recalls that when it published its first-half accounts, it announced a decision to commission an audit re-examining its property banking risks,&quot; the insurer's statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was indicated at that time that the audit may have a negative impact on its 1996 accounts and the first available signs confirm this to be the case,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;In this context, GAN has entered discussions with the state in order to define solutions to the financial problems confronting the group,&quot; it concluded.</p>
<p>The government has declined to comment on reports that GAN, a privatisation candidate, may need up to 20 billion francs ($3.5 billion) to prepare it for sell-off. A company source said earlier this month that GAN and the government were discussing an aid package but no decision had been taken.</p>
<p>GAN's shares have meanwhile been rising sharply in Paris on speculation it may be a bid target in the current round of consolidation in the insurance sector. ($ = 5.708 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
