<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="38038" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY precious metals end lower for eighth day.</title>
<headline>NY precious metals end lower for eighth day.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York precious metals futures ended lower Friday for the eighth day in a row, despite the threat of inflation revealed in today's stronger-than-expected U.S. monthly jobs data.</p>
<p>&quot;Precious metals slipped all week ahead of the news, anticipating higher U.S. interest rates, so market may have already discounted the news,&quot; North American Equity Services floor trader John Geraghty said.</p>
<p>COMEX December gold ended down 80 cents at $388.80 an ounce, after seeing a two month low at $388.60 intraday.  </p>
<p>In New York bullion trade, spot gold was quoted $384.85/385.35, from a London afternoon fix Friday at $385.40, compared to a Thursday close in New York at $385.50/386.00.</p>
<p>December silver ended down 3.5 cents at $5.158 an ounce, after seeing a three week intraday low at $5.145.</p>
<p>U.S. Treasury bond yields saw higher levels Friday after U.S. non farm payrolls rose by 250,000 and the unemployment rate fell to 5.1 pct, the lowest since 1989.</p>
<p>&quot;Our intuitive feeling is that there is enough fund interest stirring ... in the paper gold market to push prices higher in coming weeks,&quot; Merrill Lynch analyst Ted Arnold said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are picking up enough indications from U.S. funds expressing various levels of unease about bond and equity markets and the forthcoming U.S. elections that we feel the gold market will advance,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>After staging a two month recovery from the February-July decline, spot gold and silver prices drifted back down this week, and are now not far from perceived support levels around $380-385 an ounce for gold and $5.10 an ounce in silver.</p>
<p>But another rally in precious metals may again run into forward selling by North American, Australian and even South African miners, analysts said.</p>
<p>The South African rand has already fallen about 20 percent this year to around 4.50 Rand to the U.S. dollar, generating gains for South African miners.</p>
<p>&quot;South African miners simply could not afford to overlook a $5.00 or $10.00 an ounce gain in the dollar gold price as well as they could lock in Rand contango rates of around 14 percent,&quot; Arnold said.</p>
<p>In the platinum metals group, NYMEX October platinum ended down 40 cents at $395.90 an ounce, while NYMEX December palladium ended up five cents at $126.70.</p>
<p>--Clive McKeef, New York Commodities Desk, +1-212-859-1641.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
