<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="380425" id="root" date="1997-02-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Orkla takes over Pripps-Ringnes.</title>
<headline>Orkla takes over Pripps-Ringnes.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-02-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwegian food-based conglomerate Orkla ASA said on Friday it had agreed to take over the stake held by Swedish auto maker AB Volvo in beverages company Pripps-Ringnes.</p>
<p>Orkla said in a statement it valued Volvo's 55-percent share of the jointly-owned firm at four billion NOK. Orkla said it would take over Pripps-Ringnes with immediate effect.  </p>
<p>&quot;Orkla and Volvo have entered into an agreement whereby Orkla will immediately take over Volvo's ownership interest in Pripps-Ringnes, which will thereby become a wholly-owned subsidiary of the Orkla Group,&quot; said the statement, which was issued with Orkla's 1996 profits.</p>
<p>Pripps-Ringnes comprises the companies Pripps in Sweden, Ringnes in Norway and the 50-percent owned Baltic Beverages Holding (BBH), which has seven breweries in the Baltic States, Russia and Ukraine. In addition, Pripps-Ringnes owns 20.5 percent of the Finnish brewery Hartwall, the other owner of BBH.  </p>
<p>&quot;The parties agree that the bulk of the payment will be made towards the end of 1997,&quot; it said. &quot;The agreement is conditional upon the approval of Orkla's corporate assembly. Orkla will not be undertaking an equity issue in connection with the acquisition.&quot;</p>
<p>Orkla took over the Volvo food companies Procordia Food and Abba Seafood in 1995. At the same time, Pripps and Ringnes merged to become Pripps-Ringnes, in which Orkla has so far had a 45-percent financial interest.</p>
<p>&quot;Orkla's takeover of the rest of Pripps-Ringnes marks the final chapter in the takeover of all Volvo's food and beverage operations,&quot; Orkla said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Nordic countries are the natural home market for Orkla's branded products. Outside the Nordic countries, the strongest growth will mainly be in niche areas or special geographical areas.</p>
<p>&quot;Eastern Europe is one such area where Orkla has been working on several fronts for some time. The full takeover of Pripps-Ringnes confirms Orkla's position in the Nordic region and gives the Group a strong position in Eastern Europe. The takeover therefore strengthens the Group's branded products business,&quot; the statement said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
