<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="38054" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ex-Atlanta Fed chief Forrestal sees Sept rate rise.</title>
<headline>Ex-Atlanta Fed chief Forrestal sees Sept rate rise.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta President Robert Forrestal said he expected the U.S. central bank to increase the federal funds rate by a quarter point at its September 24 policy gathering.</p>
<p>&quot;My hunch would be they'll do a quarter point on September 24,&quot; Forrestal told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Forrestal, who is now a parter at the law firm of Smith, Gambrell and Russell, noted that the U.S. economy is not slowing as much as he had expected.  </p>
<p>Forrestal said, if the Federal Reserve does not hike the federal funds rate in September, the central bank will have to tighten by the end of the year if economic numbers continue to be as strong as recent data.</p>
<p>The U.S. Labor Department reported on Friday that the economy created 250,000 non-farm payroll jobs in August after generating a revised 228,000 in July. The unemployment rate tumbled to 5.1 percent from 5.4 percent and hourly earnings climbed to $11.87 from $11.81.</p>
<p>Forrestal said the economy is not experiencing an outbreak of inflation but overall inflation of nearly 3.5 percent is not all that benign.</p>
<p>&quot;While there hasn't been an outbreak, I think that if I were still on the Open Market Committee, I would be a little concerned that action be taken to stem any possible increase in inflation before it gets started,&quot; Forrestal said.</p>
<p>-- Donna Sells, 212-859-1668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
