<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="380535" id="root" date="1997-02-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-CHESTERFIELD, WREXHAM SPRING F.A. CUP SHOCKS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-CHESTERFIELD, WREXHAM SPRING F.A. CUP SHOCKS.</headline>
<byline>Mitch Phillips</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The English F.A. Cup continued its remarkable season of surprises on Saturday as second division sides Chesterfield and Wrexham beat Nottingham Forest and Birmingham respectively to reach the quarter-finals.</p>
<p>Chesterfield reached the last eight for the first time in more than a century of trying with a 1-0 victory over premier league Forest thanks to a 54th-minute penalty by Tom Curtis.</p>
<p>Wrexham, who beat West Ham in the fourth round, came from behind to win 2-1 at first division Birmingham.</p>
<p>Premier league aristocrats Leeds also slipped up at home, beaten 3-2 by first division Portsmouth, leaving Wimbledon and Middlesbrough as the only top flight sides definitely through to the quarter-finals.</p>
<p>Wimbledon recovered from going behind at home to Queens Park Rangers to win 2-1 while Middlesbrough beat Manchester City 1-0 at Maine Road with a solitary goal by Brazilian Juninho.</p>
<p>In the one outstanding fourth-round tie, Blackburn went ahead after just 50 seconds but ended up losing 2-1 at home to Coventry, who will play Derby in the fifth round.</p>
<p>In premier league action Arsenal missed the chance of going top when they were held to a goalless draw at north London rivals Tottenham, while Derby edged West Ham in a relegation battle thanks to a penalty by Aljosa Asanovic.</p>
<p>In the absence of so many big names, the road to Wembley is the most open for years.</p>
<p>It is the first time since 1946 that none of the so-called &quot;Big Five&quot; of Manchester United, Liverpool, Everton, Tottenham and Arsenal reached the fifth round and will be the first final without at least one of them since 1975.</p>
<p>Even so, few would have expected Chesterfield to be one of those taking advantage.</p>
<p>In the fifth round for the first time since 1950, Chesterfield tore into Forest from the start on a muddy Saltergate pitch.</p>
<p>Forest dearly missed suspended player-manager and inspiration Stuart Pearce as the second division players cut through the ragged visiting defence and looked much the better side.</p>
<p>The fully-deserved goal came from the penalty spot after 54 minutes after Forest keeper Mark Crossley brought down Jon Howard and was promptly sent off.</p>
<p>Replacement Alan Fettis could do nothing about Curtis's penalty and Chesterfield should have made it two when Howard fluffed his shot with an open goal beckoning.</p>
<p>Chesterfield manager John Duncan recognised that his team had made history.</p>
<p>&quot;It's brilliant for the town , the players are a credit,&quot; said Duncan, who failed to get past the fifth round as a player with Tottenham. &quot;We deserved to win the game.&quot;</p>
<p>There was no argument from Pearce, who said: &quot;We were well and truly beaten by a team that deserved to beat us.</p>
<p>&quot;It was the manner of the defeat that concerns me. Maybe some of my players think they're better than they are.&quot;</p>
<p>Wrexham, who made their name as giant-killers when beating then league champion Arsenal in 1992, added to their roll of honour with a brave win at St Andrews.</p>
<p>Former Manchester United Stalwart Steve Bruce put Birmingham ahead in the 37th minute but Brian Hughes headed the equaliser soon after the break.</p>
<p>Birmingham then had Paul Devlin sent off in the 57th minute and the Welshmen cashed in immediately when Tony Humes headed them ahead. Karl Connolly sealed the win.</p>
<p>Wrexham manager Bryan Flynn, who was in charge for the famous Arsenal win, said: &quot;To be honest it hasn't sunk in yet.&quot;</p>
<p>Portsmouth, watched by new owner Terry Venables, claimed their sixth successive win with goals by Alan McLoughlin, Mathias Svensson and Lee Bradbury and could afford a Fitzroy Simpson penalty miss. Lee Bowyer hit both Leeds goals.</p>
<p>Veteran striker Mark Hateley put QPR ahead after 41 minutes at London rival Wimbledon only for Marcus Gayle to equalise three minutes later and Robbie Earle to claim the winner.</p>
<p>Tim Sherwood scored the day's fastest goal to put Blackburn ahead at Ewood Park but Coventry's Eoin Jess equalised in the 28th minute and Darren Huckerby got Coventry's winner just before the break.</p>
<p>Two more fifth-round ties are played on Sunday when Cup favourites Chelsea visit Leicester and second division Bradford entertain Sheffield Wednesday. The quarter-final draw will be made on Sunday evening.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
