<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="380660" id="root" date="1997-02-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria's UDF urges stronger presidential powers.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria's UDF urges stronger presidential powers.</headline>
<byline>Elisaveta Konstantinova</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-02-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's Union of Democratic Forces (UDF), the favourite to win general elections on April 19, proposed at its convention on Saturday strengthening the president's powers to cope with the crisis facing the country.</p>
<p>&quot;Bulgaria is in disarray. There is large-scale organised crime and corruption... institutionalised corruption has undermined the power of state institutions,&quot; UDF leader Ivan Kostov said in his opening speech to some 4,600 convention delegates.</p>
<p>&quot;The UDF must support expanding the powers of the Bulgarian president, which will strengthen his role as a guarantor of law and social peace,&quot; said Kostov amid laud acclamation.</p>
<p>Under the constitution the president's duties are largely ceremonial, but President Petar Stoyanov, elected on the opposition ticket in November, won respect from all sides for breaking a political deadlock and brokering an agreement on early elections.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's former Socialist rulers bowed to 30 days of mass protests last week and agreed to hold elections 20 months before the end of their term.</p>
<p>The interim cabinet appointed by Stoyanov on Wednesday inherited paralysing fuel shortages, galloping inflation, bread queues, a sinking national currency, stagnant industry and enormous debts.</p>
<p>Kostov slammed the former Socialist administration for stripping factories of their assets, banks of their deposits and citizens of their savings.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bulgarian people hold the former Socialist rulers responsible for placing them in the current humiliating position,&quot; said Kostov.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not be able to overcome the economic catastrophe if we do not punish those who have caused it,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Kostov proposed setting up an investigative service under presidential supervision to crack down on corruption, strengthen state institutions and crush organised crime.</p>
<p>&quot;This anti-mafia unit should have powers...to collect evidence for crimes that have been committed and to speed up penal procedures,&quot; said Kostov.</p>
<p>During the convention, expected to end on Sunday, the UDF is expected to decide whether to become a single political party and form a broader coalition with its current partners, the ethnic Turk Movement for Rights and Freedoms and the People's Union.</p>
<p>Set up after the fall of the communist regime seven years ago, the UDF is a coalition of democratic, agrarian and monarchist parties.</p>
<p>It formed the first non-communist government after winning general elections in 1991, but surrendered power after 11 months in office after it failed to win backing for radical reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;Never in its history has Bulgaria faced such challenges...The UDF faced the challenge of today and is prepared to take charge of the new Bulgarian future,&quot; said Stoyanov in a brief greeting to the delegates.</p>
<p>Tough times lie ahead for the government elected in April, which will have to sack thousands of employees in loss-making state firms and impose severe budget restrictions and a strict fixed exchange rate regime.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
