<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="380658" id="root" date="1997-02-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Tajik rebels humiliate hostages - Russian diplomat.</title>
<headline>Tajik rebels humiliate hostages - Russian diplomat.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-02-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Russian mediator said on Saturday that Islamic rebels holding Russian and Western hostages in Tajikistan had humiliated their captives and he doubted whether a negotiated release deal would be honoured.</p>
<p>&quot;A very strong doubt appears...that they will return the hostages. They (the rebels) have simply deceived the whole world community,&quot; Gennady Sizov, a Russian diplomat in Tajikistan who mediates in the crisis, told Russian Television.</p>
<p>Asked whether he knew about the state of the hostages, Sizov replied: &quot;They are in a very, very bad shape. They are humiliated, morally and physically. They have been tied.&quot;</p>
<p>Sizov was speaking after the rebels, led by brothers Rizvon and Bakhrom Sadirov had failed to keep their part of the deal and release 11 Western and Russian hostages.</p>
<p>The hostages still held by the rebels include three U.N. observers -- two from Switzerland and one from Ukraine -- four workers with the U.N. refugee agency, two Russian television journalists and the Tajik security minister, Saidamir Zukhurov.</p>
<p>The first hostages were captured early last week and the minister was abducted last weekend when he flew in to negotiate.</p>
<p>Late on Friday the rebels freed three of the hostages -- two Russian woman journalists and a driver.</p>
<p>Under the deal mediated by Russian officials, the Tajik government flew to Tajikistan from Afghanistan 35 supporters of the Sadirovs.</p>
<p>All the fighters, armed, have been freed and allowed to reach Sadirovs' base mountain base in a rocky region about 80 km (50 miles) from the Tajik capital Dushanbe and overlooking the village of Obigarm.</p>
<p>After the last group of fighters reached the Sadirovs' base, they were expected to set the remaining hostages free and let them walk about one mile (km) down the mountain to Obigarm where Russian and Tajik government negotiators were waiting.</p>
<p>It was at that moment when the rebels apparently switched off their communications and their intentions remained unclear.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Tajik President Imomali Rakhmonov told Reuters earlier on Saturday the fighters might withdraw to the mountains and take the hostages with them.</p>
<p>A Russian Television journalist said movement had been seen at the base and the rebels appeared to be loading their weapons into a truck.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TADZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
