<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="380724" id="root" date="1997-02-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: WEEK AHEAD - Asian stocks seen volatile, nervous.</title>
<headline>WEEK AHEAD - Asian stocks seen volatile, nervous.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian stocks face another volatile week after political jitters, currency weakness, threats of rating downgrades and profit-taking buffetted markets throughout the region, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are seeing extreme volatility,&quot; said one fund manager. &quot;We're getting a lot of rotational switching and the hedge funds are playing around with Hong Kong.&quot;</p>
<p>Derivatives trading was believed to account for some of Hong Kong's sudden slide although profit-taking and rumours that China's paramount leader Deng Xiaoping was unwell also hurt.</p>
<p>Panic selling hit the weak Thai stock exchange on Friday after Moody's Investors Service Inc announced a review of Thailand's foreign currency long-term debt ratings.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, speculative wolves lingered at the door of the Thai baht, which remains under pressure from an uncertain financial services sector and a gaping current account deficit.</p>
<p>Manila, Singapore and Jakarta also suffered bouts of profit-taking, undermining any positive momentum from last week's fresh record highs on Wall Street.</p>
<p>But underlying sentiment appears to remain strong in these markets, particularly in Singapore and Jakarta.</p>
<p>The earnings period could also offer support in the coming week, but the outlook in Thailand, South Korea and Hong Kong remains very uncertain.</p>
<p>Kuala Lumpur -- one of the region's biggest and most important markets -- is expected to continue consolidating after a strong recent run-up. Regional traders said good activity in second- and third-line stocks indicates that the latest rally is now reaching its final stages.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Stocks could face more weakness this coming week before they start to stabilise after heavy losses drove the Hang Seng Index to a two-month low last week, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The support is at 12,800 points,&quot; said Alex Tang, head of research at Yamaichi International. &quot;I think the market should hold at that level and as the Hang Seng Index moves below 13,000 it will become quite attractive,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index shed 547.24 points, or 4.01 percent, last week to end at 13,113.26 on Friday. It hit its lowest level since December 19 last Friday at 12,962.15 points.</p>
<p>Tang said the market's uptrend remained intact and once the earnings reporting season gets underway, prices should rise.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TOKYO - The weak yen and financial reform proposals -- factors blamed for sending Tokyo shares plummeting earlier -- are now being seen as positives in a newly-revived market that could well push higher in the week ahead, traders said.</p>
<p>The Nikkei index of 225 leading companies, which climbed 4.8 percent to end at 18,722.00, may push through the 19,000 barrier this week, as blue-chip buying is likely to extend to other companies.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's eye is turning to favorable effects from the yen's depreciation,&quot; said Masaaki Higashida, deputy general manager at Nomura Securities Co Ltd.</p>
<p>Higashida said he expected the key stock index to range between 18,500 and 19,500 this week.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BANGKOK - The Stock Exchange of Thailand (SET) index is expected to fall further on lingering worries that Moody's Investors Service may cut Thailand's long-term debt ratings.</p>
<p>The agency said on Friday it may cut the A2 long-term foreign currency bond and deposit ratings for five Thai banks. Further declines will force sales of stocks held by margin players and extend market losses, brokers said.</p>
<p>The composite SET Index dropped 34.28 points, or 4.58 percent, in the week to end at 713.48 on Friday. The SET 50 Index fell 2.66 points, or 4.86 percent, to 52.07.</p>
<p>&quot;Comments by Moody's aren't good for the Thai market at all and they will induce foreigners to sell while local retailers who play under the maintenance margin system will be forced to sell shares,&quot; said Dusanee Klewpatinontha of Nithipat Capital.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>JAKARTA - Jakarta share prices are expected to maintain their upward trend in the coming week after the market broke through the psychological 700 barrier, brokers said.</p>
<p>Expectations of strong 1996 earnings were likely to boost overall market sentiment, with a particular focus on banking stocks, brokers said.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Jakarta composite index closed 2.89 points lower at 704.48 points after profit-taking struck with a new high of 710,43 in early trading.</p>
<p>For the holiday-shortened week, the benchmark index closed 4.96 points or 0.40 percent higher at 1,246.91 on Friday.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TAIPEI - Taiwan share prices are likely to rise next week on continued strong momentum after hitting a six-year high on Saturday, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is likely to continue rising for the rest of February, and the next technical resistance is not seen until the 7,800 level,&quot; said Lin Long-hsien at United Securities.</p>
<p>The index ended the week 252.05 points or 3.43 percent stronger at 7,598.93 compared to a finish of 7,346.88 on February 3, the market's last trading session before closing for public holidays.</p>
<p>A 7,450-7,650 range was seen for next week.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MANILA - Manila shares are seen sliding further early next week and the focus on penny stocks would persist, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a tendency for thirdliners to be played again since we do not expect any shattering news on blue chips or about the market,&quot; said Felix Barrientos, dealer at ING Baring Securities.</p>
<p>The main index ended 3,322.30 on Friday, down 59.54 points from the previous week's close of 3,381.84.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>KUALA LUMPUR - The Composite Index could correct further into next week following sharp gains on Wednesday and Thursday, although less bearish market players forecast consolidation and a strong interest in smaller stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there will still be some rotational play on the second- and third-liners,&quot; said one institutional dealer.</p>
<p>Interest this week has been concentrated on lower-valued stocks which have been left out of the market's run-up. Among blue chips, dealers said motor and banking stocks were favoured on expectations of positive earnings.</p>
<p>The small-capitalisation Second Board index rose 9.64 points or 1.56 percent to 627.82 on Friday. The market was closed from February 6 to 11 for public holidays.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SEOUL - Seoul stocks are expected to rise early next week but face consolidation towards the latter half, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The composite index is likely to test 750-770 next week before profit-taking emerges,&quot; said Yoo Jae-kyong of Daishin Securities.</p>
<p>The composite index ended at 722.32 on Saturday, up 22.10 points or 3.16 percent from 700.22 last Thursday, when the market closed for public holidays.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SINGAPORE - Sentiment remains strong in Singapore, foreign funds are buying, and higher levels are expected despite a bout of profit-taking last week, brokers said.</p>
<p>Technically, the main index is poised to attempt about 2,305 points. It ended down 2.22 points at 2,252.46 on Friday, hit by mild profit taking, compared with 2,203.39 a week ago Thursday.</p>
<p>Malaysian second line issues traded on CLOB will continue to attract attention but caution ahead of earnings periods could lead to thin volume on large-capitalisation issues.</p>
<p>Regional traders reported strong buying from U.S. and European investors last week.</p>
<p>The index has risen 2.3 percent since end-1996 and remains fundamentally supported by foreign funds' re-ratings of the entire Singapore bourse, dealers said.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SYDNEY - Australian shares were seen consolidating in the near term after the run to record highs on the back of a buoyant bank sector and stronger miners.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index closed at 2,482.6, up 1.5 percent over the week after hitting a record high of 2,506.5 in early trade on Friday before profit taking set in.</p>
<p>&quot;The futures couldn't handle the 2,500 level and that could be the next hurdle. It took a while to work through the 2,400 level and it might take a while to work through the 2,500 level also,&quot; said a Brisbane-based dealer.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>WELLINGTON - New Zealand investors' focus on corporate earnings will continue next week with third quarter results from benchmark stocks Telecom, Ports of Auckland, Air New Zealand and Natural Gas Corp. But an overall bearish tone could be reinforced next week if Australia takes a turn for the worse, said Jim Patterson at First NZ Capital.</p>
<p>Despite the volatility, the NZSE-40 Capital Index ended at 2,323.18, down just 5.11 points (0.22 percent) from a week ago.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BOMBAY - Indian stocks are seen volatile in hectic trade next week on expectations for the 1997/98 federal budget due at the month-end, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices are likely to stay volatile, with an upward bias,&quot; said a chief dealer at a local brokerage.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-share index of the Bombay Stock Exchange rose 114.77 points, or 3.37 percent, to 3,521.99 in the week ending Friday.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>DHAKA - The Dhaka Stock Exchange price index gained 50.13 points at 1,847.77 in the week to Thursday. Brokers expect profit taking to emerge early next week, pushing prices down marginally even though sentiment could remain strong.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
