<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="380822" id="root" date="1997-02-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American pilots strike halted; labor issues remain.</title>
<headline>American pilots strike halted; labor issues remain.</headline>
<byline>Robert Trautman</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton on Saturday invoked his emergency powers to end a strike by union pilots against American Airlines, the number-two U.S. carrier, but the knotty issues that triggered the strike remained.</p>
<p>James Sovich, president of the Allied Pilots Association, said when Clinton ended the strike after only 24 minutes that once the 60-day cooling off period was over, the pilots may have to &quot;go out on strike a second time.&quot;</p>
<p>Some analysts and others close to the talks sensed this week that a stalemate and strike was likely when no signs of progress emerged during the five days of marathon bargaining, even in the final hours when compromises are often fashioned.</p>
<p>The efforts to write a new contract tripped on the issue of pay and the more intractible one of who will fly the new small jets the carrier intends to buy for its commuter airline, American Eagle.</p>
<p>American wants to put lower-paid American Eagle pilots from a different union in the cockpit, but the APA wants its own members, who average $130,000 a year, to fly them.</p>
<p>Analysts said the issue of pay for pilots flying the carrier's big jets could have been split -- the union wanted 11 percent over four years, and American's last offer was six.</p>
<p>The pilots argued that the 11 percent would not have even matched inflation, because pilots have gotten no raise in basic pay for the past three years, so the 11 percent was in effect seven years of cost-of-living catch-up pay.</p>
<p>But American, which is now making money after years of red ink, said economies were needed to keep it competitive with its big jet rivals, including those who were increasingly flying low-cost commuter lines.</p>
<p>Analysts said the issue of pay for pilots flying the new small jets -- American Eagle's pilots union would fly them rather than the Allied Pilots -- was a deal breaker, and a settlement could have been precedent-setting.</p>
<p>Pilots feared the small jets, with ranges far longer than the turboprops the commuters now fly and far more comfortable for passengers, would gradually fly longer distance routes and in the end replace some of the big jets American now flies.</p>
<p>The pilots saw this as a threat to their jobs.</p>
<p>American pledged that no jobs would be lost, but the union did not accept the assurances.</p>
<p>Sovich told American in a statement: &quot;Job security and cost of living represent a modest proposal. Take the deal.&quot;</p>
<p>But American remained adamant, and in the union's view presented them an offer they had to refuse, setting the stage for the emergency board action invoked by Clinton.</p>
<p>Under board procedure, a presidential panel will be set up to take information from both the union and the company, and in 30 days will submit a draft contract to the parties. The sides then have another 30 days to accept or reject it, but if is rejected, the union is again free to strike.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
