<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="381049" id="root" date="1997-02-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: SOCCER-JARDEL HAT TRICK KEEPS PORTO FAR IN FRONT.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-JARDEL HAT TRICK KEEPS PORTO FAR IN FRONT.</headline>
<byline>Alberto Pontes</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-02-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian striker Mario Jardel scored a hat trick to help reigning champions Porto to a 4-2 away win over Chaves on Saturday that maintained their 16-point lead at the top of the Portuguese first division.</p>
<p>Behind them, Sporting and Benfica also both won to keep up the battle for second place. Sporting beat Rio Ave 2-0 at home, while Lisbon rivals Benfica overcame Setubal away by the same margin.</p>
<p>Porto have 56 points, while Sporting are second on 41, one point more than Benfica.</p>
<p>Jardel, top scorer in the Portuguese league in his first season, laid on the first of Porto's goals for teammate Joao Manuel Pinto after just 19 minutes.</p>
<p>Chaves goalkeeper Rui Vasco failed to hold a powerful header from the tall striker and the Porto defender was on hand to head the ball home.</p>
<p>It was Jardel's head that did the damage again 15 minutes later when he beat Vasco to the ball to score his first of the night.</p>
<p>Chaves managed to cut the deficit to one goal when Brazilian midfielder Edmilson Pimenta brought down Chaves' Romanian midfielder Marcel Sabou in the box. Bosnian Nicola Milinkovic slotted home the penalty.</p>
<p>Porto were reduced to 10 men before halftime when defender Sergio Conceicao was sent off for a second bookable offence but this did not stop them pressing forward.</p>
<p>Jardel struck twice more in the 75th and 78th minutes, the first a sweet volley, before Chaves got a consolation second goal four minutes from time.</p>
<p>Another Brazilian, midfielder Jamir Gomes, was also in goal-scoring mood for Benfica, opening their account against Setubal after just 18 minutes when he fired in from an acute angle.</p>
<p>But the Lisbon side had veteran Belgian goalkeeper Michel Preud'Homme to thank for keeping Setubal at bay in the second half when he produced two fine saves to deny the home side.</p>
<p>Benfica's second came from a spectacular solo effort by Edgar Pacheco who scored with a fiercely-struck drive from outside the area in the 73rd minute.</p>
<p>Bulgarian striker Ivaylo Iordanov scored Sporting's first against lowly Rio Ave afer 33 minutes when he controlled the ball on his chest with his back to goal before swivelling and volleying into the net.</p>
<p>Pedro Barbosa scored the second four minutes later.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
