<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="381054" id="root" date="1997-02-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIA MOVES TO BRIDLE CRISIS BRACES FOR ELECTION.</title>
<headline>BULGARIA MOVES TO BRIDLE CRISIS BRACES FOR ELECTION.</headline>
<byline>Elisaveta Konstantinova</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-02-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's Union of Democratic Forces (UDF) braced to win April general elections by becoming a single party while interim cabinet made first steps to contain economic chaos and lay the foundation for recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;A new united political force emerged in the past two days which will govern the country after April 19 elections,&quot; UDF leader Ivan Kostov told reporters on Sunday.</p>
<p>During a convention, expected to end later on Sunday, the UDF decided to register as a single political party in a bid to adjust its membering parties to the task of governing this crisis-ridden Balkan country.</p>
<p>&quot;In its previous shape the UDF could win elections but was unfit for governing the country...It would not have been able to cope with the collapsed economy, corrupt administration and rampant organised crime,&quot; said Kostov.</p>
<p>&quot;We will need titanic force to save Bulgaria,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The UDF emerged as the favourite to win parliamentary polls after the success of a month-long nation-wide protest campaign which induced the ruling Socialists to agree 12 days ago on early elections, 20 months before the end of their term.</p>
<p>President Petar Stoyanov appointed on Wednesday a caretaker cabinet to govern until elections led by Sofia Mayor Stefan Sofianski.</p>
<p>The interim cabinet inherited from the former Socialist administration paralysing fuel shortages, galloping inflation, bread queues, a sinking national currency, enormous debts and large-scale organised crime.</p>
<p>&quot;The next several weeks will be crucial. If we contain the crisis now, we have strong chances to stabilise quickly,&quot; Sofianski said in an interview with state television late on Saturday.</p>
<p>His immediate priorities included providing adequate fuel and grain supplies, cutting redundant state adiministration, shutting down loss-makers, speeding up sell-offs and gradually lifting price controls.</p>
<p>In a bid to curb flight of capital abroad, the interiour ministery banned former Prime Minister Zhan Videnov, his advisors and members his cabinet from travelling abroad until investigations of embezzlement allegations were made.</p>
<p>&quot;It is impossible to have a completely devastated state, to have no fuel and no grain supplies, empty coffers and say no one is guilty...These people must stay here until the investigation ends,&quot; said Sofianski in the interview.</p>
<p>On Friday the government sent troops to enforce border controls in an attempt to curb fuel and food smuggling by motorists to neighbouring Yugoslavia and Macedonia, where prices are higher.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to bring prices as close as possible to those in the neighbouring countries,&quot; said Sofianski.</p>
<p>A drastic fuel price hike is expected on Monday, as fuel shortages are threatening to paralyse Bulgaria because of insufficient cash to pay for crude supplies.</p>
<p>Sofianski saw direct foreign loans as crucial for the country's stabilisation.</p>
<p>&quot;We have possiblities to receive between $300 million and $400 million, which will stabilise the situation. Then in June Bulgaria can sharply move forward,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An IMF team is due in Sofia net week to resume talks on the implementation of a fixed exchange rate regime aimed at proping up the national currency and ailing banks. A European Union mission is also expected to come soon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
