<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="381141" id="root" date="1997-02-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexican truck drivers plan stoppage.</title>
<headline>Mexican truck drivers plan stoppage.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-02-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's largest confederation of independent truck drivers will launch a stoppage Monday to press for demands including a price cap on diesel fuel and a reduction in government red tape, a confederation leader said Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to happen, definitely, as of 0000 hours on Monday (0600 GMT on Tuesday),&quot; David Galicia, secretary general of the 40,000-member National Confederation of Transport Drivers (CNT), told Reuters.  </p>
<p>He said the strike would last until the truckers reached an agreement with the government.</p>
<p>Confederation drivers represent 10 percent to 15 percent of all the truckers in Mexico, he said. Most confederation members own one to four trucks.</p>
<p>Galicia said the confederation was attempting to re-establish order in the &quot;chaotic&quot; independent trucking sector since deregulation in 1989.</p>
<p>Among other measures, the truckers are demanding the regulation of trucking fees for independent carriers, a cap on the cost of diesel fuel and a reduction in the bureaucratic red tape associated with getting trucking licenses and permits, Galicia said.</p>
<p>The confederation is negotiating with officials in the Communications and Transport Ministry and other ministries but with little success, Galicia said. Officials at the Communications and Transport Ministry could not be reached for comment on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;The government thinks that everything is fine in the independent trucking sector,&quot; Galicia said. &quot;But this is going to last until the government meets our demands. We don't want anymore promises.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Dan Trotta, Mexico City newsroom, +525 728-9507))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
