<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="381112" id="root" date="1997-02-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Police halt Tirana rally, pyramid protests persist.</title>
<headline>Police halt Tirana rally, pyramid protests persist.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Weeks</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-02-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanian police headed off an anti-government rally in the capital on Sunday but thousands of beggared investors marched elsewhere to demand compensation for heavy losses in failed pyramid investment schemes.</p>
<p>Angry investors in three southern towns held protests again on Sunday, ignoring government appeals to shrug off millions of dollars in losses and get back to work.</p>
<p>Protesters in Fier, Vlore and Sarande chanted slogans against the right-wing government of Prime Minister Aleksander Meksi and President Sali Berisha and demanded compensation.</p>
<p>In Fier, 2,000 protesters denounced Berisha and carried local opposition Socialist Party leader Petro Koci through the streets on their shoulders.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a war between Fier residents and Berisha. Be assured we will win,&quot; Koci told the crowd.</p>
<p>The protests were quieter than in recent days. No riot police were seen in a new strategy by the government to let marches go ahead unopposed outside the capital.</p>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Tritan Shehu called on the opposition Socialists to meet him on Wednesday to lower tensions after the collapse of the schemes, which left many Albanians penniless.</p>
<p>So far the Socialists have refused to join in talks on the schemes. Albania, Europe's poorest state, has been swept by a month of protests and riots after five hugely popular pyramid investment schemes collapsed owing millions of dollars.</p>
<p>Angry investors, many of whom earned their money as illegal workers in neighbouring European Union states, blame Meksi and Berisha for failing to warn them about the unregulated schemes.</p>
<p>Attention has focused recently on four other major funds which insist they are genuine business concerns but have frozen capital investments and cut interest payments sharply.</p>
<p>The head of one of the largest companies, Vehbi Alimucaj of Vefa, appeared on television to assure his investors that their money was safe and Vefa was not a pyramid scheme.</p>
<p>He said on Vefa's private channel, EuroVefa, that investors would receive their money, that he had received $500 million in credits from foreign firms and that they should not sell their deposit certificates at a discount.</p>
<p>Vefa has frozen investors' assets but continued to pay interest, although at a reduced rate.</p>
<p>Economists and diplomats estimate $1 to $2 billion were in the failed schemes. Four others have kept paying interest but have frozen clients' capital.</p>
<p>Many among Albania's 3.4 million people were invested in the schemes. In extreme cases people sold homes and valuables in a frenzy to invest before the schemes collapsed.</p>
<p>Albania, which for 45 years lived in isolation and under a ruthless Stalinist government, emerged from communism in 1990. The pyramid crisis is the most serious challenge to the pro-market Democrats since they were elected in 1992.</p>
<p>In Tirana, police put on a show of force to ensure a rally called by the main opposition Forum for Democracy on Sunday did not take place.</p>
<p>A dozen police vans and cars cruised the area and officers moved quickly to make sure people kept going and did not loiter near the football stadium where the rally was due to be held.</p>
<p>Officers forced customers in nearby cafes out into a heavy rain storm to make sure that if any were potential protesters they would disperse or get drenched.</p>
<p>Berisha acknowledged on Saturday that the government had committed errors and had warned the public too late about the dangers of the schemes.</p>
<p>But he said responsibility also lay with those who had put millions of dollars into the high-interest schemes -- and lost everything.</p>
<p>He stressed that the state had no intention of reimbursing hundreds of thousands of Albanians who lost their savings.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not take this debt on our shoulders. No democratic government would do this. It would be cheating, printing money to pay and creating hyperinflation&quot;, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
