<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="381467" id="root" date="1997-02-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Guerrillas kill 15, wound nine in India attack.</title>
<headline>Guerrillas kill 15, wound nine in India attack.</headline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA 1997-02-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tribal separatist guerrillas on Sunday killed 15 people and wounded nine in an attack on two remote villages in the northeastern Indian state of Tripura, police said.</p>
<p>Guerrillas belonging to the All Tripura Tiger Force (ATTF) set ablaze at least 100 homes in Purbaramachandraghat and Ganda Basti in the western section of the state, then fired on fleeing residents, police in the state capital Agartala said.</p>
<p>&quot;The violence is still on. A lot of houses are still burning. The militants attacked the villages despite imposition of a curfew and deployment of the army,&quot; a police spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>The attack occurred in the Khowai region where the rebels, who are fighting for a separate nation, killed 17 people on Monday and burnt down more than 60 houses in ethnic clashes between tribespeople and Bengali settlers last Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;They belong to the ATTF, the modus operandi is the same. They first set fire to houses and when people run out, they open fire on them,&quot; the police spokesman said.</p>
<p>Police and paramilitary troops have launched a search operation for the attackers.</p>
<p>Last July, the separatist group issued a statement warning Bengali settlers to leave the state, which shares an 840-km (520-mile) border with Bangladesh.</p>
<p>The state's indigenous tribal population has been reduced to a minority by Bengali Hindu immigrants who dominate local politics and the economy.</p>
<p>More than 2,000 people were killed in the region's worst ethnic riots in June 1980.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
