<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="381404" id="root" date="1997-02-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Pressure mounts on Kohl to decide on 1998 polls.</title>
<headline>Pressure mounts on Kohl to decide on 1998 polls.</headline>
<byline>Fiona Fleck</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-02-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pressure mounted on German Chancellor Helmut Kohl on Sunday to say whether he will stand in next year's general elections despite his insistence that he will not be pressed into making a decision before he is ready.</p>
<p>Citing unnamed sources, Bild am Sonntag newspaper reported that Kohl would announce his renewed candidacy just after Easter (early April) and quoted a member of his Christian Democrats (CDU) saying Kohl would make the announcement &quot;in the next weeks&quot;.</p>
<p>The comments added to already intense speculation, fuelled by his recent remarks that he would announce his decision after a June European Union reform summit in Amsterdam, as well as worries about soaring unemployment and deadlock over reform.</p>
<p>&quot;Kohl cannot hold off much longer on this decision. If he runs, the CDU parliamentary group will be behind him. If not, it will be behind (parliamentary group leader Wolfgang) Schaeuble,&quot; CDU parliamentarian Horst Eylmann told the paper, referring to Kohl's lieutenent and the favourite for the post.</p>
<p>&quot;The party and the people have a right to find out soon whether Kohl is going to run or not,&quot; Eylmann said.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect Helmut Kohl to make it known he is standing again as chancellor in the next few weeks,&quot; Bild am Sonntag quoted another CDU parliamentarian, Friedhelm Ost, as saying.</p>
<p>The renewed speculation  follows Kohl telling a German newspaper he would announce whether or not he was standing for what would be his fourth term &quot;at the right time&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I know my duty and I don't need any remedial help on this,&quot; the 66-year-old chancellor now in his 15th year of office told the Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung on Saturday.</p>
<p>Kohl said in the interview that some of his critics were out to capitalise on the deadlock in his ruling coalition over planned tax and pension reforms: &quot;The whole country's survival depends on our success in pushing through these reforms.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I am absolutely convinced I will be successful in doing my part to push them (reforms) through and even when the tide is against me, I will not be deterred,&quot; he said, adding that he had solved seemingly insurmountable problems in the past.</p>
<p>&quot;As already announced, I will make my decision known as to whether I will stand again as chancellor in the 1998 general election when I consider the time to be right,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kohl's failure to push tax and pension reform plans smoothly through the coalition, added to the blow of record unemployment, has caused turmoil among his CDU and brought media speculation over his future to fever pitch.</p>
<p>One opposition leader dubbed the situation &quot;twilight of the chancellor&quot;, the press has run headlines such as &quot;Autumn of the Patriarch&quot; and Kohl's indecision over whether to stand again in general elections next year has added to the sense of drift.</p>
<p>Schaeuble dismissed the Bonn rumour mill, saying only a couple of months ago the media were calling Kohl &quot;the eternal chancellor&quot; referring to when Kohl overtook Konrad Adenauer's record as post-war Germany's longest-serving chancellor.</p>
<p>&quot;We should concentrate on the important problems,&quot; Schaeuble told ZDF television. &quot;We have high unemployment, we have problems with making Germany attractive for investment.&quot;</p>
<p>Kohl, whose government has been attacked from his own party ranks over the reforms, said he was not above criticism.</p>
<p>&quot;But it just annoys me when criticism is not what it says it's about, when people just want to increase their status by it. Helmut Kohl also deserves a minimum quota of fairness too,&quot; he said in response to regional CDU leaders, who had called on Finance Mnister Theo Waigel to resign over his tax plans.</p>
<p>Kohl firmed his resolve to achieve his government's goal of halving unemployment by the year 2000: &quot;It is the joint duty of industry, trade unions and politicians. When we act resolutely we can achieve this goal or come pretty close to it.&quot;</p>
<p>He said his enthusiasm for European integration did not mean he would tolerate any weakening of the Maastricht criteria for economic and monetary union (EMU) and sought to quell German fears about swapping a strong mark for a weaker euro.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
