<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="381574" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: CRICKET-BICHEL, BEVAN BOWL AUSTRALIA TO VICTORY.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-BICHEL, BEVAN BOWL AUSTRALIA TO VICTORY.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paceman Andy Bichel and occasional left-arm spinner Michael Bevan shared eight wickets as Australia beat South African provincial champions Western Province by 32 runs at Newlands on Monday.</p>
<p>Set to score 354 in 81 overs on the third and last day, the home side never gave up the chase and reached 321 all out, Bichel taking five for 62 and Bevan three for 113.</p>
<p>Western Province began their quest for victory with a stand of 61 before Bichel removed test opener Gary Kirsten for 29 with the aid of a breathtaking slip catch from Matthew Elliott, who held four excellent catches in the match.</p>
<p>Bevan took the next two wickets to leave the home side 100 for three before Herschelle Gibbs and captain John Commins added 110 for the fourth wicket at over five runs an over.</p>
<p>Gibbs was in magnificent form, reaching 50 from 70 balls and then accelerating to 80 from 92 deliveries, with 10 fours and three sixes. He fell to a fine catch in the gully by Elliott off paceman Jason Gillespie to inspire the breakthrough.</p>
<p>Bichel removed Commins for 51 and then grabbed two more wickets in his next three overs. Once again he owed his success to the safe hands of his team mates as Bevan took two successive catches in the covers.</p>
<p>Australian captain Mark Taylor said Bevan, who still regards himself as a batsman and occasional bowler, had played a vital role with figures of 29.4-3-113-3.</p>
<p>&quot;I was really pleased with all aspects of our play and I thought Michael bowled tremendously. Unfortunately he was the only batsman not to get runs but his bowling makes him an important member of the attack and he'll probably bat at seven in the first test,&quot; Taylor said.</p>
<p>Taylor continued to juggle his batting line-up when his side's second innings resumed on the third morning at 78 for four.</p>
<p>Greg Blewett, who had opened, ensured his captain could declare on time with a splendid 86 from 106 deliveries.</p>
<p>Blewett's highlight was a six over extra cover off left-arm paceman Brett Schultz but his 13 fours were spread around the ground.</p>
<p>Australia will pick from 12 players for the four-day match against Natal starting in Durban on Thursday, with Justin Langer keeping wicket in place of Ian Healy and Mark Waugh playing in place of his brother Steve.</p>
<p>Australian 12: Mark Taylor (captain), Matthew Hayden, Matthew Elliott, Mark Waugh, Greg Blewett, Justin Langer, Michael Bevan, Shane Warne, Paul Reiffel, Andy Bichel, Jason Gillespie, Glenn McGrath.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
