<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="381794" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zairean air attack as U.N. seeks end to rebel war.</title>
<headline>Zairean air attack as U.N. seeks end to rebel war.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Malu-Malu</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's government on Monday rejected a ceasefire with rebels who have captured much of the country's east and launched air raids against a rebel-held town, killing at least six people an eyewitness in the town said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government stresses that it cannot accept a ceasefire with unidentified belligerents,&quot; Foreign Minister Kamanda wa Kamanda said in a statement issued just before he met U.N. special envoy Mohammed Sahnoun, who is trying to end the war.</p>
<p>At the same time, Zaire stepped up its counter-offensive against Tutsi-led rebels who have made large territorial conquests since taking up arms last October.</p>
<p>An aid worker in the rebel headquarters of Goma said three government jets bombed the rebel-held east Zairean city of Bukavu just after 4.p.m. (1400 GMT). Another aid worker, speaking to Reuters by telephone from Bukavu, said loud explosions echoed through Bukavu and panic-stricken residents ran for cover.</p>
<p>&quot;Bukavu has just been bombed...My staff and I are sheltering in the basement. We can see people running back and forth looking for shelter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An aid worker in Bukavu who said he counted the dead and wounded after the bombing raids told Reuters by telephone that at least six people were killed and some 20 wounded.</p>
<p>The government accuses the rebels of waging a proxy war for Rwanda, Burundi and Uganda -- which deny involvement. The statement implied Zaire could consider a truce with the neighbouring states.</p>
<p>&quot;Any ceasefire with the regular armies of Uganda, Rwanda and Burundi must be linked to the withdrawal of all foreign troops from Zaire,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Zaire used the occasion of the U.N. mission to blame the world body for a threat by rebel leader Laurent Kabila to attack Tingi Tingi refugee camp near the city of Kisangani.</p>
<p>It said a statement by U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan last week that Zaire was arming exiled Hutu hardliners among some 200,000 camp dwellers gave rebels the pretext to threaten a raid. U.N. officials said they saw Zairean military supplies being unloaded.</p>
<p>&quot;The Zaire government demands that the Security Council remove from Zairean territory all Rwandan refugees&quot; including ex-Rwandan soldiers and their militia allies, it added.</p>
<p>The war in eastern Zaire is intertwined with the ethnic conflict between Hutus and Tutsis in Rwanda. The Hutu army and civilian militias massacred up to 800,000 minority Tutsis and moderate Hutus in 1994 before fleeing en masse into Zaire.</p>
<p>Hutu hardliners in refugee camps in Zaire plotted revenge attacks on the Tutsi-led government that later took power in Rwanda, stoking tensions in the region.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Zaire's ethnic-Tutsis took up arms in October after local authorities said they would expel them to their ancenstral homeland in Rwanda.</p>
<p>The rebels went on to seize vast tracts of borderland, putting Zaire's rag-tag army to flight and forcing the government to recruit foreign mercenaries for a counter-attack.</p>
<p>Sahnoun, a veteran Algerian diplomat, is trying to untangle Africa's most complex running conflict on behalf of the United Nations and the Organisation of African Unity.</p>
<p>He met ailing President Mobutu Sese Seko, who is battling cancer at the same time as struggling to keep his 31-year hold on power in the vast Central African nation.</p>
<p>Sahnoun made no statement as he emerged from the talks with Kamnda, who is also a deputy prime minister. He then went to meet Defence Minister General Lukulia Bolongo before further talks with Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
