<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="381742" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK government allows Bulgarian refugees to stay.</title>
<headline>UK government allows Bulgarian refugees to stay.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two Bulgarian refugees won their two-year battle to stay in Britain after the interior ministry said on Monday it would not appeal against the decision of an immigration tribunal.</p>
<p>Home Secretary Michael Howard did not appeal against the decision by last Friday's deadline.</p>
<p>Georgi Spasov, 29, and Dimitar Dmitrov,43, claimed political asylum in April 1995 after leading a strike on a Bulgarian fishing vessel near Shetland off northern Scotland.</p>
<p>The lawyer representing Spasov and Dmitrov said in January that the two had real reason to fear imprisonment for their trade union activities.</p>
<p>Bulgaria was recently added to the government's white list' of countries where law-abiding citizens are not in danger from their government. But the immigration tribunal decided that each case should be looked at on its merits.</p>
<p>Both Spasov and Dmitrov received work permits over a year ago and have been working for a Shetland construction company for the past five months.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
