<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="381899" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania to use external loans for 97 budget gap - PM.</title>
<headline>Romania to use external loans for 97 budget gap - PM.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's Prime Minister Victor Ciorbea said on Monday that the bulk of 1997 budget deficit, estimated at 4.5 percent of the gross domestic product, would be financed through external loans.</p>
<p>&quot;The consolidated budget gap deficit...will be financed only through non-inflationary sources,&quot; Ciorbea told a news conference setting forth a tough reform package after loan talks with international lenders.</p>
<p>Of the 4.5 percent GDP share of the budget gap, external loans would take 3.4 percent, Ciorbea said, adding that the rest would be funded through domestic loans.  </p>
<p>The consolidated budget includes the central state budget, local budgets, social insurance budget and other funds.</p>
<p>It accounted for 5.7 percent of GDP last year -- nearly triple the 2.2 percent target agreed with the International Monetary Fund.</p>
<p>The 1997 budget bill -- a plank of loan talks with the World Bank and IMF -- is expected to be presented to parliament later this month.</p>
<p>Both lenders had withheld loans to Romania last year over foreign exchange market curbs and overspending by the former ruling leftists in an election year.  </p>
<p>Romania is seeking around $1.0 billion in total loans from the IMF and the World Bank to underpin its reform drive.</p>
<p>Ciorbea said that the 1997 budget spending would stay close to the 1996 level, with subsidies for agriculture taking 2.3 percent of GDP, up from last year's 1.9 percent but the central bank would &quot;no longer give soft loans for farming.&quot;</p>
<p>Subsidies to communist-era industries would be halved, capital spending would fall by 17 percent, while social protection funds would account for 10 percent of GDP, he said.</p>
<p>Removing tax holidays, higher excise duties for alcohol and tobacco are expected to bring higher revenues to the 1997 budget, he said. But incomes to be derived from planned privatisations had not been taken into account when drafting the 1997 budget bill.</p>
<p>Ciorbea, whose centrist coalition ousted ex-communists in last November's elections, has pledged tight policies to contain surging deficits and inflation, to boost efforts to put the economy on a free-market footing.</p>
<p>Year-on-year inflation is expected to rise to 97 percent this year against 56.9 percent in 1996, led by fuel price hikes and planned electricity and food price rises. ((  -- Mirela Eremia, Bucharest Newsroom, 40-1 3120264))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
