<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="381810" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africans turn down Taiwanese oil plant plan.</title>
<headline>S.Africans turn down Taiwanese oil plant plan.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African oil and petrochemical companies have turned down an approach by a consortium of Taiwanese companies to build a world scale aromatics plant on the east coast of South Africa.</p>
<p>Speaking on behalf of a group of South African companies approached in August last year by a Taiwanese consortium led by Tuntex, Central Energy Fund spokesman Howard Roberts said in a statement on Monday the proposed plant would not serve local needs.</p>
<p>The local companies approached included AECI, BP, Caltex, Engen, Hoechst SA, Polifin, Sasol, Sentrachem, Shell and Total.</p>
<p>Trade and Industry Minister Alec Erwin last week announced that the proposed project had been ruled out but that others were being considered.</p>
<p>Roberts said that the proposals, for a world scale aromatics plant taking refinery naphtha as feedstock, had been aimed at domestic and export markets.</p>
<p>&quot;(It) included the conversion of about 20 percent of the output to polyester which in turn would be converted into synthetic fibres and fabrics,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was intended that the complex would provide fabrics to a greatly expanded local garment industry.&quot;</p>
<p>The plan had been turned down after extensive meetings with all interested parties, including the Industrial Development Corporation and CEF.</p>
<p>&quot;The private sector companies are all of the view that participation in the proposed project would not serve their interests at present,&quot; Roberts said.</p>
<p>He said their interests presently lay elsewhere. The proposals had also raised several concerns.</p>
<p>&quot;In particular, they feel that the timing is premature on the light of the current needs of the country for fuels and petrochemicals. In addition, world markets are currently in oversupply of aromatics and polyester and are expected to remain so for some years.&quot;</p>
<p>Roberts said that CEF remained interested in evaluating the production of petrochemicals at Mossgas and a number of studies were in progress with the production of aromatics a possibility.</p>
<p>Several South African publications have reported in recent weeks that state oil exploration company Soekor was opposed to tentative suggestions by Mossgas that the oil-from-gas producer could become a fullscale petrochemicals plant.</p>
<p>Soekor has for some time been pressing for Mossgas to become involved in the use of gas from its Bredasdorp fields to help develop an industrial gas pipeline to the Western Cape.</p>
<p>It believes that this will slot in with plans to pipe gas to the Western Cape from the Kudu gas field offshore Namibia, and possibly even extending the network up the east coast to link up with gas piped from the Pande gas field offshore Mozambique.</p>
<p>But Mossgas, which is trying to extend and add value to itself, is toying with the idea of going the petrochemicals route instead.</p>
<p>&quot;We have the feedstocks to go this route, but it is early days yet,&quot; Mossgas spokesman Harry Hill said.</p>
<p>The Financial Mail reported that such a move, which would involve switching current 300,000 tonnes a year output of olefin feedstock which is now being refined into 30,000 barrels a day of synthetic fuel, into petrochemical feedstock.</p>
<p>This would increase profitability as returns on propylene alone could be about 60 percent higher than synfuel production.</p>
<p>Such a switch could involve the building of a new gas-based chemical cracker, which would double olefin output to 600,000 tonnes a year within eight years.</p>
<p>This would also help meet the country's growing demand for plastic feedstock olefins such as etylene.</p>
<p>Hill said that a feasibility study was being conducted into the petrochemicals route and a final decision was expected later this year.</p>
<p>-- Cape Town newsroom +27 21 403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
