<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="381954" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenia shares extend gains, Lek up seven pct.</title>
<headline>Slovenia shares extend gains, Lek up seven pct.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Slovenian SBI index continued rising on Monday, jumping 7.14 percent as investors regained confidence in the market after it became clear the Bank of Slovenia was not blocking foreign trading activity.</p>
<p>&quot;After it became clear at the end of last week that the central bank will not entirely block foreign investment, the market regained confidence,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>The Bank of Slovenia said last Tuesday that international investors would have to open special custody accounts at one of Slovenia's 14 fully licenced banks in order to trade in Slovenian securities.</p>
<p>At a press conference on Friday the bank said the move was simply to regulate not block foreign portfolio investment.</p>
<p>Commercial banks said they would need at least two weeks to set up foreign custody accounts.</p>
<p>&quot;There may be some downward corrections in the next days, but the general trend will remain a growing one as investors believe shares will start growing significantly once foreign buyers return,&quot; said Karmen Cerar of brokerage Poteza.</p>
<p>The 11-share SBI index jumped 97.73 points to 1,467.4.</p>
<p>Overall 14 shares rose, two fell and nine were untraded. Turnover rose to 484.3 million tolars from 419.9 million on Friday.</p>
<p>Drug maker Lek's A issue was the most active share, jumping 7.17 percent to 29,000 tolars on volume of 6,989 shares for total turnover of 203.5 million tolars.</p>
<p>Health resort operator Terme Catez was the top gainer, surging 10.23 percent to 13,900 on volume of 2,955 shares for total turnover of 40.9 million tolars.</p>
<p>Financial consultancy Primofin was the leading decliner, closing 9.03 percent lower at 14,100 on volume of 15 shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
