<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="38215" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fight against California tax measure steps up.</title>
<headline>Fight against California tax measure steps up.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prominent municipal finance professionals in California are mobilising in a bid to defeat a far-reaching ballot measure that would limit the ability of local governments to raise revenues, officials said Thursday.</p>
<p>Bob Giroux, vice president at Nelson Communications, which is coordinating the campaign to defeat Proposition 218, said municipal bond underwriters, bond counsel and other professionals were joining the effort to defeat the measure.</p>
<p>&quot;Word is spreading out across the municipal finance industry,&quot; Giroux said. &quot;They have a legitimate concern with the potential impact of the initiative.&quot;  </p>
<p>Of the measures to appear on the November 5 statewide ballot, Proposition 218 could pose the greatest threat to the finances of local governments, several analysts said.</p>
<p>Proposed by the Howard Jarvis Taxpayers Association, the measure would constrain the ability of local governments to impose fees, assessments and taxes. The measure would apply to all cities, counties, special districts, redevelopment agencies and school districts in the state.</p>
<p>If passed, local taxes would be defined as special taxes or general taxes. New general taxes would require a majority vote and new special taxes would require a two-thirds vote.  </p>
<p>Local governments would also be required to reduce or repeal existing property-related fees and assessments that do not meet the measures's restrictions.</p>
<p>The mostly likely fees and assessments affected by these provisions would be those for park and recreation programs, fire protection, lighting, ambulance, business improvement programs, library, and water service. Statewide, local government revenue reductions probably would exceed $100 million annually, the state's Legislative Analyst estimated.</p>
<p>Giroux said several prominent municipal finance firms in the state were already mobilising to defeat the measure.  </p>
<p>The California Public Securities Association has become a member of the campaign committee working to defeat the proposition, Giroux said.</p>
<p>Underwriter Stone &amp; Youngberg LLC has urged its clients to vote against the measure. In a recent memorandum, the firm told its clients the initiative should be opposed because of the &quot;devastating effect the initiative will immediately have on local government finance&quot; and its potential credit implications for California municipal bonds.</p>
<p>Bond counsel Orrick, Herrington &amp; Sutcliffe said in a separate report that few, if any, local agencies in California would escape some degree of impact. The firm recommended that local agencies analyze the initiative and its potential impacts on their revenue raising and debt issuance practices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
