<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382135" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News-Feb 18.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News-Feb 18.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Under a compromise proposal on industry being discussed by the Department of Industry, Science and Tourism and Federal Treasury, cuts in car tariffs would be slowed down after 2000, with tariffs cut to five per cent by 2010 - rather than 2004, as urged by the Productivity Commission.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In opening the trial that former Coles Myer chief executive Brian Quinn was ordered to stand almost three years ago, Victoria's chief crown prosecutor Paul Coghlan QC told the Supreme Court yesterday greed and excess marked a conspiracy by Quinn, which allegedly involved using more than A$4 million of the retail company's funds for work on his Melbourne home.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard announced yesterday defence will be spared from spending cuts in the up-coming budget, which it is believed, will make it increasingly difficult to make up the A$2 billion short-fall identified last month in the mid-year budget eview. Howard announced the quarantine during his visit to New Zealand where he is pressuring Prime Minister Bolger to purchase two more ANZAC frigates from Australia.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A report by the Rural Industries Research and Development Corporation has found Australia's native bushfood farmers are facing the prospect of an over-supply of stock within the next four or five years if it does not improve on its marketing strategies and reduce prices.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard used a detailed briefing to the New Zealand Cabinet yesterday to issue a strong warning to New Zealand to give defence spending a higher priority. Howard stressed the key role defence policy played in Australia's foreign policy of engagement with Asia, and said defence would be the only area quarantined from cuts in his first two Budgets. --</p>
<p>In an admission that will increase pressure on Federal Transport Minister John Sharp and Prime Minister John Howard, Sharp admitted last night that a report by Dennis Wheelahan QC he was using to justify attempts to dismiss the Civil Aviation Safety Authoity, also criticised his office for its response to safety concerns.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Reluctant to upset China, the Federal Government has called a temporary halt to visits by officials from the Taiwan Government, ahead of Prime Minister John Howard's trip to Beijing next month. Overseas Chinese Affairs Commission vice-chairman Ming Chen-ua was the first Taiwanese official to get the cold shoulder when he failed to get a visa to enter Australia this week.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a claim dismissed as &quot;nonsense&quot; by Phillip Dunn QC, counsel for former chairman and chief executive of Coles Myer, Brian Edward Quinn, prosecutor Paul Coghlan QC told the Victorian Supreme Court Quinn wrongly billed Coles for A$4.5 million of renovatios to his Melbourne house.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Despite the Police Royal Commission identifying flaws in the way the Department of Community Services has handled child protection, the department is to co-ordinate a new code intended to stop buck-passing between Government departments. Under the code, al New South Wales public servants have to report evidence or suspicions of child abuse.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>University of New South Wales vice-chancellor Professor John Niland said yesterday he wants to make it easier to dismiss academics who are found to be lazy or incompetent - he said the current system is cumbersome and legalistic and only sees two or three academics each year being dismissed because of poor performance - in return for a pay rise of 11.45 per cent.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Crown prosecutor Paul Coghlan told the Supreme Court in Melbourne yesterday the case against former Coles Myer chief executive Brian Edward Quinn was one of &quot;greed and excess&quot;. Quinn is accused of conspiring to defraud Coles of almost A$4 million, and Coglan told the court the money was spent on renovations to Quinn's house.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a revelation that prompted Federal Transport Minister John Sharp last night to order a temporary halt to all Federal Airports Corporation work until Friday, enraged members of the Sydney Airport Community Forum claim the FAC has secretly started work tat would allow more jets to use the third runway. --</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Former Coles Myer chief executive Brian Quinn was accused in the Supreme Court yesterday of de-frauding his former company of A$4.6 million and spending it on re-furbishing his Templestowe house. Prosecutor Paul Coghlan QC said Quinn attempted to convince Coles Myer the money was being spent on Coles Myer properties.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Queensland Police Minister Russell Cooper announced yesterday the State Government would issue a A$50,000 reward for the capture of the Arnott's biscuits poisoner. The Arnotts company has already laid off hundreds of workers following police information hat there may be more than one extortionist threatening Arnott's biscuits. .</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Docklands stadium moved one step closer to its inception into the Australian Football League (AFL) after elections for positions on the AFL commission. Docklands proponent Graeme Samuels was re-elected, whilst Tribunal chairman Neil Busse who has criicised a move to the stadium failed in his bid to win one of the four available seats.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>While the cattle toll rose by 14 to 119 with anthrax outbreaks on seven more farms near Tatura, Dr John Auty, a former assistant director of the Australian Bureau of Animal Health, has criticised the handling of the outbreak, saying the quarantine restricions should have been much tighter.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
