<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382173" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia's Ekran to proceed full speed with dam.</title>
<headline>Malaysia's Ekran to proceed full speed with dam.</headline>
<byline>Christina Pantin</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Malaysian court ruled on Monday in favour of the developer of the controversial Bakun hydroelectric dam, a move that should help propel the $5.5 billion project forward.</p>
<p>Malaysia's Appeals Court dismissed a High Court environmental ruling against Ekran Bhd, developer of the dam which has been contested on environmental grounds.</p>
<p>Justice Gopal Sri Ram, who headed a three-member bench, said the Environmental Quality Act referred to by the High Court in its ruling was not applicable because that law was part of the federal constitution while the dam was in the eastern state of Sarawak.</p>
<p>The High Court ruling, which was later suspended, was based on a lawsuit filed by three Sarawak tribespeople who opposed the dam. The plaintiffs said they would appeal Monday's court decision.</p>
<p>Activists who had been among the project's opponents expressed deep disappointment.</p>
<p>&quot;We call on the government, if it is serious about its publicly-stated commitment to environment protection, to make the necessary legislative changes to reverse the effect of today's decision by the Court of Appeal,&quot; a statement from The Coalition of Concerned Non-Governmental Organisations (NGOs) on Bakun said.</p>
<p>The coalition comprises about 40 NGOs.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Ekran's jubilant executive chairman, Ting Pek Khiing, told reporters after the Appeals Court ruling: &quot;The EPC (engineering, procurement and construction) of the project can now go on full swing.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said they were not surprised by the decision. &quot;Knowing this is a national project, most people thought it would be decided in favour of Ekran,&quot; said an equity analyst with a foreign research house.</p>
<p>Another analyst said: &quot;I don't think many people in the market saw this (court ruling) as a big threat to start off with. It's all go now.&quot;</p>
<p>Championed by Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad, the dam has a capacity of 2,400 megawatts and will flood an area the size of Singapore. Construction will clear 69,000 hectares (170,000 acres) of land and displace some 9,000 tribal residents.</p>
<p>Ting said the dam would be completed on schedule by January 2003 &quot;or maybe a year earlier&quot;. Preliminary construction work began at the start of 1997.</p>
<p>Analysts said that although the court victory for Ekran was anticipated, it should make the 1.5-billion-share initial public offering (IPO) for the Bakun Hydro-Electric Corp Bhd, the dam's holding company, more palatable to investors.</p>
<p>The sheer size of the offering and uncertainties about the return on investment from the project had raised doubts about the share sale.</p>
<p>&quot;The great fear on Ekran is that fund managers do not think the listing will be hotly received,&quot; said an institutional equity dealer with a local firm. &quot;This (court ruling) was a side issue.&quot;</p>
<p>Ting tried to allay some of those concerns.</p>
<p>&quot;Profits made by Bakun will be more than enough for the public to invest,&quot; he said. &quot;Profits will come from day one.&quot;</p>
<p>Ekran has already struck a deal with national utility Tenaga Nasional Bhd, which will buy most of the power from Bakun.</p>
<p>Analyst Azlin Aliaf with Caspian Securities said: &quot;With agreement from the court, it clears the way for the IPO. This is quite positive for Ekran.&quot;</p>
<p>($1=2.49 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I1610107">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020011">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
