<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382270" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Netanyahu to testify in corruption investigation.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu to testify in corruption investigation.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli police will question Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Tuesday about alleged government corruption in the short-lived appointment of an attorney-general, his office said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime minister will present testimony tomorrow afternoon,&quot; a spokeswoman in his office said.</p>
<p>Police are investigating allegations by Israel Television that Netanyahu's government named Jerusalem lawyer Roni Bar-On attorney-general last month as part of a deal with a politician on trial for corruption.</p>
<p>Bar-On, a veteran activist in Netanyahu's Likud party, quit 12 hours after taking office amid allegations by jurists and politicians that he was a legal lightweight appointed only because of his loyalty to the prime minister.</p>
<p>The television said religious Shas party leader Aryeh Deri demanded Bar-On get the job in exchange for Shas' support for Netanyahu's accord with the PLO on Israeli troop redeployment from the West Bank town of Hebron last month.</p>
<p>It said Bar-On promised Deri a plea-bargain that would have let Deri continue his political career. The cabinet later approved the Hebron deal with Shas's support.</p>
<p>Netanyahu, Deri and Bar-On have all denied the charges.</p>
<p>Police chief Asaf Hefetz said police were ready to question Netanyahu.</p>
<p>&quot;Surely whenever you question any witness, including the prime minister, you have to prepare the investigation, what questions you want to ask, what his connection is to the investigation,&quot; Hefetz told Israel Radio.</p>
<p>&quot;They (police investigators) have prepared and are ready for this questioning.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked whether the testimony would be taken in one day, Hefetz said: &quot;I hope so but it depends how much time we will have for the investigation. If they need extra time I suppose we will coordinate this with the prime minister's office.&quot;</p>
<p>On Monday police questioned Bar-On, not for the first time, and the head of the Israeli Bar, lawyer Dror Hoter-Yishai.</p>
<p>They have already questioned Deri, Finance Minister Dan Meridor, Justice Minister Tzachi Hanegbi, Jerusalem Mayor Ehud Olmert, Deri's former lawyer Dan Avi-Yitzhak, building contractor and Likud backer David Appel, Israel television journalists and others in the case.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
