<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382241" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta shares drop on blue-chip profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Jakarta shares drop on blue-chip profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta share prices dropped on Monday due to almost across the board profit-taking as the market focused on tin miner Tambang Timah, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Jakarta Composite Index fell 2.71 points, or 0.38 percent, to close at 701.77 points. Losers led gainers by 71 to 32, with 66 counters unchanged. Turnover was 463.3 billion rupiah on a volume of 173.2 million shares.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is most likely to continue consolidating tomorrow. But it might be able to keep the index moving around the 700-points mark,&quot; a broker with European leading bank said.  </p>
<p>Another broker with foreign firm said Tambang Timah could continue to draw attention after partnership details of the huge Busang gold project in East Kalimantan were announced on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is speculation that Timah might not be involved in the Busang gold project,&quot; the broker with Singaporean firm said.</p>
<p>Brokers said the market was waiting for further details to emerge over the Busang gold project. Mines and Energy Minister Ida Bagus Sudjana was expected to hold a news conference on Tuesday at 0300 GMT.</p>
<p>Tambang Timah close 450 rupiah lower at 4,825 rupiah on active volume of 15.8 million shares.  </p>
<p>Bre-X Minerals Ltd said on Monday the company and its Indonesian partners had formed a joint venture with Freeport McMoRan Copper and Gold Inc to develop the property.</p>
<p>It said in a statement faxed to Reuters: &quot;The joint venture will be 45 percent owned by Bre-X, 30 percent by two Indonesian companies and their partners, 10 percent by the Republic of Indonesia and 15 percent by Freeport McMoRan Copper and Gold.&quot;</p>
<p>Profit-takers also targeting telecommunications stocks Indosat and Telkom after rises in both stocks helped the Jakarta index to record an all-time high last week.  </p>
<p>&quot;I believe it has no direct link to the telecommunications pact,&quot; a broker with foreign firm said.</p>
<p>Analysts said that a global pact reached this weekend opened the telecommunications industry to competition but would have no immediate impact on Telkom and Indosat.</p>
<p>&quot;It is going take some time for the whole agrement to come true and the first evidence of it would be in the 1998. Still some time away,&quot; Frederic Thomas, telecommunications analyst with PT Peregrine Sewu Securities, said.  </p>
<p>Telkom fell 25 rupiah to 4,175 rupiah on 1.8 million shares, while Indosat fell 25 rupiah to 7,175 rupiah on 1.1 million shares.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
