<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382271" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel tells state-owned banks to pay dividends.</title>
<headline>Israel tells state-owned banks to pay dividends.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli Finance Minister Dan Meridor has proposed criteria for the state-controlled &quot;arrangement&quot; banks to begin paying dividends to the government, the Treasury said on Monday.</p>
<p>Under the proposals, which were discussed with the heads of the three main banks in government hands, the banks will pay dividends on the sale of non-bank companies they have been forced to sell as part of the government's bank-reform law.</p>
<p>In addition, they will pay dividends on earnings from ongoing activities &quot;as is standard in the international banking system.&quot;</p>
<p>The Treasury said the new policy would cover the years 1996 through 1998. Payouts would be made within three months after the dividends were declared, except in the case of dividends arising from capital gains on the sale of non-bank companies.</p>
<p>The new policy, which must be approved at the banks' annual general meetings, will apply to Bank Hapoalim, Bank Leumi and Israel Discount Bank.</p>
<p>The government holds majority stakes in all three banks after it acquired their shares in the wake of a 1983 bank shares' collapse in what came to be known as the &quot;arrangement&quot;. The law prohibits the government from interfering in day-to-day management of the banks.</p>
<p>The Treasury said Meridor advised the bank heads on the new policy in order to let them implement it without the minister making a directive.</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
