<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382288" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Global telecom pact must first stand test of time.</title>
<headline>Global telecom pact must first stand test of time.</headline>
<byline>Mary Kelleher</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. telecommunications companies hailed a ground-breaking pact to open most of the world's $600 billion telecommunications market but industry analysts were more cautious, saying benefits would be longer-term.</p>
<p>&quot;This global pact holds much promise for deregulated markets and offers huge opportunities, but we must be careful not to expect too much too soon,&quot; said Jeffrey Kagan, an industry analyst at Kagan Telecommunications Association.</p>
<p>Under the auspices of the World Trade Organisation, officials from 68 countries clinched the deal late on Saturday at the end of over three years of tortuous negotiations.</p>
<p>U.S. Trade Representative Designate Charlene Barshefsky hailed the trade agreement, saying it would open new markets for U.S. firms, lower costs to consumers and double or triple the size of the $600 billion-a-year industry over the decade.</p>
<p>While a slew of U.S. companies praised the pact, telecommunications specialist Kagan warned concrete benefits could be a while in coming.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a global version of what we did last year with the Telecommunications Act of 1996,&quot; Kagan said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Telecommunications Act of 1996, enacted in February of last year, ripped down decades of legal barriers and encouraged domestic local and long-distance carriers, cable-TV operators, electric utilities and others to invade each other's b ackyards in terms of offering services.</p>
<p>Some industry analysts say that one year later, the act has drummed up more hype than competition.</p>
<p>Kagan said, &quot;The devil is in the details and for awhile, the only ones making money will be the lawyers.&quot;</p>
<p>Two other analysts also said they needed more time to study the details of the pact.</p>
<p>This pact on basic telecommunications would for the first time bring services such as satellite systems, cellular phones, data transmission and paging under the World Trade Organisation.</p>
<p>Barshefsky said before the pact, only 17 percent of the top telecommunications markets were open to U.S. companies.</p>
<p>Now, she said, companies would have access to nearly all of those markets.</p>
<p>Big companies with international clout, like AT&amp;T Corp. MCI Communications Corp., British Telecommunications Plc, Sprint Corp., and regional telephone company BellSouth Corp. would benefit first, Kagan said.</p>
<p>&quot;We might also see some more alliances with natural partners, like the UK, Germany and France,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>U.S. callback services, which let customers make international phone calls via another country with cheaper charges, might benefit short-term, but would lose popularity over time as telephone rates dropped, Kagan said.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T, the No. 1 U.S. long distance company, welcomed the pact, saying it would like to see telecommunications markets in other countries become as open as the United States.</p>
<p>But AT&amp;T spokeswoman Susan Fleming also said the pact would probably not dramatically alter the company's strategy, because it already was and would remain active abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think one agreement is going to make us change our course,&quot; she said. &quot;Certainly this agreement helps but it doesn't necessarily change our strategy.&quot;</p>
<p>Foreign firms would have trouble luring U.S. callers away from their domestic telephone service providers, Kagan said.</p>
<p>&quot;If we provide world class service and continue to stay technologically up to date, then the domestic companies can protect their customer base,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>MCI, the second largest U.S. long distance carrier, said it would work with the Federal Communications Commission to develop regulatory safeguards to ensure U.S. industry could compete effectively at home while taking advantage of opportunities abroad.</p>
<p>U.S. companies said they looked forward to a lowering of rates charged by other countries to carry a call within their borders.</p>
<p>&quot;We would like to pay the actual cost of the call, plus some profit,&quot; Fleming said &quot;Now, many countries have been charging very high rates.&quot;</p>
<p>Sprint said it was excited by the opportunities the pact offered, in that more than 60 of the most important coutnries committed to open their telecommunications market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
