<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382308" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Albright warmer in style than substance in France.</title>
<headline>Albright warmer in style than substance in France.</headline>
<byline>Alister Doyle</byline>
<dateline>PARIS</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright, kissed by French leaders and chatting in French, warmed the tone but not the substance of Washington's often stormy relations with France Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;What do you want to know? It was good,&quot; Albright told reporters in French after a 90-minute meeting with President Jacques Chirac which officials said covered NATO enlargement and reform, the Middle East, China and Africa.</p>
<p>She later said her talks in Paris had shown &quot;how close the relationship is with our oldest ally,&quot; but added: &quot;There are sometimes disagreements between brothers and sisters.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. and French officials made clear there was no progress in substance either on France's call for Washington to hand over the alliance's southern command, controlling the Mediterranean, to a European, or on Chirac's idea for a five-power summit to overcome Russian hostility to the enlargement of NATO.</p>
<p>U.S. officials said Albright told Chirac she wanted to turn over a new page in the relationship, strained by disputes last year over NATO, Africa, the United Nations and the Middle East.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States is very respectful of the European defense identity in NATO. We'd like to see France integrated into NATO and would like to see all the issues resolved amicably,&quot; Albright said.</p>
<p>French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette, determined to make a good start with his new counterpart after a bittersweet farewell to her predecessor, Warren Christopher, kissed Albright four times when she arrived at the Elysee presidential palace.</p>
<p>For good measure, Chirac kissed her hand on the way out.</p>
<p>Presidential spokeswoman Catherine Colonna said France was still weighing the idea of a &quot;big five&quot; summit to help overcome Russian hostility to NATO's eastward expansion, despite U.S. reluctance and anger among smaller allies like Italy.</p>
<p>Asked about the French idea, a U.S. official said bluntly: &quot;It's not moving ahead.&quot;</p>
<p>The official also said: &quot;There's no progress on AFSOUTH&quot; -- NATO jargon for the Naples-based southern European command.</p>
<p>Chirac told Albright that Paris would consider returning to the alliance's military command, which it quit in 1966 in protest at U.S. domination, if the current reforms allowed the creation of a real European defense pillar in NATO.</p>
<p>But de Charette suggested the issue might be postponed until after a key alliance summit in Madrid in July.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a debate. If we achieve it, that's good. If we don't achieve it, then we will pursue it later,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On a first, nine-nation, trip since taking office, Albright was keen to make a new start with the French, who often resent what they see as America's &quot;velvet hegemony&quot; in the world.</p>
<p>The new secretary spoke in French at a memorial ceremony for the late U.S. Ambassador Pamela Harriman, who died in Paris this month, and conducted part of the meeting with Chirac in French.</p>
<p>On the key aim of her 11-day tour -- the enlargement of NATO to admit former Communist central and east European countries -- Paris and Washington are in broad agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;France and the United States are marching down the road together toward Madrid,&quot; Albright said.</p>
<p>They agree the Madrid summit should invite a first wave of former Warsaw Pact countries to become members of the Western alliance. But France wants Romania added to Poland, the Czech Republic, Hungary and possibly Slovenia as candidates for that first wave.</p>
<p>In Bonn earlier, Albright also found broad agreement with Germany on plans to persuade Moscow to accept NATO enlargement.</p>
<p>But German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel said Bonn remained interested in the French idea of a five-nation mini-summit on NATO expansion to smoothe Russian acceptance.</p>
<p>The allies agree that Russia cannot have a veto over NATO membership or future European security arrangements, but France is more sympathetic to Moscow's demand for binding commitments in a charter on future ties to the West.</p>
<p>Albright, due to visit NATO headquarters in Brussels on Tuesday, was most positive to France on the Middle East.</p>
<p>Saying Washington wanted to see more progress between Israel and Syria and Lebanon, she said: &quot;It's useful if others of President Chirac's stature can put a shoulder to the wheel.&quot;</p>
<p>Washington and Israel spent the latter part of 1996 trying to keep Chirac's shoulder off the wheel after he demanded a European role as co-sponsor of the Middle East peace process.</p>
<p>Albright and Chirac also discussed the war in crumbling Zaire and the Great Lakes region of central Africa.</p>
<p>Colonna said Chirac warned of possible &quot;grave consequences&quot; if borders were called into question in central Africa.</p>
<p>Paris and Washington have backed different sides in the conflict but have moved closer together in the last two weeks in opposing foreign intervention in Zaire and in coordinating their separate plans for an inter-African peace-keeping force.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
