<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382401" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's coalition plays down Congress threat.</title>
<headline>India's coalition plays down Congress threat.</headline>
<byline>Nelson Graves</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's governing coalition on Monday shrugged off a warning by the Congress party, on which it depends for survival, and said the former ruling party could not afford to withdraw its support and force mid-term polls.</p>
<p>Congress sent the warning late on Sunday to Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda ahead of a budget meeting of parliament, telling his centre-left government not to take its support for granted.</p>
<p>Deve Gowda's 13-party coalition does not include the Congress party but depends for its support to survive in parliament.</p>
<p>The Congress Working Committee (CWC), the party's main policymaking body, issued a statement accusing the United Front (UF) minority coalition of failing to work with it to fight against the Hindu nationalist opposition.</p>
<p>&quot;The CWC resolves that Congress support to UF henceforth would be based on issues and not unconditional,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The strongly-worded statement, issued nine months after Deve Gowda took power, revived the spectre of mid-term elections.</p>
<p>&quot;Now there is a shift and change,&quot; Congress spokesman Vithal Gadgil said. &quot;They (United Front) cannot take us for granted. From now on our support will be issue-based.&quot;</p>
<p>The United Front coalition, which took power in June following inconclusive general polls, controls 178 votes in the 545-seat lower house of parliament, or Lok Sabha.</p>
<p>It needs the 142 votes held by Congress and its allies to muster a majority. The Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) and its allies have 194 votes, also short of a majority but the biggest contingent in parliament.</p>
<p>Asked if Congress planned to pull down the government, Gadgil said: &quot;We want to convey to them, 'Don't take us for granted.' We are not afraid of elections.&quot;</p>
<p>But the United Front, which assumed power after Congress suffered its worst electoral defeat, dismissed the threat.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is absolutely confident,&quot; a senior United Front leader who asked not to be named told Reuters. &quot;Congress is uncomfortable this government is surviving with their support. They are in no position to go to the polls.&quot;</p>
<p>United Front spokesman Amitabh Adhar said Congress could ill afford to withdraw its support after suffering a setback this month in assembly elections in Punjab state.</p>
<p>The BJP and its local pro-Sikh ally won a resounding victory in Punjab, forcing an end to five years of Congress rule in the state.</p>
<p>&quot;This is no occasion for Congress to say, 'We are going to withdraw support',&quot; Adhar told Reuters.</p>
<p>BJP spokesman Krishan Lal Sharma said Deve Gowda might have to face a no-confidence vote during the budget session of parliament starting on Thursday. &quot;A no-confidence motion is not ruled out,&quot; the Press Trust of India quoted Sharma as saying.</p>
<p>But the BJP official said Congress did not appear ready to withdraw support from Deve Gowda. &quot;The Congress only wants to hang a sword and keep up pressure tactics,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Until Sunday's hour meeting of its policymaking body, Congress had extended unconditional support to Deve Gowda.</p>
<p>But tensions between the government and Congress have mounted since Sitaram Kesri took charge of the party in September after former prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao, charged in three criminal cases, gave up the leadership post.</p>
<p>United Front spokesman Adhar said Congress was in an &quot;uncomfortable situation&quot; as several of its leaders including Rao, who has denied any wrongdoing, were under investigation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
