<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382573" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British government set to survive crunch vote.</title>
<headline>British government set to survive crunch vote.</headline>
<byline>Paul Mylrea</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister John Major looked certain to survive a Monday night opposition vote designed to push him into a snap election after a minority party crucial to the government's hopes said the bid could not succeed.</p>
<p>But the reputation of his battered government took another blow when his farm minister admitted the mad cow disease crisis had cost Britain 3.5 billion pounds ($5.68 billion) so far.</p>
<p>Major's hopes of surviving Monday's vote, scheduled for around 2200 GMT, centre on winning support from Ulster Unionist members of parliament from Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>John Taylor, deputy leader of the Ulster Unionists, denied that Major had offered concessions to win the party's votes.</p>
<p>But he told the BBC he was convinced the government would survive the vote. &quot;I think they (Labour) have handled this very badly and I think everyone is now recognising that the Labour Party is doomed to defeat this evening,&quot; Taylor said.</p>
<p>Monday's vote is on a Labour call to censure Agriculture Minister Douglas Hogg for his handling of the crisis caused by last year's government admission that mad cow disease, or bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE), could be transmitted to humans.</p>
<p>But Labour's real objective is to trigger a confidence vote which if he lost, would force Major to call an election.</p>
<p>With Labour rising high in opinion polls -- the latest published on Sunday gave it an 18 point lead over the ruling Conservatives, up one point from a month earlier -- the party's leader, Tony Blair, wants an election as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Major is keen to hold on as long as possible.</p>
<p>But although the election deadline is not until May, Major's hopes of hanging on are complicated by the fact he has lost his overall parliamentary majority, increasing his reliance on the Ulster Unionists and the influence of rebels in his own party.</p>
<p>The Conservatives have 323 voting members in the lower House of Commons, exactly the same as the combined opposition parties. But even if all opposition MPs vote against the government, the speaker's casting vote would ensure Major's survival.</p>
<p>Blair admitted on Sunday the odds were stacked against his party, but he said he still hoped to embarrass the government.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident that we will win the argument. Winning the vote will be more difficult,&quot; Blair wrote in the Express newspaper.</p>
<p>Labour was hammering home the point on Monday, with deputy leader John Prescott delivering a mock cheque to the ministry of agriculture to highlight the cost of the crisis.</p>
<p>But Hogg, trying to draw the sting, admitted the cost had reached 3.5 billion pounds, higher than previous estimates.</p>
<p>Hogg also rejected suggestions from farmers that he should have quit over his handling of the crisis, telling a BBC radio interviewer: &quot;I'm not a resigning character.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain claimed it won agreement at last June's European Union summit for a gradual lifting of the ban after agreeing to measures including slaughtering thousands of older cows.</p>
<p>But delays in getting the cull going has meant there has been little progress in lifting the export ban and an easing of the European embargo is still months away at the earliest, angering farmers, traditionally core Conservative supporters. ($1=.6167 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
