<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="38266" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FORECAST - UK PPI to sound no inflation alarms.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - UK PPI to sound no inflation alarms.</headline>
<byline>Merissa Marr</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>British producer prices will continue to display no signs of pipeline inflationary pressures in August, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>A Reuter poll of economists forecast unchanged output prices in July, leaving them 2.0 percent higher than a year ago. Seasonally adjusted input prices are seen 0.3 percent higher on the month, leaving them 2.2 percent lower year-on-year. &quot;The good inflation news seen from the start of the year looks set to last for some time yet,&quot; said Philip Shaw, group economist at Union Plc.</p>
<p>The data are due at 0830 GMT on Monday.</p>
<p>Economists said attention would focus on the output price figures which revealed a fall of 0.1 percent in the core measure in July for the first time since 1973, while the annual rate of 1.5 percent was the lowest recorded since November 1967.</p>
<p>Falling raw material costs and slower unit wage cost growth will continue to depress core output price inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;With upstream price pressures still weak and manufacturing only just starting to recover, further declines in output price inflation seem likely,&quot; said economists at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>On the input price side, economists said the hefty declines seen in recent months may well now be over. But with the year-on-year rate still well in negative territory, that will hardly constitute an inflation risk.</p>
<p>&quot;Commodity prices have troughed, the oil price is firmer and manufacturers are now under less pressure to discount excess stock,&quot; said the Deutsche Morgan Grenfell analysts.</p>
<p>Economists discounted the effect of movements in oil prices, following U.S. missile attacks on Iraq, on input prices. &quot;Oil prices were on a rising trend anyway, registering a near five percent increase in sterling terms during August,&quot; Shaw said.</p>
<p>Signs from recent data that the manufacturing sector could be past the worst will not derail the prevailing low inflation trend this year, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;The ratio of stocks to output remains at high levels and competitive pressures in the sector remain strong,&quot; Shaw said.</p>
<p>Simon Briscoe, UK economist at Nikko Europe, said Thursday's report from the Confederation of British Industry, which revealed a surge in British retail activity, was not a cause for concern for producer price inflation either.</p>
<p>Briscoe pointed to the wholesalers component which revealed that the orders and business outlook had not improved at all over the last six months.</p>
<p>&quot;If you find that wholesalers aren't benefitting yet from the pick-up in retail demand then manufacturers are one step further back down the train,&quot; Briscoe said.</p>
<p>The CBI said retail sales volume rose again in August and the balance of firms reporting an increase in business was the largest since November 1988.</p>
<p>Briscoe added that manufacturing output, out on Friday, was unchanged in the quarter to July versus the previous quarter and was 0.1 percent lower than in the same quarter a year ago.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom, +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
