<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382799" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Helsinki sags on soft Nokia, but forestries rally.</title>
<headline>Helsinki sags on soft Nokia, but forestries rally.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Banks and forestries lifted shares overall in healthy trade on Monday but Nokia fell on continued profit-taking, dragging the index, brokers said.</p>
<p>The general HEX index fell 0.11 percent to close at 2,863.4 points though advancing issues beat decliners by 58 to 35. Volume was a robust 700 million markka despite U.S. holiday.</p>
<p>Telecoms group Nokia closed at 308.20 markka, down 6.80 compared to its close in Helsinki on Friday but only a shade off its New York close which corresponded to 308.61 markka.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a lot of hot money in the share around its 1996 earnings report (on Thursday), with speculation driving it up. I think it will stabilise at these levels,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>The forestry sub-index added 2.21 percent with gains in most shares, but Finland's largest forestry group UPM-Kymmene failed to stay at the new 107.80 life-high it set in the afternoon and closed 2.50 markka lower at 100.00. The strong dollar boosted Finnish and Swedish paper stocks, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the strong dollar,&quot; one broker said. &quot;There's been news about falling prices so it's got to be the dollar.&quot;</p>
<p>Chemicals and fertiliser group Kemira rose briefly after it reported in-line 1996 earnings but also failed to stay in positive territory, closing down 0.40 at 72.00 markka.</p>
<p>Merita advanced another three percent to new record ground, ending at 18.70 markka, and the B share with preferred dividend rights hit 20.00 with positive sentiment partly imported from Sweden. &quot;The merger mania across the gulf (in Sweden) is boosting interest in Merita,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Swedbank and Foreningsbanken announced merger talks and Handelbanken finalised a takover of Stadshypotek.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
