<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382715" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli minister says will visit China next week.</title>
<headline>Israeli minister says will visit China next week.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign Minister David Levy, who forged Israel's ties with China five years ago, said on Monday he would return to Beijing next week for an official visit.</p>
<p>&quot;Next week I will visit Beijing,&quot; he told reporters after signing a customs agreement in Jerusalem with Chinese Vice-Premier Li Lanqing.</p>
<p>In January 1992 China, eager to play a Middle East peace role, became the last of the U.N. Security Council's five permanent members to establish ties with Israel.</p>
<p>Israel, which in the past had complained of Chinese arms sales to Arab states at war with it, received a promise from Li that China would do nothing to jeopardise the Jewish state's safety, Levy said.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we received a guarantee that China will not do anything that could harm the security of the state of Israel or its interests. We are very satisfied from this important announcement,&quot; Levy said.</p>
<p>Israel Foreign Ministry spokesman Ygal Palmor said: &quot;This is a cooperation-in-customs agreement. It is a document which establishes a framework for cooperation between the two offices responsible for customs.&quot;</p>
<p>He said this was the highest ranking visit of a Chinese official since October 1994. &quot;The significance is quite clear. It reflects the level of economic cooperation between the two countries,&quot; Palmor said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
