<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382775" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fourth spacewalk for U.S. shuttle crew.</title>
<headline>Fourth spacewalk for U.S. shuttle crew.</headline>
<byline>Steven Young</byline>
<dateline>JOHNSON SPACE CENTRE, Texas 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spacewalking astronauts worked on the Hubble Space Telescope for a fourth night on Monday as NASA engineers hurried to finalise plans to patch up the telescope's peeling, sunburned skin.</p>
<p>Astronauts Greg Harbaugh and Joe Tanner began the fourth spacewalk of the mission at 10:50 p.m. EST on Sunday (0350 GMT Monday), while on Discovery's middeck pilot Scott Horowitz prepared to fabricate makeshift sunshields for the telescope's damaged insulation.</p>
<p>NASA officials on Sunday added an extra spacewalk to Discovery's 10-day flight to make repair to the reflective silvery foil. There were concerns that crucial electronic components could overheat if nothing was done before the shuttle's next servicing call.</p>
<p>Engineers suspected that the cracks and rips in the material were caused by harsh ultraviolet radiation from the sun.</p>
<p>Harbaugh and Tanner were to patch-up two long tears in the foil during a six-hour spacewalk, but first they were to complete their planned servicing tasks.</p>
<p>They successfully installed a European-built electronic device to control the observatory's solar arrays and then headed up the telescope to install covers on two magnetic sensors.</p>
<p>While the astronauts worked overhead, engineers on the ground hurried to finalise plans to construct makeshift patches to cover four torn and tattered areas on Hubble's sun-facing side.</p>
<p>With limited supplies aboard the shuttle, Horowitz was cautioned not to start the work until engineers were sure they had thought of everything.</p>
<p>&quot;We are using up absolutely everything we have and if we get something cut the wrong length then we will have done a bad thing,&quot; astronaut Jeff Hoffman warned from mission control.</p>
<p>Ground controllers faxed the crew five pages of instructions and 14 diagrams to show them how to build sunshields from spare insulating foil, electrical wire, ropes, cords, alligator clips and wrap ties, using sissors, wire cutter, crimp tools and sticky tape.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the middeck to look as neat as your garage,&quot; Hoffman joked.</p>
<p>Discovery crewmen Mark Lee and Steve Smith were due to make an unscheduled three or four-hour outing into the space on Monday night to complete repairs to the telescope's foil insulation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHNSON SPACE CENTRE, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
