<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382862" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Weaker Swiss franc boosts prospects for exporters.</title>
<headline>Weaker Swiss franc boosts prospects for exporters.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Export-dependent Swiss companies clearly stand to gain from the weaker Swiss franc in 1997 and 1998, financial analysts said, but the picture is blurred by a shift of jobs abroad and a mixed outlook for customer demand.</p>
<p>&quot;If exchange rates remain at their current levels until the end of the year, 1997 currency gains are likely to be around nine percent, which would represent an historic high,&quot; Bank Julius Baer said in its latest Market View Switzerland report.</p>
<p>&quot;By continuing its policy of low interest rates, the Swiss National Bank obviously intends to stabilise the Swiss franc at its current level,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>The SNB's easier monetary policy has corrected by around half the franc's 17 percent nominal appreciation against the 15 major trading currencies between 1993 and 1995, it noted.</p>
<p>It cited Danzas, Hilti, Michelin, Nestle and Oerlikon-Buehrle as companies poised to gain. It identified Ascom, Bobst, Clariant and SMH as attractive.</p>
<p>But Baer noted the strong Swiss franc accelerated structural changes in Swiss companies, which moved jobs abroad, turned more to foreign suppliers and invested heavily to boost productivity.</p>
<p>It pointed out Swiss companies created or acquired around 250,000 new jobs abroad in 1990 to 1995, while 40,000 jobs were cut in Switzerland.</p>
<p>&quot;There is now a risk that the recent weakness of the Swiss franc will not bring about the significant economic recovery that the Swiss government is already forecasting for mid-1997 and the SNB for 1998,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Neither will past currency losses be converted into the equivalent curreny gains.&quot;</p>
<p>It estimated that Swiss industrial companies for which reliable figures are available produce around 20 percent of their global sales of 245 billion francs in Switzerland. Of this, two-thirds is exported, so only around 13 percent of their turnover represents export sales to other countries.</p>
<p>Exports also rely on imported components and commodities, partially eroding currency gains.</p>
<p>Baer revised its overall earnings estimates up by around 5.0 percent for 1997 and 5.1 percent for 1998. It gave these percentage earnings revisions:</p>
<p> Company	  1997    1998     Company	  1997   1998</p>
<p> Mikron	    29	34	Kuehne&amp;Nagel    11	12</p>
<p> SMH		 17	18	Michelin	  12	12</p>
<p> Bobst		5	17	Nokia-Maillefer 12	12</p>
<p> Micronas	  11	14	Tecan	     12	12</p>
<p> Clariant	  14	13	Zellweger	 15	12</p>
<p> Holderbank	 9	13	Ascom	     12	11</p>
<p> Oerlikon-Buehrle 8	13	LEM		 12	11</p>
<p> Suedelektra     13	13	Nestle	    11	11</p>
<p> Zur. Ziegeleien 12	13	Hilti	     10	 9</p>
<p> Belimo	    12	12	Phonak	    10	 9</p>
<p>Geneva-based Pictet &amp; Cie said Swiss business welcomed the franc's depreciation. &quot;The reasons for this are understandable as there is virtually no other economy in the world that is so dependent on its export trade as Switzerland's.&quot;</p>
<p>It said the mechanical engineering sector exports around 70 percent of its output, with over half of foreign sales going to Germany, France, Italy, the U.S. and Britain, whose currencies have risen at least five to 10 percent this year from 1996.</p>
<p>But in judging the prospects for electrical and mechanical engineering companies plus selected industrials, it concluded that the economic situation and market structures are more meaningful than just exchange rates.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not seeking to deny the influence of the Swiss franc on exports. There is no doubt that a weaker Swiss franc helps to alleviate price presure. This should be seen, however, as as short-term phenomenon,&quot; it said in an equities strategy report.</p>
<p>Currencies are important where Swiss companies compete head to head with foreign rivals offering similar products, it said, but it noted that many companies were able to boost profit margins across the board even in times of recession.</p>
<p>&quot;This illusatrates the point yet again that productivity gains have to be viewed as more influential that pure currency considerations,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Its preferred stocks remain ABB, Sulzer, Saurer, Agie, Esec and Oerlikon-Buehrle.</p>
<p>-- Michael Shields, Zurich newsroom +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32752">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32754">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32840">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34350">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
