<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382818" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: FOCUS-Analysts forecast NCC to buy Siab.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Analysts forecast NCC to buy Siab.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish construction group NCC could be about to buy Siab which prompted a suspension in the two companies' and Lundbergs' shares on Monday, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The most likely thing is that NCC will buy Siab, even if the size of the company makes it hard to swallow,&quot; an analyst said. &quot;NCC is likely to pay with its own shares.&quot;</p>
<p>After announcing the trading suspension on Monday, the Stockholm bourse said more information on the deal would be released on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm a bit surprised that NCC is doing this,&quot; another analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;This makes them almost too dominant in Sweden and in the Nordic area but their balance sheet is strong and they can handle the deal. Maybe they'll partly with their own shares.&quot;</p>
<p>Siab's market capitalisation amounts to about two billion crowns while NCC is valued at 6.8 billion crowns.</p>
<p>An issue dividing analysts is whether Lundbergs, which is the main shareholder in Siab, will remain in the new company.</p>
<p>Lundbergs holds 48.3 percent in Siab, while the Lundberg family in total controls Siab with 49.6 percent of capital.</p>
<p>&quot;I have difficulty in seeing that Lundbergs is interested in attempting to get a power position in the new company. With NCC's current ownership structure it is hard to get power in the company,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>Nordstjernan, the key holding company in the Ax:son Johnson family's financial empire, holds 45 percent of capital and 68 percent of votes in NCC.</p>
<p>An alternative is that Nordstjernan and Lundbergs each take a part of the shares in the new company.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not sure that NCC will buy Siab. It could also be a merger where Nordstjernan and Lundbergs share the shares,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>Swedbank's fund company Robur could also play an important part in the deal as it has power in all three companies.</p>
<p>Robur owns 23 percent of Siab's equity and 20 percent of its votes, while holding 15 percent of Lundbergs' equity and four percent of its votes. It also holds eight percent of capital in NCC and five percent of votes.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that Robur surely has been a key player in this deal. The value of the new company will be higher than what operations are valued at today,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>The new company would get a dominating position in both Sweden and the Nordic area as NCC is currently is the largest construction company in the Nordic region.</p>
<p>Several analysts speculated the new company will be divided into a construction part and a real estate part.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible that you will try to separate the real estate holdings in a separate company and list them. (The new company) will get a bit too big otherwise,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe they will also include Lundbergs' real estate in the company.&quot;</p>
<p>Siab's real estate holdings were booked at 4.4 billion crowns in its six-month report, while NCC's real estate holdings were booked at 13.1 billion crowns in late September.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1018</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
