<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382813" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany's Stoiber-Prodi didn't urge EMU softening.</title>
<headline>Germany's Stoiber-Prodi didn't urge EMU softening.</headline>
<byline>Clifford Coonan</byline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's prime minister Romano Prodi, visiting Germany for the second time in 11 days, on Monday emphasised his nation would be ready to join Europe's currency union in 1999 and expected to be allowed in.</p>
<p>Prodi's meetings in Munich with Bavaria's premier Edmund Stoiber and later in Frankfurt with German business leaders were aimed at convincing Europe that Italy, better known for inflationary policies, was set on mending its fiscal ways.</p>
<p>&quot;I fully trust the fact that Italy will be ready for next spring. I won't ask for any delay of Italy's EMU entry,&quot; Prodi said at a news conference in Munich.</p>
<p>This year will be critical for nations wishing to join the currency union in 1999 as it will be their last chance to show budget deficit and government debt ratios meet the strict Maastricht Treaty entry criteria.</p>
<p>Political leaders will choose the first group of nations to adopt the new currency early next year, and it is largely expected that Germany along with France, the Netherlands, Belgium and Luxembourg as well as a few others the first.</p>
<p>And as time is running out to convince those leaders that Italy will be ready, Prodi hinted at earlier suggestions from German officials that Italy's membership could endanger the new currency, euro.</p>
<p>&quot;Italy is a country that, unlike Germany, is totally in favour of the euro. I am not here to discuss Maastricht criteria, we need to get out of uncertainty and Germany too needs to get certainty.&quot;</p>
<p>He also stressed that Italy, unlike Germany, was making more progress in tackling its current problems.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a difference between Italy and Germany. We have economic problems and I have prepare a strategy to solve them,&quot; Prodi told Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>Germany, posting its highest unemployment level since the 1930s, appears to have fallen into a crisis as the government focuses on saving to meet the political goal of currency union rather than tackling economic problems, like high unemployment.</p>
<p>&quot;Germany has more political problems than economic problems,&quot; Prodi said, adding, &quot;if Germany wanted it could exercise the political leadership which is needed now.&quot;</p>
<p>Stoiber, who has been very vocal in insisting that any monetary union must be strong and stable, said, &quot;I welcome the fact that Prodi told me he wanted to stick to the criteria for EMU entry.&quot;</p>
<p>Stoiber had earlier voiced doubts about Italy's ability to do make the entry grade for EMU.</p>
<p>In a television interview earlier this month, Stoiber said accepting creative accounting to allow countries to join EMU meant that &quot;we'll never succeed in having the Italians and the Spanish and the Portuguese (keep to) a strict application of the stability criteria.&quot;</p>
<p>Senior bankers have recently warned of turmoil in the financial markets if Mediterranean countries like Italy, whose currencies have been less stable than the mark, were allowed to help launch the euro.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
