<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382889" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Eduscho, Melitta cool on latest KJS coffee move.</title>
<headline>Eduscho, Melitta cool on latest KJS coffee move.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>German coffee roasters Eduscho GmbH &amp; Co KG and Melitta Kaffee GmbH said on Monday they had no immediate plans to match a possible second round of retail price rises by market leader Kraft Jacobs Suchard (KJS).</p>
<p>&quot;There will probably have to be further price hikes to reflect higher costs at Eduscho (GmbH &amp; Co KG),&quot; said a spokesman at the Bremen-based company. &quot;But at the moment there are no concrete plans.&quot;</p>
<p>He pointed out Eduscho had raised the price of one of its key brands, Milde Natur, which accounts for more than half its sales, by one mark per 0.5 kg on February 3.</p>
<p>Melitta Kaffee GmbH took a similar line.</p>
<p>&quot;The initial price rise (by two marks per kilo, effective March 10 and announced on February 7) has not yet been implemented, we know it will probably not be sufficient but we've got nothing else to say at the moment,&quot; a spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will study how the March 10 price rise will go down with the consumer and what the competition does.&quot;</p>
<p>KJS, part of Philip Morris, said on Friday that it might add another two marks to already planned increases of two marks per kilo ex-works, effective March 10.</p>
<p>KJS aims for a 30 percent market share while Eduscho put its share at 11 percent last December and Melitta last year gave a 12 percent figure.</p>
<p>Roasters say they have been hit by higher raw materials costs and dollar firmness.</p>
<p>Alois Dallmayr Kaffee oHG and J.J. Darboven, which account for perhaps another 15 percent of the market, said on Friday they would fully match any new KJS move.</p>
<p>Tchibo said last Friday it had no immediate plans to add to already announced price rises of one mark per kilo across 60 percent of its product range as of February 27.</p>
<p>Tchibo and Eduscho are tied depot roasters with a combined market share of about 30 percent.</p>
<p>--Hamburg newsroom +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42390">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
