<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382985" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares ease, seen rising on Tuesday.</title>
<headline>Polish shares ease, seen rising on Tuesday.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares eased in stable turnover on Monday but analysts said strong buying after price-fixing and rises in continuous trade signalled they looked strong enough to rise on Tuesday to a new 35-month high.</p>
<p>The main market's WIG index fell 0.3 percent, to 18,122.3, and turnover eased 1.3 percent to 257.6 million zlotys ($85.9 million) on both markets as 48 issues fell, 23 rose and 17 were flat.</p>
<p>Analysts said the bourse's 36.4-percent growth since mid-December was attracting new investors, joining those already playing on the market, in expectations of further rises.</p>
<p>&quot;The growth causes an inflow of additional capital and additional investors who want to use the growth to earn, too,&quot; said Cezary Markiewicz, an analyst at Bank Gdanski brokerage.</p>
<p>Some analysts said, however, that a profit-taking correction might hit the market in the next few sessions, but were not sure where the WIG index would find resistance before falling and how deep the correction would be.</p>
<p>Analysts said Monday's news that January's consumer price growth of 2.9 percent, bringing year-on-year inflation down to 18.1 percent, was within expectations and was unlikely to move the market, which expects interest rates to remain unchanged.</p>
<p>Some analysts said the bourse's expected growth might also be helped by companies' January earnings reports due on Monday and Tuesday, which they said should prove good.</p>
<p>Continuous trade turnover amounted to 17.5 million zlotys ($5.8 million) with the WIG 20 index closing at 1,891.4 points, 0.9 percent higher than at the regular session.</p>
<p>The biggest main market loser, pharmaceuticals firm Jelfa, plunged 9.6 percent to 71 zlotys ($23.7) in moderate trade after the company on Friday priced its new share issue at 65 zlotys ($21.7) each, traders said.</p>
<p>But they could not explain the 10-percent surge by the session's top gainer, electromagnetic transmitter maker Relpol.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
