<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="382974" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak govt seeks quick sale of fridge maker Calex.</title>
<headline>Slovak govt seeks quick sale of fridge maker Calex.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Slovak government hopes to complete the sale of state-owned home appliance producer Calex s.p. by April, a senior official said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are currently negotiating with four companies interested in buying Calex, three of which are foreign,&quot; Frantisek Kubica, head of the Economic Ministry's engineering department, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We really need a quick solution. Ideally, the matter should be completed by the end of April this year.&quot;</p>
<p>He would not disclose the names of the bidders.</p>
<p>Kubica said the ministry would seek to sell the entire 100 percent it holds in Calex in one deal. &quot;It would not be good to split the company into lots of pieces with different owners,&quot; Kubica said.</p>
<p>The book value of the company is some six billion crowns, but the ministry said the final price would depend on the production programme a buyer would propose.</p>
<p>&quot;If they introduce a perspective programme ensuring no radical layoffs, the price will, of course, be lower,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>South Korea's Samsung Electronics Co Ltd cancelled its prepurchase right for Calex last November, saying it was no longer interested in producing white goods, Kubica said.</p>
<p>&quot;We accepted Samsung's withdrawal, but on condition that it would sell its stake in the joint-venture with Calex to the state,&quot; he said, adding that Samsung had accepted this.</p>
<p>In 1991, Samsung and Calex formed a joint-venture to manufacture refrigerators and freezers in which the South Korean firm holds a 44.8 percent stake. Samsung originally wanted to buy Calex outright.</p>
<p>Calex was forced to suspend production for one week on February 10 due to liquidity problems. It had to postpone payment of January wages for its 2,400 employees due to a lack of financial resources.</p>
<p>The company's debts are estimated at some eight billion crowns, most of which are guaranteed by the state.</p>
<p>Calex is on the government list of strategic companies, which should not be privatised at all or in which the state will keep a veto right over key decisions.</p>
<p>But Kubica said that &quot;the company's strategic statute ends with the state guarantees for its loans&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Though these are being repaid, the government is considering taking part in restructuring the company's debts,&quot; he added, but did not elaborate.</p>
<p>-- Peter Laca, Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-521-8402</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
