<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="383199" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Diamond Deng Xiaoping watch is latest souvenir.</title>
<headline>Diamond Deng Xiaoping watch is latest souvenir.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's entrepreneurs are showing they've picked up a trick or two from Hong Kong's capitalists.</p>
<p>Diamond-encrusted watches bearing the profile of China's 92-year-old paramount leader Deng Xiaoping went on sale on Monday, the latest souvenirs touted to celebrate Hong Kong's return to China's fold on July 1 this year.</p>
<p>The manufacturer? The government in communist China's southern province of Guangdong.</p>
<p>The price? HK$18,500 (US$2,387) for the men's model and HK$16,500 (US$2,129) for the ladies' version. Only 4,000 timepieces will be released.</p>
<p>The Beijing-funded Wen Wei Po newspaper, which faithfully reflects the Chinese Communist Party's views in Hong Kong, splashed the watches in a colour front-page advertisement.</p>
<p>&quot;Engrave historic moments on the mind. Preserve the grace of a great man,&quot; the advertisement said.</p>
<p>The watches were designed by Deng's disabled son, Deng Pufang, and proceeds would go to a foundation for the handicapped in China, the advertisement said.</p>
<p>Deng's reform policies are regarded as responsible for transforming China into one of the fastest growing economies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
