<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="383216" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks end modestly higher, consolidate.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks end modestly higher, consolidate.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks ended with modest gains on Monday, with a fall in the U.S. long bond yield and gains in the local futures market allowing prices to stabilise after heavy losses last week, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index rose 31.36 points, or 0.24 percent, to 13,144.62. Last week it shed 547.24 points. Turnover was HK$7.42 billion compared with HK$10.49 billion on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is just consolidating around these levels,&quot; said Richard Verin, head of equities trading at CS First Boston.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that the fact the futures have held up well tells you that there is come consolidation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>February Hang Seng Index futures rose 65 points to 13,205, trading at a premium to the cash market and providing support.</p>
<p>&quot;Last week the drop in the market was triggered by futures trading and today it seems like there is some support for the futures market and selling pressure reduced,&quot; said Frederick Tsang, head of research at PrimeEast Securities.</p>
<p>Brokers said a rise of 17/32 in the U.S long bond on Friday, bringing the yield to 6.53 percent, had been encouraging.</p>
<p>But after last week's drop in local share prices, analysts said investors remained cautious.</p>
<p>&quot;We particularly saw most of the selling pressure concentrated on the big cap stocks and that is not a very good sign. We need to see how the market trades this week,&quot; said Tsang.</p>
<p>Verin said European and U.S. investors had also been showing some concern about political developments in Hong Kong. &quot;I do think that there is foreign selling,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he saw support for the Hang Seng Index at 13,000 points with the upside limited to around 13,500.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no flow of news at the moment to push it up,&quot; said Verin.</p>
<p>Gains in major blue chips HSBC Holdings and Cheung Kong helped lift the Hang Seng higher. HSBC rose HK$1.00 to HK$184.50 and Cheung Kong rose HK$0.75 to HK$72.50.</p>
<p>Hongkong Telecom fell HK$0.05 to HK$13.00. Analysts said that a global pact reached this weekend on opening the telecommunications industry to competition would have no immediate impact on Hongkong Telecom.</p>
<p>Shares in South China Morning Post rose HK$0.65 to HK$7.00. The company reported interim net profit last week of HK$379 million compared with HK$427 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
