<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="383366" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: New Continent plans rights, B-share issue.</title>
<headline>New Continent plans rights, B-share issue.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shareholders of Shenzhen-listed Hainan New Continent Motorcycle Co Ltd have approved a 2.142-for-10 rights issue and an offer of 100 to 150 million B shares in 1997, a company official said on Monday.</p>
<p>The rights issue, tentatively priced between four and six yuan per share, is expected to be launched by June 30. The B share price has not been fixed, he said.</p>
<p>The rights issue needs approval from the China Securities Regulatory Commission and the B share issue requires a go-ahead from the Securities Commission of China's State Council, or cabinet, according to a statement by the motorcycle manufacturer published in Monday's Shenzhen-based Securities Times.</p>
<p>Proceeds would be used to upgrade technology and facilities and to jointly produce motorcycle engines with Japanese firm Kawasaki, it said, but gave no more details.</p>
<p>Sundiro's 1996 first-half net earnings were 65.96 million yuan (US$7.9 million), compared with 33.04 million yuan in the year-earlier period.</p>
<p>It reported net profit of 70.57 million yuan in 1995, up 26.4 percent on the 1994 figure. Sales in 1995 hit 862.79 million yuan, up from 482.69 million yuan in 1994. Output in 1995 was 198,754 units, a year-on-year rise of 92.68 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
