<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="383425" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: NTT, KDD shares up after WTO telecom talks.</title>
<headline>NTT, KDD shares up after WTO telecom talks.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Nippon Telegraph and Telephone Corp and Kokusai Denshin Denwa Co Ltd rose in Monday morning trade on the Tokyo bourse after the conclusion of World Trade Organisation (WTO) talks on telecoms trade.</p>
<p>The multilateral trade body on Saturday agreed on plans to liberalise the telecom markets of 69 of the 130 member nations.  </p>
<p>The accord may have an impact on the two major Japanese telecommunications firms by allowing foreign competitors to enter the Japanese market through the buying of stakes in other Japanese phone companies.</p>
<p>The Japanese government offered to remove all limitations on foreign investment in telecoms companies except for NTT and KDD at the WTO talks.</p>
<p>NTT shares had risen 8,000 yen to 893,000 by 0119 GMT, while KDD had climbed 180 yen to 7,700 by 0113 GMT.</p>
<p>NTT president Junichiro Miyazu said he welcomed the conclusion of the trade talks on telecommunications.</p>
<p>&quot;We view the result of the talks as positive for the company as we are seeking to actively expand into international services and participate in global competition,&quot; Miyazu said in a statement issued on Sunday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
