<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="383555" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: FEATURE - Indonesia bonds market set to boom.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Indonesia bonds market set to boom.</headline>
<byline>Mantik Kusjanto</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's bond market is set to boom following a surge in the establishment of mutual funds despite the absence of a yield benchmark.</p>
<p>Market sources say a 1996 presidential decree granting tax exemption for interest income and capital gains from investments in bonds listed on stock exchanges is bearing fruit.</p>
<p>Agus Projosasmito, president director of PT Danareksa Sekuritas, told Reuters he was confident 1997 would be an impressive year for the fast developing bond market.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very optimistic that the bond market will boom this year. There will be some 2.0 trillion rupiah ($840.6 million) of bonds to be issued this year through Danareksa alone,&quot; Projosasmito said.</p>
<p>He said this was only the amount already confirmed.</p>
<p>&quot;We are also in negotiations for some other deals which will further boost bond issues this year,&quot; Projosasmito said, adding he hoped this could help fill the demand for bonds by mutual funds.</p>
<p>The same view was also shared by Ari Murhandoko, a director of PT Bahana Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no question the market is poised for rapid growth this year due to the tax rules,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Danareksa and Bahana, both controlled by the government, are among the top players in the bond market.</p>
<p>MARKET STILL LACKS BENCHMARK</p>
<p>Although some market players were sceptical of a truly big bang in the Indonesian bond market, many remained optimistic despite the absence of a widely acceptable yield benchmark.</p>
<p>&quot;There are not enough issuances to establish a proper yield curve in Indonesia, so that is probably the biggest problem,&quot; David Tan, product manager of JP Morgan, told Reuters.</p>
<p>But Murhandoko said the boom would be mainly demand-driven.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a take-off in demand. But it won't be like a developed market because the rush in bonds will be driven by mutual funds seeking high yielding papers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>There is no official benchmark in Indonesia because the government is not allowed to issue bills to finance its budget, which is balanced by law.</p>
<p>The government did issue yankee bonds last year, but this was aimed mainly at reducing funding costs for Indonesian companies seeking funds offshore, especially in the U.S. market.</p>
<p>Central bank governor Sudradjad Djiwandono said recently that the lack of liquidity and a benchmark and the absence of a central clearing and custodial body were among the problems hampering the progress of a bond market in Indonesia.</p>
<p>However, Djiwandono said the government might select one bond issue to play the benchmark role.</p>
<p>At present, some bond dealers were looking at the five-year one trillion rupiah of the state electricity firm Perusahaan Listrik Negara V/A bonds as the &quot;emergency&quot; benchmark, which was trading at 105.25 percent and yielding 15.37 percent.</p>
<p>MUSHROOMING MUTUAL FUNDS</p>
<p>&quot;Mutual funds will mushroom. You can see a lot of firms are setting up investment funds now,&quot; Murhandoko said, adding that in the long run this would threaten traditional banking businesses.</p>
<p>A mutual fund is often an open-end management company which pools funds from investors to establish a diversified portfolio of investments. Investors buy the shares at net asset value and can redeem them at any time at the prevailing market price.</p>
<p>Pardi Kendy, treasury head of PT Bank Buana Indonesia, said many fresh mutual funds had been set up recently and the most successful were those focusing on investments in bonds.</p>
<p>&quot;Local interest rates are on a declining trend. We have to look for higher yielding long-term papers, and bonds offer the best alternative,&quot; Kendy said.</p>
<p>&quot;We can fund the purchase through the money market. The indisputable attraction is the tax exemption,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Capital Market Supervisory Agency (Bapepam) said net assets value of 24 mutual funds, and one close-end fund, totalled 2.9 trillion rupiah by January.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have almost three trillion rupiah in six months time. We are in the process of granting another seven mutual funds in the near future,&quot; said a Bapepam official.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential is enormous. We are still small compared to other countries.&quot;</p>
<p>The establishment of open-end mutual funds was possible only after the enactment of new measures by Bapepam in May last year</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
