<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="383533" id="root" date="1997-02-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: PRESS DIGEST - Italy - Monday February 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Italy - Monday February 17.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the top headlines in leading Italian newspapers.</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP POLITICAL STORIES</p>
<p>* Umberto Bossi, leader of secessionist Northern League party, threatened to organize a tax strike unless the political establishment recognised what he said was the north's right to independence (all).</p>
<p>* President Oscar Luigi Scalfaro said Italy's pensions system is unbalanced and the gap between the haves and have-nots is &quot;unacceptable&quot; (all).</p>
<p>* Prime minister Romano Prodi will meet today the Prime Minister of Bavaria Edmund Stoiber and senior German business leaders and bankers during stops in Munich and Frankfurt (all).</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>* Prime Minister Prodi and Treasury Minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi held talks with Bank of Italy Governor Antonio Fazio on Sunday. A brief statement gave no details of the talks, but the three reportedly discussed the excessive costs in the banking system and nominations to Consob (Italy's stock exchange watchdog), where the current chairman's mandate expires at the end of the month (Corriere della Sera, La Stampa).</p>
<p>* Trade union leader Sergio Cofferati in an interview replied to Fazio's call for a more flexible labour market saying wage flexibility should not try to substitute national working contracts (La Repubblica).</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129450</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
