<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="383926" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: CYCLING-SALMERON TAKES FIRST PROFESSIONAL STAGE VICTORY.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-SALMERON TAKES FIRST PROFESSIONAL STAGE VICTORY.</headline>
<dateline>JAEN, Spain 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spanish rider Gines Salmeron hung on for his first professional stage win on the third day of the Ruta del Sol on Tuesday despite seeing the chasing group slash his lead by nearly a minute in the final kilometres.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought they had me, but in the last kilometre I gave it all I had,&quot; Salmeron gasped after reaching the line nine seconds ahead of the race favourites, amongst them overall leader Erik Zabel.</p>
<p>Zabel shares the same time with Belgian World Champion Johan Museeuw and a large group of riders who will look to take the overall race in the remaining two days.</p>
<p>&quot;There are so few opportunities to win,&quot; said Salmeron, 24, whose career has been affected by allergies and breathing problems.</p>
<p>His win was the first Spanish stage victory of the European season.</p>
<p>Salmeron had broken away with the leading group in the first climb of the day, and took his chance after shaking off a challenge from Jose Manuel Uria and American Frankie Andreu in the first category climb towards the end of the stage.</p>
<p>The Spaniard saw his lead cut dramatically in the descent to the southern city of Jaen, but found fresh reserves just as the group seemed to be catching him.</p>
<p>The riders face another tough mountain stage on Wednesday over 176 kilometres from Cabra to the city of Malaga on Spain's south coast.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAEN, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
