<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="383974" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA BASKETBALL-RICE SCORES 40 AS HORNETS ROUT MAGIC.</title>
<headline>NBA BASKETBALL-RICE SCORES 40 AS HORNETS ROUT MAGIC.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Charles Barkley scored 21 points and grabbed nine rebounds in his return from a one-game suspension as the Houston Rockets scored a season high in points in routing the Atlanta Hawks 127-98 Monday.</p>
<p>Barkley shot 6-of-12 from the field and 8-of-11 at the foul line in his first game since serving a one-game suspension for Friday's scuffle with Seattle forward Shawn Kemp. Houston is 29-8 when Barkley is in the lineup and 5-10 when he is not.</p>
<p>&quot;Having Charles back was great because he was really fired up and that was a positive for us,&quot; Houston coach Rudy Tomjanovich said.</p>
<p>&quot;We just played terrific tonight,&quot; Barkley said. &quot;That was one of our best games all year. We got our fast break going, which led to some easy points. All the guys played terrific.&quot;</p>
<p>Matt Maloney and Hakeem Olajuwon added 16 points apiece for the Rockets, who won for just the second time in their last 10 games. Houston broke open a close game by going on a 20-5 run which bridged the first and second quarters.</p>
<p>Houston destroyed the Hawks on the boards, 47-24. The 24 rebounds by Atlanta matched a season low and was the second fewest by a Houston opponent in franchise history.</p>
<p>&quot;I expected the game to be much closer,&quot; Hawks coach Lenny Wilkins said. &quot;We played pretty well in the first quarter but in the second, they really hurt us. We didn't get back on defence and they penetrated whenever they wanted to. Their bench killed us and they killed us on the boards. It was just an old-fashioned whoopin'.&quot;</p>
<p>In Indiana, Reggie Miller sank a technical free throw and two of three foul shots with one-tenth of a second remaining as the Pacers erased a 19-point halftime deficit and beat the Toronto Raptors 105-103.</p>
<p>Indiana, which has won all six meetings with Toronto this season, won in the final second when Miller was fouled by Doug Christie attempting a three-pointer. Toronto coach Darrell Walker was so infuriated by the call that he came on to the court and grabbed the ball from referee Monty McCutchen.</p>
<p>Walker then slammed the ball and was whistled for a technical. Miller made the technical foul shot and sank two of his three free throws for a 105-103 lead.</p>
<p>&quot;They called it, so it must have been a foul in the ref's eyes,&quot; said Miller, who finished with 25 points.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought I made a clean play, but the referees didn't see it that way,&quot; Christie said.</p>
<p>In Charlotte, Glen Rice hit six three-pointers, including the 1,000th of his career, en route to 40 points as the Hornets routed the slumping Orlando Magic 124-110.</p>
<p>Anthony Mason had 28 points on a team-record 11-of-11 shooting, as well as 12 rebounds and nine assists for the Hornets, who won for the sixth time in their last eight games.</p>
<p>Nick Anderson scored a season-high 28 points for Orlando, which has lost five straight games since the All-Star break.</p>
<p>It may have been the last game for Magic coach Brian Hill, although management denied reports Sunday he had been fired.</p>
<p>Magic All-Star guard Penny Hardaway left the game in the fourth quarter with a strained big toe and did not return. He missed 23 games earlier this season with a knee injury.</p>
<p>In Vancouver, A.C. Green had 21 points and 15 rebounds -- both season highs -- as the undermanned Dallas Mavericks snapped a three-game losing streak, 100-95 over the Grizzlies.</p>
<p>Dallas improved to 5-0 against the Grizzlies despite suiting up just eight players.</p>
<p>Dallas made a nine-player deal with the Nets, sending forward Chris Gatling, guards Jimmy Jackson and Sam Cassell, swingman George McCloud and centre Eric Montross to New Jersey for centre Shawn Bradley, guards Robert Pack and Khalid Reeves and forward Ed O'Bannon, who were not with the team.</p>
<p>Forward Jamal Mashburn was traded to Miami last week and point guard Jason Kidd to Phoenix earlier in the season.</p>
<p>Michael Finley added 21 points and Sasha Danilovic, acquired in the Mashburn deal, went 10-for-10 from the free-throw line en route to 19 points for Dallas.</p>
<p>At Cleveland, Terrell Brandon scored 22 points and Bobby Phills had 10 of his 19 in the first quarter as the Cavaliers completed a sweep of the season series with the New Jersey Nets, 108-101.</p>
<p>Tyrone Hill recorded 17 points and a season-high 19 rebounds for the Cavs, who equalled their season high for points in a game and improved to 12-0 this season when reaching the 100-point mark. It was the first regular-season game at Gund Arena in which both teams scored 100 points.</p>
<p>Kendall Gill and Kerry Kittles scored 30 points apiece for the Nets, who reached the 100-point mark for the seventh straight game and became only the fifth team to do it against Cleveland, which came in yielding just 84.7 per game.</p>
<p>In Seattle, Gary Payton scored 26 points and 10 assists as the SuperSonics defeated the Boston Celtics for the fifth straight time, 113-108.</p>
<p>Detlef Schrempf added 24 points and Shawn Kemp, returning to the lineup after serving a one-game suspension for throwing a punch at Houston's Kevin Willis on Friday, had 22.</p>
<p>Antoine Walker scored 27 and Rick Fox added 21 for Boston, which lost its sixth straight.</p>
<p>At Washington, Calbert Cheaney converted a pair of free throws with 54.2 seconds remaining and Rod Strickland added a free throw with six seconds left to lift the Bullets to a 95-93 victory over the Milwaukee Bucks.</p>
<p>Juwon Howard scored 20 points and Strickland added 18 for the Bullets, who evened their record at 2-2 under new coach Bernie Bickerstaff.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
