<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="384285" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: Journalists' jailing hits Zambia independent press.</title>
<headline>Journalists' jailing hits Zambia independent press.</headline>
<byline>Jowie Mwiinga</byline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zambia's leading independent daily, The Post, faces further court action in Lusaka this week amid mounting concern that the government of President Frederick Chiluba is pursuing a drive to muzzle the press.</p>
<p>Fred Mmembe, a Post editor, was due to appear in magistrate's court on Thursday on libel charges for publishing an article last year in which he claimed Chiluba had fathered a love child.</p>
<p>Mmembe, one of three journalists awaiting trial on charges brought by the Chiluba government, could face three years' imprisonment if convicted.</p>
<p>Earlier this month another Post editor, Masausto Phiri, became the first Zambian journalist to be jailed on contempt of court charges.</p>
<p>He was imprisoned for publishing reports that the Supreme Court judges took government bribes to reject an opposition challenge of the results of controversial general elections held last year.</p>
<p>Phiri's three-month jail sentence provoked a flurry of protests from local and international media watchdog groups, who say it was too harsh for the offence committed.</p>
<p>Last Sunday, the editor of the independent Chronicle, Lweendo Hamusankwa, was arrested for publishing an allegedly false report on a break-in at a military base. The reporter who wrote the article, Boyd Phiri, who is not related to the Post editor, was detained the following day.</p>
<p>Both are still being held and are to be charged with criminal libel and for publishing &quot;false news&quot; with intent to cause fear and alarm to the public.</p>
<p>The Press Association of Zambia has called on journalists &quot;not to be intimidated...but to continue in their efforts to uphold the tenets of freedom of the press&quot;.</p>
<p>Media observers say Masausto Phiri's imprisonment is just one symptom of a concerted government clampdown on the media.</p>
<p>By December last year, The Post faced at least 19 criminal and civil lawsuits, most filed by government officials. But the goverment denies any campaign against the press.</p>
<p>Commenting on the Post editor, who admitted that his reports were not based on established fact, the state-run Times of Zambia said:</p>
<p>&quot;Because of a few bad eggs, the whole media can now be sensed most perceptibly as out-and-out fabricators. (Zambians) should condemn anyone within the media fraternity who tried to make it look as if Phiri was a victim of press harassment, for he was not.&quot;</p>
<p>Last November, the government suspended six journalists at the state-run broadcaster whom it believed were sympathetic to the opposition or worked with watchdog groups which questioned the fairness of November's elections.</p>
<p>Chiluba won a landslide in the ballot, boycotted by opposition groups who said he had stacked the deck against them. In January, Chiluba announced that he would establish a media council to curb malpractice and two weeks later the ministry of information announced that it would &quot;expose&quot; journalists who sent &quot;negative&quot; reports on Zambia.</p>
<p>The government has also passed legislation compelling journalists to disclose their sources before a tribunal appointed by the chief justice.</p>
<p>Some analysts say the state, which owns the only national radio and television network and the two more established dailies, is determined to tame the independent media.</p>
<p>The independent media comprises one daily and four weeklies with a total circulation of around 20,000 copies, plus two community radio stations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
