<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="384229" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: FOCUS - Canadian budget sees sharply lower deficit.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Canadian budget sees sharply lower deficit.</headline>
<byline>Peter Cooney</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>In its last budget before a likely election this year, Canada's Liberal government said on Tuesday it was nearing victory in its war on the country's deficit, but offered only mild tax relief and new spending.</p>
<p>&quot;The era of cuts is over. The finances of the nation are finally being brought under control,&quot; Finance Minister Paul Martin told Parliament, delivering his fourth federal budget.</p>
<p>Resisting calls for broad tax relief or big spending hikes, Martin pledged to stay the course on deficit cutting.</p>
<p>He predicted that Canada's deficit for 1996/97 ending March 31 would be no more than C$19 billion ($14 billion) -- $9.6 billion ($7.1 billion) below last year's --  the country's biggest ever annual deficit decline.</p>
<p>The projected 1996/97 deficit was also much lower than the government's C$24.3 billion ($17.9 billion) target for this year -- making it the third straight year that Martin has beaten his deficit targets.</p>
<p>Michael Gregory, economist at Lehman Brothers in Toronto, said the budget numbers so far this year suggested that Canada's actual 1996/97 deficit could come in as low as C$17 billion ($12.6 billion).</p>
<p>Martin's fiscal prudence and success in exceeding his conservative deficit goals have been credited with raising investor confidence in Canada and helping slash interest rates to their lowest level in almost 40 years.</p>
<p>&quot;Canada has the most prudent and the most credible budget planning process in the industrialized world,&quot; said Andrew Spence, economist at brokerage Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>Spence said that unlike some European countries, &quot;in Canada, deficit targets mean targets. They will be met and our experience since 1994 is that they will be bettered.&quot;</p>
<p>Martin, a millionaire former steamship magnate, launched his assault on Canada's fiscal woes in 1995 when the country labored under one of the heaviest budget deficits, relative to the size of its economy, in the developed world.</p>
<p>Aided by deep government spending cuts, Martin slashed the deficit to C$28.6 billion ($21.2 billion) in 1995/1996 from C$42.1 billion ($31 million) in 1993/1994.</p>
<p>He said on Tuesday that &quot;the government is clearly on track to meet its deficit targets of C$17 billion ($12.6 billion), or two percent of GDP, for 1997/1998 and C$9 billion ($6.7 billion), or one percent of GDP, for 1998/99.&quot;</p>
<p>Signs point to a balanced budget in 1999/2000. But Martin, who has pledged to erase the deficit, does not make projections beyond two years.</p>
<p>Martin's prowess cutting the deficit has provoked opposition party demands for reduced taxes, while left-leaning members of the ruling Liberals have pushed for more spending ahead of a federal election expected later this year.</p>
<p>In his budget speech, Martin repeated his opposition to general tax cuts until Canada balanced its budget and reduced its debt to gross domestic product ratio, which at 74.4 percent is second highest among G7 industrial countries behind Italy.</p>
<p>Martin, whose namesake father helped create many of Canada's generous social programs as a Liberal cabinet minister in the 1950s and 1960s, also proposed modest tax cuts and new spending of about C$1.2 billion ($888 million) aimed at the poor, education and medicare.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
