<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="384398" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Trial of Albania's last communist leader postponed.</title>
<headline>Trial of Albania's last communist leader postponed.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's last communist president Ramiz Alia and four other senior officials were charged with crimes against humanity on Tuesday, but their trial was postponed for 10 days.</p>
<p>The presiding judge ordered the postponement to allow an appeals court to rule on a call by Alia's lawyer for new judges to be appointed.</p>
<p>&quot;The appeals court will rule on your request. I declare the session closed,&quot; presiding judge Martin Deda told Alia's lawyer Kleanthi Koci after he demanded the judges' resignation.</p>
<p>Ramiz Alia, 72, the handpicked successor of dictator Enver Hoxha, and former communist interior ministers Hekuran Isai and Simon Stefani face charges of genocide and crimes against humanity.</p>
<p>Tirana prosecutor Adnan Xhelili said the defendants were responsible for ordering killings on the border even though parliament did not consider it a criminal offence.</p>
<p>&quot;They not only did not take measures to make the law valid but awarded medals to those who killed people who were fleeing abroad to earn their bread,&quot; Xhelili said.</p>
<p>If convicted, they face sentences of 15 years to death. Alia, Isai, 64, and Stefani, 68, have all served several years in jail already for abuse of power and embezzlement.</p>
<p>Two other defendants, former interior minister Gramoz Ruci and former prosecutor general Qemal Lame, were represented by lawyers and will be tried in absentia on the same charges.</p>
<p>Prosecutors started investigating Alia after passage of  a law in 1995 which banned former communist officials from holding public office till 2002 and urged people to denounce crimes committed under communism.</p>
<p>Three senior ex-communists were sentenced to death in May, charged with crimes against humanity for ordering the deportation of anti-communist dissidents but an appeals court revoked the sentences and imposed jail terms instead.</p>
<p>More than 30 ex-communists have been sentenced to up to 25 years in jail for crimes against humanity.</p>
<p>Around 100,000 Albanians are believed to have been forced into internal exile in remote villages during 45 years of communist rule because of their opposition to the Stalinist government or for trying to escape from the isolated Balkan country.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
