<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="384358" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo central bank plans to cut reserve requirement.</title>
<headline>Yugo central bank plans to cut reserve requirement.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Bank of Yugoslavia (NBY) plans to cut the reserve requirement for commercial banks, apparently to help the Serbia's indebted government fund spring sowings.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank plans to cut the reserve requirement to 10 from 15 percent to create some monetary relaxation for commercial banks,&quot; an NBY senior official who asked not to be named told Reuters.</p>
<p>Analysts said such monetary relaxation was the central bank's response to earlier demands from the Serbian government that NBY step in and help the Serbian government gather funds to issue new credits for farmers ahead of sowings.</p>
<p>The government has said it sought 200 million from the NBY, but stopped short of asking for a direct loan. Instead, it suggested the central bank could either use the reserve requirement for that purpose or issue forward contracts with future agricultural produce as collateral.</p>
<p>Lower reserve requirement would free funds at the state-owned commercial banks and the government's control of the them would ensure the money went where the authorities wanted.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank found the easiest way out. It cuts the reserve requirement and leaves more money in banks to do the credit business,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the lower reserve requirement would not be of any help to the banks if the money is used to lend to farmers. The government is already in arrears to the farmers for last year's crop and it faces a boycott of the spring sowings without fresh funds.</p>
<p>&quot;Banks already have problems to collect debt and once again they will be forced to allocate funds to farmers. And it is not exactly to farmers but to the state not paying back what it owes anyway,&quot; an economist said.</p>
<p>Analysts agreed agriculture was the part of the economy that helped the country and its people through 3-1/2 years of international trade embargo and for that reason deserved better treatment.</p>
<p>But around two thirds of Serbian farmers have not been repaid for the agricultural produce they had produced and sold. &quot;To pay them this way only means the government is trying to ensure that farmers will do their work once again,&quot; an economist said. -- Gordana Filipovic, Belgrade newsroom, +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
