<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="384384" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares set high, seen losing steam.</title>
<headline>Polish shares set high, seen losing steam.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares rose to a 35-month high and analysts said the bourse, now at 18,339.4 points, might slow its growth or stabilise in the next few sessions as it approaches its all-time March 1994 high of 20,760.3.</p>
<p>The main market's WIG index rose 1.2 percent to 18,339.4 points and turnover fell 9.7 percent to 232.5 million zlotys ($77.5 million) on both markets as 46 issues rose, 22 fell and 20 were flat.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not far from the historic maximum, which is naturally halting growth. It seems to me that the growth will slow and the market will stabilise,&quot; said Artur Czerwonski, an analyst at Bank Pekao SA brokerage.</p>
<p>Some analysts said the market, which has risen 38 percent since mid-December, was likely to suffer from significant profit-taking after reaching around 18,500 points.</p>
<p>Some said a correction could pull the WIG index down below 16,000 points.</p>
<p>Analysts said companies' January earnings reports, most of them expected later on Tuesday, were likely to make selected stocks jump or fall on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Analysts said Tuesday's over nine-percent jumps by electromagnetic transmitters maker Relpol, food trader Rolimpex and construction firm Mostostal Krakow were likely caused by speculative play before the release of their earnings reports.</p>
<p>Analysts said the market was unlikely to react to Tuesday's news that Poland's industrial output fell 3.4 percent in January after a 2.1 percent rise in December. Year-on-year industrial output in January was 8.6 percent higher.</p>
<p>Continuous trade amounted to 27.5 million zlotys ($9.2 million) with the WIG 20 index closing  at 1,885.7 points, 0.5 percent lower than at the regular session.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
