<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="38434" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Petrogal refinery shutdown to start next week.</title>
<headline>Petrogal refinery shutdown to start next week.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Petrogal's 210,000 barrels per day (bpd) refinery at Sines in southwestern Portugal is to close for maintenance from September 11 to October 21, the state owned company said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the biggest maintenance project carried out to date by Petrogal, with an estimated cost of more than four billion escudos ($26 million) and involving about 1,300 workers from national and foreign contractors,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Petrogal and the Sines refinery have already supplied the refined products to cover totally the needs of its market and the country, ensuring that the maintenance will not provide any problem in supplies to clients,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>A company official who declined to be identified said that stocks of refined oil products had been built up sufficiently to cover Petrogal's term contract commitments, but the company would not be offering cargoes on the spot market for the shutdown period.</p>
<p>The refinery normally exports 90,000 tonnes of gasoline, 30,000 tonnes of jet fuel and 25,000 tonnes of gas oil on the spot market per month, over and above its term contract commitments, the official said.</p>
<p>It has a storage capacity of 2.8 million cubic metres, including 1.5 million cubic metres for crude oil.</p>
<p>Portugal's other refinery at Oporto will not close for maintenance this year.</p>
<p>-- David Brough, Lisbon newsroom +351 1 3538254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
