<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="384580" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia government bows to demands to end strike.</title>
<headline>Colombia government bows to demands to end strike.</headline>
<byline>Tom Brown</byline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wary of the dangers of economic austerity after the crisis in neighbouring Ecuador, Colombia's government bowed on Tuesday to demands for a stiff wage hike to end a strike that threatened to erupt in mass street protests.</p>
<p>A deal ending the week-old strike by public sector workers was hammered out during a marathon 30-hour negotiating session that ended shortly before dawn. It came just 24 hours before union leaders planned to truck in workers from around the country for what they billed as a huge protest march and &quot;the siege of Bogota.&quot;</p>
<p>The government, battling to plug a gaping fiscal deficit, had insisted since the strike began at midnight on Feb. 10 that it could not give state workers more than a weighted 13.5 percent pay raise despite inflation of 21.6 percent last year.</p>
<p>But it wound up agreeing to pay hikes of as much as 20 percent and also agreed to set up a joint commission, with fiercely nationalistic union leaders, to analyse government privatisation plans on a sector-by-sector basis.</p>
<p>Among other repercussions, President Ernesto Samper said it could delay plans to open the state-run telecommunications company to private competition. Efforts to open up the jealously-guarded oil sector to greater participation by multinationals could also suffer, industry analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The subject of privatisations was probably what caused us the most headaches and took the most time,&quot; Samper told local radio.</p>
<p>Labour leaders hailed the deal as a victory for the estimated 800,000 workers who took part in the work stoppage. Government officials led by Samper said it was important because it guaranteed an end to labour unrest, but critics said it spelled disaster for the government's economic belt-tightening plans for 1997 since fiscal austerity had essentially been tossed out the window.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a success for the workers but the government failed,&quot; Juan Camilo Restrepo, a senator with the opposition Conservative Party, said. &quot;This is a weak government and it winds up negotiating everything,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government ended on its knees in front of the unions,&quot; Rudolf Hommes, a former finance minister and sharp critic of economic policy under Samper, said.</p>
<p>Armando Montenegro, head of the National Bankers' Association, told Reuters parallels with Ecuador, where a national strike led to President Abdala Bucaram's ouster by Congress on Feb. 6, should not be overstated since Bucaram triggered &quot;a massive social protest&quot; with draconian austerity measures he introduced in late December and early January.</p>
<p>&quot;Here it was just a protest by state workers and I don't think they had a lot of popular support,&quot; Montenegro said. But he said the government was clearly influenced by the crisis in Ecuador and what Bucaram himself described during a visit to Bogota on Monday as the potential &quot;domino effect.&quot;</p>
<p>Bucaram is sure to have commented during a meeting with Samper on the dangers of ramming neo-liberal economic measures down a poor nation's throat, diplomats said.</p>
<p>The Colombian government had warned of the likely outbreak of violence during the strike and leftist guerrillas vowed to back it with armed attacks. No serious violence materialised, but Montenegro said the government was &quot;afraid of the power of the unions and of what might happen during Wednesday's march.&quot;</p>
<p>In a bid to quell unrest during the strike, the government delayed planned gasoline hikes originally scheduled for this month. Scrounging for money to cut its deficit, it has also quietly told the armed forces high command that planned military spending this year has been cut by $130 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
