<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="384640" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ NatGas sees continued improved trade in 2nd hlf.</title>
<headline>NZ NatGas sees continued improved trade in 2nd hlf.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Natural Gas Corp said on Wednesday its latest half year result represented a satisfactory start to the financial year and it saw improved trading patterns continuing through the second six months.</p>
<p>The company reported a half year profit of NZ$15.26 million against $17.86 million in the previous corresponding period. It set a dividend of 11 NZ cents per share.  </p>
<p>Company chairman Mike Smith said the latest half year result was founded on increased natural gas sales and the commencement of supply to the Southdown power station in Auckland.</p>
<p>Smith said the gas market was becoming increasingly competitive and Natural Gas continued to promote a competitive market with open access.</p>
<p>He said the High Court's decision in early February on the Kapuni gas contract dispute had opened another alternative supply source for reticulated market consumers.</p>
<p>Smith said the company had still not reached any conclusions about whether to appeal any of the court's findings.  </p>
<p>The dispute is between the Kapuni Mining Companies (Shell and Todd) on the one hand, and Kapuni Gas Contracts (a wholly-owned subsidiary of Fletcher Energy and Natural Gas Corp on the other.</p>
<p>The High Court held that the Kapuni Gas Contract continued for the life of the field. It ordered that from April 1 the remainder of the gas in the field be divided equally between the plaintiffs and the defendants in the case.  </p>
<p>The directors said the judgment was unlikely to have any effect on the 1996/97 results. It was difficult to accurately quantify the decision's financial impact on the company ahead of negotiations with the field owners on the gas reserves remaining, delivery profiles and price.</p>
<p>Natural Gas also said it had asked its gas utility customers to agree to an amendment of the existing 1980 contract in order to address competition concerns.  </p>
<p>Chief Executive Richard Bentley said the company had invited the utilities to agree to the removal of exclusive supply provisions, which stopped the utilities from buying gas from other suppliers, and prevented Natural Gas from selling gas to other buyers in the utilities supply areas.</p>
<p>The company has offered the utilities unbundled supply arrangements with separate wholesale gas and transmission contracts, which did not have exclusivity provisions.  </p>
<p>Bentley said he still remained cautiously optimistic that progress would be made in the move away from existing contracts this year, but Natural Gas could no force the change on its customers.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
