<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="384793" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Medicine leads to greatest fall in heart disease.</title>
<headline>Medicine leads to greatest fall in heart disease.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most of the recent decline in deaths from heart disease in the United States was not due to healthy living but because of medical treatment advances, a study said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Our analysis suggests that only about one-fourth of the decline in coronary heart disease mortality between 1980 and 1990 was owing to primary prevention (such as lower blood pressure, lower cholesterol levels, losing weight or quitting smoking),&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the decline (72 percent) was explained by improvement in the management of patients with diagnosed coronary heart disease...&quot; it added.</p>
<p>The report, published in this week's Journal of the American Medical Association, was based on a computer analysis of medical literature and health statistics. It was done by researchers at the Harvard School of Public Health in Boston and the University of Groningen in the Netherlands.</p>
<p>&quot;The decline in coronary heart disease mortality has been a well-known fact for more than 20 years now,&quot; said Maria Hunink, lead author of the study. &quot;What startled us was that treating patients with coronary heart disease was having so much more effect than trying to prevent the disease.&quot;</p>
<p>Co-author Milton Weinstein said the lesson for the public was that treatment after diagnosis of the disease or even after a heart attack could still save lives.</p>
<p>The study found a 34 percent decline in heart disease-related deaths during the decade studied. Researchers said the prevalence of heart disease increased among both sexes during that time.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
