<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="384705" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Sri Lanka says no immediate plans for more diesel.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka says no immediate plans for more diesel.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lanka does not have any immediate plans to buy more gas oil for power generation to compensate for possible shortages of hydropower during the current dry season, a Ceylon Petroleum Corp (CPC) source said.</p>
<p>He noted that the Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) has decided to raise thermal generation to avoid power cuts and for the time being there have been no orders from the board to import extra gas oil for generation.</p>
<p>He said if an emergency occurs, such as if the low rainfall persisted until April, the board could place their import orders within two weeks.  </p>
<p>Sri Lanka has bought about 200,000 tonnes of gas oil, jet fuel and gasoline during January-March to make up for shortages during the shutdown of its 60,000-barrel- -per-day Sapugaskande refinery since January 15. The refinery is due to restart sometime next week.</p>
<p>Weathermen said late last week they did not expect 1996's drought to be repeated in 1997 despite only slight rainfall in January.</p>
<p>They said forecasts indicate intermonsoon rains and the southwest monsoon should come on time.  </p>
<p>Since 1996, CEB has raised thermal power generation to 210 megawatts from 150.</p>
<p>Electricity demand is around 1,345 megawatts of which 84 percent is met by hydro power stations.</p>
<p>Last year, after the failure of rains, Sri Lanka instigated major power cuts owing to low levels of hydro levels.</p>
<p>--Singapore Newsroom (+65 870 3081)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
