<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="384781" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Expatriates must take initiative, play up experience.</title>
<headline>Expatriates must take initiative, play up experience.</headline>
<byline>Sherwood Ross</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Returning expatriates who say their company does not value their foreign experience may need to become more assertive.</p>
<p>&quot;Expatriates have to take responsibility for planning their own career path. It doesn't get any better when you're out of sight and out of mind,&quot; said Jacqueline Hauser, of Prudential Relocation Global Services in Shelton, Conn.</p>
<p>&quot;Planning for coming back begins even before you accept the position overseas,&quot; said Hauser, who serves as director of Prudential's International Assignments Practice.</p>
<p>Four out of five expatriates &quot;will tell you that they don't think their international experience is valued,&quot; she said. &quot;We've got a ways to go.&quot;</p>
<p>Their disappointment can be shattering, particularly as most leave home believing their foreign assignment will boost their careers.</p>
<p>Even those who are stars overseas may be among the unhappy 13 percent of expatriates who leave their organisation within two years of their return, according to a relocation trends survey made in 1995 by the National Foreign Trade Council.</p>
<p>&quot;Before you accept the assignment, find out what the company thinks its effect will be on your career,&quot; Hauser advises. &quot;Get a wide variety of perspectives, from senior management and human resources.&quot;</p>
<p>If you rely on just one person for guidance and that individual leaves the firm while you are abroad, there could be no one who remembers taking an interest in you, Hauser said.</p>
<p>In companies without a formal mentoring programme, the potential expatriate &quot;should be advocating for one and very active in selecting that person,&quot; the assignments expert said.</p>
<p>Once overseas, the expatriate should talk to the mentor &quot;on a regular basis&quot; and spend a couple of days during annual home leave at  headquarters filling in the mentor &quot;and anyone else you have networked with.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This gives them the opportunity to see what you have been doing and how your capabilities have expanded,&quot; Hauser said.</p>
<p>For example, a technical expert may acquire management skills abroad that management should be apprised of.</p>
<p>Only 46 percent of the multinational companies responding to the NFTC survey said that overseas executives visited the home office for evaluation during their assignments.</p>
<p>About a year before returning, Hauser advises, prepare a &quot;repatriation resume highlighting your overseas experience,&quot; perhaps with &quot;case studies showing how you've solved problems.&quot;</p>
<p>The resume is not the kind used when trying to sell yourself to a new company. Rather, it's designed &quot;to open up other people's minds to the broad range of experience you've picked up on the international assignment,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a snapshot that people will have in their hands so they don't forget you because you're not there every day.&quot;</p>
<p>Resume in hand, tell the company your ideas about &quot;the kinds of positions in your company that you would be good for,&quot; Hauser said. She added, &quot;If you have a job in mind, don't wait for it to materialise from the home office, but say, 'This is how I can be useful.'</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps you can fill a need that hasn't been identified by the company,&quot; she added. &quot;You're the one with the international experience. You might suggest job creation or job enhancement.&quot;</p>
<p>When NFTC asked its corporate members how to reduce the attrition rate among returned expatriates, 70 percent said they should have more opportunity to use their experience; 52 percent recommended more position choices; 25 percent urged more recognition during and after their assignment; and 17 percent called for more expatriate career support.</p>
<p>(EDITORS: Sherwood Ross is a freelance writer who covers workplace issues for Reuters. Any opinions in the column are solely those of Mr. Ross.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
