<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="385062" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss shares end near day's lows on profit taking.</title>
<headline>Swiss shares end near day's lows on profit taking.</headline>
<text>
<p>1540 GMT - After reaching an all-time high of 4,548.1 SMI points in early trade, Swiss shares were hit by profit taking, ending near the day's lows.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw a healthy consolidation today,&quot; one dealer said. The easing U.S. dollar and a mixed opening on Wall Street also dampended sentiment.</p>
<p>* Blue-chip Swiss Market Index (SMI) fell 23.9 points, or 0.53 percent, to 4,490.7. The day's low was 4,487.6.</p>
<p>* The broad Swiss Performance Index (SPI) ended off 12.28 points, or 0.43 percent, at 2,853.91.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the recent strong upward trend is likely to resume after a brief consolidation.</p>
<p>* Novartis registereds, which led the actives list, end down seven francs ato 1,757 after profiting most on the day following news about the imminent spin-off of Ciba Specialty Chemicals. The IPO price range of 72 to 86 francs was within expectations, one trader noted. Roche certificates fell 140 francs to 12,570.</p>
<p>Speciality chemical firm Clariant was a clear winner, ending up 20 francs at 694 francs. Clariant seemed to be attractively priced compared with Ciba CS, one trader said.  </p>
<p>* UBS bearer shares, which have posted solid gains recently, fell 24 francs to 1,295. Dealers said some investors took profits after the recent strong performance and ahead of the bank's 1996 results due on Friday. SBC also gave ground, while CS Group advanced 0.75 francs to 152.25.</p>
<p>* Watchmaker SMH, which had been sought in the past few sessions, ended down 31 francs, or 3.16 percent, at 951.</p>
<p>* Nestle yielded eight francs to end at 1,641.</p>
<p>* Alusuisse, Swiss Re, Adecco and Holderbank all gained.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
