<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="385173" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India Basmati exports to EU seen under threat.</title>
<headline>India Basmati exports to EU seen under threat.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian rice exporters said on Tuesday they would lose about 70 percent of their Basmati exports to the European Union if a new EU regulation was approved.</p>
<p>&quot;The move will reduce exports of Basmati rice to the EU from India by over 70 percent in one year,&quot; said R.S. Seshadri, a senior official of the All India Rice Exporters Association.</p>
<p>Seshadri told reporters that the EU for the past few months had been considering the imposition of a Cumulative Recovery System (CRS) involving the payment of full duty by importers on rice.</p>
<p>He said EU authorities had prepared a draft regulation and sought the views of rice exporting countries before it was put to the vote on February 20 in Brussels.</p>
<p>Seshadri said if the regulation were enforced the current concession of 250 Ecus a tonne given to Indian brown Basmati rice since 1995 was in peril.</p>
<p>&quot;The EU gave the 250 Ecu concession because our prices were higher than the threshold levels set by them.&quot;</p>
<p>Seshadri said EU consumers could afford the Indian rice because of the lower duty imposed on it.</p>
<p>According to the draft import regime, the quality of imports would need to be verified based on factors like aroma, the milling yield and the percentage of brokens, he said.</p>
<p>AIREA said all imported rice would attract full duty and the duty on Indian exports would rise sharply.</p>
<p>If the new regulation were applied the existing concession of 250 Ecus for Indian Basmati could be claimed only after detailed data were provided on the price and quality of each consignment.</p>
<p>&quot;As Indian Basmati rice is the costliest rice, we are going to be affected very badly by this new system and the importers and exporters may feel shy of locking up a huge amount of money to be claimed after a span of 6-12 months,&quot; the AIREA said in a statement.</p>
<p>India's Basmati rice exports to the EU in fiscal 1996/97 were estimated at 75,000 tonnes, about 80 percent of the EU's total Basmati imports. India annually exports over 400,000 tonnes of Basmati rice.</p>
<p>Seshadri said Indian exporters were paying a duty of $18 per tonne on Indian Basmati rice and this would shoot up to $268 once the legislation was passed.</p>
<p>&quot;The EU must be left in no doubt that if this was done then India would take it up at the WTO (World Trade Organisation),&quot; Seshadri said.</p>
<p>The AIREA said it had asked the Indian government to take up the matter, and the Commerce Ministry had told Indian envoys in EU countries of its views.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
