<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="385178" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India wants to deport Charles Sobhraj to France.</title>
<headline>India wants to deport Charles Sobhraj to France.</headline>
<byline>Sunil Kataria</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indian government decided on Tuesday to drop all pending cases against notorious criminal Charles Sobhraj and pressed for his speedy deportation to France.</p>
<p>A special public prosecutor moved an application in a local court to withdraw a jailbreak case against Sobhraj and said permission was being sought to withdraw all other pending cases against him to pave the way for his deportation.</p>
<p>&quot;The Indian government has decided to deport Charles Sobhraj to France immediately saying his presence in India is prejudicial to the state,&quot; the Press Trust of India (PTI) news agency quoted the prosecution lawyer as saying.</p>
<p>Two cases are still pending in Indian courts against Sobhraj. One concerns a lapsed Thai extradition request, while the other stems from a 1986 jailbreak that earned Sobhraj fame.</p>
<p>Sobhraj would not spend more time in jail even if convicted since the maximum penalty would be less than the 11 years he has served since his escape, his lawyer Rajan Bakshi said.</p>
<p>A French citizen born to an Indian father and a Vietnamese mother, Sobhraj told reporters last week that he would stay in India for some months before going to France to work on a $15 million film based on his life.</p>
<p>A Foreign Ministry official said the government's prime concern was to ensure that Sobhraj left the country's boundaries and it was taking steps to ensure that happened.</p>
<p>A French Embassy official in New Delhi refused to confirm that there had been any communication from the Indian government on Sobhraj's proposed deportation to France.</p>
<p>&quot;I cannot confirm or deny it but if he is a French citizen, as he claims to be, then France will have to accept him,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>Bakshi said that if the government dropped all the charges his client would have to leave the country.</p>
<p>&quot;Since he is a foreign national the government has every right to decide whether it wants to grant him permission to stay in India or deport him,&quot; Bakshi said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are only interested in his freedom, as long as he is a free man we don't really bother,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>On Monday Sobhraj, whose exploits across Asia have been the basis of two books, won release from prison after more than two decades behind bars but police detained him again saying he did not have valid identity papers.</p>
<p>Deputy police commissioner Pradeep Srivastava told Reuters that the Foreigners Regional Registration Office (FRRO), which issued papers to foreigners, had ordered Sobhraj detained.</p>
<p>&quot;He claims he is a French citizen but he does not have valid documents,&quot; said a police official.</p>
<p>Srivastava said the FRRO had ordered Sobhraj detained in a local police station until March 2.</p>
<p>Sobhraj was first arrested in India for holding up a hotel jewellery shop in 1971. He has since been charged with a long string of crimes including murder, serving time for some and winning acquittal in others.</p>
<p>Sobhraj's lawyer Bakshi said there was no charge against Sobhraj and prepared to move fresh court appeals on Tuesday to secure his client's release.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel great, like I'm born again,&quot; Sobhraj told reporters minutes before he was detained. Asked if he would revert to crime, Sobhraj said: &quot;Never. Never ever.&quot;</p>
<p>Last week Sobhraj, who says he has converted to Buddhism, said he wanted to take up social work and could make writing his career.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
