<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="385217" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: INDIAN IPOs - Many firms vanish after IPO - PRIME.</title>
<headline>INDIAN IPOs - Many firms vanish after IPO - PRIME.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least 118 firms that had sought listing in some of India's major stock exchanges don't even have their names appearing in the quotation lists of these exchanges, says an Indian market-monitoring agency.</p>
<p>PRIME, in a study on how many firms have &quot;vanished&quot; after raising money from the public and other related issues, said there were 76 companies in which the last trading was done before December 1995 and another 166 firms where no trading has been done since July 1, 1996.</p>
<p>The text of the market monitor's report is as follows:</p>
<p>- There has been considerable concern of late regarding companies who have 'vanished' after raising money from the public.</p>
<p>- Unfortunately, only guesswork is being done about the magnitude of this problem as no government body is responsible for monitoring utilisation of issue funds, and worse, not even for ascertaining if the companies exist after they have made public issues.</p>
<p>- In a direction-finding effort, a study has been done by PRIME, the country's premier data base on the primary capital market, of all the 3911 equity issues (par and premium) which had entered the market during the 4-year period April 1992-March 1996. Of these, 27 companies had refunded application money while 12 companies merged with other companies, leaving a net of 3872 issues.</p>
<p>- According to Prithvi Haldea, Managing Director of PRIME, the study reveals that, of these, as many as 118 companies had proposed listing at one or more of the four major stock exchanges (Bombay, Delhi, Calcutta and/or Madras) but even their names (leave aside quotations) do not appear in the quotation lists of the relevant exchanges.</p>
<p>- In addition, there are 76 companies in which the last trading took place prior to December, 1995 while for another 166 companies there has been no trading after 1st July 1996 (ie. for nearly six-and-a-half months).</p>
<p>- It is also significant to note that of the 3667 companies for whom any quote was available, there was no current trading (ie. between 1-14 January 1997) for as many as 1011 companies (28 percent).</p>
<p>- The PRIME study further reveals that of the total 3872 equity issues, as many as 205 companies (five percent) were not traded at all, 2987 (77 percent) were quoted below offer price and 69 (two percent) were quoted at offer price. The total of such issues is 3261 or a phenomenal 84 percent of the total issues. Only 611 companies (16 percent) were traded above the offer price.</p>
<p>- A further analysis points that of the total 3872 equity issues, 2823 were par issues. Of these, 177 companies (six percent) were not traded at all, 2125 (76 percent) were traded below par and 61 (two percent) were traded at par. Only 460 companies (16 percent) were quoted above par.</p>
<p>- On the other hand, according to PRIME, of the 1049 equity at premium issues, 28 companies (three percent) were not traded at all, 862 (82 percent) were quoted below offer price and eight (one percent) were quoted at offer price. Only 151 companies (14 percent) were traded above the offer price.</p>
<p>- This study was done using the market prices of 14th January 1997 when the sensex had already shown a significant improvement. If the December prices had been used, the situation would have been even grimmer.</p>
<p>- Presently, the only mechanism of monitoring the post-issue performance of companies is by the relevant stock exchanges where the companies had listed. However, at most of the stock exchanges, the monitoring is very poor. Themselves ignorant of the status of the companies, they can provide negligible help to the investors.</p>
<p>- For example, if one was to look at the premier stock exchange, a total of 3379 companies had proposed listing on BSE. According to the PRIME study, of these, there were no quotations for 92 companies, 56 had not been traded since 31.12.95, 132 were last traded between 1.1.96 and 30.6.96, 678 were last traded between 1.7.96 and 31.12.96, 652 were last traded between 1.1.97 and only 13.1.97 and only 1769 were traded on 14.1.97.</p>
<p>- Haldea feels that on monitoring the post-issue performance, the situation is even more pathetic. BSE itself announced in December that a phenomenal 2021 out of 5190 companies had not filed their six-month results with the stock exchange. It further stated that there were several companies which had not submitted their half yearly results or paid listing fees since 1992.</p>
<p>- On the other hand, the two other relevant government bodies-SEBI and DCA have not applied themselves seriously to this subject. Only very recently, SEBI has announced that it has been able to pinpoint 23 companies who have apparently 'vanished' and that investigations have been launched to find out their whereabouts.</p>
<p>- Surely, there is an urgent need, according to Haldea, to bring a periodic post-issue audit till project funds raised are utilised. Moreover, if funds are to be used for purposes other than the one declared in the offer document, prior approval of shareholders should be obtained and dissenting shareholders should be given the option to withdraw their investments. It is one thing if investors lose money because of project failure. However, it is a fraud on them if the promoters misuse funds or do a vanishing act.</p>
<p>- One form of punishment meted out to errant companies is delisting. In early February this year, BSE has gone ahead and delisted 179 companies. Delisting of companies is, however, no answer. While it means literally no punishment for the corporates, it results in a dead loss for the investors. Instead of delisting, there is a need for stringent punishment through heavy monetary penalities.</p>
<p>- Another problem area concerns multiple listing. The PRIME study shows that though hundreds of companies had proposed listing at multiple stock exchanges, these are quoted at only one exchange. Companies that have failed to live up to their promise of multiple stock exchange listings should also attract penalties. For voluntary delisting too, the ridiculous 1,000 rupees penalty on companies should be significantly enhanced.</p>
<p>Source - PRIME Data Base</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
