<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="38524" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Scor first half profits climb 40 pct.</title>
<headline>Scor first half profits climb 40 pct.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's leading insurer Scor reported on Friday a 40 percent jump in first-half profit and was upbeat about full-year prospects.</p>
<p>Net attributable profit for the six months to June 30 climbed to 288 million francs ($56.7 million) from 206 million on turnover which rose 10.6 percent to 6.5 billion francs.</p>
<p>This year &quot;barring any surprises will definitely be a good year,&quot; Scor chairman Jacques Blondeau told a news conference.</p>
<p>He added that the second-half was traditionally a better period for Scor than the first half because of seasonal factors.</p>
<p>In 1995, Scor's full-year profit jumped 85 percent to 522 million francs.</p>
<p>Scor said the rise in turnover was powered particularly by a &quot;sustained performance&quot; by life reinsurance.</p>
<p>Scor shares were up one franc at 213 francs against an overall weaker market at midday following the profits announcement.</p>
<p>The company said its acquisition of U.S. insurer Allstate's reinsurance portfolio earlier this year had allowed it to double its market share in the United States, the number one reinsurance market in the world.</p>
<p>A source close to the company said the price of the Allstate acquisition &quot;had not been far off&quot; the $100 million estimated by some insurance analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;The Allstate portfolio complements that of Scor and it has very little exposure to natural catastrophe risks,&quot; Blondeau said.</p>
<p>Scor said it was pursuing development in southeast Asia with the signing of a cooperation deal with ThaiRe covering life reinsurance in Thailand. It has a new office in Rio de Janeiro.</p>
<p>-- Jean Michel Belot, Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452 ($ = 5.077 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8200318">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
