<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="38534" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German call money steady around 3.0 percent.</title>
<headline>German call money steady around 3.0 percent.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>German call rates remained stable around three percent on Friday morning with ample liquidity going into the weekend.</p>
<p>Money market traders said they expect rates to remain around current levels for the foreseeable future with the Bundesbank expected to stick to a fixed 3.0 percent securities repurchase rate.</p>
<p>&quot;Conditions have returned to normal after rates shot up last week at the end of the month,&quot; one money market analyst said. &quot;I see rates steady for some time.&quot;  </p>
<p>Traders said the Bundesbank's 2.1 billion mark net injection into the banking system in Wednesday's allocation was well timed and prevented rates from climbing.</p>
<p>Many expect the Bundesbank to stick to the fixed tender for the time being, even though it normally says it prefers a variable rate.</p>
<p>With the U.S. maybe leaning toward lifting rates, traders said there is a risk that a variable rate could be bid higher at a time when the Bundesbank would want it to remain stable.</p>
<p>&quot;A variable rate could send mixed signals,&quot; the money market analyst said.  </p>
<p>Banks held 37.8 billion marks with the Bundesbank on Thursday, down from 39 billion mark the day before. That pushed the average for the month down to 39 billion marks from 39.3 billion marks.</p>
<p>Banks did not borrow any significant amount of money from the emergency Lombard lending facility on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Frankfurt Interbank Overnight Average on Friday was 3,07600, slightly lower than Thursday's 3,09200.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom 49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
