<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="385513" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: WORLD BONDS - EMU delay need not batter BTPs, Bonos.</title>
<headline>WORLD BONDS - EMU delay need not batter BTPs, Bonos.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Thorpe</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A delayed entry into European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) by Italy and Spain would not be a spread disaster, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The spread between yields of Italian and Spanish bonds and benchmark German Bunds would certainly swell, but the significant turnaround in finances of both countries would prevent a full scale meltdown, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly there is a limit to deterioration,&quot; said Bruno Rovelli, economist at Bank of America in Milan. &quot;The improvement fundamentally is strong enough to cap the deterioration.&quot;</p>
<p>Gaps between 10-year BTPs and Bonos and Bunds shrank all last year amid market enthusiasm that Italy and Spain would have a fair shot at getting into EMU starting in 1999.</p>
<p>Government spending has been slashed, deficits pruned, inflation at least partly tamed, and interest rates cut, helping to send the BTP/Bund gap to 180 basis points from around 475 at the beginning of last year.</p>
<p>The Bonos/Bund gap has squeezed to 120 basis points from around 375 during the same time.</p>
<p>But analysts said it would still be difficult for Italy and Spain to meet the EMU criteria, which calls for deficits to be no more than three percent of GDP.</p>
<p>They said a mini-budget will be needed to cut costs further in Italy but Prime Minister Romano Prodi said late on Monday one was only &quot;very probable&quot; but not definite.</p>
<p>His remarks helped send the BTP/Bund spread shooting out six basis points early on Tuesday from the close on Monday. The lira also skidded amid renewed pessimism about Italy's EMU prospects.</p>
<p>Such spread turbulence was to be expected but major a widening on a formal delay was unlikely, analysts said.</p>
<p>Rovelli at Bank of America said the prospects for the Italian spread would depend on whether Italy was offered a deal to be admitted later, as reported in a Financial Times story in early February. The report was officially denied by the Italian and German governments and the European Commission.</p>
<p>&quot;The worst case scenario would be one if EMU goes ahead according to schedule in 1999 and Italy doesn't have a guarantee or informal arrangement to start at a later stage,&quot; he said. &quot;In this situation, I would expect the spread to go to around 250.&quot;</p>
<p>Such a target was still well away from the 475 basis points registered at the beginning of 1996 when EMU convergence plays really started to heat up.</p>
<p>And it was far off the historic high of 757 basis points hit on October 8, 1992, weeks after the lira came out of the European Exchange Rate Mechanism, Rovelli said.</p>
<p>If Italy does get a guarantee that it would eventually be admitted, the spread could eventually shrink to around 120 to 130 basis points, after any short-term swelling, he said.</p>
<p>Ifty Islam, European bond strategist at Merrill Lynch in London, agreed an improvement in the domestic fundamentals of Italy and Spain would protect speads from a dramatic widening.</p>
<p>He said a recent informal poll of 36 market participants carried out by Merrill came up with average spread forecast of 177 basis points if Italy's entry was delayed until 2002 and only 284 basis points if it was excluded from EMU altogether.</p>
<p>The average spread forecast if Spain's entry was delayed until 2002 was 128 basis points and 213 if it was excluded.</p>
<p>&quot;There doesn't seem to be much of a premium in the market on Italy joining in 1999,&quot; Islam said.</p>
<p>Phyllis Reed, European bond strategist at BZW in London, said two other factors would help prevent a huge spread widening. Both the lira and the peseta were now more fairly valued against the mark and a large part of the bond markets, particularly the Spanish market, was domestically held.</p>
<p>&quot;Just how far you want to sell the market you've got to be careful,&quot; she said. &quot;We're not looking for 500 (basis points).&quot;</p>
<p>-- International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
