<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="385661" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Shuttle astronauts walk to fit shades on Hubble.</title>
<headline>Shuttle astronauts walk to fit shades on Hubble.</headline>
<byline>Steven Young</byline>
<dateline>JOHNSON SPACE CENTRE, Texas 1997-02-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spacewalking astronauts finished upgrading the Hubble Space Telescope on Monday and began patching the telescope's cracked, peeling skin.</p>
<p>NASA officials had ordered repairs to rips in the silvery insulation that protects the telescope's insides from extreme temperature swings in orbit.</p>
<p>A fifth spacewalk, added to the mission to complete the repairs, got under way at about 10:20 p.m. (0320 GMT on Tuesday). Discovery crewmen Mark Lee and Steve Smith were to tackle the most critical damage during the impromptu four-hour outing.</p>
<p>The rips and cracks, which were extensive on the sun-facing side of the telescope, were thought to be caused by harsh ultraviolet radiation from the sun.</p>
<p>Engineers were concerned that crucial electronic components could overheat if nothing was done before the shuttle's next service call to the telescope, scheduled for December 1999.</p>
<p>Earlier on Monday spacewalkers Greg Harbaugh and Joe Tanner made the last of 10 upgrades to Hubble, installing a new control box for the telescope's power-generating solar panels and fitting covers over a pair of magnetic sensors.</p>
<p>The two men rode on the end of the shuttle's robot arm to reach the top of the four-story telescope for their final servicing task.</p>
<p>&quot;Boy, I'm glad I'm not too afraid of heights,&quot; Tanner joked as the arm lifted them 50 feet (15 metres) above the shuttle's cargo bay.</p>
<p>The astronauts quickly completed the work, placing box-shaped thermal covers over the sensors that help determine the telescope's position.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that's a wrap,&quot; Harbaugh quipped.</p>
<p>With the last task of the $350 million service call done, the astronauts turned their attention toward patching up two insulation tears near the top of the telescope.</p>
<p>The two men used wire and metal clips to lash two one foot by three foot (0.3 metres by one metre) strips of spare insulation over the torn material. They worked mostly by torchlight as the shuttle orbited in darkness.</p>
<p>&quot;Well guys, I guess we really left our mark on the telescope,&quot; Harbaugh said as the two men stood back and admired their handiwork.</p>
<p>The astronauts were back inside the shuttle at 5:15 a.m. EST (1015 GMT) after nearly six and a half hours outside.</p>
<p>While the astronauts toiled overhead, engineers on the ground hurried to finalise plans for the construction of makeshift patches to cover two torn and tattered electronic compartments. A wire mesh was fabricated to hold peeling insulation to a third box.</p>
<p>&quot;The equipment behind these bays is crucial for the operation of the telescope,&quot; Kenneth Ledbetter, a senior Hubble manager said.</p>
<p>Supplies were limited and Discovery's co-pilot Scott Horowitz was urged not to start work on the shuttle's middeck until engineers were sure they had properly calculated all the dimensions.</p>
<p>&quot;We are using up absolutely everything we have, and if we get something cut the wrong length then we will have done a bad thing,&quot; astronaut Jeff Hoffman warned from mission control.</p>
<p>Ground controllers faxed the crew five pages of instructions and 14 diagrams to show them how to use scissors, wire cutters, crimp tools and sticky tape to construct the sunshades from spare insulating foil, electrical wire, ropes, cords, alligator clips and wrap ties.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the middeck to look as neat as your garage,&quot; Hoffman joked with Horowitz.</p>
<p>If all goes according to plan, the astronauts will release Hubble back into orbit early on Wednesday morning. Discovery is due back at Florida's Kennedy Space Centre on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHNSON SPACE CENTRE, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
