<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="385747" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Juppe hints at climbdown on French immigration law.</title>
<headline>Juppe hints at climbdown on French immigration law.</headline>
<byline>Paul Taylor</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Prime Minister Alain Juppe hinted on Tuesday at a climbdown in the face of mounting opposition to an immigration bill that would oblige citizens to report to the police when foreign guests left their home.</p>
<p>Juppe told parliament his conservative government was &quot;open to discussion&quot; if legislators suggested an effective alternative way of checking that foreigners did not overstay their visas.</p>
<p>&quot;If the National Assembly finds a better formula, the government is open to discussion as long as the objective of an effective control on entry and departure is maintained,&quot; he said amid angry exchanges at question time.</p>
<p>Responding to criticism from the conservative-led French Mayors Association, Juppe also said the state could take over responsibility from mayors for supervising the presence of Third World foreigners if parliament so decided.</p>
<p>The immigration bill is due to be debated on a second reading next Tuesday. Thousands of intellectuals, artists and show business personalities have signed appeals denouncing the legislation and calling for civil disobedience.</p>
<p>Juppe, given a standing ovation by centre-right coalition deputies, branded such calls extremely dangerous, saying they played into the hands of the extreme-right National Front, which the intellectuals sought to combat.</p>
<p>Socialist opposition leader Lionel Jospin earlier urged Juppe to withdraw the bill which he said was &quot;despicable&quot; in spirit and &quot;useless&quot; in practice.</p>
<p>As a politician he could not advocate civil disobedience, but as a &quot;private citizen&quot; he could not imagine reporting to the police if a foreign friend left his home, Jospin said.</p>
<p>Juppe criticised this as a &quot;fallacious distinction&quot;. He said differentiating between legal and illegal immigration was &quot;the best rampart against racism and xenophobia&quot;.</p>
<p>But Socialist floor leader Laurent Fabius, a member of the left-wing government that introduced &quot;accomodation certificates&quot; for foreigners in 1982, warned Juppe he would create a &quot;moral fracture&quot; in France if he did not withdraw the bill.</p>
<p>New petitions against the bill sprouted like mushrooms on Tuesday with magistrates, architects, psychologists and students joining the ranks of protesters.</p>
<p>Civil rights and anti-racist groups, backed by the left-wing opposition, have called demonstrations for Thursday, Saturday and next Tuesday, the day of the assembly debate.</p>
<p>In a bid to help the government off the hook, Gilles de Robien, parliamentary floor leader of the centre-right Union for French Democracy, suggested an amendment whereby it would be up to the foreigner himself to declare his arrival and departure.</p>
<p>Juppe said he trusted veteran Gaullist deputy, Pierre Mazeaud, who has called a news conference for Wednesday to offer a &quot;solution&quot; to the dispute but refused to disclose its content.</p>
<p>The National Front, which advocates expelling three million immigrants, meanwhile derided the bill as a &quot;half-measure&quot; that showed the government was not serious about halting immigration.</p>
<p>The Front's number two, Bruno Megret, said in a radio interview that the intellectuals displayed a &quot;near-totalitarian conformism&quot; and were totally out of touch with the people.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a severe sign of degeneracy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We must bring the number of immigrants down below the threshold of tolerance...There are millions who go back to their country of origin every year on holiday. Let them stay there. It's a question of national survival,&quot; Megret said.</p>
<p>He said the new National Front city council in Vitrolles, which his wife conquered in an election this month, would sack dozens of &quot;totally ineffective&quot; social workers to create more jobs for the police in the town north of Marseille.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
