<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="385996" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: EMU provokes currency players to expand horizons.</title>
<headline>EMU provokes currency players to expand horizons.</headline>
<byline>Astrid Zweynert</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Banks will have to navigate efficiently within a variety of markets in the post-EMU world to be major players in foreign exchange, senior executives at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell (DMG) told Reuters in an interview. &quot;Post-EMU, there will be increased interaction between FX, capital markets -- in particular bonds -- and derivatives,&quot; said Zar Amrolia, head of FX sales for Europe. &quot;To get the business in foreign exchange you need to be a credible player in the other two as well.&quot;</p>
<p>Albert Maasland, global head of FX marketing, said DMG's strategy was to concentrate trading as much as possible in the most appropriate place but to have a decentralised sales force, close to the client. The link between financial markets has become stronger through technological changes that help to speed up flows of information between clients and banks globally. With a large-scale single currency area emerging in Europe at the turn of the century, trade barriers will come down further and increase the globalisation of markets, said Maasland. &quot;Not very long ago, the foreign exchange industry was made up by a number of local markets with limited interaction. Increasingly, barriers are coming down, and this will accelerate with EMU,&quot; said Maasland. &quot;But within a single currency Europe you will still have customers from many different countries who are used to doing business their way,&quot; said Maasland. In ever more globalised markets, there will be less space for niche players, said Amrolia. The increase in electronic broking has already driven many smaller players out of the market, a process that is likely to pick up speed with EMU. But the loss of liquidity in the FX market cannot be entirely blamed on electronic broking as increasing competition among banks and growing concentration of market share has also taken its toll. Many fear the days of the giddy trading profits of 1992/93 are gone forever. Banks are forced to worry more about the costs and returns of their FX operations, and not only about revenues and profits. The drive is towards better quality business. &quot;To be successful we have to be rather like an upscale department store than a bargain basement shop-style of provider,&quot; said Dan Almeida, DMG's global head of FX trading. Customers are becoming increasingly sophisticated and want to be more involved in developing strategies. &quot;It's no longer simply waiting for the phone to ring and quoting a price which comes from a trader,&quot; said Almeida. &quot;The business has evolved enormously.&quot; Strategies developed jointly between customers and salespeople are a key component of DMG's approach.</p>
<p>As several active European currencies will disappear with EMU, new markets beckon. Interest in exotic currencies has rocketed in recent years and will grow even more once the single currency is established. &quot;Customers' awareness of those markets has increased rapidly in the past few years, and demand for those products will increase even more with EMU,&quot; said Sikander Kanji, global head of forward FX. Ten years ago investors were not focused on east Europe or south-east Asia, said Kanji. A recent survey of DMG clients showed, however, that awareness of those markets is growing. &quot;Key questions are the issue of convertibility and how can they use modern financial methods to manage exposure to these markets,&quot; said Kanji. Another problem for some of the emerging markets is lack of liquidity at present but others, such as the &quot;tigers&quot; of South East Asia, are just as liquid as the mainstream European markets, he added. How much of the trading in emerging markets currencies will be done in London post-EMU is difficult to estimate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
