<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="38596" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Strikes grow as British unions get confidence back.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Strikes grow as British unions get confidence back.</headline>
<byline>Alan Raybould</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's trade unions, for 17 years the Conservative government's scapegoat for the country's economic ills, are growing in confidence as the next general election approaches, and strikes are on the increase.</p>
<p>&quot;Trade unionism is still around, and still capable of having a scrap,&quot; John Monks, leader of the Trades Union Congress (TUC), told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Postal workers have staged a series of 24-hour strikes this summer in protest at new working arrangements and London underground railway drivers have struck over a package that offered a cut in hours but a cut in wages, too, to pay for it.</p>
<p>Other railway workers, social security staff, dockers and car workers have also taken action.</p>
<p>&quot;The current spate of public sector strikes could be a prelude to the worst &quot;winter of discontent' for many years,&quot; said solicitors Dibb Lupton Broomhead, specialists in employment law, in their annual survey of unions and employers in August.</p>
<p>The infamous &quot;winter of discontent' in 1978/79 when trade unionists striking against a Labour government's pay policy left rubbish uncollected in the streets and the dead, it was reported, unburied in morgues. It also helped usher the Conservatives back into power.</p>
<p>The Confederation of British Industry, Britain's main employers' group, said the number of strikes was still low and it felt industrial relations were based much less on conflict these days.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't think this is a return to the 1970s,&quot; said a spokeswoman. &quot;We're definitely not seeing a reversion to a &quot;strike culture'.&quot;</p>
<p>Strike figures back that up, even if they are on the rise.</p>
<p>Government statistics show that 228,000 working days were lost to labour disputes in June. That was the highest monthly figure since March 1990, and the mail and railway disputes will have pushed it higher still in July and August.</p>
<p>In 1995, 410,000 days were lost to strikes, up from 280,000 in 1994. But that 1994 figure was the lowest since records began, and the 1995 number is still a far cry from the average 6.7 million days lost a year in the 20 years from 1975 to 1994.</p>
<p>TUC membership has dwindled to below seven million from a 1970s peak of 13 million, with the decline of heavy industry, low recruitment in services and anti-union laws all responsible.</p>
<p>The Conservatives have made it harder for unions to organise in the workplace and stripped away many of the immunities from the law they previously enjoyed when taking action.</p>
<p>But unions have turned some of the laws to their advantage, and their new tactics also help explain the fall in strikes.</p>
<p>In particular, the government stopped &quot;wild-cat&quot; walkouts and strikes imposed by union leaders by making unions hold ballots before a stoppage, or risk severe financial penalties.</p>
<p>At first outraged at this affront to internal democracy, the unions soon found the law had its uses.</p>
<p>As the TUC, Britain's main union umbrella group, said in a survey last month: &quot;Unions are taking a cool-headed, tactical approach to action. They increasingly use ballots as an effective bargaining lever to show employers the strength of employee feeling.&quot;</p>
<p>John Kelly, industrial relations expert at the London School of Economics (LSE), said unions often only had to show employers a positive ballot result to secure a satisfactory pay rise.</p>
<p>&quot;In effect, what the balloting laws have done is substitute for strike action a credible strike threat,&quot; Kelly said.</p>
<p>The TUC found that, after 63 percent of ballots, unions reached agreement with employers without needing to take action.</p>
<p>Thus, in July, a strike over pay by pilots and flight engineers at British Airways was averted at the last minute when management acceded to the demands of the pilots' union, BALPA, which had won 90 percent support for a strike in a ballot.</p>
<p>Even when a strike goes ahead, the ballot usually means a union has the workforce solidly behind it, and disputes are more often than not resolved within a day or two, the TUC said.</p>
<p>All the same, both the Dibb Lupton survey and the TUC's own soundings suggest the number of strikes will continue to rise.</p>
<p>One reason is that union confidence is growing due to a belief that a Labour government -- even one led by moderate Tony Blair, who has cut their influence within the party -- will replace the Conservatives in an election to be held by mid-1997.</p>
<p>Blair has refused to repeal the hated &quot;anti-union&quot; laws, but will give employees and unions more rights in the workplace.</p>
<p>However, Kelly at the LSE said a tighter labour market was the main factor. He noted a similar rise in strikes around 1989 as unemployment fell after strong economic growth from 1986.</p>
<p>John Edmonds, leader of the big general union, the GMB, told Reuters that insecurity at work and simmering resentment at high company profits would inevitably mean more strikes.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not going to come through in a new &quot;winter of discontent', but there is going to be an increase in industrial action, much more selective than in the past,&quot; Edmonds said.</p>
<p>That view is shared by Monks at the TUC.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy is getting better, and there are opportunities, at least for some workers, to say it's about time our interests were taken more into account by employers,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
