<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="386159" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian crude steady, relief Oman trades at premium.</title>
<headline>Asian crude steady, relief Oman trades at premium.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asia crude prices were steady to firmer on Tuesday as sellers indicated some relief that first Oman April deals were at a premium.</p>
<p>Traders said two cargos of April Oman were traded at MPM +3 cents and +4 cents -- levels which most traders deemed as reasonable given expectations of a much weaker market.</p>
<p>The traded levels were lower than March deals, although one late March deal was heard between MPM +1/5 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;Anything that shows trading has been done at a reasonable level is not a bad start,&quot; one trader said, reflecting the view that Oman could dip in coming days to a discount to MPM.  </p>
<p>Oman's differential with quoted Dubai went out to $1.14 per barrel for April trading from $1.04 when most players had expected the differential to come in to reflect the weaker seasonal trend.</p>
<p>Paper markets were also steady with Brent/Dubai and Dubai intermonths spreads little change from Monday.</p>
<p>A second-quarter Dubai traded between European majors at $17.85 per barrel.</p>
<p>March Tapis swaps were also holding day-earlier levels, quoted at $22.05/$22.30 per barrel. A second quarter/four quarter spread was traded at 91 cents.  </p>
<p>Regional markets were quiet as Indonesia players waited for the final March allocation figures from Pertamina.</p>
<p>Traders said they expected the Minas allocation to be at least 100,000 barrels per day (bpd), if not higher at 120,000/130,000 bpd due to the Dumai refinery turnaround.</p>
<p>Other allocations, such as for Duri are also expected to rise owing to the Dumai shut down.</p>
<p>This was already depressing prices, with Minas talked in a range of ICP 30 to 60 cents.</p>
<p>--Singapore, N Fullick (+65 870 3081), Tokyo, M. Yoshikawa (+813 5473 3706)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
