<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="386279" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai shares end sharply down on Deng rumours.</title>
<headline>Shanghai shares end sharply down on Deng rumours.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai's A and B share indices closed sharply down on Tuesday on market rumours about the health of Chinese leader Deng Xiaoping, brokers said.</p>
<p>The A share index lost 91.94 points or 8.97 percent to 932.783 on volume of 661.1 million shares worth 6.3 billion yuan. The B share index shed 4.754 points or 6.97 percent to 63.455 on volume of 42.8 million shares worth $20.1 million.</p>
<p>The indices opened higher against Monday's close but rumours on Deng's health began circulating around mid-morning, depressing market sentiment and driving prices down for the rest of the session, brokers said.  </p>
<p>China's Foreign Ministry said on Tuesday there had been no major change in the health of 92-year-old paramount leader Deng Xiaoping.</p>
<p>&quot;Buying retreated with the rumours, and liquidation selling pushed the index down sharply,&quot; one broker said. &quot;Investors are very nervous about the rumours.&quot;</p>
<p>Another broker said the market was likely to rebound after the sharp falls if there is no major negative news.</p>
<p>Of 43 B shares, 42 traded with all falling.  </p>
<p>Shanghai Industry Sewing Machine was the biggest loser, slipping $0.018 or 10.22 percent to $0.158 on volume of 139,000 shares.</p>
<p>Shanghai Chlor Alkali followed on institutional liquidation selling, falling $0.034 or 10.05 percent to $0.304 on volume of 1.8 million shares.</p>
<p>Shanghai Lujiazui Finance and Trade Zone Development traded the most on overseas selling, dipping $0.068 or 7.88 percent to $0.794 on volume of 3.4 million shares.</p>
<p>Shanghai A shares fell on the same factors with institutions taking profit and doing unwinding selling, brokers said.  </p>
<p>The SSE 30 index slipped 254.175 points or 9.42 percent to 2443.012 points.</p>
<p>Beiman Special Steel was the biggest A share loser, falling 0.45 yuan or 10.06 percent to 4.02 yuan on volume of 11.4 million shares.</p>
<p>--Shanghai newsroom (86-21)6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
