<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="386421" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: N.Korea seen hinting it may allow Hwang to defect.</title>
<headline>N.Korea seen hinting it may allow Hwang to defect.</headline>
<byline>Moon Ihlwan</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Korea has suggested it may accept the defection of a top Pyongyang official taking refuge in South Korea's embassy in China, saying it would dismiss him if he sought asylum, Seoul officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is certain North Korea is changing its attitude,&quot; said Kim Kyung-woong, a senior official at the state South-North Dialogue Office.</p>
<p>&quot;North Korea appears to be acknowledging that things are not developing as it wants in the Hwang Jang-yop case,&quot; he said. &quot;North Korea is widening its options.&quot;</p>
<p>North Korea had maintained that Seoul kidnapped Hwang Jang-yop, ranked 24th in Pyongyang's hierarchy. Seoul has called the claim &quot;preposterous&quot;.</p>
<p>Pyongyang's Foreign Ministry, commenting on the highest level defection yet from the Stalinist nation, said that if Hwang had been kidnapped, then North Korea would take &quot;decisive countermeasures&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Our stand is simple and clear. If he was kidnapped, we cannot tolerate it and we will take decisive countermeasures,&quot; said a ministry statement, carried by its official media.</p>
<p>But the statement late on Monday added: &quot;If he sought asylum, it means that he is a renegade and he is dismissed.&quot;</p>
<p>It added that North Korea had asked Beijing to investigate what it called the disappearance of Hwang, a senior aide to North Korean leader Kim Jong-il and a member of the powerful secretariat of the ruling Workers' Party.</p>
<p>Another senior Seoul official, who asked not to be identified, said: &quot;The statement's wording signals that North Korea might accept Hwang's defection.&quot;</p>
<p>Hwang, chief architect of North Korea's &quot;Juche&quot; ideology, a doctrine of fanatic self-reliance, arrived at Seoul's mission in Beijing last Wednesday, putting Beijing in a quandary over how to usher him out of China.</p>
<p>Allowing Hwang to go to Seoul, where he could be expected to reveal crucial secrets about the North, would offend Beijing's old communist comrade. Sending him back to Pyongyang would endanger China's ties with South Korea, its new capitalist friend and a valuable investor.</p>
<p>The North Korean statement was issued after the North's ambassador was believed to have met officials at China's Foreign Ministry on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the statement was issued after Pyongyang consulted with China,&quot; said Nam Man-kwon, a senior fellow at Seoul's state-financed Institute of Defence Analysis.</p>
<p>&quot;China might have persuaded North Korea that its hardline position would push it to a more difficult situation,&quot; Nam said. &quot;Hwang Jang-yop's case could now be resolved earlier than we had expected.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright voiced U.S. concern over events on the Korean peninsula, saying they underlined the need for dialogue between the two Korea's, still techinically at war since their 1950-53 war ended in a truce.</p>
<p>South Korea was on alert for possible attacks by Pyongyang as the Cold War crisis escalated, but said confrontation over the defector would not scuttle its efforts for detente.</p>
<p>Another prominent defector, Li Il-nam, a nephew of North Korean leader Kim's former wife, remained in a coma after being shot and critically wounded at the weekend by suspected North Korean agents near Seoul.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
