<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="386409" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China tightens guard around North Korean defector.</title>
<headline>China tightens guard around North Korean defector.</headline>
<byline>Mure Dickie</byline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea on Tuesday searched for a way to break an impasse over a high-level North Korean figure holed up in its embassy in Beijing after Pyongyang appeared to back away from its hard line on the defection.</p>
<p>However, Chinese police guarding the mission where Hwang Jang-yop remained marooned for a seventh day went on higher alert, sending three armoured personnel carriers rumbling into the sedate diplomatic quarter overnight to back up squads of police armed with assault rifles.</p>
<p>Seoul and Beijing were working to find a solution to the three-way diplomatic crisis that has thrown relations between China and the two Koreas into turmoil, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;Negotiations with the Chinese government are still going on,&quot; said South Korean embassy spokesman Chang Moon Ik, but declined to give details.</p>
<p>He dismissed reports that three-way talks between Beijing, its old communist ally Pyongyang and its new capitalist friend Seoul were under way to break the deadlock over Hwang's fate.</p>
<p>In Seoul, officials said North Korea had appeared to suggest it might accept Hwang's defection by saying it would dismiss him if he sought asylum.</p>
<p>&quot;It is certain North Korea is changing its attitude,&quot; said Kim Kyung-woong, a senior official at the state South-North Dialogue Office.</p>
<p>North Korea's Foreign Ministry said late on Monday it would fire Hwang, ranked 24th in Pyongyang's hierarchy and a senior aide to top leader Kim Jong-il, if he sought asylum in Seoul but warned of &quot;decisive countermeasures&quot; if it were proved he had been kidnapped by the South.</p>
<p>&quot;Our stand is simple and clear. If he was kidnapped, we cannot tolerate it and we will take decisive countermeasures,&quot; the Foreign Ministry said.</p>
<p>&quot;If he sought asylum, it means that he is a renegade and he is dismissed,&quot; it said, adding that it had asked Beijing to investigate what it called the disappearance of Hwang.</p>
<p>North Korea had so far maintained that Seoul kidnapped Hwang, architect of the Stalinist hermit nation's governing ideology of Juche, or strict self-reliance. Seoul dismissed the charge as preposterous.</p>
<p>The most senior leader to defect from North Korea spent his 74th birthday quietly on Monday, as former comrades outside demanded his return and issued harsh warnings to rival Seoul.</p>
<p>North Korean officials had kept vigil since the beginning of the crisis, but largely withdrew from the area on Tuesday.</p>
<p>China, an unwilling third party in the feuding between the two hostile sides of the Korean peninsula, has appealed to both sides to act calmly to resolve the affair.</p>
<p>The United States has urged Pyongyang to avoid all provocative actions and has said it is closely monitoring developments after an assassination attempt against a former North Korean defector near Seoul on Saturday night.</p>
<p>South Korea accused Pyongyang agents of shooting 32-year-old Li Il-nam in an attack that left him critically ill with a bullet still lodged in his skull. Doctors in Seoul said he was on life support and unlikely to regain consciousness.</p>
<p>The tussle over Hwang's defection is the latest flare-up in tense relations between the two Koreas, arch-enemies since the 1950-53 Korean civil war ended only in a truce.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
