<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="386518" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy economy seen growing 1.3 pct in '97 -Isco.</title>
<headline>Italy economy seen growing 1.3 pct in '97 -Isco.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy is not in recession and is likely to end 1997 with economic growth of 1.3 percent against 0.8 percent estimated for 1996, according to a half year report by state economic research institute Isco.</p>
<p>Isco said without additional measures to cut the budget deficit this year, the deficit could fall to 3.7 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) from 6.8 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>The objective of a three percent deficit to GDP ratio, which is one of the criteria for joining Europe's economic and monetary union, will then not be reached, posing &quot;a problem of choices for economic policy,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi said on Friday the 3.0 percent deficit to GDP ratio was reachable in 1997.</p>
<p>Speaking after a trip to Germany on Monday he said a corrective mini-budget was &quot;very probable&quot; later this year but the government would have to wait a few weeks to decide if it was absolutely necessary.</p>
<p>Isco said the expected economic recovery would be linked to exports and also to a &quot;modest rise in internal demand&quot; but it would not have positive effects on employment.</p>
<p>Price activity was seen moderating, with an annual average price growth of 2.4 percent in 1997 compared with 3.9 percent in 1996, &quot;due above all to squeezing in profit margins,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The government originally had an economic growth forecast for 1997 of 2.0 percent but Treasury Minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi said early in February that average growth would be above one percent and at most 1.5 percent.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +392 66129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
