<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="386661" id="root" date="1997-02-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks edge just firmer at open.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks edge just firmer at open.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A still buoyant bank sector led an otherwise listless Australian share market just higher at the open on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index added 3.6 points to 2,496.8.</p>
<p>Commonwealth Bank of Australia bounced back strongly after going ex-dividend on Monday, its shares up 1.4 percent to A$13.55 (US$10.38), while National Australia Bank and ANZ Bank also made solid gains, their shares up seven cents and four cents to A$17.01 and A$8.48 respectively.</p>
<p>&quot;The banks are pushing it but it is not all that strong,&quot; said a dealer at a Melbourne brokerage, noting the generally directionless trade and lack of investor inspiration.</p>
<p>&quot;I would expect it to be five to 10 points either way by the end of the day.&quot;</p>
<p>Others to feature in early trade included Golden Valley Mines, whose shares dived to an intraday low of six cents on heavy turnover of 15.5 million shares after an announcement from Canadian-based miner Bre-X Mineral on the controversial Indonesian Busang gold deposit failed to mention Golden Valley's joint venture partner.</p>
<p>Soft drink maker CC-Amatil continued to slide, losing 74 cents to an intraday low of A$12.20 as traders continued to show displeasure at Friday's soft 1996 year net profit of A$142.1 million.</p>
<p>Shares in grocery wholesaler Davids Ltd headed lower, down 12 cents to A$1.54, on fears over its ability to retain market share following Monday's announcement that grocery giant Woolworths intended to expand its wholesale division.</p>
<p>Rises outnumbered falls by a ratio of about six to five, while about 40 percent of stocks traded remained steady.</p>
<p>(A$1=US$0.77)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
