<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="386835" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IDT beefs up resale to offset call-back.</title>
<headline>IDT beefs up resale to offset call-back.</headline>
<dateline>HACKENSACK, N.J. 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>IDT Corp on Wednesday said the agreement recently struck by 68 countries to liberalize the global telecommunications market fits with its plans to expand as a reseller of international telecom services, its main source of revenue.</p>
<p>The company said it had already inked carrier resale deals in 12 countries that signed the global telecom accord.</p>
<p>In a statement, IDT sought to ease investor concerns that the pact represents a crushing blow to the company's prospects as a provider of call back services, which account for a smaller chunk of its business.  </p>
<p>IDT made its name as a pioneer in the international call back industry, which exploits differences in national phone rates to allow overseas calls to be made at U.S. rates.</p>
<p>IDT shares have slid steadily since early December when they traded around 14, reaching a 52-week low of 6-3/8 late last week. The stock was up an 1/8 to 6-7/8 Wednesday.</p>
<p>The company said it already had deals with Italy's Infostrada and the Dominican Republic's AAC&amp;R. Olivetti owns 67 percent of Infostrada, while Bell Atlantic Corp BEN holds the remainder of the venture.  </p>
<p>In addition, IDT said it was installing a facilities-based switch in London. That will allow it to haul its own traffic, reduce operating costs and enhance its capacity to offer a range of network services for its international customer base.</p>
<p>IDT said it planned to open its own switching bases in Hong Kong and other major worldwide cities during the next six months, which should permit it to operate more independently and provide lower international rates.</p>
<p>In addition, negotiations are under way with representatives in more than 25 countries to reach operating agreements to carry telecom traffic, the company said.  </p>
<p>Kaufman Brothers analyst John Money, who has placed a buy rating on the stock, said Wall Street fears were overblown.</p>
<p>IDT has forged ahead with a strategy to remake itself into a value-added reseller of long-distance services, he said.  </p>
<p>To be sure, Money said the company was still positioned to take advantage of rate arbitrage opportunities that are likely to exist until rate liberalization becomes a reality in individual nations, a process he forecast would take years.</p>
<p>He estimated that two-thirds of IDT's telecom revenues were currently derived from carrier-based business. Although the other third was related to call backs, he said only 20 percent of such revenues involved countries participating in the pact.</p>
<p>&quot;Net net the accord is not really going to hurt them too much,&quot; Money said. &quot;What they need to do is to put forth to the investment community a coherent statement of strategy that articulates where they see gaining competitive advantage.&quot;</p>
<p>The company has also suffered setbacks with its Internet access service business.</p>
<p>Last week IDT agreed to pay five states $250,000 in fines and give customers refunds as a part of a settlement regarding the Internet service's billing and advertising practices, according to New York Attorney General Dennis Vacco.</p>
<p>At the same time, IDT said it had laid off 140 employees, or more than a fourth of its workforce, and planned to focus its efforts on its telecommunication services businesses.</p>
<p>((-- E. Auchard, New York newsdesk, 212-859-1736))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HACKENSACK, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
