<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387205" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-COLE LEADS CHARGE AS UNITED WIN 2-1 AT ARSENAL.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-COLE LEADS CHARGE AS UNITED WIN 2-1 AT ARSENAL.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Striker Andy Cole reaffirmed his return to form by scoring one goal and creating another as Manchester United beat Arsenal 2-1 at the top of the English premier league on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>Cole, rejected by Arsenal as a youngster after just one appearance, put the champions ahead after 18 minutes in his first full league game of a frustrating season. He set up Norway's Ole Gunnar Solskjaer for United's second 14 minutes later.</p>
<p>Dutch striker Dennis Bergkamp scored for Arsenal after the break but the Londoners failed to find an equaliser.</p>
<p>The victory kept United a point clear of Liverpool, who spoilt Ian Rush's return to Anfield by beating Leeds 4-0, and carried them five points clear of third-placed Arsenal.</p>
<p>Stan Collymore scored twice in two minutes for Liverpool after Robbie Fowler had given Liverpool a 21st-minute lead. Jamie Redknapp scored the Merseysiders' fourth three minutes from time.</p>
<p>Trinidadian striker Dwight Yorke struck twice as Aston Villa beat Midlands neighbours Coventry 2-1 while Derby and Sheffield Wednesday shared in a 2-2 draw.</p>
<p>Newcastle's clash at West Ham was postponed due to a waterlogged pitch.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
