<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387280" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: ATHLETICS-ROMANIA'S NEGURA BANNED FOR STEROID USE.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-ROMANIA'S NEGURA BANNED FOR STEROID USE.</headline>
<byline>Radu Timofte</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's European women's cross country champion Iulia Negura was banned for two years on Wednesday for failing a doping test last year, the Romanian Athletics Federation said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Romanian Athletics Federation has banned Iulia Negura from all national and international competitions for a two-year period, dating from December 4, 1996,&quot; the Federation said in a statement.</p>
<p>Negura, 30, tested positive for the anabolic steroid stanozolol after winning the gold medal at the 1996 European cross-country championships in the Belgian town of Charleroi.</p>
<p>Her performance vaulted the national team into second place. The two medals will now be relinquished.</p>
<p>Both Negura, considered one of Romania's most prominent international athlete in recent years, and her coach Dorin Melinte denied she had taken banned substances.</p>
<p>Melinte quit his job as national long distance athletics coach after the incident, saying he could no longer work in an &quot;atmosphere of suspicion&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Both Iulia Negura and her trainer Dorin Melinte say she took no banned substances,&quot; the Federation statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;If such substances were found in samples, this could be due to a malicious act for which, unfortunately, they have no evidence for the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>The ruling was announced after a second urine sample, tested in the German city of Cologne, confirmed the initial positive result.</p>
<p>Several instances of doping have tarnished the image of Romanian athletics as competitors turned to illegal substances to win big cash prizes and foreign contracts and escape post-Communist poverty.</p>
<p>Nine athletes, eight of them women, have been banned in the last three years. Among them was 1993 indoor world champion long jumper Marieta Ilcu -- banned two years later.</p>
<p>Federation President Iolanda Balas told Reuters officials had limited Negura's ban to two years, instead of four years as stipulated by the International Athletics Federation, as the offence was her first in a long career.</p>
<p>&quot;A two-year ban is in accordance with a directive from the Romanian sports ministry introduced last year and applicable to all doping cases in all sports,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;In Iulia Negura's defence was the fact that she had been tested on repeated occasions with no violations.&quot;</p>
<p>Negura was unavailable for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
