<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387218" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: RUGBY UNION-RACE ROW TARNISHES S.AFRICAN RUGBY'S RAINBOW IMAGE.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-RACE ROW TARNISHES S.AFRICAN RUGBY'S RAINBOW IMAGE.</headline>
<byline>Ingeborg Lichtenberg</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African rugby played a key role in unifying the &quot;rainbow nation&quot; when its national squad won the World Cup in 1995 but its image has been tarnished by charges the sport is still rife with racism.</p>
<p>Since its World Cup triumph, a series of resignations and the shock firing of national hero and skipper Francois Pienaar have dragged the sport through the mud.</p>
<p>The final whistle was blown when national Springboks team coach Andre Markgraaff was forced to resign on Tuesday for using a term of gross racial abuse in reference to top black sports officials.</p>
<p>Markgraaff wept and said he was sorry if he had uttered the insult, covertly recorded on tape by a disgruntled player whose contract the coach had refused to negotiate -- further evidence of ungentlemanly squabbling in the sport.</p>
<p>Markgraaff called it &quot;blackmail&quot;. The media expressed indignation over the comment, but not much surprise.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the makeup it's the same old face,&quot; said one radio phone-in caller, referring to unreconstructed elements in the rugby hierarchy who appear to be scrumming down against progressives.</p>
<p>On the playing fields, rugby's image is little changed: stadiums are still filled by all-white supporters, many of them defiantly waving the old orange-white-blue South African flag of previous apartheid governments.</p>
<p>In a slap at the white preserve, Finance Minister Trevor Manuel caused a furore last year when he cheered New Zealand's All Blacks at a game against the Springboks.</p>
<p>In a country of five million whites and 37 million blacks struggling to heal the scars of decades of forced white supremacy, sport is playing an important role in the drive for national reconciliation.</p>
<p>For a while, rugby seemed part of that effort.</p>
<p>In the apartheid years, it had been an exclusively white game reviled by blacks, and South Africa, though once an international champion, was isolated from world competition.</p>
<p>As the country emerged from pariah status with the release from jail of President Nelson Mandela and the unbanning of his African National Congress (ANC) in 1990, it regained the global arena.</p>
<p>When South Africa was chosen to host the World Cup, and won it, Mandela put on one of his strongest shows of reconciliation -- which left few eyes dry -- coming on to the pitch after the final in South Africa's yellow and green rugby colours and embracing the team as &quot;our boys&quot;.</p>
<p>But the glow of triumph dimmed as efforts by some prominent players to develop the game among blacks were met with what sports writers described as a brick wall of political conservatism in the top echelons of the sport. The players resigned and the atmosphere soured.</p>
<p>The national squad was rocked when World Cup skipper Pienaar was fired by Markgraaff in a move some now believe had more to do with politics than with his athletic abilities.</p>
<p>&quot;Pienaar was for a new South Africa and did all he could to promote rugby in our country,&quot; one reader said in a letter to a newspaper. &quot;Pienaar and Markgraaff were not on the same political wavelengths. That is why Pienaar was not a part of the future plans of South African rugby.&quot;</p>
<p>The South African Rugby Football Union (SARFU) held an emergency meeting in Johannesburg on Wednesday to discuss how to try to repair the damage.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
