<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387216" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-PIENAAR BRANDS MARKGRAAFF'S COMMENTS IRRESPONSIBLE.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-PIENAAR BRANDS MARKGRAAFF'S COMMENTS IRRESPONSIBLE.</headline>
<byline>Barney Spender</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former South African captain Francois Pienaar branded racist comments by ousted Springbok coach Andre Markgraaff as &quot;irresponsible&quot; on Wednesday, but played down his chances of an international recall against the British Lions later this year.</p>
<p>Markgraaff, who dropped World Cup-winning captain Pienaar in October, resigned on Tuesday after a year in the job because of the comments he made about National Sports Council chairman Mluleki George.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a serious blow to South African rugby. We spent a lot of time building up trust among the communities and now this happens,&quot; said Pienaar, who left South Africa in December to join English first division club Saracens.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't make any sense out of it. But people must remember it is the irresponsible views of one person and not the views of the whole country, nor the views of the players.</p>
<p>&quot;Even so, the feeling over here now is going to be, have there actually been so many changes in sport in South Africa? It's a serious blow.&quot;</p>
<p>Pienaar, however, is among those who could ultimately benefit from Markgraaff's fall. A personality clash between the two led to Pienaar's omission from the Springbok tour party to Argentina, France and Wales at the end of last year and his subsequent move to England.</p>
<p>But the former captain was playing down his chances of a return to the international fold in time for the three-test series against the British Lions.</p>
<p>&quot;I haven't really thought about it, all of this has happened so quickly, but at this stage I don't really see myself being involved.</p>
<p>&quot;All I can say is that I am a very loyal person and that the people here at Saracens have shown great faith in me and I intend to repay that.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
