<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387364" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Albright hopes for smooth transition in China.</title>
<headline>Albright hopes for smooth transition in China.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright said on Wednesday that it would be a great advantage to China and to the rest of the world if there were a smooth transition of power in Beijing following Deng Xiaoping's death.  </p>
<p>Speaking to reporters after talks with British foreign minister Malcolm Rifkind, Albright called Deng &quot;a historic figure&quot;.</p>
<p>Deng was in power during the Tiananmen Square killings in June 1989, which Albright described as &quot;very troublesome&quot; in regard to China's human rights record. On the other hand, Deng was instrumental in opening up China to political and economic reforms, she added.</p>
<p>Rifkind said he assumed there would be a short period of uncertainty in China until a new leader emerged but hoped that the reform process would then soon regain speed.</p>
<p>Albright said officials were consulting with Beijing as to whether it was still convenient for her to stop in China next week on the last leg of her visit to Europe, Moscow and China.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
