<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387305" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: HUNGARY O/N RATES CLIMB UP TO 22.25 PERCENT.</title>
<headline>HUNGARY O/N RATES CLIMB UP TO 22.25 PERCENT.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's overnight rates continued to climb up slowly on Wednesday, suprising many dealers following Monday's repo rate cuts.</p>
<p>The overnight money closed at around 22.25, slightly up from Tuesday's 22.125 closing.</p>
<p>&quot;Expectations of repo cuts had been strong (before the cuts),&quot; said Sandor Szatmari of Unicbank. &quot;I believe considerable amounts may have went (before the cuts into reverse repo deals) to the National Bank of Hungary (NBH).&quot;</p>
<p>On Monday, the central bank cut all four repo rates by 0.5 percent, with the one-week reverse repo falling to 21 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;I think many banks placed substantial amounts in one-week reverse repo deals (before the repo cuts),&quot; said Levente Fulop of Magyar Fejlesztesi Bank, adding that this must have tightened the forint liquidity of some banks.</p>
<p>Traders said the banks needed money to replenish their reserves and for tax-payments on February 20.</p>
<p>However, money supply on the market has not weakened substantially and the overnight rates may reverse the current rising trend this week or early next week, traders said.</p>
<p>-- Sandor Peto, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
