<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387317" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Albright heads for Russia.</title>
<headline>Albright heads for Russia.</headline>
<byline>Carol Giacomo</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright ended consultations with allies on Wednesday ahead of talks in Moscow in which she will outline new sweetners aimed at assuaging Russia's fierce objections to NATO enlargement.</p>
<p>&quot;My purpose in going to Moscow is to lay out... a package that would make it clear to the Russians that enlargement of NATO is something positive (and) is based on creating a new sense of stability in central and eastern Europe,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>At a news conference with British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind, Albright said the package would be comprised of the conventional arms reduction proposal NATO approved on Wednesday and a more detailed proposal for a Russia-NATO charter that includes the concept of forming a joint military unit.</p>
<p>She also said that in talks with Russian leaders she would &quot;make it clear that they are repected members of the international community and they have global reponsibilities.&quot;</p>
<p>She leaves London on Thursday for talks with Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin and Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov in Moscow. She sees President Boris Yeltsin on Friday.</p>
<p>Albright declined to say whether a Russian demand for full inclusion in the Group of Seven leading industrial nations would be met. A senior U.S. official told Reuters this is not something the allies have agreed on.</p>
<p>London was the fifth stop on Albright's first overseas trip as top U.S. diplomat, a nine-nation tour of Europe and Asia.</p>
<p>Her main goal in Europe was to solidify NATO support for NATO enlargement and the sweetners, something accomplished at an alliance foreign ministers meeting on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Her last stop was to be Beijing on Feb 24. But officials said that visit was now uncertain because of the death of China's paramount leader Deng Xiaoping.</p>
<p>The alliance is due to formally decide which former Warsaw Pact states to invite to become the first new post-Cold War members at a July summit in Madrid. Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic are the top contenders.</p>
<p>Albright has made a point of making expansion appear inevitable, despite continued Russia opposition to the idea.</p>
<p>Even as she extends olive branches to Moscow with one hand, she had made clear in repeated statements that expansion will proceed whether or not Russia cooperates in negotiating a charter defining a special relationship.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Albright offered a new but still vague sweetner to Moscow in a proposal to create a joint NATO-Russia military unit for peacekeeping or other uses and a promise of close consultation at all levels of NATO's command structure.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the alliance approved a proposal for significant cuts in conventional arms in Europe below levels in the 1990 Conventional Forces in Europe treaty. Albright will cite this in Moscow as proof an expanded NATO would be non-threatening.</p>
<p>While specific numbers must be negotiated, a U.S. official said under the CFE proposal, NATO, which now has a three-to-one advantage over Russia, has vowed to slash further ground equipment like tanks, armoured personnel carriers and artillery.</p>
<p>CFE already has caused the United States, Russia and others of the pact's 30 signatories to eliminate more than 58,000 pieces of equipment from their forces in Europe.</p>
<p>The alliance has proposed to set national limits on arms, rather than the bloc-to-bloc limits now in the treaty. The proposal also inludes territorial limits, which would effectively cap foreign forces in a country, officials said.</p>
<p>The proposal establishes a &quot;sensitive geographic region&quot; in central Europe comprising Kaliningrad, Ukraine, Slovakia, Belarus, the Czech republic, Hungary and Poland and argues that ground equipment in that area cannot increase, officials said.</p>
<p>That means if Washington decided to deploy equipment in an expected new NATO member country like Poland, for instance, Poland's equipment levels must be decreased, they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
