<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387472" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Gencor Cerro Matoso buy seen helping growth.</title>
<headline>Gencor Cerro Matoso buy seen helping growth.</headline>
<byline>Marius Bosch</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gencor Ltd's purchase of the Colombian government's 46.58 percent stake in the Cerro Matoso nickel mine will help the company's growth beyond South Africa while at the same time consolidating its position in the global nickel market, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Gencor could also use the mine's cashflow to fund other acquisitions and developments like the Maggie Hays nickel project in Western Australia, owned jointly with Forestania Gold NL.</p>
<p>The South African mining house is also looking at nickel deposits in Cuba and Indonesia.</p>
<p>Gencor subsidiary Billiton BVI Ltd paid $165.8 million for the stake, pushing Gencor's shareholding in Cerro Matoso -- the world's fourth-largest nickel producer -- to 98.88 percent.</p>
<p>The company said in a statement that Cerro Matoso was a vital element in Gencor's South American and global nickel strategies. &quot;Acquisition of the additional shareholding will contribute to Gencor's international growth,&quot; Gencor said.</p>
<p>Analysts said Gencor had managed to gain control of a good asset. &quot;The reason for the purchase was that there was a tension between Gencor and the Colombian government. It really related around different assumptions as to what to do with the asset,&quot; said one mining financial analyst who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;They can control the cashflow, they can basically gear up the production and they will probably do very well,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Cerro Matoso produced just over 50 million pounds of high quality nickel in 1996.</p>
<p>Gencor says the mine can continue operating until at least 2027 and probably to 2041. &quot;Currently pre-feasibility studies are commencing for an expansion that could lead to doubling of production,&quot; the Gencor statement said.</p>
<p>The analyst said Gencor would probably use the cash flow from Cerro Matoso to fund other projects.&quot;Essentially what they would probably do is that they would use the cash flow to fund the development of say Maggie Hays or whatever else&quot;.</p>
<p>Another analyst said Gencor holding almost 99 percent of equity in Cerro Matoso was a positive development.</p>
<p>&quot;This is exactly what Gencor has been looking for, to get hold of projects that are going to generate good cash flow offshore and they can then take the income from those projects and use them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In addition to Maggie Hays, Gencor held a stake in an Indonesian nickel project with Australian nickel producer QNI Ltd.</p>
<p>The analyst said Gencor could also use cash from Cerro Matoso to fund a bid for the mining assets of Brazil's state-run Companhia Vale do Rio Doce (CVRD).</p>
<p>Brazilian officials said earlier this month that tender documents for the initial sell-off of the 40-45 percent controlling stake would be published by the latest on March 7.</p>
<p>Gencor said in December that it was considering a bid for the assets of the Brazilian mining giant.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27-11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
