<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387400" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LME copper holds on to bulk of gains by close.</title>
<headline>LME copper holds on to bulk of gains by close.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Copper managed to hold on to most of its heady gains on Wednesday afternoon as fears of further tightness kept the market on the boil.</p>
<p>Three months copper finished the afternoon kerb at $2,340 per tonne, off its 8-1/2 month high of $2,360 touched in the morning but up a respectable $54 on the day.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a crazy market. Everyone is a bit nervous,&quot; one floor trader said, adding that market tightness was showing wild variations among coming dates.</p>
<p>The immediate squeeze had evaporated, with cash for a day going into a 50-cent contango after steadily trading in the couple of weeks preceding the February date at backwardations of $23-25, the LME limit.</p>
<p>But tightness was developing in March and April, traders said. The March/April and April/May spreads flared to $40 and $43 backwardations respectively, up $6-$7 from Tuesday.</p>
<p>The premium of cash over three months metal firmed about $10 to $85/7. In addition, the option market saw a boost in activity from Wednesday's spike, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the market makers are definitely long for the second half, but there's speculative players who haven't got them and want them,&quot; an option trader said. Volatility had jumped a couple of points.</p>
<p>June $2,400 calls had traded at 21 percent volatility and June $2,450 calls at 21.5 percent this morning, with interest shown in March and April $2,350s and May $2,400s, he added.</p>
<p>Options traders also noted news that Asarco had bought calls at a strike price of 104 cents ($2,292 per tonne) to hedge 149.5 million lb of production as part of a synthetic put operation.</p>
<p>Whoever granted the calls would have had to cover their exposure when prices jumped above $2,300 unless they already had it in their books, dealers said.</p>
<p>But the second stage of the Asarco's move would be to sell forward the same amount of output above 104 cents, which could cap the market, they added.</p>
<p>Many of the other metals took a ride on copper's coat-tails.</p>
<p>Zinc notched up a fresh two-year high of $1,235, coming within a whisker of the January 1995 peak of $1,239. Another burst of fund buying could take it through there, but chartists noted the 14-day RSI was in overbought territory at 74.</p>
<p>The market ended the day $17 higher at $1,230.</p>
<p>Aluminium tried to cement its foothold back above $1,600, finishing at $1,604, up $20. The next major resistance area was seen at $1,620, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>Nickel leapt $255 to end at $7,910, but the market looked vulnerable, a chartist said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the face of severe resistance on the approach to $8,000, nickel has now completed a small top area and the risks are growing that there could be at least a secondary correction against the recent uptrend,&quot; said chartist David Charters of Investment Research of Cambridge.</p>
<p>The immediate target was $7,500, where the rising 30-day moving average came into play, with major support pegged at $7,300/$7,400.</p>
<p>Lead gained $13 to $670 and tin closed unchanged at $6,065.</p>
<p>Alloy finished $30 firmer at $1,530.</p>
<p>	 --Eric Onstad, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8065</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
