<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387433" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bre-X says would weigh bids at right price.</title>
<headline>Bre-X says would weigh bids at right price.</headline>
<byline>Darren Schuettler</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bre-X Minerals Ltd. said on Wednesday it would consider merger offers at the right price, but was content for now to develop Busang -- the richest gold discovery this century -- with its existing partners.</p>
<p>&quot;The 'For Sale' sign is not on the front yard,&quot; Bre-X Chief Executive David Walsh told analysts in a conference call. &quot;That is not to rule out discussions with a potential suitor if the price is right. The old expression 'everything has its price' must be taken into account here.&quot;</p>
<p>His comments came after an agreement announced on Monday on ownership of the Busang discovery in Indonesia. Under the deal, Bre-X would have 45 percent, with 15 percent to U.S.-based Freeport-McMoRan Copper and Gold Inc., 30 percent to Indonesia's PT Askatindo Karya Minerals and PT Amsya Lyna and partners and 10 percent to the Indonesian government.</p>
<p>Bre-X officials declined to speculate on potential bidders for their Calgary, Alberta-based company, which discovered the 71 million-ounce Busang gold find. Some Bre-X executives said the gold field, which was not yet fully explored, may contain as much as 200 million ounces of gold.</p>
<p>Walsh said Bre-X, which once owned 90 percent of the deposit, received no cash compensation for giving up a piece of Busang. But he said the Indonesian partners provided &quot;tangible value&quot; in developing the site.</p>
<p>&quot;This relationship will ensure that things run smoothly. Without a good relationship, things can take years to get processed, and years of hold up for a 4 million ounce a year producer is very, very costly,&quot; Walsh told Reuters.</p>
<p>Vancouver-based gold miner Placer Dome Inc. said on Wednesday its $5 billion offer to merge with Bre-X made before Monday's agreement was no longer feasible because Bre-X was now worth less. But Placer said it remained interested in the project and would like to hold talks with Bre-X.</p>
<p>Walsh said Bre-X would inform the Indonesian government if it agreed to a merger or sale of its Busang stake. But asked if a deal required government approval, Walsh replied: &quot;No.&quot;</p>
<p>Walsh added that Bre-X's Busang partners did not have rights of first refusal if Bre-X received a third-party offer.</p>
<p>He said the Indonesian government indicated it would process contracts of work, known as COWS, for the Busang site as early as possible. &quot;I do know the government has a wish to process these very, very quickly. So I would not think that we would have to wait very long,&quot; said Walsh.</p>
<p>A feasibility study of the project should be completed later in 1997, with construction of the mine expected to begin in 1998. Capital expenditure is estimated at about $1.5 billion.</p>
<p>Production was expected to begin in 2000 at a rate of two million ounces annually and climb to four million ounces a year in 2002, said John Felderhoff, Bre-X's senior vice-president of exploration.</p>
<p>Bre-X's latest estimate for the Busang Two area was about 71 million ounces of gold, but Felderhoff said it could be much higher. &quot;If you would ask me what is the total potential, I would feel very comfortable with 200 million ounces,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bre-X's financial adviser, J.P. Morgan and Co. Inc., said on Wednesday it would provide a fairness opinion on the agreement. &quot;We're very confident it provides very good value to the shareholders of Bre-X,&quot; said J.P. Morgan's Leslie Morrison, who is advising Bre-X on the deal.</p>
<p>Canadian newspapers reported on Wednesday that Indonesian businessman Jusuf Merukh alleged that the deal with Freeport and the Indonesian interests was illegal and asked Indonesian President Suharto to cancel it.</p>
<p>Merukh is suing Bre-X for $2 billion in a Canadian court, alleging that his company was entitled to 30 percent of Busang. Bre-X has filed a motion to dismiss the suit.</p>
<p>Bre-X topped Toronto Stock Exchange actives on Wednesday, gaining C70 cents to C$21.50 on 7.7 million shares after falling sharply Monday and Tuesday on news of the deal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
