<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387481" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: African ministers pursue peace mission in Zaire.</title>
<headline>African ministers pursue peace mission in Zaire.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Malu-Malu</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>African foreign ministers visited Zaire on a peace mission on Wednesday and Nelson Mandela of South Africa said he would host a meeting between the warring parties in the east of the sprawling Central African nation.</p>
<p>South Africa's foreign minister, Alfred Nzo, was among four African ministers visiting Kinshasa but there was no immediate Zairean government confirmation of any meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;Representatives of the contesting parties have made a request that they would like to meet in South Africa... to be able to discuss their problems,&quot; Mandela said in Cape Town.</p>
<p>He told reporters South Africa would send air transport to pick up Zaire's rebel leader from Kigali in Rwanda and that he hoped the talks could take place on Thursday.</p>
<p>Zaire has repeatedly rejected talks with rebel leader Laurent Kabila, dismissing him as a puppet of neighbouring Rwanda, Uganda and Burundi, which it accuses of invading in support of the rebels. All three deny the charge.</p>
<p>Earlier, Zaire criticised a U.N. Security Council resolution calling for a truce in the civil war as too timid, saying that it should have condemned aggressors in the conflict.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Kamanda wa Kamanda said there could be no truce for Zaire without a withdrawal of all foreign troops.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a timid advance. We sincerely regret that this resolution does not condemn the aggressors,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Tuesday's Security Council call was part of a five-point U.N. peace plan. It followed a request from U.N. special envoy Mohammed Sahnoun, who left Kinshasa for Rwanda on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Rwanda dismissed the resolution as &quot;absurd&quot;, saying it did not take account of rebel views.</p>
<p>Ethnic Tutsi rebels took up arms last October accusing the Zaire authorities of denying them nationality and of seeking to expel them to Rwanda, their ancestral home. They hold towns and territory along the border with Rwanda, Burundi and Uganda.</p>
<p>Zaire, which launched a counter-offensive on January 20, opened a new phase of the war on Monday by bombing rebel-held towns in the east. Relief workers there put the toll in the air raids to at least 19.</p>
<p>Zaire announced fresh raids on Tuesday. There was no independent confirmation of the raids.</p>
<p>The U.N. plan envisages an immediate ceasefire, withdrawal of all foreign forces, including mercenaries and respect for the national sovereignty and territorial integrity of Zaire and other states in the region.</p>
<p>Kamanda said that the resolution did not specify how the withdrawal of foreign troops would be accomplished or monitored. &quot;If the foreign troops do not pull out, we consider that there is no cessation of hostilities,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The plans also called for protection of refugees and displaced persons and a peaceful settlement of the crisis through dialogue, elections and the convening of an international conference on peace, security and development.</p>
<p>Organisation of African Unity (OAU) secretary-general Salim Ahmed Salim, himself expected in Kinshasa, said during a visit to Cameroon the OAU might organise a summit on the conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel very strongly that every effort must be made to contain the situation and find a solution,&quot; he said after talks in Yaounde with President Paul Biya, the current OAU chairman.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UGANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
