<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387538" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FEATURE-S.Africa's Marxists flirt with capitalism.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-S.Africa's Marxists flirt with capitalism.</headline>
<byline>Anton Ferreira</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cracks are appearing in the once monolithic Marxist facade of South African trade unions as former firebrands discover that capitalism might not be so bad after all.</p>
<p>In recent months several unions, including the powerful National Union of Mineworkers (NUM), have committed the previously unthinkable heresy of investing in the same big businesses against which they used to rail.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's a good thing,&quot; said political analyst David Welsh.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope it contributes to an unfreezing of these old ideas that seem to remain popular here, Cuba, North Korea and nowhere else.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no more corrupting force, if you're a Marxist, than capitalism, and to the extent that they're nibbling on these capitalist goodies I hope it rots their teeth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Labour analysts said unions were joining the drive for black empowerment, in which white-owned corporations are selling assets to blacks to improve their image, and were eyeing investments in parastatals up for privatisation.</p>
<p>According to Robin McGregor, who tracks company ownership in South Africa, unions in the black National Empowerment Consortium (NEC) have a 1.34 billion rand ($300 million) stake in the recently unbundled Johnnic.</p>
<p>He listed another major union stake as the 63.5 percent that mine and textile union leaders have taken in Hosken Consolidated Investments (HCI).</p>
<p>THRILL OF THE DEAL</p>
<p>Two of the unionists behind that deal are John Copelyn and Marcel Golding, both African National Congress members of parliament until they decided to join the corporate world.</p>
<p>&quot;Those people who focus too much on the cleanliness of each transaction they're doing and don't build a capital base are really missing the gap,&quot; Copelyn, former general secretary of the South African Clothing and Textile Workers Union, said in a recent newspaper interview.</p>
<p>Asked about his motives in becoming a market player, Golding, who had an ultra-leftwing reputation in the NUM, said: &quot;It's about the same thrills we had in the union: seeing the transaction, doing the negotiation, acquiring something.&quot;</p>
<p>While Copelyn and Golding plunge into high finance, some of their former union colleagues still divide the world into the working class and the bourgeoisie.</p>
<p>&quot;We accept that business represents the rich,&quot; Sam Shilowa, general secretary of the Congress of South African Trade Unions (Cosatu), said last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously the position of the poor and the working class is diametrically opposed to that of the rich.&quot;</p>
<p>PROFITS NOT ALL BAD</p>
<p>Labour analyst Duncan Innes said at least some union leaders were moving away from this kind of ideological position.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a growing recognition that the times have changed and that in the new political dispensation business is increasingly a partner in building a new democratic South Africa,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no longer the same feeling that capitalists and profits are completely bad.</p>
<p>&quot;I think a lot of unions are beginning to say, 'well in some way or another we need to be making investments in the new South Africa as well, we need to be finding ways in which our members can benefit from the growth and expansion of business'.&quot;</p>
<p>Innes said some unions were still concerned about the conflict of interest presented by workers obtaining an interest in their companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Those unions that are not really keen on this approach are concerned that their members will be pulled in two directions and it's going to dilute their militancy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Innes said some unions were studying the possibility of employee share ownership schemes, virtually unheard of in South Africa due to previous union opposition based on Marxist precepts.</p>
<p>&quot;So in addition to union provident funds buying into companies at the top, possibly we could see in the next year or so proposals coming out for employees to buy shares as well,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Innes said such schemes could lead to a more &quot;responsible&quot; attitude in a South African work force that has grown accustomed to using the strike as a basic bargaining tool.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
