<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387684" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria refinery ends limits on fuel distribution.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria refinery ends limits on fuel distribution.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's biggest oil refinery, Neftochim, has lifted the limits on its fuel distribution following a drastic hike of fuel prices, a spokeswoman said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;From today our clients can buy fuel as much as they wish as the prices were increased and we expect them to become higher soon,&quot; Tatyana Hadzhieva said by telephone.</p>
<p>The interim government, which inherited crippling fuel and grain shortages, raised petrol prices by up to 178 percent on Tuesday in a bid to free suppliers' volumes kept in storage. It also banned fuel exports until April 30 and troops enforced border controls in a bid to curb oil smuggling.</p>
<p>Since last Tuesday, Neftochim has distributed only some 1,000 tonnes of petrol and 1,000 tonnes of diesel per day in order to preserve its crude oil stocks. The refinery has been unable to pay for new supplies because of a lack of cash.</p>
<p>This led to a severe petrol crisis in the country and most petrol stations have been closed.</p>
<p>Municipalities are distributing petrol and diesel for ambulances, food delivery trucks, the police, the army and social services, officials said. Bus transport in towns has been strongly reduced causing problems for industry, they added.</p>
<p>The cash-stripped Bourgas refinery will continue refining some 9,000 tonnes of crude per day, down from 22,000 tonnes in December. It expects two more tankers with Russian crude by the end of the month, Hadzhieva said.</p>
<p>She added that Prime Minister Stefan Sofianski, who visited the refinery last week, has promised the help of the interim cabinet for opening new credit lines for Neftochim for buying crude.</p>
<p>The refinery, Bulgaria's only domestic supplier, owes millions of dollars to its crude suppliers.</p>
<p>A 61,500-tonne tanker from a private firm, Yukos Bulgaria, arrived on Tuesday at Bourgas port from Odessa, Hadzhieva said.</p>
<p>Sofianski announced on Friday plans for partial privatisation of the debt-ridden Neftochim refinery, but gave no further details.</p>
<p>-- Liliana Semerdjieva, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
