<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387730" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine corporate peso bond opens mkt for more.</title>
<headline>Argentine corporate peso bond opens mkt for more.</headline>
<byline>Axel Bugge</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The placement of the first peso-denominated corporate bond in the international markets by an Argentine borrower opens the way for more such issues and is fresh evidence of falling country risk, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's another good signal that investors don't see devaluation risk,&quot; said Roberto Costa Bourdieu, the senior fixed-income analyst at Banco Rio de la Plata.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect more of these kind of issues in the short-term.&quot;  </p>
<p>Argentina's CEI Citicorp Holdings SA last week announced a three-part Eurobond deal underwritten by Merrill Lynch, including a 10-year 175-million-peso bond.</p>
<p>It yielded 11.25 percent, compared with a 10-year $225 million bond by CEI on the same day that yielded 9.79 percent at issuance.</p>
<p>&quot;The greater confidence in Argentina's economy and the high international liquidity levels made the issue possible,&quot; Juan Casas, a director at Merrill Lynch, told Reuters.  </p>
<p>&quot;Possibly this bond will be followed by other firms,&quot; Casas added. He said it is important for Argentine companies to obtain international financing in pesos &quot;given that it diversifies the risk of their financing.&quot;</p>
<p>Merrill said the issue also marked the first time a Latin American borrower had issued bonds abroad in its domestic currency.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Argentine government's opening up of the international peso bond market with two recent bonds paved the way for corporations to tap the market as well.</p>
<p>&quot;The government made this possible,&quot; Bourdieu said.  </p>
<p>Taking advantage of the recent narrowing of spreads between dollar and peso bonds, Argentina launched its first ever international peso bond in December - a 250 million peso two-year issue with an 8.75 percent coupon.</p>
<p>It said at the time the issue was part of a strategy to gradually develop a peso yield curve which could be used as a reference point for the private sector.</p>
<p>The government topped the two-year issue at the end of January when it placed 500 million in 10-year peso Eurobonds with a coupon of 11.75 percent.  </p>
<p>Last week Miguel Kiguel, the undersecretary of finance, admitted that Argentina has even received offers to issue a 20-year peso bond but said there were no plans for such a placement now.</p>
<p>Other news, like the announcement by Moody's Investors Services at the end of January that it assigned a B1 rating to Argentina's peso-denominated long-term sovereign debt, has also helped the peso sector. The B1 grade is the same as Moody's rating on Argentina's foreign currency debt.</p>
<p>The government's opening of this market must be paying off traders said.  </p>
<p>The CEI bond was priced at 498 basis points over comparable U.S. Treasuries, while the government's 10-year issue came to market at 525 basis points over comparable U.S. Treasury issues.</p>
<p>While the cost of a peso-denominated bond is still more expensive than a dollar denominated bond -146 basis points more in the case of the CEI bonds - Hugo Diaz Lourenco, chief analyst at consultancy C&amp;E Consultores, points out it may be useful for companies with income in pesos to have peso debt.</p>
<p>Bourdieu says Argentine banks wanting to increase their peso mortgage loan portfolios may find issuing bonds like this abroad a useful way to finance more loans.  </p>
<p>Because the current high international liquidity levels allows peso issuers abroad to get lower yields than if they issued in the domestic market, more overseas corporate peso issues could put downward pressure on domestic rates as well, analysts said.</p>
<p>((--Buenos Aires Newsroom, 541 318-0668))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
