<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387999" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Asian Sugar - China gov't buying seen aiding price.</title>
<headline>Asian Sugar - China gov't buying seen aiding price.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chinese government's move to buy sugar and support wilting domestic prices was having a small effect in some parts of the country but no dramatic price shifts were expected, sugar industry sources said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The sugar price has gone up by about 50 yuan (US$6) because of the policy,&quot; a factory source said by telephone from China's southern sugar-producing province of Guangxi.</p>
<p>He said the average price of sugar in Guangxi was still around 3,800 yuan per tonne.</p>
<p>China's Ministry of Internal Trade issued a circular last month to government sugar firms nationwide to buy sugar to boost reserves and bolster flagging domestic sugar prices.</p>
<p>&quot;If the prices do not go up further and continue to slide, the government may buy another 400,000 tonnes of sugar,&quot; the factory source said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong and China sugar traders agreed that no spectacular shifts in the domestic price of sugar would take place in the rest of February.</p>
<p>&quot;It's pretty dull,&quot; said a Hong Kong trader.</p>
<p>A trader in Japan said China may step into the market if domestic sugar prices firmed to 4,500 or 4,600 yuan per tonne.</p>
<p>Views on China's sugar imports were contradictory.</p>
<p>One trader reported a 20,000-22,000 tonne cargo, probably from Thailand or Australia, arriving at the southern port of Shekou last month.</p>
<p>Another China-based source said a cargo had been turned away by customs at a southern port, but no further details were available.</p>
<p>Neither report could be confirmed.</p>
<p>China's reduced temporary import tariff on raw sugar to 12 percent from 30 percent, announced last week, was primarily to satisfy requirements for World Trade Organisation membership, a China-based sugar source said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's good for imports but bad for factories,&quot; the source said, noting that increased imports would depress already ailing domestic prices.</p>
<p>Indonesian buying continued at a healthy clip and purchases of another 300,000-400,000 tonnes could come in the short term, a Hong Kong trader said.</p>
<p>Asian sugar markets remained quiet, although market players slowly returned from the Lunar New Year holidays, traders in Japan said.</p>
<p>Thai raw sugar premiums had firmed slightly but little business was done so far, they said.</p>
<p>Thai premiums for March/May delivery were quoted at 0.20/0.30 cents (bid/offer) per pound over New York's Coffee, Sugar and Cocoa Exchange on an FOB (free on board) basis, compared with 0.20/0.25 a week ago, they said.</p>
<p>May/July deliveries were quoted at 0.30/0.45 cents over the New York exchange, up from 0.30 cents the previous week. July/September deliveries were at 0.50 cents.</p>
<p>The traders said firmer premiums were mainly attributable to small-lot physical buying and position adjustments, but added that the premiums were likely to ease amid slack physical demand in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think China will enter the market before May this year,&quot; a trader at a major trade house said. &quot;It appears that China has ample stocks, and China's domestic sugar price is still too low for the country to buy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>($1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
<p>-- Mishi Saran in Hong Kong (852) 2843 6358</p>
<p>-- Keiko Takagi in Tokyo (813) 3432 7391</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
