<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="387965" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila court orders suspension of senator.</title>
<headline>Manila court orders suspension of senator.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Philippine court on Wednesday ordered the suspension of Senator Miriam Santiago from the Senate on graft charges, a move that the combative lawmaker charged was designed to silence her as a government critic.</p>
<p>The anti-graft court said it was ordering Santiago's suspension for 90 days after finding there was ground to bring the case against her to trial.</p>
<p>State prosecutors had accused Santiago of violating the anti-graft law when she was immigration commissioner in 1988 by legalising, without proper authority, the stay in the Philippines of 32 foreigners whose visas had expired.</p>
<p>&quot;This is stupidity begging to be noticed,&quot; Santiago, who lost to President Fidel Ramos in 1992 presidential elections, said in a speech at the Senate after learning about the court order.</p>
<p>She accused Ramos of instigating the suspension to remove her as chairman of the Senate committee on constitutional amendments, clearing the way for the administration to change the constitution and allow Ramos to run for a second term.</p>
<p>The constitution limits a president to one term of six years. Ramos's term expires in June 1998, but some of his aides said there was a need to amend the charter so he could run for re-election.</p>
<p>Santiago opposes any such amendment and, as chairman of the senate committee on amendments, could block such a move.</p>
<p>Santiago said prosecutors asked for her suspension in 1995 and it was surprising that the court should act on it only now.</p>
<p>&quot;Ramos initiated this to intimidate me into silence,&quot; Santiago said. She asked the Senate, the only body empowered to suspend a member, to reject the order.</p>
<p>Senator Ernesto Maceda, president of the opposition-controlled Senate, said the chamber would have to study the court order but that any judicial intrusion into the Senate's independence was unacceptable.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
