<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="388046" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares gain 1.13 pct.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares gain 1.13 pct.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Istanbul shares firmed on Wednesday in a continued rise amid positive sentiment after parliament rejected sending Deputy Prime Minister Tansu Ciller to the Supreme Court in two corruption charge votes on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Brokers said prices eased from early highs on selling triggered by caution ahead of another parliamentary vote this evening on a third corruption probe against Ciller.</p>
<p>The IMKB National-100 closed 18 points, or 1.13 percent higher at 1,614, but fell from a day's high of 1,632 on profit-taking. It had jumped 2.7 pct on Tuesday amid positive political expectations ahead of the votes.</p>
<p>Daily volume jumped to 36.50 trillion lira from Tuesday's 27.44 trillion.</p>
<p>&quot;The index eased in the afternoon because the market began to wait for today's parliamentary vote. Those who bought in the morning came to sell in the second session,&quot; said Nazmi Sarikaya from Dis securities.</p>
<p>Parliament began the third corruption debate after the market closed.</p>
<p>Brokers said the market was likely to remain cautious due to three censure motions filed by opposition parties against the Islamist-led goverment, scheduled to be taken up in parliament on February 25 on 26.</p>
<p>Of the 236 shares traded, rises outdid falls by 117 to 62 and 57 ended steady. The IMKB Industrial  firmed 0.48 percent to 1,676, the IMKB Services rose 1.62 percent to 1,444 and the IMKB Financial gained 1.66 percent to 1,653.</p>
<p>Top actives were largely state-owned flat steel giant Eregli, up 500 lira at 21,500, car and commercial vehicle producers Tofas, steady at 8,600 lira, T.Isbank's C series shares, up 1,500 lira at 40,000 and utility Cukurova Elektrik, up 5,000 lira at 210,000.</p>
<p>They made up 23.2 percent of the total turnover.</p>
<p>-- Aydan Eksin, Istanbul newsroom +90-212-2750875</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
