<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="388039" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Radical PLO group says ready to join peace talks.</title>
<headline>Radical PLO group says ready to join peace talks.</headline>
<dateline>RAMALLAH, West Bank 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Palestinian group opposed to PLO-Israel peace deals said on Wednesday it was ready to participate in talks with the Jewish state on final status of the occupied West Bank and Gaza Strip.</p>
<p>But Tayseer Khaled, a politburo member of the Damascus-based Democratic Front for the Liberation of Palestine (DFLP) demanded that the Palestinian Authority first consult all Palestinian factions on the talks through a national dialogue.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to be a participant in the final status negotiations, but...this depends on the outcome of this (Palestinian national) dialogue,&quot; Khaled told a news conference in the West Bank town of Ramallah.</p>
<p>Under existing interim peace deals, Israel and the Palestine Liberation Organisation (PLO) are due next month to restart talks on the nature and boundaries of a Palestinian entity in the West Bank and Gaza Strip, occupied by Israel in the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
<p>The talks will focus on the thorniest issues dividing the sides such as Jewish settlements, Palestinian refugees, borders and the fate of Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The DFLP, a radical member of the PLO, has condemned existing interim Israeli-PLO peace deals and refused to participate in the Palestinian Authority created by the pacts.</p>
<p>The DFLP said in a statement distributed at the news conference that final status issues were so critical for Palestinian aspirations towards statehood and independence that all Palestinian groups must have a say in them.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite existing disputes regarding Oslo agreements...it is essential to reach common ground to be the base for a national consensus on the major elements of the Palestinian position on final-status talks,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>It said that the PLO must insist that Israel withdraw from all of the West Bank and Gaza Strip, including Arab East Jerusalem, and cling to the right of Palestinians displaced in the 1948 war to return to their homes in Israel.</p>
<p>Yasser Arafat's Palestinian Authority has said it was ready to enter into a dialogue with all Palestinian factions, including radical PLO groups and Islamic militant organisations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RAMALLAH, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
