<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="388216" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. activist Wu predicts power struggle in China.</title>
<headline>U.S. activist Wu predicts power struggle in China.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Croft</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chinese-American human rights activist Harry Wu predicted on Wednesday the death of China's leader Deng Xiaoping would spark a power struggle.</p>
<p>Deng, 93-year-old architect of China's market-oriented economic reforms, died late on Wednesday of complications from Parkinson's disease and a lung infection. Although he died as just a common member of the Communist Party, having retired from his last official position in 1990, he remained the No. 1 leader because &quot;this is an empire system,&quot; Wu said.</p>
<p>&quot;The empire system is always looking for No. 1. Who will become the next real emperor? That means a power struggle,&quot; Wu, a longtime critic of China's prison system, told Reuters in a telephone interview from his northern California home.</p>
<p>&quot;If the power struggle is only limited to the Forbidden City and they kill each other ... I don't mind. That's their business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he said there was a danger of civil war. Looking back over Chinese history, he said, the power struggle went on and on. Sometimes it was limited to the palace and sometimes it turned the whole society upside down.</p>
<p>Wu said Deng's death was an encouragement for the Chinese dissident movement. Deng has &quot;two bloody hands. He is a criminal,&quot; he said, referring to Deng's role in suppressing the 1989 Tiananmen Square pro-democracy demonstrations and earlier crackdowns.</p>
<p>Wu, born in Shanghai, spent 19 years in Chinese labour camps in the 1960s and 1970s and has since devoted himself to exposing alleged human rights abuses in the prison system. He left China in 1985 and became a U.S. citizen.</p>
<p>Wu was arrested agains after entering China in 1995 in an incident that chilled Sino-U.S. relations and was expelled soon after being sentenced to 15 years in jail for spying.</p>
<p>Wu is a research fellow at the Hoover Institution in California and executive director of the Laogai Research Foundation, a group that investigates Chinese labour camps.</p>
<p>Wu said Deng was the architect of China's &quot;so-called reform, openness&quot; and that policy had brought an improvement in the country's economic development.</p>
<p>&quot;The other result is amazing. The Communist system survives in China,&quot; he said, noting that it had failed everywhere else.</p>
<p>Wu said Deng's death would not stop economic reform in China. &quot;Nobody can stop it. This is a historical current, the energy coming from the people,&quot; he said. &quot;Deng Xiaoping was very clever. He said 'Let's forget talking about ideology.'&quot;</p>
<p>But Wu said he did not foresee more political freedom in China in the next five years. &quot;In 100 years, definitely yes.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
