<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="388236" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US lawmakers urge strong defense in WTO Cuba case.</title>
<headline>US lawmakers urge strong defense in WTO Cuba case.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of U.S. lawmakers urged U.S. trade officials Wednesday to use whatever defense is necessary to avoid an adverse World Trade Organization ruling on a U.S. law aimed at curbing investment in Cuba.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States has a strong interest in promoting international trade,&quot; the lawmakers, including House Speaker Newt Gingrich, wrote in a letter to U.S. Trade Representative designate Charlene Barshefsky.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is precisely for this reason that we must do everything possible to prevent the WTO from undermining its own credibility by reaching a decision on a non-trade matter that purports to circumscribe our ability to adopt policies essential to our national security,&quot; they wrote.</p>
<p>They urged Barshefsky to invoke a national security exception in the case to avoid an adverse WTO decision.</p>
<p>&quot;We defer to your office regarding the best timing for putting forward the various defenses available to the United States, but we believe that the earliest possible use of the strongest defense is appropriate,&quot; the letter said.</p>
<p>The letter was also signed by Senate Foreign Relations Committee Chairman Jesse Helms, a North Carolina Republican, and House Government Reform and Oversight Committee Chairman Dan Burton, a Republican of Indiana, authors of the controversial law that bears their names.</p>
<p>The letter was signed by nine lawmakers.</p>
<p>The WTO is expected to formally appoint a dispute settlement panel on Thursday to hear a complaint by the European Union against the Helms-Burton law.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
