<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="388367" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT corn futures sharply higher, fast on funds.</title>
<headline>CBOT corn futures sharply higher, fast on funds.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT corn futures were sharply higher at midsession with new crop contracts in fast dealings on continued heavy commodity fund buying, traders said.</p>
<p>Funds bought at least 25 million bushels of corn on the day, on top of Tuesday's 100 million bushels, floor sources said.</p>
<p>Traders noted open interest in corn increased by 100 million bushels, according to CBOT data. That was the largest single-day jump in recent memory, they said.  </p>
<p>Traders said Refco Inc bought eight million bushels May, two million bushels July and one million December. Cargill Inc also bought eight million bushels May and Dean Witter and Rosenthal Collins each bought three million bushels May.</p>
<p>Traders said gains in new crop December were a function of the market trying to buy corn acres away from soybeans. A week-long rally in that market had made planting soybeans an attractive option for farmers and the market needed to buy back those acres, floor sources said.</p>
<p>At 1145 CST, corn was 6-1/2 to two cents per bushel higher with March up 5-1/2 at $2.88-1/4 and December up 5-1/4 at $2.80.</p>
<p>((Emily Kaiser 312-408-8749))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
