<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="388397" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wider Dec U.S trade gap may have firm dlr to thank.</title>
<headline>Wider Dec U.S trade gap may have firm dlr to thank.</headline>
<byline>Alden Bentley</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A deterioration in the December U.S. import/export balance brings trade back in line with the underlying trend, and economists said the wider gap was no surprise given the dollar's firmer trend last year.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, a 1.6 percent drop in exports combined with a 1.5 percent import jump pushed the U.S. international trade deficit to $10.29 billion in December, from a revised $7.94 billion gap in November.</p>
<p>Economists had expected a slightly narrower $9.9 billion, but said the actual December gap was pretty close.  </p>
<p>While some forecasters said December would have been too soon for the dollar's 1996 advance to show up in the trade figures, Carl Weinberg, chief economist at High Frequency economicsm, said the strong dollar is already biting into exports.</p>
<p>&quot;We were talking about the higher dollar taking a toll over time and the drop in exports is I think the key to what is going on in our trade figures right now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The import surge can be explained away by the strong demand for foreign goods as the U.S. economy continues to outperform its major trading partners, economists said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Imports jumped quite sharply -- near record levels -- and obviously that's symptomatic of strong underlying domestic demand,&quot; said Alan Ruskin, research director at I.D.E.A. Inc. &quot;It's consistent with a robust economy, certainly, both strong exports and strong imports.&quot;</p>
<p>Ruskin noted that despite the drop, the still-high $71.40 billion level of exports indicates the U.S. was still holding its own competing in the global marketplace.</p>
<p>On a country-by-country basis, the trade gap with Western Europe expanded to $2.052 billion in December from $1.380 billion the previous month.  </p>
<p>The trade gap with Canada also widened $573 million to $2.318 billion.</p>
<p>But the increasingly crucial balance with China and the widely watched bilateral deficit with Japan both improved.</p>
<p>The China gap fell to $2.645 billion from just under $3.0 billion in November. But the deficit with Japan shrank an ever-so-slight $51 million to $4.265 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The Japan figures were pretty much unchanged but we knew that from Japan's data published more than a month ago. The deficit with China came down but that is more a political than an economic issue for the markets,&quot; Weinberg said.  </p>
<p>The wider December gap means the average deficit for the final three months of 1996 was slightly wider than suggested by the smaller October and November numbers.</p>
<p>But while the monthly average in the fourth quarter was narrower than in the third quarter, December could signal a wider gap in the first quarter, economists said.</p>
<p>John Ryding, managing director and senior economist at Bear Stearns &amp; Co Inc, said on a month-to-month basis the data were too distorted to identify underlying trends. But Ruskin said the December data were consistent with the bias before the aberrant October and November data.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
