<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="388463" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German doctors anaesthetise foetus in the womb.</title>
<headline>German doctors anaesthetise foetus in the womb.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two German doctors have for the first time anaesthetised a foetus for a life-saving operation in the womb while leaving the mother conscious, an advance which should make it easier to operate on unborn children in future.</p>
<p>Doctors Bernd Ebeling and Manfred Hansmann made the breakthrough in an operation to give blood to the unborn child of a 29-year-old mother, endangered because of a potentially fatal blood incompatibility, Bonn University said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The transfusion involves inserting a needle through the mother's abdomen and into the umbilical cord, and requires the foetus to make no sudden movements.</p>
<p>Until now, this has meant anaesthetising the mother, with risks to her health and an uncontrolled effect on the child, or giving the foetus a substance to paralyse its muscles, but without dulling the pain.</p>
<p>Research indicates that foetuses can feel significant pain from the sixth month of pregnancy.</p>
<p>Ebeling and Hansmann delivered the anaesthetic through the umbilical cord, monitoring the child to be sure that its heart beat normally throughout the 10-minute operation, and that its movements returned to normal when the anaesthetic wore off.</p>
<p>A statement from the university said the advance would make it easier to carry out other kinds of minimally invasive operations on unborn children in future.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
