<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="388438" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FTelecom ad campaign to use emotional pull.</title>
<headline>FTelecom ad campaign to use emotional pull.</headline>
<byline>Denis Thomas</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The advertising campaign for the privatisation of France Telecom will be based on persuasion using emotional pull rather than facts, an executive at Alice, the advertising agency handling the campaign, told Reuters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are aiming to persuade by emotions rather than by reason,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not the first privatisation, and it is a very major company. We will play the likeable card,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He declined to give more details of how the campaign, which he said would begin &quot;in the week of May 1 and last for over three weeks&quot;, would be handled.</p>
<p>&quot;We are aiming at a very broad public and will use the appropriate media -- television, newspapers, radio, direct mail and toll-free telephone lines,&quot; the executive said.</p>
<p>Alice will run the campaign aimed at the public, while Euro RSCG Finances, part of Havas Advertising, will handle the financial press.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a big budget campaign,&quot; the executive said, but declined to give a figure. On January 22 the agency, announcing that it had won the campaign, said it had a budget of 75 million francs.</p>
<p>France Telecom said earlier on Wednesday that the sale of 20 percent of its capital by the French state will take place in May, but the exact dates had not been fixed.</p>
<p>Financial newspaper La Tribune said the sale of France Telecom shares would begin on May 20 and last six days, with stock trading expected to begin at the beginnning of June.</p>
<p>The government is to privatise France Telecom in two tranches this year. The sale of the first tranche was initially expected to be in April.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
