<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="388694" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bombardier launches new regional jet program.</title>
<headline>Bombardier launches new regional jet program.</headline>
<byline>Robert Melnbardis</byline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>With scores of potential sales on its order book, Canada's Bombardier Inc. launched its 70-seat Canadair Regional Jet program on Wednesday, saying the aircraft would likely cost C$645 million ($477 million) to develop.</p>
<p>The Montreal-based maker of aerospace, rail and personal motorized transportation equipment said it had four firm orders for the CRJ Series 700 aircraft from Brit Air, of Morlaix, France. It also had 28 options and 41 memoranda of understanding from eight airlines on four continents.</p>
<p>Bombardier declined to identify all the airlines, but told a news conference that Great China Airlines, of Taiwan, signed a memorandum of understanding for four of the jets.</p>
<p>The CRJ 700, which is a stretch version of Bombardier's 50-seat Canadair Regional Jet, will have a sticker price of $23 million each in 1995 dollars, a range of 2,032 nautical miles and a maximum cruising speed of 461 knots, company officials said.</p>
<p>The jet, which is being built by Bombardier at its Canadair facilities in Montreal, and its Short Brothers plant in Belfast, Northern Ireland, is scheduled to make its first flight in the second quarter of 1999. Brit Air is expected to take delivery of the first jet in late 2000.</p>
<p>Bombardier will be responsible for C$440 million ($326 million) of the CRJ 700's development cost, while its suppliers would fund the rest.</p>
<p>Suppliers for the new jet include Mitsubishi, which will make the aft fuselage section, General Electric Co., which is designing new engines, and avionics systems maker Rockwell Collins.</p>
<p>Pierre Lortie, president of Bombardier Regional Aircraft Divsion, told reporters the new plane strengthened the company's position in the growing global market for turboprop and jet-engine regional aircraft.</p>
<p>&quot;We forecast a requirement for about 2,000 regional jet aircraft in the 20- to 90-seat market by the year 2015. Bombardier's share of the jet portion of this market -- 53 percent in calendar 1996 alone -- will be further reinforced by the Canadair Regional Jet Series 700,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts were positive Bombardier's announcement about the orders and possible sales for the CRJ 700 although the jet was about three years away from its first flight.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a very good number, more than we expected,&quot; said an analyst who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>Xavier Leclerq, president of Brit Air, which operates a network from Paris to London, Madrid, Vienna and Hamburg, said the airline already flew Bombardier's 50-seat jet and was looking forward to using the 70-seater.</p>
<p>&quot;We chose the aircraft because of the economics and cost,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bombardier is competing against seven other aircraft manufacturers in the regional jet market, including Saab of Sweden, Embraer of Brazil, and Dornier Luftfahrt GmbH, of Germany, a unit of Fairchild Aircraft of San Francisco. At the end of January, Bombardier's order book for its 50-seat jet stood at 313, involving 200 firm orders and 113 options.</p>
<p>Bombardier's growing reach in the international aerospace market includes close working relationships with other manufacturers. Robert Brown, president of Bombardier Aerospace, said Bombardier continued to have talks with Mitsubishi Heavy Industries Ltd. regarding the possible development of a 100-seat jet.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, we are having some discussions with Mitsubishi,&quot; Brown told reporters.</p>
<p>He added that although Bombardier was unlikely be the lead manufacturer on any such joint venture project for a 100-seater, &quot;anything is possible.&quot; Meanwhile, Bombardier would focus on products already under development, he said.</p>
<p>Bombardier shares were up C40 cents to C$26.45 in thin trading on the Toronto Stock Exchange on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
