<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="388752" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Budget plan stems lira drop for now -- analysts.</title>
<headline>Budget plan stems lira drop for now -- analysts.</headline>
<byline>Chizu Nomiyama</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The lira gained some respite from its recent battering on Wednesday after Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi announced his long-awaited decision to form a special budget to clean up Italy's finances and qualify for Europe's single currency.</p>
<p>However, analysts said it was too early to rejoice that the lira's troubles were over with the mini-budget since the currency was likely to remain under pressure for some time to come.</p>
<p>The lira, which had plunged on the latest round of jitters on whether Italy would be able to join European economic and monetary union (EMU) at its launch in 1999, stopped just short of weakening to 1,000 to the mark before Prodi's statement.</p>
<p>By midday it was quoted at 994.85, recovering from its low of 999.60 and from 996.72 in late European trade on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The initial knee-jerk reaction was a positive one, because although the idea of a mini-budget had been floated, the statement by the prime minister was a much firmer commitment than what we've had so far,&quot; said Ken Wattret, economist at Paribas in London.</p>
<p>A statement issued by the prime minister's office said the budget would be launched in the coming weeks and that it would enable Italy to meet the conditions needed to qualify for monetary union.</p>
<p>However, analysts were sceptical how long this factor could shore up the lira.</p>
<p>&quot;The lira is going to become increasingly susceptible to downward pressure as it becomes clear to the market that the Italians won't qualify for EMU in the first round,&quot; said Paul Chertkow, head of global currency research at UBS.</p>
<p>Wattret said the lira's fall through its central rate in Europe's exchange rate mechanism (ERM) of 990 per mark on Tuesday could be a warning of further falls to come.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the currency plunged by 10 lire to the mark.</p>
<p>The run was triggered by a newspaper quoting Belgian central bank governor Alfons Verplaetse as saying European Union countries would not be able to cut their budget deficit-to-gross domestic product ratio to three percent from seven percent in just one year to qualify for monetary union.</p>
<p>Market players believed that this referred to Italy.</p>
<p>Verplaetse denied that he was speaking about Italy but the damage had been done in a market ever hungry for any hints on whether Italy would be able to win its coveted EMU membership.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not saying there will be crisis of confidence in the lira. But over the next several months we'll see the lira weakening and we're looking at a move to 1,010 (per mark) initially with a risk to 1,050,&quot; UBS's Chertkow said.</p>
<p>In any case, making the special budget materialise would be a problem since the Communist Refoundation party, on which Prodi relies for a majority in parliament, on Wednesday said it would not accept a mini-budget which involved spending cuts and new taxes.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll have to wait until we see exactly what they will do -- first to see if the Communists will support it and then if it will actually have the impact they (the government) say it should have. Then maybe you'll see the lira starting to trade a bit stronger,&quot; said Ernesto Ramirez, economist at Bankers Trust.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the mood of the currency market as a whole did not bode well for the lira, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The international backdrop is not as supportive as it was (for the lira), with the mark recovering against the U.S. dollar and on the European currencies,&quot; Wattret said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44-171-542-6721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
