<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="388873" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: POLITICAL UNCERTAINTY DOMINATES TURK BOND MARKET.</title>
<headline>POLITICAL UNCERTAINTY DOMINATES TURK BOND MARKET.</headline>
<byline>Tulin Aygunes</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Political uncertainties are holding Turkey's bond market in a tight grip and would continue to determine the trend in the near future, bankers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Markets are on a wait-and-see and volatility will continue in coming days,&quot; said a private bank treasurer.</p>
<p>Turkish t-bill and bond yields which leapt by around 15 points in the last two weeks amid political caution and higher-than-expected January inflation, eased around four points after Turkish parliament voted against sending Deputy Prime Minister Tansu Ciller to the Supreme Court in two corruption charge votes on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Bond yields reversed from around 95 percent to 91 percent levels, but are not settled,&quot; said Ali Ozenc, cash flow manager at private Finansbank.</p>
<p>&quot;Caution due to upcoming censure motions against the Islamist-led government still unnerve the markets. The trend may change again depending on political developments and liquidity in the system,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Turkey's two leftist and one conservative opposition parties have submitted censure motions, scheduled to be taken up in parliament on February 25 and 26.</p>
<p>A continuing cash squeeze, dollar demand spurred by recent political worries as well as the central bank's control over currency and overnight money rates also pushed up the bond yields in the last two weeks, bankers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Central bank is seen giving priority to the dollar due to fresh currency demand. This week's two interventions and reverse repo sales intensified cash squeeze and kept money rates firmer,&quot; a private bank treasury official said.</p>
<p>Bond yields had jumped to 95 percent in the last two weeks after bottoming out at 79 percent at the end of January.</p>
<p>&quot;Higher-than expected January inflation, the Treasury's paper sale with 1997 maturity instead of 1998 in the last two auctions, investors shying away from long-term paper as well as political tension caused the downtrend to reverse two weeks ago,&quot; said one senior banker.</p>
<p>Bond yields had earlier dived by some 30 points in January in a downtrend sparked by a rise in withholding tax on interest income from state securities for 1997 and delay in the introduction of income tax on interest earnings.</p>
<p>Turkish bankers had recently been warning that heavy long-term bond portfolios posed funding risks for banks because private investors continued to seek short-term bills.</p>
<p>-- Istanbul newsroom +90-212-275 08 75</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
