<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="388890" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraq to send pilgrims to Mecca this year.</title>
<headline>Iraq to send pilgrims to Mecca this year.</headline>
<byline>Leon Barkho</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraqi leader Saddam Hussein has decided to allow Iraqis to go on pilgrimage to Mecca this year, Baghdad newspapers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;President Saddam Hussein has ordered the preparations of necessary requirements to enable our people to perform the haj for 1997,&quot; the papers said.</p>
<p>Last time Iraqis were seen in Mecca was in 1994 when about 500 pilgrims travelled by land to Saudi Arabia. Iraq halted the haj in 1995, saying U.N. trade sanctions imposed for its 1990 invasion of Kuwait had emptied its coffers of hard cash.</p>
<p>Iraqi religious scholars then ruled that the country's Moslems could defer their pilgrimage and spend the money on Iraq's poor instead.</p>
<p>In 1994 every pilgrim was allowed to carry $500. Demand used to surge for the greenback during haj seasons, increasing pressure on Iraq's volatile dinar currency.</p>
<p>The papers, quoting Endowment and Religious Affairs Minister Abdul-Muneim Ahmed Saleh, said Iraq would take into account its financial condition in preparing for this year's pilgrimage. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Iraq's 20 million people are given a quota of 19,000 places a year for the pilgrimage to Mecca under an arrangement of the Organisation of Islamic Conference limiting the number from any member country to 1,000 per one million Moslems.</p>
<p>But it unlikely so many Iraqis would be able to make the haj, one of Islam's five obligations on believers which all Moslems should carry out once in their lifetime if they can.</p>
<p>Iraqis wishing to travel abroad have to pay a fee of 400,000 dinars ($296), a big sum for most Iraqis. Once other costs are added, then only the rich in Iraq could afford to make the haj.</p>
<p>Iraq has unsuccessfully appealed to Moslem states to urge Saudi Arabia, Bahrain and the United Arab Emirates to release frozen Iraqi assets to cover the cost of this year's haj.</p>
<p>Earlier appeals to the United Nations to allow Iraqi Moslems to fly to Mecca also fell on deaf ears.</p>
<p>Iraq's southern and northern skies are shut to both civilian and military aircraft by U.S. and allied planes policing two no -fly zones over the country.</p>
<p>Flights by international carriers are also not allowed despite Iraqi arguments that this ban was not part of the terms ending the 1991 Gulf War over Kuwait.</p>
<p>Iraqi pilgrims will have to travel by land, going through immigration at the Saudi border post of Ar'ar. The journey takes 24 hours by bus.</p>
<p>$=1,350 Iraqi dinars</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
