<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="388927" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS - Evergreen moves solidify its status.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Evergreen moves solidify its status.</headline>
<byline>Lisa Marie</byline>
<dateline>PANE NEW YORK 1997-02-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Evergreen Media Corp's proposed acquisitions of Chancellor Broadcasting Co and 10 radio stations owned by Viacom Inc would cement its status as the largest U.S. pure-play radio broadcasting company.</p>
<p>Not only would the additional stations solidify Evergreen's presence in the top U.S. markets, they would ensure that the combined company is not left behind in an era of radio consolidation.</p>
<p>Although the offer for Viacom's station group is on the high end, the deal should pay off by giving the proposed combination of Evergreen and Chancellor deep roots in the lucrative top markets, particularly New York and Los Angeles, analysts said.</p>
<p>The combined deal for Chancellor and Viacom's radio group is valued at about $2.6 billion in cash, stock and debt.</p>
<p>&quot;It's more than defensible,&quot; Bankers Trust analyst Mark McFadden said, referring to the $1.075 billion price tag for the Viacom stations. &quot;This takes them from three companies with pretty strong positions to a juggernaut.&quot;</p>
<p>Although Evergreen and Chancellor had made independent plays for Viacom's stations, the decision to join forces minimizes the financial impact, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;If either separately chose to pay this price for Viacom, there would've been a significant dilutive effect on their stock,&quot; UBS Securities analyst Edward Hatch said.</p>
<p>&quot;It would've been a very big pill to swallow,&quot; Oppenheimer &amp; Co analyst  Edward Atorino said.</p>
<p>Several analysts said they were told by company executives that the deal was expected to be moderately accretive to after-tax cash flow in 1998 -- the new entity's first full year -- and highly accretive in the following years.</p>
<p>Evergreen has agreed to acquire Chancellor's common stock, valued at about $600 million, for 0.9091 shares of Evergreen's Class A common stock, Hicks said in an interview with Reuters. The new entity would also assume Chancellor's obligations, which was valued at about $900 million, Hicks said.</p>
<p>The combined entity would then acquire Viacom's 10 stations for about $1.075 billion.</p>
<p>Afterwards, it would have 103 radio stations in 21 markets, including outlets in the nation's top 12 markets. Even before the deal, Evergreen was the nation's largest pure-play radio broadcaster with 42 major-market stations in 11 cities.</p>
<p>While Evergreen has focused on being a player in the top 10 markets, Chancellor has focused on stations in the top 50.</p>
<p>Evergreen Chairman Scott Ginsburg said in a conference call with reporters that the company planned to swap or sell at least six stations: two FM stations in San Francisco, two FM stations in Chicago, one FM station in Detroit and an FM and two AM stations in Washington.</p>
<p>The deal is viewed as a direct outgrowth of the passage last year of the Telecommunications Act, which loosened restrictions on ownership of radio stations in any single market. The measure has led to a spate of consolidations among broadcasters.</p>
<p>Companies such as Evergreen and Chancellor have been forced to consider such moves while there are enough competitors to gobble up. There are a total of about 11,000 radio stations in the country.</p>
<p>Until the Telecommunications Act was enacted, companies were limited to owning no more than four radio statons in any single large market. Companies may now own eight radio stations in each.</p>
<p>The new law also places no overall cap on total ownership nationwide. Previously, companies could own no more than 40 stations.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a once-in-a-lifetime chance,&quot; McFadden said. &quot;You either do it now, or the door shuts forever. ... In about two years, there won't be any. So you have to buy them now.&quot;</p>
<p>That's particularly true for stations in the top 10 markets.</p>
<p>&quot;There are only so many major market stations and you don't get too many opportunities to get those,&quot; Oppenheimer's Atorino said. &quot;You've got to react to opportunities in this consolidation phase, or you don't get a second chance.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PANE NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
