<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="38911" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Sept 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Sept 5.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Egyptian press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-AHRAM</p>
<p>- The cabinet reviews three reports on hydrocarbon discoveries, Iraqi developments and the security situation.</p>
<p>- President Hosni Mubarak's advisor Osama el-Baz: Iran is involved in the bid to assassinate Mubarak.</p>
<p>AL-AKHBAR</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Amr Moussa in Paris says Egypt is against use of force against Iraq.</p>
<p>_ President Mubarak receives telephone call from Palestinian President Yasser Arafat and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu after their talks yesterday to maintain the momentum of the peace process.</p>
<p>AL-GOMHURIA</p>
<p>- Three new hydrocarbon discoveries.</p>
<p>AL-WAFD</p>
<p>- Britain threatens to prosecute participants in the terrorism conference if they go beyond the law. The official spokesman of the British foreign minitsry said all speeches during the conference would be recorded. He added that any one who goes beyond the law, through statements, comments or actions, would be prosecuted.</p>
<p>_ Water level in Lake Nasser continues its daily increases.</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +20 2 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
