<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="389396" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Air New Zealand profit dives in tough first half.</title>
<headline>Air New Zealand profit dives in tough first half.</headline>
<byline>James Gray</byline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Air New Zealand Ltd is expected to report a full year profit of NZ$140-150 million (US$97-104 million) after absorbing a one-off NZ$25 million charge, coupled with the likelihood of a leaner second half, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Analysts had previously forecast an outcome of around NZ$175 million for the year to June, down from $225.2 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>Air NZ earlier reported a slump in first half earnings to December 31 to NZ$76.74 million from $135.1 million in the previous comparable period, in line with analysts' forecasts.</p>
<p>The company's &quot;project save&quot; campaign would account for a one-off loss of NZ$25 million in the current year, but the short term pain would bring long term gain, with more than NZ$100 million in annual cost reductions accruing the following year.</p>
<p>Robert Bode at Merrill Lynch said the one-off cost would not be regarded as too negative by the market because it suggested some progress had been made.</p>
<p>&quot;It's evidence that they are serious about their cost cutting exercise and we've seen little evidence to date as to what was going to happen. This suggests a little more imminence in that whole area,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ansett Australia's contribution was higher than expected, returning NZ$16.7 million in the December quarter. But like other Australasian carriers, Ansett International's operations had a tough half year and Air NZ expected it to return a loss.</p>
<p>Air NZ owns half of Ansett in a deal settled on October 1.</p>
<p>David Copley at Cavill White Securities said there were a few positives that indicated a better year lay ahead in 1997/8.</p>
<p>&quot;The balance of probability is that the (New Zealand) dollar is going to be coming down,&quot; he said. &quot;The balance of probability again is that jet fuel is at a peak,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Similarly, there was evidence that competition on routes between New Zealand and Australia had peaked over the first half.</p>
<p>&quot;If you remove those one-offs and then throw in the cost savings for Air NZ and Ansett, there are some major positives there,&quot; Copley said. Ansett is on a similar cost-cutting drive.</p>
<p>Furthermore, there was the prospect of Air NZ's alliance with UAL's United Airlines coming on stream in April.</p>
<p>Air NZ earlier said it had been a tough operating environment over the six months.</p>
<p>Growth in inbound and outbound traffic went some way to offset the continuing strength of the New Zealand dollar and higher jet fuel prices.</p>
<p>The New Zealand dollar's Trade-Weighted Index gained 4.0 percent over the six months, including a 9.0 percent appreciation against the yen. Over the past three years, the Kiwi dollar had risen more than 20 percent against the U.S.</p>
<p>Those influences had posed big challenges for the company, as they made New Zealand comparatively more expensive to visit.</p>
<p>Air NZ received a tax credit of NZ$593,000, versus a debit of $18.875 million in the previous first half. Analysts said this was probably linked to Air NZ's aircraft leasing and purchase agreements.</p>
<p>In early afternoon trade, Air NZ's &quot;A&quot; shares were at NZ$2.82, down three cents, while the &quot;B&quot; shares were up one at $3.88.</p>
<p>($1 = NZ$1.45)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
