<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="389490" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks end flat amid cautious mood.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks end flat amid cautious mood.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cautious sentiment left Hong Kong stocks flat by Wednesday's close, with concerns about the health of China's paramount leader Deng Xiaoping and continued unwinding of overweight positions keeping prices in check.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index closed 3.38 points, or 0.03 percent, higher at 13,106.32. Turnover was HK$7.12 billion compared with HK$7.55 billion on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's mainly because of Deng's health and a lack of interest from foreign funds,&quot; said Peter Lai, associate director at OCBC Securities, adding that the Hang Seng should remain trapped in a range in the near term, trading around 13,000 points.  </p>
<p>The blue-chip index fell to a low of 13,002.55 earlier in the session. Julian Ings Chambers, assistant director at BZW Securities, said there had been &quot;reasonably heavy selling from the States and overseas&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;What you have seen is unwinding of very, very overweight positions people had last year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;They have had very overweight positions through last year and there comes a time when it is just too much of a risk to hold those going forward. While last year it was a fairly safe bet, this year it is not so clear. It's a question of people deciding what the risk reward profile looks to be this year.&quot;  </p>
<p>Analysts said some investors were hesitant to enter the market now, with further short-term volatility linked to Deng's condition possible. But they said reactions would be short-lived.</p>
<p>&quot;His health has been under question for a while and as such the market has had to think about this a number of times to the point where you would have expected the market to discount the fact that he won't be around forever,&quot; said Ings Chambers.</p>
<p>&quot;Day-to-day power I think has moved fairly securely into the hands of the prominent politicians you see operating at the helm and Deng stopped being directly involved a while ago.&quot;  </p>
<p>Banking stocks recovered on Wednesday, with HSBC Holdings advancing HK$1.50 to HK$185.00 and Hang Seng Bank moving up HK$0.75 at HK$88.75.</p>
<p>Property stocks remained under pressure. Cheung Kong fell HK$1.25 to HK$71.00 and Henderson Land slumped HK$1.50 to HK$67.50.</p>
<p>Hongkong and Shanghai Hotels reported a 40 percent rise in 1996 net profit to HK$916 million. The stock ended on a gain of HK$0.05 at HK$13.95.</p>
<p>-- Jennifer Genevieve (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
