<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="389452" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: SE Asian Grain-Trade subdued, prices mostly stable.</title>
<headline>SE Asian Grain-Trade subdued, prices mostly stable.</headline>
<byline>Barani Krishnaan</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southeast Asian domestic grain and oilseed prices were largely steady in a subdued market this week as firms got back to business after the long Chinese New Year and Hari Raya holidays, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Market participants showed little appetite for trade with most still in a holiday mood. Serious activity was only expected after the celebrations officially end on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;There might be some buying this week if the price falls, but I doubt there will be as people are still holidaying,&quot; said the sales manager of a flour mill in Kuala Lumpur.  </p>
<p>The Malaysian office of China's official agency for grains trading denied rumours that some Malaysian importers bought up to 50,000 tonnes of Chinese corn last week.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't done any business for the last two months,&quot; a spokeswoman said, adding that there were also no bids placed with the agency.</p>
<p>Traders said Malaysian consumers were generally covered until April and may only need to start buying for their forward requirements in early March.</p>
<p>Bulk corn, ex-factory/godown in Malaysia's central region, was quoted at 390-400 ringgit a tonne.  </p>
<p>&quot;A&quot; grade wheat in bags, ex-factory/godown in the central region, was at 800 ringgit a tonne. The price of low-grade wheat, also central-based, was around 450 ringgit a tonne.</p>
<p>Imported wheat was seen at 820 ringgit while local material fetched quotes of 810 ringgit, both in the central region.</p>
<p>Corn prices in Indonesia were generally stable in Jakarta, with the harvest in the key growing region of Lampung in South Sumatra proceeding without any hitches, traders said.</p>
<p>They said feedmills seemed to be well stocked, having bought corn locally ahead of the back-to-back Lunar New Year and Moslem Eid al-Fitr celebrations earlier this month.  </p>
<p>&quot;Several large feedmills bought in relatively large quantities to avoid transportation problems during the festivals,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Business in predominantly-Moslem Indonesia usually grinds to a halt for a week during Eid al-Fitr as employees return to their hometowns.</p>
<p>One trader said sellers were offering U.S. corn at around US$180 a tonne C&amp;F, but did not know if any deals had been done recently. He said China was also offering corn in Indonesia, but did not know the price.  </p>
<p>Soybean meal was easier at around 780 rupiah a kg in Jakarta, compared with 795-800 rupiah last week on ample stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;India and Brazil have been offering,&quot; a trader said. Further details about the offers were not available.</p>
<p>In Thailand, soymeal and corn prices edged up from last week on active demand but buyers, sidelined by world high prices, were reluctant to place new orders, trade sources said.</p>
<p>Local soymeal stocks, which have been declining, will be given a boost next week with the arrival of soymeal from India and almost four cargoes of U.S. soybeans bought by a major oil crusher.  </p>
<p>The vessel C Tausin is expected to arrive in Bangkok from the U.S. with 47,849 tonnes of soybeans. Thai Vegetable Oil was said to be the buyer.</p>
<p>Soymeal prices were quoted around 9.55 baht a kg from 9.30-9.40 baht last week.</p>
<p>Traders said there have been no corn imports so far as the industry is still waiting for the Commerce Ministry to come up with the new schedule for zero-tariff corn imports.</p>
<p>But buying in the local market has been active. Some major feed producers were buying to chase the price up in an attempt to persuade the government to allow imports soon, dealers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;If the prices in Bangkok market reach 4.50 baht a kg, which was earlier set as a benchmark by the government, it might be easier to ask them to open for imports,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Corn was quoted around 4.38-4.40 baht a kg this week from 4.30-4.35 baht a kg last week, traders said.</p>
<p>    SOUTHEAST ASIAN GRAIN/MEAL PRICES	   Feb 19    Feb 5</p>
<p>Thailand - Corn/maize (baht/kg)		4.38-4.40  4.25-4.30</p>
<p>Thailand - Soymeal, imported (baht/kg)	   9.55   9.30-9.40</p>
<p>Malaysia - Corn (ringgit/tonne)		  390-400     395</p>
<p>Malaysia - Grade A wheat (ringgit/tonne)	 800	 800</p>
<p>Malaysia - Low grade wheat (ringgit/tonne)     450	 450</p>
<p>Malaysia - Local soymeal (ringgit/tonne)	 810	 810</p>
<p>Malaysia - Imported soymeal (ringgit/tonne)    820	 820</p>
<p>Indonesia - Corn (rupiah/kg)			 390     385-395</p>
<p>Indonesia - Soymeal (rupiah/kg)		    780     785-790</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (65-870335)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
