<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="389597" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan parties seen agreeing on holding companies.</title>
<headline>Japan parties seen agreeing on holding companies.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's ruling Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) and its allies are expected to reach an agreement on Thursday on lifting a decades-long ban on holding companies, an official at a trade watchdog said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>An agreement between the LDP, the Social Democratic Party and the small Sakigake party would enable the government to work out necessary changes to Japan's anti-monopoly law and submit them to the current session of parliament by March 11, the Fair Trade Commission (FTC) official said.</p>
<p>The FTC, Japan&quot;s anti-monopoly watchdog, has drawn up proposed changes to the law that would allow the establishment of certain types of holding companies, overturning a ban imposed by U.S. Occupation forces after World War Two.</p>
<p>Holding companies are firms which control one or more other firms, often by holding a majority stake in them, but do not themselves engage in a specific business.</p>
<p>&quot;Without reaching an agreement, it is difficult to finalise the necessary legal revisions, get approval by the cabinet and submit the bill to parliament on March 11,&quot; the official said. &quot;We expect the parties will reach agreement on Thursday.&quot;</p>
<p>If submitted after March 11, the legislation could not be passed in the current session.</p>
<p>The official, who did not want to be identified, said the revised anti-monopoly law should take effect early in 1998 but declined to be more specific. The parties are expected to agree on the outline proposed by the FTC.</p>
<p>U.S. Occupation forces introduced the ban on holding companies in 1947 to break up powerful conglomerates known as &quot;zaibatsu&quot; which the United States believed had contributed to Japan&quot;s war effort.</p>
<p>But big businesses and banks have demanded that the ban be lifted to help them streamline and compete with overseas rivals.</p>
<p>Under the draft legislation recently worked out by the FTC, three types of holding companies will continue to be banned to avoid an excessive concentration of business strength.</p>
<p>The three include extremely large corporate groups, corporate groups headed by a large financial institution and groups formed by leading firms in the same or related industries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
