<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="389539" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: China may send Hwang to SKorea this week - report.</title>
<headline>China may send Hwang to SKorea this week - report.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>China and South Korea have agreed that North Korean official Hwang Jang-yop can leave Beijing for asylum in South Korea as early as this week, Japan's Yomiuri newspaper reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In a front-page story, the Yomiuri Shimbun said the only details stopping Hwang's swift departure were Beijing's demands that Hwang tell a Chinese official in person that he wanted to defect and that South Korean President Kim Young-sam promise not to use the defection for political gain at North Korea's expense.</p>
<p>Quoting South Korean sources in Beijing, the newspaper said both demands were likely to be quickly met. Hwang has been living in the South Korean consulate in Beijing since last week while China, Seoul and Pyongyang argue about his fate.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese and South Korean governments have basically agreed to transfer Hwang and his aide directly to Seoul, hopefully meeting a target of by the end of this week,&quot; the newspaper said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese government demands that Hwang confirms to a Chinese official his desire to defect and before he leaves that China have in their hands a letter signed by President Kim Young-sam promising not to make political capital of the incident,&quot; the newspaper added.</p>
<p>Hwang, once a closer advisor to North Korea's defacto leader Kim Jong-il and ranked 24th in the Stalinist nation's power structure, defected in Beijing eight days ago.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
