<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="389684" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: PRESS DIGEST - Turkey - Feb 19.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Turkey - Feb 19.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Turkish press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>SABAH</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan will try to persuade the armed forces at a meeting next week that his Islamist Welfare Party is not trying to destroy secularism.</p>
<p>MILLIYET</p>
<p>- Welfare helps clear coalition partner Tansu Ciller from two separate corruption charges against her in a parliamentary vote.</p>
<p>HURRIYET</p>
<p>- One deputy from the conservative wing of the coalition resigned before parliament voted on corruption charges against Ciller.</p>
<p>YENI YUZYIL</p>
<p>- Former head of nuclear power board says 1,150 tonnes of German nuclear waste was buried in the southern town of Isparta and another 800 tonnes was burned in the central town of Konya.</p>
<p>RADIKAL</p>
<p>- U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright turns down foreign minister Ciller's request for separate talks while both were in Brussels for a NATO foreign ministers meeting.</p>
<p>CUMHURIYET</p>
<p>- Culture minister says a touristic park will be build in Taksim Square in Istanbul in contrast to the wishes of Islamists to erect a mosque there.</p>
<p>DUNYA</p>
<p>- Uncertainty over privatisation of Tekirdag port in row over bids.</p>
<p>ZAMAN</p>
<p>- Education ministry likely to back down on its decision to scrap studying subjects in a foreign language in top-grade secondary schools.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
