<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="389654" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: North Korea accepts Hwang defection - report.</title>
<headline>North Korea accepts Hwang defection - report.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A top North Korean official has said the communist country does not intend to fight the defection of ideologue Hwang Jang-yop, a major Japanese newspaper reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The economic daily Nihon Keizai Shimbun reported that Kim Jong-u, head of North Korea&quot;s Overseas Economic Cooperation Committee, made the remark on Wednesday in Beijing during a meeting with international investment and financial organisations.</p>
<p>The newspaper quoted sources at the meeting as saying that when was asked if North Korea accepted Hwang&quot;s defection, Kim replied:</p>
<p>&quot;That is what the government has decided. The matter is already closed. He has already been dismissed.&quot;</p>
<p>The sources said Kim strongly criticised Hwang during the meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;Betraying the people when the country is in great difficulty is an unforgivable act. Because of his old age we will not pursue him,&quot; the sources quoted Kim as saying.</p>
<p>The newspaper said other unidentified North Korean officials also had confirmed Pyongyang&quot;s decision to condemn but not pursue Hwang.</p>
<p>Hwang, who on Wednesday began his eighth day inside the South Korean embassy in Beijing, is the architect of North Korea&quot;s national ideology of Juche, or self-reliance, and is the highest-ranking North Korean to defect from his Stalinist homeland.</p>
<p>In a statement released by South Korean authorities, Hwang said he will die in the embassy compound unless he is allowed to defect to South Korea.</p>
<p>China, already occupied with reports of the failing health of paramount leader Deng Xiaoping, is playing for time as it agonises over how to usher Hwang out of Beijing without offending either its old socialist comrades in North Korea or new capitalist friends in the south.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
