<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="38961" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Denmark, Iceland to continue fish row talks soon.</title>
<headline>Denmark, Iceland to continue fish row talks soon.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Denmark said on Friday it planned to hold more talks with Iceland soon in an attempt to resolve a North Atlantic fisheries row following two days of discussions between officials in the Danish capital.</p>
<p>&quot;The talks were aimed at reaching both a permanent and an interim solution on fishing areas. The parties agreed to continue their consultations in Reykjavik in the near future,&quot; the Danish Foreign Ministry said in a statement</p>
<p>The dispute was sparked by recent Icelandic demands that Danish vessels cease fishing a 10,000 square km (4,000 sq mile) area in the Denmark Strait between east Greenland and Iceland.</p>
<p>Last month Danish and Icelandic ministerial delegations held a first round of unsuccessful negotiations on the issue in the Icelandic capital Reykjavik.</p>
<p>Also under discussion are fishing rights in the North Atlantic between the Faroe Islands and Iceland.</p>
<p>In an incident in July, an Icelandic fisheries inspection vessel forced three Danish trawlers to quit the fishing area off Greenland.</p>
<p>Denmark maintains the two countries agreed in talks in Reykjavik in 1988 that trawlers with licences from Greenland, Denmark and Iceland would be allowed to fish in the so-called grey zone, which is rich in capelin.</p>
<p>Copenhagen conducts foreign policy for Greenland and the Faroe Islands, which have home rule under the Danish crown.</p>
<p>Iceland fought and won a protracted cod war with Britain in the 1970s.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ICEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I03000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
