<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="389766" id="root" date="1997-02-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: FORECAST-Volvo '96 profit 4 pct higher.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Volvo '96 profit 4 pct higher.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish vehicle manufacturer AB Volvo was on Wednesday expected to post a higher pre-tax profit for 1996 of 13.61 billion crowns, including capital gains, against 13.05 billion crowns in 1995, a Reuters poll showed.</p>
<p>A poll of 17 analysts found forecasts varied between 12.27 and 14.80 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Capital gains in 1996 were seen at between 8.21 and 8.40 billion crowns.</p>
<p>The difference was explained by estimates in Volvo's gains from its associate interests in other companies, which were 184 million crowns in its nine-month report.</p>
<p>In 1995 Volvo's capital gains from sales of wholly and part-owned companies was 4.21 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Earnings per share excluding capital gains for 1996 was forecast at 8.66 crowns. In 1995 earnings per share was 20.20 crowns.</p>
<p>Analysts estimated that Volvo would lift its dividend to 4.73 crowns a share in 1996 compared to 4.00 crowns in 1995.</p>
<p>Most analysts said it was open for Volvo to choose to give an extra dividend on the ground that the divestment of its ownership in Pripps-Ringnes was still not settled.  </p>
<p>The likelihood of Volvo handing out its stake in the drinks company to shareholders seemed less likely after Coca-Cola's decision to end its distribution agreement with Pripps-Ringnes.</p>
<p>Forecasts for coming years varied considerably on different estimates about when Volvo would sell its stakes in Pharmacia &amp; Upjohn and Pripps-Ringnes and how much it would get for these holdings.</p>
<p>Analysts interviewed for the poll were from Fiba Nordic, James Capel, Fischer Partners, Swedbank, Kleinwort Benson, Paribas, Morgan Grenfell, Handelsbanken, Nordiska, Foreningsbanken, Aros, CSFB, Enskilda, Danske Bank, Carnegie, Aragon, Ohman and Salomon Brothers.</p>
<p>Volvo will release its 1996 earnings report on February 19 with a press conference to be held at 1500 GMT.  </p>
<p> (MLN SKR)		 AVG	 RANGE	ANALYSTS</p>
<p> Pre-tax profit '96   13,609   12,269-14,803     17</p>
<p> Pre-tax profit '97    8,052    5,570-11,001     18</p>
<p> Pre-tax profit '98    9,726    5,270-13,002     15</p>
<p>(SKR)</p>
<p> Profit/shr 1996	  8.66     4.70-12.80	15</p>
<p> Profit/shr 1997	 10.88     4.70-15.50	17</p>
<p> Profit/shr 1998	 14.71     7.90-19.80	16</p>
<p> Dividend 1996	    4.73     4.00-6.00	 15</p>
<p> Dividend 1997	    5.30     3.80-7.00	 14</p>
<p> Dividend 1998	    6.28     4.00-9.00	 13</p>
<p>-- Henrik Alberius, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1250</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
