<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="38979" id="root" date="1996-09-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Kohl allies echo opposition tune on budget.</title>
<headline>Kohl allies echo opposition tune on budget.</headline>
<dateline>COLOGNE, Germany 1996-09-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chancellor Helmut Kohl's junior partners, the Free Democrats (FDP), took an unusually open slap at the government's budget and labour policies on Friday ahead of weekend coalition talks.</p>
<p>Otto Lambsdorff, honorary chairman and economic spokesman of the FDP, sounding more like an opposition Social Democrat (SPD), said the government's budget plan for 1997 was short by 10 billion marks ($6.75 billion).</p>
<p>&quot;In view of the dramatic labour market situation, one can only fear that this figure will rise even higher,&quot; Lambsdorff told the Cologne-based newspaper Express.</p>
<p>The SPD sees an 18 billion mark gap between budgeted spending and revenues next year that is not covered by planned government borrowing.</p>
<p>Germany and other European nations must meet strict deficit and debt targets if they hope to qualify for the European monetary union based on their economic performance in 1997, the key year for deciding the starting participants.</p>
<p>But higher outlays for unemployment benefits and other ends have boosted 1996 spending above budgeted levels, and Bonn would be forced to increase its borrowing, Lambsdorff said.</p>
<p>The situation was getting worse instead of better, as German unemployment was headed toward five million, not two million, he said.</p>
<p>Unemployment has hovered around a postwar record four million since the start of the year. The government's goal is to halve this figure by the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea that the number of unemployed could be halved by the year 2000 was illusory from the start,&quot; Lambsdorff said.</p>
<p>&quot;Germany is moving further away from the Maastricht criteria. Finance Minister (Theo Waigel) must bear most of the blame, because he rejected a budget-securing law,&quot; Lambsdorff said.</p>
<p>The 1997 draft budget was passed by the cabinet in July. Coalition budget experts are due to hold talks with Waigel over the weekend about the budget and further austerity proposals. A first reading in parliament is slated for next week.</p>
<p>The 1996 budget deficit, planned at 60 billion marks, is now seen at 70 billion to 75 billion marks.</p>
<p>-- Terence Gallagher, Bonn newsroom, 49 228 26097150 ($1=1.4816 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOGNE, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
