<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="390363" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: ATHLETICS-NEGURA DECRIES IAAF BAN COMPLAINT.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-NEGURA DECRIES IAAF BAN COMPLAINT.</headline>
<byline>Radu Timofte</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romanian Iulia Negura, stripped of her 1996 European women's cross country title after a positive doping test, said on Thursday any extension of her two-year ban would be a tragedy.</p>
<p>The Romanian Athletics Federation, invoking national regulations, imposed the ban after a second urine sample confirmed an initial positive test for the steroid stanozolol after her victory last December in Belgium.</p>
<p>But Romanian officials said the International Amateur Athletic Federation (IAAF) had indiciated it wanted an explanation of the ruling, pointing to international rules imposing a four-year ban for all steroid infringements. They said the IAAF could seek an extension of Negura's ban.</p>
<p>&quot;This would be a tragedy for me. I was relieved yesterday to get only a two-year ban, even though I am sure of my innocence,&quot; Negura, 30, told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm exhausted. After seven years of pressure and stress, my mental resistance is worn away. There is so much hostility in our sport. More and more money is circulating. Former champions are envious that we can compete and earn money.&quot;</p>
<p>Negura, a physical education student in eastern Romania, said she was considering legal action to clear her name.</p>
<p>Iolanda Balas, President of the Romanian Federation, made no comment on the IAAF's request for an explanation and repeated that the two-year ruling was based on a Ministry of Sports regulation applicable to all doping cases.</p>
<p>&quot;If Negura won any sort of court action, we would immediately ask the IAAF to lift the ban,&quot; she said by telephone.</p>
<p>Negura automatically lost her gold medal. The Romanian national team was also stripped of the silver medal they won for finishing in second place in Charleroi.</p>
<p>Both Negura and her coach Dorin Melinte denied she had taken a banned substance. Melinte quit his job as national long distance athletics coach after the announcement, saying he could no longer work in an &quot;atmosphere of suspicion&quot;.</p>
<p>Several instances of doping have tarnished the image of Romanian athletics as competitors have sought the big cash prizes and foreign contracts to escape post-Communist poverty.</p>
<p>Nine athletes, eight of them women, have been banned in the last three years. Among them was 1993 indoor world champion long jumper Marieta Ilcu -- banned two years later.</p>
<p>A statement on Wednesday by the Federation also said the lenient attitude to Negura was based on the fact that the offence was her first in a long career.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
