<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="390354" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Stockpile opens white metal sale on March 24.</title>
<headline>U.S. Stockpile opens white metal sale on March 24.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. government will dip a toe in the white metals market for the first time on March 24 when it offers for sale part of its large hoard of platinum and palladium.</p>
<p>In the current fiscal year the Defense National Stockpile Center has authority to sell 10,188 troy ounces of platinum and 15,000 troy ounces of palladium on a sealed bid process.</p>
<p>Both metals are 99.95 percent pure, with the platinum supplied by Engelhard Minerals and Chemical Corp, and the Russian produced palladium supplied by Engelhard-Philipp Brothers.  </p>
<p>The minimum amount that can be bid for is one lot of palladium or 500-600 ounces, and one lot of platinum or 600 ounces. All the stockpiled metal was bought in the 1950s and 1960s.</p>
<p>DNSC inventory of platinum and palladium total 431,760 ounces and 1,264,601 ounces respectively.</p>
<p>All of this fiscal year's allocation of both metals will be up for grabs on March 24, but any unsold amounts will be offered on the fourth Monday of each month until exhausted.</p>
<p>The DNSC held a meeting for platinum and palladium industry officials on Wednesday to unveil how the metals will be sold.  </p>
<p>DNSC officials said bidders will have to make their offer based on a percentage of the London afternoon fix for both metals. The London fix for the day after the bids are accepted will be used as a basis for awarding.</p>
<p>Stockpile officials said they decided against using the New York Mercantile Exchange (NYMEX) platinum and palladium futures contracts as a price basis.</p>
<p>&quot;It's pretty typical that platinum and palladium is priced off London. It's not a big deal,&quot; Johnson Matthey's general manager, precious metals sales and services, Gordon Bassett told the meeting.  </p>
<p>There were concerns about bidders being caught out by sudden price movements between submitting their bids and the following day's London afternoon fix.</p>
<p>Bassett said bearing in mind the amount for sale, the bidding process will generally have no effect on the market. &quot;But if it was a very very quiet day, it may do something,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Stockpile administrator, Richard Connelly said he would consider introducing a price floor into the final solicitation by March 24.  </p>
<p>Bassett, Allen Miller of Complex Elements Corp and others at the meeting said they expected all bid offers to be at a discount to the London fix.</p>
<p>The platinum up for sale could not be delivered against the NYMEX futures contract in its present form, and the sample of palladium outlined by stockpile officials also appeared to be in the wrong form for NYMEX, Bassett said.</p>
<p>Bruce Dunn of Gerald Metals Inc told the meeting that much of the stockpiled metal for sale would probably have to be refined or recast. Most of those interested in the sale would therefore be refiners rather than brokers.  </p>
<p>&quot;You have to factor in that cost. There will be a steeper discount,&quot; Dunn said.</p>
<p>No platinum or palladium has been included in future DNSC sales plans. &quot;But we have sizeable inventories and I would expect that having broken the ice, Congress will be offering more of these in the next year or two,&quot; Connelly said.</p>
<p>((Huw Jones, New York Commodity Desk 212-859-1646))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
