<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="390376" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: CRICKET-ENGLAND CRUISE TO ONE-DAY VICTORY.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-ENGLAND CRUISE TO ONE-DAY VICTORY.</headline>
<dateline>CHRISTCHURCH, New Zealand 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A classy, controlled partnership of 170 between Alec Stewart and Graham Thorpe carried England to a four-wicket win over New Zealand in Thursday's opening one-day international.</p>
<p>England left-arm spinner and man-of-the-match Phil Tufnell had earlier bounced back from an off-field controversy to do the damage to New Zealand, claiming four for 22 from 10 overs, his best one-day international figures.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, England manager John Barclay rejected allegations by staff at a Christchurch restaurant that Tufnell and two companions had smoked cannabis in a toilet there.</p>
<p>Chasing New Zealand's inadequate 222 for six, England had a brief hiccup when they lost two wickets at 28, before Stewart and Thorpe took charge, adding 170 in 156 minutes off 207 balls and often toying with the New Zealand bowling.</p>
<p>England had a late scare when three wickets fell in 19 balls for the addition of nine runs, but got through to 226 for six, with seven balls to spare.</p>
<p>Nasser Hussain was unbeaten on 11 while Robert Croft eased a tricky late situation for England by thumping his first two balls through the offside to the fence to secure the victory.</p>
<p>Having won the second and third tests of their series, England carried on from where they left off on Tuesday and had New Zealand's measure from early in the day.</p>
<p>New Zealand's batting struggled after a bright start while the bowling lacked discipline and penetration.</p>
<p>After England captain Mike Atherton got his team off to a snappy start with three early boundaries, New Zealand struck back with two wickets in three balls.</p>
<p>Atherton played inside a straight ball from off-spinner Dipak Patel and was bowled for 19, then fellow opener Nick Knight edged Simon Doull to wicketkeeper Lee Germon.</p>
<p>But Stewart and Thorpe settled quickly into their work.</p>
<p>The England 50 arrived in the 12th over and Stewart took boundaries in consecutive deliveries from Nathan Astle before clubbing the first ball from medium-pacer Chris Cairns into the stand at long on.</p>
<p>Stewart took England to 100 with two fours in three balls from Cairns and at the halfway stage they were 14 runs and one wicket better off than New Zealand at 117 for two.</p>
<p>England needed 30 in the last 10 overs, but both batsmen were then out in the eighties, in quick succession, to fast bowler Heath Davis.</p>
<p>Garvin Larsen and Davis restricted England near the end,  14 runs being needed off the last five overs, and six off the last two when Davis had Dominic Cork caught at mid-wicket off a full toss.</p>
<p>Croft then ended New Zealand's hopes of an improbable victory with two fours in succession.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHRISTCHURCH, New Zealand"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
