<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="390454" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: SOCCER-FEYENOORD RISK LOSING POINTS IF ANY FURTHER FAN VIOLENCE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-FEYENOORD RISK LOSING POINTS IF ANY FURTHER FAN VIOLENCE.</headline>
<dateline>ROTTERDAM 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Feyenoord, fined seven times already this season because of their rampaging supporters, risk losing points if there is any further trouble, Dutch media reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Dutch soccer association (KNVB) have urged the Rotterdam club to discourage their followers from travelling to Sunday's potentially explosive league match at Ajax Amsterdam.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the frequency of the disturbances and the club's claim that it is powerless to stop the trouble, it would appear necessary to take more drastic measures,&quot; the KNVB said.</p>
<p>The Daily Algemeen Dagblad said if supporters caused trouble at Sunday's game in Amsterdam, the KNVB would officially ban Feyenoord fans from away games. Any further misbehaviour would result in points being docked.</p>
<p>Feyenoord chairman Jorien van den Herik was quoted as saying: &quot;I'm open to any solution, but the KNVB mustn't hold Feyenoord entirely responsible. We're powerless.&quot;</p>
<p>Amsterdam police have said they are well prepared for crowd violence at Sunday's match and do not plan any extra measures, even after rival fans armed with knives and clubs clashed last weekend on a road just north of Amsterdam.</p>
<p>A spokesman said 400 uniformed police would be on duty and plain-clothes police would be in among the crowd. Closed-circuit television would film fans inside and outside the stadium.</p>
<p>Feyenoord have been allocated 1,600 tickets for Sunday's game.</p>
<p>When Ajax played in Rotterdam last November, Feyenoord fans lobbed fire-bombs at police and bombarded the Ajax team bus. One newspaper labelled the fixture &quot;The Match of Hate&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROTTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
