<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39048" id="root" date="1996-09-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-JUNINHO THRIVING AT GOAL-HAPPY MIDDLESBROUGH.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-JUNINHO THRIVING AT GOAL-HAPPY MIDDLESBROUGH.</headline>
<byline>Gideon Long</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Juninho has played for Brazil under the South American sun and competed in the Olympics in the heat of Atlanta but, for the moment, nothing compares to soccer at Middlesbrough on the bracing northeast coast of England.</p>
<p>&quot;It's lovely to play in a team like this,&quot; he enthused after his side's latest high-scoring triumph. &quot;The frontmen move very well and when you get the ball you've always got a choice of two or three players to pass to.</p>
<p>&quot;If the team passes as well as we can do, we can beat anyone.&quot;</p>
<p>If this week is anything to go by, Juninho is right.</p>
<p>Middlesbrough slammed four goals past West Ham in midweek at the Riverside stadium, before repeating the feat against hapless Coventry on Saturday, this time without conceding a goal.</p>
<p>They have now scored 12 times in five games -- a strike-rate matched only by defending champions Manchester United -- and Italian Fabrizio Ravanelli is the premier league's top scorer with six goals.</p>
<p>Two of those came on Saturday as Bryan Robson's side tore Coventry apart. The little Brazilian added the other two.</p>
<p>&quot;Ravanelli and Juninho have settled into the side earlier than I could have expected,&quot; Robson said. &quot;They are top players who have great presence.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;But what's pleased me is the way they've slotted in alongside Nick Barmby and Robbie Mustoe,&quot; the former England captain added.</p>
<p>&quot;Juninho gave his best performance this season today but they are taking it in turns to deliver. People are hitting form at different times which is good.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Our attacking play was good again, our passing and movement was excellent, and we look as though we are going to score goals all the time. We also kept a clean sheet for the first time this season which is pleasing.&quot;</p>
<p>Given the money Middlesbrough have spent on their side over the past year or so, their success should not surprise anyone.</p>
<p>Ravanelli cost $7.0 million from Juventus, Juninho's compatriot Emerson cost a further $4.0 million from Porto, and that was after Robson made serious inroads into last season's budget to bring Juninho and Branco to England.</p>
<p>But despite the big spending, no one seemed to believe Middlesbrough had the experience and strength in depth to challenge for the league title. Now perhaps they do.</p>
<p>Chelsea player-manager Ruud Gullit also reaped dividends from his summer spending as his cosmopolitan side went to Hillsborough and ended Sheffield Wednesday's 100 percent record with an impressive 2-0 win.</p>
<p>While Middlesbrough appear hell-bent on attack, Chelsea, who let slip a two-goal lead at Arsenal in midweek to draw 3-3, are concentrating on defence.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought our play against Arsenal was a bit too open,&quot; Gullit said. &quot;In between the two games we worked on not giving away chances and I was happier with the way things went today.</p>
<p>&quot;Wednesday did create some opportunities, but there were more from dead-ball situations than open play.&quot;</p>
<p>Arsenal again came from 2-0 down to salvage a point at Villa Park on Saturday, to the anger of Aston Villa's new Yugoslav signing Sasa Curcic, who thought the referee should have blown for time before Andy Linighan stole an injury-time equaliser.</p>
<p>&quot;I asked the referee if he had lost his watch and pointed to our clock at the ground which showed five minutes overtime,&quot; Curcic said.</p>
<p>&quot;He showed me the yellow card and I was very upset because a beautiful game had been spoiled. I wasn't so much concerned that we had lost two points and a two-goal lead but that the game had been ruined.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
