<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="390569" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Coffee rally reignites, gold jumps.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Coffee rally reignites, gold jumps.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A rally in world coffee prices was reignited on Thursday just as it had seemed that consumers could expect some respite. Traders cited continuing worries about tight nearby supplies.</p>
<p>Gold also jumped in a further correction to its recent tumble to 3-3/4 year lows and traded above $351 per ounce - a gain of more than $5 from the afternoon London fixing. The death of Deng Xiaoping had no apparent impact on the commodity sector although analysts said that, with 1.2 billion people and a burgeoning economy, China is a huge buyer of raw materials so that any subsequent instability there would be unnerving.</p>
<p>May futures for arabica coffee in New York hit new life-of-contract highs at 173 cents per pound before profiting.</p>
<p>London robusta futures touched $1,655 per tonne. This didn't match last Friday's $1,705 at the recent height of a rally that has taken coffee up about 50 percent since the end of 1996.</p>
<p>But it was way up on $1,460 to which the market sank on Wednesday when it seemed that the rally was over. Traders say the market is now very volatile and hard to predict. Industrial metals prices were steadier on Thursday after a brisk advance on Wednesday on prospects that China may buy copper for its strategic stockpile.</p>
<p>Three months delivery copper on the London Metal Exchange had raced to an 8-1/2 month peak of $2,360 on Wednesday for a gain of almost $75 from Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>Thursday saw copper ease to around $2,330 late in the London afternoon.</p>
<p>Copper's surge this week fuelled parallel rallies in nearly all of the other base metals. Aluminium held its gains on Thursday and was trading above $1,600 a tonne late in the LME day.</p>
<p>New York futures led the late rally by gold bullion which took it up in little more than an hour from a London fix at $345 an ounce to above $350.50.</p>
<p>Traders said stop loss orders kicked in when the New York futures market edged up above the week's previous best values, then fund money came in. The gold price has been correcting up in a rather subdued, technical market, after fears of central bank selling sent it to its 3-3/4 year low, down almost to $336, on February 12. Oil prices were just easier.</p>
<p>Some key prices at 1730 GMT on Thursday -</p>
<p>					  Thursday	  Wednesday</p>
<p> Ldn Spot Gold ($ per ounce)     350.50	     346.75</p>
<p> IPE Brent Crude Oil (Mar)	  19.96		20.28</p>
<p>Ldn Metal Exchange (3 mths delivery)</p>
<p> Copper ($ per tonne)	     2332.00	    2340.00</p>
<p> Aluminium ($ per tonne)	  1607.00	    1608.00</p>
<p>LIFFE</p>
<p> Robusta Coffee ($ per/)(May)   1560.00	    1506.00</p>
<p> Cocoa (Stg per tonne) (May)     876.00	     880.00</p>
<p> White Sugar ($ p/t May)	   309.50	     307.60</p>
<p>Chicago Board of Trade</p>
<p> Wheat (Cents per bushel)(Mar)	364		  365</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
