<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="390529" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Omens not promising for Major in by-election.</title>
<headline>Omens not promising for Major in by-election.</headline>
<byline>Alan Wheatley</byline>
<dateline>WIRRAL, Britain 1996-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The omens for Prime Minister John Major's Conservative party are not promising, less than a week before a crucial parliamentary by-election in an affluent corner of northwest England.</p>
<p>The seat is traditional Conservative territory. Unemployment is below the national average, more than eight in 10 people own their own homes and nearly half work in professional or managerial jobs.</p>
<p>Yet, if the opinion polls are correct, Wirral South is about to return a member of parliament from the main opposition Labour party for the first time since the constituency was created in 1983.</p>
<p>In what is billed as a dress rehearsal for general elections that must be held within three months, voter surveys suggest Labour's Ben Chapman will easily overturn the 8,183 majority won by the late Conservative member at the 1992 election.</p>
<p>If they are accurate, the Conservatives would be thrust into a minority of one in parliament and Labour, out of power since 1979, would get a big psychological boost for the national election campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;Labour has never won a safe Conservative seat so close to a general election in any circumstances. It would be a first,&quot; said Ian McCartney, a Labour member of parliament who is coordinating Chapman's campaign.</p>
<p>Conservative strategists privately accept the possibility of defeat but insist that their supporters, if they lodge a protest in the by-election on February 27, will flock back to their natural home in the general election.</p>
<p>But, if the comments of a dozen or so floating voters in the key swing ward of Bebington are anything to go by, the Conservatives have a hard task ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;I just think it's about time we got rid of the Tories,&quot; said Derek Evans, 45, who works at Liverpool University on the other side of the River Mersey.</p>
<p>Whereas Liverpool is synonymous with industrial decline, Wirral South is a prosperous commuter belt. It has earned the tag &quot;Surrey by the Mersey&quot; after the well-off county south of London preferred by well-heeled stockbrokers.</p>
<p>Evans, who voted for the minority Liberal Democrats at the last election, appeared unwilling to give the Conservatives any credit for the lowest inflation and home-loan rates in a generation. &quot;I just don't feel any better off,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A former teacher said she might switch from the Conservatives in protest against local education cuts. Another, worried about crime, health and unemployment, said she would either stay at home or vote Labour.</p>
<p>Jean Christian, 66, voiced similar concerns and said she would desert the Conservatives for either Labour or the Liberal Democrats.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation in the country is not good,&quot; she said. &quot;The whole of society has changed since I was younger, and especially in the past 20 years.&quot;</p>
<p>But, giving a glimmer of hope to Major, Christian said she was worried that a Labour government, despite the iron grip of moderate leader Tony Blair, might herald a return to industrial strife and high taxes.</p>
<p>&quot;We seem to have got over a bit of that, but I feel if the Labour party got in at the general election, a lot of those problems might emerge again,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>John McCormack, 63, said he would switch to Labour with some misgivings. &quot;It's not that I support their policies but because I think the Conservative government needs a good kick up the arse,&quot; he said. &quot;They've made all these promises for years but they've never carried them out.&quot;</p>
<p>Wirral South does not figure on Labour's list of the 60 key marginal seats it must capture at the general election if it is to regain power. It ranks about 140th.</p>
<p>But its voters, in an admittedly unscientific sample, seem to be saying that it is time for a change.</p>
<p>&quot;I've been very disenchanted really, generally speaking,&quot; said one woman who plans to switch from Conservative to Labour. &quot;And I don't think it's good for any country to be ruled for so long by any one party.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WIRRAL, Britain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
