<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="390649" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire's Mobutu still able to spring a surprise.</title>
<headline>Zaire's Mobutu still able to spring a surprise.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Malu-Malu</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's Mobutu Sese Seko may be weakened by illness but all the signs are that the political reflexes that have kept him in power for over three decades remain as sharp as ever.</p>
<p>Reports from South Africa linking the president's nephew and chief security adviser, Ngbada Nzambo Ko Ayumba, to a bid to mediate an end to Zaire's five-month civil war suggest that the veteran strongman still sees himself very much in the driving seat.</p>
<p>Neither Zaire's prime minister nor visiting African foreign ministers appear to have known anything about the initiative suggesting Mobutu's ability to act independently and unexpectedly -- one of the secrets of his staying power -- remains intact.</p>
<p>&quot;Until now, I am completely unaware that President Mobutu may have sent any emissary to meet Mr Kabila,&quot; Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo told journalists on Wednesday, referring to rebel leader and veteran Mobutu foe Laurent Kabila.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't say anything. I know nothing about it,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>African foreign ministers, including South Africa's Alfred Nzo, appeared equally in the dark. &quot;Now we are returning we will get the details,&quot; Nzo told a news conference in Nairobi one day after talks in Kinshasa with Zairean ministers.</p>
<p>The Tutsi-led rebels took up arms in October accusing Mobutu officials of denying them citizenship and seeking to expel them to neighbouring Rwanda, their ancestral home. They now hold towns and territory in the east.</p>
<p>Zaire accuses neighbouring Rwanda, Uganda and Burundi of invading in support of the rebels, a charge all three reject.</p>
<p>Mobutu, one of Africa's longest serving leaders, seized power in 1965 -- five years after independence from Belgium.</p>
<p>He has ruled the sprawling and anarchic Central African nation with a mixture of military might and political acumen -- keeping opponents in disarray or buying off his enemies.</p>
<p>Prostate surgery in Europe in August and prolonged convalesence there raised questions at home and abroad about how long he would live but he returned in December to reshuffle the military leadership and government and set Zaire on a war footing before leaving for further medical tests in Europe.</p>
<p>Kengo then took the initiative, ordering a much touted government counter-offensive on January 20 but rebel counter-attacks on several fronts blunted that counter-thrust.</p>
<p>Mobutu, 66, returned home on February 7 but little had been heard from him -- until South African President Nelson Mandela let slip on Wednesday, to everyone's surprise, that Mobutu and Kabila had asked South Africa to host exploratory peace talks.</p>
<p>One diplomat in South Africa told Reuters the initiative had come from the Zairean authorities.</p>
<p>Zaire had previously ruled out talks with Kabila, dismissing him as a puppet of Rwanda, Uganda and Burundi.</p>
<p>The Zairean government, in particular Kengo, have staked their reputation on a military solution to the war.</p>
<p>The deputy leader of Mobutu's supporters in Zaire's transitional parliament, Banza Mukalayi, on Tuesday restated the official commitment to the military option.</p>
<p>&quot;We have said that we won't negotiate. It's clear that not negotiating implies recourse to military means,&quot; he said, defending government air raids on rebel-held towns on Monday.</p>
<p>Relief workers said the air strikes, which appeared to mark a new phase in the conflict, killed at least 18 people.</p>
<p>Amid the government sabre-rattling, the main opposition of Etienne Tshisekedi, a bitter foe of Kengo, has repeatedly advocated peace talks.</p>
<p>Politician, businessman and Mobutu associate Bemba Saolona called for peace talks earlier this month. &quot;We have to achieve a genuine national reconciliation if we want Zaire to take off economically. If we do not negotiate with Laurent Kabila, things will not fall back in place,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>The opposition went further, talking of an independent peace mission to Kabila. Mobutu may have beaten them to it.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
