<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="390789" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian stocks mixed, foreign buyers needed.</title>
<headline>Croatian stocks mixed, foreign buyers needed.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks were mixed in slower trade on Thursday, and market participants expected the prices to stagnate unless foreign investors step in to prop up trade.</p>
<p>&quot;It is hard to say what any of the big buyers are up to,&quot; said Marko Nikolac of Metroholding brokerage.</p>
<p>However, he singled out chocolate maker Kras as the market's favourite in the days ahead after the firm said it was soon to close an agreement on investment with the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD).</p>
<p>After the announcement it added another seven kuna to 497 and was among the most active stocks with 1,501 shares sold.</p>
<p>Nikolac said Kras could rise further but if not, it would definitely continue to be traded on large volumes.</p>
<p>Rumours about the deal have moved its price up again over the past week after a long stagnation.</p>
<p>Four other issues also rose on Thursday while three fell and two were flat. Volume halved to 5,946 kuna and turnover shrank to 2.1 from 9.4 million kuna.</p>
<p>Biggest gainer cable maker Elka inched up eight kuna to 175, selling 110 shares.</p>
<p>Fully-listed drugs firm Pliva rose two kuna to 487, with 130 shares sold. Zagrebacka Banka ordinary stock lost 49 kuna to 1,841, selling only 41 units.</p>
<p>Foreign investors were now said to be reluctant to buy bigger packages of Pliva and Zagrebacka, as the spread between their Zagreb and London prices was too small.</p>
<p>Pliva's Global Depository Receipts (GDRs) eased to $16.475 in London, from the $16.55 opening. Zagrebacka's GDRs, trading on Seaq, also fell to $31.12 from $32.12 in the morning.</p>
<p>Food processor Podravka was the most actively traded issue, holding its ground at 319.9 kuna with 2,620 units sold.</p>
<p>Hotelier Laguna led decliners, losing 40 kuna to 1,400 on volume of 21 shares and Nikolac said it was losing pace after one big foreign buyer withdrew its orders.</p>
<p>Jadranturist edged down five kuna to 320, with 559 shares.</p>
<p>But two other active hoteliers firmed, Riviera by five kuna to 180 and Suncani Hvar three kuna to 67. Volume for both was in the hundreds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
