<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="390719" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Albright meets Russians, NATO proposes arm cuts.</title>
<headline>Albright meets Russians, NATO proposes arm cuts.</headline>
<byline>Carol Giacomo</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright met Russian leaders on Thursday to try calm their fears over NATO's eastward expansion plans, and the Western defence alliance proposed big conventional arms cuts as a sweetener.</p>
<p>Russian officials reiterated their opposition to NATO's enlargement before Albright's arrival in Moscow, but she reported a good start at talks with Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin and Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we had some good meetings. It was a matter of establishing a relationship and getting to know each other,&quot; Albright, who is on an inaugural tour as secretary of state, told reporters. &quot;Then we got down to work.&quot;</p>
<p>She gave no details although she said talks covered the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation's plans to take in former Warsaw Pact states, which Moscow says threatens its security, and preparations for a U.S.-Russian summit next month.</p>
<p>Albright began her two-day visit as NATO officials presented its arms reduction plan to a body in Vienna dealing with the 1990 Conventional Forces in Europe (CFE) treaty.</p>
<p>Moscow wants the treaty revised and NATO intended the proposal to soften Russian opposition to expansion and soothe Moscow's fears that the alliance could pile up weapons on its borders.</p>
<p>&quot;Specifically, the total of future aggregate national ceilings of ground treaty limited equipment of (NATO's) 16 members will be significantly less under the adapted treaty,&quot; the proposal said.</p>
<p>It would also establish a &quot;sensitive geographic region&quot; in central Europe, comprising the Baltic enclave of Kaliningrad, Ukraine, Slovakia, Belarus, the Czech Republic, Hungary and Poland, in which ground equipment could not be increased.</p>
<p>Albright was expected to touch on the proposal during her talks in Moscow, which culminate in a meeting with President Boris Yeltsin on Friday. A U.S. official said she would hand Yeltsin a letter from President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>She brought an offer of a charter defining NATO-Russian relations and explain an idea to create a joint NATO-Russian military brigade, mainly for peacekeeping.</p>
<p>Russian and U.S. officials played down the chances of a breakthrough during Albright's visit, but NATO leaders hope for progress when Clinton and Yeltsin meet in Helsinki next month.</p>
<p>Albright's spokesman, Nicholas Burns, said the meetings so far had been &quot;very constructive and very detailed&quot; and conducted in a warm atmosphere. He quoted Primakov as telling Albright: &quot;I'm going to be nice to you&quot;.</p>
<p>But Yeltsin's press secretary, Sergei Yastrzhembsky, said before Albright arrived that Russia remained implacably opposed to NATO expansion, which it regards as a threat to its security.</p>
<p>&quot;(Our opposition) will remain, whatever the outcome of the negotiations between Russia and the Atlantic alliance,&quot; Interfax news agency quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>Yastrzhembsky repeated the Kremlin's demand for a legally binding contract providing security guarantees for Russia in the event of NATO's expansion.</p>
<p>The foreign ministers of Italy and Germany, who both visited Moscow this week trying to sell NATO's plans, found a rare unanimity among Russians across the political spectrum.</p>
<p>&quot;NATO is an instrument of the Cold War and we have only just learned to live without the Cold War,&quot; the communist speaker of the State Duma lower house of parliament, Gennady Seleznyov, told Italy's Lamberto Dini.</p>
<p>Dini said after his talks in Moscow that Italy believed NATO expansion could &quot;only take place with the consensus of Russia and not against its will.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
