<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="390834" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech Unipetrol to detail merger plan on Monday.</title>
<headline>Czech Unipetrol to detail merger plan on Monday.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The government-held Czech petrochemical holding company Unipetrol a.s. said on Thursday it would reveal next week details of its plan to merge with Kaucuk Group a.s. and Chemopetrol Group a.s..</p>
<p>Unipetrol spokesman Jiri Polak said the ratio at which shares in the two petrochemical firms will be swapped for Unipetrol stock will be announced at a news conference on Monday, as well as the firm's plans for listing on the bourse.</p>
<p>Polak declined to comment on an unsourced report on Thursday in the economic daily Hospodarske Noviny which said Chemopetrol owners would get 11 100-crown shares in Unipetrol for one 1,000 crown share, while Kaucuk shares would be swapped at a 12 to one ratio.</p>
<p>Unipetrol has said earlier that the swap would give between 1.05 and 1.20 of Unipetrol shares for one Chemopetrol share, and between 1.10 and 1.25 of Unipetrol shares for one Kaucuk share, of the same nominal value.</p>
<p>&quot;Our last official statement was the interval,&quot; Polak told Reuters on Thursday.</p>
<p>Kaucuk and Chemopetrol shares, which have normally been converging toward each other ahead of an expected announcement of the swap, on Thursday moved in different directions.</p>
<p>Kaucuk rose 19 crowns to 1,364 at the daily fixing on the Prague Stock Exchange, while Chemopetrol was down 12 crowns at 1,318 midway through Thursday's session.</p>
<p>Any plan must be approved by three general shareholders meetings, planned for March 27, but any one submitted is likely to sail through as the government still hold majority stakes in Chemopetrol and Kaucuk.</p>
<p>The merger gives Unipetrol a commanding position over the whole petrochemical sector in the country.</p>
<p>It also controls fuels distriution company Benzina, as well as 51 percent of refineries  Ceska Rafinerska a.s., created from the separating of the refining units from Chemopetrol and Kaucuk.</p>
<p>A consortium of Conoco, Agip SpA, and Royal Dutch/Shell took a 49 percent stake in Rafinerska in 1995.</p>
<p>The new corporate structure after the merger should take effec on July 1, Polak said.</p>
<p>Unipetrol shares are still 100 percent held by the Czech government until the merger is complete.</p>
<p>Analysts do not expect public trading in Unipetrol shares until well after the deal is finalised.</p>
<p>-- Jan Lopatka, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
