<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="391006" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil to divulge 1996 deficit figures Friday.</title>
<headline>Brazil to divulge 1996 deficit figures Friday.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's Central Bank will divulge the 1996 public sector operational deficit at 1100 local/1400 GMT Friday, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>The bank will also reveal January monetary base aggregates, deficit figures and debt levels, he added.</p>
<p>Altamir Lopes, head of the bank's economics department, has previously confirmed market predictions of a 4.5 percent of gross domestic product operational deficit last year.</p>
<p>On Tuesday this week, he told Reuters that though the results were not completely finalized, the trend suggested a &quot;pleasant surprise&quot;. He did not elaborate.  </p>
<p>Brazil posted an operational deficit of 5 percent of GDP in 1995 and the government originally intended to halve that shortfall in 1996.</p>
<p>Its aim to slash the gap to about 2.5 percent of GDP this year was dealt a blow Wednesday when the Supreme Federal Tribunal, the country's highest court, ruled in favor of a 28.9 percent wage claim lodged by 11 civil servants.</p>
<p>The government fears the pay rise could be extended to up to one million other public sector workers, putting considerable strain on its finances.</p>
<p>((-- Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom 55-61-2230358))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
