<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="391283" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. pets chowing down on more rice-based foods.</title>
<headline>U.S. pets chowing down on more rice-based foods.</headline>
<byline>Anna Driver</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Use of rice as an ingredient in dog and cat foods in the U.S. has skyrocketed as consumers grow more health conscious about their pets' diets and more pet food companies introduce new products containing rice.</p>
<p>&quot;Rice is getting more notice as a nutritious food by the consuming public, and those same people are going to feed their animals the most nutritious food that they can find,&quot; said Bill Reed, vice president with  Riceland Foods cooperative in Stuttgart, Ark. </p>
<p>The amount of broken grain rice in pet food has more than doubled since 1991, when usage totaled 206.5 million lbs, according to statistics compiled by the USA Rice Federation in Houston, Texas. In 1996, 483.5 million lbs were used.</p>
<p>Beer brewers are still the primary buyers of U.S. rice with broken kernels, a lesser grade than the usual long or short grain rice that is sold in food stores.</p>
<p>But the brewers now have growing competition from pet food manufacturers for supplies, and that competition has pushed prices higher, market observers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's definitely a livelier battle between the brewers and the pet food people today,&quot; said Mark Creed, president of Creed Rice Co. Inc in Houston, Texas.</p>
<p>Last week, broken grains were quoted at $15.00 to $14.00 per hundred lbs (cwt), compared to the $12.00 to $13.00 range established a year ago. Part of that price increase is due to the increased use of rice in pet food, Creed said.</p>
<p>Rice was once only used in premium or all-natural pet foods but now familiar name brands such as H.J. Heinz' Nine Lives and  Mars Inc's Kal Kan have introduced pet foods blended with rice that are readily available in supermarkets.  </p>
<p>Rice was orginally fed to dogs and cats that had allergies to corn, wheat or other cereals used in pet foods.</p>
<p>But rice specialists say the grain has gained popularity recently among pet owners because it is viewed as a more beneficial ingredient for their pets, industry sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;They see rice as a healthier alternative,&quot; said James Sokolowski, a veterinarian for Kal Kan Inc in Vernon, Calif. &quot;Rice is the most digestible grain source and it contains some protein and carbohydrates.&quot;  </p>
<p>While cereals are always mixed with meat products in pet foods, nutrition experts said that rice in combination with either lamb or poultry was easier for animals to digest than corn or wheat combined with other meats.</p>
<p>Sokolowski said that rice products have proven to be so popular with dog owners that Kal Kan plans to introduce a puppy food containing rice. This would join the Kal Kan cat and dog food rice varieties already on grocery shelves.</p>
<p>Linda Case, author of a book on pet nutrition and lecturer in the Animal Science Department at the University of Illinois, said that although rice does have health benefits for some animals, its popularity has been boosted by the successful marketing efforts of pet food manufacturers,</p>
<p>&quot;Rice is perceived as more healthful alternative, but there's really no reason for it,&quot; Case said. &quot;Corn properly prepared is also an excellent source of nutrition for pets.&quot;</p>
<p>Most rice industry observers expect the use of rice in dog and cat food to continue grow as long as Americans continue to pamper their pets.</p>
<p>((Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42210">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
