<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="391243" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Georgian diplomat surrenders in car accident case.</title>
<headline>Georgian diplomat surrenders in car accident case.</headline>
<byline>James Vicini</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Georgian diplomat surrendered to police on Thursday to face criminal charges over his role in a car accident that killed a teenage girl in Washington last month, U.S. law enforcement officials said.</p>
<p>The surrender of Gueorgui Makharadze, his country's No. 2 diplomat in Washington, followed an announcement last weekend that the Republic of Georgia had taken the rare diplomatic step of formally waiving his diplomatic immunity.</p>
<p>The officials said Makharadze, 35, was being formally charged with involuntary manslaughter and four counts of aggravated assault, charges that carry a maximum possible punishment of 70 years in prison.</p>
<p>Police have said speed and alcohol may have played a role in the five-car crash in downtown Washington on January 4, allegedly triggered when Makharadze, travelling at an estimated 80 miles per hour (129 kph), slammed into a car stopped for a red light at Dupont Circle.</p>
<p>The accident killed Joviane Waltrick, a 16-year-old Brazilian girl living in the Washington suburb of Kensington, Maryland, and injured three other people.</p>
<p>Police said Makharadze lost control of his car and ran into a vehicle waiting at a stop light. The force of the crash catapulted the second vehicle into a third car, killing Waltrick, who was a passenger in it.</p>
<p>&quot;He has turned himself in,&quot; one official said. &quot;He is in the process of being charged right now.&quot;</p>
<p>The officials said Makharadze was taken into custody and would be processed by the police, a step that includes having his fingerprints taken. An arraignment had been set for late Thursday afternoon in a local court.</p>
<p>U.S. Attorney Eric Holder, whose office will prosecute the high-profile case, scheduled a news conference for later Thursday to detail the charges.</p>
<p>The officials have said tests at Georgetown University hospital, taken several hours after the accident, showed that Makharadze had a blood alcohol level far above that required to establish drunkenness under the law.</p>
<p>The officials said prosecutors wanted Makharadze to surrender his passport but he probably would be released on certain conditions, possibly to the custody of a third party. Those details still are being worked on, they said.</p>
<p>Lawyers close to the case said there have been no discussions between prosecutors and Makharadze's attorneys about a possible plea deal.</p>
<p>Georgian President Eduard Shevardnadze said this week, after waiving diplomatic immunity, that he may seek to have Makharadze serve any prison time in Georgia, rather than the United States, if he is convicted.</p>
<p>Makharadze was a rising star in the Georgian foreign service, making the decision to grant the rare waiver of immunity an even harder one for Shevardnadze.</p>
<p>The officials said the next step in the case will be for the judge to set a trial date.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
