<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="391228" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Laggard funds could lead the pack.</title>
<headline>Laggard funds could lead the pack.</headline>
<byline>Clint Willis</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON</dateline>
<text>
<p>With the stock market setting record after record during the past few years, most investors have found it easy to choose winning mutual funds.</p>
<p>But a turnaround in the stock market could lead to serious losses for today's most popular funds. At the same time, many of today's laggard funds could become the leaders.</p>
<p>How likely is a stock market decline? Well, the current bull market is the longest in history -- and at six years old, the economic recovery is pretty long in the tooth. Those two facts are enough to worry more than a few analysts.</p>
<p>Others maintain that today's low-inflation, slow-growth environment can persist indefinitely, supporting stock prices for years to come. If they're right, we'll all do well. If not, investors might wish they had spread some money among funds that can hold up reasonably well in a bear market.</p>
<p>Look for them among the many first-rate funds that have shunned the hottest sectors of the recent bull market. Some of these funds invest in staid, dividend-paying issues that will likely deliver solid long-term returns, but probably will not keep up with the trendiest growth stocks in a bull market like this one.</p>
<p>Example: T. Rowe Price Equity-Income (800-638-5660; $2,500 minimum initial investment; no-load). Manager Brian Rogers avoids hot technology firms and instead favours undervalued shares of large firms that pay dividends.</p>
<p>Other funds stick to value stocks -- shares that trade at modest prices relative to the values of the companies that issue them. They include Oakmark Fund (800-625-6275; $2,500 minimum investment; no-load), which holds shares of medium- and large-size companies that manager Robert Sanborn believes are undervalued relative to the companies' actual worth.</p>
<p>A handful of funds go even further, betting against the market's hottest stocks by using a technique called &quot;short selling&quot;. The funds' aim is to profit when the most popular stocks finally nosedive. Such funds will be among the best equity funds to own during the next stock market decline.</p>
<p>Short-selling calls for selling borrowed shares of stock, and then buying them back later. If the share price declines, you'll buy the stock back at a lower price than you sold it for -- thus pocketing a profit. If the stock's price rises, you will have to buy it back later at a higher price. That can mean sizable losses if you sell short a stock that keeps on rising ... and rising.</p>
<p>That's exactly what has happened to many funds that sold shares short during the past year or two. Among them: Crabbe Huson Special (800-541-9732; $2,000 minimum investment; no-load); and Lindner Bulwark (314-727-5305; $3,000 minimum investment; no-load).</p>
<p>The two funds are managed by teams of excellent stock pickers -- and both of them have lagged their typical competitors at some point during the past year or two. But they may be among the top funds during the coming months, especially if the market suddenly slumps.</p>
<p>Jim Crabbe at Crabbe Huson Special favours battered shares of out-of-favour companies. His fund began shorting high-flying technology stocks in early 1995 and gained a mere 8.3 percent annually during the next two years, compared to a 30 percent annual return for the S&amp;P 500.</p>
<p>But Crabbe insists that he will stick to his strategy, and expects that the fund will reward patient shareholders during the next market decline. Recently, short sales accounted for around 20 percent of the portfolio's investments.</p>
<p>Lindner Bulwark Fund tries to protect investors from big losses in a bear market. The fund recently held 22 percent of its assets in short sales and another 17.9 percent in cash. Manager Eric Ryback also looks for shares that trade below their firms' book values as a way to reduce downside volatility. The results so far have been erratic: The fund lagged the S&amp;P 500 in 1995 by around 48 percentage points, then registered a 28.8 percent gain last year.</p>
<p>Should you invest in these funds? Fact is, it's never a good idea to try to predict where stock prices will head next month -- or even next year. But it does make sense to be prepared for a variety of circumstances.</p>
<p>Right now, few fund investors are prepared for a market slump. Are you? If not, a modest stake -- say 10 percent to 15 percent of your portfolio -- in one or two funds that are loaded for bear might make sense.</p>
<p>(EDITORS: Clint Willis is a freelance writer who covers mutual funds for Reuters. Any opinions in the column are solely those of Mr. Willis.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
