<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="391343" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Two imprisoned for South Carolina church burnings.</title>
<headline>Two imprisoned for South Carolina church burnings.</headline>
<dateline>CHARLESTON, S.C. 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two former Ku Klux Klan members were given 18 and 19-year prison sentences by a federal court on Thursday for the 1995 burning of two black South Carolina churches.</p>
<p>Gary Cox, 23, was sentenced to 19 years and six months without parole. Timothy Welch, 24, was sentenced to 18 years without parole.</p>
<p>The men, both from Manning, South Carolina, were also ordered to serve five years' probation after completing their jail terms and pay $200 court fees.</p>
<p>The two pleaded guilty in August to burning Macedonia Baptist Church in Bloomville, South Carolina and Mount Zion AME Church in Greelyville, South Carolina.</p>
<p>They pleaded guilty to two counts of using fire in commission of a felony, and two counts of conspiracy to violate civil rights.</p>
<p>Dressed in street clothes but shackled at the ankles, the two men apologised for their acts before they were sentenced.</p>
<p>&quot;I wanted to say I'm sorry for what I've done ... I didn't have anything against those people. I didn't hate them then, and I don't hate them now,&quot; Cox said before U.S. District Judge David Norton.</p>
<p>Welch said: &quot;I'm deeply sorry for all the pain I've caused the (pastors) and their parishoners, to the state of South Carolina, to humanity itself. What we did was terrible.&quot;</p>
<p>Rev. Terrance Mackey, pastor of Mount Zion, who was in court, said: &quot;We have no ill feelings towards them or their families. We will move on with our lives.&quot;</p>
<p>Cox and Welch were arrested shortly after torching the churches in June 1995, when a wave of burnings swept across the South at churches attended mainly by blacks.</p>
<p>The incidents continued through the summer of 1996, reviving memories of Ku Klux Klan firebombings of churches in the 1960s during the Civil Rights Movement.</p>
<p>Cox and Welch told federal investigators about KKK members who prodded them to burn the churches.</p>
<p>Their cooperation led to the arrests of Arthur Haley, 51, and Hubert Rowell, 52, for providing flammable liquids used to accelerate the fires. Haley and Rowell pleaded guilty last year to conspiracy charges in connection with burning Macedonia Baptist Church in June 1995. They have not been sentenced.</p>
<p>Lawyers for Cox and Welch told the court they were young, impressionable men led astray by leaders of the Christian Knights arm of the Ku Klux Klan in rural South Carolina.</p>
<p>Cox's attorney, Michael O'Connell, said: &quot;There is no fool like a young fool, and I think that's what Gary was when this all started. He is genuinely sorry.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHARLESTON, S.C."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
