<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39146" id="root" date="1996-09-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Burundi appeals for end to sanctions.</title>
<headline>Burundi appeals for end to sanctions.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bigg</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-09-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burundi's prime minister appealed on Saturday to East African ministers meeting in Tanzania to lift sanctions imposed after a July coup on the central African country riven by ethnic violence.</p>
<p>A committee of East African interior ministers meeting in northern Tanzania on Saturday was expected to decide whether humanitarian aid to Burundi should be excluded from sanctions.</p>
<p>&quot;My message to interior ministers is to understand Burundi and to understand the negative impact that sanctions are having on the country. This embargo isn't going to bring peace,&quot; Prime Minister Pascal Firmin Ndimira told a news conference.</p>
<p>Ethnic Tutsi Pierre Buyoya seized power in an army coup on July 25 and named Hutu Ndimira to head his government in an effort to display his moderate credentials.</p>
<p>Ndimira warned sanctions could &quot;boomerang on neighbouring countries,&quot; increasing their responsibility if Burundi declined into an all out ethnic war like the one in neighbouring Rwanda in 1994, which killed up to one million people.</p>
<p>African states including Tanzania, Kenya, Uganda and Rwanda on July 31 closed their borders with Burundi and imposed stiff economic and transport sanctions on the landlocked country.</p>
<p>They demanded a return to constitutional government and the start of all-party talks to include the Tutsi-dominated army and Hutu rebel groups currently waging a civil war.</p>
<p>Buyoya left Bujumbura on Saturday for the Lake Victoria town of Musoma in Tanzania for a meeting with Burundi negotiator Julius Nyerere.</p>
<p>Diplomats said the main point of discussion would be a regional summit and whether Buyoya would be allowed to attend.</p>
<p>Ndimira outlined his plan of action this week in a 20-page speech, saying he wanted to bring peace, revive the economy and restore the state's democratic institutions.</p>
<p>A senior aid official said the plan was &quot;academic and irrelevant&quot; in the light of sanctions and continued fighting in Burundi, which has killed 150,000 people since October 1993.</p>
<p>European nationals living in Burundi on Saturday appealed to European Union president Jacques Santer in a letter to help end sanctions, Burundi state radio reported.</p>
<p>&quot;The European nationals in Burundi underlined that there is no other country where such harsh sanctions have been imposed with so little cause,&quot; the radio said.</p>
<p>In Brussels on Friday, Burundi's banned Frodebu party said it was considering starting armed resistance against the military government if peaceful political pressure fails to restore democracy to the tiny central-African country.</p>
<p>&quot;If the international community does not take action, if the massacres continue and if the military junta remains in power, Frodebu will have to review its principle of non-violence,&quot; Frodebu Chairman Jean Minani told a news conference.</p>
<p>Minani also called for a strict application of the embargo imposed on Burundi by neighbouring states.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UGANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
