<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="391445" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Snapple losses behind Quaker Oats - analysts.</title>
<headline>Snapple losses behind Quaker Oats - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Commins</byline>
<dateline>NAPLES, Fla. 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The worst may be over for Quaker Oats Co's Snapple beverage business, which has posted operating losses for the two years since it was acquired for $1.8 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;I suppose Snapple has declined all that it is going to decline,&quot; Robert Cummins, managing director of Schroder Wertheim, said on Thursday.</p>
<p>To be sure, Quaker still faces challenges to recover the hefty investment it made in the Snapple iced tea and fruit-flavor beverage business.  </p>
<p>&quot;To get the return on this investment, they still have a long way to go,&quot; Goldman Sachs analyst Nomi Ghez said.</p>
<p>Quaker Chairman William Smithburg, speaking to reporters in Naples, Florida, after a presentation at an analyst conference, again acknowledged that Snapple had been a disappointment. Snapple's sale volume declined in 1996 from the previous year, and it posted an operating loss before amortization.</p>
<p>For 1997, Smithburg reiterated that he expected a turnaround for Snapple, promising to an end to operating losses.  </p>
<p>&quot;We believe the business can be stabilized and run for positive cash,&quot; Smithburg said.</p>
<p>Being cash positive means Snapple would post a profit after amortization costs.</p>
<p>Smithburg declined to give a sales projection for Snapple in 1997. Analysts have said previously that flat sales and reduced costs would help the beverage line break even this year.  </p>
<p>&quot;At least they'll ebb the bleeding,&quot; said SBC Warburg analyst Chris Jakubik, who expects Snapple to break even this year.</p>
<p>Disappointing results at Snapple have prompted speculation that Quaker might look to get rid of the business. Quaker has been rumored to be shopping Snapple around to prospective buyers.</p>
<p>Smithburg declined to comment on any rumors or potential merger and acquisition activity.</p>
<p>But he reiterated that Quaker would continue to &quot;evaluate all options for the business.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;The first order of business is to run it better,&quot; Smithburg said.</p>
<p>He said the company had improved Snapple's distribution system and planned more aggressive promotion of the Diet Snapple line, which enjoyed a 20 percent rise in sales in 1996 and gains of 30 percent during the last four months.</p>
<p>((Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAPLES, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
