<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="391641" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: Jurisdiction over oral contracts according to trade practice.</title>
<headline>Jurisdiction over oral contracts according to trade practice.</headline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Court of Justice ruled on Thursday that a court's jurisdiction over oral contracts may be established by references made on pre-printed invoices paid in the normal course of business.</p>
<p>Invoking the Brussels Convention on Jurisdiction in Civil and Commercial Matters, the court said failure to object to references on regularly paid invoices, or to dispute a reference made by one party to a place of contract performance and jurisdiction described in a commercial letter, may result in an agreement as to jurisdiction.</p>
<p>A so called &quot;abstract&quot; agreement on the place of performance to confer jurisdiction is acceptable, the court said, if the contract involves international trade and the practice which established the agreement is consistent with the normal course of business for that industry. In addition, the parties must be aware of that practice..</p>
<p>&quot;It is for the national court to determine whether the contract in question comes under the head of international trade or commmerce and to find whether there was a practice in which the parties are operating, with knowledge,&quot; the court said.</p>
<p>The court advised that national courts should look further than the question of whether a practice exists in international trade and into the particular branch of commerce being considered.</p>
<p>As to presumptive knowledge of certain practices, the national courts are to consider whether the two parties have had previous dealings with each other, or with other parties operating in the same commercial sector.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>EXCERPTS FROM THE JUDGMENT</p>
<p>(Court translation into English. Original language of the case: German)</p>
<p>&quot;Brussels Convention - Agreement on the place of performance of the obligation in question - Agreement conferring jurisdictioin&quot;</p>
<p>Case C-106/95</p>
<p>Reference from the Bundesgerichtshof for a preliminary ruling between</p>
<p>Mainschiffahrts-Genossenschaft eG (MSG)</p>
<p>and</p>
<p>Les Gravieres Rhenanes SARL</p>
<p>on the interpretation of article 5(1) and the third hypothesis mentioned in the second sentence of the first paragraph of article 17 of the Convention of 27 September 1968 on jurisdiction and the enforcement of judgments in civil and commercial matters (OJ 1978 L 304, pl. 36), as amended by the Convention of 9 October 1978 on the accession of the Kingdom of Denmark, Ireland and the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland (OJ 1978 L 304, p. 1; amended version of the Convention at p. 77)</p>
<p>THE COURT hereby rules</p>
<p>1. The third hypothesis in the second sentence of the first paragraph of article 17 of the Convention of 27 September 1968 on jurisdiciton and the enforcement of judgments in civil and commercial matters (OJ 1978 L 304, pl. 36), as amended by the Convention of 9 October 1978 on the accession of the Kingdom of Denmark, Ireland and the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland must be interpreted as meaning that, under a contract concluded orally in international trade or commerce, an agreement conferring jurisdiction will be deemed to have been validly concluded under that provision by virtue of the fact that one party to the contract did not react to a commercial letter of confirmation sent to it by the other party to the contract or repeatedly paid invoices without objection where those documents contained a pre-printed reference to the courts having jurisdiction, provided that such conduct is consistent with a practice in force in the field of international trade or commerce in which the parites in question operate and the latter are aware or ought to have been aware of the practice in question. It is for the national court to determine whether such a practice exists and whether the parties to the contract were aware of it. A practice exists in a branch of international trade or commerce in particular where a particular course of conduct is generally followed by contracting parties operating in that branch when they conclude contracts of a particular type. The fact that the contracting parties were aware of that practice is made out in particular where they had previously had trade or commercial relations between themselves or with other parties operating in the branch of trade or commerce in question or where, in that branch, a particular course of conduct is generally and regularly followed when concluding a certain type of contract, with the result that it may be regarded as being a consolidated practice.</p>
<p>2. The Convention of 27 September 1968 must be interpreted as meaning that an oral agreement on the place of performance which is designed not to determine the place where the person liable is actually to perform the obligations incumbent upon him, but solely to establish that the courts for a particular place have jurisdiction, is not governed by article 5(1) of the Convention, but by article 17, and is valid only if the requirements set out therein are complied with.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
