<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="391696" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India PM inducts Kashmir leader into cabinet.</title>
<headline>India PM inducts Kashmir leader into cabinet.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda on Thursday inducted two ministers, including one from troubled Kashmir, into his cabinet in an expansion of his centre-left coalition.</p>
<p>Saifuddin Soz, a lawmaker of the National Conference party of the state of Jammu and Kashmir, was given a cabinet rank.</p>
<p>M.P. Veerendra Kumar, a lawmaker from the southern Indian state of Kerala, was inducted as a minister of state (junior minister).</p>
<p>A government spokesman said their portfolios would be announced later.</p>
<p>The entry of Soz, whose regional party won local elections in Kashmir that were held after a gap of nine years in 1996, took the number of parties in the United Front cabinet to 13.</p>
<p>India held local elections in the northern state, mainly Hindu India's only Moslem-majority province, in a move seen as a containment of a separatist rebellion that began in 1990.</p>
<p>Two parties are members of the ruling political alliance, but are not represented in the government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
