<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="391657" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: IAWS says acquisition to assist in growth.</title>
<headline>IAWS says acquisition to assist in growth.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish agri-business company IAWS Group Plc said on Thursday that its recent acquisition of a 45 percent shareholding in French fertiliser company Cedest will provide further growth opportunities for the firm.</p>
<p>&quot;This investment will be earnings enhancing and we believe the geographic expansion of our operations into continental Europe will bring further opportunity for us to grow,&quot; chief executive Philip Lynch said after the annual meeting.  </p>
<p>Lynch said France was the largest consumer of fertilisers in Europe, accounting for over 12 million tonnes per annum or over 25 percent of total EU fertilisers.</p>
<p>It is also the largest cereal market in Europe producing over 30 percent of total EU cereal output, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Cedest is a major French producer and we believe the association with IAWS will benefit the company,&quot; Lynch said.</p>
<p>&quot;Cedest management will be involved in our fertiliser executive team which plans our strategic investment programmes,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Lynch said IAWS had a balanced earning stream operating in Ireland and the UK in the agri-food sector and that as highly specialist niche operators, the group had grown only in sectors where it could demonstrate some competitive advantage.</p>
<p>--Dublin Newsroom 353-1-661-3377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25130">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
