<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="391794" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Zambian mine sees big loss unless trading improves.</title>
<headline>Zambian mine sees big loss unless trading improves.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zambia Consolidated Copper Mines, the jewel in the Zambian state's asset crown, warned on Thursday it would incur &quot;a substantial loss&quot; this financial year unless trading conditions improved dramatically in February and March.</p>
<p>In a statement released in London, chairman Luke Mwananshiku blamed falls in the prices of copper and cobalt, production difficulties at the group's smelters and a deferment by the company of a planned &quot;retrenchment programme&quot; because ZCCM could not pay for associated redundancy payments.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe the recent increases in ZCCM's share price do not reflect the company's real situation,&quot; Mwananshiku stated.</p>
<p>ZCCM, which saw a production peak of 700,000 tonnes in the 1970s fall to around 310,000 tonnes in 1995/96, started last month on the road to a privatisation which is seen as crucial to the survival of Zambia's mining industry.</p>
<p>But Mwananshiku said the group, which made a loss of around $7.0 million in 1995/96, faced a very difficult six months in the run-up to its sell-off. &quot;I do not expect shareholders to receive any proceeds from the privatisation,&quot; he reiterated.</p>
<p>&quot;The company is currently operating at a loss and whilst the forthcoming privatisation is good news for ZCCM, shareholders should not forget that the company is burdened  with over $800 million of debt and other liabilities, much of it short term.&quot;</p>
<p>The sell-off of ZCCM, the biggest state-owned company, began last month with the $28 million sale of an 80 percent stake in the Kansanshi copper mine.</p>
<p>Mwananshiku said he had warned at the time of that sale that investors were unlikely to receive any money from privatisation.</p>
<p>The government holds a 60 percent stake in the company, Anglo American Corp of South Africa a 27 percent stake with private investors holding the balance.</p>
<p>ZCCM, whose stock is quoted on the Paris stock exchange, saw its shares close 5.26 percent lower at 19.80 francs on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
