<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="391863" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: HK shipping leader cautiously welcomes handover.</title>
<headline>HK shipping leader cautiously welcomes handover.</headline>
<byline>Paul Berrill</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong shipping leader Helmut Sohmen said last night that China harboured &quot;substantial goodwill&quot; toward the colony, but that after its handover Beijing would not allow opposition that was not couched in terms of the national interest.</p>
<p>Speaking in London prior to the announcement of Deng Xiaoping's death, the chairman and president of World-Wide Shipping Group said: &quot;Hong Kong should proceed on the premise that it is needed, but without becoming arrogant.&quot;</p>
<p>Sohmen, who is a director of a number of companies including the Hong Kong and Shanghai Banking Corporation and is a former member of the Hong Kong legislature, said it might not be possible to retain all the characteristics of the Joint Declaration on the colony's future signed between China and Britain in 1984.</p>
<p>However, he said it was up to the Hong Kong business and political community to have &quot;the courage and strength to explain why their arguments are the best way to achieve desired results and are in all China's national interests, not just that of Hong Kong.&quot;</p>
<p>Sohmen was critical of China's designated chief executive for the colony following the handover on July 1, 1997 - saying that Tung Chee-hwa appeared to reflect attempts to turn the clock back.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;Tung would not have been selected if he was not trusted by China's central government as reliable and that should allow him more elbow room in practising domestic autonomy for Hong Kong.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There is substantial goodwill in Beijing. Hong Kong's views will be listended to if they are constructive.&quot;</p>
<p>However, he warned: &quot;Beijing will not allow a void to exist in Hong Kong and will take action to prevent it, even if at the cost of economic suceess.&quot;</p>
<p>Sohmen also criticised current Hong Kong governor Chris Patten, saying: &quot;The best that can be said is he achieved the status quo by pushing for more than he could expect to get.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Governor Patten's biggest mistake was to raise local expectations which he should have known could not be delivered,&quot; Sohmen added.</p>
<p>Despite the tit-for-tat disputes between Britain and Hong Kong over infrastructure projects such as Hong Kong's new airport, Sohmen said progress on many issues was now speeding up as the deadline approached.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
