<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="391833" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - UK's Railtrack sets 15 bln stg revamp.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - UK's Railtrack sets 15 bln stg revamp.</headline>
<byline>Arindam Nag</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>British railway infrastructure company Railtrack Group Plc unveiled a more than 15 billion pound ($24.2 billion) spending plan on Thursday aimed at creating one of the world's most efficient rail networks.</p>
<p>Railtrack, floated on the London Stock Exchange last year, said it would invest 8.3 billion pounds on renewal investments over 10 years.</p>
<p>It said it would spend 5.7 billion pounds on day-to-day maintenance and another 1.9 billion stg on network enhancement over the same period.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a duty to spend these large sums wisely,&quot; said Robert Horton, Railtrack's chairman.</p>
<p>The company is under pressure to expedite its capital expenditure with watchdog, the Office of Rail Regulator, accusing it of not spending enough on maintenance.</p>
<p>Horton said the spending plans marked &quot;a new dynamic phase in the regeneration of the nation's railway system.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Ten years from now Britain will have a railway that is second to none -- both in the quality of its infrastructure and in the dependability of its train service,&quot; Horton said.</p>
<p>This was the first time Railtrack had announced such detailed plans since its 1.93 billion pound flotation last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Now that the flotation is complete, Railtrack is free to commit all its energies to providing tangible benefits for its customers....freight operators,&quot; the chairman said.</p>
<p>Railtrack is also aiming to complete a 760 million pound upgrade of its stations and depots by 2001, including clearing the backlog of maintenance and renewals at 2,360 stations and 87 depots.</p>
<p>Railtrack has kept a provision of 1.4 billion pounds for modernising the West Coast Main Line.</p>
<p>The Office of the Rail Regulator said it was not yet ready to comment on the blueprint, but an official said it would have a strategy &quot;to monitor&quot; the actual implementation of Railtrack's plans.</p>
<p>The Office said Railtrack's backlog on capital expenditure had piled up to 330 million pounds from 270 million. It said Railtrack had only spent 20 million pounds out of a 450 million provision for 1996/97.</p>
<p>The Office was also recently joined by the UK opposition Labour Party which demanded Railtrack to be more accountable on investment commitments.</p>
<p>'Save our Railways' a pressure group, said the blueprint still implied that Britain spent &quot;far less&quot; on rail network than the French and Germans.</p>
<p>Horton played down the criticism in a BBC Radio interview broadcast immediately after the announcement saying &quot;we spent every penny we were allowed to.&quot;</p>
<p>He did agree that many stations dotting Britain's landscape were &quot;falling apart.&quot; ($ = 0.620 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
