<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="391827" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS- FEB 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS- FEB 20.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek financial press:</p>
<p>KATHIMERINI</p>
<p>--The Federation of Greek Industries (SEB) warned yesterday that any attempt by the government to introduce productivity bonuses for civil servants would overturn the government's incomes policy, leading to claims by all civil servants for the blanket receipt of the bonus.</p>
<p>--The public service's engineers will stage a 24-hour strike tomorrow to protest the government's new wage bill. At a press conference yesterday, they threatened to block work on all infrastructural projects if their demands were not met. </p>
<p>--Some self-criticism can never go astray, National Economy and Finance Minister Yannos Papandoniou appeared to say yesterday, calling the 80s an &quot;exceptionally unsuccessful&quot; period for economic policy by then-ruling party PASOK. Papandoniou was then deputy finance minister.</p>
<p>--There is movement on major institutional changes to the capital market. The final draft on the restructuring of the guarantee fund foresees it taking on more duties and guaranteeing the clearance of transactions through the clearing house.</p>
<p>IMERISIA</p>
<p>--Open war on the market as SEB launches volleys against the retail world over trading hours and payment of commissions for the favourable treatment of products on shelves. </p>
<p>--Papandoniou admits to &quot;losing a decade&quot; at his speech yesterday before European Commissioner Monika Wulf-Mathies presented the EU's report on Economic and Social Cohesion.</p>
<p>--OECD officials visiting Athens have urged the government to proceed to privatisations immediately, with emphasis on structural changes which will allow the speedier stabilisation and development of the economy.</p>
<p>KERDOS</p>
<p>--The conflict between SEB and the retail trade, ahead of the drafting of new procurements contracts this year, is expected to continue as the retailers consolidate their position.</p>
<p>--The Bank of Greece's move yesterday to soak 200 billion drachmas through a 14-day depo tender has sent positive messages for the further fall of interest rates.</p>
<p>EXPRESS</p>
<p>--OECD officials on a round of consultations in Athens ahead of their new report said yesterday they acknowledged the improvement in economic indicators in 1996 but that efforts to contain spending had to continue as did efforts to deregulate money and labour.</p>
<p>--The Athens Stock Exchange's general price index is preparing the ground for its final assault on the 1,300 mark, sources say, after the index rose again yesterday, closing at 1,284.81 points.</p>
<p>--Hoteliers are confident of a recovery in tourist numbers this season but warned against complacency. Hoteliers said they were also coming under great pressure from foreign tour operators to reduce prices further. </p>
<p>--Olympic Airways's administration was optimistic yesterday that it would get the go-ahead from the Commission to continue with its expansion programme early next month.</p>
<p>NAFTEMBORIKI</p>
<p>--The three factors which will determine the health of the Greek economy are absorption of Community funds, containing the cost of labour and promoting institutional changes, Papandoniou said. --Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4 (c) Reuters Limited 1997</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
