<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39194" id="root" date="1996-09-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia's deputy PM urges more liberal media.</title>
<headline>Malaysia's deputy PM urges more liberal media.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-09-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim on Saturday urged the Malaysian media to play a more liberal role and feel freer to criticise and air the views of the public.</p>
<p>&quot;We should have more confidence in our society's maturity in making objecting assessments,&quot; the national news agency Bernama quoted him as saying at the opening of a building for the Chinese language newspaper Nanyang Siang Pau.</p>
<p>Anwar said that while the electronic media and newspapers were bound by guidelines giving priority to political stability and racial unity, that should not create a &quot;fear culture&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;If we are too restrictive, the leadership and the government will not have the capacity to overcome problems,&quot; Anwar was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>The Printing Presses and Publications Act, as amended in 1987, contains important limitations on press freedom.</p>
<p>Under the act, domestic and foreign publications must apply annually to the government for a permit. Publication of &quot;malicious news&quot; is a punishable offense and the government has expanded powers to ban or restrict publications.</p>
<p>Press freedom is also limited in practice by the fact that major corporations allied to leading political figures own all the major newspapers and radio and television stations, Western diplomats say.</p>
<p>&quot;These mass media provide generally laudatory, noncritical coverage of government officials and government policies, and give only limited and selective coverage to political views of the opposition or political rivals,&quot; a recent U.S. State Department report said.</p>
<p>Anwar, alluding to the issue of media ownership, said it was important for the government and the corporate sector that controls the press to understand that the media had its own role to play and a moral responsibility to society.</p>
<p>&quot;Our efforts in the area of the media and information should be separated from direct business interests and the government's political interests,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
