<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39207" id="root" date="1996-09-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Wall Street rise should benefit Asian markets.</title>
<headline>Wall Street rise should benefit Asian markets.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most Asian stock markets are expected to gain ground in the next trading week after Wall Street surged following release of key U.S. jobs data on Friday.</p>
<p>Brokers said the Dow industrials' 53-point rise had erased worries that Tokyo shares would suffer if Wall Street reacted negatively to the August jobs figures.</p>
<p>The focus would be on whether the key Nikkei index could stay above the psychological 20,000 level, with investors keeping a low profile on talk of early eections.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's Hang Seng was likely to recoup losses from the past week on the back of Wall Street, brokers said.</p>
<p>However, the Dow rise was unlikely to greatly affect Jakarta shares since foreign participation in the bourse had been low since political tensions surfaced in Indonesia in recent months.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TOKYO - Tokyo stocks are expected to be vulnerable at the start of the coming week, but could be mired in a narrow range later, brokers said.</p>
<p>With fears allayed that the U.S. jobs data would hit Wall Street and then depress Tokyo shares, brokers said the focus would be on whether the benchmark 225-share Nikkei average would stay above 20,000 points.</p>
<p>The key 225-share Nikkei average closed on Friday down 227.29 points or 1.12 percent at 20,152.53.</p>
<p>Analysts expect consolidation around the key level in thin trading, with no major factors to trade on, but talk of early elections was likely to prompt investors to keep a low profile.</p>
<p>&quot;There is now fear that instability in politics could become a hindrance to economic recovery,&quot; said Hiroshi Yamamura of Nissay Research Institute.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Hong Kong stocks are expected to regain some lost ground in the week ahead after U.S. August employment data failed to rattle U.S. markets as some investors had feared, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the reaction on Wall Street will help the recovery of local shares next week,&quot; said Ben Kwong, director of research at Dharmala Securities.</p>
<p>But he said many investors were still expecting a U.S. rate hike this month and trading would be cautious. He expected stocks to trade in a range of 10,850 to 11,250 points.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng fell 133.43 points, or 1.2 percent, last week to close at 11,025.59 on Friday.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BANGKOK - The Stock Exchange of Thailand (SET) index is expected to move sideways after sharp falls in the past week.</p>
<p>The market was savaged by selling on rumours some brokerages may be hit by client defaults on margin loans, and sentiment was hurt by news on Tuesday that Moody's Investor's Service had downgraded Thailand's short-term debt ratings, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The index is not expected to move much next week because investors, especially foreigners, are waiting to sell on persistent concerns about the Thai economy,&quot; said Busaba Kunasirin of Chao Phya Finance and Securities.</p>
<p>The SET index closed at 1,007.51 on Friday, compared to 1,102.32 last Friday.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BOMBAY - Indian shares would take a beating if the government fails to give anticipated tax breaks to industry, brokers said.</p>
<p>Finance Minister P. Chidambaram announced some incentives on Friday after the markets closed, but traders were disappointed.</p>
<p>He will make a detailed statement in the coming week and the market was expecting the dilution of a controversial minimum tax on high-growth firms.</p>
<p>In the week to Friday, the Bombay Stock Exchange 30-share index dropped 6.54 points or 0.19 percent to 3,508.07.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>COLOMBO - Sri Lankan stocks are expected to continue sidestepping in tight ranges in the absence of sellers.</p>
<p>&quot;It all depends on whether we can find sellers,&quot; said Sanjeeva Gunewardena of Commercial Stock Brokers. &quot;There is local and foreign buying interest in about 15 stocks which can break the index free, but the problem is to find these shares.&quot;</p>
<p>Sellers are firmly on the sidelines after the all share index showed firm support at around the current level, brokers said. The index closed at 558.70 on Friday, little changed from 559.23 a week earlier.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>DHAKA - Dhaka stocks, propelled by euphoric buying by mostly retailers, gained sharply over the week, and analysts said the politics in the aftermath of Thursday's by-election to 15 constituencies would determine the market trend when it reopened after the Moslem Friday weekend.</p>
<p>The polls were ordered after candidates who won more than one seat in June 12 parliamentary elections vacated the extra seats. &quot;Market trend will largely depend on how the opposition is going to react to poll results,&quot; said broker M A Hossain.</p>
<p>The DSE benchmark index gained 132.46 points, one of the highest in weekly gains, to 1328.81.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>JAKARTA - Jakarta share prices are likely to be mixed in the coming week as local-led buying is expected to mitigate the effects of a possible rise in U.S. interest rates, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreigners are likely to focus on the macroeconomic situation and fears that the U.S. Federal Reserve would raise interest rates. But local operators are likely to dominate trade as they have their own stories,&quot; said Johan Purnama, sales director of PT Mashil Jaya Securities.</p>
<p>One analyst from HSBC Securities Indonesia said the U.S. jobs data would not affect Jakarta greatly since foreign participation in the bourse had been low since political tensions surfaced in June.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Jakarta composite index closed at 543.75 points, against last week's close of 547.61 points.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>KUALA LUMPUR - Kuala Lumpur stocks are expected to be cheered by the U.S. jobs data, although keen market interest would remain in secondary stocks, analysts said.</p>
<p>The U.S. data and Wall Street's 53-point jump on Friday would help attract early buying of blue chips.</p>
<p>&quot;We should see some strength in the major stocks, but there's no local news to provide a sustained climb,&quot; said an analyst at a foreign house.</p>
<p>Sizzling second boarders that hit an all-time high on Friday would provide the most volumes.</p>
<p>The key Lumpur Stock Exchange Composite Index ended on Friday at 1,105.33 against 1,118.57 the previous week.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MANILA - Manila stocks are expected to move sideways to higher as fears of a sharp rise in U.S. interest rates eased following the key job numbers, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The sharp rebound of the Dow Jones on Friday in reaction to news that August jobs data were within the market's expectations will boost sentiment in emerging markets in Asia-Pacific,&quot; said Mike Ordinanza at Kerry Securities.</p>
<p>The composite index fell by 50.55 points, or by 1.56 percent, week-on-week to 3,170.16 on Friday from 3,220.71 on August 30.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SEOUL - Consolidation is expected to continue in the Seoul bourse with the index moving in a boxed range of 760-800 next week, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;With no fresh money flowing into the market, the market will continue to drift sideways next week,&quot; said Kim Wan-hee of Dongsuh Securities.</p>
<p>Some shares favoured by foreigners are expected to rise ahead of the expansion of the foreign stock holding limit to 20 percent from October 1.</p>
<p>On Friday, the composite stock index ended at 784.05, up 1.18 points or 0.15 percent from last Friday's 782.87.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SYDNEY - The outlook for Australian shares remained mixed to weaker in the near term.</p>
<p>The benchmark All Ordinaries finished at 2,237.0, down 31.7 points over the week.</p>
<p>The week ahead is the last of the current reporting season and typically sees more underperforming firms release results.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is fairly fragile at the moment. Volumes have been light and the index choppy - it's hard to pick a strong lead,&quot; said Derek Bond, a dealer at brokerage Burrel and Co.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TAIPEI - In Taiwan, brokers said they expected share prices to rise, reflecting gradual recovery in selected sectors, chiefly electronics, paper and textiles.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign orders are returning to electronic firms, pulp prices are rising and textile product prices are rebounding... We can expect the market to reflect recovery in selected sectors,&quot; said Michael Hung of Nikko Securities.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Taiwan index ended at 6,290.23 points, compared with 6,309.82 a week earlier. A 6,250-6,500 range was seen for the  week ahead.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>WELLINGTON - The New Zealand share market ended in a buoyant mood on Friday, seemingly impervious to the steep rise in bond yield and a general election just five weeks away.</p>
<p>The top 40 index ended the week three points up at 2231.82, but brokers said it was a good performance against the negative background. Offshore demand has solidly underpinned the market.</p>
<p>&quot;The mood of the market has changed dramatically. The equities market has become much more buoyant and optimistic,&quot; said Cavill White Managing Director Don Turkington.</p>
<p>However, the Reserve Bank's six monthly economic projections on Friday may be pivotal to interest rates and, vicariously, the equities market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
