<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="392168" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - Feb 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - Feb 20.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following are the leading stories in the Indonesian press on February 20. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>Telephone: (6221) 384-6364. Fax: (6221) 344-8404.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>KOMPAS</p>
<p>Chairman of the National Commission of Human Rights Munawir Sjadzali believed the recent ethnic riots which hit Indonesia in the past three months could be stopped but said it needed much effort because of the complexity of the problem.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>JAKARTA POST</p>
<p>Indonesian Armed Forces Commander General Feisal Tanjung said the military was ready to secure the explotation of the huge gas reserves in Natuna islands in the South China Sea.</p>
<p>The Indonesian government has accepted the proposal of Canada's Bre-X Minerals Ltd and its Indonesian partners to develop the Busang gold find in East Kalimantan.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>OBSERVER</p>
<p>State-owned company Pertamina plans to sell a 13 percent stake of the Natuna gas project in South China Sea to Japanese investors, reducing its amount of shares to 11 percent.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MERDEKA</p>
<p>The ousted leader of the Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI) Megawati Sukarnoputri will attend a police questioning on Thursday in relation to the gathering she held at her residence in January to celebrate the party's 24th anniversary.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
