<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="392160" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: World pays tribute to China's Deng Xiaoping.</title>
<headline>World pays tribute to China's Deng Xiaoping.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>World leaders from President Bill Clinton to Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto paid tribute on Thursday to China's paramount leader Deng Xiaoping, praising him for opening up the world's most populous nation.</p>
<p>Clinton called Deng an &quot;extraordinary figure on the world stage over the past two decades&quot;.</p>
<p>Hashimoto said he was greatly saddened, adding &quot;the Japan-China relationship is of growing importance for peace and stability in Asia and the world&quot;.</p>
<p>Deng died late on Wednesday of respiratory failure. He was 92 and in the advanced stages of Parkinson's disease.</p>
<p>In a statement during a visit to Boston, Clinton expressed his sadness and described Deng as &quot;the driving force behind China's decision to formalise relations with the United States&quot; in the late 1970s.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright, visiting London, paid tribute to Deng and told reporters: &quot;It would obviously be a great advantage to the Chinese as well as to all of us if there were a smooth transition (in Beijing).&quot;</p>
<p>Reactions were mixed among Beijing residents.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel a great sadness,&quot; said snack vendor Xie Weicai as he prepared his pavement stove for the morning's business.</p>
<p>But not so for one taxi driver on an early morning shift. &quot;I would consider losing 100 yuan ($12) much sadder than the death of Deng Xiaoping,&quot; the driver said. &quot;It has nothing to do with me.&quot;</p>
<p>Hong Kong Governor Chris Patten said he had learned with regret of the death of Deng, whom he described as &quot;an historic figure&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;He will be regarded by future generations as an historic figure. His concept of 'one country, two systems' helped to make possible the successful negotiation of the Joint Declaration, and thus to lay the foundation for Hong Kong's stability and prosperity after 1997,&quot; Patten said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong reverts to Chinese sovereignty at midnight on June 30, ending more than 150 years of colonial rule.</p>
<p>Taiwan's Presidential Office sent its condolences to Deng's family and urged a &quot;peaceful, cooperative, prosperous new era&quot; between Taipei and Beijing.</p>
<p>But the island, which Beijing regards as a renegade province, maintained a military alert and advised its people to stay calm.</p>
<p>Chinese-American activist Harry Wu said Deng's death would spark a power struggle and possibly lead to a civil war.</p>
<p>Wu, who spent 19 years in Chinese prisons, said Deng remained the country's paramount leader despite his age because &quot;this is an empire system&quot;.</p>
<p>Canadian Prime Minister Jean Chretien expressed regret over Deng's death but said feelings were mixed because of his record on human rights.</p>
<p>Xiao Qiang, the leader of Human Rights in China, a prominent New York-based rights group, called on China to free all political prisoners to give the Beijing government &quot;a good start&quot; after Deng's death.</p>
<p>Sir Leon Brittan, European Commissioner with responsibility for relations with Asia, said he expected China to continue along the path of modernisation set out by Deng, who he said had &quot;played a remarkable and courageous role as leader&quot;.</p>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac praised the dead Chinese leader as the main architect of China's modernisation.</p>
<p>Former U.S. President George Bush, who was U.S. ambassador to China from 1974 to 1976, praised Deng as a &quot;remarkable leader&quot; who brought the benefits of capitalism to millions of his countrymen by liberalising the economy of the world's largest Communist nation.</p>
<p>In London, the office of British Prime Minister John Major expressed regret at the paramount leader's passing, adding in a statement that his &quot;initiative played the crucial part in creating today's economically dynamic and successful China&quot;.</p>
<p>Asia-Pacific nations were swift to pay tribute with South Korean President Kim Young-sam saying he was saddened by the news but hoped Seoul's friendly ties with Beijing would be strengthened.</p>
<p>Kim sent a telegram to Chinese President Jiang Zemin and Deng's family, hailing the late leader as &quot;an outstanding political leader who opened a new chapter in world history&quot;.</p>
<p>New Zealand Prime Minister Jim Bolger expressed sympathy to China and said the whole world had gained from Deng's reformist policies, while Australian leader John Howard said Deng's death would have little impact on Beijing's international relations.</p>
<p>China's communist neighbour Vietnam remained silent but analysts said Hanoi would be watching events in China closely.</p>
<p>An Indonesian Foreign Ministry official said Jakarta was &quot;deeply saddened at the death of a great statesman. Deng has made a great contribution to China...and Indonesia shares in the loss felt over his death.&quot;</p>
<p>A Funeral Committee formed by the Chinese government shortly after the announcement that Deng had died in Beijing, said no foreign dignitaries would be invited to the funeral in accordance with the country's practice.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
