<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="392549" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Israeli shelling kills Lebanese shepherd.</title>
<headline>Israeli shelling kills Lebanese shepherd.</headline>
<dateline>NABATIYEH, Lebanon 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A shepherd was killed on Thursday when Israeli and allied militia forces shelled the outskirts of a village in south Lebanon, security sources said.</p>
<p>They said Khodor Shehadeh, 23, was killed when shells slammed near the village of Froun just north of a south Lebanon zone occupied by Israeli forces. He was the second Lebanese civilian killed in Israeli shelling in three days.</p>
<p>Sources with the Israeli-backed South Lebanon Army (SLA) militia said at about the same time that guerrillas fired mortar bombs and anti-tank rockets at a post manned by the militiamen at Shoumariyeh on the edge of the zone facing Froun.</p>
<p>Israeli and SLA forces returned fire, they added.</p>
<p>Earlier on Thursday, guerrillas attacked another SLA post at Toumat Niha in another sector of the south.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, a civilian woman was killed by Israeli shelling after guerrillas shelled three SLA posts in the zone.</p>
<p>Lebanon has complained over Tuesday's killing to a five-nation committee monitoring a U.S.-brokered south Lebanon ceasefire agreement that bars both sides from targeting civilians.</p>
<p>The ceasefire monitors from the United States, France, Lebanon, Syria and Israel began a meeting on Wednesday to discuss the Lebanese complaint and are still in session at U.N. peacekers' headquarters in Naqoura in the south Lebanon zone.</p>
<p>The pro-Iranian Hizbollah (Party of God) leads a guerrilla war on Israeli and SLA forces in a bid to oust them from the 15-km (nine-miles) -deep south Lebanon zone set up to prevent cross-border attacks on northern Israel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NABATIYEH, Lebanon"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
