<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="392535" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan analysts see no Deng impact in Tokyo bourse.</title>
<headline>Japan analysts see no Deng impact in Tokyo bourse.</headline>
<byline>Michiko Iwasaki</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Many Japanese fund managers and analysts said on Thursday they do not expect the death of China's paramount leader Deng Xiaoping to create turmoil in the Tokyo bourse as it has already been factored into the market.</p>
<p>But some said the news could induce a sharp decline in Hong Kong's stock market.  </p>
<p>Deng, who died on Wednesday evening, had retired from government leadership in 1989 and was succeeded by current Communist Party chief Jiang Zemin.</p>
<p>The fund managers and analysts said the Tokyo market had digested Deng's death, as a deterioration in his health had been repeatedly reported in the last few years.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese government apparently does not want major changes as a result of Deng's death ahead of Hong Kong's return to Chinese sovereignty and a Communist Party convention scheduled for later this year,&quot; said an analyst at Nikko Research Center.  </p>
<p>The market watchers said, however, that the news may have a short-term impact on sentiment in Asian stock and foreign exchange markets.</p>
<p>Some said the news may cause a sharp fall in Hong Kong stocks, which have rallied on bullishness in U.S. stocks. &quot;It's possible to see a major decline in the Hong Kong stock market,&quot; said a fund manager at Sanyo Investment Management.</p>
<p>Among Asian markets, those in Hong Kong, Taiwan and South Korea would be most affected by Deng's death, fund managers said.</p>
<p>On the back of the robust New York Dow industrial index, U.S. investment money has been flowing into Asia, so many participants are looking for the best timing to take profits, they said.  </p>
<p>On the currency market, fund managers and analysts appear to be paying more attention to worries about the health of Russian President Boris Yeltsin.</p>
<p>Any worsening in his health would likely cloud the country's political climate and trigger a weakening in the German mark, which might also lead to a further fall in the yen.</p>
<p>Many believe the yen may stay weak for the time being, with some even seeing it weakening to near 130 yen to the dollar.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
