<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="392564" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Saudi oil minister set for U.S. visit.</title>
<headline>Saudi oil minister set for U.S. visit.</headline>
<byline>Ashraf Fouad</byline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi Arabian oil minister Ali Naimi will visit the United States next week as part of a large Saudi delegation but he is not expected to discuss oil-for-arms deals, Gulf sources said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not believe that there have been even indirect hints (in recent exchanges between the two allies) that there is something like this in the air or laying the ground for it,&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>Prince Sultan, the defence minister, is due in France on Saturday and will later go to Washington at the head of a large Saudi Arabian delegation which will include Naimi, the trade and foreign ministers, a deputy finance minister and several other senior officials and ministers of state, Gulf sources told Reuters.</p>
<p>They said the prince, a full brother to King Fahd, was going to Washington on an official visit in his capacity as Second Deputy Prime Minister and not only as defence minister of the world's leading arms importer.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia, the world's largest oil producer and exporter, has had a &quot;special&quot; relationship with the United States since the modern state was formed in 1932.</p>
<p>The two sides &quot;will conduct a major policy review of bilateral ties, including oil, economic, trade, political, general security and many other issues,&quot; said a Gulf source.</p>
<p>There was speculation earlier this month that Prince Sultan planned to discuss an oil-for-arms formula with the United States amid speculation that Naimi would accompany him to discuss details.</p>
<p>Industry experts say although Riyadh and Washington have been discussing a Saudi requirement for 100 fighter jets for several years, they doubt the two sides are close to a deal.</p>
<p>&quot;Just look at what the White House sent Congress in December (proposed foreign military sales). There is no request for fighters for Saudi Arabia in 1997,&quot; one source familiar with the agenda for the talks said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Another expert earlier said: &quot;I don't think a final announcement is imminent and Saudi Arabia has not made a formal request to buy F-16s.&quot; The Lockheed Martin Corp warplane is high on the Saudi procurement list.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia &quot;learnt its lesson and this is the end of it,&quot; one expert familiar with the programme said of Riyadh's oil-for-arms contract with London in the mid-1980s.</p>
<p>He said if Riyadh eventually finalised a deal for the fighters, state-owned Saudi oil company Aramco &quot;will sell the oil, proceeds go to a trust fund at SAMA (Saudi Arabian Monetary Agency or central bank) and then SAMA pays for the aircraft.&quot;</p>
<p>In recent months Aramco ended a decade-old arrangement and took control of al-Yamamah $20 billion oil-for-arms deal with Britain, under which Royal Dutch/Shell Group and British Petroleum Co Plc marketed some Saudi crude, passing proceeds to British Aerospace Plc to pay for the arms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
