<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="392619" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: PRESS DIGEST - Turkey - Feb 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Turkey - Feb 20.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Turkish press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>SABAH</p>
<p>- Former prime minister and leftist party leader Bulent Ecevit rebuffs proposal by left-wing Republican People's Party to merge the two parties.</p>
<p>MILLIYET</p>
<p>- Ruling Welfare Party helps clear coalition partner Tansu Ciller from charges of raising personal wealth by illegal means.</p>
<p>HURRIYET</p>
<p>- Ciller mentions difficulties of being in coalition with Islamist Welfare but says she will not split the alliance and leave the country without a government.</p>
<p>YENI YUZYIL</p>
<p>- Scandal grows over German nuclear waste dumped in Turkey.</p>
<p>RADIKAL</p>
<p>- Foreign writers will be coming to Istanbul on March 10 in order to support Turkish writers and intellectuals charged with writing and publishing a book called &quot;Freedom of Thought&quot;.</p>
<p>CUMHURIYET</p>
<p>- Treasury intervenes in the sell-offs of three banks to asking for an inquiry into those who applied for the tender.</p>
<p>DUNYA</p>
<p>- Economy awaits for the ruling coalition partners to end their disagreements which have blocked business life.</p>
<p>ZAMAN</p>
<p>- Dolmabahce Palace in Istanbul gearing up to claim back furniture that was given away to other state-owned estates.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
