<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="392853" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German coalition clashes with SPD on reform drive.</title>
<headline>German coalition clashes with SPD on reform drive.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Busvine</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's coalition government on Thursday appealed for a cross-party drive to battle a national jobs crisis and said that, despite strained state finances, it would plough more cash into job-creating investments.</p>
<p>But, days before coalition chiefs meet opposition Social Democrats (SPD) for a tax reform summit, SPD leaders slammed policies which they said had put 4.7 million people out of work -- the highest since the 1930s.</p>
<p>Mocking government tax and welfare reform proposals, SPD parliamentary chief Rudolf Scharping said they had &quot;degenerated into meaningless promises and false starts -- nothing more.</p>
<p>&quot;The greatest risk to Germany as an industrial centre is the policies of this government,&quot; Scharping told a parliamentary debate on the government's annual economic report.</p>
<p>Turning his fire on the 14-year record of Chancellor Helmut Kohl, who sat mute during the debate, Scharping said: &quot;No government has lied to the people as often as this one. Like no government before, you have failed to plan for the future.&quot;</p>
<p>Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt stood by the official forecast of 2.5 percent growth in 1997, urging support from all sides to achieve a turnaround on the jobs market this year.</p>
<p>But in order to create jobs, coalition plans for a major 30 billion mark ($17.8 billion) package of tax cuts must be implemented as soon as possible to stimulate investment, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our goal must remain to achieve a trend change on the jobs market this year. It must last,&quot; Rexrodt said, reaffirming the government goal of halving unemployment by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel said it would be possible to hold to government plans for a budget deficit of 2.9 percent of gross domestic product -- meeting the Maastricht deficit target of three percent to qualify for European monetary union in 1999.</p>
<p>But, he warned, savings measures currently blocked by the SPD -- which controls the upper house of parliament -- would have to be passed in order to hit the deficit goal.</p>
<p>Despite tight finances, Waigel announced an investment drive to help the backbone of the German economy, the so-called &quot;Mittelstand&quot; of smaller companies. &quot;To fight unemployment, the measures must take effect in 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The government has dropped for now the idea of a spending freeze, looking instead to tighten up on welfare spending and keep channelling funds into job-creating investment.</p>
<p>&quot;Investment expenditure should, where possible, not be affected, because of its significance for the growth process and the jobs market,&quot; Waigel said.</p>
<p>Despite the often heated tone of the debate, leaders on both sides also tried to sound each other out on areas where compromise could be reached on taxes at next week's tax talks.</p>
<p>Gerhard Schroeder, the influential SPD premier of Lower Saxony, said it would be possible to achieve a quick compromise on cutting the entry rate of income tax, although the two sides remain far apart over the peak rate.</p>
<p>Plans thrashed out by the coalition last month would cut the entry rate of income tax to 15 percent from 26 percent. A sliding scale would then kick in from 22.5 to 39 percent.</p>
<p>The SPD's own tax reform plan sees a starting rate of 19.5 percent -- close to the government position. Schroeder also said a deal to cut corporate taxes was possible.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be very important to reach a quick agreement,&quot; Schroeder said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Wolfgang Schaeuble, parliamentary leader of Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU), offered to negotiate a &quot;transitional solution&quot; on fully taxing night, weekend and holiday work -- something that the SPD has flatly opposed.</p>
<p>But fundamental differences remain. Schroeder said the government's tax reforms had a financing gap of 44 billion marks.</p>
<p>Schaeuble said the difference could be made up by raising indirect taxes and more revenues stemming from economic growth.</p>
<p>&quot;The SPD just wants to shift around the tax burden. But who does that will not cut the economic share taken by the state. And that share must fall,&quot; Schaeuble said. &quot;We say 30 billion marks in taxes must go by 1999 and we will achieve that.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Bonn newsroom, 49-228-26097 150 ($ = 1.687 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
