<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="392855" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Boss profits up, increases dividend payout.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Boss profits up, increases dividend payout.</headline>
<dateline>STUTTGART, Germany 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German men's fashion retailer Hugo Boss AG said on Thursday it would pay out almost all of its 1996 profits to shareholders through a special dividend and an increase in the regular dividends.</p>
<p>Boss tied the higher dividend payout to an almost 30 percent increase in 1996 group net profit to 75.2 million marks and a 10.5 percent increase in sales to 995.3 million marks.</p>
<p>The company said it raised the payout per ordinary share to 45 marks from 41 marks in 1995 and to 46.50 marks from 42.50 marks for each preference share.</p>
<p>In addition Boss said it would make a special payment of 57 marks per share.</p>
<p>The dividend payouts will total 65.8 million marks compared with 26.7 million marks in 1995, according to Boss, which is majority-held by the Marzotto Group of Italy.</p>
<p>Boss said the special dividend payout would provide it with tax relief, noting its group net profit excluding plans for the dividend payout would have totalled 64.8 million marks.</p>
<p>Boss has seen strong growth from its decision to split its product lines into three groups from one -- Boss for traditional buyers, Hugo for younger, more contemporary buyers and Baldessarini for top-line customers.</p>
<p>But the company has been hampered by leadership issues after Boss chief executive Peter Littmann, 49, left the firm at the start of 1997 after an apparent dispute with Marzotto officials over the direction of the Stuttgart-based group.</p>
<p>Joachim Vogt, a 44-year-old production and logistics executive at Boss, has taken over as management board chairman from Littmann.</p>
<p>Despite the leadership questions, Boss said in January that it expected sales for the first half of 1997 to rise about five percent to 475 million marks, buoyed by strong sales for the Hugo brand and the Baldessarini brand.</p>
<p>Boss executives have said they were particularly looking for stronger sales in Spain, Britain, eastern Europe, Asia and South America.</p>
<p>--John Gilardi, Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STUTTGART, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
