<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39291" id="root" date="1996-09-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Poll says Clinton has 61 percent approval rating.</title>
<headline>Poll says Clinton has 61 percent approval rating.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sixty-one percent of Americans approve of the way President Clinton is handling his job, according to a Time Magazine/CNN poll released Saturday.</p>
<p>Thirty percent of Americans disapprove of the president's performance, his lowest disapproval rating since March 1993.</p>
<p>The survey gave Clinton a 14-point lead over Republican presidential nominee Bob Dole among likely voters, 52 to 38 percent, with six percent backing billionare third-party candidate Ross Perot.</p>
<p>No presidential candidate who has trailed after the Labour Day holiday has come back to win except for incumbent Democrat Harry Truman in 1948.</p>
<p>In a sign Clinton's high approval rating could help fellow Democrats, 49 percent of likely voters said they would be more likely to cast a ballot for a congressional candidate who supported the president's policies, while 40 percent said they would be less likely.</p>
<p>If congressional elections were held today, 48 percent polled said they would vote for a Democrat while 44 percent said they would back a Republican.</p>
<p>The Time/CNN poll surveyed 2,080 Americans between Sept. 4-5 and had a sampling error of 2.2 percent.</p>
<p>Another poll released Saturday found 49 percent of voters said Clinton does a better job addressing the concerns of parents raising children while 31 percent favoured Dole.</p>
<p>The poll by U.S. News &amp; World Report said there was a &quot;Mommy and Daddy gap&quot; with mothers twice as likely as fathers to view Clinton as better able to speak to parental concerns.</p>
<p>It said Clinton is supported for re-election by 52 percent of voters, while Dole is backed by 35 percent and the Reform Party's Perot by six percent.</p>
<p>The U.S. News survey of 1,000 registered voters was done between Sept. 3-4 and has a margin of error of 3.1 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
