<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393035" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Tietmeyer says states must not cheat to join EMU.</title>
<headline>Tietmeyer says states must not cheat to join EMU.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer was quoted as saying nations must fulfil the Maastricht criteria for European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) without &quot;statistical cheating&quot; to convince Germans the single currency will be as stable as the mark.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer told Bild newspaper in an interview that he hoped Germany would fulfil the criteria but added the country still needed to make significant efforts to consolidate public budgets at the national, regional and municipal levels.</p>
<p>&quot;What is decisive is a 'lasting' fulfilment of the conditions by us and our partners,&quot; Bild quoted Tietmeyer as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;A 'soft' interpretation could endanger the stability of the euro. It would undermine from the start the confidence of wage earners, pensioners and savers as well as of foreign investors in the euro. That could lead to interest rate increases which would be harmful to employment.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked how Germans could be made to trust the planned single currency, Tietmeyer said: &quot;By founding the currency on stability in a convincing way. That is why the stability criteria must determine the choice of (EMU) members without ifs and buts, and also without statistical cheating.</p>
<p>&quot;Only in this way can one give people the justified expectation that the euro will be as stable as the mark.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
