<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393008" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Finland - Feb 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Finland - Feb 20.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the leading stories in Finnish papers this morning.</p>
<p>HELSINGIN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Valmet may win a large U.S. recycled newsprint machinery order.</p>
<p>- Two Finnish police officers charged with provoking 20-year-old to buy hashish.</p>
<p>- Some goods crossing the tax border between Finland's Aland islands and the rest of the European Union may be taxed twice from March. @</p>
<p>- Final report about the 1994 Estonia disaster delayed again to April, earlier expected in March, investigating committee head Kari Lehtola says.</p>
<p>- Finnish farmers' income has fallen 1.1 billion markka since Finland joined the EU to 6.7 billion markka last year, farmers' economic reasearch institute says.</p>
<p>- Estonia house only place in New York serving Finnish food without advance orders. @</p>
<p>KAUPPALEHTI</p>
<p>- EU agreement with Russia to cap steel trade is good news for the Finnish steel industry, says Sirpa Smolsky, head of the steel producers' lobby.</p>
<p>- Stamp duty favours foreign banks and distorts competition, Finnish banks say.</p>
<p>- Companies' interest in raising money from debt market has increased with falling yields but there is still virtually no secondary corporate bond market, experts say. @</p>
<p>- Finland in the centre of the Nordic area in plans for a European natural gas pipeline network.</p>
<p>HUFVUDSTADSBLADET</p>
<p>- Conflicts in the Social Democratic Party which leads the government are worrying, says opposition leader Esko Aho, chairman of the Centre Party.</p>
<p>- Growing market for pirate video recordings and compact discs is a threat to the legal domestic market.</p>
<p>AAMULEHTI</p>
<p>- Countries left outside NATO after the Madrid summit in July will get another chance, says information chief Jamie Shea. @</p>
<p>- All jobless Finns to be interviewed this spring for information to be put on a database for prospective employers.</p>
<p>TURUN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Knives and Koskenkorva vodka no longer part of Swedes' perception of Finns, which has improved so much it is almost flattering, survey shows.</p>
<p>DEMARI</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Tarja Halonen concerned that Finland may be left on the sidelines while Russia modernises its relations with NATO; says a grey zone should not be created in Europe.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki Newsroom +358-9-680 50 242</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
