<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393070" id="root" date="1997-02-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Europe's firms say Deng death won't hit Asia plans.</title>
<headline>Europe's firms say Deng death won't hit Asia plans.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Marshall</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>European investment in China and Hong Kong will not be dented by the death of paramount leader Deng Xiaoping, European companies and fund managers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Deng's death at 92 had long been expected and incorporated in the strategy of firms doing business in the region, and was not expected to lead to a major change of direction in China's economic policies, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Do you think that investors in Hong Kong believed Deng was immortal? No,&quot; said Jean-Pierre Beguelin, chief investment strategist at leading Geneva private bank Pictet &amp; Cie. &quot;Fund flows out of the region will depend on the level of uncertainty but we don't really expect any changes in the short term.&quot;</p>
<p>Leading multinationals promised to push ahead with their plans in China.</p>
<p>Financial services group HSBC Holdings Plc, which owns Hongkong Bank and Hang Seng Bank and plans to expand further in China, said the economic policies begun by Deng would continue and the handover of Hong Kong to China on July 1 would not be affected.</p>
<p>&quot;Under his leadership, China embarked on a remarkable programme of economic modernisation. We believe the programme will continue and its direction is is irreversible,&quot; spokeswoman Mary Jo Jacobi told Reuters.</p>
<p>Imperial Chemical Industries Plc (ICI), which aims to derive 25 percent of its turnover from Asia by 2005 compared with around 17 percent now, said its plans would not alter.</p>
<p>&quot;We spoke to our people in China this morning. There is no real change in our plans. The economic development of China is expected to continue along the track that has already been set,&quot; a spokesman said.</p>
<p>He said ICI would press on with its expansion in China, including a $400 million investment in a polyeurethane joint venture in Shanghai, and expected to increase its Chinese workforce to 2000 from 500 by the end of the decade.</p>
<p>Swedish telecoms group Ericsson said it did not expect a major impact from Deng's death in either the short or the long term.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who for all practical purposes already have taken over the power from Deng have personally stated that they want to see a continued stable economic development. This should create the same business opportunities as previously,&quot; said Bo Landin, chairman of Ericsson China Ltd.</p>
<p>China, Hong Kong and Macau together constitute Ericsson's second largest market after the United States. In 1996, its turnover in China amounted to $1.5 billion.</p>
<p>British tobacco and financial services group B.A.T. Industries also saw little impact from the news.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still actively trying to get an insurance licence in China,&quot; spokesman Michael Prideaux said. &quot;The cigarettes that we sell there shouldn't be affected.&quot;</p>
<p>Anglo-Dutch food-to-detergents group Unilever said it was monitoring the situation but saw no immediate impact on its strategy.</p>
<p>And Britain's Inchcape Plc, which imports and markets cars and consumer goods into China and is moving its entire marketing base to Asia, said its investment plans would not change in the wake of Deng's death.</p>
<p>&quot;We still plan further significant investment in China. That hasn't changed,&quot; investor relations manager Bridget Walker said.</p>
<p>Fund managers said they did not expect to see fund flows out of Hong Kong, China and Taiwan into Switzerland or other safe havens. Swiss private bankers say some funds flew out of Hong Kong into Switzerland in 1996 ahead of the Chinese takeover, but expected no drastic capital flight because of Deng's death.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody was expecting Deng's death. It was priced in the market. There is no big risk for the market in the short-term,&quot; said Michel Juvet, vice-president of Bordier &amp; Cie, one of Geneva's oldest private banks.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course, Deng's death will add to the uncertainty, but I don't think there will be a huge outflow,&quot; Juvet said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
