<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393146" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish PM, economists welcome union's pay pledge.</title>
<headline>Swedish PM, economists welcome union's pay pledge.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Kristina Zetterlund,</p>
<p>Swedish economists joined Prime Minister Goran Persson in welcoming major retail union Handels' proposal Thursday to freeze a current wage pact, with moderate pay rises, until the year 2000.</p>
<p>Persson said other unions might follow Handels' lead.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it's with no prospect of others following,&quot; Persson told journalists after a session in parliament.</p>
<p>The union and retail employers made a joint declaration in the Dagens Nyheter daily on Thursday calling on workers and industry to extend existing pay agreements and give politicians room to fight unemployment without boosting inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not sure the freeze will take place at all if other unions choose not to follow. But the declaration shows there is a new way of thinking&quot;, Nordbanken chief economist Olle Djerf said.</p>
<p>Although economists agreed that the proposal was encouraging they differed in their expectations for unemployment.</p>
<p>&quot;The European labour crisis is unlikely to be solved by moves like this. The main problem is flexibility,&quot; Paine Webber's James McKay said. &quot;The outlook is still poor...I think we will see seasonally adjusted unemployment hitting bottom sometime in 1998 at 6.5-7 percent before it heads up again.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;You have to generate more flexibility at the same time as loyalty is maintained...And you have to use the carrot instead of the stick. The U.S. uses the stick&quot;, Keld Holm, senior international economist at Lehman Brothers said.</p>
<p>Some economists saw generous welfare benefits as the biggest threat to full employment while other looked to the U.S. labour market, with greater wage differentials, as a model.</p>
<p>Others said that Sweden should commit itself to building a highly-educated workforce able to command a premium on the global labour market, as it would not be able to compete on price with cut-rate workers from developing countries.</p>
<p>Hubert Fromlet, chief economist at Sparbanken, emphasised the importance of stable and consistent government policies.</p>
<p>&quot;There can't be policies which make yields turn back up. Ideological antagonism must come second,&quot; Fromlet said.</p>
<p>Unemployment in Sweden was 8.8 percent in February, unchanged from a month earlier.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
