<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393192" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bre-X chief clarifies Busang rights.</title>
<headline>Bre-X chief clarifies Busang rights.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bre-X Minerals Ltd owns its 45 stake in the huge Indonesian gold deposit, Busang, through a wholly-owned Dutch subsidiary, chief executive officer David Walsh told Reuters on Friday.</p>
<p>Because of this corporate structure, Bre-X does not need to offer its Indonesian partners in Busang the right of first refusal if Bre-X decides to sell its Dutch subsidiary, Walsh said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Bre-X's 45 percent shareholding is owned by a wholly owned Dutch subsidiary of Bre-X,&quot; Walsh said. &quot;Bre-X has the right to sell any or all of that Dutch subsidiary without prior notice to anybody.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;We can do whatever we want with that,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Walsh was responding to comments by Muhammad &quot;Bob&quot; Hasan, who told the Toronto Globe and Mail on Friday that Bre-X must give first rights of refusal to its partners in the joint venture company that will own the huge Busang gold mine.</p>
<p>Hasan owns controlling stakes in two Indonesian companies in the joint venture.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's just get this clear,&quot; said Walsh. &quot;Mr. Hasan is correct in that at the joint-venture company level, any owner has to offer rights of first refusal to the other partners.&quot;</p>
<p>But the rule does not apply to selling off the subsidiary, Walsh said.  </p>
<p>Walsh also said that an arrangement with Sigit Harjojudanto, the son of Indonesian President Suharto, had expired. Last year, Bre-X set up an alliance with Sigit which would have given him a 10 percent stake in Busang as well as US$40 million over 40 months.</p>
<p>&quot;That agreement expired without compensation,&quot; Walsh said on Friday.</p>
<p>He reiterated that Bre-X has always had clear title to the Busang site and that none of the company's directors or managers has been involved in &quot;any impropriety.&quot;</p>
<p>Walsh said he will make a public announcement on Monday outlining Bre-X's history with Busang.</p>
<p>((Heather Scoffield, Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8104))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
