<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393243" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: OLYMPICS-ARGENTINA UPBEAT AFTER IOC EVALUATION.</title>
<headline>OLYMPICS-ARGENTINA UPBEAT AFTER IOC EVALUATION.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina was upbeat on Friday after the IOC's evaluation of Buenos Aires' bid to host the 2004 Olympics.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very satisfied and optimistic about the evaluation,&quot; Francisco Mayorga, the Argentine tourism secretary and former racing driver heading the city's Olympic bid, told a news conference.</p>
<p>Buenos Aires' bid to become the first South American city to host the Games is based on promoting itself as the &quot;safe&quot; option for the event.</p>
<p>The bid committee argued that Buenos Aires had a low level of street crime for a city of its size.</p>
<p>The evaluation gave Buenos Aires, bidding for the fifth time, high marks for its local awareness and support as well as for the existing standard of certain venues and facilities.</p>
<p>However, it drew attention to a number of weaknesses, including a lack of accomodation and the need for a new international airport.</p>
<p>A short-list of five of the 11 cities competing to host the Games will be announced on March 7 with the winner named on September 5.</p>
<p>Mayorga was optimistic that Buenos Aires would reach the short-list.</p>
<p>&quot;Abroad, they are falling in love more and more with our city...the remodelling going on day by day contributes a lot to their fascination,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mayorga played down the fact that Rome and Athens had emerged from the evaluation as front-runners.</p>
<p>&quot;I will limit myself to the experience I have gained after 30 years in car racing -- until one sees the flag it's not possible to say who will win.&quot;</p>
<p>However, he promised that if Latin American rival Rio de Janeiro was short-listed ahead of Buenos Aires he would support its bid.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
