<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393346" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Three UK prisoners freed after 18 years in jail.</title>
<headline>Three UK prisoners freed after 18 years in jail.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three men jailed 18 years ago for the murder of a newspaper delivery boy walked free on Friday in a case that dealt another body blow to Britain's tarnished legal system.</p>
<p>Michael Hickey, his cousin Vincent Hickey and Jimmy Robinson had always protested their innocence since being sentenced to life imprisonment in 1979 for the murder of 13-year-old Carl Bridgewater, shot dead during a burglary.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not child killers,&quot; Robinson told an emotion-charged press conference after being hugged on their release by weeping relatives at London's High Court.</p>
<p>&quot;For long lonely years we have cried and been racked with despair. People have looked at us with hate in their eyes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The three were released on unconditional bail pending an appeal on April 8. Michael Hickey, who kissed the ground on leaving the courthouse, said he wanted the murdered paperboy's parents to be sitting with them at the hearing.</p>
<p>The trio, who had staged hunger strikes and rooftop protests in prison, were released after prosecution lawyers said the trial was fundamentally flawed and the convictions unsafe.</p>
<p>Defence lawyers said police had tricked Patrick Molloy, the fourth man arrested after the murder, into signing an admission after saying that Vincent Hickey had confessed. The lawyers said the confession was forged and concocted by police.</p>
<p>Molloy, convicted of manslaughter, died of a brain haemorrhage in prison in 1981 aged 57.</p>
<p>His son Nick, joining the trio at the press conference, said: &quot;I feel very sad. It's great to see these men today. I salute the heroes, these men. They have courage, true courage.&quot;</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Major said he was sure there would be an inquiry into the original convictions.</p>
<p>The trio's release is the latest in a number of wrongful imprisonment cases in Britain that date back to the 1970s. Many involved Irishmen suspected of Irish Republican Army attacks.</p>
<p>In 1989, the so-called &quot;Guildford Four&quot; were released after convictions were quashed against them for a IRA bomb that killed five people in a pub.</p>
<p>In 1991, the &quot;Birmingham Six&quot; were freed after being cleared of 1974 pub bomb blasts that killed 21 people and injured 162.</p>
<p>The three could be entitled to compensation that may top two million pounds ($3.23 million) but the shaven-haired Vincent Hickey said: &quot;Nothing compensates for 18 years locked up.&quot;</p>
<p>The trio insisted they would not be eaten up with bitterness after spending almost two decades in prison for a crime they did not commit. But the anger in their voices was palpable.</p>
<p>&quot;Not only have the police been devious and deceitful with us in our campaign to keep innocent men in prison. Far worse, after having a child killer, the police have deceived Mr and Mrs Bridgewater,&quot; Vincent Hickey, 42, said.</p>
<p>Robinson said of the police: &quot;It wasn't about one or two rotten apples in the barrel. The whole barrel was rotten. You had to be rotten to get into the barrel.it was a concerted conspiracy from day one.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain abolished the death sentence in 1964 and has resisted several attempts to bring it back in parliamentary votes. &quot;If the hang-'em-all brigade had had their way, we wouldn't be here today,&quot; Robinson said.</p>
<p>The men were asked what they planned to do with their first weekend of freedom. The 63-year-old Robinson said: &quot;The garden is overdue for a dig.&quot;</p>
<p>Michael Hickey, 35, had other ideas: &quot;I want a woman.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
