<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393453" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: U.S. confirms Zaire proximity talks in S.Africa.</title>
<headline>U.S. confirms Zaire proximity talks in S.Africa.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Friday confirmed that South Africa was leading proximity talks in a search for peace in Zaire, where the government has intensified air raids against rebel strongholds.</p>
<p>South African officials remained silent about progress towards a face-to-face meeting in Cape Town between representatives of President Mobutu Sese Seko's government and the Zaire rebel movement headed by Laurent Kabila.</p>
<p>They declined to comment on a statement in New York by United Nations spokesman Fred Eckhard that Kabila was expected in Cape Town by the weekend.</p>
<p>A U.S. embassy official in Cape Town confirmed that George Moose, assistant secretary of state for African affairs, and U.S. National Security Council official Susan Rice expected to remain in the city through the weekend and would be available to bolster the Zairean peace initiative.</p>
<p>&quot;We welcome the effort of South Africa...to begin talks separately with representatives of both sides in the conflict with the aim of trying to determine whether there is a basis for the peaceful resolution of the conflict in Zaire,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>South African government sources said Deputy President Thabo Mbeki, working from an undisclosed location, was managing the exploratory talks about a possible meeting between the rebels and representatives of Mobutu.</p>
<p>Eckhard said the aim of the talks would be to get both sides to accept the five-point plan submitted by U.N. special envoy Mohammed Sahnoun and endorsed by the U.N. Security Council as a basis for discussion.</p>
<p>The proposal includes a ceasefire and plans for elections.</p>
<p>This appeared to contradict South African President Nelson Mandela, who said when he announced the proposed talks on Wednesday that they would not be based solely on the U.N. proposal or on a proposal by Ugandan President Yoweri Museveni.</p>
<p>Ngbanda Nzambo Ko Ayumba, Mobutu's nephew and chief security adviser who has been in Cape Town since Sunday, has played down the idea of peace talks in South Africa.</p>
<p>He told Radio France International in a telephone interview from Cape Town on Thursday that Zaire had pre-conditions for any talks and said there would be no meeting in South Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;We are being attacked by three neighbouring countries and we demand that the three neighbouring countries pull out their soldiers and let Zaireans find a solution to their internal problems,&quot; Ngbanda said.</p>
<p>Zaire says forces from Rwanda, Uganda and Burundi invaded its territory in support of Tutsi-led rebels who took up arms in October accusing Zaire of denying them citizenship and preparing to expel them.</p>
<p>&quot;There's never been any question of meeting any member of the (Zairean) rebellion in South Africa,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;For us there are conditions. We want first of all the real people behind this aggression to show their goodwill and respect the decisions of the Security Council,&quot; he added, referring for a U.N. call for all foreign forces to withdraw.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that South Africa is doing an appreciable job in trying to bring points of view together and pass one's sides points of view to the other,&quot; Ngbanda said.</p>
<p>He said he met Mbeki on Wednesday and Thursday, adding: &quot;It's not my presence that can be useful. It's rather the work that...Mbeki is undertaking through the many contacts he is having with the authorities, let's say the presidents of the region...which can move things forward.&quot;</p>
<p>A South African source told Reuters that representatives from the two sides remained in Cape Town and implied that a meeting was still possible despite Ngbanda's comments.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
