<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393477" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</title>
<headline>S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The rand ended a lethargic day little change on Friday after the Reserve Bank successfully capped the currency at the 4.49 level earlier, dealers said.</p>
<p>At the local 1400 GMT close, the rand was pegged at 4.4825/4855 against the dollar from 4.4815/4845 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Dealers said the Reserve Bank had been active in the market at the start of trade, offering dollars through various banks and preventing the rand from moving to the key 4.50 area.</p>
<p>They said the central bank was keen to defend the 4.50 level for two reasons.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of offshore guys are saying that there are big stop losses up there so the bank is trying to keep a cap on it,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Another trader said that after the rand had broken the 4.47 level earlier in the week, technical factors had pointed for an assault on the 4.52 level.</p>
<p>&quot;The 4.50 level is more of a psychological thing from his point of view,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dealers said that as the currency retreated, it met up with local and offshore demand for dollars, although volumes on the day had been paltry.</p>
<p>Next week, the currency's movement would depend on how much the market wanted to take on the central bank, dealers said, although the market was expected to continue settling down after an eight-cent blowoff on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Against the crosses, the rand was last quoted at 7.2442/2567 against sterling from 7.2128/2230 overnight and at 0.3758/3764 marks from 0.3754/3758 previously.</p>
<p>Activity on the bond market was described by most traders as a non-event, in part because of a golf day hosted by one of the local banks, they said.</p>
<p>At 1400 GMT, the key R150 was at 14.66 percent from 14.64 percent at Thursday's close.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been dead the whole afternoon,&quot; a trader said, adding that activity should pick up again next week ahead of a barrage of economic indicators.</p>
<p>Five key indicators -- trade data, gross domestic product, consumer inflation, money supply growth and credit extension data -- are due for release on Tuesday on Thursday next week.</p>
<p>&quot;The data should dictate what the market should do next week,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>A Reuters consensus poll of economist forecast a trade surplus of 817 million rand in January from 2.04 billion rand in December, while fourth quarter GDP was expected to come in at 3.3 percent quarter-on-quarter on a seasonally adjusted and annualised basis.</p>
<p>Consumer inflation is expected to rise 9.2 percent year-on-year from 9.4 percent in December, money supply growth is expected to increase 15.8 percent from 13.73 percent in December and private sector credit extension growth is seen slowing to 15.3 percent from 15.75 percent previously.</p>
<p>On the money market, three-month NCD rates were quoted steady at between 16.50 to 16.70, while the 90-day BA rate was also unmoved at between 15.90 and 16.10 percent.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank quoted the shortage at 9.762 billion rand on Thursday from 10.539 billion rand on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Bond Exchange statistics show foreigners sold 270.98 million rand's worth of South African bonds on Thursday after selling 299.1 million rand on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Nominal cumulative volume on Thursday, settlement day, was 43.43 billion rand from 11.82 billion rand on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Paul Richardson, Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
