<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393480" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African stock market closing report.</title>
<headline>S.African stock market closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African gold shares were the market's flavour of the day on Friday, closing firmer on the back of a better bullion price.</p>
<p>The gold index jumped 3.2 percent, or 46.9 points, to end at 1,517.8, helping to push the all-share index 21.5 points up to 7,124.1.</p>
<p>&quot;Golds were very firm on the bullion price which is still going strong,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;The gold index would have been higher but being a Friday, people were taking a cautious view as they rounded off their positions for the weekend,&quot; another one said.</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected the metals and gold sectors to continue strong on Monday if the price of the yellow metal holds at current levels.</p>
<p>Gold fixed at $350.75, its highest fixing since January 29, compared with $345.00 on Thursday afternoon.  </p>
<p>&quot;If the gold price holds, the market will take heart from that and we will see a strong market again,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Johannesburg Stock Exchange later announced that its overall share index reached a new record closing high of 7,124 on Friday. The previous high was 7,108 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said despite industrials' weak drift on the day, overall market sentiment remained upbeat on positive economic fundamentals.</p>
<p>&quot;Industrials were drifting off on weaker Dow Jones and also there was some profit-taking,&quot; a dealer said in reference to DOW industrials'93-point drop on Thursday.</p>
<p>The industrial index shed 12.4 points to end at 8,379.3.</p>
<p>&quot;If Dow goes firmer industrials will go up on Monday,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Randgold was up 75 cents to 39.75, Rusplats rose 1.75 rand to 76.75 rand.</p>
<p>On the futures market, the all-share March contract was at 6,545/63 from 6,529, the industrial contract was at 8,177/85 from 8,173 and golds contract was at 1,085/95 from 1,043.</p>
<p>--Emelia Sithole, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482 1003--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
