<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393630" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Foreign investors shrug off Russian Duma vote.</title>
<headline>Foreign investors shrug off Russian Duma vote.</headline>
<byline>Peter Henderson</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign investors were openly skeptical on Friday that a plan by Russia's lower house of parliament to ban or limit foreign investment in areas from telecommunications to oil would derail Russian economic reform.</p>
<p>&quot;There are lots of people in different areas ... that say crazy things,&quot; said Bill Browder, managing director of Hermitage Capital Management equity fund in Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;But the government policy is generally open to investment and I do not expect that to change.&quot;</p>
<p>State Duma deputies voted 261 to 10 in a first reading to ban foreign activity in some areas involving national security such as power supplies and telecoms and limit it in others, such as oil and financial services.</p>
<p>But the Duma, dominated by the Communist Party and its allies, is often seen as a toothless institution.</p>
<p>&quot;Because it is a powerless institution, I don't expect it (the bill) to have any effect in practice,&quot; said Jim Nail, head of research at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;The main information coming from the Duma, for those who did not know it already, is that this institution is generally hostile to rapid economic reform and ignorant of general principles of economics,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Grigory Yavlinsky, head of the liberal Yabloko party, told reporters the Duma often passed bills in a first reading with no regard to reality or economics.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a very serious reworking of this law, and I think there is no reason for worry,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>To take effect, the bill would have to pass a total of three readings in the Duma and be approved by the upper house of parliament and President Boris Yeltsin.</p>
<p>Presidential decrees and government orders are arguably equally important to legislation in Russia.</p>
<p>Government opposition to the bill had begun building within hours of the Duma vote.</p>
<p>&quot;I have to find money for enterprises, and there's none in the budget, so for that reason we have to look for private money,&quot; Sergei Mikhailov, a senior Industry Ministry official, told a news conference.</p>
<p>Traders on the Russian equities market, which has rallied more than 50 percent this year, said that the market was watching the Duma but doubted that the bill would pass or that investor reaction would be sharp or prolonged.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think people will take it seriously,&quot; said Alexander Bubnovsky, head of sales at Alfa Capital bank. &quot;It is obvious Russia needs foreign funds in these capital-intensive sectors.&quot;</p>
<p>Bids had not been affected and hungry investors looking for cheap shares offered support just below current trading levels, operators said.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors working in Russia have nerves of steel,&quot; said Andrei Galperin, senior trader at Creditanstalt-Grant. &quot;They have been here for a long time, they know our peculiarities, and they know the extent of the Duma's power.&quot;</p>
<p>--Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
