<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393652" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian share gains seen helping companies.</title>
<headline>Russian share gains seen helping companies.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian share prices will grow steadily over the next two years and the real economy will benefit as companies find it easier to raise capital and state privatisation revenues rise, a U.S. economist said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We can begin to talk about the Russian market as a serious market and compare it to other emerging countries' markets,&quot; Simon Johnson, a professor at the Fuqua School of Business at Duke University, told a news conference.</p>
<p>With Russian banks switching from government securities where yields are falling and foreign investors putting more trust in the Russian economy, the Russian Trading System index of 24 shares rose to 347.20 on Thursday from 274.68 on December 31, 1996.</p>
<p>Johnson, who is working at the Russian-European Centre for Economic Policy, forecast the share market would develop steadily without major crashes.</p>
<p>&quot;Fundamentals in Russia, which means earnings of the company after taxes, look good over the next couple of years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Although the market is still small compared to the size of the Russian economy, making less than 15 percent of GDP, the threat of a financial bubble is small, as individuals take very little part in stock market speculation, Johnson said.</p>
<p>But he forecast that in 1998 individuals would come rapidly to the market as the number of mutual funds would grow.</p>
<p>&quot;We would expect the mutual funds industry to develop steadily and become important in several years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Currently there are four mutual funds in Russia and only one is dedicated to investment in equities.</p>
<p>The rise in share prices will help big companies, especially in the oil and gas, telecommunications and power production sectors, to raise capital. Management of smaller companies will learn to be more positive about the share market, Johnson said.</p>
<p>Johnson also said that as companies raise more capital on the stock market they would find funds to pay tax arrears.</p>
<p>--Julie Tolkacheva, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
