<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39377" id="root" date="1996-09-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Kashmiri separatists detained as polling starts.</title>
<headline>Kashmiri separatists detained as polling starts.</headline>
<byline>Nelson Graves</byline>
<dateline>SRINAGAR, India 1996-09-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian police detained Kashmiri separatist leaders on Saturday as the Himalayan region began voting in its first local elections since a violent revolt against Indian rule erupted six years ago.</p>
<p>At least five leading separatists, including a man sometimes called &quot;the Nelson Mandela of Kashmir&quot;, were detained or placed under house arrest, their aides said.</p>
<p>Most leading separatist groups have urged voters to boycott the polls, viewed as crucial to Indian Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's efforts to restore democracy in Jammu and Kashmir state, where more than 20,000 people have been killed since early 1990.</p>
<p>Around 200,000 soldiers, paramilitary troopers and police were deployed to prevent attacks on the 2,000 polling stations in 26 of the state's 87 constituencies voting on Saturday.</p>
<p>A small bomb exploded before polls opened at 7.00 a.m. (0130 GMT) in a house at Digwar village, some 250 km (150 miles) north of the state's winter capital, Jammu, and near the line of control with Pakistan, police said. No injuries were reported.</p>
<p>Residents say an average of 10 to 20 people die each day in mostly Hindu India's only Moslem majority state in clashes between security forces and militants, as well as in bomb, grenade and other attacks.</p>
<p>Dozens of militant organisations are fighting either for independence or merger with Pakistan, which New Delhi accuses of arming and training guerrillas. Islamabad denies the charge.</p>
<p>An Indian defence spokesman said Indian and Pakistani troops exchanged routine fire around the line of control in western Poonch district. Firing is routine in the area but it intensified slightly on Saturday, he said.</p>
<p>Pakistan and India have fought two of their three wars since independence in 1947 over the region. Pakistan controls one third of Kashmir and has staked a claim over the rest.</p>
<p>Some 1.3 million voters were eligible to vote on Saturday before polling stations closed at 5.00 p.m. (1130 GMT).</p>
<p>Voting in remaining constituencies will be over three days -- September 16, 21 and 30 -- to enable election officials and some 200,000 security personnel to move between regions.</p>
<p>Final results were expected in early October.</p>
<p>Shabir Shah, compared by supporters with South African President Nelson Mandela because they both spent years in jail for political convictions, said he was under house arrest.</p>
<p>Paramilitary troopers were deployed in streets around his house in the state's summer capital, Srinagar, and state police took positions in and around the house, witnesses said.</p>
<p>A Reuter correspondent saw two policemen prevent Shah from leaving the compound to visit voting stations in north Kashmir.</p>
<p>&quot;They are not allowing me to go out,&quot; Shah told Reuters. &quot;Now police have entered my home.&quot;</p>
<p>Police were stationed outside a Srinagar hospital where Yasin Malik and Jawed Mir, president and vice-president of the Jammu and Kashmir Liberation Front, were recovering from injuries they said were caused when soldiers beat them on Friday. The army denied the claim.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not being allowed to go out,&quot; Mir told Reuters.</p>
<p>The All Parties Hurriyat (Freedom) Conference, grouping about 30 separatist organisations, said two of its leaders -- Abdul Gani Lone and Syed Ali Shah Geelani -- had been detained by authorities in north Kashmir, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>Asked whether the separatists were being detained, senior police officer V.K. Singh said: &quot;This is an arrangement for their physical security, so there is no untoward incident.&quot;</p>
<p>A Hurriyat spokesman said the organisation had received reports that some voters in two districts in north Kashmir were being forced by security forces and pro-government militants to cast ballots. The government earlier had denied similar allegations of coercion during general elections in May.</p>
<p>The last state assembly was dissolved in 1990 to allow New Delhi to impose direct rule and move thousands of paramilitary troops into the state to try to quell the insurgency. It was elected in 1987 amid widespread allegations of rigging.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SRINAGAR, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
