<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393726" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: FEATURE - Hungarian agriculture suffers post-communist crisis.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Hungarian agriculture suffers post-communist crisis.</headline>
<byline>Denes Albert</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's economy has undergone many painful adjustments since communism collapsed, but few sectors have had as rough a time as agriculture.</p>
<p>In a country that prides itself on eating and living well, food consumption is down substantially from communist times. The size of livestock herds has shrunk to the level just after World War Two of less than one million head of cattle.</p>
<p>Attempts at distributing former state holdings of farmland have resulted in a patchwork of tiny farms dotting the countryside.</p>
<p>And, experts say, faulty planning at the government level has resulted in Hungary making some extremely disadvantageous deals which strictly curtail its farms subsidies and make its products uncompetitive on world markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Agriculture is in crisis, but not in an impossible situation,&quot; says Agriculture Minister Frigyes Nagy, the fifth person to hold the post in six years.</p>
<p>&quot;The greatest loss of the last years was not that of our export markets, but the decline of domestic consumption,&quot; Nagy said, adding that since the collapse of communism basic food consumption had shrunk 30 percent.</p>
<p>Meat and fish consumption dropped to 69.5 kg per person in 1994 from its 79.6 kg peak in 1985, while consumption of milk and dairy products dropped to 141.1 kg from 183.2 kg, statistics showed.</p>
<p>AD-HOC PRIVATISATION IN 1990</p>
<p>Communist Hungary created large state-run agricultural cooperatives with a solid domestic market and reasonable barter export deals within Comecon, the communist world's version of the European Union.</p>
<p>Reforms introduced by the first post-communist government led to the dismantling of cooperatives. Small patches of land were awarded to hundreds of thousands of farmers, who had neither the machinery, nor the capital for effective farming.</p>
<p>&quot;There are many properties that are not even wide enough for a harvester,&quot; Attila Kovacs, general director of the trading company Agrimpex, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Although 90 percent of the land was distributed, only 52 percent of the transactions are legally complete,&quot; Nagy said.</p>
<p>The land privatisation set a maximum 300 hectares (740 acres) ownership limit and banned foreigners from owning land.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreigners rent land through 'black' contracts because they don't have any choice,&quot; Nagy said.</p>
<p>UNCLEAR PROPERTY RIGHTS - NO FINANCING</p>
<p>Today's cooperatives also resort to leasing land, which means they lack the long-term stability of the only asset on which they could take up much-needed loans: the land itself.</p>
<p>As a result, Hungary's agricultural machinery is on average about 10 years old, according to statistics which also show a steady decline in the purchase of new equipment since 1993.</p>
<p>Lack of financing also severely restricts the use of fertilisers and pesticides.</p>
<p>&quot;Most farmers can ill afford even the most basic pesticides, let alone the required level of fertilisers,&quot; said Istvan Grebats, managing director of grains company Termin.</p>
<p>STATE SUBSIDIES HELP, BUT REMAIN UNPREDICTABLE</p>
<p>Last year, Hungary spent 94 billion forints ($538.2 million) on agricultural subsidies, but the constant shift of focus over the last few years meant farmers were unable to plan ahead.</p>
<p>The target for this year is 101 billion forints, but Nagy said farmers' cooperation would be an essential prerequisite of properly targeted subsidies.</p>
<p>&quot;Hundreds of thousands of farmers refuse to provide us with even basic (crop and property size) information,&quot; he told a conference of members of parliament from the Socialist party, which heads a coalition government.</p>
<p>Nagy, appointed last November, is expected to prepare Hungary's agriculture for joining the European Union and tackle inherited problems.</p>
<p>The single biggest inherited problem is that of export subsidy limits imposed on Hungary by the World Trade Organisation (WTO) based on GATT's 1992 Uruguay round.</p>
<p>Hungary claims that the limits imposed are based on wrong export subsidy figures for the period between 1986 and 1990, supplied by the then communist government.</p>
<p>In Uruguay Hungary reported export subsidies of 22 billion forints instead of the actual 58 billion and is expected to reduce this to 14.32 billion by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Hungary would like 1995 to be used as the base year and to register the subsidy figures in dollars instead of forints because of high inflation, currently around 24 percent.</p>
<p>Four countries, Argentina, Australia, New Zealand and the United States have initiated the creation of a WTO ruling panel, but the dispute is likely to drag on at least until the end of the year.</p>
<p>Trade sources told Reuters that while Hungary would try to haggle for the longest possible time, it will eventually bow to international pressure.</p>
<p>POSSIBLE SOLUTIONS</p>
<p>Most experts agree the future lies in quality rather than quantity, as landlocked Hungary is disadvantaged in terms of high-volume, low-price commodities exports to remote markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, the closer (the export market), the better, but this is more so in our case, with the nearest Adriatic port some 600 km (372 miles) away,&quot; Kovacs said.</p>
<p>Grebats added that Hungary has potential for higher value products with more favourable price per transport cost ratios.</p>
<p>&quot;Our climate favours durum wheat, a sought-after commodity, and we are among the world leaders in quality wines,&quot; he said. &quot;I could also mention goose liver (which) we export as far as Japan&quot;.</p>
<p>Grains will, however, remain the main agricultural export product and the ruling Socialist-led coalition is yet to deliver its 1994 election promise of streamlining agriculture.</p>
<p>Nagy said a comprehensive programme is nearing completion and should be implemented at the beginning of 1998. When appointing Nagy, Prime Minister Gyula Horn said a change was needed in order to prepare Hungary's agriculture for European Union requirements.</p>
<p>However, short-term political considerations could weigh more heavily in devising the programme than EU-membership hopes.</p>
<p>($ = 174.6 Hungarian Forints)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
