<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393796" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuela pay deal need not boost inflation - Casas.</title>
<headline>Venezuela pay deal need not boost inflation - Casas.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Venezuelan inflation need not rise on recent public sector pay deals, Central Bank President Antonio Casas Gonzalez said -- it all depends on how the pay rises are financed.</p>
<p>&quot;Planning Minister Teodoro Petkoff has said inflation this year could reach 35 percent, but that's a very approximate measure,&quot; Casas told a congressional committee. &quot;We still don't know how much the pay rises will finally be, nor, just as importantly, how they will be financed.&quot;  </p>
<p>Casas was speaking to a committee studying the question of wages and bonus payments for public sector workers. The government announced last week an improved 35 percent pay rise offer and a 50 percent increase in bonus payments for the sector.</p>
<p>Central Bank director Domingo Maza Zavala, also present, stressed that in a recession-bound economy such as Venezuela's that has considerable idle capacity, the pay increases need not be inflationary.  </p>
<p>&quot;On the other hand, if the pay rises are too great, nominal wage gains will be eroded by inflation. One has to find a point of equilibrium,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Casas earlier said average inflation for the year would be between 40 and 50 percent. Average inflation is a little-used measure that averages annualized inflation rates extrapolated from monthly inflation rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The official inflation target for the year remains 25 percent,&quot; Casas said.</p>
<p>&quot;The crux of the matter is not controlling pay rises, but how those rises will be financed,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>((-- John Paul Rathbone, Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
