<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393973" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMM currencies finish mixed after rangebound day.</title>
<headline>IMM currencies finish mixed after rangebound day.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>IMM currency futures finished mixed after a rangebound session, with March yen and marks near the bottom of the day's range.</p>
<p>An early bid in currencies was tied to followthrough from Thursday's gains when the dollar's rally faltered. Many had expected more currency gains again Friday as the dollar pulled back from its recent multi-year highs, but pre-weekend dollar buying helped stabilize the U.S. unit.</p>
<p>March marks poked above Thursday's session high early, but then eroded for the rest of the day. March yen shaved its early small gains soon after the opening.  </p>
<p>Action appeared consolidative in many contracts, with March yen trading in the upper portion of Thursday's range. March Swiss francs filled in an upside gap left over from Tuesday's open, only to close in the middle of the day's range.</p>
<p>Traders said a slim data line-up on Friday and into next week was keeping players wary -- particularly after the slight pullback in the dollar this week. Some said all attention was now fixed on upcoming testimony from Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan. His semi-annual Humphrey Hawkins testimony is February 26-27.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're going to have a slow week,&quot; one IMM currency futures trader said.</p>
<p>He noted a second day of heightened interest in peso options.</p>
<p>Ralph Delzenero, vice president foreign exchange marketing at First Chicago, said it appears dollar bulls were still buyers on dips.</p>
<p>&quot;There's some real resiliency here and they keep buying dollar/yen,&quot; Delzenero said.</p>
<p>Some had expected the dollar to correct further, particularly in light of recent comments out of Germany.  </p>
<p>Even today, German Chancellor Helmut Kohl said he believed the mark had fully corrected against the dollar and that the German job situation would improve in 1997.</p>
<p>But one trader said players were tiring of German officials' attempts to swat the dollar down.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's not taking comments too seriously any longer, as you can tell,&quot; he said, adding that the overall bent of the dollar was still bullish.</p>
<p>Also on Friday, Alice Rivlin, vice-chairman of the Federal Reserve said the strong dollar &quot;certainly helps&quot; curb inflation.  </p>
<p>At the end of pit trading, March yen fell $0.000042 to $0.008137, marks fell $0.0011 to $0.5929, Swiss francs rose $0.0020 to $0.6810, sterling rose $0.0070 to $1.6172, Can dollars fell $0.0015 to $0.7343 and Aussie dollars rose $0.0055 to $0.7777. ((DerivativesDesk(312)408-8750/E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
