<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="393924" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Latin American debts firm on economic outlook.</title>
<headline>Latin American debts firm on economic outlook.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investors piled back into Latin American debt papers after two days of repose as confidence in the region's economic growth surged and worries about the potential rise of Brazil's fiscal deficit subsided, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>Spreads of actively traded Latin Bradies narrowed by about 10 to 15 basis points, traders said.</p>
<p>Argentina appeared to be the flavor of the day, with FRBs ARFLC05=RR trading near its all-time high at 91-3/4. It was bid 91-3/8, up 1/2 on the day.  </p>
<p>James Barrineau, Latin America debt strategist at Smith Barney, said amid all the positive data out of Argentina, the forecast of industrial output was particularuly encouraging.</p>
<p>Industry Secretary Alieto Guadagni on Thursday forecast the industrial output would grow by more than five percent to reach a record high.</p>
<p>Argentina's gross domestic product rose 4.4 percent in 1996 after shrinking by 4.6 percent in the previous year, the government reported on Thursday.  </p>
<p>Mexico's economic growth of 5.1 percent in 1996, showing a broadly based recovery, also drew sidelined investors back into the market, he said. The data were released on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, concerns about Brazil's supreme court ruling on civilian pay rise eased, as any potential impact on fiscal deficit was unlikely to be felt before 1999, Barrineau said.</p>
<p>The court ruled on Wednesday that 11 civil servants were entitled to a 29 percent pay rise, sparking fears that similar claims would be made by one million federal workers and pensioners.  </p>
<p>But traders said for the time being Brazil C BR8D14=RR was capped at 82.00, the all-time high reached on Tuesday. &quot;Theere's still lots of doubt about the pay ruling,&quot; said a trader. The C bond rose 3/4 to bid 81-1/8.</p>
<p>Ecuador, reversing its position adopted earlier this week, announced on Friday that it intended to renegotiate the Paris Club debt after all.</p>
<p>Marco Santamaria, sovereign credit analyst at ING Barings, said the decision was not a surprise.  </p>
<p>&quot;It has always been understood that the debt would be renegotiated,&quot; he said, noting that the debt renegotiation plan dated back to President Abdala Bucaram, who was outsted two weeks ago.</p>
<p>But to renegotiate the debt, Ecuador must get past the review of economic conditions by the International Monetary Fund, he said.</p>
<p>Despite some stumbling, the economic team of interim President Fabian Alarcon &quot;has been saying the right things&quot; to restore foreign investors' confidence in the country, Santamaria said.</p>
<p>Ecuador Pars ECPARS=RR rose 1/2 to 47 bid and PDI ECPDI=RR gained 1/4 too 64-1/4 bid.</p>
<p>U.S. Brady bond market shrugged off the upgrade of the Philippine long-term foreign currency debt by one of the rating agencies, traders said.</p>
<p>Standard and Poor's raised the sovereign rating to BB-plus from BB on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been expected,&quot; said a trader, noting that with the Philippine Bradies trading close to par, there was little room for gains.</p>
<p>Phillipine DCB eased 1/8 to 97-3/4 bid and NMB bond was unchanged at 99.00 even.</p>
<p>(( -- Nailene Chou Wiest - 212-859-1674))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
