<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="394054" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed's Rivlin - wage growth not boosting inflation.</title>
<headline>Fed's Rivlin - wage growth not boosting inflation.</headline>
<dateline>CORAL GABLES, Fla 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Recent growth in U.S. wages has not sparked inflation yet because productivity appears to be growing even faster, Alice Rivlin, vice-chairwoman of the Federal Reserve said Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no strong evidence that the wage growth is proceeding faster than the productivity increase at the moment,&quot; Rivlin told reporters after moderating a panel at a Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta Conference here.  </p>
<p>&quot;Eventually, if wage increases are not matched by productivity increases, they will lead to inflation,&quot; Rivlin said. &quot;But that's not happening yet.&quot;</p>
<p>Rivlin observed that the current U.S. economic conditions have put the Fed on alert for signs of inflation. &quot;The risks are on the upside when you have tight labor markets for a very long time -- you should be vigilant,&quot; Rivlin said, adding the Fed is being vigilant currently.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy's on a good track at the moment,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>Asked if the strong dollar was helping to curb inflation, Rivlin said, &quot;It certainly helps, it's an off-setting factor.&quot;</p>
<p>Rivlin explained that a strong dollar could hurt U.S. exporters but noted that &quot;American industry is much more competitive than it used to be.&quot;  </p>
<p>Asked about the risk of inflation accelerating in coming months, Rivlin said the current unusual economic conditions made it difficult to predict.</p>
<p>&quot;I very frankly think we don't know,&quot; Rivlin said. &quot;This is a situation that we really haven't been in before: Very tight labor markets for a long time with relatively moderate wage increases and very little if any inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;How long can this go on?&quot; Rivlin asked. &quot;We don't really know. We aren't even sure why it's happening exactly.&quot;</p>
<p>Although the Federal Reserve has not paid close attention to monetary aggregates in recent years, Rivlin said M2 may now be &quot;behaving in a more regular way,&quot; thus making it more &quot;interesting&quot; to the Fed in the future.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CORAL GABLES, Fla"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
