<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="394082" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan's Lee cast doubts on China succession.</title>
<headline>Taiwan's Lee cast doubts on China succession.</headline>
<byline>Joyce Liu</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan President Lee Teng-hui expressed doubts on Friday that Chinese President Jiang Zemin will succeed in replacing Deng Xiaoping as the mainland's top policy-maker and undisputed leader.</p>
<p>Deng, paramount leader and Long March veteran, died late on Wednesday aged 92. He had anointed Jiang, also Communist Party chief, as his heir.</p>
<p>It is widely believed the Party's key 15th Congress in October will provide a first major test for Jiang, 70, whose tenure as general secretary will be up for review.</p>
<p>&quot;President Lee said he was not optimistic about Jiang Zemin's firm position for succession after Deng Xiaoping died,&quot; state-run television quoted Lee as telling a group of senior local newspaper executives.</p>
<p>Lee did not elaborate why he was not hopeful.</p>
<p>Lee, who offered in 1996 to make a peace journey to China and hold a meeting with Jiang, also slammed China's human rights record, saying China cannot compete with Taiwan on democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;They (China) often talk about democracy, but their democracy is different. It is not democracy without human rights,&quot; Lee said on the television.</p>
<p>&quot;Do they (China) dare to compete with us on democracy? I think they definitely dare not,&quot; Lee said.</p>
<p>Lee said on Friday that his government would continue to promote ties with China and predicted that long-suspended Taiwan-Beijing talks would resume next year if Jiang consolidated his power during the party congress in October.</p>
<p>The president said that, in the meantime, China's Communist leadership would be occupied by political transition and would not have time for negotiation with Taiwan.</p>
<p>China has regarded Taiwan as a renegade province since the Nationalists sought refuge there after losing the civil war on the mainland in 1949. Both governments say they want reunification but under very different terms.</p>
<p>Nineteen months ago, China clamped a freeze on what had been slowly warming unofficial ties with Taiwan after a controversial visit to the United States by Lee in June 1995.</p>
<p>Beijing, which interpreted Lee's private but high-profile trip as an attempt to promote independence for Nationalist-held Taiwan, later staged several missile tests near the island to warn the Taiwanese not to drop its commitment to reunification.</p>
<p>The war games hit the island's financial markets in early 1996 and triggered panic buying of U.S. dollars and gold.</p>
<p>Beijing refuses to drop its threat to use military force to retake the island should it declare independence.</p>
<p>Taiwan officials, including Lee, have urged people of the island not to overreact to Deng's death.</p>
<p>&quot;We should not take this issue too seriously,&quot; Lee was quoted as telling a group of national assemblymen on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have experienced the most dangerous missile crisis, so we should have confidence and not become unravelled,&quot; the Central Daily News newspaper, owned by the ruling Nationalist Party, quoted Lee as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;It (Deng's death) happened and the stock market rose... We should set our heart at ease,&quot; Lee told the assemblymen.</p>
<p>The island's sensitive stock market has so far shrugged off political fears, rising 0.28 percent on Thursday and a further 1.47 percent on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing will be affected by them (China) and we have been prepared for a long time ago,&quot; the independent China Times newspaper quoted Lee as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;Why should you worry if I am not worried?&quot; Lee said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
