<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="394224" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Global One cuts 180-200 jobs in Brussels, U.S..</title>
<headline>Global One cuts 180-200 jobs in Brussels, U.S..</headline>
<byline>Nick Louth</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Global One, a communications venture owned by Sprint Corp., Deutsche Telekom AG and France Telecom disclosed on Friday that it cut 180-200 of its 2,900 jobs to get a better grip on ballooning spending.</p>
<p>The jobs were cut on Wednesday. No announcement was made, but a spokesman confirmed them in answer to Reuter inquiries. Half of the job cuts were in Reston, Va., and half in Brussels, most of those at the company's European headquarters.</p>
<p>&quot;It is 180-200 evenly distributed between Europe and Reston,&quot; said a Global One spokesman.</p>
<p>A source disclosed last month that job cuts were imminent because the venture had overshot its original 1996 budget of $250 million by almost 50 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;What we did well is that we made our revenue target. What we did less than right is that we have to get a better handle on expenses,&quot; the spokesman said. The European headquarters employs about 225 people and the Reston office about 1,000 for Global One.</p>
<p>the spokesman said Sprint would not have to take a charge against its earnings for the restructuring and job cuts. Sprint already took $62 million in charges for Global One losses in 1996, including $22 million in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Most of the employees whose jobs in Brussels are being eliminated will return to the three shareholding companies from which they were brought to set up the venture, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Those in Reston would be offered outplacement assistance to help find them new jobs.</p>
<p>Global One is designed to cater to the global telecommunications needs of large corporations and to act as a carrier of data and voice traffic to other telecommunication firms.</p>
<p>It will compete with Concert, a joint venture between MCI Communications Corp. and British Telecommunications Plc, and Unisource, which is run by AT&amp;T Corp. and four European partners.</p>
<p>Global One ended 1996 with annualised revenues of $800 million. It expects $1.3 billion in revenues in 1997.</p>
<p>However, the complexities of putting together products, personnel and corporate cultures from three different linguistic backgrounds have been daunting.</p>
<p>The venture will now move more of its resources toward sales and products and away from centralized overhead, the spokesman said. By this time next year Global One is expecting to employ 500 more people than it does now. (( New York Newsroom 212 859 1712))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
