<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39428" id="root" date="1996-09-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Second Iraqi Kurdish town falls in fighting.</title>
<headline>Second Iraqi Kurdish town falls in fighting.</headline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-09-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fighting raged in northern Iraq on Sunday and the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK) said rival Kurdish rebels backed by Iraqi government forces had captured the strategic town of Degala.</p>
<p>&quot;Iraqi troops supported by KDP (Kurdistan Democratic Party) tanks and artillery have taken Degala. I confirm that Degala has fallen,&quot; Latif Rashid of the PUK's London office told Reuters.</p>
<p>Degala lies just outside the city of Koi Sanjaq, 100 km (60 miles) to the northwest of Sulaimaniya, the last main PUK stronghold near the Iranian border.</p>
<p>A PUK spokesman in Washington, Barham Salih, said Koi Sanjaq had also fallen at 3.30 p.m. (1130 GMT) to combined Iraqi-KDP forces. There was no immediate independent confirmation of this.</p>
<p>U.S. cruise missile attacks on Iraq last week were precipitated by the attack on Arbil on August 31 when the PUK was driven out of the northern city by the combined forces of Iraqi armour and KDP guerrillas, Baghdad's new ally in the mainly Kurdish north.</p>
<p>The fall of Degala followed several days of fierce fighting between the rival Kurdish militias.</p>
<p>PUK leader Jalal Talabani told the British Broadcasting Corporation by telephone that thousands of people were fleeing Koi Sanjaq.</p>
<p>Talabani said the U.S. missile attacks on southern Iraq had done nothing to stop Iraqi President Saddam Hussein from continuing his attacks in the Kurdish-held north.</p>
<p>&quot;They must prevent Saddam Hussein...Now we have to punish him,&quot; Talabani said.</p>
<p>&quot;We call on the U.S. and its coalition partners to intervene urgently to halt the Iraqi aggression and end this onslaught against the Kurdish people,&quot; the PUK said.</p>
<p>Earlier, KDP radio said its forces had killed 300 PUK fighters and demanded the rest surrender.</p>
<p>In Baghdad, a senior Iraqi official warned Turkey not to go ahead with plans to set up a security zone inside Kurdish-held territory in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;We will take every necessary action in our part to prevent it (the buffer zone),&quot; said Hamed Youssef Hummadi, head of the culture and information committee of Iraq's parliament. He did not elaborate on what measures Iraq might take.</p>
<p>It was Baghdad's first warning to its northern neighbour since Ankara started a military buildup along their common border in an apparent attempt to establish a five to 10 km (three to six mile) -wide cordon to deter attacks by rebel Turkish Kurds.</p>
<p>Turkish Foreign Minister Tansu Ciller said on Saturday that Turkey might empty some settlements within the buffer zone.</p>
<p>Turkey fears that rebels of the Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK), fighting for self-rule in southeast Turkey using bases in northern Iraq, will profit from the inter-Kurdish fighting there to mount attacks across the mountainous and porous border.</p>
<p>Iraq, keen to resume some form of trade with Turkey despite U.N. trade sanctions imposed on Baghdad for its 1990 invasion of Kuwait, has always been cautious not to antagonise its northern neighbour.</p>
<p>Iraqi media on Sunday also reiterated Baghdad's threats to shoot down U.S. or allied aircraft flying over Iraq.</p>
<p>Official newspapers carried on their front pages a foreign ministry statement vowing that &quot;our air defences throughout Iraq will hit at any hostile target violating our skies.&quot;</p>
<p>Iraq's military said on Saturday it had fired surface-to-air missiles but they had missed. The Pentagon said it could not confirm that missiles had been fired at U.S. planes.</p>
<p>Gulf Arab foreign ministers meeting in Saudi Arabia backed international efforts to ensure Iraqi compliance with U.N. resolutions, but made no direct mention of last week's missile attacks on Iraq by the United States, their key Western ally.</p>
<p>Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC) members Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Bahrain, Oman, Kuwait and Qatar asserted &quot;the importance of a unified political stand by the countries of the international coalition&quot;.</p>
<p>They said the GCC &quot;strongly condemns the interference of some neighbouring countries in northern Iraq and calls on these countries to immediately and completely halt the interference in Iraq's internal affairs&quot;.</p>
<p>The statement was apparently referring to reported Iranian support for the PUK and Turkey's plans to set up a buffer zone in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>Iran again rejected accusations that its forces had intervened and said it wanted a peaceful solution to the region's problems, Iranian television reported.</p>
<p>In Paris, Foreign Minister Herve de Charette said France did not back the U.S. missile attacks because Paris believed they were unjustified and it had not been sufficiently consulted.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
