<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="394855" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil prices hit six-month low, more losses forecast.</title>
<headline>Oil prices hit six-month low, more losses forecast.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>World oil prices melted to six-month lows under $20 a barrel on Friday as traders said good-bye to the heating oil season and faced more Iraqi barrels hitting the U.S. market.</p>
<p>The 20 percent drop in benchmark Brent crude oil prices over the last six weeks also damaged the technical foundation enough to prompt many analysts to predict further losses until demand starts to pick up for the spring driving season.</p>
<p>At 1227 GMT, April Brent crude futures traded 20 cents lower at $19.88 a barrel after dropping to $19.81. That is the weakest price for the spot month since $19.70 was hit on August 8.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's probably more a kiss good-bye to the heating season than taking a look at the gasoline season yet,&quot; said Peter Gignoux, manager of Smith Barney's petroleum desk in London.</p>
<p>&quot;The technicals have turned weak and last but not least, there is a bout of mild weather along the East Coast (U.S.),&quot; he said. &quot;I don't think the technicals are going to give it a chance to turn yet.&quot;</p>
<p>More Iraqi sales to the U.S. darkened the crude market after reports earlier this week that inventories there rose 3.1 million barrels in the last week and were now nearly six million above a year ago.</p>
<p>A United Nations sanctions committee on Thursday approved deeper discounts for Iraqi crude sales to account for deteriorating prices of sour crude.</p>
<p>Demand for sour crude, which has a high sulphur content, has dropped off in the United States in part because of a heavy programme of refinery maintenance, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is clearly enough crude around in the U.S. at present and there is more to come from Iraq,&quot; said Leslie Nicholas, energy analyst at GNI Ltd.</p>
<p>Perhaps coincidentally, one of Iraq's first crude shipments under the U.N. oil-for-food exchange has arrived in South Africa, more than two months after leaving Iraqi shores.</p>
<p>Gignoux said the U.S. market was also misinterpreting a planned visit to Washington by Saudi oil minister Ali Naimi later this month.</p>
<p>U.S. officials plan to discuss leasing out space in the Strategic Petroleum Reserve to Saudi Arabia, but they are not expected to talk about any oil-for-planes exchanges, according to U.S. officials.</p>
<p>Oil traders wrongly believed that the visit could lead to higher Saudi oil production and sales, which in turn hurt U.S. crude oil prices, Gignoux said.</p>
<p>There is no evidence Saudi Arabia has increased its oil output, currently running at 8.01 million barrels per day, according to a Reuter survey.</p>
<p>Forecasts for well-above normal temperatures in the Northeast U.S., the world's largest heating oil market, hit the prices of gas oil futures, which dropped to a seven-month nadir of $170.75 a tonne.</p>
<p>Weather Services Corp predicted temperatures will elevate to 20-30 degrees Fahrenheit above normal in the Northeast U.S. this weekend and Northwest Europe will enjoy 5-10 degrees F above normal this weekend and into next week.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an extremely bearish picture on gas oil,&quot; said Nick Wilson, a technical analyst at Mees Pierson on the Isle of Man. &quot;Over the course of the next two to three weeks I would look for it to come down to major support at $156-$159.&quot;</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>						Feb 21    Feb 20</p>
<p>					     (1227 GMT) (close)</p>
<p>    Dated Brent			   $20.21    $20.57</p>
<p>    IPE London Brent futures (Apr)  $19.88    $20.08</p>
<p>    NYMEX light crude futures (Apr) $21.47    $21.69</p>
<p>-- John Hanley, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8185</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
