<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39498" id="root" date="1996-09-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Deutsche German fund unit sees no impact from MGAM.</title>
<headline>Deutsche German fund unit sees no impact from MGAM.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deutsche Bank AG's German funds unit, DWS, said this weekend it did not expect to have to implement changes in its control mechanisms as a result of the severe problems at three of the bank's British funds.</p>
<p>In an interview with the Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung, Christian Strenger, spokesman for the management at DWS, said that the DWS standards were already high and that investors were continuing to invest in the funds, despite the U.K. problems.</p>
<p>Asked whether he expected the events at Morgan Grenfell Asset Management in London to have a negative impact on the German operation he said, &quot;Definitely not, as German investors are well aware of the quality and solidity of German funds companies such as DWS.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;In case this needs confirmation - even today we registered not insignificant purchases of DWS funds,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Trading in three funds managed by MGAM, the Deutsche Bank group's British fund management unit, was temporarily halted this week due to &quot;suspected irregularities&quot;.</p>
<p>The manager of two of the funds, Peter Young, was suspended and his personal assets frozen pending a probe into his management of the funds, which held a high proportion of unlisted, speculative high-technology stocks.</p>
<p>Worried investors sold off eight percent of the funds which were worth 1.14 billion pounds when they resumed trading on Thursday. A further five percent was sold on Friday.</p>
<p>Deutsche has pledged to tighten up its controlling mechanisms to prevent any recurrence.</p>
<p>Strenger denied that the German-based funds could be vulnerable to similar problems, adding that DWS would only invest in stocks without a full listing if it was clear that a listing was likely soon and that the company was sound.</p>
<p>&quot;We examine such stocks particularly closely and using quality documents,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said there was no need for new, tighter controlling mechanisms, adding that standards were already being reviewed and improved all the time.</p>
<p>&quot;The control systems which have been established and proven over 40 years are constantly being reviewed and reworked to build in new developments,&quot; he said. &quot;This means our internal controls are guaranteed to be effective.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
