<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="395073" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYC MAC okays bonds, city vows to protect budget.</title>
<headline>NYC MAC okays bonds, city vows to protect budget.</headline>
<byline>Joan Gralla</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Municipal Assistance Corporation for New York City (MAC) approved bond sales giving the city an extra $250 million, and in return, the city vowed not to spend the money in ways that would raise outyear budget gaps.</p>
<p>The pact between New York City and MAC, which was set up in the mid-1970s to rescue the city from its fiscal crisis, leaves the city free to find more funds or cut spending elsewhere in order to keep programs to be funded by the $250 million windfall running past the 1998 fiscal year.</p>
<p>But Joseph Lhota, city budget director, said there now were no plans to do so for the biggest program, one that also was likely to please voters, a $125 million effort to help elementary children learn to read at the third-grade level.</p>
<p>Asked if the Giuliani Administration did not plan to continue the reading program for more than one year, Lhota told reporters at a MAC board meeting: &quot;That's correct.&quot;</p>
<p>The extra $250 million that the city will get over the next 17 months will be produced by $2.9 billion worth of bond refundings by MAC, including last December's $677 million sale.</p>
<p>The windfall also will help pay for arts education in the public schools, which had been cut out of the curriculum.</p>
<p>And New York City plans to spend $50 million of the funds on the Board of Education's early retirement program.</p>
<p>In addition, various initiatives by the schools chancellor will get $30 million, and computers and construction another $14.1 million. And a program to stop drug trafficking around schools will collect $5 million.</p>
<p>The chairman of MAC, Edward Regan, noted that the  board had forced the city to promise not to take advantage of the windfall by starting recurring programs because it was concerned about big outyear gaps in its budget, which total $2 billion in fiscal 1999 and $3 billion in 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;These are pilot programs and one-time initiatives,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>When pressed on this point, Regan added: &quot;If I thought these pilot programs and initiatives were going to generate the need for future expenditures, I would ask them to do something else.&quot;</p>
<p>MAC officials noted the city still was free to find other sources of funds if it wished to keep the new programs in place.</p>
<p>While the chairman said the city's near-term budget appeared to be in good shape, he noted that debt service would spike up over the next year or two under the Giuliani Administration's financial plan.</p>
<p>Though Quentin Spector, MAC's executive director, said the city, which last year promised the board it would cut spending by $125 million each year for the next four years, needs to come up with another $50 million of reductions, he did not foresee any difficulty.</p>
<p>He noted the Giuliani Administration successfully dealt with the same $50 million problem last year.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see any need for the board to have concern about the city's failure to comply,&quot; said Quentin Spector, MAC's executive director.</p>
<p>The city's budget director made a point of noting that the Giuliani Administration, which has seen revenues rise sharply as strong equities markets pumped up profits at Wall Street's banks and brokerages, was basing its over $31 billion budget for 1998 on conservative estimates for this sector.</p>
<p>Lhota also promised MAC that the city would provide $250 million of funds for the Metropolitan Transportation Authority, a need the corporation had filled.</p>
<p>He added the state legislature next Wednesday was expected to vote on a pact to give the city, which is forecast to hit its debt cap before the end of its 1997 fiscal year on June 30, a new financing arm, the New York City Transitional Finance Authority. The Authority will be able to sell up to $7.5 billion of bonds over the next four years.</p>
<p>((--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
