<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39503" id="root" date="1996-09-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MOTOR RACING-VASSER TAKES INDYCAR TITLE AS ZANARDI WINS RACE.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-VASSER TAKES INDYCAR TITLE AS ZANARDI WINS RACE.</headline>
<dateline>MONTEREY, California 1996-09-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jimmy Vasser won the IndyCar series championship and his teammate Alex Zanardi of Italy made a dramatic pass on the last lap of the Grand Prix of Monterey to win the last race of the season Sunday.</p>
<p>Three turns from the end of the race, Zanardi, like Vasser a member of the Chip Ganassi team and driving a Honda-powered Reynard, took advantage of a conservative turn by leader Bryan Herta.</p>
<p>Zanardi daringly passed wide, and the momentum of the pass carried him over a curb, across a small sandpit and back onto the raceway ahead of Herta's Mercedes-powered Reynard.</p>
<p>&quot;The only reason I tried that manoeuvre was that I knew in that particular point it was impossible to overtake, so it came as a surprise,&quot; said Zanardi.</p>
<p>Vasser, 30, finished fourth in the 83-lap race to win his first championship. Vasser needed a finish of fifth or better to clinch the PPG IndyCar World Series title no matter what closest competitors Michael Andretti and Al Unser Jr did.</p>
<p>Both Unser and Andretti fell off the pace midway through the race, and Vasser cruised to the points championship. Andretti finished ninth and Unser 16th in the race.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the best day of my racing career,&quot; said Vasser, who earned a $1 million bonus for the championship and earlier this year won the U.S. 500 in Michigan, also worth a million dollars.</p>
<p>&quot;To win the championship was our goal coming in.  The whole team deserves it.&quot;</p>
<p>Zanardi broke Herta's heart for the second day in a row. He took the pole away from Herta on the last lap of qualifying Saturday, and stole victory from the 26-year-old racer about a mile and a half (2.5 km) from what would have been Herta's first IndyCar win.</p>
<p>&quot;I just didn't finish the job,&quot; said Herta, who crossed the finish line 1.412 seconds behind Zanardi.</p>
<p>&quot;Alex made a move I don't think he could've done twice in his lifetime, but he did it once and he did a great job. He was so far back I didn't think he was going to even try it. It couldn't have been any closer.&quot;</p>
<p>Zanardi jumped into the lead right at the start, and sat out front until the 42nd lap when blistering problems with his Firestone tires forced him to let Herta zip right past him.</p>
<p>Vasser, meanwhile, vaulted from sixth into third.</p>
<p>The pair of red Chip Ganassi team racers held on to second and third positions while Herta led. After the final set of pit stops, Zanardi and Vasser both stepped up their performance, but Herta seemed to still have the race in hand.</p>
<p>Zanardi pulled away from Vasser and closed on Herta, setting up his final move.</p>
<p>&quot;I have to give credit to Bryan. Today he was a very tough guy to beat,&quot; said the 29-year-old Zanardi, who came to IndyCar after making 25 career Formula One starts.</p>
<p>&quot;I was a little bit demoralised on the last laps, but then I saw that on the last lap he was driving a little more carefully maybe, and as we came out to the previous corner I realised that it was possible to outrun the guy.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a point where you never look in your mirror so I knew I was going to surprise him because the circuit is curved and it goes up and down. I knew he couldn't see where I was, and on the previous lap I was far behind.</p>
<p>&quot;It was very risky but it worked.&quot;</p>
<p>While the leaders had their excitement up front, Scott Pruett stole third place from Vasser, who ended the season with 154 points, 22 ahead of Andretti.</p>
<p>&quot;I was cruising early on just to take care of the car, and then I could see that Al (Unser) and Michael (Andretti) were having problems and they were in no position (to challenge),&quot; said Vasser.</p>
<p>&quot;I was a little bummed out that Pruett got around me, but hey it's the championship.&quot;</p>
<p>Herta's runner-up finish equalled his career best, earlier this year in the Marlboro 500 at Michigan and in 1995 at the Grand Prix of Cleveland.</p>
<p>Herta and Zanardi led 41 laps each, while averaging 102.687 miles per hour (165.254 kph) over the 186-mile (299 km) event -- 83 laps at the 2.238-mile (3.602 km), 11-turn Laguna Seca Raceway.</p>
<p>The championship was the first for Chip Ganassi racing, which is partly owned by former National Football League star quarterback Joe Montana.</p>
<p>Vasser, a native of northern California, won four of the first six races this year -- his first IndyCar victories.</p>
<p>Zanardi, who finished the season with 132 points but in third place because Andretti had more victories, took top rookie honours. He also led the series by earning the pole position five times.</p>
<p>Honda won the IndyCar Manufacturer's Championship while Reynard took the constructors title and the United States won the Nation's Cup.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTEREY, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
