<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="395181" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek bull drives equities 2.03pct higher.</title>
<headline>Greek bull drives equities 2.03pct higher.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Banks and construction shares led the Athens bourse 2.03 percent higher on Friday on heavy volume as the bull run continued strong after the market pierced the 1300 resistance level on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in a bull market, it's as simple as that. In bull markets you invest and sit on your position, you don't trade them,&quot; commented Xiosbank's portfolio strategist Stathis Nazos.</p>
<p>His view that the market's fast rise this year has left a lot of people underinvested in equities was shared by other market watchers.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of people were out of the market and now whoever wants to buy has to pay up. That's how bull markets behave. Longer term players should not worry even if we see a correction. They should not fear this market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Fixed-income investors, long accustomed to attractive yields, are now realising that returns on government debt paper are quite lower with yields barely in double digit territory while earned interest is also taxed at 7.5 percent.</p>
<p>This had led to a reappraisal and a reallocation of portfolios into equities, brokers say.</p>
<p>Construction shares led the advance on Friday, warming to strong expectations that Athens will be among the candidate cities to host the 2004 Olympic Games. They jumped 4.96 percent.</p>
<p>The International Olympic Committee (IOC) gave a favourable review to Athens' bid to host the games. It will shortlist four to five cities in early March and announce its final decision in September.</p>
<p>Bank shares, the market's locomotive so far, also dashed higher, gaining 2.60 percent followed by industrials which settled 1.27 percent higher. Small-caps were also spirited and gained 1.43 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Construction is reacting to positive expectations on Athens' successful candidacy to host the 2004 Olympic Games,&quot; the strategist said.</p>
<p>National Bank of Greece which gained 795 drachmas said its fiscal 1996 profit before taxes and provisions rose 14.2 percent to 61.4 billion drachmas. It settled at 26,600 drachmas.</p>
<p>The Athens general share index settled 2.03 percent or 26.47 points higher at 1332.93 points from Thursday's 1306.46, after opening at 1314.66. The session's high was at 1335.39 points.</p>
<p>Turnover rose to 23.1 billion drachmas on volume of 6.6 million shares. Advancers led decliners 165 to 73 with 21 issues unchanged.</p>
<p>The Merrill Lynch call spread warrant on OTE with a strike price of 3,800 drachmas was quoted at 998.00-1016.00. Shares of OTE telecom the underlying, gained 85 drachmas to close at 5,950.</p>
<p>The recently launched ING Baring Financial Products American style call warrant based on a basket of six bank stocks was quoted higher at $43.93-$45.68. The strike price is set at $99.60 and the warrants expire October 8, 1997.</p>
<p>The Morgan Stanley Hellenic Blue Chip Warrant, which has a strike price of 100 marks, was quoted higher at 11,630-12,250 drachmas.</p>
<p>--George Georgiopouloas, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
