<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="395197" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Danish Conservative boss quits in drink-drive case.</title>
<headline>Danish Conservative boss quits in drink-drive case.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish Conservative leader Hans Engell resigned as party chairman on Friday after a car accident in which his blood-alcohol level was found to be well over the legal limit.</p>
<p>&quot;I have committed a serious mistake and must take the consequences. We stand ahead of a decisive political period with several elections ahead and there must be no doubt regarding the party's prime ministerial candidate,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>Although his Conservatives command less electoral support than the main opposition Liberals, Engell was considered a contender to lead a coalition government as did Conservative Poul Schlueter under similar circumstances from 1982 to 1993.</p>
<p>Local authority polls are scheduled for November this year, and general elections by September 1998. Current opinion polls tip a Liberal-Conservative alliance as likely to oust the incumbent Social Democrat-led coalition.</p>
<p>Engell veered off a motorway north of the capital and hit a lamp post on Wednesday night while driving his Mazda 626 car. He was unhurt.</p>
<p>He reported the accident to police and a test showed him to have a blood alcohol content (BAC) of 1.37. The legal limit is 0.8 and is shortly to be lowered to 0.5. The test measures the units of alcohol per 1,000 units of blood.</p>
<p>A former journalist, Engell was defence minister from 1982-87 and justice minister from 1989-93.</p>
<p>The statement said that Engell would remain chairman of the parliamentary Conservative group but a new party leader would be chosen.</p>
<p>A likely candidate to replace him could be Anne Birgitte Lundholdt, the party's political spokeswoman and a former energy and industry minister.</p>
<p>Ex-fisheries minister Henning Grove's position as party vice-chairman did not make him a leading contender for the top job. &quot;It's just on paper,&quot; a party official told Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
