<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="395411" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian biscuit-maker dumps stock.</title>
<headline>Australian biscuit-maker dumps stock.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's biggest biscuit-maker, Arnotts Ltd, began dumping millions of packets of biscuits on Friday after an extortion threat that forced the company to withdraw its stock from supermarkets.</p>
<p>Arnotts said it believed none of the packets, removed from retail shelves in the eastern states of Queensland and New South Wales, were contaminated, but said it wanted to be &quot;ultra-safe&quot;.</p>
<p>Much of the stock dumped at an outer Sydney dump had also been damaged when it was hastily cleared last Friday after news of the threat to plant poisoned Arnotts biscuits in shops was revealed, the company said.</p>
<p>Arnotts managing director Chris Roberts said no returned stock would be sent back to shops.</p>
<p>&quot;Only new stock will go onto the shelves...when the company believes it is appropriate to do so,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>Police earlier this week called on the extortionist to contact them by next Monday or they would consider the threat ended.</p>
<p>The extortionist threatened to poison biscuits made by Arnotts unless police involved in a 1991 murder case took a lie detector test.</p>
<p>The extortionist said police lied in giving evidence that resulted in Ron Thomas serving two life sentences for a double shooting murder he did not commit.</p>
<p>Thomas, who says he is innocent, has issued a letter from jail calling on the extortionist to stop his bid to free him. &quot;I want everyone to know that I had no part in these threats,&quot; Thomas said.</p>
<p>Arnotts, a 70 percent-owned subsidiary of U.S. food giant Campbell Soup Co, said it would lose A$5.0 million (US$3.8 million) a week in sales and has suspended a few hundred casual staff.</p>
<p>The New South Wales and Queensland state governments have offered a combined A$100,000 reward for the capture of the extortionist.</p>
<p>(A$1 = US$0.76)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
