<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="395488" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Deng's open door policy led HK into China.</title>
<headline>Deng's open door policy led HK into China.</headline>
<byline>Kathleen Kearney</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deng Xiaoping's open-door economic policy brought riches not only to China but to Hong Kong, and tied the two inextricably together long before the British colony's political reversion to its neighbour this year.</p>
<p>&quot;No (foreign) economy was better positioned than Hong Kong to capitalise on the market opening that Deng achieved,&quot; said David Dodwell, director of Jardine Fleming Holdings Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;Deng's initiatives, his successful liberalising of China's economy provided immense opportunities for all businesses,&quot; said Dodwell.</p>
<p>The late Chinese patriarch's reforms launched in 1979 opened China to foreign investment, and Hong Kong, on the doorstep of southern Guangdong province, was at the head of the queue.</p>
<p>And when Hong Kong's economy was ready to burst the seams of the tiny territory in the mid 1980s, the reforms across the border allowed growing industries to find ample labour and land in its giant neighbour.</p>
<p>For many Hong Kong manufacturers which moved production across the border, this meant a swift expansion of their workforce, said Professor Yiu-Kwan Fan, dean of the School of Business at Hong Kong Baptist University.</p>
<p>&quot;Over a short period of a few years, we are talking about 80 percent of the manufacturing processes moving to China.&quot;</p>
<p>As a result, manufacturing's contribution to Hong Kong gross domestic product fell to less than 10 percent at the end of 1994 from a hefty 23.7 percent in 1980, said Fan.</p>
<p>In contrast, trade-related services in Hong Kong boomed as raw and semi-finished materials poured through the territory to China, and finished goods poured out. In 1996, some 90 percent Hong Kong's re-exports of HK$1.19 trillion (US$128.2 billion) involved China.</p>
<p>In another illustration of the intertwining of ties, 54 percent of outgoing international telephone calls in the year to March 1996 from Hong Kong went to China.</p>
<p>Hong Kong is now China's largest foreign investor.</p>
<p>By 1995, Hong Kong contributed a cumulative total of US$20.19 billion in investment, more than 50 percent of the total. More than 100,000 joint ventures in China are funded with Hong Kong capital.</p>
<p>Isolating China's contribution to Hong Kong's domestic economy was difficult since the territory does not restrict capital flows, but it was considerable, said George Leung, economic adviser at the Hongkong and Shanghai Banking Corp Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;PRC (People's Republic of China) investment in Hong Kong is estimated at US$20 billion by some sources,&quot; Leung said.</p>
<p>China's profile is rising. China-related companies are rushing to list on the Hong Kong stock market and buy high-profile office blocks which they emblazen with their names. Hong Kong's economy now booms in line with China's.</p>
<p>&quot;One can only look at the indirect evidence, the contribution to the growth of the service sector, the consumer wealth created, the number of cars on our roads,&quot; said Fan.</p>
<p>But Deng's contribution was more than just economic.</p>
<p>&quot;The economic reform programmes were only possible because of the political stability in China, because there were no upheavals except for four weeks in May and June 1989,&quot; said Dave O'Rear, regional economist at The Economist Conferences.</p>
<p>Deng sent in the tanks to quash the student-led pro-democracy movement around Tiananmen Square in June 1989.</p>
<p>&quot;Deng's greatest contribution is that he kept a very stable and prosperous China going for a long enough period of time that the issue of (the handover of Hong Kong to China in) 1997 could be dealt with by a China not in turmoil,&quot; said O'Rear.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
