<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="395501" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia rubber ends lower, tracks Tokyo's fall.</title>
<headline>Malaysia rubber ends lower, tracks Tokyo's fall.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian rubber prices extended losses at the close following a weak trend in Tokyo and continued absence of consumer demand, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's nothing new in the market. Buyers are not coming in while sellers are also in no hurry to sell,&quot; said one trader. &quot;The paper market may come off further if Tokyo stays weak.&quot;</p>
<p>He said some dealers were away celebrating the last day of the Chinese Lunar New Year festival.</p>
<p>Traders said physical prices have been flat as producers were holding back in anticipation of tighter supply during the wintering period.  </p>
<p>At the close, benchmark March RSS1 buyer was quoted by the Malaysian Rubber Exchange and Licensing Board at 303 cents ($1.22) a kg, down a cent from Thursday.</p>
<p>March SMR 20 buyer was down two cents at 296 cents ($1.19).</p>
<p>Trading houses offered the SMR 20 at 297 cents a kg, SMR CV at 359, SMR L at 339, SMR 5 at 307, SMR 10 at 298 and drum latex FOB at 237.</p>
<p>The INRO five-day moving average was 234.42 Malaysian/Singapore cents per kg on Feb 20 against 234.72 on Feb 19. The daily indicator price was 234.10 versus 234.35.</p>
<p>-- Syed Azman (603-230 8911) ($1=2.4830 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
