<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="395564" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: China defence chief visits Indonesia despite Deng.</title>
<headline>China defence chief visits Indonesia despite Deng.</headline>
<byline>Lewa Pardomuan</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chinese Defence Minister Chi Haotian met Indonesian Vice-President Try Sutrisno and defence officials on Friday on what Asian diplomats saw as a visit to build better ties with Southeast Asian nations.</p>
<p>The death of China's paramount leader Deng Xiaoping compelled him to cut his five-day visit short by one day, an Indonesian Defence Ministry spokesman said. Chi would leave on Monday to attend the funeral the following day, he said.</p>
<p>This meant Chi would miss a meeting with Indonesia's President Suharto scheduled for Tuesday following Suharto's return from state visits to Cambodia, Laos and Burma.</p>
<p>Chi instead paid a courtesy call on Sutrisno, who visited China when armed forces commander in 1992. Details of their talks were not immediately known.</p>
<p>Chi said on his arrival on Thursday that Beijing was willing to develop lasting relations with Indonesia and promote peace and stability in the Asia-Pacific region.</p>
<p>&quot;I think this is part of a whole process of building a better understanding with all ASEAN countries, including Indonesia,&quot; a senior Asian diplomat told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea is to build more confidence and reduce the threat perception towards China,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>China's sovereignty claims in the South China Sea and confrontations with other claimants of potentially oil-rich islands in the area has caused unease in the region.</p>
<p>But Beijing has also sought to allay concerns among the seven members of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN), stressing dialogue rather than confrontation.</p>
<p>ASEAN comprises Indonesia, Philippines, Vietnam, Thailand, Brunei, Singapore and Malaysia.</p>
<p>Diplomatic sources saw nothing strange in Chi continuing his Indonesia visit despite the death of Deng. The Chinese leader died from respiratory failure on Wednesday aged 92.</p>
<p>&quot;Deng's death was not a totally unexpected thing. The groundwork and preparations were already in place. There was no need for Chi to rush back in that sense,&quot; a diplomat said.</p>
<p>An Indonesian Defence Ministry spokesman told Reuters Chi would visit the holiday island of Bali for a day of relaxation and the military academy in Magelang, central Java.</p>
<p>Indonesia resumed diplomatic ties with China only in 1990 after severing them following a 1965 coup attempt blamed on the Indonesian Communist Party (PKI), which is still officially banned.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
