<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="395779" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Holding firms no saviour for Japan banks - analysts.</title>
<headline>Holding firms no saviour for Japan banks - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Fumiko Fujisaki</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's top banks are touting a plan to lift a 50-year-old ban on holding companies as the cure for what ails their industry, but analysts say it will take more than that to solve their problems.</p>
<p>&quot;We doubt that a simple change in ownership structure will result in aggressive restructuring of financial institutions,&quot; said Kathy Matsui, a strategist at Goldman Sachs (Japan).</p>
<p>She said restructuring was dependent on the will of managements, and it was doubtful if holding companies alone would spur the necessary changes in the troubled industry.</p>
<p>The banks, groaning under massive bad loan problems, fear that Japan's &quot;Big Bang&quot; reforms will lead to a bloodletting that could end in the collapse of financial institutions which are in poor financial health.</p>
<p>Many bank officials see the holding company route as the key to coping with the reforms, which are designed to liberalise the nation's financial markets by 2001.</p>
<p>Under a holding company, barriers between banks, brokers and insurers could be broken down and major banks could streamline their financial groups and bail out weaker affiliates.</p>
<p>The umbrella companies would also allow huge, inefficient corporate giants to split into several leaner operations.</p>
<p>But most analysts are unconvinced about the banking industry's willingness to tackle large-scale streamlining.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has been becoming more critical of Japanese banks in the past one or two months as they have delayed their disclosure of problem loans,&quot; said Yushiro Ikuyo, a first vice-president at Smith Barney International.</p>
<p>Banks still appear to be hoping for a soft landing scenario and they lack a sense of crisis control, Ikuyo said.</p>
<p>Bankers, meanwhile, say they need a freer hand to establish financial holding companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Concern is growing about Japanese banks' declining international competitiveness, so I would like (the government) to make sure that nothing will be done to reduce the effectiveness of holding companies,&quot; Shunsaku Hashimoto, the chairman of the Federation of Bankers' Associations of Japan, told reporters this week.</p>
<p>If all goes as planned, Japan will overturn the ban next year. It was imposed by U.S. Occupation forces five decades ago to break up powerful conglomerates known as &quot;zaibatsu&quot;.</p>
<p>Japan's ruling Liberal Democratic Party and its policy partners are in last-ditch talks on to issue, and if they agree the government will submit a bill to parliament in March.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry has also begun to work out necessary revisions in financial laws to enable the establishment of financial holding firms.</p>
<p>The corporate structure of a holding company will also make it easier and less costly to combine poorer-performing banks than a corporate merger, banking officials said.</p>
<p>In a merger, Japanese banks find it difficult to smooth relations between two distinct corporate cultures, and layoffs are also hard to justify when two banks merge, they said.</p>
<p>A holding company system would also allow big city banks to team up with regional banks. Regional markets offer the promise of new business for the big banks, they added.</p>
<p>Katsuhito Sasajima, an analyst at Nikko Research Center, said many banks saw holding companies as a tool to give them greater management flexibility. &quot;I expect big commercial banks will benefit most from holding companies,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts and bankers say, however, that there are a number of obstacles involving tax, commercial and securities rules which must be addressed before holding companies can be practically implemented.</p>
<p>Unless Japan introduces a new corporate tax system in which tax is calculated based on the combined profits or losses of group companies, there will not be many cost benefits in setting up a holding company, they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
