<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="395795" id="root" date="1997-02-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Asian naphtha remains firm despite bearish factors.</title>
<headline>Asian naphtha remains firm despite bearish factors.</headline>
<byline>Kiyoshi Takenaka</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian naphtha prices, buoyed by brisk regional demand, have been holding steady despite ethylene output cuts in Japan and recent losses in crude prices, traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>Global crude oil prices have fallen more than 10 percent since the beginning of this year, while near-term naphtha prices on Asia's benchmark open-specification forward contract slipped only about three percent over the same period in dollar terms.</p>
<p>Naphtha prices in Asia usually synchronise with crude oil value, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Naphtha (prices) has lately been out of line with crude prices,&quot; Akio Kosai, vice chairman of the Japan Petrochemical Industry Association told a news conference earlier this week.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very much concerned about this situation,&quot; said Kosai, also president of Sumitomo Chemical Co Ltd.</p>
<p>Higher naphtha prices have squeezed profit margins for petrochemical firms, which use naphtha to manufacture ethylene and other basic petrochemical products.</p>
<p>Most Japanese petrochemical firms have formed their budget for the second-half of fiscal 1996, which started last October, based on the assumption that naphtha prices would average around 16,000 yen per kilolitre (kl).</p>
<p>However, naphtha import prices have hovered well above the 19,000-yen-per-kl level since mid-November.</p>
<p>In an effort to cool down bullish regional naphtha markets, several petrochemical firms in Japan have slashed their ethylene production.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi Chemical Corp, Japan's largest petrochemical firm with an annual ethylene production capacity of 1.45 million tonnes, has cut its ethylene output by 10 percent since January.</p>
<p>Showa Denko KK has lowered its ethylene output by a few percent at its 735,000-tonne-per-year Oita plant, and Idemitsu Petrochemical Co Ltd earlier this week said it had cut ethylene production at its Chiba plant, with an output capacity of 365,000 tonnes a year, by 12 percent.</p>
<p>However, the production cuts, just like crude losses, had little impact on naphtha prices.</p>
<p>Market participants said strength in regional naphtha was derived from physical tightness as well as expectations of an even tighter supply and demand balance in the coming years, with petrochemical plants springing up in the region.</p>
<p>Petrochemical Corp of Singapore (SPC), the city state's sole ethylene producer, plans to put its 515,000-tonne-per-year ethylene plant on line in April.</p>
<p>The new facility will bring the firm's total production capacity to 965,000 tonnes a year.</p>
<p>Thailand's ethylene output capacity is expected to grow by 350,000 tonnes a year to about 1.1 million tonnes when Thai Petrochemical Industry Plc starts up a new plant this spring.</p>
<p>In Taiwan, Formosa Petrochemical Corp is planning to start up a new plant early next year.</p>
<p>&quot;Downward pressure from output cuts might kick in later,&quot; one naphtha trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;But underlying naphtha sentiment is expected to remain strong, supported by ever-increasing physical demand,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
