<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39585" id="root" date="1996-09-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: ATHLETICS-STARS LIKELY TO IGNORE PLEA TO COMPETE IN SARAJEVO.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-STARS LIKELY TO IGNORE PLEA TO COMPETE IN SARAJEVO.</headline>
<byline>Mike Collett</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Many of the world's top athletes are likely to ignore pleas to take part in an international meeting in the war-torn Bosnian capital of Sarajevo on Monday.</p>
<p>Despite a request to elite athletes from Primo Nebiolo, president of the International Amateur Athletic Federation, who together with the International Olympic Committee have organised the Solidarity Meeting for Sarajevo, only about 50 are expected to compete.</p>
<p>IAAF officials were putting a brave face on matters on Sunday before a specially chartered plane left Milan, the venue of Saturday's final Grand Prix meeting, for the 90-minute flight to Sarajevo, venue of the 1984 Winter Olympics.</p>
<p>The meet will be held at the Kosevo Stadium, stage for the opening and closing ceremonies of those Games 12 years ago but which was extensively damaged during the four years of the Bosnian war when it was used as an army base.</p>
<p>Although the former restaurant in the stadium is now an empty shell, the electronic scoreboard has been destroyed and the floodlight pylons out of operation, a new track has been laid and between them the IAAF and the IOC have provided $1.5 million to start the long job of restoring the stadium to its former glory.</p>
<p>Nebiolo, IOC president Juan Antonio Samaranch and Bosnia-Herzegovina President Alija Izetbegovic will be present at Monday's event which is regarded as having an important political and social significance by the IAAF.</p>
<p>In an official statement the IAAF said: &quot;(We), in conjunction with the IOC, are deeply committed to this meeting for peace in a city which has become a symbol of suffering.&quot;</p>
<p>And in a letter to the sport's top names, Nebiolo said: &quot;In order to promote the humanitarian aspect of this event, and the virtue of promoting peace in Bosnia, we are asking all the athletes to forego any appearance fees or prize monies which would normally be considered.&quot;</p>
<p>With no entry charge being made, a capacity crowd of 50,000 is expected for what the IAAF and IOC hope will be the biggest sports meeting in Bosnia, not only since the end of hostilities but also since the 1984 Winter games.</p>
<p>But while mainly eastern European and African athletes such as Olympic 1,500 metres champion Noureddine Morceli of Algeria and Daniel Komen of Kenya, who set a world 3,000 metres record last weekend and won the men's overall grand prix title on Saturday, have pledged themselves to the meeting, many others have not.</p>
<p>American Dennis Mitchell, the American 100 metres champion and a 100 metre finalist at the Olympics last month, said he was staying away because he feared for his safety.</p>
<p>&quot;Although track and field is my life, it's not worth my life,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't believe it is safe for me to go there and a few other athletes feel the same way. I would like to one day, but I have talked this over with my family and we have decided it would not be good for me to run.&quot;</p>
<p>A senior IAAF source indicated before the charter left on Sunday he expected around 50 athletes to be on the plane, part of an unprecedented &quot;athletics airlift&quot; organised to enable the meeting to take place.</p>
<p>Three Italian military airbuses will carry equipment to Sarajevo including a portable video screen and timing equipment, while the Italian parachure regiment Fulgore, currently serving with the I-FOR peace-keeping force, will take responsibilty for the athletes, journalists and officials making the trip.</p>
<p>The meeting will start at 1445 (1245 gmt) local time with a short opening ceremony and 16 events are due to take place in a packed two-hour programme.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
