<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39588" id="root" date="1996-09-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIA AVIATION DISPUTE DELAYS INTNL AIR TRAFFIC.</title>
<headline>BULGARIA AVIATION DISPUTE DELAYS INTNL AIR TRAFFIC.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-09-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Failure to resolve a wage dispute between Bulgaria's association of air traffic controllers (Bulatca) and employers has produced up to 90 minutes delay of overflying traffic, officials said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;Latest information from Eurocontrol in Burussels is that delays were between 30 minutes to 90 minutes per flight overflying Bulgarian aerospace,&quot; president of the International Federation of Air Traffic Controllers Association (IFATCA) Preben Lauridsen told a news conference.</p>
<p>On Friday some 40 air traffic controllers were fired on the grounds that they refused to do their job after a local court ruled that their strike planned for last week was illegal.</p>
<p>The controllers demanded their monthly wage be increased from some $230 to some $1,000 per month, as well as the resignation of the air traffic service's management.</p>
<p>They also demanded the financial separation of the 350 air controllers from the technical staff.</p>
<p>The air traffic service director general Valentin Valkov said their claims were immoral and that despite the court's ruling traffic controllers at airports in Sofia, Varna and Bourgas did not show up at work regularly simulating sickness.</p>
<p>They were replaced by their chiefs and air traffic control instructors.</p>
<p>Overflying capacity was halved to 700 flights daily, from the usual 1,500. But these steps did not help overcome delays caused by understaffing.</p>
<p>&quot;This cost the airlines millions of dollars. By not having the on-route charges paid to the Bulgarian state, this country is also loosing money day afer day,&quot; said Lauridsen.</p>
<p>Although Valkov said on Friday that air traffic in Bulgaria was not endangered, Lauridsen said that IFATCA was concerned about the safety of all planes flying transit or landing and taking off.</p>
<p>IFATCA representatives arrived in Sofia to mediate a dialogue between Bulatca and their employer, the transport ministry.</p>
<p>On Saturday Transport Minister Stamen Stamenov said he would begin negotiations after the traffic controllers go back to work. -- Elisaveta Konstantinova, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
