<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396088" id="root" date="1997-02-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: NORDIC SKIING-COOL AHONEN WINS SKI JUMPING GOLD.</title>
<headline>NORDIC SKIING-COOL AHONEN WINS SKI JUMPING GOLD.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Vignal</byline>
<dateline>TRONDHEIM, Norway 1997-02-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finn Janne Ahonen kept his cool in miserable weather to recover from a modest first jump and win gold in the normal hill ski jumping event of the Nordic skiing world championships on Saturday.</p>
<p>The 19-year-old from Lahti, only eighth after a first effort of 95 metres, braved light snow and changing winds to land at 98.5 metres in his second jump and score a winning total of 263.5 points.</p>
<p>&quot;I wasn't expecting anything after my first jump but I had no pressure either and that probably explains why the second jump was so good,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ahonen had to wait for the seven skiers who had outjumped him in the first round to perform their second jump before celebrating.</p>
<p>&quot;The jump was easy, it was the waiting after it that was tough,&quot; he explained.</p>
<p>Masahiko Harada, the 1993 world champion, showed plenty of consistency with a first jump at 99 metres and a second one at 98 metres to take second place with 258.5 points.</p>
<p>&quot;This will boost my condidence ahead of Nagano,&quot; he said, his mind already on next year's Winter Olympics in Japan.</p>
<p>Austrian Andreas Goldberger's best jump was 96 metres but his faultless technique earned him the bronze medal with 257 points.</p>
<p>&quot;I would have preferred gold but there are two events left,&quot; said Goldberger, referring to the high hill and the team competitions.</p>
<p>The 30,000 fans shaking cowbells and waving Norwegian flags who lined the 90-metre hill were in high spirits after Espen Bredesen jumped 98 metres in the first round to lead the provisional standings.</p>
<p>But a disappointing second jump of 86.5 left the Norwegian in 15th place.</p>
<p>There was disappointment, too, for German Dieter Thoma, second to Bredesen after the first jump.</p>
<p>He launched himself  99 metres second time around but after landing he fell on his back, forcing the judges to give him low points. He finished 22nd.</p>
<p>&quot;He was so fast, perhaps a little too fast,&quot; said Ahonen. &quot;I feel sorry for him.&quot;</p>
<p>Slovenian teenager Primoz Peterka, who won the coveted Four Hills tournament last month and leads the World Cup, failed to make the second round after an opening jump of 89 metres.</p>
<p>Earlier, Ahonen's compatriot had taken the lead in the Nordic combined event after the ski jumping.</p>
<p>A first effort at 90.5 and a second one of 90 left Lajunen out in front before Sunday's second part of the competition, the 15-km freestyle cross-country race.</p>
<p>Experienced Japanese Kenji Ogiwara, the 1993 world champion, was a close second after jumps of 87.5 and 90.</p>
<p>Lajunen had 234.5 points compared to Ogiwara's 232. German Jens Deimel, more at ease in ski jumping than in cross-country, was third on 227.5.</p>
<p>Norway's Bjarte Engen Vik jumped 96 metres, the day's best mark, in the second round to climb to fourth place.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TRONDHEIM, Norway"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
