<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396161" id="root" date="1997-02-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian Socialist dissidents form new movement.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian Socialist dissidents form new movement.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-02-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Defectors from Bulgaria's former ruling party joined other leftist organisations on Saturday for the founding forum of the Euro-Left movement, set up as a rival to the discredited Bulgarian Socialist Party.</p>
<p>Some 3,000 delegates, many of them young people and students, elected a 20-member leadership including three former Socialist deputies.</p>
<p>The Euro-Left will be led by liberal Marxist Alexander Tomov, who came fourth in presidential elections last November.</p>
<p>&quot;Our main aim is to unite all those who want a true social democratic formation in Bulgaria,&quot; Tomov said in his opening speech.</p>
<p>&quot;The failure of the cabinet of (former Socialist prime minister) Zhan Videnov is not only the failure of its policy but also the failure of cohabitation between social democracy and neocommunism.&quot;</p>
<p>The Socialists, who include many former communists who renamed the party after the end of one-party rule in 1989, gave in to demands for general elections earlier this month after 30 days of mass protests.</p>
<p>Elections are due on April 19, giving the new movement just two months to mobilise enough support to poll at least the four percent minimum for entering parliament.</p>
<p>Tomov said the Euro-Left aimed to bring together his own Civil Alliance for the Republic, Socialist dissidents and smaller social democratic parties, and wanted to reform and restructure the economy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
