<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396327" id="root" date="1997-02-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N. report weighs effects of air embargo on Sudan.</title>
<headline>U.N. report weighs effects of air embargo on Sudan.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Goodman</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-02-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.N. air embargo against Sudan could affect food production, patients seeking treatment abroad and the distribution of medicines, but should not hamper food aid, a U.N. report said on Friday.</p>
<p>The report, on the possible humanitarian impact of such an air embargo, was requested by the Security Council in December, four months after it voted to impose a ban on flights abroad by Sudanese aircraft but postponed setting a date for it to go into effect.</p>
<p>The ban was to punish Sudan for failing to extradite to Ethiopia three men accused of trying to assassinate Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak during a visit to Addis Ababa on June 26, 1995. Sudan has repeatedly said it has found no trace of the wanted men.</p>
<p>Mandatory diplomatic sanctions and a travel ban on senior Sudanese government and army officials have been in force since last May.</p>
<p>The report on the effects of an air embargo said: &quot;From this review, it appears that the imposition of the flight ban envisaged in SCR (Security Council Resolution) 1070 (1996) will impair the capacity of the public health authorities to facilitate patients' receiving specialised medical treatment outside the country.&quot;</p>
<p>It quoted the Sudanese Health Ministry as saying about 3,000 patients a year required medical evacuations.</p>
<p>The report also said domestic air transport could be affected by a ban on flights abroad since the same airlines &quot;rely on international access for their maintenance and economic viability.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Considering the dependence of domestic air carriers on offshore maintenance capacities, a flight ban could have a serious impact on immunisation programmes nationwide, domestic distribution of drugs, and on food production,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Regarding food relief operations in Sudan, where a civil war has long been raging, it said &quot;it appears that emergency food assistance in government-controlled areas in the south, with the exception of Wau and Juba, does not substantially rely on domestic air transport.&quot;</p>
<p>Most of the food there was provided by the U.N.-coordinated Operation Lifeline Sudan and was either delivered by air from Kenya, using aircraft registered outside Sudan, or by road and river.</p>
<p>&quot;The supply of food assistance, in the present circumstances, should not be affected by the flight ban. However, the logistics of the assistance providers such as WFP (the U.N. World Food Program) could be affected by the flight ban since they use domestic air carriers for the transport of equipment and personnel,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Regarding non-food assistance, it said a flight ban might hinder large aid providers such as the U.N. Children's Fund (UNICEF) and international non-governmental organisations by causing the suspension of operations until further financial arrangements were made to allow them to function independently of domestic air carriers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
