<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396585" id="root" date="1997-02-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Chechen leader reaffirms independence goal.</title>
<headline>Chechen leader reaffirms independence goal.</headline>
<dateline>GROZNY, Russia 1997-02-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chechen President Aslan Maskhadov renewed his pledge to win independence from Russia on Sunday in a speech marking the 53rd anniversary of Stalin's deportation of the entire Chechen nation during World War Two.</p>
<p>&quot;I fully intend building an independent state,&quot; Maskhadov, who was elected a month ago, told a crowd of several hundred at a recently rebuilt memorial to the victims of the deporation in the war-ravaged Chechen capital, Grozny.</p>
<p>Moscow, which pulled out its troops last autumn after a bloody but unsuccessful two-year intervention against separatist rebels, refuses to countenance recognising Chechen sovereignty.</p>
<p>Negotiations are continuing between the two sides. Chechnya needs massive investment to rebuild its economy and housing after the war, which killed tens of thousands. It will have to rely mainly on Moscow as foreign states are unlikely to risk Russia's wrath by recognising Grozny's independence.</p>
<p>Stalin accused the million-strong Chechen nation and other mainly Moslem North Caucasus peoples of aiding the invading German army. He ordered them to be deported en masse in 1944.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands died in transit and on the bleak steppes of Kazakhstan, where they were dumped and forced to fend for themselves. After Stalin's death in 1953, the Chechens were allowed to return home but memories of the deportation are still vivid and helped stiffen resistance to Russia during the war.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GROZNY, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
