<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39662" id="root" date="1996-09-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenyan president pardons repentant guerrillas.</title>
<headline>Kenyan president pardons repentant guerrillas.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-09-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenyan president Daniel arap Moi pardoned two self-confessed guerrillas, who said they had been trained to overthrow his government, when they asked for his forgiveness on Saturday, the Kenyan media reported.</p>
<p>Nairobi newspapers on Sunday reported that Moi surprised a rally, attended by thousands in a stadium at Nakuru, 160 km (100 miles) northwest of Nairobi, when he called on other Kenyans who may have been recruited as guerrillas to give themselves up.</p>
<p>Television viewers saw pictures of the two men, Anthony Njui and Herbert Lusiola, saying they and other Kenyans had been trained as guerrillas in a neighbouring unnamed country with the aim of overthrowing Moi's government.</p>
<p>Both men had earlier been charged in a local court with illegal possession of arms, and were awaiting trial.</p>
<p>Lusiola, who had previously served in the Kenyan army, told the rally he was recruited four years ago by an underground movement and helped to train other recruits.</p>
<p>Witnesses at the rally said the two men were driven away with an escort of security men.</p>
<p>Opposition MP Joseph Kimani, who was at the rally, was quoted by local newspapers as dismissing the incident as a propaganda ploy by Moi's ruling Kenya African National Union (Kanu) party.</p>
<p>Moi has in the past accused Uganda of supporting underground groups operating against his country. But he and Ugandan President Yoweri Museveni recently supported measures to enhance co-operation between countries in the East African region.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
