<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396772" id="root" date="1997-02-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Regulator says Israel stock market still in crisis.</title>
<headline>Regulator says Israel stock market still in crisis.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1997-02-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Israeli stock market has not experienced a real recovery, despite rallying share prices, the chairman of Israel's securities watchdog warned in the authority's annual report released on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;One must be careful that the signs of a re-awakening seen in the bourse recently are not enough to signal an end to the capital markets crisis,&quot; Arie Mientkavich, chairman of the Securities Authority, said in a cover letter to the report.</p>
<p>Sharp increases in share prices, he said, usually indicated problems in the market and not underlying strength.</p>
<p>&quot;When the weight of long-term savings in the capital markets is declining, the problems of institutional investors have not been solved and only a small number of needed measures have been undertaken by the government and other authorities, it is too early to speak about recovery,&quot; Mientkavich said.</p>
<p>Since the start of November, the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange's Mishtanim index has risen about 40 percent following a three-year slump that began in early 1994.</p>
<p>Mientkavich said that among the steps needed to create a &quot;fair and functioning market&quot; were structural changes in the bodies responsible for securities regulation, measures to deconcentrate control of the market and better internal controls among market institutions.</p>
<p>He said the government also had to rethink its practice of issuing high-interest non-tradable bonds to the pension funds.</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
