<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396719" id="root" date="1997-02-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK emigrants' return deadline may be extended - paper.</title>
<headline>HK emigrants' return deadline may be extended - paper.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The July 1 deadline requiring Hong Kong emigrants to return home in order to retain their right of abode may be extended for up to three years, a newspaper reported on Sunday.</p>
<p>British and Chinese officials are understood to be close to a compromise which would avert a potential flood of permanent residents rushing back to meet the deadline ahead of the territory's reversion to Chinese rule at midnight on 30 June, the Sunday Morning Post quoted unidentified sources as saying.</p>
<p>Hong Kong residents with foreign passports have been required to return and settle in the colony before the sovereignty transfer in order to retain the right of abode and access to consular protection under Chinese guidelines.</p>
<p>About 500,000 people have emigrated from Hong Kong over the past 10 years and the government warn tens of thousands could try to return in time for the handover to secure their right of abode. The Joint Liaison Group, a Sino-British diplomatic body handling the handover, has been discussing the length of time Hong Kong people with foreign passports now living overseas can remain outside the territory after the handover without losing permanent residency, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>Those living overseas are expected to be granted a grace period of at least one year after the handover, the newspaper quoted a &quot;well-informed&quot; source as saying.</p>
<p>The source said British officials were pushing for a longer period, while Chinese officials have put forward the one-year time frame, it said.</p>
<p>Negotiations are continuing although Beijing says any decision should be made by the SAR administration, it added.</p>
<p>&quot;It is believed a compromise will be reached, with a period of grace possibly around three years,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>The period will also be the length of time permanent Hong Kong residents, who have made a declaration to be considered foreign nationals, can live outside the territory after their return and retain the right of abode.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
