<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39675" id="root" date="1996-09-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Cheery Yeltsin meets Kohl, aides jostle for power.</title>
<headline>Cheery Yeltsin meets Kohl, aides jostle for power.</headline>
<byline>Alastair Macdonald</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-09-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Boris Yeltsin displayed cheerful confidence in the face of his forthcoming heart operation, chatting and strolling with German Chancellor Helmut Kohl at his hunting lodge near Moscow on Saturday.</p>
<p>But despite his personal friend Kohl's assurance that the Russian president was &quot;fully active&quot; and &quot;very optimistic&quot; about the surgery, senior figures in the Kremlin continue to jockey for advantage in the 65-year-old leader's enforced absence.</p>
<p>In an interview released on Saturday by the German magazine Der Spiegel, his security chief Alexander Lebed conceded some Kremlin insiders may already be positioning themselves for the succession, just two months into Yeltsin's new four-year term.</p>
<p>&quot;You could be quite correct,&quot; he said when asked if the post-Yeltsin era had already begun in Moscow.</p>
<p>Lebed, a 46-year-old ex-general who signed an ambitious peace deal with Chechen separatist rebels last month, is himself a key player in the manoeuvring evident since Yeltsin virtually dropped out of sight before his re-election on July 3 and which stepped up a gear when he confirmed his illness last week.</p>
<p>On Friday, Lebed said it was time for Yeltsin to step aside and let Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin, 58, take over until he recovered.</p>
<p>But Yeltsin's chief-of-staff, Anatoly Chubais, dismissed the idea on Saturday, saying the president was in &quot;normal working condition&quot; and would at most hand over the reins of power to Chernomyrdin for &quot;a couple of days&quot; if the operation went ahead.</p>
<p>Under the constitution, the prime minister takes over temprorarily if the president is incapacitated. But the law does not specify how or by whom that incapacity is determined.</p>
<p>Chubais, a 41-year-old former free-market reform guru, is, with Lebed and Chernomyrdin, one of a powerful trio of rivals whom analysts see at the centre of current Kremlin jostling.</p>
<p>His friends in the west, who were greatly relieved when Yeltsin beat a strong communist challenge in the election, may take comfort from his cheerful and relatively sound demeanour during the meeting with Kohl, his first encounter with a western leader since he retreated from view in late June.</p>
<p>&quot;President Yeltsin was fully active throughout these discussions,&quot; Kohl said. &quot;Of course you can see that he is facing a serious operation. He knows this and talks about it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Boris Yeltsin is very optimistic that this procedure, which is essential...will be successful,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Yeltsin was planning confidently beyond the operation, due at the end of the month in Moscow. He told Kohl he would be back after the surgery to play an active role in settling Russia's dispute with NATO over the western alliance's plans to admit former Soviet-bloc countries in eastern Europe.</p>
<p>He also agreed with Kohl during four-hours of informal talks that included a lunch of wild boar and a stroll around the lodge where he is on holiday that they should get together for a short break next year on Lake Baikal in Siberia.</p>
<p>Russian doctors have said Yeltsin, who had two heart attacks last year, plans a relatively routine bypass operation to relieve clogged arteries around his heart.</p>
<p>But his western allies, who see Yeltsin as the guarantor of stability in Russia's fledgling democracy, will be unsettled by the infighting revealed in stray phrases from the Kremlin and the opinions of independent medical experts who say television footage suggests the president may need more complex treatment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
