<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396789" id="root" date="1997-02-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Saudi shares a fraction firmer in post-Eid trade.</title>
<headline>Saudi shares a fraction firmer in post-Eid trade.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-02-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares on the Saudi stock market were fractionally firmer in post-Eid trading, figures from the Riyadh-based Bakheet Financial Advisors (BFA) showed on Sunday.</p>
<p>The index ended on Thursday at 163.35 points -- up from 163.13 points on February 5, before the Eid al-Fitr holiday marking the end of the Moslem fasting month of Ramadan.</p>
<p>Of the 58 companies traded, 37 rose, 17 fell and four were unchanged.</p>
<p>Services stocks continued to dominate, accounting for 53 percent of volume. Industrials followed with 13 percent and cement stocks accounted for 12 percent of turnover, which BFA put at 9.72 million shares worth 1.2 billion riyals ($322 million).</p>
<p>Arriyadh Development was the most active stock in the period, with 1.3 million shares worth 115 million riyals changing hands. It closed seven percent stronger at 89 riyals.</p>
<p>Saudi Cable was the biggest gainer, clocking up almost 15 percent to 124 riyals. National Industrialisation Co was more than 13 percent firmer at 85 riyals and Al-Mawashi Al-Mukairish 100 percent was over 12 percent stronger at 107.</p>
<p>The biggest loser was Amiantit, which slipped over 11 percent to 60 riyals, BFA figures show.</p>
<p>Other stocks which were weaker included United Saudi Commercial Bank, which was down seven percent at 306; Saudi British Bank, which lost six percent to 510, and Saudi American Bank, which ended five percent weaker at 550.</p>
<p>Riyad Bank was three percent down at 245. ($1=3.75 riyals)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
