<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39674" id="root" date="1996-09-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Peacekeeper guarding Bosnia vote supplies killed.</title>
<headline>Peacekeeper guarding Bosnia vote supplies killed.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-09-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A soldier in Bosnia's NATO-led peace force was shot dead on Sunday while guarding a Sarajevo warehouse filled with voting materials for next weekend's elections, international officials said.</p>
<p>Three unidentified people approached the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe warehouse just after midnight and open fire, killing one of three Ukrainian soldiers on sentry duty, an OSCE spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Ukrainians returned fire but we don't know if anyone was hit,&quot; spokesman Thomas Leary told Reuters.</p>
<p>NATO said the 12:30 a.m. (2230 GMT) attack occurred after the Ukrainians illuminated the warehouse area with a searchlight from their armoured vehicle to check out indications of intruders.</p>
<p>&quot;One Ukrainian soldier was shot by a so-far unidentified person,&quot; said Major Simon Haselock of the peace Implementation Force (IFOR). &quot;He was evacuated to IFOR's hospital at (nearby) Rajlovac where he was pronounced dead a half hour later.&quot;</p>
<p>The Ukrainian's identity was being withheld pending notification of his family.</p>
<p>Haselock said the two other Ukrainian soldiers were not injured in the incident and no assailants were apprehended.</p>
<p>&quot;A thorough search of the area around the warehouse by IFOR military police for some clue to the (gunman's) identity began immediately after the shooting and continues today,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Leary said nothing appeared to have been stolen or disturbed in the warehouse, now filled with ballot papers and other materials for Bosnia's first post-war elections next Saturday, supervised by the OSCE.</p>
<p>IFOR troops began guarding the building a week ago after heaps of election supplies were stored there.</p>
<p>Bosnia remains divided into hostile Moslem, Serb and Croat- dominated sectors and the OSCE, IFOR and international monitors are on the alert for possible violence and other incidents which could influence the outcome of the elections.</p>
<p>Sarajevo, the capital, is controlled by the Moslem-led central government of President Alija Izetbegovic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
