<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396761" id="root" date="1997-02-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Israel, Jordan try to put aside Jerusalem row.</title>
<headline>Israel, Jordan try to put aside Jerusalem row.</headline>
<byline>Dominic Evans</byline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-02-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan's King Hussein and Israeli Prime Minster Benjamin Netanyahu tried on Sunday to brush aside a row over Jewish construction plans around Arab East Jerusalem and breathe new life into their three-year peace accord.</p>
<p>Putting on a public show of good neighbourliness after more than three hours of talks, the two leaders warned against escalation of tension in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;We have our views. The Israelis have their views. But we would like to have an atmosphere of calm and understanding,&quot; King Hussein told a news conference. &quot;We need to have a good atmosphere.&quot;</p>
<p>Netanyahu, making his first trip to an Arab state since Israel signed a long-delayed deal for limited Palestinian self-rule in the West Bank town of Hebron in January, sought to gloss over the Jerusalem issue, which Jordanian officials described earlier on Sunday as &quot;very dangerous&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We spent quite a lot of time working out how to make the peace between Jordan and Israel come alive in terms of the prospects and opportunities for ordinary Jordanians and Israelis,&quot; he said. &quot;This could be a model for the kind of peace we would wish to see throughout the Middle East.&quot;</p>
<p>Most Jordanians remain disillusioned over their 1994 peace accord after the promises of rapid economic dividends failed to materialise. A number of ambitious joint projects, including gas supplies and an airport near the Red Sea, have since been shelved or run into difficulties.</p>
<p>King Hussein's warm relations with Netanyahu cooled noticeably after the Israeli Prime Minister approved the opening of a tunnel in Arab East Jerusalem last September, sparking widespread violence in the West Bank. The tunnel was also next to Moslem holy sites.</p>
<p>Jordan's peace treaty with Israel specified that Jordan, which ruled the West Bank until the 1967 Middle East War, would retain custodial duties over Jerusalem's Moslem holy sites.</p>
<p>The king, saying Sunday's talks had been &quot;cordial and frank&quot;, reiterated his opposition &quot;to any change (in Jerusalem) which affects or threatens the peace process in any way.&quot;</p>
<p>Israel says the whole of Jerusalem is its indivisable capital, while Palestinians say the East Jerusalem will form the capital of a future state.</p>
<p>Jordanian officials said earlier on Sunday the talks were overshadowed by Jordan's concerns over the Israeli plans to build 6,500 new homes for Jews in East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>&quot;We consider them as very dangerous, a threat not just to the Palestinian negotiations but the peace process as a whole,&quot; one official said.</p>
<p>Netanyahu, facing an investigation back home about alleged government corruption, warned his domestic political opponents against preparing for his early demise.</p>
<p>&quot;I have one suggestion for them: Wait patiently. You have four good years in the opposition,&quot; Netanyahu said. &quot;I intend that you will enjoy another four years in the opposition after that...I'm going to continue to lead Israel in my way, to lead to peace, security, and economic prosperity.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
