<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396766" id="root" date="1997-02-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ABU DHABI: Job-seekers in Bahrain stand at 4,500 - minister.</title>
<headline>Job-seekers in Bahrain stand at 4,500 - minister.</headline>
<dateline>ABU DHABI 1997-02-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bahrain's Labour and Social Affairs Minister Abdel-Nabi al-Shula said on Sunday 4,500 Bahrainis, mostly new university graduates, were seeking jobs in the small Gulf Arab island.</p>
<p>He also said Bahrain had no real unemployment problem as two-thirds of job-seekers remained without jobs for only six months in a labour market that absorbs 6,500 a year.</p>
<p>Manama has embarked on an ambitious vocational training programme to find more jobs for Bahrainis to combat rising unemployment that has helped fuel sporadic anti-government unrest since December 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;Bahrain has no unemployment problem in terms of the criterion used in other countries...it is more of a problem of integrating the national workforce in the labour market,&quot; Shula told a news conference after talks in the United Arab Emirates (UAE) to boost labour and social affairs cooperation.</p>
<p>&quot;It is masked unemployment as there are 130,000 jobs held by foreigners in Bahrain.&quot;</p>
<p>Bahrain, the least wealthy country in the oil-rich Gulf region but a business and banking hub, has a population of 518,243, of whom 223,928 are foreigners.</p>
<p>Shula put unemployment at two percent -- in a total workforce of 239,000.</p>
<p>Independent economists have put the figure at 10 to 15 percent. Most of the jobless come from the island's majority Shi'ite Moslem community who live in villages that have been at the centre of protests that erupted over two years ago.</p>
<p>The protesters say they are demanding economic reforms, including more jobs as well as the restoration of parliament dissolved in 1975 by the Sunni Moslem government.</p>
<p>Shula said the government's drive to &quot;Bahrainise&quot; the workforce by increasing the number of its nationals in the private sector that is heavily dominated by expatriates had reaped major gains.</p>
<p>&quot;Now Bahrainis hold 70 percent of jobs in banks, 95 percent in telecommunications and 95 percent in the aluminium sector,&quot; added the minister who arrived in Abu Dhabi on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;Bahrainis in the private sector now stand at 35 percent which is a much better percentage than that in other Gulf countries,&quot; Shula said.</p>
<p>The UAE and Bahrain are members of the GCC, a political and economic alliance that also groups Saudi Arabia, Qatar, Oman and Kuwait,</p>
<p>Other GCC states have also begun a drive to find jobs for their citizens and reduce reliance on expatriates.</p>
<p>A Gulf official said in December foreign workers accounted for more than 80 percent, and in some cases 90 percent, of labourers in some GCC countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BAHRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABU DHABI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ABU DHABI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
