<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396820" id="root" date="1997-02-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Kasich wants vote on U.S. budget amendment delayed.</title>
<headline>Kasich wants vote on U.S. budget amendment delayed.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>House Budget Committee Chairman John Kasich said on Sunday the balanced budget amendment to the Constitution was in trouble because not enough senators support it and the vote set for this week should be delayed.</p>
<p>Asked on the CBS television programme &quot;Face the Nation&quot; if the amendment was dead because it lacked the required votes, Kasich said, &quot;I think it's in trouble.&quot;</p>
<p>The Ohio Republican suggested that Senate leaders delay this week's vote to give more time for Republicans to sell the measure and for the public to pressure more Democrats into supporting it.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to rally the public to make the phone calls and put some pressure on ... even some of these senators to change their minds,&quot; Kasich said. &quot;I'd delay it. You don't want to take a vote if you don't think you're going to win. They ought to delay it.&quot;</p>
<p>The proposed amendment would require the government to balance its budget each year during peacetime and would make it harder for Congress to raise taxes, approve deficit spending or borrow more money.</p>
<p>A constitutional amendment must clear the House and Senate by a two-thirds majority and must be ratified by 38 of 50 states. Republican leaders had been looking to passage in the Senate to lend momentum to the amendment in the House later this month. The vote in that body was also thought to be too close to call.</p>
<p>Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin, appearing on the same CBS programme, repeated the Clinton administration's view that a balanced-budget amendment could harm the U.S. economy and said the administration's deficit-reduction programme does the same job without the risks.</p>
<p>&quot;We are deeply commited to fiscal discipline, and a balanced budget subjects our economy to enormous risks,&quot; he said. &quot;We shouldn't do it.&quot;</p>
<p>Just last week freshman Democratic Sen. Tim Johnson of South Dakota said he would vote against the amendment, saying it would jeopardise Social Security as well as the government's ability to set aside funds for disasters, recessions or other crises.</p>
<p>The fate of the amendment, which Republican leaders have made a priority for the year, hinges on two other freshmen Democratic senators -- Robert Torricelli of New Jersey and Mary Landrieu of Louisiana -- who have not declared their votes.</p>
<p>Both have said they favour adoption of a constitutional amendment requiring that the budget be balanced annually. But they have also raised concerns about the future of Social Security under a constitutional amendment.</p>
<p>Rubin, asked if the White House might support a gradual reduction in capital gains taxes, would not be prompted into saying that negotiations with Republicans could lead to inclusion of a broader capital gains tax cut in the president's programme.</p>
<p>The top capital gains tax rate on most investments is 28 percent, though a few Democrats would reduce the rate on a sliding scale based on how long an asset was held, with it bottoming out at 14 percent.</p>
<p>But the administration's capital gains tax cut proposals are limited to home sale profits.</p>
<p>&quot;The president's budget creates enough room to put in place a moderate, targeted set of middle-income tax cuts, focusing on education, deductions in credits on a child tax credit and on an IRA,&quot; he said. &quot;I believe that is the right tax programme for the country.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
