<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396872" id="root" date="1997-02-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Portugal 97 privatisation income 500 bln esc - paper.</title>
<headline>Portugal 97 privatisation income 500 bln esc - paper.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-02-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Portugal should make around 500 billion escudos from privatisations in 1997 of which it will use 410 billion to pay off public debt, Finance Ministry No. 2 Fernando Teixeira dos Santos told the weekly Expresso newspaper.</p>
<p>Privatisations last year brought in a total of 464.4 billion escudos, the Secretary of State for the Treasury and Finance said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd like the privatisation process to be seen as a real boost to debt reduction, but when (this process) stops the reduction will continue fuelling itself,&quot; he told the paper. He said falling interest rates would help to reduce debt levels.  </p>
<p>The government will have sold off most of the major stakes it is planning to privatise by the end of 1999.</p>
<p>Teixeira dos Santos said the sale of a stake of up to 49 percent in electricity utility Electricidade de Portugal (EDP), which will be Portugal's largest ever state sell-off, would probably take place on May 19.</p>
<p>He said the government was still aiming to sell between 20 and 25 percent of the company but the stake could be raised to as much as 49 percent if there were sufficient demand.  </p>
<p>Likewise, the amounts to be placed internationally and on the domestic market would be flexible and could be altered according to demand.</p>
<p>The secretary of state said the government was also looking at bonuses for shareholders who held their EDP stakes for more than a year after the sale.</p>
<p>&quot;We could introduce incentives so that whoever keeps their shares for a year would receive an extra share for every 20 already held,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The sale of a third, 26 percent, tranche of Portugal Telecom would either take place in July or in September, depending on market conditions, the secretary of state said.</p>
<p>This sale will leave the state with a 25 percent &quot;golden share.&quot;</p>
<p>The sale of a stake of up to 49 percent in road operator BRISA would take place between the EDP and Telecom sales.</p>
<p>Texeira dos Santos said that the sale of a second stake in bleached pulp company Portucel Industrial might still take place this year but it would depend on the pulp market and on a restructuring of Portugal's paper industry.</p>
<p>&quot;We wouldn't exclude the possibility of postponing this operation until 1998,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the privatisation of a further stake in cement company Cimpor was likely to take place next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
