<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396874" id="root" date="1997-02-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: S.Africa trade, animal traps top EU meeting.</title>
<headline>S.Africa trade, animal traps top EU meeting.</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-02-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union foreign ministers will tread carefully through an agenda littered with traps -- figuratively and literally -- during a meeting in Brussels on Monday.</p>
<p>The figurative traps come in the form of reviewing trade links with South Africa and the latest developments on political ties with countries ranging from China to the United States.</p>
<p>But the literal hazard surrounds debate over the European Commission's latest proposals for laws relating to leg-hold traps used to capture animals for their fur.</p>
<p>At issue are standards for traps intended to kill or catch 18 species of wild animal -- including muskrat, beavers, sable, lynx and wolves.</p>
<p>Russia, the U.S. and Canada -- the world's biggest trappers -- have been pressing the EU to allow imports of fur from animals caught using certain kinds of leghold traps legal in their own countries.</p>
<p>But EU states are divided and in January representatives from nine EU states rejected the latest Commission proposals at committee level and so the matter has now gone for ministerial debate.</p>
<p>Indigenous Inuits from Canada and the U.S. have long lobbied in Europe for a ban on fur gathered from animals caught using steel-jawed traps to be lifted.</p>
<p>However, animal rights and anti-fur activists have won significant backing for laws to be tightened up both in the European Parliament and at national government level, and sources say Monday's discussions &quot;could lead nowhere&quot;.</p>
<p>On trade with South Africa, diplomatic sources say Spain is the most vocal of the bloc in expressing complaints to the Commission about the type and scope of an agreement currently being negotiated with Pretoria.</p>
<p>The latest round of talks between South Africa and the Commission ended in Brussels last Tuesday with progress but no conclusion on either a bilateral trade agreement or terms for Pretoria's partial accession to the Lome Convention, which governs the EU's relations with 70 African, Caribbean and Pacific (ACP) countries.</p>
<p>Sources said Spain wanted commitments from Pretoria for a separate fisheries agreement and also had reservations over the effect of imports of South African wines and spirits on the EU market.</p>
<p>The EU -- with an eye on the richest economy in sub-Saharan Africa -- wants a free trade deal excluding South African agricultural products, but Pretoria is seeking to include its farm products and is also wary of the effect any deal may have on its regional partners.</p>
<p>Among more routine matters being discussed are relations with Mediterranean countries, former Yugoslavia, the situation in the Balkans and Albania, and a recent EU ministerial meeting with the Association of Southeast Asian Nations.</p>
<p>A planned discussion on human rights in China has been given extra relevance by the death last Wednesday of paramount leader Deng Xiaoping and ministers are to debate whether to press -- possibly in collaboration with the U.S. -- for a motion to be raised at the United Nations.</p>
<p>Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat will also be in Brussels on Monday to sign an interim association agreement after which he will brief foreign ministers and Commission officials on the latest situation the the Middle East.</p>
<p>The agreement governs EU relations with the Palestinian entity and promises lucrative trade and other privileges for its exports.</p>
<p>Ministers are due also to hear a report from special envoys on the situation in Africa's Great Lakes region as well as hold so-called &quot;association councils&quot; with Bulgaria, Slovenia and Cyprus.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
