<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39686" id="root" date="1996-09-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian battalion starts leaving Chechnya.</title>
<headline>Russian battalion starts leaving Chechnya.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-09-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A battalion of Russian troops began leaving Chechnya on Sunday under a peace deal signed by Russian security chief Alexander Lebed, Itar-Tass news agency said.</p>
<p>A departure ceremony had already taken place at the military airport just east of the regional capital Grozny, it said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Today's attempt at a peaceful resolution of the military conflict in Chechnya is already the third. There will not be a fourth,&quot; the commander of Russian troops in Chechnya, Vyacheslav Tikhomirov, said at the ceremony, according to Tass.</p>
<p>&quot;If this attempt fails, the issue will be resolved with other methods and means.&quot; Tass did not elaborate.</p>
<p>The agency said the 133rd battalion had been in the region since the start of the conflict and had a fiercesome reputation among the rebels, who signed the deal with Lebed last month.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, most of Russia's troops are to pull out of Chechnya, though the details and timetable are unclear. President Boris Yeltsin said on Thursday he backed the deal but that Moscow &quot;should not be in a hurry&quot; to pull out the troops sent in to crush separatist rebels in December 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
