<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396953" id="root" date="1997-02-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korean opposition blasts probe on Kim's son.</title>
<headline>S.Korean opposition blasts probe on Kim's son.</headline>
<byline>Jean Yoon</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-02-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's main opposition party attacked state prosecutors on Sunday for trying to cover up a scandal by clearing President Kim Young-sam's son of any wrongdoing over loans to the failed Hanbo Steel Co</p>
<p>The National Congress for New Politics insisted that a new probe was necessary into what it calls the nation's biggest financial crisis.</p>
<p>On Saturday prosecutors cleared Kim Hyun-chul, President Kim's second son, of any wrongdoing in connection with $5.8 billion worth of loans piled up by Hanbo Steel before it was declared insolvent on January 23.</p>
<p>&quot;The probe was designed to acquit Kim Hyun-chul,&quot; said Park Sun-suck, a spokeswoman for the National Congress.</p>
<p>&quot;The investigation was wrong from the start,&quot; she said. &quot;Prosecutors were trying to cover up the suspicions surrounding him.&quot;</p>
<p>Kim Hyun-chul was questioned after he lodged a libel complaint last Tuesday against six opposition politicians who had alleged he pressured banks to offer loans to Hanbo Steel, flagship of South Korea's 14th-biggest conglomerate.</p>
<p>Kim Hyun-chul denied allegations that he had received donations in return for pressuring the banks, but speculation persisted that he had links with Hanbo, particularly after the discovery in a Hanbo Group warehouse earlier this month of more than 10,000 copies of his autobiography.</p>
<p>The opposition claimed the discovery was proof that Hanbo had been sponsoring Kim Hyun-chul by boosting his sales figures and his reputation.</p>
<p>&quot;Rising criticism that prosecutors gave Mr Kim an opportunity to clear himself from accusations shows how people views the investigation,&quot; the leading daily Chosun Ilbo said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no one who believes the prosecutor's claim that all allegations made against Kim Hyun-chul were found to be false,&quot; it said in an editorial.</p>
<p>Another leading newspaper, the Dong-A Ilbo, said the unprecedented investigation of an incumbent president's son over a scandal was itself a disgrace.</p>
<p>&quot;President Kim should take responsibility for letting the matter go so far,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The scandal has tarnished the image of the president who launched an anti-corruption drive shortly after taking office in 1993.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, prosecutors indicted 10 people in the scandal, including Hanbo Group founder Chung Tae-soo and three close associates of the president, on bribery and embezzlement charges.</p>
<p>Prosecutors said the six National Congress politicians who alleged wrongdoing by the president's son would be summoned soon for questioning over his libel complaint.</p>
<p>The six include party spokesman Chung Dong-young, his deputy Sul Hoon and three other members of parliament.</p>
<p>But the National Congress said on Sunday the politicians would ignore the prosecution's summons because the libel investigation &quot;lacked credibility&quot;.</p>
<p>President Kim, whose single five-year term expires in February 1998, is due to make a statement this week on the political situation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
