<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396949" id="root" date="1997-02-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany's Waigel keeps up hard line on EMU targets.</title>
<headline>Germany's Waigel keeps up hard line on EMU targets.</headline>
<byline>Clifford Coonan</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-02-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany will meet the fiscal goals for European currency union membership without seeking any softening of the criteria or using accounting tricks, Theo Waigel, Germany's finance minister, said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;The German Finance Minister will spare no effort in meeting the criteria,&quot; Waigel said in an interview with the Frankfurter Allgemeine Sonntagszeitung.</p>
<p>EU members are scheduled to decide in early 1998 which countries will be in the first wave of monetary union, which is due to begin in 1999. Their decision will be based on financial data for 1997.</p>
<p>There has been much talk of late of softening the criteria, but Waigel insists that Germany will adhere to the requirement for would-be members to reduce budget deficits down to or below three percent of gross domestic product by year end.</p>
<p>Waigel said: &quot;Three is three. We have developed our budgetary concept in such a way, and agreed this with the different states and local authorities, so that the deficit in 1997 will be three percent of GDP.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The banks and building societies have always demanded that the criteria must be met. We want a strong stable euro, one just as strong as the deutschemark,&quot; Waigel said.</p>
<p>Waigel said that the Maastricht Treaty contained powerful policies for establishing stability in currency union.</p>
<p>The statute establishing the European Central Bank, which will be set up in Frankfurt in 1998, was clearly oriented towards stability and had given the ECB a stronger status than even the powerful German Bundesbank, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Treaty contains sensible economic criteria. With these we have succeeded in establishing a culture of stability which no-one in Europe would have thought possible ten years ago.&quot;</p>
<p>There was no question of Germany using creative accounting to meet the criteria either.</p>
<p>The daily newspaper Bild on Saturday quoted Waigel as telling the parliamentary budget committee: &quot;When it comes to meeting the Maastricht criteria, then crediting German payments to the EU must also be discussed.&quot;</p>
<p>It said this meant Germany's net contribution to EU coffers of 21 billion marks ($12.4 billion) a year could be subtracted from Bonn's budget deficit, ensuring it was inside the three percent of GDP to qualify for the single currency.</p>
<p>A ministry spokeswoman said the report was wrong, adding that Waigel had merely pointed out to the committee the heavy burden placed on Germany through its big payments to the EU.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not pulling any tricks,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>European Commission President Jacques Santer also takes a hard line on meeting the criteria. Santer said on Saturday it was vital that the criteria for EMU membership laid out in the Maastricht Treaty should be strictly adhered to.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't hesitate to say that the euro has every chance of being at least as strong as the deutschemark,&quot; Santer said at a meeting of the Baden-Wuerttemberg wing of the Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democratic (CDU) party.</p>
<p>He dismissed calls to delay the planned 1999 EMU start date. &quot;I am worried that if we delay the start date now, we will delay currency union for a whole generation,&quot; Santer said.</p>
<p>Not everyone is convinced  that the criteria will be met on time and that there should be no thoughts of delay.</p>
<p>A former Bundesbank member, Wilhelm Noelling, threatened to lodge a legal challenge to the German government if Germany went ahead with EMU while missing strict entry criteria.</p>
<p>Writing in Britain's Financial Mail on Sunday newspaper, Noelling called for EMU to be postponed saying he believed not even Germany would meet the entry criteria.</p>
<p>He went on to reiterate comments he made in German newspapers last week -- that he was determined to go the Constitutional Court in Karlsruhe if, having clearly missed the criteria, the government decides in spring 1998 to take part.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
