<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396930" id="root" date="1997-02-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India import duty cuts seen stymied by politics.</title>
<headline>India import duty cuts seen stymied by politics.</headline>
<byline>Narayanan Madhavan</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-02-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Finance Minister P. Chidambaram is unlikely to make major cuts in import duties in his federal budget later this week in view of political pressures, analysts said at the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the right time to reduce the peak (rate of import duty) to 40 percent,&quot; said Rajesh Chadha, an adviser at the National Council for Applied Economic Research, but added Chidambaram was unlikely to cut it from the current 50 percent.</p>
<p>Chidambaram, a free-market radical in the company of communists in the ruling United Front coalition, was under pressure in the cabinet to tread cautiously in lowering tariff protection for domestic industries, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are so many parties, it is difficult to get a clear picture,&quot; said Somasri Mukhopadhyay, research fellow at the Indian Institute of Foreign Trade (IIFT), saying there was no indication of major import duty cuts.</p>
<p>India, which launched an ambitious programme to integrate its closed economy with the world in 1991, has chipped away at the import duty rates that once stood as high as 350 percent in some cases, but is now seen taking smaller strides.</p>
<p>Chadha said the minister, who is scheduled to unveil his budget proposals for 1997/98 (April-March) on February 28, might keep the peak at 50 percent but cut import duties on some raw materials and intermediates to help lower industrial costs.</p>
<p>An across-the-board two pct surcharge slapped on imports last year to garner extra revenue was criticised by pro-reform economists, who want it to be removed.</p>
<p>Analysts said the government would immediately focus on removing quantitative restrictions on imports, particularly of consumer goods, in view of India's commitment to the World Trade Organisation to do so by June.</p>
<p>An immediate worry for the government is a slowdown in export growth, which slumped in the April-December period of the current 1996/97 year to 6.36 percent from heady highs of around 24 percent last year and 16 percent the year before.</p>
<p>India's exports grew by 21.4 percent in 1995/96, and the trade deficit stood at $4.5 billion. The 1996/97 gap was earlier expected to fall to $2.0 billion, but Commerce Minister B.B. Ramaiah said this month it was likely to touch $4.0 billion.</p>
<p>Ramaiah has urged steps to boost exports, including an exemption for exports from a minimum alternate tax (MAT) imposed in the last budget on firms that avoided taxation by ploughing back profits by using a legal loophole.</p>
<p>The slump in the annual export growth in dollar terms, which averaged 15.8 percent between 1992/93 and 1995/96, is mainly attributed by economists to a sluggish world market.</p>
<p>Chadha said slow export growth could also be linked to a relatively strong rupee, combined with domestic inflation of around 7.0 to 8.0 percent. &quot;The Indian rupee has remained a little too strong,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The rupee appreciated against the British pound, Japanese yen, the German mark and the French franc by about 1.22 percent, 0.66 percent, 0.37 percent and 0.26 percent per month, respectively, between April 1996 and January 1997.</p>
<p>But a leading industry official said slower export growth could also be linked to trade controls linked to environmental lobbies in the West, and free-trade blocs like the European Union and North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA).</p>
<p>&quot;The latest we have heard is that regional groupings the world over have been a major reason for (our) poor exports,&quot; said R.K. Dhawan, director-general of the Federation of Indian Export Organisations (FIEO).</p>
<p>Tariff-free imports from within regional countries made Indian exports comparatively costlier, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
