<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="396929" id="root" date="1997-02-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Caution pervades Indian stocks ahead of budget.</title>
<headline>Caution pervades Indian stocks ahead of budget.</headline>
<byline>Anshuman Daga</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-02-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Subdued sentiment ahead of Friday's budget is expected to depress Indian shares this week, but lingering optimism could prevent heavy losses, analysts said at the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets have shown a total lack of conviction,&quot; said Ramesh Damani, a member-broker of the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE). &quot;Indecisiveness on the part of bull and bear operators might lead to choppy trading.&quot;</p>
<p>Finance Minister P. Chidambaram will present the 1997/98 (April-March) budget to Parliament on February 28, against a backdrop of inflation edging up as industrial growth slows.</p>
<p>Last week the BSE's benchmark 30-share index tumbled 82 points, or nearly 2.3 percent, in lacklustre trade, to close at 3,439.49.</p>
<p>Brokers said the budget was unlikely to include any radical initiatives to accelerate the reforms process.</p>
<p>&quot;People are not very optimistic. There is a general feeling that the government cannot take bold steps,&quot; Kamal Kabra, a former BSE president, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Brokers said sentiment-boosting steps could include the dilution of a new minimum tax on firms, allowing companies to buy back their shares and the elimination of double taxation on company dividends.</p>
<p>Present laws require investors to pay taxes on dividends paid out of the already-taxed profits of companies.</p>
<p>But brokers said the political demands of a fractious 13-party centre-left coalition could block Chidambaram from taking any radical budgetary moves to cut expenditure.</p>
<p>Expected focus areas include the reversal of the economic slowdown, boosting infrastructure investment and exports, and consolidating measures to encourage foreign direct investment, local brokerage Prabhudas Lilladher said in a pre-budget study.</p>
<p>India's industrial growth as measured by the index of industrial production (IIP) slowed to 9.8 percent in the period from April to October last year, against 11.7 percent in the corresponding period the previous year.</p>
<p>Inflation rose to a 58-week high of 7.75 percent year-on-year in the week ending January 4.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel the finance minister will be bold and innovative and respond positively. But, if the hopes do not fructify by and large, the market will react,&quot; Prabhudas Lilladher said.</p>
<p>Brokers expect the government will encourage more private participation in Indian infrastructure projects.</p>
<p>&quot;The budget will give an opportunity for the government to go ahead in the reforms process. A lot still remains to be done, especially in the infrastructure sector,&quot; said Parag Parikh, a leading BSE broker.</p>
<p>&quot;Aside from the political reservations, I believe that the reforms process would be given a thrust and if that is done, I see the market taking a bullish stance,&quot; Parikh said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
