<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="397199" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Urologix seeks pre-market approval on T3.</title>
<headline>Urologix seeks pre-market approval on T3.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Urologix Inc said Monday it submitted a Pre-Market Approval Application to the U.S. Food and Drug Administration for its Targeted Transurethral Thermo-ablation (T3) System.</p>
<p>The system is designed to treat benign prostatic hyperplasia, or enlarged prostate disease.  </p>
<p>&quot;This is another significant milestone for Urologix in our objective to make the benefits of the T3 System available to benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH) sufferers worldwide,&quot; said Jack Meyer, president and chief executive officer. &quot;An estimated six million men in the United States have moderate to severe symptoms of BPH, and our plan is to provide the T3 System through a direct sales force upon FDA commercial marketing approval, if granted.&quot;</p>
<p>Meyer added, &quot;The submission will now be reviewed by the FDA to determine its fileability, which the company expects to occur within approximately 45 days. If the FDA determines the PMA is fileable, an extensive review will follow to determine if the T3 System can be cleared for commercial marketing in the U.S.&quot;</p>
<p>The T3 System is a non-surgical, anesthesia-free, catheter-based solution developed for treating BPH with minimal discomfort and post-treatment complications, Urologix said.</p>
<p>	     ((Chicago newsdesk 312 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
