<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="397259" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: ATHLETICS-SJOBERG SEEKS LEGAL ACTION AFTER ATTACK.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-SJOBERG SEEKS LEGAL ACTION AFTER ATTACK.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former world high jump champion Patrik Sjoberg said on Monday he was seeking legal action against a woman pop singer who is alleged to have smashed a glass in his face during a nightclub row.</p>
<p>Sjoberg needed nine stitches in his face after the incident at a celebrity party in a trendy central Stockholm night club on Friday night.</p>
<p>He had to pull out of an indoor athletics meeting in Birmingham, England, on Sunday because of his injuries.</p>
<p>&quot;Had she hit a little higher I would probably have lost the sight in my right eye,&quot; Sjoberg told Swedish news agency TT.</p>
<p>Sjoberg said he had reported the 21-year-old woman, who is a member of a Stockholm band, to the police.</p>
<p>He said he was very upset about what had happened.</p>
<p>&quot;I was really very frightened. I have never been involved in something like this,&quot; Sjoberg said.</p>
<p>Sjoberg said the row started when he asked the woman to stop spilling beer on him but she just laughed and carried on. Then she allegedly smashed a glass in his face.</p>
<p>Sjoberg was taken to hospital where he needed stitches.</p>
<p>He said he still had no feeling in the right side of his face.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole thing is very regrettable, not the least as I should have competed in Birmingham at the weekend,&quot; Sjoberg said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Grand Prix gala in Birmingham on Sunday was the last big high jumping competition before the indoor world championships in Paris in March. I plan still to take part in Paris but I needed a big competition before Paris.&quot;</p>
<p>The woman involved in the row has tried to contact Sjoberg since the incident to explain how sorry she is but Sjoberg has refused to speak to her.</p>
<p>&quot;I think she is unstable and she scares me. Now it is a matter for the courts,&quot; Sjoberg said.</p>
<p>Sjoberg dismissed the woman's version of events that was published in Sweden's tabloid newspapers on Sunday.</p>
<p>She said the row broke out because Sjoberg spilt champagne on her dress and refused to apologise. She threw the contents of her drink at him and did not mean to hit him with the glass.</p>
<p>&quot;Absolutely not. We never had such a discussion,&quot; Sjoberg said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
