<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="397249" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NHL ICE HOCKEY-AVALANCHE BURY SENATORS WITH THIRD-PERIOD SPLURGE.</title>
<headline>NHL ICE HOCKEY-AVALANCHE BURY SENATORS WITH THIRD-PERIOD SPLURGE.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Claude Lemieux, Scott Young and Sandis Ozolinsh scored in a 2:21 span late in the third period as the Colorado Avalanche surged past the Ottawa Senators 4-3 on Sunday for their third straight comeback victory.</p>
<p>It was the Stanley Cup champions' sixth straight win and third in which they erased a third-period deficit. The NHL's leading team (38-14-8) won their last two games in overtime.</p>
<p>Peter Forsberg had a pair of assists for the Avalanche.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a lot of confidence right now,&quot; centre Mike Ricci said. &quot;It's nice to know we can come back and win but it's got to stop if we want to continue to win.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Tonight they had more chances than us,&quot; Ottawa (20-27-13) coach Jacques Martin said. &quot;They (the Avalanche) used their speed and their size to their advantage.&quot;</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, rookie Janne Niinimaa scored off a nifty pass from John LeClair to break a tie in the second period and Garth Snow needed to make just 14 saves to make it stand up as the Philadelphia Flyers held off the New York Rangers 2-1.</p>
<p>The Flyers (35-17-9) improved to 14-5 in one-goal games, having won their last 10. They held the Rangers, who played without their captain, centre Mark Messier, to a season-low 15 shots on goal. Messier is day-to-day with back spasms.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt fresh tonight, maybe because it was against the Rangers, I don't know,&quot; said Niinimaa. &quot;We did talk about it before the game that we owed them for the last time they were in here (a 4-2 Rangers victory on February 1).&quot;</p>
<p>Adam Graves scored a power-play goal for the Rangers, who saw their winless streak reach seven games (0-5-2). Mike Richter had 35 saves for New York, which has scored just nine times in the slide.</p>
<p>&quot;An effort like this is not acceptable to our fans, our ownership and not to us,&quot; Rangers coach Colin Campbell said. &quot;It's frustrating in a lot of areas. Some players put out, some didn't.&quot;</p>
<p>At Tampa Bay, unlikely hero Brantt Myhres scored with just under seven minutes left as the Lightning erased a three-goal deficit and rallied for a 4-3 win over the San Jose Sharks.</p>
<p>Myhres, who entered the game with a goal and an assist and 110 penalty minutes in 35 games, was streaking at the net from the left wing when he re-directed Rob Zamuner's crossing pass under goalie Kelly Hrudey to put Tampa Bay (23-29-7) in front.</p>
<p>&quot;It was unbelievably exciting,&quot; said Myhres. &quot;I just grabbed the puck and batted it in. Every kid dreams of making a goal like that.&quot;</p>
<p>Jason Weimer sandwiched a pair of second-period goals around a score by Roman Hamrlik to spark the comeback, which extended Tampa Bay's unbeaten streak to 4-0-1.</p>
<p>In Anaheim, Teemu Selanne's acrobatic goal with 2:41 left in regulation snapped a 2-2 tie and lifted the Mighty Ducks of Anaheim to a 5-2 victory over the Vancouver Canucks.</p>
<p>Steve Rucchin won a faceoff in the right faceoff circle and tapped the puck to the left of the goal. Selanne lunged forward and managed to get enough of the puck to wrist it between the pads of Vancouver goaltender Kirk Mclean.</p>
<p>Selanne extended his point-scoring streak to nine games, marking the fourth time this season he has had a streak of at least nine games. &quot;I thought it was a lucky goal,&quot; he said. &quot;I lost my balance and just tried to shoot it, but I'll take it.&quot;</p>
<p>At New York, Niklas Anderson had a goal and an assist and Zigmund Palffy set up three scores as the New York Islanders claimed a 4-1 victory over the Pittsburgh Penguins, who played without stars Ron Francis and Jaromir Jagr.</p>
<p>Tommy Salo made 27 saves for the Isles, who broke a two-game losing skid and won for the third time in five games.</p>
<p>Francis was out with back spasms and Jagr missed his third straight game due to a groin injury. The Penguins lost for the sixth time in seven games.</p>
<p>In Dallas, Sergei Zubov scored twice, including the tie-breaking goal with 12 seconds left in the second period, and Mike Modano had a goal and three assists as the Dallas Stars cruised to a 6-1 victory over the Edmonton Oilers.</p>
<p>Joe Nieuwendyk scored twice, Brent Gilchrist had a goal and Todd Harvey had a pair of assists for the Stars, who won for the sixth time in eight games.</p>
<p>In Buffalo, Michal Grosek scored twice and Matthew Barnaby had a goal and two assists as the Sabres ran their unbeaten streak to 12 games with a 5-1 win over the Boston Bruins, sending them to their longest losing streak in 30 years.</p>
<p>Adam Oates had his 20-game points streak stopped for Boston (20-33-7), 0-8-1 in their last nine games. The Bruins' recent free-fall leaves them with the league's worst record.</p>
<p>The Sabres are 7-0-5 in their streak.</p>
<p>The Bruins were scoreless in seven power-play chances.</p>
<p>In St Louis, Steve Chiasson's fifth goal of the season highlighted a third-period comeback as the Calgary Flames rallied for a 5-3 victory over the St. Louis Blues.</p>
<p>The Flames trailed 3-2 entering the third period but charged to victory on goals by Robert Reichel, Chiasson and rookie Jarome Iginla.</p>
<p>Reichel knotted the game 5:33 into the period. Chiasson snapped the deadlock just under two minutes later and Iginla capped the rally with an empty-net tally with 26 seconds left.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
