<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="397678" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: FEATURE - Czechs seek to increase market transparency.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Czechs seek to increase market transparency.</headline>
<byline>Nigel Stephenson</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech authorities, seeking to improve the tarnished image of the country's capital markets, are taking steps to increase transparency and boost investor confidence.</p>
<p>More prices are being published and market supervision has been enhanced. Market participants have welcomed the moves but say more needs to be done.</p>
<p>&quot;Things are getting better, although we are at a stage where things couldn't get much worse,&quot; said Jan Sykora of brokers Wood &amp; Co in Prague.</p>
<p>The Central Securities Registry (SCP) began from February 4 to publish, with one day's delay, the price and other information about each stock trade it registers. The SCP is where some 60 percent of share transactions are executed.</p>
<p>The governing chamber of the Prague Stock Exchange (PSE) has agreed to publish immediately the prices of off-market trades conducted by its members from March 3.</p>
<p>Previously, the SCP published a weekly average price and the PSE published prices of direct trades through the bourse.</p>
<p>The PSE also said it would delist by the end of June some 400 mainly illiquid shares, out of the 1,751 on the bourse.</p>
<p>The changes, to be followed later this month by the publication of a tender to set up a securities clearing house, derive from a government pledge last December to support the establishment of an independent body to supervise markets.</p>
<p>As a first step, the Finance Ministry's markets supervision department has been transformed into a Bureau for the Control of Securities with an 11-strong advisory board, including market players.</p>
<p>But, in a move which dismayed the market, a finance ministry official acknowledged in late January that regulators withheld disclosure that a major investment fund had been fined for irregularities.</p>
<p>TWO STEPS FORWARD, ONE BACK</p>
<p>&quot;It is two steps forward, one back,&quot; said George Collins, portfolio manager at Patria Asset Management.</p>
<p>Foreign and domestic investors have long criticised the lack of transparency on Czech markets.</p>
<p>While Polish shares rose some 80 percent in 1996 and Hungarian stocks gained 135 percent, as measured by key indices, Czech stocks rose just 20 percent last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The Czech capital market got a bad reputation because of bad regulation and low transparency.&quot; PSE chairman Tomas Jezek told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;The secondary market is not liquid and the lack of liquidity blocks primary issues. I see the solution in (an independent) securities commission,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Analysts say there are other factors behind the relative performance of the three markets and that many Czech blue chips are perfectly happy to disclose information to investors. But they agree that lack of transparency is one reason why Prague has lagged.</p>
<p>&quot;The major problem of the market was the total lack of transparency...The prices are not relevant, they do not reflect the balance between supply and demand,&quot; Sykora said.</p>
<p>But the PSE's PX50 index has gained nearly 10 percent so far in 1997, and analysts say the moves towards market transparency have contributed to the rise.</p>
<p>FOREIGN INVESTORS HEARTENED</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign investors have definitely been heartened by official movement on cleaning up the market,&quot; said one foreign broker, who declined to be named.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus had, until December, adopted a hands-off approach to market regulation. But he acknowledged the stock market, created by the mass voucher privatisation programme of 1992-95, was entering a new phase.</p>
<p>He backed the creation of an independent regulator but said this would happen gradually.</p>
<p>Jezek heads a group drawing up a draft law on setting up a securities commission, modelled on the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), this year.</p>
<p>He said the draft law should be ready later this month.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel parliament will be ready to accept it because everybody feels the need for it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Jan Veverka, head of the finance ministry's revamped securities bureau, says the aim is clear but that a hasty decision would be wrong.</p>
<p>&quot;Our goal is to create a really independent securities commission but it is not an easy task because we have to prepare changes in the law,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>He also wants further development of a system of self-regulatory organisations based on investment funds, brokers and dealers and the PSE, which he said would form the cornerstone of market supervision.</p>
<p>Veverka said it was not possible to say whether the independent watchdog would be in place this year.</p>
<p>Wood's Sykora said the debate over the pace of change will hot up as the Czech Republic, widely seen as a leading candidate, comes closer to membership of the European Union.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Czech Republic wants to get into the EU, it has to have a transparent, regulated market,&quot; he said. &quot;It is not a matter of whether we want it or not.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
