<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39768" id="root" date="1996-09-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK judge mulls dumping knighthood in leadership bid.</title>
<headline>HK judge mulls dumping knighthood in leadership bid.</headline>
<byline>Diane Stormont</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's top judge is considering relinquishing his British knighthood in a bid to lead the territory after the handover to China next year, the South China Morning Post newspaper said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Chief Justice Sir Ti Liang Yang, who entered what had been regarded as a one-horse race for power last week, also told Hong Kong reporters in London he had no regrets about giving up his British passport -- a precondition for the job.</p>
<p>&quot;It was not a big decision. I needed only five minutes to think about it,&quot; Yang, who is holidaying in London, told the Hong Kong press corps.</p>
<p>He said he was checking whether he needed to drop his knighthood, awarded in 1988, the year in which he became the first Chinese head of Hong Kong's judiciary, the Morning Post reported.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there will be no conflict if I am not using it to do anything. I still have to clarify this,&quot; the English-language daily quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>Yang, who announced his resignation as chief justice on Friday in order to pursue his bid, admitted he lacked administrative experience but dismissed this as &quot;not the most important quality&quot; needed to run the wealthy and sophisticated territory of 6.2 million people when the British depart.</p>
<p>Hong Kong, a British colony for more than 150 years, reverts to China at midnight on June 30, 1997, now just 296 days away.</p>
<p>Few Hong Kong residents, however, share Yang's views on administrative ability, a poll published by the Hong Kong Standard newspaper on Sunday indicated.</p>
<p>The majority of the 200 people surveyed on Saturday once again picked Hong Kong's head of the civil service, Anson Chan, as the top choice for future leader.</p>
<p>&quot;She has been serving Hong Kong for years and knows all about administrative issues...she has good relations with both Britain and China,&quot; the paper said.</p>
<p>However, Chan's role as number two to Governor Chris Patten and her defence of Patten's policies, implemented often to Chinese fury, are believed to have scuppered her chances.</p>
<p>Yang, though unpopular among Hong Kong's democratic lobby for declining to support Hong Kong's human rights laws in the face of Chinese oppposition -- his views were leaked to his embarrassment by Beijing's representatives in Hong Kong last year -- ranked second in the survey.</p>
<p>But his distance from the business world is regarded as a plus by many in Hong Kong who, mindful of the purges on corruption rampant in the 1970s, are keen to see the separation of commerce from government continue, analysts say.</p>
<p>The former chief justice got 18 percent of the votes in the Standard's poll, while Chan weighed in with 40.5 percent.</p>
<p>Billionaire shipping magnate Tung Chee-hwa, tipped as the front runner since Chinese president Jiang Zemin singled him out from a roomful of prominent Hong Kong advisers in January and pointedly shook his hand, lagged with 5.5 percent of the vote.</p>
<p>But 35.5 percent of the respondents replied they were undecided, underlining the degree of apathy towards one of the most vital stepping stones in Hong Kong's transition.</p>
<p>Academic Lau Sui-kai, a member of the China-appointed Preparatory Committee responsible for the handover, ascribed this to the exclusion of the public from the selection process.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's future leader will be chosen by a 400-strong Selection Committee to be chosen by the Preparatory Committee.</p>
<p>Nominations close in about two weeks and it remains to be seen how the 400 members will be chosen and how they in turn will select Hong Kong's future leader by a November deadline.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
