<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="397621" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungarian farmers block roads in tax protest.</title>
<headline>Hungarian farmers block roads in tax protest.</headline>
<byline>Blaise Szolgyemy</byline>
<dateline>VAROSFOLD, Hungary 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of Hungarian farmers irate over new taxes used tractors and ploughs to block roads throughout the country on Monday, the first day of a planned three-day protest.</p>
<p>Disruptions were kept to a minimum, however, as police managed to keep traffic moving at most locations and there were no reports of violence.</p>
<p>Outside this central Hungarian village, dozens of ploughs, tractors and harvesters closed one of the two lanes on Highway 5, which links the Balkans and Turkey with western Europe.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, a Reuters photographer said 1,000 tractors stretching in a line for five km (three miles) blocked one lane of traffic on a highway at Kiskoros, also in central Hungary.</p>
<p>Hundreds more tractors blocked traffic about 15 km (eight miles) outside the city.</p>
<p>Police and Hungarian radio said the farmers had partially or fully blocked roads in dozens of locations, but police supervising the blockades kept traffic moving and there were no reports of violence.</p>
<p>&quot;It is already hard to survive from agriculture and now the government is making it absolutely impossible,&quot; said protester Jeno Fenyvesi, who raises pigs and other livestock in Varosfold.</p>
<p>The farmers, who are protesting the end of an exception from social security contributions as of January 1 and new requirements to document expenses, received permission to protest in about 200 places, the official MTI news agency reported.</p>
<p>Bacs-Kiskun county police spokesman Laszlo Ferenczi told Reuters that slightly over 20 of the 39 proposed sites were manned by demonstators in the county, the protests' centre.</p>
<p>The Hungarian media reported protests in eight of Hungary's 19 counties. A group of people sympathetic to the farmers also gathered for a small demonstration outside the parliament in the capital Budapest.</p>
<p>Hungarian radio said there was no violence at any of the protest sites, but some roads were entirely closed and cars lined up for several kilometres (miles) at some places.</p>
<p>Gyula Kosa, the organiser of the demonstration, told Radio Kossuth that he would be ready to call it off if government ministers came to his hometown of Kiskoros and promise to reduce tax burdens.</p>
<p>On Friday, after Kosa cancelled planned talks at the finance ministry, Finance Minister Peter Medgyessy said he would be ready to talk to the demonstrators at any time and any place.</p>
<p>But he said he would not agree to reinstating social security exceptions for farmers because that would mean unequal taxes for farmers and non-farmers and would jeopardise the country's finances.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VAROSFOLD, Hungary"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
