<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39786" id="root" date="1996-09-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Thousands flee capture of Iraqi Kurdish towns.</title>
<headline>Thousands flee capture of Iraqi Kurdish towns.</headline>
<byline>Osman Senkul</byline>
<dateline>KOI SANJAQ, Iraq 1996-09-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of Kurds fled fierce fighting in northern Iraq on Sunday as a Kurdish faction backed by Iraq captured two strategic towns held by its rivals in the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK).</p>
<p>Refugees raced for the Iranian border in coaches, trucks, minibuses, cars and even bulldozers loaded with beds, blankets, utensils and television sets.</p>
<p>Besieged PUK guerrillas pleaded for U.S. help after their lines of defence crumbled under an assault by the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) which captured first Degala and then the town of Koi Sanjaq in a matter of hours.</p>
<p>&quot;Urgent and decisive help is needed. We call on the U.S.-led coalition to move urgently to stop the Iraqi onslaught,&quot; the PUK said in a statement.</p>
<p>In Koi Sanjaq, a city of 80,000, more than 5,000 residents fled after learning of the fall of Degala.</p>
<p>Koi Sanjaq is 100 km (65 miles) northwest of Sulaimaniya, the PUK's last remaining stronghold in Iraq.</p>
<p>KDP officials -- whose forces seized the main northern city of Arbil a week ago with Iraqi help -- later confirmed seizing Koi Sanjaq in a telegram sent from their military command in Salahuddin, just outside Arbil.</p>
<p>The KDP denied Iraqi involvement, at least in the Degala takeover, and it was not clear if Iraqi troops or armour were directly involved in the capture of Koi Sanjaq.</p>
<p>At KDP headquarters in Salahuddin, spokesman Falat Bekir spoke in terms of hundreds of PUK dead, wounded and captured but offered no specifics. He had no casualty count for KDP fighters. In KDP villages, gunmen fired their weapons in celebration.</p>
<p>&quot;It is important because we have pushed the PUK forces back who were threatening to retake Arbil,&quot; Bekir said.</p>
<p>Last week the United States fired 44 cruise missiles at military targets in southern Iraq in retaliation for Iraqi President Saddam Hussein's intervention on the side of the KDP in seizing the PUK-held town of Arbil.</p>
<p>Sunday's advances followed several days of fierce fighting between the rival militias, battling for control of predominantly Kurdish northern Iraq.</p>
<p>PUK commanders said their commander-in-chief, Jalal Talabani, had joined his fighters at Heibet Sultan mountain, the next line of defence after Koi Sanjaq.</p>
<p>&quot;There is nothing so natural as the head commander's coming to the battleground,&quot; said a local PUK commander.</p>
<p>But later at KDP headquarters in Salahuddin, spokesman Bekir said the KDP had also taken the mountain. He said the KDP position had improved and it would be easier for the militia to move towards the power-generating Dokan Dam should it want to.</p>
<p>The two main Kurdish factions have clashed off and on for decades but had maintained an uneasy alliance against Saddam.</p>
<p>PUK commanders said on Saturday that Iraq had moved tanks into a position that would place the Kurdish faction under attack from three fronts around Sulaimaniya, 140 km (85 miles) south of Arbil.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KOI SANJAQ, Iraq"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
