<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="397821" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Growth continues in NZ earnings, jobs in Nov quarter.</title>
<headline>Growth continues in NZ earnings, jobs in Nov quarter.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The average ordinary time hourly earnings of private sector employees rose 0.6 percent in the November quarter to NZ$15.51, and were 3.8 percent higher than a year ago, Statistics New Zealand said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Public sector employees' average ordinary time earnings rose by 1.5 percent in the quarter and 3.6 percent in the year, to $18.33.</p>
<p>Total average ordinary time hourly earnings rose 0.7 percent in the November quarter, to $16.20. They were up 3.5 percent on the November 1995 figure, following rises of 3.4 percent in the years to May and August 1996.  </p>
<p>The average total hourly earnings of employees in November, including both ordinary time and overtime, rose 3.5 percent in the year to NZ$16.34. SNZ said the rise was the largest annual increase since August 1991 and compared with a 3.2 percent rise in the year to August 1996.</p>
<p>Female ordinary time hourly earnings ($14.31) were 80.8 percent of male earnings ($17.71) in November, compared with 81.0 percent in August.  </p>
<p>Employees were paid for an average of 39.32 hours a week in November, virtually the same number as in November 1995. Ordinary time paid hours rose by 0.2 percent over the same period, while overtime hours fell by 5.3 percent.</p>
<p>The number of filled jobs in surveyed industries in November was 3.0 percent higher than November 1995, at 1.52 million.</p>
<p>Annual increases in filled jobs have been recorded in each quarter since August 1992. There are now 21.1 percent more filled jobs than there were in August 1991, when filled jobs were at a low point.  </p>
<p>There were 1.08 million full-time jobs in November, 2.6 percent more than a year ago. The number of part-time jobs rose 3.9 percent in the year to November. There were 0.44 million part-time filled jobs in November.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom (64 4) 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
