<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="398054" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Enron seen offering Ore. more rate savings.</title>
<headline>Enron seen offering Ore. more rate savings.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Enron Corp at a settlement meeeting on Tuesday is expected to offer customers of Portland General Electric Co at least $5 million a year in rate savings for four years following the companies' merger, industry sources said Monday.</p>
<p>The merger partners submitted on Friday a revised plan to the Oregon Public Utilities Commission (OPUC).</p>
<p>Sources close to the negotiations, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the new plan expands the companies' earlier estimate of $3 million in annual merger-related savings.</p>
<p>Tom Riordan, an OPUC analyst, said the new proposal includes &quot;variations&quot; on the rate cut plan as well as &quot;a number of conditions and contingencies.&quot;</p>
<p>The staff of the OPUC earlier approved the merger, but with conditions including a $47.4 million annual rate cut for four years after the merger.</p>
<p>The three-member OPUC has said Enron would have to come up from the $3 million figure in order to gain final merger approval from the state.</p>
<p>The latest proposal also calls for customers to split with shareholders some of the merger-related savings above $5 million, the sources said.</p>
<p>Enron reportedly said the companies would have an economic incentive, but not an obligation to achieve a target savings level of $9 million a year.</p>
<p>Officials at the OPUC as well as Enron and Portland General would not comment on the specifics of the proposal until after Tuesday's settlement meeting.</p>
<p>--D Beasley, Los Angeles bureau + 1 213 955 6761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
