<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="398382" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian bonds/futures.</title>
<headline>Italian bonds/futures.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian bond futures held to higher levels after Italian Treasury Minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi said Italy's revised 1996 deficit was 127.5 trillion lire and that inflation was currently running at 2.4 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>The market started easier on disappointment over preliminary CPI figures late last week and the softer tone to the dollar and lira, but soon picked up as operators saw the market oversold.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market took comfort as Cimapi told a news conference that the 1996 deficit to Gross Domestic Product ratio was 6.81 percent, and that Italy's debt servicing costs would be 184 trillion lire in 1996.  </p>
<p>The Italian Treasury was restating public accounts from 1992-96 in the light of last week's Eurostat approval relating to its Euro-tax due to be levied in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The debt servicing costs were a little lighter than most thought and the confirmation of the inflation figures helped the market to gain some strength,&quot; said one LIFFE trader.</p>
<p>Preliminary February CPI figures on Thursday and Friday pointed to year-on-year inflation of 2.2 percent, but due to a delay in electricity tariff cuts inflation was likely to be revised to 2.4 percent from January's official 2.6 percent.  </p>
<p>The National Statistics Office ISTAT is due to release official February inflation data on March 4.</p>
<p>Dealers said that worries over EMU were still apparent and were keeping some investors cautious, while the dollar and the lira were also a little eaiser.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
