<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="398453" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Doctors struggle to save victims of India inferno.</title>
<headline>Doctors struggle to save victims of India inferno.</headline>
<byline>Narayan Sarangi</byline>
<dateline>BARIPADA, India 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Doctors struggled on Monday to save dozens of badly burned victims of a raging blaze that engulfed a gathering of Hindu worshippers in eastern India, killing at least 182 people, authorities said.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment more than 100 doctors are working on the patients,&quot; Dr Binoy Kumar Aggarwal of District Headquarters Hospital in Baripada town told Reuters.</p>
<p>Blackened bodies lay strewn across the makeshift camp site where 158 devotees were burnt alive on Sunday when flames tore through a cluster of makeshift bamboo and straw shelters, packed with napping worshippers.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like a burial ground with dead bodies littered all over,&quot; said P.K. Mishra, deputy police chief of Baripada town where the inferno struck on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;The bodies are charred beyond recognition.&quot;</p>
<p>The inferno erupted on the last day of a convention dedicated to a Hindu guru in Baripada, about 220 km (135 miles) north of the capital of Orissa state, Bhubaneshwar.</p>
<p>Aggarwal said 24 of 187 injured died in hospital. About a dozen others were in serious condition in the Baripada hospital with burns to over 70 to 80 percent of their bodies.</p>
<p>Another 24 patients in very serious condition had been shifted to a hospital in Cuttack, about 175 km (110 miles) southwest of Baripada, Aggarwal said. At least 50 doctors had rushed to Baripada headquarters hospital to complement the resident team of a similar number.</p>
<p>The inferno swept through the temporary huts on the last day of a convention dedicated to a Hindu guru. All the victims were believed to be male. The cause of the fire was thought to be a short circuit or gas cylinder that exploded.</p>
<p>&quot;The scene looked like people were roasted alive on a battlefield,&quot; said resident Amarendra. &quot;The bodies were so mutilated that they were beyond recognition.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I saw rows of charred bodies,&quot; said Sandeep Sahu, a local journalist who arrived at the site early on Monday, more than 14 hours after the fire erupted. &quot;The structures were razed to the ground and I could still smell the smoke.&quot;</p>
<p>Sahu said about one third of the 158 bodies had been marked with identification tags, but others were disfigured. &quot;Relatives were crying desperately, looking for any information from police,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Orissa home (interior) secretary, S.C. Hota, said strong winds fanned the fire, which broke out at about 3:30 p.m. (1000 GMT) on Sunday.</p>
<p>The flames swiftly engulfed eight huts in the camp at Baripada, 175 km (110 miles) southwest of Calcutta, he said.</p>
<p>Most of the victims were men taking a siesta after lunch at the annual national convention, dedicated to the memory of the Hindu guru Nigamananda, Hota said. &quot;The number of exits at the camp was very limited,&quot; Hota said. &quot;That was a problem.&quot;</p>
<p>Women and children attending the convention which began last Thursday were in 10 huts in a separate area of the camp.</p>
<p>Straw had been spread on the ground to serve as bedding. The temperature in the region was 32 degrees Celsius (90 Fahrenheit) and the weather was dry.</p>
<p>&quot;Accommodation for the delegates was made almost entirely of straw,&quot; survivor Bhagbal Sahu said. &quot;That made it easier for the fire to spread and hardly allowed people any time to get out.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BARIPADA, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
