<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="398778" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - London Evening Standard - Feb 24.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - London Evening Standard - Feb 24.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>BRITISH TOURISTS ON TERROR ON THE 86TH FLOOR</p>
<p>Today British tourists told of their terrifying experience at the hands of a gunman who went on the rampage at the top of New York's Empire State building. Seven people were shot and one person was killed before the gunman turned the gun on himself.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>BANK ROW SHADOW ON AVIS FLOAT PLANS</p>
<p>The planned 250 mn stg public flotation of car rental firm Avis Europe next month is being undermined by a row between the company and one of its investment banks UBS Securities.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>CAPITAL GAVE WARNINGS ON 'WEAK CONTROLS'</p>
<p>Casinos group Capital Corporation, under pressure from a 180mn stg hostile bid by London Clubs International, warned shareholders in September that its financial controls were still weak.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>GAME PLAN SOUGHT FROM FROZEN LANICA</p>
<p>Before trading resumes on the Stock Exchange, Lanica Trust, the investment vehicle whose share price has shot up incredibly in past months, is under pressure to come clean about its intentions. Officials want to clear up several issues before trading resumes.</p>
<p>-- BMC +44 171 377 1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
