<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="398775" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-US firms to buy UK's Yorkshire Electricity.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-US firms to buy UK's Yorkshire Electricity.</headline>
<byline>Jeff Daeschner</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>American Electric Power Co Inc and Public Service Co of Colorado said on Monday they planned to buy Britain's Yorkshire Electricity Group Plc in an agreed deal valuing it at 1.5 billion pounds ($2.43 billion).</p>
<p>The U.S. utilities expected the acquisition of one of Britain's last independent regional electricity companies (Recs) to create trans-Atlantic synergies in power supply, technology and generation.</p>
<p>&quot;Yorkshire is particularly attractive to us because of its tradition of low-cost, high-customer service,&quot; AEP chairman Linn Draper told reporters in a telephone conference call.</p>
<p>Yorkshire said would not contest the bid as it saw no competitive advantage to staying independent.</p>
<p>&quot;We always said that if somebody came along and offered us a sufficiently high price, and a good deal for our shareholders, we would consider it. And we think this is a very fair price,&quot; Yorkshire chairman Christopher Hampson said.</p>
<p>AEP and PS Colorado said they expected to receive British regulatory clearance for the deal before the next national election which must be held by May 22.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the timelines that have been experienced by other transactions, that would say that there's a high likelihood that it might occur before the election,&quot; Draper said, adding that he did not expect the bid to run into problems with regulatory authorities.</p>
<p>However, some analysts questioned the companies' timing, noting that the Labour Party was expected to be less amenable to clearing such an acquisition if it won the next election.</p>
<p>Britain's ruling Conservative government has nodded through bids for 10 of the 12 regional electricity companies set up in 1990.</p>
<p>But Labour, ahead in current opinion polls, has proposed a windfall tax on utilities and criticised so-called &quot;fat-cat&quot; pay awards for senior management of the companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Financially, for shareholders, it looks a fair offer,&quot; said SocGen analyst Marshall Whiting.</p>
<p>&quot;(But) not everybody thinks it's going to go through ... That's what the (share) price is saying to us,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Yorkshire's shares surged 60.5 pence to 879 by 1345 GMT but stayed below the offer price of about 927 pence.</p>
<p>The offer represented a premium of 13.3 percent to Yorkshire's closing price on Friday and a multiple of 11.3 times the company's earnings before exceptional items for the year ended March 31, 1996.</p>
<p>If approved, the British utility would be bought by Yorkshire Holdings, a firm owned equally by AEP and PS Colorado.</p>
<p>The U.S. utilities expected the deal to be immediately accretive to their earnings, and added that they did not foresee restructuring charges from the transaction.</p>
<p>They also expected to reap unspecified cost savings from the deal, which would be a leveraged transaction composed of 75 percent debt and 25 percent equity.</p>
<p>AEP and PS Colorado, which has more than five million customers across nine U.S. states, said they planned to expand Yorkshire's electricity generation activities in Britain.</p>
<p>They also expected to benefit from Yorkshire's experience when Britain opens up the electricity supply market in 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;We think that we will learn from that,&quot; Draper said. &quot;We are actively involved in trying to promote customer choice in our (U.S.) service area.&quot;</p>
<p>American Electric and PS Colorado said they had considered other possible acquisition targets in the UK and abroad, including the other major independent regional electricity company, Southern Electric Plc.</p>
<p>But the companies said they did not contact Southern officials and did not give further details.</p>
<p>When asked about job cuts, company officials said the fact that Yorkshire's management would be retained bode well for the rest of the utility's workforce.</p>
<p>However, they stopped short of pledging that they would not make job cuts at Yorkshire, noting that the management would continue to evaluate the size of the work force. ($1=.6168 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
