<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="398861" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Contango beckons for oil after 20 pct price drop.</title>
<headline>Contango beckons for oil after 20 pct price drop.</headline>
<byline>Sam Arnold-Forster</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>World oil markets are toying with contango, pricing prompt oil below forward months, after the biggest drop in oil prices for five years.</p>
<p>Brent crude oil futures, the world benchmark, have plunged 20 percent since early January to just under $20 a barrel, crushing the big prompt premiums that existed for much of last year.</p>
<p>Some refined oil product markets have already dipped into contango, which traders say is a strong signal of underlying price weakness.</p>
<p>Contango on crude oil &quot;looks possible, perhaps even probable,&quot; said Nigel Saperia, managing director of the oil division at Bankers Trust International in London.</p>
<p>But any move towards contango is likely to be slowed when oil refiners get the chance to stock up on crude at cheaper levels. Prompt crude at 30 cents a barrel below a month ahead would attract extra refinery buying, said oil traders.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market will move into contango over the next few weeks but there will be some strong buying on the way down. At about 30 cents (contango) you should start to see refiners stepping in to buy,&quot; said a trader at a Wall Street bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the (investment) funds have been short this year which is keeping pressure on the market. They won't buy back until they see the (downward) trend has finished&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The first month traded on Brent futures has fallen to 26 cents a barrel above the second month from about 90 cents last October when the underlying price hit a six year high above $25 a barrel.</p>
<p>Steep backwardation on futures, when prompt prices are higher, typically reflects a strong underlying market for physical oil. Shallow backwardation or contango reflects a weak underlying market.</p>
<p>Despite the big losses on outright prices the forward curve on Brent remains saucer shaped - but only just. It is still gently backwardated until the middle of 1998 before slowly rising again from mid-1999 into the next century.</p>
<p>The towering backwardation of 1996 was built up over three years on surging world demand for oil and lower working stock levels at oil refineries.</p>
<p>Last year nearby Brent averaged 61 cents a barrel more than the second month out, up from a low point in 1993 when it averaged a discount of 13 cents.</p>
<p>The last time Brent sank into contango on nearby months was in the middle of 1995 when outright prices of $16.50 a barrel were $3 below current levels.</p>
<p>The shape of the forward Brent curve is broadly symmetrical with nearby prices roughly the same as those in 2003 but some $2 a barrel above the low point which extends from mid-1998 to mid-1999.</p>
<p>The chance of that low point creeping backwards in time towards the present day and tipping the whole curve into contango gained last week when heating oil and fuel oil both slipped into contango in Europe.</p>
<p>Last year the two nearest months on gas oil futures in London only dipped into contango for a day each in May and August.</p>
<p>The fuel market stayed in backwardation until well into the second quarter last year due mostly to delays in spring exports from Russia.</p>
<p>The only areas of the market that could lend support at the moment are jet fuel and gasoline, said oil traders in London.</p>
<p>Airlines have snapped up more than a million tonnes of fuel in recent weeks and gasoline stocks are below year ago levels in Europe and the United States.</p>
<p>But swap markets suggest a lack of confidence further forward in both markets.</p>
<p>The premium for jet swaps has barely moved despite the big buying by airlines for the summer of this and next year.</p>
<p>&quot;The buying has just meant that swaps haven't come off. It the underlying market had been strong they would have firmed,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, gasoline is currently holding at $4.40 a barrel above Brent, rising to $5.25 in the critical second quarter this year.</p>
<p>But this is well below the second quarter last year which averaged more than $6.00 a barrel and Europe is still producing around 10 percent more gasoline than it needs.</p>
<p>--London newsroom +44 171 542 4984</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
