<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="399051" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China makes a buck out of Deng.</title>
<headline>China makes a buck out of Deng.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The people Deng Xiaoping encouraged to make money are now out to make money out of him.</p>
<p>During his lifetime, the diminutive Chinese leader spurned personality cults, and output of souvenirs and trinkets bearing his image never reached anywhere near the same profusion as for his predecessor, Mao Zedong.</p>
<p>But now that Deng is dead, aged 92, his countrymen are using their newly-honed entrepreneurial skills to cash in on China's fond and respectful memories of him.</p>
<p>After all, it was Deng who wanted people to prosper and who exhorted them to &quot;enrich yourselves&quot; -- without specifying too closely how to go about it.</p>
<p>In the budding Deng-mania, printers of posters bearing the Deng image, in a variety of heroic and grandfatherly poses, seem to be the big winners so far.</p>
<p>The official Xinhua news agency said on Monday that in the five days since the patriarch died the People's Art Publishing House had printed just over one million Deng posters, and public appetite had still not been sated.</p>
<p>In Beijing's Tiananmen Square, a boxed souvenir set comprising a tiepin, necklace and badge, all stamped with a grinning Deng and selling for 68 yuan (US$8), has been a hot-selling item.</p>
<p>&quot;The Deng badges were sold out,&quot; said a shop assistant on Monday on the ornate rostrum overlooking the square. &quot;We've just got in a new stock.&quot;</p>
<p>Among other enterprises on the bandwagon, a tableware company in south China says its Deng plates are nice little earners, and demand is such that customers are clamouring at factory gates to get hold of them.</p>
<p>&quot;Comrade Deng Xiaoping passed away too early,&quot; lamented one company official. &quot;We weren't ready.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
