<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="399012" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: INTERVIEW - INL sees improved earnings.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - INL sees improved earnings.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Brockett</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Independent Newspapers Ltd is confident of bettering its NZ$47.18 million 1995/96 year profit this financial year, Managing Director Mike Robson said on Monday.</p>
<p>Commenting after INL posted a first half net profit of NZ$26.19 million, up 0.9 percent on last year's interim result and 10.7 percent before tax and unusual items, Robson told Reuters in a telephone interview that the company expected earnings to continue to improve in the second half.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think it's generally conceded that the last six months have been difficult ones for almost every New Zealand company and for us to achieve a 10 percent lift in our trading performance in that environment we thought was a pretty good effort,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We see no reason why we won't continue that through into the second half because we feel we really have got our foot on the costs and we're extracting whatever dollars there are out there.&quot;  </p>
<p>Robson said the restructuring of Australian magazine distributor Gordon and Gotch, which would be completed by the end of this financial year, was already starting to pay off and its profits would continue to grow.</p>
<p>&quot;We're satisfied that this year's trading result will be a very good one and we're satisfied that next year's one will not have any abnormals in it, so it'll be even better,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;And coupled with our restructuring, Gotch has had a great deal of success in regaining clients. We've picked up more business probably in the last six months than we have since we owned the business.  </p>
<p>&quot;So on both fronts, both picking up new business and finally getting what we wanted done on the cost side, we're very confident that we will see an excellent result from Gotch next year.&quot;</p>
<p>The situation with U.S. CD-Rom publishing house Teramedia was less certain and Robson said it remained to be seen whether its market improved.</p>
<p>&quot;But we've taken some pain in that area to try and tidy that issue up as well and we will certainly have it tidy by the end of the financial year.&quot;  </p>
<p>Although some final restructure costs and write-offs would be included in the second half result, Robson said he anticipated an improvement in INL's bottom line profit.</p>
<p>Robson was confident of bettering the last full-year result.</p>
<p>&quot;I would think so, yes. We're very confident the way the (second) half year's started. We'll see an improvement this year notwithstanding the special costs.</p>
<p>&quot;We were pretty pleased with the first half in fairly adverse circumstances, and notwithstanding a couple of quite big write-offs, we've still managed to outperform last year, so trading-wise we're very pleased.&quot;  </p>
<p>Robson said the proposed purchase of a stake in pay-TV operator Sky Network Television was by no means a done deal.</p>
<p>He said the chances of the deal going ahead were still 50-50 and indicated it may be some time yet before a final decision was made.</p>
<p>INL is just under half-owned by Rupert Murdoch's News Corporation. -- Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
