<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="399116" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan gold buyers sidelined, eyeing stock market.</title>
<headline>Taiwan gold buyers sidelined, eyeing stock market.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold buying interests in Taiwan will remain sidelined unless the stock market rally spurs new demand for the metal, traders said on Monday.</p>
<p>Local demand for physical gold was strong after prices fell below US$340 an ounce in recent days, but a quick rebound to above US$350 sent buyers to the sidelines, one dealer said. &quot;Demand for physical gold is strong below US$340 an ounce, but buyers are taking a wait-and-see stand now,&quot; said a trader at Taiwan's Central Trust of China.</p>
<p>Said a trader at Pan Asia Bank: &quot;below US$340 an ounce is a good buying point.&quot;</p>
<p>Gold bounced back from a low of US$336 an ounce on February 12 to US$351.90 on Saturday in recent volatile activity.</p>
<p>Traders said a further rise in Taiwan's booming stock market could boost local gold consumption, in part because demand for jewellery could be expected to rise. The Taiwan stock index has gained more than 1,000 points in January and February.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold consumption will increase significantly if the stock market bull rally continues,&quot; the Central Trust trader said.</p>
<p>More than 90 percent of Taiwan's gold imports are used for fabrication of jewellery, he said.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (2-508-0815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
