<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="399271" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China Fangda 1996 net 107.9 mln yuan.</title>
<headline>China Fangda 1996 net 107.9 mln yuan.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Building materials producer Shenzhen Fangda Industrial Co Ltd said on Monday its 1996 net profit was 107.9 million yuan based on international accounting standards.</p>
<p>Under domestic accounting standards, the profit was 107.26 million yuan, a surge of 157 percent from 1995's 41.74 million yuan, the company said in its annual report published in Monday's Shenzhen-based Securities Times.</p>
<p>The company was listed as a foreign currency B share company last year and its 1995 results had not been audited according to international accounting practices.</p>
<p>Earnings per share for 1996 were 0.511 yuan against 0.32 yuan in 1995 on a full diluted basis, the annual report said.</p>
<p>Turnover rose by 150.32 percent to 327.13 million yuan in 1996 from 130.69 million yuan in 1995, it said.</p>
<p>The report said the company planned to offer a 0.15 yuan per share cash dividend for all shareholders from its 1996 earnings. The plan will be submitted to shareholders for approval, it said.</p>
<p>Earlier, the company had made a four-for-10 bonus issue from the earnings for the first half of 1996.  </p>
<p>The firm forecast its 1997 post-tax profit to rise sharply due to the completion of two new projects, which would go into trial operation in March and would add 210 million yuan net earnings each year once in full operation, the report said.</p>
<p>It said it sold materials to major construction projects in 1996, including Zhengzhou International Airport and a railway station in Guangzhou, capital of Guangdong province.</p>
<p>By the end of 1996, Fangda had a total of 210 million outstanding shares, comprising 112 million legal person shares, 67,200 staff shares, 27.9328 million A shares and 70 million B shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
