<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39927" id="root" date="1996-09-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's League builds up to &quot;Independence Day&quot;.</title>
<headline>Italy's League builds up to &quot;Independence Day&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Paul Holmes</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-09-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>One of the more surreal political acts in modern Italy unfolds next week when firebrand secessionist Umberto Bossi gathers his forces on the River Po to declare independence for a &quot;republic&quot; that does not exist.</p>
<p>&quot;Padania&quot;, the name the Northern League party gives to its self-styled state in the affluent north, will be proclaimed by leader Bossi in Venice on September 15 after a near-mystical three-day pilgrimage along Italy's longest river.</p>
<p>From its source near Turin in the west to the 625 km (405 mile) long river's mouth in the east, Bossi is planning a series of high-profile rallies and demonstrations to mark the birth of a &quot;republic&quot; which no-one recognises.</p>
<p>Bossi, who has seized on northern frustration with central government, hopes one million supporters will flock to the river's banks next Sunday to form symbolic human chains along its course, the border of his &quot;virtual reality&quot; republic.</p>
<p>He says &quot;Padania&quot; will liberate what he portrays as repressed northerners from the scourge of rule from Rome.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to transform Italia into I-taglia,&quot; Bossi said on Sunday, playing on the name of the nation and a pun that translates as &quot;I-cut&quot;.</p>
<p>Several demonstrations in support of unity are set for the same weekend to counter a campaign that has raised howls across the political spectrum with reactions ranging from mockery to calls for Bossi's arrest.</p>
<p>Porn stars have announced plans to parade in Venice next Sunday with a banner reading: &quot;Dividing Italy is really obscene&quot;.</p>
<p>Bossi's party has built its appeal in the north, the powerhouse of Italy's economy, on deep discontent with high taxes, years of central government inefficiency and the corruption that sank the ruling political class four years ago.</p>
<p>It won up to 30 percent support in parts of the north to win some 3.7 million votes in a general election in April, making the League Italy's fourth largest party.</p>
<p>Despite its strong showing, however, the League failed to secure the balance of power in Italy's parliament, a setback which Bossi's chorus of critics say is behind his recent switch from a federalist to a secessionist agenda.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an element of desperation in Bossi,&quot; said Walter Veltroni, deputy prime minister in the centre-left government formed after the April election.</p>
<p>&quot;He was one of the many who had bet on a hung parliament that would have made his parliamentarians decisive for the formation of a government,&quot; Veltroni said.</p>
<p>He noted at the same time that Bossi's &quot;desperation may conjure up a monster which will be difficult to control, something that has had tragic consequences in Europe's history&quot;.</p>
<p>The government has resisted calls from the far right to ban Bossi's &quot;independence day&quot; demonstrations.</p>
<p>It reasons that to crack down would boost support for a split, which even many League voters oppose, and that the best response is planned legislation to make Italy a federal state.</p>
<p>That path, however, will take at least two years to tread since it will require constitutional reform.</p>
<p>Critics argue that the slow approach could play into Bossi's hands, giving him more ammunition to chip away at the unity of a relatively young nation. What is now Italy was a patchwork of statelets ruled by Popes, princes and foreign powers until 1870.</p>
<p>La Stampa newspaper, published in Turin, last week called the independence push &quot;the biggest political farce ever seen in Europe&quot; but argued that to ignore it was dangerous.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that the League's dream, Padania, is absurd from every point of view now risks becoming irrelevant,&quot; it wrote.</p>
<p>&quot;Indeed some scholars...are whispering that Italy itself seemed an absurd idea 150 years ago.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
