<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="399290" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan stocks jump 2.18 pct to six-year high close.</title>
<headline>Taiwan stocks jump 2.18 pct to six-year high close.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan share prices surged sharply to close at a six-year peak on Monday as expectations grew that the island's sputtering economic recovery was building steam, brokers said.</p>
<p>The weighted index closed 2.18 percent or 168.67 points higher at 7,908.61. That surpassed the 7,857.01 finish on June 2, 1990, and marked the market's highest close since it ended at 7,927.17 on May 17, 1990.  </p>
<p>At T$158.88 billion, turnover was only slightly below Friday's sizzling three-year high T$166.9 billion.</p>
<p>Hopes for a strong economy, which have fuelled prices since January, got a boost on Thursday with word that the economy grew a higher-than-expected 6.62 percent in the 1996 fourth quarter.</p>
<p>The uptick prompted the government to raise its forecast for 1997 gross domestic product growth to 6.28 from 6.20 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now it is difficult to see when this bull run will end, as the market seems to ignore all technical resistance,&quot; said Wang Jieh, an analyst for Foremost Investment Services.</p>
<p>The index has gained more than 1,000 point since January.  </p>
<p>Monday's buying focused on big-capital shares. Formosa Plastics and Nan Ya Plastics, both members of the giant Formosa group, rose T$4 and T$2 respectively to T$76.50 and T$67.50.</p>
<p>China Development Corp, one of Taiwan's largest venture capital firms owned in part by the ruling Nationalist Party, gained T$3.50 to close at T$114.</p>
<p>&quot;The large amount of liquidity in the market is circulating from share to share, and today was the big firms' turn to rise,&quot; said Yungli Securities analyst Chen Han-chung.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
