<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="399296" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan tells Albright post-Deng China looks stable.</title>
<headline>Japan tells Albright post-Deng China looks stable.</headline>
<byline>Yvonne Chang</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto told U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright on Monday that China appeared to be stable after the death of Deng Xiaoping and Tokyo expected no major changes there.</p>
<p>Hashimoto met the newly appointed Albright for breakfast before she left for Beijing, the last stop on a nine-nation tour.</p>
<p>&quot;Deng's death has been factored in and I don't expect any major change (in China),&quot; Hashimoto was quoted by a Japanese Foreign Ministry official as telling Albright.</p>
<p>On Sunday, Japanese Foreign Minister Yukihiko Ikeda said the fact that China was willing to play host to Albright so soon after Deng's death was a sign that it was stable.</p>
<p>Albright will be one of the first foreign dignitaries to meet Chinese leaders since Deng's demise last Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Japanese ministry official said Albright and Hashimoto had agreed that ties with China were growing in importance and promised to continue exchanging views on the issue.</p>
<p>The two did not discuss North Korea or the situation on the Korean Peninsula, the official said.</p>
<p>On bilateral issues, Hashimoto told Albright his cabinet was committed to easing the burden on residents of Okinawa caused by the U.S. military presence there and requested U.S. cooperation in relocating U.S. bases as already agreed by the two countries.</p>
<p>More than half the 49,000 U.S. military personnel in Japan are based on the sub-tropical island of Okinawa, about 1,600 km (1,000 miles) southwest of Tokyo. Opposition to the U.S. presence flared up after the rape of a 12-year-old schoolgirl by three U.S. servicemen in 1995, and islanders voted in a referendum last year for a scaling back of U.S. bases.</p>
<p>During a visit to Tokyo last April, President Bill Clinton agreed to a 20 percent cut in the size of the Okinawa bases.</p>
<p>Albright said she understood the sensitivity on the Okinawa issue but said it was equally important to maintain firm U.S.-Japan security ties, the Japanese ministry official said.</p>
<p>In talks with Ikeda soon after arriving in Tokyo on Sunday, Albright said Washington would maintain its current force levels in Japan and Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. presence in Asia is indispensable to ensuring stability of the region,&quot; Japanese officials quoted Albright as telling Hashimoto in Monday's talks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
