<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="399390" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Iraq-based Iran rebels seen reverting to force.</title>
<headline>Iraq-based Iran rebels seen reverting to force.</headline>
<byline>Michael Georgy</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran's exiled main opposition group is once again pinning its hopes on military operations after failing to promote itself diplomatically in the West as an viable alternative to Tehran's Islamic government, analysts say.</p>
<p>Iraq-based Mujahideen Khalq forces have recently engaged in a spate of clashes with Iranian security troops and the rebel group says more armed action is in store.</p>
<p>Tehran has said its troops killed some 25 Mujahideen members in about 10 clashes since early January, a cycle of violence unseen in recent years.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in a new phase of resistance,&quot; said Shahin Qobadi, a spokesman for the National Council of Resistance of Iran, the Mujahideen's Paris-based political arm.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the final phase in the rule of the mullahs' regime. The momentum is shifting. Hundreds of the mullahs' agents have been killed or wounded across the country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Most Western and Gulf-based analysts say the rebels' dream of toppling the government, which has kept a firm grip on power since the 1979 Islamic revolution, remains elusive.</p>
<p>They say the Mujahideen has little support in Iran because of its collaboration with Iraq during the 1980-88 Iran-Iraq war. But they see the Mujahideen perhaps trying some dramatic attacks in the coming months as Iran gears up for an election to replace President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani.</p>
<p>In the last presidential elections in 1993, the rebels said they attacked several oil installations, including Iran's largest refinery. Iran denied most of the attacks ever occurred.</p>
<p>Qobadi refused to say whether the group was about to adopt a similar strategy, but said &quot;You can expect more (attacks)&quot;.</p>
<p>London-based Iranian journalist Alireza Nourizadeh said the Mujahideen had returned to military action partly because of the failure of its diplomatic offensive.</p>
<p>&quot;The Mujahideen initially had some success in their diplomatic campaign in the West by getting support from some parliamentarians but I think the drive has gone downhill ever since the U.S. report on them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nourizadeh was referring to a State Department report which said in 1994 that the Mujahideen &quot;are not a viable alternative to the current government in Iran&quot;.</p>
<p>When Western countries led by the United States stepped up political and economic pressure on Iran in the early 1990s to isolate the Islamic republic, the Mujahideen saw an opening.</p>
<p>Some of its leaders travelled to Western capitals to seek political support for bringing down Iran's government.</p>
<p>Group members stood on street corners in the West hoping to win sympathy with gruesome photographs of comrades allegedly tortured by the Tehran government.</p>
<p>But the Mujahideen found itself empty-handed, despite Western opposition to the Iranian government for its alleged support for terrorism -- a charge denied by Tehran.</p>
<p>Despite pressure in Congress, the Clinton administration refused to deal with the Mujahideen, citing past anti-American actions, dependence on Iraq and a lack of support inside Iran.</p>
<p>The Mujahideen, originally Islamic leftists, played a key role in the 1979 revolution that ousted the Shah but soon broke with Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini. It was suppressed in a widespread crackdown launched in 1981.</p>
<p>Iran's government brands them terrorists.</p>
<p>The Mujahideen were recently given a badly needed bonus.</p>
<p>Iraqi President Saddam Hussein, facing souring relations with non-Arab Iran, has given the group greater freedom.</p>
<p>&quot;Iraq is letting them launch some attacks across the border but I think Baghdad will keep these limited because it does not want a new war with Iran,&quot; said Nourizadeh.</p>
<p>Tensions have mounted between Iran and Iraq after Baghdad in December accused Tehran of involvement in an attack which wounded Saddam's eldest son.</p>
<p>London-based Middle East analyst Hazhir Teimourian said: &quot;In my opinion the military activity of the Mujahideen always reflects the state of relations between Iran and Iraq.&quot;</p>
<p>The Mujahideen denys launching cross-border raids and insist underground cells in Iran are engaged in the clashes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
