<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="399311" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai rates to stay high to beat baht speculators.</title>
<headline>Thai rates to stay high to beat baht speculators.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Minister Amnuay Viravan said on Monday that Thailand would keep interest rates at a high level to counter any attack by offshore speculators on the baht.</p>
<p>He also reiterated to Reuters Financial Television in an interview that there would be no devaluation or depreciation of the baht at any time.  </p>
<p>The minister also said that he did not see any Thai finance firm collapsing because of loan exposure to the troubled domestic property sector. The market has been worried about the quality of finance company loans to ailing property firms.</p>
<p>Amnuay also said he was confident that Thailand would be able to convince ratings agency Moody's Investor Service that the country's economic policies were on track.</p>
<p>Moody's recently warned that Thailand's long-term foreign currency debt and deposit ratings faced a possible downgrading because of concerns over the soundness of the Thai financial sector and constraints on macro-economic policy making.</p>
<p>A Moody's team is due to visit Thailand early next month to study further details of economic trends.  </p>
<p>Amnuay said: &quot;Yes, we will keep interest rates high...we would not allow other people to speculate against our currency.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Speculation (against the baht) has greatly subsided and I would expect this to go away. We also expect that once the currency becomes more stable, other aspects of the financial markets, including the stock market, will gradually return to normal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The minister said although short-term Thai interbank rates have surged in recent weeks, prime lending rates quoted by major Thai banks have remained relatively stable at about 13.50-13.75 percent.</p>
<p>Asked about the weak earnings outlook of finance companies with large lending exposure to the ailing property sector, the minister said not all financial institutions have problems.</p>
<p>&quot;Some marginal institutions have liquidity problems but the central bank has watched it very closely and it has measures that it can inject liquidity to ensure that financial institutions will be able to survive problems.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't believe there will be any collapse of financial institutions or finance companies or commercial banks. Some are very strong and affiliated with banks. I don't think anything will go out of control.&quot;  </p>
<p>Asked if he expected Moody's to reaffirm Thailand's current A1 sovereign debt rating, Amnuay said: &quot;We cannot tell them what to do. But we have facts and figures to show that we have made policies to correct and address some of their concerns. It is something we cannot do overnight but we have taken the right actions at the right time.</p>
<p>&quot;I have reasonable confidence that we will able to convince the academics that what we are doing for the economy of Thailand is correct,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The minister said sceptics of the baht's stability would be proved wrong.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank governor and the finance ministry have come out publicly and strongly, and in unequivocal terms, that we will not devalue the currency,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The stability of the currency is in the best interest and devaluation of the baht will do more harm than good...the baht only depreciated only less than three percentage points against the dollar in the past year or so, from 25.40 to about 25.95 or 25.99.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662)-6520642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
