<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="399447" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turk opposition unable to bring down Islamists.</title>
<headline>Turk opposition unable to bring down Islamists.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Lyons</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's Islamist-led coalition looks set to survive its fifth parliamentary challenge in as many months, underscoring the inability of mainstream secularists to put forward a government formula of their own.</p>
<p>Analysts say opposition parties appear incapable of mobilising the 276 votes needed in the 550-seat parliament when a censure motion against Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan is considered on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The opposition is not opposing,&quot; said one senior Western diplomat.</p>
<p>Passage of the motion would bring down Erbakan's 10-month-old government, an uneasy partnership between his Islamist Welfare Party and the conservatives of U.S.-educated Tansu Ciller. The two control 278 seats between them.</p>
<p>The censure vote follows a string of defeats last week, when parliament voted not to impeach Ciller for alleged corruption while head of the previous cabinet. Anti-government forces fell short by 19 votes in their best showing.</p>
<p>Analysts and politicians say this repeated failure is all the more glaring, given Turkey's officially secularist system, strong backing from the officer corps, and growing unease within society at Islamist policies.</p>
<p>President Suleyman Demirel, whose role is mostly symbolic, has tried to compensate for the lack of a strong opposition.</p>
<p>&quot;I urge the free media, the free judiciary and politicians to come and protect Turkish democracy and the Turkish republic,&quot; he said in an interview with the Milliyet daily published on Monday. Demirel voiced rare criticism of Islamists last week.</p>
<p>A series of Islam-based proposals, including the lifting of a ban on Islamic headscarves for female government workers, has alarmed the secular public and upset the powerful armed forces. Most were later withdrawn or toned down.</p>
<p>Even the defection of 17 MPs from Ciller's True Path Party -- leaving her with 118 -- has failed to turn the tide.</p>
<p>Mesut Yilmaz, laconic leader of the main opposition Motherland Party (ANAP), has proved largely ineffective and is subject of a budding leadership challenge.</p>
<p>And a bitter feud between rival leftist parties has further complicated the search for a formula that would exclude Erbakan and his Islamist Welfare Party.</p>
<p>Restive ANAP deputies have begun to go public.</p>
<p>MP Cemil Cicek, in remarks to the mass-circulation Sabah daily, issued a thinly-veiled call for Yilmaz to step down for failing to lead the party of late president Turgut Ozal back to power.</p>
<p>&quot;In the West political leaders are convergent and make concessions. Ours are quarrelsome, provacative, gossipy and splittist,&quot; Cicek said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the West you stay in your job if you win and do well. You go if you lose. Here you stay whether you win or not.&quot;</p>
<p>Divisions on the left have also plagued the campaign to replace Erbakan with a government more in line with modern Turkey's secularist vocation.</p>
<p>A proposal to unite the Republican People's Party and the Democratic Left Party was shot down late last week by Bulent Ecevit, leader of the Democratic Left and former prime minister.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if the whole world wanted it, I would not unite (with the Republican People's Party),&quot; Ecevit declared.</p>
<p>The failure of the secularists to oust Erbakan, who captured a plurality of just 21 percent of the vote in the last general polls, has drawn the armed forces into the political limelight.</p>
<p>Three times in the last 36 years the military has stepped in to domestic politics, deposing elected governments. Earlier this month the general sent tanks into an Islamist district to express their concern for the direction of the country.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
