<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="399414" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordanian shares maintain modest gains.</title>
<headline>Jordanian shares maintain modest gains.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordanian shares registered modest gains for a third day on Monday, rising 0.13 percent on the back of cautious but sustained demand from institutional investors, brokers said.</p>
<p>The official Amman Financial Market (AFM) index rose 0.21 points to 156.85 points in trade worth 653,000 dinars ($922,000).</p>
<p>&quot;There is still institutional demand and it is picking up slowly,&quot; said analyst Mohammad Abdallah of Pearl Consulting. &quot;The market is just taking it step by step.&quot;</p>
<p>Brokers said a cabinet decision on Saturday to cancel a 1,000 dinar minimum investment level for foreign investors on the exchange was positive but had little tangible effect because foreign share purchases tended to be at much higher quantities.</p>
<p>Arab Pharmaceutical Manufacturers, Monday's busiest stock with a turnover of 130,000 dinars, rose 0.05 dinars to 3.90 dinars. Arab Bank, another blue chip stock, rose 0.5 dinars to 262.5 in trade worth 116,000 dinars.</p>
<p>Other banks and industrial stocks which gained in busy trade included Jordan National Bank, relisted last week after merging with the Business Bank, Jordan Cement Factories and Jordan Worsted Mills, which all rose slightly.</p>
<p>Overall 21 shares rose on Monday and nine fell, while another 12 traded but closed unchanged.</p>
<p>The private Pearl Index of the 45 most-traded shares on the exchange rose 0.12 percent to 82.87 points, still 0.62 percent down from the start of the year.</p>
<p>-- Amman newsroom +9626 623776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
