<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="399495" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: D.C. airport reopened after suspected gas leak.</title>
<headline>D.C. airport reopened after suspected gas leak.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Washington's National Airport was partially evacuated and flights were diverted to a nearby airport on Sunday after gas fumes were detected in the lobby of the main terminal, airport officials said.</p>
<p>Spokesman Jonathan Gaffney said the lobby of the main terminal and the control tower were reopened at 8 p.m. EST after two hours.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not back to normal, but we're getting there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Spokeswoman Tara Hamilton said the local gas company, Washington Gas, had arrived on the scene, turned off the gas and an investigation into the cause of the odor was underway.</p>
<p>It was still unclear what caused the fumes in the lobby, which houses the ticket counters of United Airlines, Air Canada and Trans World Airways (TWA).</p>
<p>She later told reporters that hazardous material investigators had removed a trash can that was emitting a suspicious odor, although it was unclear what was inside.</p>
<p>A total of six flights had been diverted to Washington Dulles International Airport, Gaffney said.</p>
<p>Passengers and airport employees were evacuated only from the lobby area, the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Hamilton said the incident appeared unrelated to a similar one several months ago in which a transit bus hit a gas pipeline in a tunnel on the airport grounds, forcing the evacuation of another smaller terminal and delaying flights for hours.</p>
<p>The fumes were first detected between 5:30 p.m. and 6 p.m., she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
