<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="399561" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: NATO-Russia move closer to enlargement deal.</title>
<headline>NATO-Russia move closer to enlargement deal.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Clayton</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>NATO and Russia have moved closer to a groundbreaking deal on a new post-Cold War relationship though major problems still cloud the alliance's eastwards expansion, alliance sources said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The pace is quickening, we share a great deal of common ground,&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>He was commenting after the latest round of talks between NATO Secretary-General Javier Solana and Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov which ended late on Sunday.</p>
<p>NATO sources said the two sides had agreed on the need to set up a permanent consulatative mechanism to govern future relations. Russia had expressed a preference for this to be enshrined in a new document rather than a NATO-proposed charter.</p>
<p>A new joint Russia-NATO Council would be separate to NATO with its own secretariat in which both sides would have an equal voice, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;We are drawing closer together on the idea of a distinct NATO-Russia consultative council,&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>A brief joint communique issued after the talks at Solana's private residence said progress had been made at the talks although differences remained. It gave no other details.</p>
<p>Alliance sources said Russia was still pushing for a legally binding document whereas NATO preferred a more flexible political commitment and was seeking assurances new military equipment would not be placed on the territory of new members.</p>
<p>NATO sources say any final NATO-Russia document could be endorsed by heads of state and government at a summit in Madrid next July at which NATO will invite some former Warsaw Pact states to join the alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;It would in itself be a solemn and very important document,&quot; another source said. NATO is concerned that a legal document would take years to be ratified by all the alliance's 16 member parliaments, a tactic favoured by Russia to delay expansion.</p>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin accepted on Sunday enlargement may go ahead, but said his country's plan was to stall it as long as possible.</p>
<p>Senior NATO sources cautioned no major breakthrough could be expected in the near future, but said a real dialogue had no started after months of shadow-boxing.</p>
<p>&quot;The Russians want to engage, and are serious,&quot; one official said.</p>
<p>Primakov declined to talk to reporters during his visit to Brussels. Early on Monday, a black limousine swept the former Cold War spy-master to a private aircraft waiting in a secluded corner of Brussels airport. He left shortly afterwards.</p>
<p>Before his talks started, Yeltsin, speaking in Moscow, gave the clearest hint yet the pace of the negotiations was hotting up.</p>
<p>Making his first public appearance since his bout of pneumonia at the New Year, Yeltsin said he expected a compromise to be struck during his summit with U.S. President Bill Clinton next month.</p>
<p>He said Moscow would continue its resistance to NATO expansion but then told reporters at a Kremlin wreath-laying:</p>
<p>&quot;We have agreed to look for a compromise and I think we will find this compromise at the summit we are holding with President Clinton on March 20-21.&quot;</p>
<p>While NATO insists it will not let Moscow have a veto over who can join the alliance, it has offered a range of measures to try to reassure Russia that the admission of former Soviet satellites on its western flank will not be a security threat.</p>
<p>It would like to set down an agreement guaranteeing Russia a place in the new European security architecture before the July summit when the alliance is expected to invite Hungary, Poland and the Czech Republic to join.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
