<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39963" id="root" date="1996-09-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: News Corp's Star stalks Hindi market.</title>
<headline>News Corp's Star stalks Hindi market.</headline>
<byline>Simon Cameron-Moore</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The big cat of the media world, Rupert Murdoch's News Corp, has moved closer to sinking its teeth deeper into India's vast Hindi and regional language television audience, analysts said at the weekend.</p>
<p>The government announced on Friday approval for an $11 million direct foreign investment for News Television India Private Ltd (NTVI), a News Corp affiliate.</p>
<p>While this represents little in money terms, clearance for NTVI effectively to operate as an Indian company will send shudders through domestic broadcasters, the sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Murdoch) is trying to push aggressively into the market through this move,&quot; Ashish Bhatnagar, media analyst for Bombay brokerage SS Kantilal Ishwarlal Securities (SSKI), told Reuters.</p>
<p>India's television industry currently is dominated by state- owned Doordarshan, with access to more than 70 million homes in a nation with an estimated population of 930 million people.</p>
<p>Independent industry consultant Iqbal Malhotra described Friday's news as a victory for Murdoch that would probably annoy domestic operators.</p>
<p>&quot;It gives NTVI carte blanche to operate in India,&quot; Malhotra said, adding that NTVI's next step could be to apply to become an Indian broadcaster.</p>
<p>News Corp's Hong Kong-based subsidiary, Star TV, owns 40 percent of NTVI. The rest is owned by a Mauritius-based offshore company  International Graphics Holdings, which has the advantage of being headed by a Non-Resident Indian (NRI).</p>
<p>NTVI is a production house and an advertising sales agent effectively managing Star's interests in India.</p>
<p>If NTVI applies to become a broadcaster, and if the law changes to allow links to satellites from Indian soil -- currently prohibited -- Star will be better placed than any rivals to beam in on the direct-to-home market across India.</p>
<p>A senior Star offical in Bombay refused to comment on the new status of NTVI.</p>
<p>Industry sources say domestic broadcasters are concerned over foreign entry into the market in an apparent attempt to protect their advertising revenues.</p>
<p>They said Star might consider satellite links to broadcast live news and sports out of India if the laws changed.</p>
<p>The domestic political lobby against foreign media involvement in India is strong as the government pushes ahead with economic liberalisation.</p>
<p>But it has already stalled a bid by Pearson Plc, the owners of the Financial Times, to form a joint venture with an Indian newspaper.</p>
<p>There was immediate media speculation after a meeting in June between Murdoch and then newly-appointed Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda that the press baron had smoothed the path for Star's ambitions.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Mr Rupert Murdoch has a long term plan for India,&quot; said SSKI's Bhatnagar.</p>
<p>Four Star channels are currently broadcast in India via cable link to the major cities. Now, there is speculation that Star plans to transform programming of the Star Plus channel in India to appeal to the Hindi-language market.</p>
<p>But cable is an expensive method of delivery. Setting up access to the vast market outside the major cities via satellite could provide Star with the crown for some badly needed jewels.</p>
<p>News Corp needs to turnaround loss-maker Star's fortunes. In the year to June 30 Star increased revenues by 35 percent but its operating losses were estimated at around $80 million as it continued to regionalise its programming and push into Japan.</p>
<p>The Indian market has been identified as a prime target for growth. At stake is India's annual spending on television advertising of $350 million, said Malhotra.</p>
<p>Other independent forecasts say that figure could rise close to $1.0 billion by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Malhotra estimated Star's current share at less than seven percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
