<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="399638" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Court delays judgment on French cyberspace claim.</title>
<headline>Court delays judgment on French cyberspace claim.</headline>
<byline>Irwin Arieff</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Paris court on Monday delayed a ruling on the extent of France's reach into cyberspace, ordering more hearings on whether the French campus of a U.S. university violated French law by using English alone on its Internet site.</p>
<p>The court set further arguments for April 28 on procedural aspects of France's 1994 Toubon law promoting the French language -- a move suggesting the court may be trying to throw out the case on technical grounds, officials on both sides said.</p>
<p>&quot;This would be a pity because the fundamental question in the case is an important one,&quot; said attorney Marc Jobert, representing the private French culture watchdog groups who brought the case against the French campus of the Georgia Institute of Technology.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very important that we prevail in this case, or a large number of (Internet) sites in France will be quickly disconnected and set up in other countries, a development which would be inconsistent with France's economic development hopes,&quot; countered Hans Puttgen, director of Georgia Tech Lorraine in the eastern city of Metz.</p>
<p>The legal debate is part of a long-running battle by France to protect the language of Moliere and Racine against the growing global grip of English.</p>
<p>The ruling is likely to have wide implications for the reach of national laws over the Internet. While Internet champions argue the network should operate free of local restraint, many national governments have asserted authority over it, often to restrict pornography or stifle political dissent.</p>
<p>The Paris court asked for additional debate specifically on the Toubon law's procedures for bringing complaints. Lawyers predicted a judgment before the end of June.</p>
<p>Georgia Tech argued in the January 6 trial that communications on the Internet were like telephone calls and outside the reach of the Toubon law, which requires that all advertising in France be in French.</p>
<p>The two watchdog groups, Defence of the French Language and Future of the French Language, said the Internet was public in nature rather than private like a phone call.</p>
<p>They urged the court to force Georgia Tech Lorraine to pay a fine and damages of 20,000 francs ($4,000) and oblige it to translate the Internet site into French.</p>
<p>&quot;You cannot legislate language,&quot;  Puttgen told reporters on Monday. &quot;People must want to learn that language.&quot;</p>
<p>He argued that numerous other French Internet sites including some under state control were in English alone and said he regretted that Georgia Tech had been singled out since it sought to promote multicultural integration.</p>
<p>But Jobert dismissed as &quot;paranoia&quot; Puttgen's argument that Georgia Tech had been made into a scapegoat by his clients.</p>
<p>&quot;We are entirely prepared to pursue all offenders,&quot; he said, denying any anti-American bias. &quot;All we want is a French version of the site.&quot;</p>
<p>The Georgia Tech Lorraine site -- whose Internet address is www.georgiatech- metz.fr -- offers course descriptions, a guide to the campus and other information for current and potential students.</p>
<p>Georgia Tech Lorraine, most of whose students are French, has argued that the site is in English because all its courses are taught in English and all its students are required to be fluent English-speakers.</p>
<p>But Puttgen said the site might be revised in the future to add material in other languages including German as well as French though it would not be revised until the current lawsuit had been decided.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
