<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="39980" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks end mixed, ignore Wall St. rally.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks end mixed, ignore Wall St. rally.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toronto stocks ended mixed on Monday as sagging gold shares depressed Canada's biggest stock market while New York equities surged.</p>
<p>The TSE 300 Composite Index slipped 1.35 points to close at 5148.55 in turnover of 70.2 million shares valued at C$783 million ($571 million).</p>
<p>But advancing stocks still outpaced declines 448 to 418 with 293 issues ending flat.</p>
<p>By comparison, the Dow Jones average soared nearly 74 points.</p>
<p>&quot;New York was leading the way, but Toronto was weighed down by the poor performance in golds,&quot; said Ira Katzin, an investment advisor for Richardson Greenshields of Canada Ltd.</p>
<p>The TSE's heavyweight gold group sank 256 points as gold prices hit fresh two-month lows during the session. COMEX December gold ended down US$1.60 at US$387.20 an ounce.</p>
<p>Toronto also posted minor losses in communications, conglomerates, base metals and pipelines.</p>
<p>The TSE's nine strong sectors were led by consumer products, transportation, financial services and retailing.</p>
<p>Toronto's strong side was also helped by buoyant North American bond markets.</p>
<p>Canada's 9.00 percent bond due 2001 climbed C$0.75 to C$101.50 to yield 7.863 percent.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Among weak gold stocks, Barrick Gold Corp. fell 0.90 to 36.30 on 989,000 shares. Placer Dome Inc. dropped 0.90 to 32 on 1.06 million shares.</p>
<p>* Shell Canada Ltd. jumped 1.05 to 46.40 after announcing a major natural gas deal with Houston-based Coral Energy LP.</p>
<p>* Laidlaw Inc. class B gained 0.15 to 13.50 after the waste and transportation giant was upgraded to outperform from market perform by U.S.-based Donaldson, Lufkin and Jenrette.</p>
<p>* Biovail Corp International was the top gainer, rising 5.50 to 42.50. The stock climbed on a positive article on the biotechnology firm published in the U.S. business magazine Barron's.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
