<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="399824" id="root" date="1997-02-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Finland - Feb 24.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Finland - Feb 24.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the leading stories in Finnish papers this morning.</p>
<p>HELSINGIN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Some 20-30 percent of the world's cosmetics industry's aromatic raw material come from Cultor's CAL plant in southern France.</p>
<p>- Fish fingers are children's favourite dish at schools.</p>
<p>- Motorsleighing hobby spreading from Lapland to central Finland.</p>
<p>- Interior ministry plans easier procedure for citizenship application; waiting times now approaching three years. @</p>
<p>- Army planning to increase sports in its training.</p>
<p>- Lifetime prison sentences should be implemented for paedophiles and other sex criminals, Justice Minister Kari Hakamies says.</p>
<p>KAUPPALEHTI</p>
<p>- Metsa-Serla has in the past year sold its stake in UPM-Kymmene, Merita and Pohjola have reduced holdings, large-holdings register shows.</p>
<p>- Mobile phone companies are a good investment this year, says Colin Stone, manager of  Fidelity 's Nordic and European smaller companies fund. @</p>
<p>- Mutual life-insurer Suomi's assets belong to its policy holders, who should get proper compensation if they are sold to Pohjola, says Jarmo Leppiniemi, chairman of the private investor lobby.</p>
<p>AAMULEHTI</p>
<p>- Women's fear of becoming victims of violence is turning to a daily problem, a study shows.</p>
<p>- Finland needs more personnel to manage its relationship with NATO, says Finland's ambassador to Belgium Leif Blomqvist.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki Newsroom +358-9-680 50 242</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
