<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40005" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Buba's Welteke says M3 to determine rate cut room.</title>
<headline>Buba's Welteke says M3 to determine rate cut room.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bundesbank council member Ernst Welteke on Monday kept hopes alive for another German interest rate cut, saying there may still be room to ease rates further if German money supply growth continues to slow.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters Financial Television, Welteke said, &quot;When this (M3 growth) comes closer to the corridor or into the corridor... then there is room enough because the discount rate is at 2.50 percent and we therefore have room for The Bundesbank's money supply growth target is set between four and seven percent. M3 in July grew at an annualised seasonally-adjusted rate of 8.6 percent, below double-digit levels seen earlier in the year.</p>
<p>Welteke noted that M3, a key policy guideline, had slowed in recent months, helping the council to justify its decision to slice 30 basis points off the main money market rate, the repo, in late August.</p>
<p>The repo is now fixed at three percent, down from 3.30 percent where it had been since February.</p>
<p>The discount rate, the floor on German interest rates, is at 2.50 percent while the Lombard rate, the ceiling on rates, is at 4.50 percent. Both rates were last cut in April.</p>
<p>Money supply growth has slowed dramatically since early in the year when buoyant private-sector borrowing and sluggish capital formation, or savings at the long-end of the yield curve, helped lock growth at double-digit levels.</p>
<p>Welteke, who is also the president of the state central bank of Hesse, earlier on Monday told a group of foreign bankers that German interest rates were unlikely to change direction in the near future.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
