<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40001" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Blue chips soar; market confident on interest rates.</title>
<headline>Blue chips soar; market confident on interest rates.</headline>
<byline>Betty Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue-chip stocks jumped Monday as investors grew more confident that the Federal Reserve will increase interest rates only modestly, if at all, later this month.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average ended up 73.98 points, or 1.31 percent, at 5,733.84, just below its record closing high of 5,778.00 set on May 22.</p>
<p>In the broader market, advancing issues beat declines 1,536 to 851 on moderate volume of 310 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Analysts said investors took a second look at Friday's August jobs report and attributed some of the data's strength to seasonal factors.</p>
<p>&quot;There's some renewed investor confidence for the time being that inflation and interest rates are not a problem,&quot; said Michael Metz, chief investment strategist at Oppenheimer &amp; Co.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Dow index surged 53 points after an increase of 250,000 in non-farm payrolls for August was not as strong as many had feared.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of the new employees were teachers and managerial types. The more you look at it, there's a seasonal swing,&quot; said Robert Stovall, president of Stovall/21st Advisers.</p>
<p>&quot;Portfolio managers drew a little courage from the figures and there's the expectation of no move by the Fed,&quot; Metz said.</p>
<p>He said Monday's buying was mostly concentrated in blue chips. &quot;People did not have the courage to trade down.&quot;</p>
<p>The central bank's policy-setting Federal Open Market Committee, which meets on Sept. 24, last changed monetary policy in January, when it lowered the federal funds rate by one-quarter percentage point to its current target rate of 5.25 percent.</p>
<p>Opinions are mixed as to whether the central bank will decide this time to raise or leave interest rates unchanged, perhaps until after the Nov. 5 presidential election.</p>
<p>In the bond market, the 30-year Treasury bond rose 14/32 of a point, or $4.375 per $1,000 face value, and its yield, which moves in the opposite direction of its price, dropped to 7.07 percent from Friday's close of 7.11 percent.</p>
<p>Federal Reserve Bank of Boston President Cathy Minehan cited only limited signs of price pressures in the otherwise healthy economy.</p>
<p>&quot;Throughout this period of strong employment and output performance, the core rate of inflation remained remarkably well-behaved,&quot; Minehan told the annual conference of the Association of Business Economists in Boston on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Surges in oil and grain prices contributed to a small increase in overall consumer price inflation. But it appears that these industry-specific price disruptions may not feed into overall wages and prices,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the market will be closely watching this week's inflation barometers, especially the August Producer Prices Index, due Thursday, and the Consumer Price Index on Friday.</p>
<p>Gold mining stocks fell as inflation fears ebbed. Newmont Gold Co. lost 1-3/4 to 52-1/2 and Newmont Mining Corp. fell 1-1/8 to 51-3/4.</p>
<p>Stovall said oil stocks, which have been supported by U.S.-Iraq tensions, &quot;have quieted down.&quot; Chevron Corp. rose 1/8 to 60-3/8, Texaco Inc. added 1/2 to 93-1/2 and Exxon Corp. inched up 1/4 to 84-1/4.</p>
<p>Among other blue-chips, United Technologies Corp. rose 3-1/2 to 115-3/4, International Business Machines Corp. gained 2-3/8 to 117-5/8, Caterpillar Inc. was up 1-3/4 to 73-1/2, DuPont Co. rose one to 84-5/8, and Union Carbide Corp. was up 1-7/8 to 45-1/8.</p>
<p>A spate of merger announcements galvanised some buying interest. Big B Inc. climbed 3-1/4 to 15-7/8 and was the most-active Nasdaq issue after a hostile $15 a share offer from Revco D.S. Inc., which slipped 1/8 to 25-1/2.</p>
<p>Britain's Danka Business Systems Plc agreed to buy Eastman Kodak Co.'s office imaging business and facilities management business for $684 million in cash. Danka surged 6-5/8 to 36-1/2 in U.S. trading and Kodak slipped 1/2 to 71-3/4.</p>
<p>Also, Phar-Mor Inc. and ShopKo Stores Inc. said they will merge, creating a new company -- Cabot Noble Inc. Phar-Mor lost 3/4 to 7-3/8 and ShopKo lost 1/8 to 16-1/8.</p>
<p>DAKA International slumped 5-3/8 to 10 and DII Group Inc. lost four to 19 after both warned of earnings shortfalls.</p>
<p>SGS-Thomson Microelectronics surged four to 43-7/8 in U.S. trading on news that it developed an integrated circuit that protects digital video systems from copyright pirates who copy film, music and other material.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index rose 9.32 points to 1,148.71.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks was up 8.09 to 663.77. The American Stock Exchange index was up 1.94 to 561.96.</p>
<p>The NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks rose 3.61 to 356.28. The average share was up 40 cents.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 6,515,512 up 65.760 or 1.02 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
