<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="400120" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ClinTrials sees Q1 to be $0.04 vs $0.08.</title>
<headline>ClinTrials sees Q1 to be $0.04 vs $0.08.</headline>
<dateline>NASHVILLE, Tenn. 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>ClinTrials Research Inc said Tuesday its earnings per share for the first quarter ending March 31, 1997 are expected to be about $O.04, compared with $0.08 in the year earlier period.</p>
<p>The figure takes into account an increase in number of shares outstanding of 33 percent in 1997 compared with 1996, William C. O'Neil Jr., chairman and chief executive officer of the company, said.</p>
<p>He said earnings per share could be further affected by the unfavorable resolution of a dispute regarding an ongoing project.  </p>
<p>At the same time, the company said revenues in the first quarter are expected to be in the $27-28 million  range, an increase of 61 percent compared with $17.7 million for the comparable quarter in 1996.</p>
<p>O'Neil said ClinTrials recently learned that three projects totaling $27 million were canceled in February 1997, one of which approximated $21.5 million in size.</p>
<p>The three projects are in addition to the previously reported cancellation of two medium size ones amounting to $10 million in the fourth quarter of 1996, he said.  </p>
<p>O'Neil said that none the cancellations were related to service or quality problems.</p>
<p>&quot;This decrease in backlog of work to be performed is the primary reason for the expected earnings decline in the first quarter, as the company was left with unbillable resources related to these projects,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>ClinTrials is currently discussing with a client the status of work on a &quot;significant&quot; project, he said. If the resolution of those discussions turns out to be negative, it could result in a charge to ClinTrials's earnings in the first quarter of up to $1.5 million or $O.05 per share, he said.  </p>
<p>The company, he said, has also reached a higher level of general and administrative expense to cover the expected higher revenue levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The timing and magnitude of these events are certainly unfortunate, but they always have been and will continue to be potential industry events and do not affect the fundamental strengths of our business, which is a strong management team and quality service,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>O'Neil said ClinTrials was working diligently to replace the canceled backlog and anticipate that it can return to improved revenue and earnings growth by year-end 1997.</p>
<p>ClinTrials contract research organization serving the pharmaceutical, biotechnology and medical device industries on a global basis.  The company designs, monitors and manages clinical trials and provides clinical data management and biostatistical services, as well as other ancillary support programs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NASHVILLE, Tenn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
