<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="400407" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: SOCCER-ALBANIA LEAGUE LEADERS BOYCOTT FIXTURES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ALBANIA LEAGUE LEADERS BOYCOTT FIXTURES.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's soccer league leaders Flamurtari say they will boycott further matches in support of protests in their home town of Vlore against a savings scheme scandal, a soccer official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Albanian soccer federation secretary-general Eduard Dervishi said officials had hoped to resume league fixtures this weekend following security guarantees from the interior ministry.</p>
<p>Sports events were halted a month ago when violent protests against collapsed pyramid investment schemes swept the country.</p>
<p>&quot;Flamurtari, the soccer club of Vlore, let us know today they will not take part in the league in support of their town's protest,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The team is currently in top position and its action puts the league in doubt. We shall urgently decide what to do next.&quot;</p>
<p>The team said in a statement: &quot;Flamurtari soccer club have decided to act in solidarity with the citizens of Vlore. We live and feel everyday their concerns which cannot but touch our club and its players.&quot;</p>
<p>Demonstrators in Vlore, 150 km south of Tirana, some of whom have lost their life savings in the investment swindle, have held daily peaceful protests in the Adriatic port town for the past three weeks.</p>
<p>Albania's secretary of state for sport Marjeta Zace told the soccer foundation last week it could resume its weekly soccer fixtures.</p>
<p>&quot;Starting the league this weekend would serve as a test for the coming World Cup qualifiers,&quot; Dervishi said. &quot;The Vlore case is a very disturbing situation for us as FIFA will decide next week what to do with our two qualifiers.&quot;</p>
<p>Tirana hopes Albania's World Cup group nine home matches against Ukraine on March 29 and Germany on April 2 will go ahead but officials said they were still awaiting an answer from FIFA.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
