<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="400464" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: RADIO ROMANIA AFTERNOON HEADLINES AT 1 PM.</title>
<headline>RADIO ROMANIA AFTERNOON HEADLINES AT 1 PM.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Radio Romania news headlines:</p>
<p>* Prime Minister Victor Ciorbea is the guest of a talk show on Romanian national radio at 6 p.m. to answer questions on reform and social security.</p>
<p>* Lower Chamber of Deputies' Chairman Ion Diaconescu met Victor Orban, the chairman of Hungarian parliament's European integration commission to discuss joint efforts for the countries' admission in NATO and the European Union.</p>
<p>* Deputies resumed debate on a draft law on the status of pharmacists.</p>
<p>* King Michael's visit to Romania could be the first step to restoring the monarchy, Greater Romania Party deputy Corneliu Ciontu told parliament. He asked the government to reveal how the monarch's visit is being financed.</p>
<p>* The government should assume responsibility for the unpredictable effects of the king's visit to Romania, Petre Turlea, deputy of the National Unity Party said.</p>
<p>* Theoretically we could discuss certain reparations concerning the assets of the royal house, justice ministry secretary of state Dinu Ianculescu told the radio.</p>
<p>He said that legally the government's decision to restore King Michael's citizenship cannot affect the constitutional order in Romania. Neither can property rights be changed for the monarch in the current legislation.</p>
<p>The former king needs to subject himself to the country's the constitution, Ianculescu said.</p>
<p>* Trade unions in geology, the steel industry and mining from the northern county of Maramures demand clear government announcements on planned reforms and restructuring in the area. They asked that job cuts be negotiated with unions.</p>
<p>* Four mines in the western Apuseni mountains closed on Tuesday after the Renel electricity authority made power cuts due to outstanding energy bills.</p>
<p>Mine officials said the mines will need to make temporary job cuts of some 75 percent of the employees before energy supplies are restored. -- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
