<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="400423" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA BASKETBALL-MAGIC BEAT PISTONS AS HARDAWAY SCORES 29.</title>
<headline>NBA BASKETBALL-MAGIC BEAT PISTONS AS HARDAWAY SCORES 29.</headline>
<dateline>ORLANDO, Florida 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Penny Hardaway scored 29 points and the Orlando Magic held Pistons superstar Grant Hill in check in a 93-84 victory over Detroit Monday that kept interim coach Richie Adubato unbeaten.</p>
<p>Rony Seikaly added 19 points and eight rebounds for the Magic, who are 4-0 since Adubato replaced the fired Brian Hill on Tuesday. Orlando had lost its last five games under Hill, including one to Detroit.</p>
<p>&quot;In Detroit, I was missing a lot of shots and a couple of their players that I don't want to name -- maybe two or three of them -- were talking a lot of trash, really being a little cocky,&quot; said Hardaway.</p>
<p>&quot;I said, 'Hey, it's just one game,' and I missed a lot of shots. I tried to make up for it tonight.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;He made threes. He made steals. He played defence,&quot; Adubato said of Hardaway. &quot;He penetrated, and he got big baskets whenever we needed him tonight. He played like the true star that he is.&quot;</p>
<p>Theo Ratliff scored 17 points and Hill added just 14 for the Pistons, who had a six-game winning streak snapped. Hill averages better than 21 points per game but was slowed by Nick Anderson and Brian Shaw, who pressured Hill's ballhandling on the perimeter.</p>
<p>&quot;Defensively, this is the best game we've put together for the entire 48 minutes,&quot; said Hardaway, who shot 12-of-16 from the field. &quot;We made sure that we put forth the effort to try to beat these guys.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I thought they were more energetic, more alert,&quot; Pistons coach Doug Collins said. &quot;They wanted this game more, early. They're trying to win this crowd back. They're playing like a possessed team right now.&quot;</p>
<p>In Atlanta, Christian Laettner scored 25 points, including the go-ahead basket, as the Hawks blew a 16-point first-half lead before defeating the Golden State Warriors 106-100.</p>
<p>Steve Smith added 21 points and Mookie Blaylock 18 points, nine rebounds and eight assists for the Hawks, who closed the game with a 10-4 run after the Warriors tied the game at 96.</p>
<p>The Hawks shot 68 percent from the field in the first 24 minutes and improved to 23-3 at home.</p>
<p>&quot;This game tonight was a lesson to us,&quot; Atlanta centre Dikembe Mutombo said. &quot;I'm glad we won, as long as we can win those ballgames, it's very important. We need to stay focused for an entire game. You have to make sure you finish them to the end.&quot;</p>
<p>Joe Smith scored 25 points for the Warriors, who lost their third straight and fell to 0-16 when allowing opponents to shoot 50 percent or better. Chris Mullin added 24 points on 10-of-11 from the field.</p>
<p>In Chicago, Michael Jordan scored 37 points in three quarters and Scottie Pippen added 22 points, 11 assists and nine rebounds as the Bulls rolled to their seventh straight victory, 112-89 over the Portland Trail Blazers.</p>
<p>Jordan, who shot 13-of-27 from the field in 30 minutes, had more points than minutes played for the second straight game. He scored 34 in 31 minutes Saturday against Golden State.</p>
<p>&quot;Michael has been in a total zone as of late, and my shot has been falling as well,&quot; Pippen said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know if we can play much better than we are right now,&quot; Pippen said. &quot;Every shot we take is falling. Everything's just going perfect for us.&quot;</p>
<p>Chicago has beaten Portland five straight times and improved to 49-6 this season, one win short of their record-setting pace of last season.</p>
<p>Jordan refused to speak with reporters because he was upset the locker room was opened so soon after the game.</p>
<p>In San Antonio, Glen Rice scored 33 points as the Charlotte Hornets extended their winning streak to a season-high five games with a 96-84 victory over the Spurs.</p>
<p>Anthony Mason added 24 points and 16 rebounds and Vlade Divac blocked nine shots for the Hornets, who won for the 10th time in their last 12 games. Divac finished one block shy of a triple-double with 12 points and 13 rebounds.</p>
<p>&quot;We played good defence and that's the reason we won the game,&quot; said Divac. &quot;Team defence and hard work are why we're playing so well.&quot;</p>
<p>Charlotte's new guard Ricky Pierce, acquired from the Denver Nuggets just before the trade deadline, came off the bench to score six of his 13 points in a game-breaking first-period run. He was 6-of-10 from the field with two assists in 27 minutes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ORLANDO, Florida"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
