<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="400493" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain watchdog disciplines final Barings executive.</title>
<headline>Britain watchdog disciplines final Barings executive.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's securities market watchdog said Tuesday it disciplined former Barings executive James Bax, completing the cases of managers blamed for the bank's collapse.</p>
<p>Barings went bust in February 1995 under the weight of some 800 million British pounds ($1.3 billion) of losses racked up in unauthorised derivatives trades by trader Nick Leeson, currently imprisoned in Singapore.</p>
<p>The Securities and Futures Authority (SFA) started proceedings against nine former senior executives of Barings but did not proceed against Peter Baring and Andrew Tuckey, chairman and deputy chairman, respectively of Barings group.</p>
<p>The nine were former chief executive Peter Norris, Ron Baker, Bax, Geoff Broadhust, Tony Gamby, Tony Hawes, Ian Hopkins, George Maclean and Mary Walz.</p>
<p>Of these nine, only Hopkins and Baker have any outstanding business with the SFA.</p>
<p>After its spectacular collapse, Barings was taken over by Dutch financial services group Internationale Nederlanden Groep NV and now operates as ING Barings.</p>
<p>The spotlight now turns to Britain's Department of Trade which this week confirmed it has started legal proceedings that could ban the Barings nine plus Tuckey from being directors of any British company for up to 15 years.</p>
<p>Norris, Tuckey, Baker, Walz, Hopkins, Gamby, Broadhurst and Bax also face suits from accounting firm Cooper's &amp; Lybrand in third party proceedings after it was sued by Barings administrator Ernst &amp; Young for what is thought to be around $1.5 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
