<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="400528" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Union abandons UK money market role.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Union abandons UK money market role.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Huddart</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Union Plc, once a pillar of the London financial scene, said on Tuesday it would abandon its long-established role as a British money market dealer and try to salvage viability by rationalisation and possibly merger</p>
<p>Union, struggling as a diversified financial services and trading group, confirmed a warning it gave last month that it could not keep pace with Bank of England (BoE) market reforms set to kill off discount houses like its Union Discount for good.</p>
<p>In a statement Union said it had advised the BoE that it &quot;will no longer wish to enjoy a money market counterparty relationship with them under their new arrangements commencing on March 3, 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>The start of these new rules will end the special role of the discount houses and widen the range of participants in the central bank's money market dealings.</p>
<p>For the time being Union remains in its discount house's famously palatial offices in Cornhill, in London's financial heartland, but Tuesday's statement implied radical change soon.</p>
<p>For several years, as the BoE has gradually introduced a range of reforms, the group has tried with limited success to diversify away from its traditional role in the mysterious and highly volatile money market.</p>
<p>Union said that after a deterioration in second half trading it now expected to post a 1996 operating loss of 1.7 million pounds ($2.78 million) in its earnings report due in late March.</p>
<p>It had already said last month that it would not be able to pay a dividend for 1996.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, all the remaining parts of Union which have had what it called a volatile profits record would be progressively closed down and the assets &quot;realised in an orderly fashion.&quot;</p>
<p>As a result of the reorganisation it has begun 30 days of consultation with employees &quot;as a precursor to what is expected to be a substantial programme of redundancies&quot;, it added.</p>
<p>And negotiations to sell its Glasgow based equity market maker, Aitken Campbell, which are at an advanced stage, should also bring an announcement shortly.</p>
<p>At the same time as it runs out its outstanding money market trading positions over the next few weeks, Union is also likely to report progress on discussions with potential buyers.</p>
<p>Union's announcement that it had had several unsolicited approaches over the last few weeks, and would be pursuing discussions with interested parties, lifted its share price.</p>
<p>The shares ended up 9.0 pence on the day at 95-1/2 pence.</p>
<p>&quot;The board's strategy of building fee-based businesses and withdrawing from proprietary trading ones was and is the correct one,&quot; Union said in a statement, which also revealed the departure of its chief executive George Blunden and managing director Ian Martin.</p>
<p>Chairman Graeme Knox, appointed as caretaker chief executive, added that going forward Union should not only be profitable but ought also to have considerable unutilised assets which could be returned to shareholders.</p>
<p>The group's principal continuing businesses in future would be Union Fund Management (UFM) and Union CAL, a derivatives broker and specialist in margin foreign exchange.</p>
<p>Union said its shareholders could be confident that, based on its balance sheet at December 31, 1996, net assets per share should be comfortably in excess of the share price at close of business on Monday of 86-1/2 pence. ($1=.6107 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
