<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="400533" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: China Airlines to fly cargo to Miami.</title>
<headline>China Airlines to fly cargo to Miami.</headline>
<byline>Bob Murphy</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan flag carrier China Airlines (CAL) expects to start operating twice-weekly Taipei-Miami Boeing 747-200 freighter services next month, the carrier's deputy cargo sales and marketing director Mike Lee told Reuters.</p>
<p>Details were currently being finalised but in all likelihood an aircraft wet-leased from U.S. carrier Atlas Air would be used, with one flight operating on a Taipei-Anchorage (technical stop)-Chicago-Miami-Taipei routing and the other, Taipei-Miami-Dallas and back to Taipei, Lee said in an interview.</p>
<p>Wet-leasing covers the hire of both aircraft and crew.</p>
<p>Lee said that one of the key reasons for starting the new route was to transport cargo from Asia to Latin America via Miami, where negotiations for onward transhipment flights were currently underway between CAL's newly-opened Miami office and Challenge Air Cargo, Fine Air and Tampa Airlines.</p>
<p>&quot;In the past, Far Eastern exporting countries did not pay too much attention to Latin America but, more recently, the political situation there has generally stabilised and, as a result, Central and Latin American economies are growing fast,&quot; noted Lee.</p>
<p>&quot;Latin American countries have traditionally been importing from the United States and Europe but the prices are too high for local populations to sustain and goods from Asia will be priced much lower,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lee predicted there would be demand in Latin America for a wide range of cargo from Asia rather than specific items and that on return flights a variety of perishable items would be carried, along with general freight.</p>
<p>He said that, at present, CAL was unable to use its own aircraft to operate the planned Miami flights as the U.S. government, on Federal Aviation Administration recommendations, had placed a halt on new U.S. traffic rights for Taiwan airlines.</p>
<p>&quot;This is to do with a perceived safety problem caused by lack of China Aviation Administration manpower in the check-in and cargo inspection stages in Taiwan,&quot; stated Lee.</p>
<p>&quot;But this does not stop us from using U.S.-registered aircraft, in this case a leased Atlas Air 747 freighter, for the Miami service,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>China Airlines currently wet-leases four 747-200Fs from Atlas, with a fifth due to join the fleet later this year, and also operates three of its own 747-200 freighters.</p>
<p>&quot;And next year we will convert two of our passenger 747-200s into all-cargo configuration,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lee was optimistic that &quot;open-skies&quot; bilateral air talks between the United States and Taiwan, due to start in Washington DC next month, would lead to CAL starting further cargo services to the U.S. in the not-too-distant future.</p>
<p>&quot;If the outcome of these talks is successful then we would definitely look at operating cargo flights to Atlanta. And after that, there would be no limitations on us in the U.S....there would be many opportunities available,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In another development, Lee said Taiwan had obtained an air traffic rights agreement with Russia, under which CAL would commence operating twice-weekly MD-11 passenger flights, each capable of carrying 15 tonnes of cargo, in May or June.</p>
<p>&quot;The prospects for carrying a broad range of outbound cargo from Taiwan to Russia are good,&quot; said Lee. - Reuters Air Cargo Newsroom Tel +44 171 542 7706 Fax +5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
