<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40060" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: S&amp;P says Belgian banks ripe for consolidation.</title>
<headline>S&amp;P says Belgian banks ripe for consolidation.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's credit rating agency said on Monday that the Belgian banking system was ripe for consolidation, even though the sector had coped relatively well with the upheaval in European banking in the past decade.</p>
<p>&quot;Deregulation, despecialisation, and disintermediation, augmented by the effects of recession in the early 1990s, have caused fewer casualties (in Belgian banking) than in many other systems,&quot; S&amp;P said in a report. &quot;And none of the largest banks has incurred serious problems over the past 20 years.&quot;</p>
<p>But the agency said that deregulation -- which has accelerated in recent years -- had put pressure on Belgian banks' revenues and led to increasing competition.</p>
<p>&quot;The Belgian market is one of the most competitive in Europe because of the large number of domestic players in such a small country in addition to the strong presence of foreign banks.&quot;</p>
<p>S&amp;P said that disintermediation, too, was putting pressure on the banks, though trends in this direction were &quot;less advanced&quot; than in other countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Disintermediation, together with ever fiercer competition, means that Belgian bank margins are among the lowest in Europe,&quot; the report said. But it added that Belgian banks have improved their financial profile in recent years.</p>
<p>S&amp;P cited recent merger talks in the sector and said the market was ripe for change.</p>
<p>&quot;A clear sign of Belgian bankers' consciousness of the need to consolidate is the proposed link between Credit Communal de Belgique and Credit Local de France,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;A further indication were the merger discussions (though fruitless) between Generale Bank, Credit Communal de Belgique, and Banque Bruxelles Lambert at the beginning of this year.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
