<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="400787" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAJIKISTAN: Red Cross resumes operations in Tajikistan.</title>
<headline>Red Cross resumes operations in Tajikistan.</headline>
<dateline>DUSHANBE 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) said on Tuesday it had resumed operations in the former Soviet republic of Tajikistan.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, the ICRC and some other foreign aid organisations suspended activities in the country, devastated by a four-year civil war, after several of their employees were taken hostage by one of several armed factions.</p>
<p>Two of the hostages, including a British national, were employees with the ICRC.</p>
<p>&quot;The ICRC has decided following the end of the recent hostage crisis to restart operations,&quot; Thomas Merkelbach, head of the ICRC delegation in Tajikistan, told a news conference in the capital Dushanbe.</p>
<p>However, Merkelbach said the ICRC could only operate if the country's various factions provided and honoured security guarantees for its workers.</p>
<p>&quot;Only if we are really sure that our goods and people are respected by the different forces can we continue our activities,&quot; Merkelbach said.</p>
<p>A fragile peace has reigned in Tajikistan, which borders Afghanistan and China, since the government and the armed Islamist opposition agreed a ceasefire last December.</p>
<p>But the kidnappings by rogue guerrilla groups forced many foreign organisations to review their security, with several agencies yet to resume full operations in the republic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TADZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUSHANBE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAJIKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
