<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="400846" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: FEATURE - Albania capital bustles but focus still on pyramids.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Albania capital bustles but focus still on pyramids.</headline>
<byline>Ron Popeski</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Everyone has something to sell on Tirana's dusty streets six years after eastern Europe's most repressive communist administration gave way to unfettered, and often ruinous, entrepreneurship.</p>
<p>Pavements teem with ramshackle stalls offering sweaters alongside utensils, cleaning materials, car parts and drinks. A ground floor flat is a boon for business, an outside window quickly converted into a display case and cash desk.</p>
<p>The department store seems an alien notion. Small wonder, when only a handful of items in one renovated clothes shop, its owners warily observing a foreign visitor pretending to browse, cost less than the average monthly salary equivalent to $80.</p>
<p>Talk everywhere naturally turns to the failed pyramid investment schemes in which most of Albania's 3.4 million people placed their life savings.</p>
<p>Warm and engaging, Albanians now chat willingly about how the manic isolationism of Stalinist dictator Enver Hoxha affected their day-to-day lives.</p>
<p>There is plenty of invective about current President Sali Berisha and his promotion of free market values. But there is also fear. Almost no one gives a last name.</p>
<p>&quot;My boyfriend and I put away tens of thousands of dollars. It might all be gone,&quot; said Ornela, a shop assistant working her way through a law degree. &quot;We thought the end of the communists was a new beginning, year zero. But we've got absolutely nowhere. We could even be headed for civil war.&quot;</p>
<p>Streets where Hoxha banned private cars little more than a decade ago are now choked with exhaust, though horse-drawn carts slow traffic. Pedestrians must take care not to run foul of fast-moving bicycles, their owners often carrying oversize loads on the handlebars.</p>
<p>Rubbish containers remain overturned in the same spot day after day. And dust hangs in the air, despite the weather-worn women who sweep it away in vain every night after midnight.</p>
<p>DILAPIDATED CITY</p>
<p>Factories appear all but abandoned. A line of greenhouses stretching more than a kilometre (600 yards) along the road from Tirana's dilapidated Rinas airport stands useless, most of its windows smashed.</p>
<p>The concrete bunkers built under Hoxha's campaign to deter the invasion by preying neighbours which never materialised, absurdly dot the hills rising just outside the capital.</p>
<p>A stream flows down a concrete channel running through the city centre. Locals say sewage is poured directly into it.</p>
<p>The most visible effect of the pyramids are Tirana's city centre bars hurriedly erected by entrepreneurs flush with the interest they initially collected before things went sour.</p>
<p>Two square blocks in what was once a park are occupied by dozens of bars, each barely distinguishable from the next, their clientele almost exclusively male.</p>
<p>Holes poke through floors and ceilings to accommodate trees and allow the owners, critics say, to circumvent city by-laws.</p>
<p>All that remains of another park is a hole the size of several city blocks now used as a free-for-all tip -- the legacy of a foreign developer who pulled out of a hotel project.</p>
<p>&quot;They have utterly ruined our city,&quot; said Elena, a teacher and one of the few Albanians encountered who ignored promises of big returns and invested nothing in the pyramid schemes.</p>
<p>&quot;In our hearts we knew things were dreadfully wrong under Hoxha, though we kept silent. Even bringing a foreign magazine to school was out of the question. But none of our new leaders could persuade me that this was a realistic way to make money.&quot;</p>
<p>A scant 50 metres (yards) from the profusion of bars stands the dramatically sloping concrete and glass structure that was the Hoxha museum, devoted to the leader's life and times.</p>
<p>It was turned into an exhibition hall after communism fell and Tirana's liveliest disco is in the basement.</p>
<p>FEW DISTRACTIONS FOR TIRANA'S RESIDENTS</p>
<p>But distractions are few for Tirana residents carefully watching their budgets.</p>
<p>Many complain that once-popular cinemas show nothing but soft porn or martial arts films. The arts have met the same fate as in other ex-communist societies, with the most talented performers working abroad and those left behind scraping by on meagre state subsidies.</p>
<p>Albanian state television is stolid by anyone's standards in eastern Europe.</p>
<p>News programmes slavishly related government statements that leftist extremists, armed and seditious, were behind this month's rioting by enraged pyramid investors demanding their money back and the resignation of Berisha's government.</p>
<p>Unlike communist-era viewers, Albanians had only to switch to U.S., Italian, German or French channels which were readily available.</p>
<p>Audiences soar for Sunday lunch when the country's most popular show business personalities host &quot;Telebingo&quot; live from the &quot;Palace of Culture&quot; -- once a revered communist institution in central Skanderbeg Square.</p>
<p>Prizes amounting to $70,000 are small by Western standards.</p>
<p>But then so is the stake (less than half a dollar) and the risks.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't really learned the capitalist ways yet. Maybe it was too much to expect after so many years of doing things another way,&quot; said teacher Elena.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought for a time the people in charge would get us on the right path. But I've given up on them. The wrong message is getting through -- that corruption pays and that you can somehow make money without producing anything.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
