<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="400808" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak Jan PPI +6.1 pct yr/yr (+4.9 pct Dec).</title>
<headline>Slovak Jan PPI +6.1 pct yr/yr (+4.9 pct Dec).</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovak producer prices (PPI) rose 6.1 percent year-on-year in January 1997, after rising 4.9 percent in December 1996, the Slovak Statistical Bureau (SUSR) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>SUSR did not provide comparison figures for January 1996, saying it has begun calculating PPI according to European Union standards.  </p>
<p>Prices of coke, oil products and nuclear fuels were the fastest rising components of PPI, up 24.5 percent year-on-year, compared with a 23.7 increase in December 1996, SUSR said.</p>
<p>SUSR added that industrial producer prices were up 6.5 percent year-on-year, compared with a 5.2 percent year-on-year increase last month.</p>
<p>Prices of electricity, gas and water rose 4.6 percent, up from a December increase of 4.1 percent.</p>
<p>SUSR said in a statement that the adjustment to EU standards for PPI included a revision of the structure of the index, increasing the number of items to 2,966 from a previous 1,820.</p>
<p>The price base for the calculation is December 1995, and the bureau collects information from around 480 respondents.</p>
<p>The weight of the items in the index was derived from the structure of industrial producers income. The statement did not elaborate further.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, SUSR reported that Slovak consumer price index rose 1.1 percent month-on-month in January, putting the prices 5.8 percent higher than in the same month last year.</p>
<p>-- Peter Laca, Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-521-8402</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
