<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40086" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam seeks solutions as trade gap hits record.</title>
<headline>Vietnam seeks solutions as trade gap hits record.</headline>
<byline>John Chalmers</byline>
<dateline>HANOI, Vietnam</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam said Monday it notched up a record trade deficit of $3.25 billion in the first eight months of this year as the fast-developing economy sucked in imports at a faster rate than exports.</p>
<p>The official Vietnam News Agency (VNA) said imports rose by 45 percent from the same period of 1995 to $7.60 billion, while exports were just 22.6 percent higher at $4.35 billion.</p>
<p>The trade gap was about 5.8 times higher than the cumulative deficit of $554 million reported for January-August last year.</p>
<p>VNA quoted government officials and exporters as saying the trade deficit for the full year was unlikely to be lower than $2.50 billion.</p>
<p>Bankers and economists said the Communist government was urgently seeking ways to create a value-added export regime and find funds to bridge a ballooning balance of payments gap.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to explore the deficiency and in the long term how Vietnam could ... solve the problem of the balance of payments,&quot; said Le Dang Doanh, president of the Vietnam Central Institute for Economic Management.</p>
<p>Doanh said it was inevitable that a country like Vietnam -- whose economy has taken off since capitalist-style reforms were introduced a decade ago -- should run a trade deficit.</p>
<p>He pointed out that consumer goods accounted for less than 10 percent of total imports and that most of the country's imports were capital goods that would ultimately contribute to exports or a drive for import substitution.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, he said investment in manufacturing industry was needed because a country could sustain a balance of payments deficit only if it had a strong export base.</p>
<p>At present, Vietnam's main exports are low-value goods such as raw materials, crude oil and rice. Only 20 percent come from manufacturing.</p>
<p>Earlier this year Hanoi reached a framework agreement on the restructuring of its approximately $1 billion debt to foreign commercial creditors. But foreign bankers say approval by the creditors is unlikely to come before the end of this year.</p>
<p>Without their approval, Hanoi's plans to make its debut in the international bond market -- where it hopes to raise at least $100 million -- will have to remain on hold.</p>
<p>The country's annual debt service bill, around $270 million a year, leaves little to fill yawning financial gaps at home, such as bad loans in the largely state-owned banking system.</p>
<p>One Western banker said the central State Bank of Vietnam could engineer a &quot;subtle devaluation&quot; of the dong, the local currency, from around 11,020 per dollar now to 11,150 in coming months to boost exports and trim the import bill.</p>
<p>He said the government, proud of cutting annual inflation to around 3 percent this year, would be reluctant to risk upsetting confidence in the economy by sanctioning a more dramatic devaluation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI, Vietnam"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
