<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="400849" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Americas ministers discuss region-wide trade bloc.</title>
<headline>Americas ministers discuss region-wide trade bloc.</headline>
<dateline>RECIFE, Brazil 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deputy commerce ministers from the Americas gathered in the northeastern Brazilian resort of Recife on Tuesday for a three-day meeting on establishing a regional free trade zone, officials said.</p>
<p>Brazilian newspapers reported that the summit, which will debate the Free Trade Area of the Americas (FTAA), would be a stage for a scuffle between Brazil, its Mercosur trade bloc partners and the United States and Canada.</p>
<p>&quot;What's at stake here is who is going to have influence over the continent in the next century,&quot; a Brazilian Foreign Ministry official told the financial daily Gazeta Mercantil.</p>
<p>Newspapers said Canada and the United States were pushing for talks on reducing tariffs in the FTAA to start by March next year. The region-wide free trade zone is meant to come into existence by the year 2005.</p>
<p>Brazil believes that the Mercosur trade bloc, which groups Brazil, Argentina, Uruguay and Paraguay, must be strengthened first as a counterweight to the bulk of Nafta, grouping the United States, Canada and Mexico.</p>
<p>Brazilian officials also say that talks on business facilitation -- basically levelling the playing field between FTAA countries -- must precede tariff negotiations.</p>
<p>In an opening speech, Brazilian Foreign Minister Luiz Felipe Lampreia made his country's standpoint clear.</p>
<p>Noting Mercosur's free trade deals with Chile and Bolivia and another under negotiation with the Andean Pact countries, Lampreia said the FTAA must be based on the &quot;building blocks&quot; already established in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;Mercosur is a success story that is here to stay, one that strengthens the international identity of its members and gives critical mass to the FTAA,&quot; he said, according to a copy of the speech prepared for delivery.</p>
<p>The Recife meeting is aimed at preparing for a full ministerial meeting of the 34 FTAA signatory countries due to take place in the Brazilian city of Belo Horizonte on May 13-16 this year.</p>
<p>Another final preparatory meeting was scheduled for April in Rio de Janeiro, Brazilian officials said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RECIFE, Brazil"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
