<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="400968" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Fujimori blames police, officials for Peru crisis.</title>
<headline>Fujimori blames police, officials for Peru crisis.</headline>
<byline>James Craig</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Alberto Fujimori blamed police and &quot;some officials&quot; for failing to prevent Peru's 70-day hostage siege as Marxist rebels and government negotiators prepared for new face-to-face talks on Tuesday to end the crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot speak about culpability yet. There is no trial,&quot; Fujimori told reporters on Monday on a trip to Peru's eastern jungle. &quot;But there is responsibility on the part of some officials and of members of the National Police.&quot;</p>
<p>An investigation was underway and published reports said some authorities may be punished.</p>
<p>Fujimori said Peru's intelligence service informed police in the Huancayo region and Lima that Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels had slipped weapons and fighters into the capital for a hostage-taking operation.</p>
<p>Police high command ordered &quot;corrective measures&quot; on Nov. 15 but, &quot;apparently, adequate measures were not taken to assure that the reception at the Japanese embassy take place normally,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>His comments confirmed a secret intelligence report obtained by Reuters that showed regional anti-terrorist police warned authorities in Lima weeks before the takeover that the MRTA was planning an assault around Nov. 30.</p>
<p>On Dec. 17, rebels seized the diplomatic compound and took hundreds of hostages. All but 72 have been released.</p>
<p>Fujimori spoke on Monday after a fifth round of talks and the second meeting between government negotiator Domingo Palermo and MRTA chief Nestor Cerpa.</p>
<p>A statement issued by guarantors overseeing the talks merely said the two met in a &quot;cordial atmosphere&quot; and broached &quot;important issues&quot;. The statement added that a sixth round of negotiations would be held on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Speaking in the jungle town of Mazamari, Fujimori said talks were in a &quot;preliminary stage&quot; and the two sides had not reached &quot;a base agreement&quot; for formal negotiations to end the crisis.</p>
<p>He denied a report in a Japanese newspaper that he had agreed to place on the agenda for final negotiations the rebels' main demand of freedom for 400 jailed comrades. The government flatly rejected the idea.</p>
<p>&quot;That is not true,&quot; Fujimori said of the report in Mainichi Shimbun. &quot;The government's position is the same.&quot;</p>
<p>Cerpa and his deputy, Rolly Rojas, were driven back to the besieged Japanese ambassador's residence in a Red Cross car from a safe house across the street after Monday's meeting, which lasted more than two hours.</p>
<p>When they left the diplomatic compound earlier in the morning, their fellow rebels cheered, broadcast a revolutionary anthem commemorating dead comrades and bellowed defiant slogans. &quot;We are the ones who have taken the Japanese residence. Until death, damn it!&quot; they shouted.</p>
<p>Talks began on Feb. 11 after weeks of intransigence over the rebels' central demand for the release of jailed comrades.</p>
<p>Argentine human rights group Mothers of the Plaza de Mayo were rebuffed again on Monday in their bid to play a role in resolving the hostage crisis.</p>
<p>A Mothers delegation was turned away at Government Palace when they tried for a second time to meet with Fujimori and were barred from visiting a women's prison as well as paying a visit to the hostages.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
