<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="401231" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Midwest direct hogs seen flat-up $0.50 -dealers.</title>
<headline>US Midwest direct hogs seen flat-up $0.50 -dealers.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Midwest direct cash hog prices Wednesday were seen steady to $0.50 per cwt higher, lifted by continued light hog supplies and a slight advance in wholesale pork prices, livestock dealers said.</p>
<p>Top cash prices for interior Iowa and southern Minnesota hogs at packing plants were seen ranging from $51.50 to $52.00 and Illinois top prices at plants could span $50.50 to $51.00, sources in those areas said.</p>
<p>Indiana/Ohio plant prices were seen at $50.50 to $51.00.</p>
<p>This week's advance in hog prices brought out a few more marketings, but they remained below packer needs, they said.  </p>
<p>Tight hog supplies and unfavorable market conditions spurred production cutbacks by several packers.</p>
<p>IBP Inc on Monday announced it was cutting the second shift at its Columbus Junction, Iowa plant on March 3 and ceasing slaughter April 24 at its Council Bluffs, Iowa plant.</p>
<p>ConAgra Inc cut pork production by one hour a day at its three Swift and Co. pork plants Monday and Tuesday and would review schedules for the rest of the week.</p>
<p>Smithfield Foods Inc's John Morrell hog slaughter plant in Sioux City, Iowa continues to operate one shift after cutting its second shift in early February.</p>
<p>Company officials said it has not been determined when the second shift will be reinstated.</p>
<p>((Bob Janis 312-983-7347))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
