<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40156" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France's Madelin says tax reform not enough.</title>
<headline>France's Madelin says tax reform not enough.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former French finance minister Alain Madelin has criticised the government's tax reforms as not enough to fuel an economic recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;I welcome this reform...But it is not a tax choice which will create an economic recovery,&quot; he said on French radio on Sunday.</p>
<p>The government said last week it was cutting income taxes by 75 billion over five years and by 25 billion francs next year. Given higher taxes to fund the welfare system, it said the net tax cut next year would be 18 billion francs.</p>
<p>Madelin, who resigned as finance minister last year, said the economy was suffering from &quot;deflationary pressures,&quot; squeezing companies which are hesitating about investing. He said short-term interest rates were still too high and should be nearer to one percent than around 3.5 percent now.</p>
<p>He also complained the government's reforms were running on credit, noting that it planned to use 37.5 billion francs in funds from France Telecom to reduce the state deficit next year.</p>
<p>The funds are being transferred to the state when it assumes its pension liabilities ahead of the partial privatisation of the telecommunications company.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 42 21 53 81</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
