<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="401540" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Planned 1997/98 farm price spending cuts may be halved.</title>
<headline>Planned 1997/98 farm price spending cuts may be halved.</headline>
<byline>Peter Blackburn</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Commissioners, in a discussion on Wednesday of the 1997/98 (July/June) farm price package, may halve the need for extra spending cuts, EU agricultural sources said.</p>
<p>Additional cuts of only about 450 million Ecus may now be needed, compared with 1.1 billion Ecus originally envisaged in order to keep within budget guidelines.</p>
<p>The Commission has already proposed 1.4 billion Ecus of cuts in compensatory payments - consisting of seven percent for cereals and four percent for oilseeds as well as a 27 percent cut in set-aside aid.</p>
<p>&quot;The farm spending problem may have been exaggerated...1998 is still a long way off,&quot; said one source, adding it might be unnecessary to rush into making sharp cuts as the situation could change completely.</p>
<p>One Commission source said the 1997/98 farm price proposal could be delayed until mid-March, while other sources said the delay could be longer.</p>
<p>The Commission was recently forced to revise its 1997/98 farm price plans in order to keep within a new 0.5 percent spending increase in the 1998 farm budget to 41 billion Ecus.</p>
<p>It was originally considering four options to achieve the 1.1 billion Ecus additional cuts, according to a text discussed by EU Commissioners' aides: - A five percent price cut in all farm sectors. But a two percent cut would be virtually sufficient to achieve a new saving target of 450 million Ecus, sources said. This assumes a saving of 220 million Ecus for each one percentage point cut in prices. - Concentrating price cuts in sectors where expenditure is likely to rise the most in either 1997 or 1998. - An extra nine percent cut in cereals and oilseeds compensatory payments. - Amending the EU's agrimonetary system for converting green rates -- Ecu-based farm subsidies and support prices -- into national currencies. It would involve halving to 2.5 percent the franchise -- the gap between green and market rates -- before green rates are revalued. Savings of some one billion Ecus could be made by making speedier revaluations.</p>
<p>But EU agricultural sources said this option was unlikely to be chosen. Firstly green rates for reform aids have been frozen until January 1999 in eight EU member states. Secondly, the Commission said in an agrimonetary report last December that it would make no major changes until the introduction of a single currency.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
