<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40162" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Chidambaram measures fail to cheer Indian markets.</title>
<headline>Chidambaram measures fail to cheer Indian markets.</headline>
<byline>Priya Ramani</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Incentives announced by Finance Minister P. Chidambaram failed to cheer Indian stock markets on Monday but analysts said investors expected more measures when the minister wraps up a delayed budget debate later this week.</p>
<p>&quot;The incentives aren't of much immediate use to investors so the market is unlikely to run away,&quot; said a trader at a foreign brokerage.</p>
<p>On Friday, Chidambaram removed a 30 percent ceiling on investment in debt by foreign institutional investors.</p>
<p>He exempted investments in mutual funds from capital gains tax, upped the ceiling marginally on tax-spared dividend income and doubled the limit for bank advances against shares to one million rupees ($280,112).</p>
<p>But market reaction was muted with traders saying the relief measures fell below expectations. In afternoon trade on Monday, the 30-stocks Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) index was trading 30.15 points or 0.86 percent lower at 3477.92 in low volumes.</p>
<p>The benchmark index has fallen about 300 points or some eight percent since India's budget announcements on July 22.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no one-time or magic solutions,&quot; Chidambaram told parliament in the first stage of his budget reply on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;But I am persuaded that there is urgent need to perk up market sentiment since a good part of market behaviour is based on psychology and sentiment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chidambaram will address parliament again this week before the budget for 1996/97 (April-March) is put to the vote.</p>
<p>Brokers are expecting him to dilute a controversial 12.9 percent minimum alternate tax on profits of high-growth companies and offer other tax incentives.</p>
<p>&quot;There are other things that he could do and other things that he is likely to do,&quot; said Shaun Browne, equity capital markets director at HSBC James Capel.</p>
<p>&quot;But the whole philosophy of the Indian liberalisation process has been gradually, gradually, softly, softly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Economists said the finance minister could not be expected to announce radical measures as he had to work within the limits of a 13-party ruling coalition.</p>
<p>&quot;Within the constraints he's doing an excellent job,&quot; said Arup Raha, senior economist at Lehman Brothers in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>In its latest strategy report, Lehman Brothers said it was overweight on the Indian market from a 12-month perspective.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation currently is that liquidity is ample and relative yields are moving in favour of equities from a domestic investor perspective and with a forecast decline in interest rates and a pick-up in economy later this year,&quot; Lehman said.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook for equities is positive,&quot; the report said, forecasting a 12-month target of 4750 points for the Bombay index, representing an upside of 33 percent in rupee terms and 21 percent in dollar terms.</p>
<p>($1=35.70 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
