<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="401797" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ABU DHABI: Yemen leader denies moving toward ties with Israel.</title>
<headline>Yemen leader denies moving toward ties with Israel.</headline>
<dateline>ABU DHABI 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yemeni President Ali Abdullah Saleh on Tuesday denied his country was establishing ties with Israel and said the Jewish state was not interested in peace, the official WAM news agency reported.</p>
<p>Saleh told a news conference before leaving Abu Dhabi after a brief visit that Yemen's policies were based on the principle of Israel handing back occupied Arab land.</p>
<p>&quot;Israel is not serious about peace,&quot; said Saleh. &quot;The matter of establishing any type of ties can only be discussed within the framework of an Arab summit.&quot;</p>
<p>Yemen on Monday dismissed Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy's talk of secret contacts between the states as &quot;mere fabrication&quot;. Levy had said they were discussing establishing official ties through opening interest offices.</p>
<p>Israel has a foothold in the Arabian peninsula, with trade missions in Oman and Qatar. Oman has a trade office in Tel Aviv. But Oman and Qatar said last year they had frozen contacts with Israel because of hardline Israeli policies toward Palestinians.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABU DHABI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ABU DHABI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
