<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="401766" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: BELGIAN CEN BANK SEEN DRIVING MONEY RATE RISE.</title>
<headline>BELGIAN CEN BANK SEEN DRIVING MONEY RATE RISE.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Belgian central bank pulled the rug out from under the money market on Tuesday and dealers said it may be some time before it recovered.</p>
<p>One week repo rates mushroomed to 3.65/70 percent, from 3.47/50 at Monday's close, as the bank surprised participants by cutting liquidity at its regular four-day repo operation.</p>
<p>&quot;There are two possible reasons: they want rates to return to German levels, which is obviously not the case here, or they want to stop speculation against the Belgian franc,&quot; one trader said. &quot;Maybe they want to strike before there's anything really going on in the market by using money market rates.&quot;</p>
<p>The Belgian National Bank's central rate for money market lending presently stands at 3.00 percent. Tomorrow/next day deposits were quoted at 3.30/80 percent. One trader said this was the biggest difference for several years.</p>
<p>&quot;I guess they (the bank) are a little bit concerned that the Belgian franc is trading slightly weaker than its central rate in the European Monetary System,&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>The Belgian franc was quoted at 20.6395/10 to the mark late on Tuesday, down slightly from 20.6384/94 at Monday's close. The franc has been trading weaker than its midpoint to the mark of 20.6255 for several weeks because of domestic political worries.  </p>
<p>Belgium's French-speaking socialist party, a member of the centre-left governing coalition, has been accused of accepting bribes from defence companies in the late 1980s, and there have been calls from opposition parties for it to step down.</p>
<p>One trader noted, however, the sharp rise in money market rates had not hit the OLO market and this was probably a sign there was no belief that a real crisis was in the offing.</p>
<p>Few expected the Belgian National Bank to change its official interest rates as a response to the rise in money market rates. &quot;It would be a bad idea to do this while the political situation is still uncertain,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>Belgian OLOs lagged bonds on Tuesday, with the 10-year spread edging out slightly to 12 basis points from 10 on Monday. The benchmark OLO 26 (March 27) was yielding an unchanged 5.65 percent in late trade. One trader said there had been a seller early on in the bond.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Treasury bill rates reflected the rise in money market rates. At the Belgian Treasury's weekly auction 3-, 6- and 12-month bills were all sold at a stop rate of 3.30 percent.</p>
<p>Three-month bills were sold at an average 3.29 percent, up from 3.11 percent at last week's auction.</p>
<p>-- Nick Antonovics, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6817, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
