<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="401720" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan's oil marketing sector expected to surge.</title>
<headline>Pakistan's oil marketing sector expected to surge.</headline>
<byline>Tahir Ikram</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's oil marketing companies are set for &quot;tremendous growth&quot; on the back of deregulation of the oil and gas sector coupled with burgeoning demand, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Tremendous growth of oil marketing companies is expected in the coming years,&quot; Rizwan Butt, senior analyst at brokerage house Khadim Ali Shah Bukhari &amp; Co, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The demand for furnace oil is expected to double by the end of 1998 as 3,000 megawatts of power plants come on stream,&quot; he said. &quot;It will significantly increase revenue for the sector.&quot;</p>
<p>A research report by James Capel Asia endorsed that view.</p>
<p>&quot;The (oil marketing) sector is poised to experience growth in revenue as a result of increasing demand for petroleum products by the power sector and rising prices,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Official projections show demand for oil products rising to 26.9 million tonnes a year by 2000 from 14.3 million now.</p>
<p>James Capel said the sector grew impressively over the last five years as petroleum product consumption grew at a compound annual rate of seven percent.</p>
<p>&quot;This growth has been accompanied by increased capacity in oil marketing companies, establishing subsidiaries engaged in distributing lubes and chemicals and periodic margin revisions due to frequent price changes of petroleum products.&quot;</p>
<p>Pakistan, which imports 60 percent of its crude oil and 62 percent of its refined product requirements, imported oil and products worth $1.9 billion in 1995/96 (July-June), or 17 percent of the total import bill.</p>
<p>James Capel said the oil marketing companies could be expected to prosper under a far-reaching deregulation policy introduced by the caretaker government.</p>
<p>&quot;(Profit) margins would be doubled to four percent from the present two percent in the next four years, enhancing the future profitability of oil marketing companies,&quot; Ammar Qureshi, an analyst at James Capel, said.</p>
<p>Former petroleum and natural resources minister Javed Jabbar said last week the government would end its 30-year-old practice of importing oil products, handing responsibility to the private sector after a 16-month transition period.</p>
<p>Other reforms ordered by the caretakers included scrapping a state-subsidised -- and widely abused -- Inland Freight Equalisation Margin (IFEM) mechanism designed to ensure that oil products are sold at uniform prices all over Pakistan.</p>
<p>&quot;If IFEM is abolished, oil marketing companies stand to benefit...as it will lead to improved liquidity in form of excess cash which can be reinvested in oil distribution infrastructure development,&quot; James Capel said.</p>
<p>Pakistan's largest oil marketing company is Pakistan State Oil with a 76 percent market share, followed by Shell with 18.5 percent and Caltex with 5.4 percent.</p>
<p>Oil accounts for 41 percent of Pakistan's energy needs. Crude oil imports have grown an average 2.3 percent a year over the last five years. Oil products imports have grown 11.8 percent a year.</p>
<p>-- Islamabad newsroom 9251-274757</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
