<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="401876" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: World Markets Summary.</title>
<headline>World Markets Summary.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>STOCKS				     GOLD</p>
<p>    Dow Jones close			  Latest spot rate</p>
<p>	 7008.20 (+76.58)		   $352.15 per troy oz</p>
<p>    FTSE-100 close			     CRUDE OIL</p>
<p>	 4331.1 (-5.7)			  Brent DTD</p>
<p>   Nikkei-225 latest			 $20.10 per bbl</p>
<p>	 18904.57 (+7.58)</p>
<p>			- - - - - - - - - - - - -</p>
<p>Stocks rose sharply Monday, boosted by big gains in International Business Machines Corp. and Philip Morris Cos. Inc., but bonds and the dollar fell.</p>
<p>Oil prices dropped to the lowest level since last summer. Gold moved higher.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average jumped 76.58 points, a gain of 1.10 percent, to 7,008.20. In the broader market, advancing issues led declines 1,482 to 1,031 on active volume of 459 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;The nod keeps going to the big-cap, blue-chip stocks,&quot; said Alan Ackerman, market strategist at Fahnestock &amp; Co.</p>
<p>IBM and Philip Morris accounted for nearly half of the rise in the 30-share Dow, the world's most widely watched stock index.</p>
<p>The blue-chip index has been locked in a relatively narrow range since chalking up a record close of 7,067.46 last Tuesday, falling in two straight sessions and managing a small gain on Friday. But as has happened with stubborn regularity lately, the brief pullback quickly attracted buyers.</p>
<p>&quot;We had some sellers at the 7,000 level but they couldn't bring the market down too much,&quot; said Peter Canelo, chief investment strategist at Dean Witter. &quot;I don't think this rally's over. We have a very happy confluence of events.&quot;</p>
<p>That confluence includes an upbeat economy, a strong dollar and low inflation that recently has dipped to barely noticeable levels.</p>
<p>&quot;You could make a case that with inflation as low as it is and, in our judgment, likely to stay low, this market could even sustain somewhat higher multiples,&quot; said James Crawford, senior vice president at Trevor Stewart Burton &amp; Jacobsen Inc.</p>
<p>But one strong session did not throw all Wall Street's caution to the wind. Crawford, for one, still believes large-name stocks in particular are due for a pause.</p>
<p>&quot;We're probably close to a point where the market is in a short-term toppy area,&quot; he said. &quot;It would be healthy to see some of this money spread out.&quot;</p>
<p>In the bond market, the 30-year Treasury rose 7/32, or $2.19 on a $1,000 bond, raising its yield to 6.66 percent from 6.64 percent on Friday.</p>
<p>In currency markets, the dollar fell against the German mark, Japanese yen and other major currencies as traders locked in profits ahead of Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan's semiannual testimony to Congress.</p>
<p>Weighing on the dollar were worries about a delay in Europe's plans for a single currency, which helped the mark, and fears that Japanese companies might sell large amounts of dollars before the end of Japan's fiscal year.</p>
<p>The dollar fell to 1.6745 marks late in New York from 1.6893 marks late on Friday. It settled at 122.23 yen, below Friday's close of 123.25.</p>
<p>&quot;We've seen a round of profit-taking,&quot; said John McCarthy, manager of foreign exchange at ING Barings Capital Markets. He said there were &quot;increased concerns&quot; about Europe's single currency and that there has been &quot;talk about Japanese repatriation, allthough it's hard to say at this point.&quot;</p>
<p>April crude oil fell 68 cents to $20.71 a barrel, the lowest since August, at the New York Mercantile Exchange.</p>
<p>April gold rose $1.10 to $355.20 an ounce on New York's Commodity Exchange.</p>
<p>Overseas, the London's FTSE stock index fell 5.7 points to 4,331.1 and Tokyo's Nikkei average of 225 leading shares fell 137.55 points to 18,896.99, a drop of 0.72 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
