<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="401896" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NASD announces G-37 fines against variety of firms.</title>
<headline>NASD announces G-37 fines against variety of firms.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Association of Securities Dealers announced a series of fines against municipal bond firms for violating recordkeeping requirements of the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board's &quot;pay-to-play&quot; rule G-37, and other securities rules.</p>
<p>Enacted in April 1994, rule G-37 generally requires broker-dealers who contribute to issuer clients from doing negotiated bond business with those municipalities for two years.</p>
<p>Firms are required to report regularly to the MSRB if they did any negotiated deals during any calendar quarter or made political contributions or hired consultants to help them win business.</p>
<p>None of the firms admitted or denied wrongdoing.</p>
<p>In its latest round of actions, NASD jointly fined LM Capital Securities Inc. of West Palm Beach, Fla. and Leslie Corley, a registered principal for the firm who lives in New York City, $5,000 for a variety of securities rule violations.</p>
<p>NASD said Capital, acting through Corley, failed to report five negotiated muni underwritings between September 1994 and November 1995 as required by G-37.</p>
<p>It also said the firm failed to report net capital problems to regulators in a timely fashion.</p>
<p>NASD also fined First Kentucky Securities Corporation and R. Strand Kramer, a registered muni securities principal at the firm, a total of $2,750 for G-37 related violations.</p>
<p>The firm failed to file G-37 reports on time for two recent quarters, NASD said. Since October 16, 1995, the firm and Kramer also failed to properly supervise employee Rosemary Woodruff, who acted as a muni securities representative without being registered as such with NASD, NASD said. NASD ordered Woodruff censured.</p>
<p>NASD said it fined Clark Melvin Securities Corp. of Hato Rey, Puerto Rico, and principal Cesar Montilla a total of $2,500, for late reports that the firm was a synicate member on seven bond deals in 1995.</p>
<p>NASD also said the firm did not have proper written procedures for supervisors to follow to ensure compliance with G-37.</p>
<p>The association fined five firms $1,000 for reporting violations under rule G-37, including Mark Pressman Associations and Van Kasper &amp; Company, both in San Francisco; Summers &amp; Company, Inc. in Fort Wayne, Ind.; Gates Capital Corp. in New York City; Hazlett, Burt &amp; Watson, Inc. in Wheeling, W.V.; and Gardnyr Michael Capital, Inc. in Winter Park, Fla. and the firm's president Pfilip Gardnyr Hunt, Jr.</p>
<p>NASD fined three additional firms $500 each and roughly a dozen more firms $250 each for rule G-37-related violations.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
