<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="401843" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Saudi United Sugar starts commissioning refinery.</title>
<headline>Saudi United Sugar starts commissioning refinery.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi Arabia's United Sugar Co has started commissioning the kingdom's first sugar refinery and commercial production is expected to begin in late March, its executive general manager said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Things are moving forward. We have begun commissioning part of the refinery. Everything is on schedule,&quot; Mohammad Kashgari told Reuters by telephone from the Red Sea port city of Jeddah.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect commercial production probably in the second half of March,&quot; he said, adding that the white sugar will be sold mainly in the Saudi market.</p>
<p>Per capita consumption of sugar in the Arabian peninsula is among the world's highest at around 30 kg.</p>
<p>Commissioning of the 500,000 tonne annual capacity refinery means that imports of white sugar by Saudi Arabia -- a country of some 18 million people -- will drop sharply and the kingdom will become a predominantly raw sugar market.</p>
<p>Kashgari said during the year production will gradually increase to full capacity: &quot;Production will be built gradually to full capacity. Our production for 1997 will not be 500,000 as we will be producing for nine months or so.&quot;</p>
<p>The refinery is 51 percent owned by Savola -- Saudi Arabia's biggest food group, 15 percent by Britain's Tate and Lyle Plc and the rest by Saudi sugar trading firms.</p>
<p>In late December United Sugar Co took delivery of its first cargo of raws from Australia's Queensland Sugar Corp.</p>
<p>Kashgari did not comment on future raws purchases.</p>
<p>-- Hilary Gush, Dubai newsroom +9714-626990</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
