<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="401959" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Alleged prostitute ringleader too fat for NY court.</title>
<headline>Alleged prostitute ringleader too fat for NY court.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A New York man charged with running a prostitution ring was arraigned in the outdoor courtyard of Manhattan Supreme Court on Monday because he was too fat to fit through the courtroom's doors.</p>
<p>Robert York, wearing a white hospital gown dotted with tiny blue flowers, lay on an oversized hospital bed inside a city ambulance and pleaded not guilty to promoting prostitution through his escort service.</p>
<p>York, who weighs 400 pounds (181 kg), stayed in the ambulance during the seven-minute appearance.</p>
<p>Police alleged that York, 48, ran the call-girl ring from a hospital bed in his Manhattan office, where he maintained a bank of six phones and placed ads in the Yellow Pages and other magazines offering the girls' services. He is being held on $75,000 bail. His next court appearance is scheduled for March 12.</p>
<p>Court and Correction Department officials said it was the first time an arraignment was held outdoors because a suspect, not only could not fit through the doors but also was unable to get on an elevator due to his size.</p>
<p>A corrections officer said it took eight officers to lift York into the ambulance at Rikers Island prison for transport to the courthouse. York has been held there since his arrest in January.</p>
<p>&quot;He's miserable. He's been beaten up and robbed of his gold chain in the jail. He has no clothes. He's naked there. He has skin problems related to his bedridden status,&quot; York's lawyer complained to the judge.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
