<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40191" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish anti-monopoly body probes telecom firm TPSA.</title>
<headline>Polish anti-monopoly body probes telecom firm TPSA.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish government's Anti-Monopoly Office has launched anti-trust proceedings against state-owned telecommunications company TPSA, the office's spokeswoman said on Monday.</p>
<p>The proceedings, initiated late last month, concern TPSA's decision to charge higher fees for its subsidiary, Centertel SA, to use its group telecommunications facilities, the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>&quot;On August 27, 1996, proceedings were initiated in connection with alleged monopolist practices by Telekomunikacja Polska SA (TPSA),&quot; Jolanta Micel-Thor told Reuters.</p>
<p>The proceedings could lead to a ruling by a special anti-monopoly court, which may fine TPSA and order it to discontinue its actions.</p>
<p>TPSA is in conflict with Centertel's foreign partners -- France Telecom and Ameritech Corp, which have a privileged position on the company's boards, although they hold only 24.4 percent of its shares each.</p>
<p>For more than a year TPSA has been seeking more say in Centertel's management and a bigger share in the company's profits -- goals opposed by the foreign shareholders.</p>
<p>In the latest run-in, TPSA has cancelled its agreement with the cellular operator allowing it to use ground telecommunications facilities. Centertel continues to use the equipment and TPSA is seeking hefty compensation for that.</p>
<p>Centertel, which is currently Poland's sole cellular phone company and uses an analogue system -- will soon face competition from two firms which have gained licences to set up modern GSM digital networks.</p>
<p>TPSA has blocked a bid by Centertel's foreign partners for a GSM licence.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
