<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="401979" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil bounces but no end to price slide yet in sight.</title>
<headline>Oil bounces but no end to price slide yet in sight.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil prices bounced on Tuesday but the move was seen unlikely to herald more than a temporary pause to a slide that has seen levels slump by more than 20 percent in just six weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a bounce from an oversold situation,&quot; said Peter Gignoux, manager of Smith Barney's petroleum desk in London, adding that the weather, particularly for the U.S. market, remains the key.</p>
<p>International benchmark Brent Blend futures for April delivery on London's International Petroleum Exchange (IPE) was 46 cents higher at $19.58 per barrel at 1636 GMT.</p>
<p>Brent hit a low of $19.09 on Monday and is still almost $5 below the high seen in January.</p>
<p>A mild winter in the northern hemisphere and rising Iraqi oil sales have combined to force prices down this year.</p>
<p>Independent forecaster Weather Services Corporation predicted &quot;above average temperatures&quot; throughout Europe this week as well as a warmer spell in the United States, cutting into demand for heating oil.</p>
<p>&quot;The direction of heating oil is the direction of the market in the short-term,&quot; said Gignoux.</p>
<p>The market will also be watching for the weekly U.S. oil inventory data from the American Petroleum Institute (API) scheduled for release after markets close on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Few weeks of the winter season remain, while stocks (of heating oil) have been on the rise compared with a year ago,&quot; said Leslie Nicholas with brokers GNI Ltd in a daily report.</p>
<p>&quot;Although a draw of around two million barrels is expected, remember that is was cold late last season so the year-to-year excess is likely to widen.&quot;</p>
<p>In the week ended February 14, the API said heating oil supplies were about even with a year ago in the energy hungry northeast United States and 1.3 million barrels over year ago levels for the country as a whole.</p>
<p>One effect of this year's price drop is that Iraq will export more oil to meet a target allowed under the United Nations' oil-for-food exchange which began in December.</p>
<p>Iraq can export one billions dollars' worth of oil by March 9, and a futher billion dollars by early June when the deal comes up for review at the United Nations.</p>
<p>With Iraqi crude now fetching about $5 a barrel less than in December, analysts say Baghdad will need to export around 800,000 barrels per day over the next week and a half to meet its cash target -- down from around 500,000 bpd in January.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>						Feb 25    Feb 24</p>
<p>					    (1636 GMT)   (close)</p>
<p>    Dated Brent			   $20.07    $19.87</p>
<p>    IPE London Brent futures (Apr)  $19.58    $19.12</p>
<p>    NYMEX light crude futures (Apr) $21.09    $20.71</p>
<p>LON MME</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
