<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="402084" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Emerging Europe Advertising &amp; Media Digest -Feb 25.</title>
<headline>Emerging Europe Advertising &amp; Media Digest -Feb 25.</headline>
<text>
<p>REUTERS EMERGING EUROPE PRESS DIGEST FOR ADVERTISING &amp; MEDIA</p>
<p>--------------- February 25, 1997 ------------------</p>
<p>Weekly Press Digest from Central and Eastern Europe on Advertising, Marketing, the Media and Brand-name Products ***********************************************</p>
<p>ADVERTISING &amp; MARKETING:</p>
<p>-- The Czech Olympic Commission's Executive Committee has decided to establish its own marketing company. The company's goal will be to ensure the &quot;Top 10&quot; project, which should bring in 250 million crowns ($8.8 million) by the year 2000. The new company will take over the former job of APC. (Lidove Noviny, February 20, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- The Czech Hockey League has decided to terminate its relationship with its marketing partner, Teleaxis, after Teleaxis asked a trade court to object to the sale of advertising rights of the hockey league. The hockey league said it would end its relationship with Teleaxis at the end of the season, although Teleaxis' contract runs until 1999. (Lidove Noviny, February 20, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- The Reader's Digest 1996 Gold Pegazus Prize for the best advertisement in Hungary has been awarded to advertising agency hat Reklamugynokseg for its Suzuki ad. DDB Needham Budapest came in second with a McDonalds advertisement, while McCann-Erickson Budapest ended up in at third place with an ad for the telecommunications firm Pannon GSM.(Vilaggazdasag, February 20, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- The Czech Republic's National Federation of Hotels and Restaurants and the International Institute of Tourism and Management will hold a seminar on the marketing strategy of three- and four-star hotels. The seminar will be held at Prague's Hotel Intercontinental from February 23 to 25. (TTG Czech Republic, February, issue 4)</p>
<p>**************************</p>
<p>MEDIA:-- The Czech Republic's council for radio and television broadcasting wants Radio Nova Alfa to pay a 10 million crown fine for not complying with the authorised music format. Alfa has until March 10 to pay the fine, or the council will cut off the station's broadcasting, council vice chairman Zdena Hulova said. (Pravo, February 19)</p>
<p>***************************</p>
<p>BRAND-NAME PRODUCTS AND MARKETS:</p>
<p>-- Nokia, the Finnish industrial concern, reports a flourishing mobile phone business in Hungary and says it plans to double its staff in Hungary in 1997, up from the current 800. Telecommunications company Panon GSM is Nokia's main partner in Hungary, with Pannon's orders for 1997 at $50 million.</p>
<p>(Vilaggazdasag, February 17,1997 )</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Britain in 1996 became the main export market for Hungarian wines, with exports to the UK totalling $17 million or 15 percent of total wine exports. One in every seven bottles of Hungarian wine is bought by British consumers. (Vilaggazdasag February 19, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Hollywood Photo Kft, Hungarian subsidiary of Canadian photo firm Sooter's, faces lawsuits from Hungarian franchisees seeking modifications to their contracts. The franchisees allege Sooters has failed to supply them with sufficient quantities of goods and marketing aids over the past few months. Photo Kft admitted problems existed but said this was offset by concessions and said new revised franchise contracts would be signed soon. (Vilaggazdasag, February 18, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Leading German food retailer group Rewe plans to open 250 to 300 new units within its Penny Market supermarket chain in Hungary by the end of 1997. Over the past five months Rewe has opened 17 new supermarkets, offering products at prices lower than all its competitors in Hungary. (Vilaggazdasag, February 18, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Hungary's Skala-Coop Rt appears interested in acquiring a controlling stake in its main rival, Centrum Rt, the country's largest department store chain. Centrum, which needs fresh capital, may accept Skala's offer, which would raise HUF1bn.</p>
<p>(Figyelo, February 13, 1997)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Software company Novell is introducing to the Czech market network software called IntranetWare for Small Business. The product lists for $895, but Novell is selling it at $495 to to customers who want to upgrade from old software versions.</p>
<p>(Reflex, February 20)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- French automaker Renault will introduce the Megane Scenic, named European Automobile of the Year for 1997, on the Czech market in early March. Renault will also introduce the Megane Classic. (Lidove Noviny, February 20)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Coca-Cola Amatil Czech Republic is leading in the Czech soft drink market, breaking away from its main competitor, Pepsi-Cola Czech Republic, whose sales also increased considerably.</p>
<p>Domestic beverage company Toma, which has drastically increased its output, ranks third. (Hospodarske Noviny, February 17)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- Czech brewer Plzensky Prazdroj is discussing a proposed merger with Jihoceske Pivovary, which would give it control of the Samon, Regent and Platan beer brands. A merger would push Plzensky Prazdroj share of the Czech beer market in 1997 to close to 30 percent, up from the 25 percent it seeks to obtain on its own. (Hospodarske Noviny, February 17)</p>
<p>*********</p>
<p>-- SPT Telecom on July 1 will begin offering telecommunication integrated services ISDN in Prague and in Czech cities with more than 200,000 residents a. By the end of the year. ISDN enables the customer to connect voice, data and picture services, and all three combined through one digital connector. (Pravo, February 17, 1997)</p>
<p>-- Reuters London Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 2792</p>
<p>***********************************************</p>
<p>See more stories on Eastern Europe and the rest of the world on Reuters Advertising &amp; Media Briefing. Why not visit our Internet site at http://www.bizinfo.reuters.com?</p>
<p>*********************************************** ($ = 28.39 Czech Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
