<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="402094" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: FOCUS-Pressure mounts on Swedish govt to join EMU.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Pressure mounts on Swedish govt to join EMU.</headline>
<byline>Belinda Goldsmith</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pressure is mounting on the Swedish government to join the first round of European economic and monetary union (EMU), with three central bank board members and the opposition joining the pro-EMU drive on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But the centre-left Social Democratic government which has to take the final decision is keeping quiet, keenly aware that supporting EMU entry may well cost it the general election due to be held in September 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;It is unacceptable that the government is playing musical chairs on the European question and especially on EMU,&quot; said Lars Tobisson, who is deputy leader of the conservative opposition, the Moderates. &quot;The government should have a more positive attitude towards EMU.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists say Sweden is now cleanly split down the middle on the crucial issue, with the industrial lobby pleading for membership and powerful unions and the population at large rejecting it.</p>
<p>Pragmatic Prime Minister Goran Persson appears set to listen to voters by trying to bring Sweden into EMU in a second wave of entrants around the turn of the century, political analysts say.</p>
<p>Opinion polls show a majority of Swedes are opposed to joining EMU at the start -- and would even vote against joining the European Union if a referendum were held now.</p>
<p>Sweden joined the EU in January 1995 after a 52.5 percent vote on favour of membership in a referendum in November 1994.</p>
<p>Sweden's central bank, the Riksbank, has made its views on EMU clear. Sweden should join the EMU from the start.</p>
<p>&quot;The economic benefits and the possibility of influencing the future direction of monetary policy leads the Riksbank's governing board to conclude that Sweden should participate in the EMU from the start,&quot; the bank said in a recent statement.</p>
<p>On Tuesday three Riksbank board members gave their backing to this position. Chairman Kjell-Olof Feldt, vice Chairman Bengt Westerberg and board member Johan Gernandt dismissed a wait-and-see recommendation by a government commission led by Lars Calmfors.</p>
<p>&quot;Our conclusion is that the Calmfors commission's arguments for waiting with EMU membership do not hold when scrutinised,&quot; the trio wrote in the Swedish daily Svenska Dagbladet.</p>
<p>The Calmfors commission said Sweden should wait to join EMU until unemployment was lower and the labour market functioned better.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no reason to believe that the possibilities to fight unemployment would be better if we choose to remain outside (EMU),&quot; the Riksbank board members said.</p>
<p>&quot;But we do not want to argue that membership per se will solve our employment problems. To handle these problems requires a range of measures spanning a broad field, where wage development is a key factor.&quot;</p>
<p>The three argued that Sweden should be among the first wave of countries to join EMU on January 1, 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;It is evident that the countries -- even if they meet convergence criteria -- that choose to stand aside will have less influence in these issues than those that want to join and do join from the start,&quot; they said.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
