<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="402005" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Benefits from clone sheep years away, researchers say.</title>
<headline>Benefits from clone sheep years away, researchers say.</headline>
<byline>Maggie Fox</byline>
<dateline>ROSLIN, Scotland 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cloning adult animals could eventually offer a range of benefits, from a cure for mad cow disease to effective new treatments for haemophilia, the researchers who pioneered the technique said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Herds of animals could now more easily be bred to produce milk, blood and organs used in a wide variety of medical treatments -- but such possibilities are years away, they said.</p>
<p>Ian Wilmut and colleagues at the Roslin Institute near Edinburgh have made scientific history by successfully cloning a sheep from the cell of another adult sheep.</p>
<p>&quot;There are some scientists for whom it is just pure knowledge,&quot; Wilmut said. But there are also commercial benefits -- and these are the aim of Wilmut's group, which works with biotechnology company PPL Therapeutics Plc.</p>
<p>PPL already breeds genetically engineered animals that are used to produce human proteins. It is clinically testing a product known as AAT (alpha-1 antitrypsin), a protein derived from the transgenic sheep's milk that they hope can be used to treat cystic fibrosis.</p>
<p>They are also working to create animals whose blood or milk produces human chemicals such as fibrinogen and Factor IX, important for blood clotting and of possible use in surgery and treating haemophilia.</p>
<p>&quot;The immediate application is in biotechnology, particularly in the production of pharmaceutical proteins,&quot; Wilmut said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the longer term there is the possibility of doing this in pigs for organ transplant.&quot;</p>
<p>Pigs are currently favoured for the still controversial idea of transplanting animal organs into people, because of their similar size to humans.</p>
<p>The pigs must be genetically engineered so the human's immune system will be tricked into accepting their organs. The creation of a perfectly transgenic pig would allow doctors to clone it and farm organs from its genetic twins.</p>
<p>The technology will also offer better opportunities to study scrapie and related diseases like bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE, or mad cow disease), Wilmut said.</p>
<p>BSE, scrapie and the human Creutzfeldt-Jakob Disease all have genetic components. &quot;We now have the opportunity to modify that gene and to study its role in disease,&quot; Wilmut said.</p>
<p>Another idea is genetically modifying cows' milk to remove proteins and sugars to which many people are allergic.</p>
<p>But such genetic targeting is highly inefficient. Genetic engineering involves removing a cell's genetic material, inserting a gene, and then injecting this new mix into other cells. Sometimes the cells &quot;take&quot; the new gene or genes and sometimes they don't.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the animals born of this technology are not transgenic,&quot; Alan Colman, PPL's research director, said.</p>
<p>His hope is that adult transgenic animals, for instance a sheep known to produce good amounts of a human protein in her milk, could be cloned.</p>
<p>Fewer animals would be &quot;wasted&quot; and more of the desirable chemicals would be produced. It can work the other way around, too. &quot;For the first time, one can now consider selectively removing genes from livestock,&quot; Colman said.</p>
<p>However, cloning itself is still hit-and-miss. &quot;It is a significant breakthrough but there are limitations to this technology,&quot; Wilmut said.</p>
<p>Out of hundreds of attempts to grow a clone, only a few work -- and Dolly the cloned sheep is the only successful efforts using an adult cell.</p>
<p>&quot;Very few of the eggs progress at all,&quot; Wilmut said. &quot;But we expect the procedure to become more efficient.&quot;</p>
<p>The process is also subject to all the weaknesses of growing an embryo in a test-tube. Many of the foetuses become oversized, something Colman thinks may be due to growing embryos in a test-tube culture. Others die for no obvious reason.</p>
<p>But PPL and Roslin are confident they can make the process work. Asked how much money the company stood to earn from the technology, Managing Director Ron James answered simply: &quot;Lots.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROSLIN, Scotland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
