<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="402178" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Winter sales tame Irish Jan consumer prices - CSO.</title>
<headline>Winter sales tame Irish Jan consumer prices - CSO.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The impact of the winter sales on food and clothing and durable household goods helped tame Ireland's consumer price index in January, the Central Statistics Office (CSO) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The January CPI, the first monthly Irish CPI index to be published, showed a 0.5 percent drop on November 1996 and rose 0.9 percent in the 11 months since February last year.</p>
<p>This was well below market forecasts which had anticipated a 0.1 to 0.3 percent rise on November and a 1.7 to 1.8 percent increase on February.  </p>
<p>Up until now, the CSO has published CPI data on a quarterly basis so there are no monthly comparable readings for 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Clothing and footwear and durable household goods are the main players in the reduction,&quot; senior statistician Kevin McCormack told a new conference. &quot;This is the first January CPI and the effect we can see standing out here is the sales.&quot;</p>
<p>The price of clothing and footwear fell by 8.3 percent in the two months since November and was down 8.5 percent in the eleven months since last February.</p>
<p>The price of durable household goods was down 2.1 percent on November and 1.2 percent on February.</p>
<p>CSO statisticians warned against reading too much into one month's figures and noted that last February's index included the impact of the 1996 budget while the January figures were not affected by the 1997 budget, announced on January 22.</p>
<p>But they said the data suggested there was no evidence of an upward move in prices last month.</p>
<p>Analysts have been concerned that recent Irish pound weakness against sterling could result in import price increases, fuelling inflation, while Irish credit growth remains strong and well above the central bank's target.</p>
<p>&quot;One thing you can say comfortably is that the figures do not indicate any upward pressure on inflation,&quot; CSO director-general Donal Murphy said.</p>
<p>-- Jane O'Sullivan, Dublin Newsroom +353 1 676 9779</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
