<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="402109" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Rato won't say where Spain Telefonica funds headed.</title>
<headline>Rato won't say where Spain Telefonica funds headed.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spanish Economy Minister Rodrigo Rato declined to specify on Tuesday exactly what the government intended to do with the 607 billion pesetas ($4.3 billion) it received from the privatisation of Telefonica.</p>
<p>&quot;(The sale of the state's 20.9 percent stake in Telefonica) is substantial income for (tax authority) Hacienda, but I won't say any more,&quot; Rato replied to questions on whether the government planned to cut the public deficit with part of the money.</p>
<p>Fernando Diaz Moreno, vice-secretary for the Economy Ministry, told reporters on Monday that the Treasury received 375 billion pesetas from the privatisation, which is expected to go towards writing down public debt.</p>
<p>Public debt currently stands at 69.3 percent of gross domestic product.</p>
<p>Additionally, Hacienda will receive a total of 180 billion pesetas via two corporate tax payments from state holding SEPPa, under which the Telefonica stake was administered, as capital gains on the privatisation, Diaz Moreno said.</p>
<p>By accounting for part of the privatisation income as tax receipts, the government could use the money to reduce the public deficit, local press reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The European Commission specifies that privatisation income cannot be used to reduce the public deficit but can be used to redeem public debt for purposes of European convergence.</p>
<p>&quot;The privatisation does not fall under the heading of the government's budget policy. It's difficult to account for this income according to the Maastricht criteria...but rather, under the government's liberalisation and structural reforms,&quot; Diaz Moreno himself said on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom +341 585 2160 ($ = 142.0 Spanish Pesetas)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
