<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="402275" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: White House officials vow push for Chile NAFTA bid.</title>
<headline>White House officials vow push for Chile NAFTA bid.</headline>
<byline>Donna Smith</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Clinton administration officials are likely to promise Chilean President Eduardo Frei in meetings this week that they will work hard to win Congressional approval of trade legislation to bring Chile into NAFTA.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to work hard to get fast track passed,&quot; White House Chief of Staff Erskine Bowles told reporters following a speech this week to the U.S. Chamber of Commerce.</p>
<p>But administration officials decline to say when they plan to send to Congress proposed &quot;fast track' bill. The legislation is needed to negotiate an agreement to bring Chile into the North American Free Trade Agreement without fear it will be subjected to changes by Congress.</p>
<p>&quot;We're in the process of working with Congress and various other groups interested in fast track to determine the bounds of the bill and its scope,&quot; U.S. Trade Representative Designate Charlene Barshefsky told reporters this week.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there's no question but that this administration, as every administration over many decades, should have the negotiating authority to enter into the kinds of comprehensive market access agreements that we need to have in order to keep the exports going out the door,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Frei is likely to make a case for fast track legislation when he addresses a joint session of Congress on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Complete trade liberalisation between Chile and the United States not only would strengthen our economic relations, but will also have a significant impact in the process of free trade in the Americas, which is an objective pursued by both countries,&quot; Frei told a business group in Chicago. He meets President Bill Clinton on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Chile was invited to join the North American trade bloc, which links the United States, Canada and Mexico, at the first Summit of the Americas in Miami in December, 1994.</p>
<p>But Chile has declined to go forward until Congress passes the fast track authority. It fears special interest groups could lobby lawmakers to derail trade pacts without the authority. With fast track, lawmakers would vote either for or against the agreement with no opportunity of amendments.</p>
<p>Administration officials have said they are optimistic Congress will pass fast track legislation, but it is clear they face an uphill battle.</p>
<p>Anti-NAFTA groups are already gearing up for a fight.</p>
<p>Consumer advocate Ralph Nader's Public Citizen released a report this week saying that NAFTA failed to deliver on promises that the 1993 agreement would create thousands of new jobs for American workers.</p>
<p>&quot;The real life record is that while the promised jobs have failed to materialise, existing U.S. jobs continue to be lost to NAFTA,&quot; Joan Claybrook, president of Public Citizen said in a statement.</p>
<p>House Minority Leader Richard Gephardt, a strong opponent of NAFTA, said at an AFL-CIO meeting last week that there could be no fast track authority until NAFTA's problems are fixed. He said wages in Mexican border towns had dropped from an average of about $1 an hour to 70 cents and hour.</p>
<p>&quot;NAFTA has validated a system, a governmental and business system, that does not allow workers to have the ability to get paid and compensated for their hard work. Their productivity is way up, their wages are way down,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Efforts to pass fast track legislation were put on hold during last year's presidential election campaign after the administration and Republican Congressional leaders failed to agree on authority to negotiate labour and environmental issues in trade agreements.</p>
<p>Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott said he does not want fast track authority to include labour and the environment.</p>
<p>But it will be difficult for Clinton to win support among his own Democrats without authority to negotiate on labour and environmental issues.</p>
<p>&quot;They are going to have trouble on the Democratic side, said one Republican congressional aide. &quot;If President Clinton can't deliver Democrats, he is not going to get fast track.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton will have to rely on the Republican majority in Congress to win passage of the fast track legislation. But he will need &quot;a respectable number of Democrats&quot; to get Republican swing votes on board, the aide said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
