<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="402387" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - British women eye history in Polar quest.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - British women eye history in Polar quest.</headline>
<byline>Scott McCormack</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>They are 20 ordinary women aiming for the extraordinary -- to be the first all-female expedition to trek overland to the top of the world.</p>
<p>Their journey to the North Pole will take them across 1,000 km (620 miles) of frozen ocean as they drag 55 kg (120 lb) sleds over razor-sharp ridges of ice.</p>
<p>The women are not veteran adventurers but housewives, teachers, financiers, a policewoman, even a great niece of the Queen Mother. Their ages range from 21 to 50 and one is the mother of two-year-old triplets.</p>
<p>&quot;They are all very ordinary women who see this as the opportunity of a lifetime to achieve something special,&quot; said 33-year-old Caroline Hamilton, a London-based film financier who has spearheaded the expedition, which the women believe is the largest to the pole.</p>
<p>On reaching the Pole, the women will not find a distinct landmark. Ice floes on the ocean that covers the point shift constantly.</p>
<p>&quot;That is the beauty of it. My North Pole will be different from anyone else's,&quot; said Hamilton. &quot;There is a sheer exhilaration from surviving in those kinds of conditions.&quot;</p>
<p>Twenty-six-year-old Victoria Riches, who will be joined on the polar ice cap by her mother Sue, explained her motivation for joining an all-women endeavour: &quot;We all like to think we are as strong as men, but are we? That's what this is all about -- proving we are the same and can do it.</p>
<p>&quot;When I told my mother I was doing it, she said, 'Excellent, I'm going with you. Just don't tell your father'.&quot;</p>
<p>Hamilton approached a British travel agency specialising in Arctic voyages last year. She decided she wanted to make history with an all-women team and then had to find 19 others willing to share the risk.</p>
<p>News of the plan spread quickly, and Hamilton received more than 200 inquiries. &quot;If it had not been an all women's trip, most of them would probably have been scared away. Too often women are just token members of an expedition and not the most important part,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>SURVIVAL OF THE FITTEST</p>
<p>Over two intensive survival weekends, the aspirants were whittled down to the chosen 20.</p>
<p>The final selection test consisted of an &quot;absolutely hellish&quot; two-day outing on the English moors modelled on training by the Special Air Service (SAS), Britain's elite military commandos.</p>
<p>Nearly everyone, save two hypothermia victims, finished the first weekend unscathed. But during the second -- which featured night runs and swimming in freezing waters with a rucksack -- the women began to crack.</p>
<p>&quot;We had to push them to the limits because so much of this trip is going to be mental, not physical. It's about pushing on, never letting up,&quot; said Hamilton.</p>
<p>The women will split into five groups of four and form a relay team, led by two professional female guides, to cross the frozen ocean separating their base camp on the tip of Canada's Northwest Territories from the North Pole.</p>
<p>The first team leaves London for Canada's Resolute Bay on Friday and, after a week of training, sets out on the first leg of the journey.</p>
<p>The last group must reach its goal by the end of May, when warming weather begins to make the ice floes dangerous.</p>
<p>Since their selection, the women have undergone intensive physical training. Some have gained nearly a stone (14 lb) in muscle.</p>
<p>&quot;We work as a team and are there for one another, no matter how difficult it might get. That is a great comfort,&quot; said Rose Agnew, a teacher in London and one of two 50-year-olds on the expedition.</p>
<p>&quot;But the nearer it looms, the more realistic your thoughts become. We are headed to the Arctic. I worry, am I strong enough to keep going? How will I cope with the cold? How will it actually feel?&quot;</p>
<p>Victoria's mother Sue, who battled cancer several years ago and at 50 is the oldest member of the expedition, echoed many of her teammates' fears of being the one person to hold the group back, but drew comfort in the experience that comes with age.</p>
<p>&quot;The older you get, the more you can just keep going. I might not have the speed of a 30-year-old, but mentally I am very strong. I'm not that worried about the cold because I've been told women have an extra layer of fat than men. We should be all right. We're very tough.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;But a man could be useful on the trip,&quot; she added. &quot;We joke that our luxury would be to have one in our sleeping bags to help keep us warm.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
