<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="402339" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INTERVIEW - Guardian see hopes for rates in.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Guardian see hopes for rates in.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Premium rates in the motor and household insurance markets are expected to strengthen in the coming year but commercial rates are expected to continue to be weak, Guardian Royal Exchange finance director James Morley said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The German market was &quot;difficult to call&quot; but was likely to be flat said Morley, speaking after the company reported a 17 percent fall in trading profits for the year to 281 million stg.</p>
<p>&quot;Motor was up three to four percent during 1996 and is expected to be positive again during 1997 and possibly quite a lot more than that,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview.  </p>
<p>&quot;In UK household in 1996 we saw a rating environment where prices were going down rather than up. The particularly cold spell at the beginning of the year will have reminded people not to underprice household and we would expect the second half of the year to be flattish or slightly positive.&quot;</p>
<p>The results included a second half provision for the integration of the Legal &amp; General business and fundamental restructuring of the UK insurance business and the company said it had achieved a great deal in effectively positioning the group for the future.</p>
<p>&quot;A new management structure was put in place at the beginning of 1997. We believe that in the next two years realised cost svaings will equal the 39 million stg in exceptional charges for the year,&quot; said Morley.</p>
<p>This year's exceptional charge is expected to cover all the costs required to complete the restructuring over the next 12 to 18 months.</p>
<p>There will be some facility closures and further staff losses to come, said Morley but declined to put an overall number on the extent of the layoffs.  </p>
<p>Following the acquisition of RAC Insurance services in May, nine million pounds was provided at the half year for integration and standardising accounting systems.</p>
<p>&quot;The integration of RAC into the direct telephone operation is complete. As policies come up for renewal customers are being offered terms by Guardian Direct and the conversion rate is close to 100 percent,&quot; said Morley.</p>
<p>The company said it continued to target increases in premiums only in sectors and regions where it was confident of profitable growth and acceptable underwriting margins and to withdraw from non-core, non-performing markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Where we form a strategic view that we see no benefit from being in a market segment and that market segment will not give us the rates of return we require then we will withdraw from it,&quot; said Morley.</p>
<p>&quot;Where we have a strategic benefit from being in a market segment then we will use our market presence to ensure we get the rate we require over the medium term. In the shorter term we will walk away from certain business if we can't get the right rates.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
