<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="402488" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia trade gap narrows in '96, seen improving.</title>
<headline>Malaysia trade gap narrows in '96, seen improving.</headline>
<byline>Christina Pantin</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's trade gap shrank in 1996, data released on Tuesday showed, and analysts widely expect a further narrowing in the deficit over 1997, but at a slower pace as infrastructure projects suck in imports.</p>
<p>The Statistics Department said the country's 1996 trade deficit slid to 617.97 million ringgit ($250.19 million) from 9.36 billion ringgit in 1995.</p>
<p>In December 1996 alone, Malaysia had a trade surplus of 872 million ringgit, compared with a deficit of 526.4 million in November and a surplus of 637.34 million in December 1995.</p>
<p>Economists said Malaysia's turnaround in December reflected regional strength as demand picked up from the country's Western trading partners in the second half of the year.</p>
<p>The 1996 deficit was significantly less than the deficit of 5.2 billion ringgit forecast in the Finance Ministry's Economic Report, released last October.</p>
<p>Desmond Supple, chief economist at BZW, said: &quot;Overall, we are going to see an improving trend. The current account deficit is on a long-term narrowing trend.&quot;</p>
<p>Supple noted that the current account deficit of 11.0 billion ringgit in 1996 fell below five percent of gross domestic product (GDP) in 1996, from 8.8 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>Andy Tan, general manager of MMS International in Singapore, added: &quot;We don't expect this year to be another big improvement such as we saw in 1996, but we expect the trend established last year to be maintained this year.&quot;</p>
<p>Malaysia has forecast a 1997 trade deficit of 340 million ringgit.</p>
<p>The department said exports last year totalled 196.69 billion ringgit, up 6.3 percent from 1995. Imports were 197.31 billion ringgit, up 1.5 percent from 1995.</p>
<p>Electronic parts reamined the country's biggest export earner in 1996 with receipts totalling 35.2 billion ringgit, or 17.9, percent of total export earnings. Commodities products generated the second largest export revenues.</p>
<p>A recovery in the electronics industry, which suffered a sharp drop in demand last year due to industry overcapacity, will help Malaysia's exports, economists said.</p>
<p>The biggest contributor to the increased level of imports in 1996 was machinery and transport equipment, which rose 1.6 billion ringgit, or 1.4 percent, the department said.</p>
<p>Malaysia's construction boom has led to imports of heavy machinery, and economists say the rush to complete infrastructure projects before the 1998 Commonwealth Games, which Malaysia is hosting, will hamper big trade improvements.</p>
<p>&quot;As the Commonwealth Games nears, they (the government) will have to import,&quot; said Liew Yin Sze, chief economist at J.M. Sassoon &amp; Co in Singapore. &quot;My view is that the improvement in 1997 will be harder to come by.&quot;</p>
<p>Malaysia's improved December trade position is in line with other countries in the region such as Singapore, said Bernhard Eschweiler, vice president of economic research at J.P. Morgan in Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we have a good chance of seeing stronger numbers in the next few months, largely led on the export side,&quot; he said. &quot;This doesn't mean there could not be a disappointing month which could show a lumpy import item,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>($1=2.47 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
