<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="402528" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Telekom net seen up 14-18 pct.</title>
<headline>Telekom net seen up 14-18 pct.</headline>
<byline>Reme Ahmad</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Net earnings at state-run telecommunications firm Telekom Malaysia Bhd are expected to rise between 14 percent and 18 percent for 1996, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said Telekom should post earnings of around 1.8 billion ringgit to 1.85 billion ringgit ($725.8 million to $746 million) for calendar 1996, up from 1.575 billion ringgit in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;There're not going to be any surprises. It should be within market expectations,&quot; said a telecommunications analyst at a European brokerage.</p>
<p>A Telekom official said the company was expected to report year-end results this week.</p>
<p>Analysts said higher revenues from local and long-distance domestic calls -- which make up about 50 percent of turnover -- will underpin earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;If you are looking at the bottom line per se and nothing else, it won't deviate much from the consensus,&quot; said Haizan Khir Johari, analyst at Schroder Research. &quot;But I heard there could be slight disappointment in one or two aspects of the business.&quot;</p>
<p>The consensus forecast of analysts in the Estimate Directory puts Telekom's net profit at 1.85 billion, or 92.5 cents a share.</p>
<p>Analysts said for the ongoing financial year, the immediate concerns for Telekom come from worries about competition in the local market.</p>
<p>Other Malaysian telecommunications players have been calling for an earlier start to industry liberalisation, while Telekom's newly launched mobile phone service has arrived in an already overcrowded market.</p>
<p>Telekom's stock has been under pressure in recent weeks, due partly to concerns that the government would bring forward an earlier start to &quot;equal access&quot;. This would let Telekom's three million subscribers use the networks of other fixed-line operators to make international calls.</p>
<p>But analysts said recent official comments suggested the industry would not be ready for equal access before the original starting date of January 1, 1999.</p>
<p>The government has awarded fixed-line licences to Time Engineering Bhd's telecommunications unit, Technology Resources Industries Bhd, Mutiara Telecommunications Sdn Bhd and Binariang Sdn Bhd.</p>
<p>&quot;The feeling is that all operators must be prepared. But by the time that happens, it will be near the end of 1998,&quot; said a research head at a Malaysian brokerage.</p>
<p>Analysts said issues such as interconnection costs and sharing of revenue have yet to be resolved.</p>
<p>Telekom's recently launched mobile phone service, called TMTouch, will take time to make money in the highly competitive market. There are six other mobile service operators and they all have a big head start over Telekom, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It takes time for them to break even, maybe two to three years,&quot; said the Malaysian brokerage's research head.</p>
<p>($1 = 2.48 ringgit)</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
