<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="402611" id="root" date="1997-02-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs end firmer after rebounding toward close.</title>
<headline>JGBs end firmer after rebounding toward close.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key March Japanese government bond futures contract ended firmer on Tuesday on short-covering that emerged toward the close.</p>
<p>Comments made by Chief Cabinet Secretary Seiroku Kajiyama that the interest rate gap between Japan and other countries should be narrowed invited some selling early in the afternoon, but the impact was limited overall, traders said.</p>
<p>The comments seemed to suggest displeasure at the current low level of interest rates, but the impact on the market was limited because Kajiyama's words were too ambiguous, a city bank trader said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Our interest rates (on deposits) are the lowest compared to other countries with the exception of Switzerland. However, looking at companies, rates (on borrowing) are higher compared to other countries. As part of the internationalisation component of the current reforms, we need to raise the low things and lower the high things,&quot; Kajiyama told a key parliamentary committee.</p>
<p>The March ended bid only, and was last traded at 126.10, up slightly from the previous day's close of 126.08. Turnover was 58,666 contracts.  </p>
<p>The Ministry of Finance's announcement of the results of a 10-year JGB auction late in the afternoon had little impact on the market, traders said.</p>
<p>MOF offered 1.0 trillion yen of 2.6 percent 10-year JGBs through a price-competitive auction on Tuesday.</p>
<p>MOF said the lowest price at the auction was 100.40 and the average price was 100.45.</p>
<p>The market will be watching to see how much demand there is among investors for the new issues, a trader for a city bank's securities unit said.  </p>
<p>The benchmark 182nd JGB yield stood at 2.405 percent as of 0651 GMT, down from the previous day's close of 2.415 percent.</p>
<p>In the cash bond market, the trader for a city bank's securities unit said there was talk that investors had been selling cash JGBs ranging from the 190th to 193rd issues in the morning.</p>
<p>Traders said investors were detected selling six-year cash JGBs in the afternoon.</p>
<p>City banks were apparently behind the sales of six-year JGBs, a trader for a trust bank's securities unit said.</p>
<p>--Tokyo Treasury Desk, +81-3-5473-3748</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
