<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403235" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Uncertainty high in Staples/Depot.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Uncertainty high in Staples/Depot.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investors expect the proposed merger between office superstores Office Depot Inc and Staples Inc to be completed but options activity suggests uncertainy over the timing remains high, traders said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Today the option activity suggests the deal may be consummated but the timing of it is a little uncertain,&quot; Frank McGarvey of TFM Investment Group said, referring to Staples options, which trade on the Philadelphia Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;The key word right now is uncertainty,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Staples, which had some of the most active options around, was down 13/16 at 21-7/16 in late trade Wednesday.</p>
<p>Office Depot, whose options on the American Stock Exchange were fairly busy, added 3/8 to 19-1/8.</p>
<p>Michael Schwartz, managing director at Oppenheimer &amp; Co, said some of the Staples option activity appeared to be from arbitrageurs protecting positions and taking on synthetic stock positions.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks to me like some arbitrageurs were buying the March 30 in-the-money puts to protect their positions and taking June 20 calls for stock substitution,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;If they have to keep rolling out the puts for protection, they will,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>McGarvey said both strategies were taking place.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people were closing out positions they had and some were opening positions and buying Office Depot against it,&quot; he said. &quot;Net net, some people were closing and others were trying to re-establish positions.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the call activity reflected investors' uncertainty.</p>
<p>The Staples March 20 call traded more than 9,700 contracts, making it the most active individual equity option.  </p>
<p>The Staples March 17-1/2 call traded nearly 7,000 contracts.</p>
<p>Other busy Staples options included the March 30 put, which traded 1,675 contracts, the March 22-1/2 put, which traded 1,060 contracts, and the June 20 call, which traded more than 1,000.</p>
<p>Among Office Depot options, the most active was the April 15 put, with volume of 2,125 contracts.</p>
<p>The March 20 call traded nearly 2,100, the April 22-1/2 call traded 1,505 and the April 20 call traded about 1,045.  </p>
<p>On Monday, consumer advocate Ralph Nader released a study that found lower prices where Staples and Office Depot stores compete with each other and called on the government to prevent the merger.</p>
<p>McGarvey at TFM Investment Group said the Nader comments raised speculation yesterday that the deal would fall through.</p>
<p>The two companies have already extended the Hart-Scott-Rodino waiting period to March 5 from February 25 and said Wednesday they intended to delay special shareholder meetings for a merger vote to March 7 from February 27. ((--G.Crawford, 312 408 8750/Email: derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
