<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403324" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Greenspan Q&amp;A, PART III - Indexed securities.</title>
<headline>Greenspan Q&amp;A, PART III - Indexed securities.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are excerpts from the question and answer session following the first leg of Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan's semi-annual Humphrey-Hawkins address before Congress.</p>
<p>Greenspan addressed the Senate Banking Committee at 1000 EST/1500 GMT.</p>
<p>SEN. MACK (R-FL): &quot;In a sense it seems like the Treasury agrees with your comments with respect with indexing ... it seems to me that one can make the argument that if the Treasury wants to protect investors in Treasury bonds by indexing that they would be interested in protecting those who make investments in other areas as well. Would you agree or disagree with that?&quot;</p>
<p>GREENSPAN: &quot;There's a simple way to find out: Ask them.&quot;</p>
<p>MACK: &quot;Well let me ask you. I would assume that you are supportive of the concept of indexing capital gains. Would you do that if you had to establish some prioritites lowering the tax rate or indexing -- which would you do?&quot;</p>
<p>GREENSPAN: &quot;Actually I'd go to indexing. And the reason I would is that it's really wrong to tax a part of a gain in assets which are attributable to a decline in the purchasing power of the currency, which is attributable to poor governmental economic policy. So for the government to tax peoples' assets which rise as a consequence of inferior actions on the part of government strikes me as most inappropriate. I would therefore say, that at a minimum, indexing capital gains at least eliminates that problem ... I must say ... had capital gains been indexed several years ago when there seemed to be some general bipartisan interest in doing so, I think you would find that all discussions of rate cuts currently would've in fact been implemented by the previous indexing that could've occurred. I don't deny there were very considerable difficulties in managing from a IRS point of view, indexing capital gains.</p>
<p>MACK: &quot;Which of the lower tax rate or indexing ... from an economic standpoint ... has the greater economic affect?&quot;</p>
<p>GREENSPAN: &quot;I don't know the answer to that. One of the reasons is that the way in which the capital gains tax works is very complex and subtle. And the way it raises revenues and looses revenues at times is very difficult to tell. Economists who have endeavored to apply detailed econometric analyses to these elements ... have not come up with any robust answers. It may be that somebody knows the answer to that question, but at the moment I do not. Maybe I'll become informed at a later date.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
