<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40336" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian Interbrew to take 50.8% of Ukraine brewer.</title>
<headline>Belgian Interbrew to take 50.8% of Ukraine brewer.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Privately-owned Belgian brewer Interbrew has agreed to buy a majority stake in Ukranian brewer Chernigiv Brewery - Desna, Interbrew said in a statement on Monday.</p>
<p>It gave no financial details of the deal. Interbrew would take a 50.8 percent stake in the share capital of Desna through a capital increase.  </p>
<p>Interbrew said this was the first strategic alliance between a Ukrainian brewer and an international player.</p>
<p>The statement said Desna was a strong regional brewer whose main brand was Chernigiv.</p>
<p>Located in Chernigiv itself, about 150 kms north-east of Kiev, the brewery produced over 500,000 hectolitres of beer and soft drinks in 1995. It employs about 650 people.</p>
<p>&quot;Interbrew has decided on this investment after a very thorough environmental study...which showed that both the barley and water were of high quality,&quot; the Belgian company said in the statement.</p>
<p>Best know for its Stella Artois brand, Interbrew is one of the world's leading brewing groups, and exports products to over 80 countries around the world.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
