<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403570" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-CONTROVERSIAL PENALTY TAKES CHELSEA THROUGH.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-CONTROVERSIAL PENALTY TAKES CHELSEA THROUGH.</headline>
<byline>Gideon Long</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A bitterly disputed penalty in the 117th minute gave Chelsea a 1-0 victory over Leicester in a compelling English F.A. Cup fifth round replay on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Referee Mike Reed adjudged Leicester's Matt Elliott had barged Chelsea's Norwegian Erland Johnsen as he closed in on goal in the dying minutes of extra-time after the initial 90 minutes ended goalless.</p>
<p>The decision appeared harsh and the Leicester players swarmed around Reed in protest.</p>
<p>When the pushing and shoving had ended French fullback Franck Leboeuf converted the spot kick and three minutes later Chelsea were through to the quarter-finals where they will meet first division Portsmouth.</p>
<p>The decision and the final result were all the more cruel for Leicester as they had held their own against Ruud Gullit's talented Chelsea side throughout the evening.</p>
<p>Leicester manager Martin O'Neill, whose side had hauled themselves back into the original tie to draw 2-2 after being 2-0 down, appeared shell-shocked after the match.</p>
<p>&quot;It's unbelievable, absolutely unbelievable,&quot; he said. The referee was five yards (metres) away when he gave the penalty. That is shocking. It's a disgrace.</p>
<p>&quot;The players have been heroic and to go out like that is heart-breaking.</p>
<p>Leboeuf was understandably happy.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt I had all the players behind me. I was sure I would score,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the night's other fifth round tie, Derby fought back from 2-0 down to win 3-2 courtesy of an 88th minute winner from Dean Sturridge.</p>
<p>Coventry, suprise F.A. Cup winners in 1987, surged ahead in the first 13 minutes thanks to goals from in-form Darren Huckerby and Noel Whelan.</p>
<p>But Derby were level by the interval and clawed their way into the last eight thanks to Sturridge's dramatic late strike, his 10th goal of the season.</p>
<p>Derby's quarter-final opponents Middlesbrough took a big step towards their first major final when they won 2-0 at second division Stockport in a semifinal first leg tie in England's other cup competition, the League Cup.</p>
<p>Danish striker Mikkel Beck scored Middlesbrough's first, beating the Stockport offside trap after 73 minutes and sliding a shot through the goalkeeper's legs.</p>
<p>Italy's Fabrizio Ravanelli added a second on a rain-soaked pitch at Stockport's tiny Edgeley Park ground, packed with a capacity 12,000 fans.</p>
<p>Stockport, conquerers of premier league Blackburn, West Ham and Southampton in previous rounds, now have a mountain to climb in the second leg at the Riverside stadium.</p>
<p>In the night's only premier league match Wimbledon drew 0-0 at Southampton to go fifth in the table, 11 points behind leaders Manchester United with two games in hand.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
