<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403578" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-INTER SURPRISED AS HODGSON NAMED NEW BLACKBURN BOSS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-INTER SURPRISED AS HODGSON NAMED NEW BLACKBURN BOSS.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Roy Hodgson was named as Blackburn Rovers' new manager on Wednesday -- although the announcement appeared to take his current club Inter Milan by surprise.</p>
<p>Hodgson, who has been at Inter for 16 months, is expected to take over from caretaker boss Tony Parkes at Ewood Park in July, Rovers' chairman Robert Coar said.</p>
<p>The announcement came just three months after Hodgson extended his contract with Inter until June 1999.</p>
<p>In a statement issued on November 20, Inter said that Hodgson had turned down an approach from Blackburn and had extended his contract, originally due to end in June this year, for a further two years.</p>
<p>Inter, clearly taken aback by Wednesday's announcement, said they could make no official comment until they had checked the reports from Blackburn and spoken to Hodgson who was in Naples with his squad preparing for an Italian Cup semifinal second leg match against Napoli on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>English premier league side Blackburn were left to find a new manager after Swede Sven-Goran Eriksson changed his mind about coming to Ewood Park from Sampdoria last week and decided to stay in Italy at Lazio instead.</p>
<p>Hodgson, 49, has not worked as a manager in his native England since he left Bristol City in 1982.</p>
<p>He made his name in Europe, enjoying success with the Swiss national team which qualified for the 1994 World Cup finals against the odds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
