<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403504" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NASD should drop bond fund risk ratings curbs--S&amp;P.</title>
<headline>NASD should drop bond fund risk ratings curbs--S&amp;P.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's has urged the National Association of Securities Dealers to permit bond funds to provide risk ratings developed by rating agencies to potential investors.</p>
<p>&quot;Research clearly shows that investors want more information about the market risk factors that could affect their mutual bond funds,&quot; S&amp;P President Leo O'Neill said in a 10-page comment letter delivered late Monday to NASD.  </p>
<p>S&amp;P Ratings Group in 1994 launched a service to rate the risk of bond funds, including municipal bond funds. But NASD, which regulates mutual fund advertising, ruled that funds may not use such ratings in sales literature.</p>
<p>NASD said it was worried that the ratings could mislead investors because they hinge on &quot;assumptions and speculation&quot; about the economy in general and about a company's solvency.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, NASD reopened the issue in December by calling for a new round of comments, which are due this week.  </p>
<p>O'Neill said S&amp;P's three-year-old risk ratings have demonstrated that they can accurately depict a fund's volatility. He noted the past few years, particularly 1994, have been marked by unusual volatility.</p>
<p>S&amp;P's president said NASD's recent position is &quot;puzzling&quot; since NASD has permitted localities to include credit ratings in sales documents for years.</p>
<p>Risk ratings provide investors with valuable, additional information, O'Neill said. &quot;The current prohibition is contrary to the public interest, ill-serves investors, stifles competition among bond funds, and otherwise is without merit,&quot; O'Neill said.</p>
<p>Mutual funds can still get market risk ratings from S&amp;P, but NASD policy bars funds from distributing the ratings in advertising and supplement sales materials.</p>
<p>S&amp;P has made repeated requests since 1994 for NASD to drop the restriction.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas ((202-898-8314))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8395416">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
