<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403550" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: NORDIC SKIING-YEGOROVA STRIPPED OF WORLD TITLE FOR DOPING.</title>
<headline>NORDIC SKIING-YEGOROVA STRIPPED OF WORLD TITLE FOR DOPING.</headline>
<dateline>TRONDHEIM, Norway 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Lyubov Yegorova was stripped of the gold medal she won in Sunday's 5-km classic women's cross-country race at the Nordic skiing world championsips after testing positive for a banned drug.</p>
<p>International Ski Federation (FIS) general secretary Gian Franco Kasper said on Wednesday that Yegorova, 30, six times an Olympic champion, was also excluded from the championships.</p>
<p>She admitted taking bromantan, a banned stimulant-cum-masking agent, and said she was the only one responsible for taking it, Kasper said.</p>
<p>The fact she admitted taking the drug did not make it necessary to wait for the result of a second test on another sample before imposing sanctions, he added.</p>
<p>The world title will be awarded to Russian Yelena Vialbe, who finished second. Italian Stefania Belmondo and Russian Olga Danilova, who were third and fourth respectively, will get the silver and bronze medals.</p>
<p>Yegorova was also disqualified from Monday's 10-km race, the second part of a pursuit event which started with the 5-km, Kasper said. The Russian was sixth in that race.</p>
<p>Bromantan was at the centre of controversy at last year's Olympic Games in Atlanta.</p>
<p>A world tribunal, the Court of Arbitration for Sport, defied the International Olympic Committee (IOC) and upheld a Russian appeal in the case of two medal winners, swimmer Andrei Korneyev and wrestler Zafar Guliyev, who had tested positive for bromantan.</p>
<p>The tribunal said in a statement there was scant scientific literature on bromantan and its properties. It gave the pair &quot;the benefit of the doubt&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TRONDHEIM, Norway"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
