<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403511" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS - U.S. oil refiners ripe for consolidation.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - U.S. oil refiners ripe for consolidation.</headline>
<byline>Oliver Ludwig</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>In the profit-starved U.S. refining industry many companies are likely to be looking for deals aimed at boosting profitability and competitiveness in an industry plagued by overcapacity, analysts said.</p>
<p>The trend is already well underway, with the largest downstream deal in U.S. history, that between Shell Oil Co, the U.S. unit of Royal Dutch/Shell Group and Texaco Inc's, expected to be signed by the end of next month.</p>
<p>But amid a flurry of deals early this year and rumors of more to come, the pace is seen quickening, analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The next 10 to 12 months are going to be interesting,&quot; said Bruce Lanni, analyst at Oppenheimer &amp; Co in New York. Statements from two mid-sized refiners, Ultramar Diamond Shamrock and Total, on Tuesday confirming that they had talked and would consider a deal is just the tip of the iceberg, industry participants said.</p>
<p>&quot;Everbody is talking to everbody in U.S. refining,&quot; a Total spokesman in Paris told Reuters Tuesday, a view echoed widely by analysts and U.S. oil industry sources.  </p>
<p>&quot;Let's face it, refining has been a terrible business in the 1990s,&quot; said James Falvey, an oil analyst with Smith Barney in Boston, noting that a return on equity for most U.S. players has routinely been less than five percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Refining margins are not as good as they used to be because manufacturing costs have increased with the advent of new (more environmentally-friendly) fuels,&quot; said Norman Sefer, an independent oil industry consultant based in Texas.</p>
<p>Excess capacity around the world is also keeping downward pressure on profits as well.  </p>
<p>&quot;The bottom line is that refining is a global business and there's a global surplus,&quot; Smith Barney's Falvey said.</p>
<p>&quot;A million barrels per day of new crude oil refining capacity came up in Asia alone in 1996,&quot; said Nizam Sharief, an oil analyst at Hornsby &amp; Co in Houston.</p>
<p>Many beleagured players in the U.S. downstream sector, particularly the mid-sized refiners, cannot wait for a shakeout and a reduction of capacity, analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Margins have been so horrible for so long...the trend for consolidation is very definitely in place,&quot; said Tom Knight, a New Jersey-based refinery executive with Fina Inc, the U.S. unit of Belgium's Petrofina SA.</p>
<p>The list of possible deals reads like a &quot;Who's Who&quot; of U.S. refining, including talk of another possible mega-merger among majors such as Mobil Corp, Chevron Corp and Exxon.</p>
<p>Among possible deals mentioned are:  </p>
<p>*  The sale of the three refineries on the U.S. Gulf Coast operated by Salomon Inc's Basis Petroleum refining unit, with San Antonio-based independent Valero Energy Corp and Venezuela's PDVSA mentioned as possible buyers.</p>
<p>*  An alliance between Amerada Hess Corp and PDVSA involving Hess's huge and sophisticated refinery on the eastern Caribbean island St Croix in the U.S. Virgin Islands.</p>
<p>*  An alliance in the mid-continent involving the region's big players Ashland Inc, USX-Marathon Group's Marathon Oil Co unit and major Amoco Inc.  </p>
<p>*  A possible alliance between U.S. majors Exxon Corp, Mobil Corp and Chevron Corp.</p>
<p>Apart from sale, merger or takeover some refiners have chosen to close plants (an expensive option because of environmental requirments) while others opt to upgrade in an effort to improve margins.  </p>
<p>BP Oil last year, for example, closed one Ohio plant and is upgrading another there, having earlier sold off its Marcus Hook, Pennsylvania to independent refiner Tosco, which has a pending deal to buy Unocal's downstream assets for $1.4 billion and is frequently mentioned as a buyer when assets are up for sale.</p>
<p>A combination of upgrading refineries to handle Venezuela's heavy crude while also selling a stake to one of state-owned PDVSA's operating units has been the favored option.  </p>
<p>Coastal and Phillips are among those upgrading plants in conjunction with a joint venture with a PDVSA unit. But with upgrading capacity in the U.S. Gulf rising, the economics of this route are not as attractive as they were, analysts said.</p>
<p>-- New York Energy Desk, 1 212 859 1633</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
