<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403518" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. futures exchanges slam Supreme Court decision.</title>
<headline>U.S. futures exchanges slam Supreme Court decision.</headline>
<byline>Stephanie Sprague</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The two largest U.S. futures exchanges criticized a U.S. Supreme Court ruling on regulation of &quot;off-exchange&quot; trading in foreign currency options Tuesday, and supported efforts in Congress to level the playing field.</p>
<p>&quot;The unfair predicament raised by today's ruling can now only be corrected in Congress,&quot; Patrick Arbor, chairman of the Chicago Board of Trade, said in a news release.</p>
<p>The high court ruled that the Commodity Futures Trading Commission does not have jurisidiction over foreign currency transactions &quot;unless they involve sales for future delivery on a board of trade.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. futures exchanges, including the CBOT, have supported the CFTC's stance that certain transactions, such as forex options, are subject to CFTC oversight.</p>
<p>U.S. exchanges argue that the over-the-counter (OTC) market has sapped business from their exchange-traded products since the OTC market is less burdened with regulatory costs and paperwork.  </p>
<p>&quot;Our message to Congress all along has been that if the OTC markets are exempt from government regulation, futures exchanges should receive the same treatment,&quot; CBOT president Thomas Donovan said in a statement.</p>
<p>Chicago Mercantile Exchange chairman Jack Sandner said the Supreme Court's decision would leave small investors vulnerable to &quot;scam artists and unregulated exchanges who prey upon the investing public.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This illustrates the urgency of a legislative solution to the Treasury amendment loophole, and should give the strongest possible impetus to the Commodity Exchange Act reform bills now in Congress,&quot; Sandner said in a statement.</p>
<p>The 1974 Treasury amendment to the Commodity Exchange Act (CEA) permits instruments like government securities, repos and &quot;transactions in foreign currencies&quot; to be traded over-the-counter without CFTC regulatory oversight.</p>
<p>Futures on those instruments are also outside the CFTC's jurisdiction unless they are traded on an exchange.</p>
<p>The International Swaps and Derivatives Association Inc, which represents 300 banks and institutions active in the OTC markets, was pleased with the U.S. Supreme Court's decision.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Supreme Court has reaffirmed that the Treasury amendment provides a clear boundary defining the limits of the CEA,&quot; Elizabeth Davy, ISDA's general counsel, said in a statement.</p>
<p>In its case against William Dunn and his firm, Delta Consultants, the CFTC argued that options on foreign currencies were subject to the agency's oversight.</p>
<p>&quot;While we are disappointed in the outcome of the case, we note that the Supreme Court's opinion was limited to the narrow issue of whether the Treasury amendment treats futures and options the same,&quot; CFTC general counsel Dan Waldman said.</p>
<p>The CFTC has argued in several previous cases that it has oversight on off-exchange futures and options when transactions occur for the small retail client, as opposed to the institutional or sophisticated investor.</p>
<p>Jurisidictions have ruled differently, creating legal uncertainty and leading several lawmakers to propose bills to clarify the Treasury amendment.  </p>
<p>&quot;The important thing is that it is not a Supreme Court decision in a vacuum,&quot; said Jack Gaine, general counsel for the Managed Futures Association, an industry trade group.</p>
<p>&quot;It is in very much in the legislative process,&quot; Gaine said. &quot;I'm certain they can work out a legislative answer that will provide appropriate public protection yet permit the institutional users of these markets to continue using them free of regulation.&quot; ((Derivatives desk 312-408-8750;E-mail</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
