<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403729" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE naphtha ends firm as Med cargoes head east.</title>
<headline>NWE naphtha ends firm as Med cargoes head east.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>NWE naphtha prices ended higher on Wednesday after signs of cargoes heading out of the Med to the east buoyed the local swaps market, traders said.</p>
<p>The NWE physical market was still sluggish with little end-user demand and few large parcels traded.</p>
<p>Smaller Russian parcels were still heard offered near $200 cif but larger pipeline spec material traded at about $207/$209 cif, a slight premium to swaps.</p>
<p>March swaps rose about $1 to $206/$207 a tonne and April gained $1.50 to $203/$204, further tightening the March/April backwardation on speculation more cargoes will head out of the Med.</p>
<p>One source said at least two cargoes of 25,000-30,000 tonnes were being sent to the Far East--in the form of a large cargo. An additional six cargoes were also rumored but not confirmed to be trying to sail east, he said.</p>
<p>He said traders were buying NWE swaps and selling the paper market in Japan on expectations of more cargoes leaving the Med.</p>
<p>A new study by Poten and Partners said naphtha prices in the United States and Europe, reversing the trend of the last two years, will head lower into the year 2000 as growing North African supply outstrips moderate demand.</p>
<p>NWE prices were expected to fall to $169 cif a tonne by the year 2000, it said.</p>
<p>- John Hanley, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8185</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
