<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403736" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Navia in Whessoe counter bid.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Navia in Whessoe counter bid.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Huddart</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two European technology firms launched a 52.6 million pound ($86 million) counter-bid for instruments and controls firm Whessoe on Wednesday, hoping to trump an agreed offer by British controls giant Siebe.</p>
<p>The partners, Norway's Seatex ASA and Swiss-based Endress+Hauser (E+H), said their cash offer of 175p per share was worth 12.9 percent more than Siebe's agreed 46 million pound, 155 pence-per-share bid that was launched two weeks ago.</p>
<p>The new bid is also worth 94.4 percent more than Whessoe shares valued the company at before Siebe's bid surfaced.</p>
<p>The pair have already bought 3.14 million Whessoe shares, or about 10.6 percent of its capital, and said they had been able to bid more than Siebe because their businesses fit better.</p>
<p>Whessoe quickly issued a statement saying its board would consider the new offer as soon as practicable and then advise its shareholders on whether or not to sell -- and to whom.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Whessoe shares surged during the trading session to close up 26-1/2p at 183-1/2p.</p>
<p>Share analysts said this price move suggested investors believed that Siebe could afford to return to do battle with the hostile raiders through a raised bid.</p>
<p>However, Siebe's only initial reaction was to say that it was considering its options.</p>
<p>The Swiss-Norwegian alliance is focused primarily on the Norwegian partner Seatex, soon to be renamed Navia, which has long had its eyes on Whessoe's Norway-based unit Autronica.</p>
<p>In 1995 it tried to buy Autronica from its parent but at that time could not contemplate bidding for all of Whessoe.</p>
<p>Navia's chief executive told Reuters that the firms had been in discussions with Whessoe about a possible bid in January and February but these talks had ended with Siebe's deal.</p>
<p>Navia controls two-thirds of the Whessoe shares the partners have now bought -- a split that reflects the planned division of Whessoe's units should the duo's bid succeed.</p>
<p>&quot;Our bid is 100 percent complementary, while Siebe would probably have to do some restucturing,&quot; Navia chief executive Hans Olav Torsen told Reuters in a London telephone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Even at this increased level, our bid is very much earnings-enhancing (for Navia),&quot; Torsen added.</p>
<p>Like Whessoe itself, Navia and E+H are both relatively small players in the specialist controls and instruments business.</p>
<p>Siebe, a broadly diversified engineer, has a global presence in several major electronic controls markets and a market capitalisation of several billion pounds.</p>
<p>Torsen argued that Siebe would have areas of overlap with Whessoe units but the Swiss-Norwegian partners would not.</p>
<p>&quot;Autronica fits perfectly with our main operations in Norway as well as expanding our marine and offshore technology business worldwide,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>His Swiss counterpart, Klaus Riemenschneider, said the Whessoe units E+H is keen to acquire would be a platform for new growth.</p>
<p>For privately-owned E+H, Whessoe offers an opportunity to expand in the U.S market, especially in the tank and liquid level measurement sector, where Whessoe would give it new reach.</p>
<p>The Navia chief said that a completed deal would effectively double his group's annual turnover to about 1.0 billion Norwegian crowns ($150 million).</p>
<p>The cash and debt-funded offer, at the current offer price, would lead to a fall in Navia's equity ratio to between 25 and 30 percent from its current 60 percent level, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We can still live with that... I think Autronica is a fairly mature business,&quot; Torsen said. ($1=.6109 Pound) ($1=6.660 Norwegian Crown)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32040">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
