<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403725" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med/West African crude markets look sour.</title>
<headline>Med/West African crude markets look sour.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crude oil in the Mediterranean and West African markets continued oversupplied and under downward pressure, traders said.</p>
<p>Although few Urals cargoes were seen offered, a deal on Tuesday heard below dated Brent -$1.10 a barrel reflected the oversupply.</p>
<p>&quot;And we should see a few small cargoes emerging before the end of the month,&quot; one refiner said.</p>
<p>One Kirkuk contract holder said the Iraqis were still offering spot barrels but buying interest was subdued.</p>
<p>&quot;They are offering barrels on the spot market for markets other than the Med,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Negotiations continued between Syrian state oil company Sytrol and term contract holders. Prices were wide apart with Sytrol around dated Brent -40/45 cents and some buyers holding off around dated Brent -80 cents.</p>
<p>With such a large discrepancy in price ideas some customers expected the first March barrels to be lifted on the basis of an official selling price to be agreed later.</p>
<p>&quot;Then maybe lifters for the second half of the month can threaten not to take their second half (of the month) barrels,&quot; one regular customer said.</p>
<p>West African grades were all plentiful and with little buying interest emerging from the U.S. to support prices, most traders expected differentials to fall further.</p>
<p>The next Forcados cargo offered was to load March 9-11 and thought destined for the U.S. This was followed by an unsold March 12-14 loader, a 14-15 and a 16-17 loader. In total at least eight cargoes remained unsold in March. By the 26th of January all February barrels had been sold, traders said.</p>
<p>Forcados was assessed around dated Brent +45 cents though traders said they would not be surprised if the next deal was actually lower.</p>
<p>&quot;This market is a dog,&quot; one seller said.</p>
<p>Although some Nigerian equity holders were looking at contingency plans should the threatened DPR oil workers strike go ahead on Friday, most felt the Nigerian government would ensure any disruptions were minimal.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't see them allowing major disruptions to occur with their main revenue earner (crude),&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Another added that nobody expected loadings to be disrupted and did not see a problem in bills of lading being signed but that further paperwork might take longer to come through.</p>
<p>&quot;So you might get the documents 40 days after loading rather than 30 days,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Siobhan Hayden London Newsroom +44 171 542 8978</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
