<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403748" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British transsexual challenges sex-change refusal.</title>
<headline>British transsexual challenges sex-change refusal.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A 51-year-old transsexual father of two won the right on Wednesday to a court hearing to try to force British health officials to pay for a sex-change operation.</p>
<p>&quot;I am desperate to obtain the surgery required to give me a normal life,&quot; the transsexual, identified only as &quot;K &quot;, said in a written statement to the High Court.</p>
<p>The judicial review may be a major test case over the right of transsexuals to have sex change surgery at the cost of Britain's comprehensive state health service.</p>
<p>&quot;K&quot; will claim the refusal of the government-funded Shropshire Health Authority in western England to pay for his sex-change operation was unlawful .</p>
<p>After the hearing , his lawyer, Madeline Rees, said the case could have major implications for other health authorities facing similar requests.</p>
<p>&quot;K &quot;has undergone hormone therapy for nine years and doctors have given medical clearance for the operation.</p>
<p>In two similar recent cases in Britain, transsexuals have received the operation after medical officials changed their minds in the face of court challenges.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
