<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403751" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Adams calls on Dublin to monitor N.Irish parades.</title>
<headline>Adams calls on Dublin to monitor N.Irish parades.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sinn Fein leader Gerry Adams urged Dublin on Wednesday to send observers to British Northern Ireland during volatile Protestant marches in a bid to ease anxiety among minority Catholics.</p>
<p>Adams, whose party is the political arm of banned Irish Republican Army (IRA) guerrillas, condemned the province's chief pro-British Protestant leader, David Trimble, for saying Protestants should be allowed to parade past Catholic homes next July.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very important that beleagured communities have some sense that ...there is someone trying to assist them during these difficult time,&quot; Adams said after talks with Catholics in a south Belfast zone that is a sectarian flashpoint during annual summer parades by Protestants.</p>
<p>Adams said Ireland, to whom the province's Catholics owe allegiance, should &quot;agree to send monitors during marches who will scrutinise developments...and provide some assurance for local communities that their fears and concerns are being acknowledged.&quot;</p>
<p>His remarks came 24 hours after Britain said parade organisers must give police three weeks' notice of intended parades instead of the current one week.</p>
<p>It also said police would be empowered to confiscate alcohol, often blamed as a key factor in confrontations.</p>
<p>Last weekend Trimble, leader of the Ulster Unionist Party, said members of the Protestant Orange Order, of which he is a member, should be allowed to hold a march through a Catholic district of Portadown, southwest of Belfast, at the height of the Order's &quot;marching season&quot;.</p>
<p>Adams branded Trimble's remarks to an American magazine as &quot;totally unacceptable&quot;.</p>
<p>A similar march at Portadown last year lit a fuse for the province's worst sectarian disturbances for many years.</p>
<p>Protestants, backed by streets protests and road blocks, had a furious three-day standoff with riot police until senior officers reversed a decision and allowed them to parade through the district.</p>
<p>Gangs of Catholic youths hurled hundreds of petrol bombs at police in Londonderry and other areas. Two people died and many were injured.</p>
<p>Politicians across the province, already pessimistic because of a fresh eruption of IRA violence, fear a repetition of marching season disturbances that would deal another blow to the region's crippled peace drive.</p>
<p>The IRA, drawing support among some Catholics, is fighting to end British rule of Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>Protestants regard their annual marches as a cornerstone of a public reaffirmation of loyalty to their religion and to the British Crown. They say Catholics want to deny them their right to be British.</p>
<p>Catholics regard the often boisterous Protestant marches as displays of triumphalism, commemorating ancient victories over the native Irish.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
