<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403779" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FORECAST - BoE independence seen in 1st Labour term.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - BoE independence seen in 1st Labour term.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Steele</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of England could have a bigger say under a Labour government than it currently gets under the Conservative party and full independence beckons, a Reuters survey of economists showed.</p>
<p>Of 22 experts polled in London on Wednesday, 13 said they believed Labour, hotly tipped to win an imminent election, would give the central bank more influence.</p>
<p>Eight economists said they believed Labour would keep the status quo and only one said the Bank would have less say in setting the monetary agenda.</p>
<p>&quot;The current relationship between the Treasury and the bank is relatively successful, but Labour is making clear the bank will get more say,&quot; said Ciaran Barr, UK economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>To qualify for European economic and monetary union (EMU), which is set for launch in January 1999, central banks in potential member countries must have been granted independence from government.</p>
<p>In Britain the Bank of England governor currently makes recommendations on monetary policy to the Chancellor of the Exchequer, who can choose to ignore that advice.</p>
<p>For example, Bank Governor Eddie George has in recent months counselled a small rise in interest rates, advice which has been rejected by Chancellor Kenneth Clarke.</p>
<p>The vast majority of economists polled in the survey said the current means of liaising between central bank and Treasury was either successful or at least neutral, with only three saying it was ineffective.</p>
<p>Mainstay of the relationship is a monthly meeting between George and Clarke, often dubbed the &quot;Ken and Eddie show&quot;, at which the bank's advice is conveyed to government.</p>
<p>But the need to grant independence as a prerequisite for EMU entry would be a central part of Labour's plans for the bank, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Labour party is committed to holding a referendum on EMU entry and finance spokesman Gordon Brown has pledged to test the effects of EMU on Britain's jobs, financial services industry and investment climate before committing to entry.</p>
<p>Sixteen of the economists in Wednesday's survey said they expected a Labour government, in preparation for EMU, would make the bank independent some time in their first term of office, which could run a maximum of five years. Two of the 16 said they though a Labour government would act on independence immediately</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
