<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="403915" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Poland - Feb 26.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Poland - Feb 26.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>The Gdansk shipyard receiver has approached Bank Pekao SA bank for $100 million in credit to finance construction of five ships contracted by Germany's Scholler Holdings, a source who declined to be named said.</p>
<p>Pekao is not conducting any formal negotiations about financing the yard's output, the bank's spokeswoman Beata Wojcik said.</p>
<p>- Credit card issuers produced 500,000 cards in 1996, which showed growth by 420,000 cards compared with the year before, the PolCard credit card firm said.</p>
<p>- State-owned PKO BP bank reported the biggest return on capital in 1996 of all banks operating in Poland, France's Societe Generale branch had the biggest fund accrual, while BNP-Dresdner Bank reported the biggest asset growth, a survey by the Gazeta Bankowa banking weekly said.</p>
<p>- Public sector employees, whose pay grew by less than 25.3 percent in 1996 compared with the year before, will receive a one-off bonus of 97.8 zlotys, the government said.</p>
<p>- Krzysztof Markowski, bank PKO BP's financial policy director, has been appointed the bank's deputy director.</p>
<p>- A banking consortium led by Bank Gdanski has signed a $44.9 million credit agreement with the Szczecin shipyard to finance construction of two vessels, the bank said.</p>
<p>- The total value of leasing services provided by Poland's leasing firms in 1996 was 2.48 billion zlotys, KPL leasing firm association president Wojciech Kolanczyk said.</p>
<p>- The listed Echo Investment firm is planning to build 100 two-star and three-star hotels worth $350 million in cooperation with France's Sphere International and Holland's Copron BV firms, Echo said.</p>
<p>Hotel industry experts find the project unrealistic.</p>
<p>NOWA EUROPA</p>
<p>- The listed Budimex and its Budimex Trading subsidiary will merge, the firm's shareholders decided. As the result, Budimex's own funds will increase by 10 million zlotys, Budimex president Grzegorz Tuderek said.</p>
<p>- Poland's National Investment Fund (NFI) No.12 is the most interesting element of the NFI programme and in up to four years time it may become a model investment fund, Wood &amp; Company analyst Don Murray said.</p>
<p>- Around 17 percent of Poles are satisfied with the country's economic condition and 39 percent expect it to improve this year, while 34 percent are critical and 22 percent think the economy will deteriorate, a survey by the Pentor polling institute said .</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>- Warsaw municipal authorities will sell six Warsaw-based hotels controlled by the Syrena group to Austria's Bau Holding AG for $24 million, Warsaw president Marcin Swiecicki said.</p>
<p>- If organised crime will launder money in Poland, parliamentarians should be blamed as no appropriate legislative steps have been taken, central bank president Hanna Gronkiewicz-Waltz said.</p>
<p>ZYCIE</p>
<p>- Around 30 percent of mineral water sold in Poland is bottled tap water, PZH state hygiene controlling body expert Teresa Latour said.</p>
<p>PARKIET</p>
<p>- The U.S.'s J.P. Morgan investment bank will coordinate the second Eurobond issue by the state-owned Bank Handlowy bank this year.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
