<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40399" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-SHOCKED WILKINSON SACKED BY LEEDS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SHOCKED WILKINSON SACKED BY LEEDS.</headline>
<dateline>LEEDS, England 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leeds United sacked their manager Howard Wilkinson on Monday two days after the club lost 4-0 at home to champions and big rivals Manchester United.</p>
<p>The announcement was made at a hastily-called news conference.</p>
<p>Wilkinson told reporters: &quot;I am very disappointed and obviously very shocked. My immediate reaction is that I have left a club which has made excellent progress over recent years.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope the measure they have taken will allow the club's fine reputation to continue.</p>
<p>&quot;I have been sacked for reasons which they see as essential. That is their right, hopefully the future will prove them right,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see how Saturday's result had anything to do with what happened today.&quot;</p>
<p>Wilkinson said: &quot;I am sure this has been a difficult decision for Bill Fotherby (club chairman) and he has had to make it for the best reasons. A small section of the supporters have voiced their views on this and now matters have come to a close.&quot;</p>
<p>Fotherby said: &quot;I decided after Saturday's game with Manchester United that a change of direction had to be made at management level.</p>
<p>&quot;We all appreciate the single-minded effort and outstanding leadership Howard has given us since 1988 and hope his critics will now recognise the job he's done in establishing them as a top premier league club.&quot;</p>
<p>Youth coach Paul Hart is taking over as caretaker manager until a successor is found. Kenny Dalglish and George Graham are names that have been mentioned in the past. </p>
<p>Wilkinson, 52, arrived at Leeds almost eight years ago from Sheffield Wednesday and took the club out of the second division and on to the league title in 1992 with Eric Cantona in the team.</p>
<p>But his position has been under pressure since late last season and he came under fire again from sections of the crowd during his side's thrashing by Manchester United on Saturday.</p>
<p>Wilkinson said: &quot;Of late, a small section of our supporters have focused their disapproval, disappointment and dismay on me and I think that started to have an effect on the players.&quot;</p>
<p>However, he has been unable to repeat the success demanded by supporters and the club finished 13th last season. They are currently ninth with seven points from a possible 15.</p>
<p>Wilkinson is the latest big-name managerial casualty with the season less than a month old. Others to fall include Arsenal's Bruce Rioch, Ray Wilkins of Queen's Park Rangers and Manchester City's Alan Ball.</p>
<p>Wilkinson said: &quot;When I came here I talked about a 10-year plan and, looking at the young players we've got here, I could see that coming to fruition.</p>
<p>&quot;We are an established force with a terrific stadium and in the next 12 months to two years people will see the benefits of the youth policy we have established.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LEEDS, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
