<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40394" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: CYCLING - JALABERT TAKES TOUR LEAD WITH THIRD STAGE WIN.</title>
<headline>CYCLING - JALABERT TAKES TOUR LEAD WITH THIRD STAGE WIN.</headline>
<dateline>ALBACETE, Spain 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Frenchman Laurent Jalabert took a big step towards his second consecutive Tour of Spain title by claiming the leader's yellow jersey after winning the third stage on Monday.</p>
<p>Jalabert gained over seven minutes on three-times winner Tony Rominger and Spanish hopeful Fernando Escartin as his ONCE team led a group of thirty riders who broke away from the pack early in the wind-affected 184 km stage across the Castilian plains from Cuenca.</p>
<p>Among those left behind was former race leader Biagio Conte.</p>
<p>Of the pre-race favourites only ONCE team mate Alex Zulle and local hero Miguel Indurain, helped by three other Banesto riders, could keep up the pace.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we surprised everybody by moving early, but rounding it off by winning the sprint was fantastic,&quot; said Jalabert, who had been fifth overall after being pipped at the post in Sunday's sprint.</p>
<p>The Frenchman was not to be outdone this time and timed his move perfectly to catch Italian sprinter Fabio Baldato just 10 metres from the line.</p>
<p>A ceremony was held ahead of the stage to open a sports complex in Cuenca bearing the name of the late Spanish rider Luis Ocana, winner of the 1973 Tour de France.</p>
<p>With part of the Mediterranean coast bracing itself for the arrival of late summer storms, wind and possibly rain could again play a part as the Tour continues on Tuesday with another largely flat stage over 160 km from Albacete to Murcia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALBACETE, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
