<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="404245" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Reid expects yr profit to match 1995/96.</title>
<headline>Reid expects yr profit to match 1995/96.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Farm services company Reid Farmers said on Thursday that while the indications were the second six months &quot;may not be as buoyant as previous years&quot;, it expected the group's full year result to be similar to the NZ$3.3 million profit achieved last year.</p>
<p>Earlier, Reid reported a first half profit of NZ$1.13 million against $1.01 million in the corresponding period last year.  </p>
<p>Reid said while the outlook for farming had not been as bright as hoped, the lift in prime lamb prices had given encouragement to farmers.</p>
<p>Reid recently announced an offer for the stock and station business of Southland Farmers Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe this acquisition, if successful, will strengthen our company and make available more avenues for Reid Farmers to expand,&quot; Reid said, adding it would also enable some savings where both companies operate and compete in the same area.  </p>
<p>&quot;The present indications are that the second six months may not be as buoyant as previous years. Putting aside any impact that the proposed acquisition of Southland Farmers might have, we expect the group's full year result to be similar to that achieved last year,&quot; Reid said.</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
