<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="404239" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Mayne says Optus stake sale crucial.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Mayne says Optus stake sale crucial.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Transport, security and health care group Mayne Nickless said on Thursday that failure to sell its 25 percent stake in Optus Communications by July would impair growth opportunities.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the float option is realistic in the short term unless we want to do it while litigation is occurring, Mayne Managing Director Bob Dalziel told reporters.</p>
<p>He said the short term meant by June or July &quot;because our goal is to exit our optus investment by June, July&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot let our failure to get out of Optus to impair our growth opportunities and it will if it goes past July.&quot;  </p>
<p>Mayne has told credit rating agencies Standard and Poor's Corp and Moody's Investors Service that it would exit its stake by July.</p>
<p>Mayne said earlier in a statement accompanying its half year results that it was considering four other options to achieve a sale of its shareholding in Optus.</p>
<p>Mayne has said it wants to sell its stake in order to focus on its core businesses.</p>
<p>Optus Communications had planned to float in 1996, but the process has been held up by a dispute between shareholder in its associate, Optus Vision, and the Seven Network.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
