<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="404337" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China markets expect bank ratio cut shortly.</title>
<headline>China markets expect bank ratio cut shortly.</headline>
<byline>Graham Earnshaw</byline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's financial markets expect the central People's Bank of China to cut bank reserve ratios soon as promised by Beijing as early as last July, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The cut, which would be the first since 1988, is expected to dramatically increase the amount of money pouring into the stock and state debt markets, but could depress interest rates on the interbank market, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;They will definitely do it, and my guess is that it will come in the second quarter,&quot; said a foreign banker based in Shanghai.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank wants the banks to use the extra money to help the state-owned enterprises, but one way or another the money is going to find its way into the stock market. The banks want to make a profit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Banks and other financial institutions currently have to put 13 percent of their deposits in the central bank as state reserves and to keep another five to seven percent as their own reserves.</p>
<p>Analysts estimated the amount of cash freed up by a reserve ratio cut could come to tens of billions of yuan, or billions of dollars.</p>
<p>The foreign banker said that reducing the ratios could be part of a central strategy to ensure that the markets are on a healthy track as Hong Kong returns to China on July 1 after more than 150 years of British colonial rule.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we can bet on the authorities not being too heavy-handed (on restrictions for use of the funds) during that period,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A trader on the Shanghai-based Chinese yuan interbank market said the markets were eagerly awaiting an announcement on the reserve ratios.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the cut to come in the first quarter of this year,&quot; he said. &quot;It has already been delayed several times.&quot;</p>
<p>A Beijing-based banker with a major Chinese commercial bank said: &quot;The signs are there that the central bank will make the cut a part of a package of financial reforms.&quot;</p>
<p>He said it was likely the central bank would start using the reserve ratio as a means of fine-tuning the money supply.</p>
<p>Traders said they would welcome the move as a step towards making China's financial management more market-driven, compared to the heavy-handed use of administrative edicts as in the past.</p>
<p>The central bank currently controls money supply largely by setting loan quotas for the big four state commercial banks, but it was finding this method less and less effective, they said.</p>
<p>The big four state banks -- the Construction Bank, the Agricultural Bank, the Bank of China, and the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China -- now account for 75 percent of money supply in China, compared to more than 90 percent in the 1980s.</p>
<p>&quot;By manipulating bank reserve ratios, the central bank will be able to more effectively control money outside the hands of the big four,&quot; said a Shanghai-based banker.</p>
<p>Traders said they believed annual rates for contracts on the yuan interbank market could drop by an average one percentage point when the reserve ratio cut is eventually announced.</p>
<p>($1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
