<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="404364" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Morocco group says human rights retreated in 1996.</title>
<headline>Morocco group says human rights retreated in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>RABAT 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Moroccan human rights group said on Wednesday the country's record had worsened in 1996 with nine deaths in police headquarters and no progress on the issue of people who it said had disappeared.</p>
<p>&quot;We had noted a partial progress in the early 1990s after the liberation of most political prisoners but last year there was a fresh outbreak of deaths in custody and forced disappearances,&quot; the president of the independent Moroccan Association of Human Rights told a news conference at the release of the group's annual report for 1996.</p>
<p>Abderrahman Benameur said the fate of 90 people who had disappeared since the 1960s was still unknown and compensation for those who had been imprisoned in secret detention centres had not be given except for military officers once held at Tazmamart prison.</p>
<p>Tazmamart was a secret prison in the Atlas mountains renowned for harsh detention conditions.</p>
<p>No immediate comment was available from Morocco's Ministry of Human Rights.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot be satisfied with small or relative progress, as long as there are violations, we will be dissatisfied,&quot; Benameur added.</p>
<p>The report also deplored lack of freedom of expression, such as the ban on performances by satirist Ahmed Sanoussi and bans on newspapers and rallies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RABAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
