<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="404330" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: INTERVIEW-Fore Systems sees strong growth.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Fore Systems sees strong growth.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Wong</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. computer network communications company Fore Systems expects to post strong profits this financial year and next, chief operating officer Tom Gill said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Gill told Reuters in an interview that this growth would be aided by recent acquisitions and the launch of broader network services to clients.</p>
<p>&quot;This fiscal year, our rough consensus is for revenue to be about (US) $415 million,&quot; Gill said.  </p>
<p>The company's revenue for the third quarter of fiscal 1997 totalled US$112.66 million, an increase of 76 percent against a year ago.</p>
<p>Gill said earnings were above the anticipated target of US$108-109 million forecast for that quarter.</p>
<p>He said Fore Systems aimed to boost its networking potential via service provider operations currently under development, which would link the local area network (LAN) to the broader wide area network (WAN).</p>
<p>This would serve the needs of high-end corporate clients, such as telecommunications and information companies.  </p>
<p>He noted that analysts had already published these estimates for the company's financial year ending in March 1997.</p>
<p>Fore Systems is a specialist provider of sophisticated networking computer products based on asynchronous transfer mode (ATM) technology.</p>
<p>ATM technology allows networks to deliver simultaneously voice, video and data through fibre optic cables or wire.</p>
<p>Gill said analysts' forecasts for 1998 placed revenues at about US$620 million, nearly a 50 percent increase year-on-year.</p>
<p>&quot;This is based on some of the acquisitions we've made, services which latch onto the ATM network,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Growth in service provider networks would also be propelled by the current burst of internet activity at the low-end.</p>
<p>&quot;The key application is to have a service provider that will provide ATM connection to the home,&quot; vice-president of Asia Pacific operations Stephen Young said.</p>
<p>With the exception of Japan and the U.S., Young noted service providers were not extensively available at the home level.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the bandwidth requirements have exploded, ATM is very suitable technology to relieve congestion in that area. That's what it was designed for,&quot; Young said.  </p>
<p>About 18 to 25 percent of Fore's revenues come from Asia.</p>
<p>--  Singapore newsroom (65 8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
