<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="404357" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Strong trade in paint stock but Egypt shares slip.</title>
<headline>Strong trade in paint stock but Egypt shares slip.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Active trade in PACHIN/Paints and Chemical Industries kept the share on top of the Egyptian stock market for the second day on Wednesday but the overall index slipped again amid profit taking.</p>
<p>The all-share index fell 9.3 points to 414.75 in a high volume of 94.62 million pounds ($27.87 million), the Capital Market Authority (CMA) said in its daily report.</p>
<p>The index had in previous weeks hit record levels, climaxing at 427.77 points on Monday but brokers said it was slipping due to profit taking and as a result of a &quot;natural correction&quot;.</p>
<p>PACHIN was the day's most active stock, trading in more than 18.25 million pounds but the share slipped 0.1 pounds to close at 156.9, the CMAsaid.</p>
<p>Public Enterprise Minister Atef Obeid had said that the state would offer another share tranche to anchor investors.</p>
<p>Commercial International Bank (CIB) was the second most actively traded stock, with more than 8 million pounds changing hands but it closed 48.5 pounds lower at 921.5.</p>
<p>Misr International Bank/MIBANK traded in more than 5.47 million pounds but it too closed down at 885 after slipping 42 pounds.</p>
<p>Cairo Precision Industries, one of the first Egyptian so-called &quot;closed&quot; companies to open up to the public through a share issue on the stock exchange, closed 6.7 pounds higher at 140.76 after trading in more than 7.20 million pounds.</p>
<p>Cairo Precision is a subsidiary of the family-owned Olympic Electric Group. The parent company said on Sunday that each applicant for shares in Cairo Precision would get 8.8 percent of the requested shares after its share offer was 11.4 times oversubscribed.</p>
<p>The index for openly traded firms fell to 712.11 points from 738.19 points on Tuesday and the index for rarely traded &quot;closed&quot; firms also fell, closing at 267.83 from 271.11.</p>
<p>Out of the 89 shares traded, 22 gained, 47 lost and 20 ended the day unchanged.</p>
<p>$1 = 3.395 pounds</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +20 2 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
