<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="404408" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Star Wars boosts prices of artifacts from Long Time Ago.</title>
<headline>Star Wars boosts prices of artifacts from Long Time Ago.</headline>
<byline>Richard Chang</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Star Wars&quot; is back in Force, and so is the merchandise.</p>
<p>As toys, ties, trading cards, T-shirts, bedspreads, costumes and other collectibles swarm the Galaxy, fans of the science fiction trilogy have embarked on a seach for rare artifacts from A Long Time Ago -- and are willing to lay down big bucks for them.</p>
<p>&quot;It's because of childhood memories. It's the stuff you grew up with. You want to remember the simpler things in life,&quot; said Brian Rachfal, a dealer and collector in San Jose, Calif. &quot;The movies are at theatres now. There are new toys now. It's the same thing all over again. You get excited.&quot;</p>
<p>The excitement is so intense that &quot;Star Wars&quot; merchandise is popping up on home shopping channels and in retailing catalogues. The Sharper Image has devoted 10 pages of its March catalogue to &quot;Star Wars&quot; memorabilia.</p>
<p>The official Star Wars Fan Club sells a life-sized Stormtrooper for $4,995, a fiberglass Darth Vader mask for $1,100, a Boba Fett helmet for $995 and a Skywalker Lightsaber weapon for $349.95.</p>
<p>All are replicas, of course, and are available by calling &quot;Star Wars Insider&quot; magazine at 1-800-878-3326. Customers in Canada and other countries can call 1-303-574-0907.</p>
<p>Fans with smaller budgets can get a key chain for $10, a 20th anniversary mug for $18.50, a calendar for $11.99, a datebook for $13.95 and posters for as little as $8.</p>
<p>Original props from the trilogy would cost a treasure, but these are guarded jealously by director George Lucas in his Lucasfilm archives. Even toys and posters sold at the time of the movies' original release are as elusive as the true identity of Darth Vader, making them extremely valuable.</p>
<p>Sotheby's will auction two &quot;Star Wars&quot; posters by 20th Century-Fox on March 1 for an estimated price of $1,000 to $1,500 each. Collectors say that's a bargain.</p>
<p>One, printed on silver mylar, from 1976 announces &quot;Coming to your Galaxy This Summer&quot; and the other celebrates the first anniversary of &quot;Star Wars&quot; with a birthday cake surrounded by figures of its main characters.</p>
<p>&quot;I've never seen a mylar,&quot; said Rachfal, who has dealt in &quot;Star Wars&quot; memorabilia for about eight years. &quot;They're both undervalued, but the mylar excessively so.&quot;</p>
<p>After all, a framed 10 inch by 8 inch colour photograph of the cast from &quot;Star Wars,&quot; autographed by Carrie Fisher, Harrison Ford, Mark Hamill and Chewbacca, was also expected to fetch $1,000 to $1,200 at Christie's Los Angeles in December 1996. It sold for $2,990.</p>
<p>Even more desirable are small 3-3/4 inch figures by Kenner, packed in a see-through plastic bubble with a cardboard backing. The toys cost $1.99 then.</p>
<p>Not now. A rocket-firing Boba Fett figure that was not released because of safety concerns fetched $2,000 in 1995, and should be worth more than $5,000 now, said Rachfal. Only 30 were made, he said, and the final version of the toy had its firing mechanism plugged.</p>
<p>In 1978 Kenner made Jawa trader figures with a vinyl cape, but replaced the cape with a knitted hood for a classier look before selling them in stores. The rare caped Jawas cost $45 in the early 1980s and went up to $1,400 at a recent auction, said Steve Sansweet, a collector for 20 years.</p>
<p>&quot;To find one in the bubble has become the Holy Grail for many people,&quot; said Sansweet, who quit his job last year as a Wall Street Journal reporter after 27 years to become a marketing director for Lucasfilm.</p>
<p>Expect to pay $1,200 for figures of Snaggletooth, Yak Face and Anakin Skywalker (before he gave in to the dark Force and became Darth Vader) in their original packaging and if the plastic bubble is clear.</p>
<p>Add $200 if the toy has never been hooked on store hangers. Evidence -- the cardboard backing still has the little piece of paper where the hole is punched. If the bubble is yellowed, the price tag is $700 to $800, Rachfal said.</p>
<p>&quot;People want perfect material. They want to improve their collections. The challenge is to find one unpunched. A couple years ago it didn't matter,&quot; Rachfal said.</p>
<p>As George Lucas produces the first three &quot;prequels&quot; to &quot;Star Wars&quot; -- which was part four in the nine-part series conceived by the director -- the value of the collectibles should appreciate even further.</p>
<p>But don't jump to conclusions.</p>
<p>&quot;There were literally millions of Star Wars action figures made from 1978 to 1985. The average figure with no packaging is worth only $5, although certain ones are worth a lot more. There are about 100 figures and only a handful are rare,&quot; said Jon Snyder, editor in chief of &quot;Star Wars Insider&quot; magazine.</p>
<p>For a better understanding of the Force, read &quot;Star Wars: From Concept to Screen to Collectible&quot; by Steve Sansweet, published by Chronicle Books. &quot;Tomart's Price Guide to Worldwide Star Wars Collectibles&quot; by Tomart Publications is being updated and will be in stores in April.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>For comments on the Assets column, you may write to Richard Chang at Reuters, 199 Water Street, New York, N.Y. 10038 or send e-mail to richard.chang(at)reuters.com.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
