<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="404542" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Reno, Republicans to cooperate on crime bill.</title>
<headline>Reno, Republicans to cooperate on crime bill.</headline>
<byline>Robert Green</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Attorney General Janet Reno and Republicans who control Congress promised Wednesday to work together on programmes to fight juvenile crime.</p>
<p>&quot;Working together in a bipartisan way I believe we can fashion a bill that truly makes a difference for the youth of America,&quot; Reno said at a House hearing on legislation proposed last week by President Clinton.</p>
<p>House Crime Subcommittee Chairman Bill McCollum, a Florida Republican, said he agreed with Clinton's comments last week in Boston that the country must act quickly to curb juvenile crime before tens of millions of American children just starting school became teenagers.</p>
<p>&quot;The president is absolutely right about this coming storm of juvenile crime. All levels of government must act now before it is too late,&quot; McCollum said. &quot;I look forward to working with...the administration in crafting a juvenile crime bill which will meet this challenge.&quot;</p>
<p>California Republican Frank Riggs, chairman of the House subcommittee on early childhood, youth and families, called Clinton's bill &quot;a solid proposal&quot; and pledged bipartisan support for the measure.</p>
<p>House and Senate Republicans have their own juvenile crime bills which will be considered with Clinton's plan.</p>
<p>McCollum said one problem with the juvenile justice system was that only about 10 percent of violent offenders got any type of punishment.</p>
<p>&quot;There simply must be a sanction for every crime,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Reno agreed, saying, &quot;There should be a fair, firm sanction that fits the crime.&quot;</p>
<p>She said the administration bill would increase federal penalties for violent gang activity and gave federal prosecutors more authority to prosecute juveniles as adults.</p>
<p>But Reno said the bill also stressed crime prevention with funds for anti-truancy and after-school programmes.</p>
<p>New York Democrat Charles Schumer said a key to curbing juvenile crime was stronger gun control laws that would keep teenagers from getting guns.</p>
<p>Michigan Democrat John Conyers said he had concerns about the legislation, especially the provisions that call for prosecuting older juveniles as adults for violent crimes.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's be careful about mixing kids with adults in prison,&quot; Conyers said. He said teenagers imprisoned with adults were more likely to commit more crimes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
