<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40452" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: SOCCER-TINA TURNER FANS LEAVE AJAX PITCH WORSE FOR WEAR.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-TINA TURNER FANS LEAVE AJAX PITCH WORSE FOR WEAR.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of Tina Turner fans danced through the first live pop concert at Ajax Amsterdam's Arena soccer ground, giving Ajax a Monday morning hangover -- big bald patches on the pitch.</p>
<p>Ajax moved to the new 51,000-seater arena with its retractable roof during August but have struggled to find the form that saw them crowned league champions for the third year in succession last season.</p>
<p>The ANP news agency on Monday reported crowds of joyous Turner fans sang and danced their way through her two-hour concert on Saturday, leaving the pitch without grass by the corner flags and with big areas patched up with sand.</p>
<p>Barely a month into the season and with only four soccer games played at the Arena, the pitch has only a couple of weeks to recover before the pop fans return with Michael Jackson scheduled for two concerts at the end of September.</p>
<p>Quite apart from Ajax's alarming loss of form, the Amsterdam club has been bedevilled by problems with the playing surface which, despite its computer-controlled heating and air-flow management, has been criticised for looking patchy and for altering the natural bounce of the ball.</p>
<p>Ajax are currently a modest ninth in the first division.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
