<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="404593" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton funds case has long cast of characters.</title>
<headline>Clinton funds case has long cast of characters.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are some of the key figures named in the campaign fund-raising controversy involving President Bill Clinton's Democratic Party.</p>
<p>John Huang - Naturalised American of Chinese descent. Former top Democratic fundraiser who raised several million dollars from Asian-American groups, much of it returned after controversy broke. Joined Democratic National Committee, party leadership group, after stint as Commerce Department official. Before joining Commerce in 1994, was top U.S. executive of the Lippo Group, Indonesia-based financial conglomerate.</p>
<p>Mochtar Riady and James Riady - Father and son, and high executives of Lippo. James visited White House and had a controlling stake in bank in Little Rock, Arkansas, Clinton's former base. Riady family and business in U.S. gave $225,000 to the Democrats in 1992.</p>
<p>Soraya and Arief Wiriadinata - Indonesia couple living modestly in Virginia suburb of Washington. He is a gardener and she the daughter of Hasjim Ning, big investor in Lippo Group. They donated $450,00 to Democratic Party at suggestion of Democratic fundraiser John Huang. Money was returned.</p>
<p>Hsing Yun - Taiwanese who heads a monastic order and temples including Hsi Lai Buddhist temple near Los Angeles visited by Vice President President Al Gore last April when $140,000 was collected for Democrats. Money returned as improperly raised. Gore later said he did not know money was being raised and called it mistake for him to have been there.</p>
<p>Webster Hubbell - One-time law partner of Hillary Clinton and associate U.S. attorney general before quitting in 1994. Pleaded guilty to defrauding their former law firm in Little Rock. Recently completed 15-month prison term. Investigators want to know if his hiring as consultant with Lippo and others before his plea were meant to encourage him to keep quiet about Whitewater land-deal investigation involving Clintons.</p>
<p>Charles Yah Lin Trie - One-time restaurant owner in Little Rock who became international consultant and delivered $640,000 to legal defence fund set up to help the Clintons pay legal bills. Money was returned after sources of the funds could not be determined.</p>
<p>Wang Jun - A weapons dealer in China brought by Trie to a White House reception in February 1996. Clinton later said it was inappropriate for Wang to be there. His company implicated in alleged scheme to smuggle guns into United States.</p>
<p>Pauline Kanchanalak - Thai international consultant living in U.S. who gave $253,000 to Democrats. Money returned.</p>
<p>Yogesh Gandhi - California businessman who said he was relative of late Indian leader Mohandas Gandhi. His $325,000 to Democrats returned after source of money questioned.</p>
<p>John H.K. Lee - Chairman of South Korean outdoor electronic display company. His U.S. subsidiary made a $250,000 donation to Democrats apparently solicited by Huang. Money returned along with $10,000 given by Lee.</p>
<p>Johnny Chung - Taiwanese-American entrepreneur living in Torrance, California. Visited White House 49 times. His company gave $366,000 to Democrats since 1994. A National Security Council memo had called him &quot;a hustler&quot; out to impress Chinese business friends with his White House ties.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
