<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="404698" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: EVC tumbles to loss, sees PVC upturn.</title>
<headline>EVC tumbles to loss, sees PVC upturn.</headline>
<byline>Lien van der Leij</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's biggest PVC producer, EVC, on Wednesday said results tumbled to a net loss of 25 million guilders ($13.3 million) in 1996 but should improve on the back of a general industry upturn over the current year.</p>
<p>EVC -- minority-owned by Britain's ICI  and Italy's Enichem -- said slumping PVC prices and record low margins, plus a stronger lira and pound, had slashed results.</p>
<p>The 1996 loss compared with a 1995 profit of 163.9 million guilders. Turnover fell 18 percent to 2.09 billion guilders.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year was one of the worst for the west European industry as a whole,&quot; EVC's finance director, Nigel Taylor, told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;However, at the operating level we managed to stay in profit, which represents a far better performance than before, (during the last industry downturn),&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Operating profit dropped to just one million guilders from 176.5 million in 1995.</p>
<p>One-off charges of 24.9 million guilders resulting from group reorganisation, restructuring at its rigid films business and a loss on the sale of its U.K. Weston Hyde flexible films unit helped tip EVC into a net loss, he said.</p>
<p>Taylor said the company would maintain its dividend at 3.00 guilders per share.</p>
<p>The unchanged pay-out reflected EVC's policy of basing dividends on the overall long-term development of the business rather than short-term fluctuations in earnings, he said.</p>
<p>EVC chairman Ettore dell'Isola said that polymers had been the main drag on group turnover. &quot;Three-quarters of the sales reduction was due to polymers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A three per cent rise in polymer sales volumes was not enough to offset a 28 percent fall in the price of S-PVC (suspension polyvinyl chloride), he said, adding west European PVC margins crashed to a 10-year low in 1996.</p>
<p>EVC's compounds business had managed to book stable profits, despite lower margins due to increased price pressure, he said.</p>
<p>The group warned last August that it had fallen into small losses and did not expect much improvement, although it said on Wednesday that PVC markets had turned the corner and were expected to improve this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Improvements in the west European PVC market which emerged in the fourth quarter of 1996 have continued into 1997,&quot; Dell'Isola said.</p>
<p>&quot;Together with other initiatives to improve the business and a continuing contribution from compounds and fabrication (these) are expected to lead to a better trading performance for EVC in 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the years to 2000, worldwide PVC capacity was seen growing broadly in line with demand. Growth in U.S. production capacity would likely be swallowed up by burgeoning demand in Asia, allowing western European supply and demand to remain in balance.</p>
<p>&quot;There are enough reasons to be optimistic but there are also some clouds,&quot; Dell'Isola said.</p>
<p>These might include lower-than-expected economic growth resulting in lower PVC demand and U.S. overcapacity coupled with a lower dollar leading to cheap European imports, he suggested.</p>
<p>EVC's strategy for the future would be to focus on continued cost reductions and expansion into fast-growing markets such as the Asia-Pacific region and eastern Europe, he said.</p>
<p>In addition the firm was pressing ahead with an experimental plant in Wilhelmshaven, Germany, aimed at producing vinyl chloride monomer (VCM) -- the building block for PVC -- more cheaply.</p>
<p>The plant, which will manufacture VCM directly from the raw material ethane rather than the intermediate ethylene, will start operations in the final 1997 quarter.</p>
<p>If the transfer to large-scale production proves successful, it could generate savings of 30 percent over the traditional mode of VCM production, Dell'Isola said.</p>
<p>Taylor said that in 1996 EVC had bought back 4.4 percent of its shares at a cost of 34 million guilders as part of a company strategy to increase shareholder value.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of these shares have already been cancelled and the remainder will be cancelled in April,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said EVC would consider further share buy-backs in the future but it was unlikely to undertake a similar operation in 1997 due to substantially higher planned investments of around 250 million guilders.</p>
<p>EVC shares were the strongest gainers on the Amsterdam bourse on Wednesday, surging 4.60 guilders or 8.5 percent to 58.60 guilders each. ($ = 1.875 Guilders)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25140">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
