<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="404731" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Honecker told Schmidt guerrillas hiding in East Germany.</title>
<headline>Honecker told Schmidt guerrillas hiding in East Germany.</headline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>East German leader Erich Honecker informed West German chancellor Helmut Schmidt that guerrillas of the ultra-leftist Red Army Faction (RAF) had received new identities in the communist state during the 1970s and 1980s, a lawyer said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Karl Pfannenschwarz, defending former East German Stasi intelligence officers charged with helping the guerrillas escape justice in West Germany, made the assertion in court and urged the judge to call Schmidt as a witness.</p>
<p>The court said it would consider the request. Schmidt, now a newspaper publisher, was chancellor between 1974 and 1982.</p>
<p>&quot;Honecker had informed Chancellor Schmidt about 10 RAF members,&quot; Pfannenschwarz said, arguing that because Schmidt did not request their extradition, the charges should be dropped.</p>
<p>&quot;Schmidt and Honecker agreed to keep silent about the retired RAF members in the east.&quot;</p>
<p>Four former Stasi officers are on trial facing charges of helping the RAF guerrillas escape justice by providing them with new identities and cover in the former East Germany.</p>
<p>The accused are Harry Dahl, 67, chief of the counter-terrorism department in the feared Ministry for State Security (Stasi) and three officers, Guenter Jaeckel, 62, Hans-Hermann Petzold, 52 and Gerd Zaumseil, 48.</p>
<p>The case is the latest to try to determine how far East Berlin supported international terrorism and punish those behind an &quot;unholy alliance&quot; between the Stasi and the RAF. The RAF waged a campaign of terror against the West German establishment during the 1970s and 1980s.</p>
<p>Defence lawyers in the case say their clients do not dispute they helped to give the retired guerrillas a new start in life, but deny preventing the course of justice.</p>
<p>The guerrillas were taken in on orders from former Stasi chief Erich Mielke and witnesses have testified that Honecker had known of the operation.</p>
<p>The 10 guerrillas were arrested in 1990.</p>
<p>The guerrillas included some of  West Germany's most dangerous criminals. Susanne Albrecht had been wanted for her part in the 1977 murder of banker Juergen Ponto, the chairman of Dresdner Bank in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Silke Maier-Witt and Monika Helbing were wanted in connection with the 1977 kidnapping and murder of Employers' Federation chief Hanns-Martin Schleyer and other RAF attacks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
