<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="404875" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India allows private cargo airlines to fly abroad.</title>
<headline>India allows private cargo airlines to fly abroad.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's private airline operators are to be allowed to develop cargo operations to and from the country under new guidelines issued by the Director General of Civil Aviation (DGCA).</p>
<p>Officials on Tuesday international listed four conditions under which cargo operations would be permitted.</p>
<p>These are that they are operated on a non-scheduled basis; operate outside the purview of the bilateral Air Service Agreements; the necessary authorisation is obtained directly from the foreign aeronautical authorities concerned although DGCA India may give the operator the necessary letter of introduction and that such services would not confer any right on the operator for allotment of slots on grounds of 'historicity'.</p>
<p>DGCA and Civil Aviation Ministry Officials said applications could be made by any private Indian operator, with a valid DGCA operating permit for cargo operations, and a plan to run foreign cargo operations. They would have to submit details such as aircraft type, route, dates and timings etc. giving 10 days notice for the processing of the application.</p>
<p>Industry sources said the government move is seen as a response to the needs of the growing air cargo market which is largely dominated at the moment by Lufthansa, KLM and to a much lesser extent Air India for products such as garments, carpets, perishable foods and flowers.</p>
<p>Civil Aviation Minister C M Ibrahim has regularly made it clear he wants to support Indian aviation operations competing with foreign airlines large networks and investment muscle.</p>
<p>He has also been encouraging Indian companies to purchase aircraft outright rather than leasing.</p>
<p>Air Indian is known to feel at a serious disadvantage on cargo since it stopped flying its freighters. Private airlines have also wanted to capitalise on cargo to improve their operating margins from passenger revenue, the industry sources said.</p>
<p>The liberalisation could have an early impact on foreign airlines' cargo routes as the private domestic carriers will be able to fly direct out of more than a dozen airports around the country, without having to tranship to a foreign carrier at India's major international transit airports such as Delhi, Bombay and Chennai before shipment to Europe, the Far East and the Gulf.</p>
<p>It would also provide a boost for Indian transport of electronics, software and flower cargo out of Bangalore in the south, where there are a large number of multinationals' IT subsidiaries and an important flower industry.</p>
<p>It is less clear how the move will affect the government's internal national carrier Indian Airlines, which already flies to some 17 foreign destinations within the region and to the Gulf and Far East. - Reuters Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax:5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
