<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405106" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Ashdown lays out EU referendum plan.</title>
<headline>UK's Ashdown lays out EU referendum plan.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paddy Ashdown, leader of Britain's minority Liberal Democrats, on Wednesday laid out his plans for a referendum to give voters a say about Europe.</p>
<p>Ashdown said the British people should be asked a clear question -- &quot;Should the UK put into effect the European Union treaty agreements negotiated by the government and passed by parliament?&quot; -- after any substantial constitutional changes in Britain's relationship with Europe.</p>
<p>And if the government decided to sign up for a single European currency at any stage, a referendum should ask -- &quot;Should the UK join the European single currency on the terms negotiated by the government and passed by parliament?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If you want your say on Europe, then you need a party in parliament to make it happen,&quot; Ashdown told a European Movement gathering. &quot;If you want a referendum, only the Liberal Democrats will have the MPs in parliament to make it happen.&quot;</p>
<p>Ashdown said it was ironic that at a time when the benefits of EU membership were greater than ever, hostility to Europe is sharper than for 25 years.</p>
<p>He said Prime Minister John Major had missed the chance offered by five years in power with a parliamentary majority in favour of closer ties with Europe. Instead, he chose to appease Eurosceptic members of his Conservative Party.</p>
<p>&quot;The PM chose appeasement and paid a very high price and so has the country,&quot; Ashdown told reporters.</p>
<p>He said the debate over Europe had been so damaged that a further question may have to be asked of the British people in the future -- Do you wish to be in or out of the European Union?</p>
<p>&quot;Our judgement is that is not needed now but it could be in due course unless we steer a different course,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A poll conducted by Reuters and NOP, released on Wednesday, showed 41 percent of Britons want to see how European economic and monetary union works out before joining. Some 30 percent want to stay out altogether.</p>
<p>Efforts must be made to tell the man on the street about the advantages the EU offers, Ashdown said. Failings in the EU must be tackled and a &quot;People's Europe&quot; must be built on the basis of popular support.</p>
<p>Britain is not committed to joining a single currency in the first wave, scheduled for January 1, 1999. Officially, the government is keeping its options open.</p>
<p>The Conservative government and main opposition Labour Party have both said they would hold a referendum before signing up for a single currency.</p>
<p>-- Mike Peacock, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
