<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405239" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: PRESS DIGEST - Canada - February 26.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Canada - February 26.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the headlines for selected Canadian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE GLOBE AND MAIL:</p>
<p>- Megacity trustees ruled illegal: Court backs challenge to appointments, but Leach says ruling won't affect plans.</p>
<p>- Seniors face care shortage: Ontario waiting lists top 16,000; funding cuts cited as main factor.</p>
<p>- Fewer doctors foreseen in future: Review points to reduced demand.</p>
<p>- London's Tube may go private: Subway system next on Major's list.</p>
<p>- Sale of Indian lands tainted by cunning, federal report says: Commissioners recommend compensation for 1907 deal.</p>
<p>- Report cites accident risk at nuclear stations: Sleeping employees, computer games, unsafe operation among dangers found at Ontario Hydro plants.</p>
<p>REPORT ON BUSINESS:</p>
<p>- Baton takes control of CTV: Station swap with CHUM gives private network a controlling shareholder for first time.</p>
<p>- Skalbania roller coaster swoops downhill again: Today's sentencing for a C$100,000 theft could put the colorful entrepreneur in jail.</p>
<p>- Magwood out in shakeup at OMERS: Realty subsidiary's board is eliminated.</p>
<p>- Canadian Airlines gets creditor deal: But Ottawa feud threatens bailout.</p>
<p>THE FINANCIAL POST:</p>
<p>- Baton wins CTV control: After four-station with CHUM, Baton will grab 84.5 percent of the English-speaking TV market, putting it second only to the CBC in national coverage.</p>
<p>- Land claim threatens Royal Oak's Kemess project.</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
