<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405257" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Minproc says half yr loss A$24.4 mln.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Minproc says half yr loss A$24.4 mln.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Minproc Engineers Ltd said on Wednesday that it would undertake a fully underwritten rights issue to all shareholders due to a capital deficiency arising from provisions made in the first six months of 1996/97.</p>
<p>The mining engineer said in a statement that it made a net loss of A$24.43 million in the latest half year compared with a A$17.39 million loss a year ago. It said its shares had been suspended at the request of directors.</p>
<p>The latest loss included an abnormal loss of A$27.8 million, which included a provision of A$19.1 million to account for problems with the Yolanda Nitrates project in Chile.  </p>
<p>Minproc said the remainder of the abnormal loss consisted of A$4.7 million for other contractural provisions and A$4.0 million for intangibles.</p>
<p>It said the share suspension had been sought due to the latest loss and the recapitalisation proposal which should be agreed over the next two to four weeks.</p>
<p>An agreement had been reached with other parties in the Yolanda dispute which included a payment by Minproc of US$7.5 million to creditors of Minproc Overseas Projects Pty Ltd which is operating under voluntary administration. There are 78 creditors, Minproc said.  </p>
<p>The Yolanda deal would consist of paying a total of US$800,000 to 78 creditors in full who are owed amounts of less than US$100,000. A further US$6.7 million of new shares in Minproc would be issued to 10 Chilean-based creditors whose claims exceed US$100,000 at an issue price of A$0.45 per share.</p>
<p>These shares would not be listed or have any voting rights for two years.</p>
<p>It said Minproc's largest shareholder, Union Gold Mining Co NL, had indicated it supported the recapitalisation of Minproc by way of a rights issue. Details of the issue were not given but would be released soon, Minproc said.  </p>
<p>Minproc chairman Brettney Fogarty said the payment to Yolanda creditors was designed to end grave uncertainties flowing from certain guarantees agreed to by the previous board of Minproc.</p>
<p>&quot;We have, in effect, inherited a disaster and been forced to do the cleaning up,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Minproc announced a rise in 1996/97 first half sales to A$93.57 million from A$68.44 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Operating profit was A$3.36 million compared with a A$5.39 million loss previously.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
