<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405294" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Novus preferred bidder for WMC assets.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Novus preferred bidder for WMC assets.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Novus Petroleum Ltd said on Wednesday it had been picked by base metals and gold miner WMC Ltd as the preferred bidder for WMC's Australian petroleum assets.  </p>
<p>&quot;Novus Petroleum Ltd has been advised by WMC Resources Ltd that Novus is the preferred bidder for the purchase of WMC's Australian petroleum assets which are currently being sold,&quot; Novus said in a statement to the Australian Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>It said the portfolio being sold by WMC comprised joint venture interests in a number of exploration and production licences in the Carnarvon Basin offshore Western Australia, including some existing producing fields.  </p>
<p>Novus said sale and purchase agreements had been negotiated and signed for some of WMC's interests and negotiations were continuing on others. The consideration for WMC's 30 percent stake in the WA-13-L field was A$173 million.</p>
<p>The joint venture interests in that field and in others being bought were subject to preferential purchase rights of other joint venture partners, Novus said.</p>
<p>Novus said it was arranging debt facilities covering the total amount of the bid. If any of the preferential purchase rights were exercised a lower level of debt would be drawn.  </p>
<p>Novus managing director Bob Williams said Novus had long targeted the Carnarvon Basin as a material business environment for the company. &quot;As Novus' production and revenues have grown since the float, we have also been pursuing a policy of increasing the proportion of gas in our producing portfolio, which at the moment is minor compared to oil. To date, this policy has mostly been manifested in the gas orientation of many of our new venture exploration projects,&quot; Williams said.  </p>
<p>&quot;WMC's Australian assets therefore offer an attractive fit with Novus-gas from East Spar and its synergy with our existing Harriet interest; and a significant exposure to material oil and gas prospectivity in the Carnarvon Basin,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Also given our existing tax base, we have been seeking an increased Australian revenue stream for some time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our very strong balance sheet has enabled us to pursue an acquisition of this scale through debt. Our current debt levels are very low and will remain at manageable levels even if the entire WMC portfolio were acquired,&quot; Williams said.  </p>
<p>&quot;However, we are contemplating a number of options involving selling parts of our existing and expanded portfolio and to restructure the debt following the acquisition.</p>
<p>&quot;The current environment for selling oil properties makes this a ready option,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;...However, I must emphasise again that this is not a 'done deal' and it is possible that we may emerge with only part of the WMC assets. We shall keep the market informed as events unfold,&quot; Williams said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
