<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405369" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Deng &quot;will&quot; a fabrication, says China's HK rep.</title>
<headline>Deng &quot;will&quot; a fabrication, says China's HK rep.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Chinese government spokesman in Hong Kong denied on Wednesday that deceased leader Deng Xiaoping had written a will apologising for the bloody 1989 crackdown on the democracy movement.</p>
<p>Hong Kong newspapers had said Deng wrote a will saying he was sad and felt remorse about the shooting of students during the 1989 military crackdown in Beijing's Tiananmen Square.</p>
<p>The reports said Deng apologised to families of the dead, and to the people of China for the bloodshed and loss of life.</p>
<p>Apple Daily and Ta Kung Pao reported there was a will but gave no sources.</p>
<p>&quot;Relevant departments confirm the so-called Deng Xiaoping will, reported on by some media in Hong Kong and overseas, is a fabrication by some elements of the 'democracy movement' in the United States who sent it to the media,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;These few 'democracy movement' elements clumsily made up stories with some secret aim. Anybody with a conscience would despise this,&quot; said the spokesman for China's mission in Hong Kong, the Xinhua news agency branch.</p>
<p>Deng, who died a week ago, was in power when tanks were sent in to crush a student-led democracy movement in Tiananmen Square on June 3-4, 1989.</p>
<p>Deng died last Wednesday aged 92, just 132 days before his dream of reintegrating Hong Kong into China was due to come true. The British colony reverts to Beijing's control at midnight on June 30 under a plan drawn up by Deng.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the head of the Xinhua office, Zhou Nan, said he would ask Beijing to consider a request by Hong Kong people for some of Deng's ashes to be scattered over the territory's waters.</p>
<p>Last week, Hong Kong's largest pro-Beijing party wrote to Deng's family to request that some of his ashes be sent to the territory to mark its handover to Chinese rule.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
