<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405413" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HSBC Holdings set to show strong growth.</title>
<headline>HSBC Holdings set to show strong growth.</headline>
<byline>Kathleen Kearney</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>International banking giant HSBC Holdings Plc is set to report strong growth in 1996 earnings from almost every corner of its far-flung empire, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;In fundamental terms, the group is firing on all cylinders for the first time in years and is in an exceptionally strong financial position with considerable domestic and international competitive advantages,&quot; said Robin Hammond, research director at Asia Equity.</p>
<p>The London-based bank is forecast to report earnings for the year ended December 31, 1996, of slightly more than HK$37 billion (US$4.78 billion) or 3.08 billion sterling on March 3, said Hammond.</p>
<p>In Hong Kong dollar terms, this would represent an increase of 24 percent and in sterling terms an increase of 25 percent from the previous year.</p>
<p>The units chiefly responsible for the robust growth picture were the bank's Hong Kong operations, including 61-percent held subsidiary Hang Seng Bank Ltd, U.K.-based clearing bank Midland Bank Plc, the bank's Asian operations outside Hong Kong and HSBC Americas Inc, the analysts said.  </p>
<p>Hongkong Bank of Canada and the group's investment banking operations should also contribute to a positive performance, they said.</p>
<p>A key factor driving earnings growth was the strong increase in lending, specifically mortgage lending, in Hong Kong, said Keith Irving, banking analyst at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>Residential mortgages in the territory, which rose by more than 17 percent in 1996, are likely to continue to be a principal contributor to overall credit growth for Hong Kong banks, said Irving.</p>
<p>On top of that, the average net interest margin widened to more than three percentage points during much of 1996, he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said profitability for both HSBC's Hong Kong operations and subsidiary Hang Seng Bank was at a cycle high with cost-income ratios falling to a low.</p>
<p>Hang Seng Bank, with a cost-income ratio of around 27 percent, might be the most profitable in the world, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The subsidiary has the ability to attract low-cost deposits due to its good reputation in Hong Kong,&quot; said Robin Fox, banking analyst at Nomura Research Institute.  </p>
<p>Hang Seng Bank, which will also release its results on March 3, was forecast to report earnings of HK$9.3 billion, a 16 percent increase over 1995's HK$7.98 billion.</p>
<p>Another big factor boosting the group's bottom line should be cost containment at Midland Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate that Midland's income rose by only seven percent but with costs held flat and general provisions for loan losses falling, profit after tax and minorities are forecast to rise 36 percent to HK$9.77 billion,&quot; said Irving.</p>
<p>Several of the bank's units have reported 1996 earnings.</p>
<p>Wholly-owned HSBC Americas Inc, whose principal subsidiary is Marine Midland Bank, reported a 34 percent increase in net income to US$380 million for the year ended December 31, 1996.</p>
<p>Hongkong Bank of Canada reported consolidated net income of C$118.1 million (US$86.88 million) for the 1995/96 year ended October 31, a 15.8 percent increase over 1994/95's C$102 million. On Monday, it reported net income of C$31 million for the first quarter of 1996/97, up 28 percent from the same period the year before.  </p>
<p>With more than 3,000 offices in 71 countries, analysts said they believed HSBC was the largest bank in the world in terms of capital. The group also was probably the world's largest in terms of market capitalisation, they said.</p>
<p>Based on Tuesday's closing share price of HK$193.50, the bank had a market capitalisation of HK$343.38 billion.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the stock hit a record high of HK$195.50 and was at HK$194.00 in late afternoon trading.</p>
<p>(US$1 = HK$7.74) (US$1 = C$1.36)</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6933</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
