<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405598" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Vanda buys Polmont for HK$65.4 mln.</title>
<headline>Vanda buys Polmont for HK$65.4 mln.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vanda Systems &amp; Communications Holdings Ltd said on Wednesday it would buy Polmont Property Investments Ltd from Lam Lui Ming for HK$65.4 million, to be paid through the issue of new shares and internal resources.</p>
<p>The company said in a statement it would issue 12.0 million new shares at HK$3.15 to Lam, an independent third party. The shares represent about 5.54 percent of Vanda's existing shares.</p>
<p>Vanda controlling shareholder Lam Ma &amp; Wai Ltd has also agreed to place 9.66 million shares at HK$3.15 per share to independent investors and subscribe to the same amount of new shares at a price equal to the net proceeds of the placement.</p>
<p>The new issue to Lam Ma &amp; Wai would raise HK$30.43 million, of which HK$27.60 million would be used to finance the acquisition and the remainder for general working capital.</p>
<p>The sole asset of Polmont is 75 percent of the issued share capital of Comtech Engineering and Consultant Co Ltd. Comtech's main business is the general trading of communication products and cables and system integration and installation.</p>
<p>Based on unaudited financial statements, it had net profit before tax and extraordinary items of about HK$4.31 million for the seven months to October 31, 1996.  </p>
<p>Following the transactions, Lam Ma &amp; Wai will hold about 53.4 percent of the enlarged issued share capital of the company compared with about 58.75 percent as of February 21.</p>
<p>Lam has agreed to hold the 12.0 million new shares for a minimum 18 months after the acquisition and should not become a substantial shareholder of the company, Vanda said.</p>
<p>Trading in Vanda shares was suspended on Tuesday and is due to resume on Wednesday. The stock rose HK$0.025 to close at HK$3.325 on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
