<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405512" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Major holders to sell Team Concepts stake.</title>
<headline>Major holders to sell Team Concepts stake.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Team Concepts Holdings Ltd said on Wednesday its major shareholders had entered into an agreement to sell their combined 46.3 percent stake in the firm.</p>
<p>The stake purchaser will be required to make a general offer for the company shares, the statement said.</p>
<p>Team Concepts said the majority shareholders -- Holystone Ltd, Hambrook Ltd and King's Union Corp -- had entered into a conditional agreement on February 25 with a third party to sell 104.27 million shares in the company.</p>
<p>It gave no further details.</p>
<p>As of January, King's Union Corp held 24.14 percent of Team Concepts, and Holystone and Hambrook each held 11.07 percent.</p>
<p>King's Union Corp is equally owned by Holystone and Hambrook.</p>
<p>Trading in Team Concepts shares was suspended at its own request on Wednesday. The company said it would apply to the stock exchange for a resumption of trading upon the publication of the offer announcement.</p>
<p>Team Concepts manufactures telephones, answering machines and electronic educational products.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6370</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
