<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405641" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt bank shares too high - bank official.</title>
<headline>Egypt bank shares too high - bank official.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of the Egyptian Banking Federation said in remarks published on Wednesday that he was worried by the recent gains in bank shares on the Cairo bourse and called on market makers to help push prices lower.</p>
<p>Mahmoud Abdel Aziz, who is also chairman of the government-owned National Bank of Egypt, told the state's al-Ahram daily in an interview that he would much rather investors bought into industrial or manufacturing firms rather than banks which do not give comparable yields.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately, bank shares have a lustre that draws (investors) like no other (shares) especially because they are shares of institutions that are highly-regulated by nature, which makes the investor feel confident buying them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the rising prices of bank shares is a worrying phenomenon... I'm not happy because it deprives other sectors like the industrial, spinning and cement sectors,&quot; he said. &quot;We need market makers to regulate prices as shares are limited.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Also banks in other markets do not give out dividends as high as the market is used to,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Last year, the state said it would sell its holdings in joint venture banks which whipped up trading in their stock. Several share tranches were sold to the foreign partner and now some of these shares trade on the bourse.</p>
<p>Abdel Aziz said the foreign interest was the main driving force behind the recent gains, which in turn have helped push the bourse to record levels. According to the Capital Market Authority, its financial sector index hit a record 702.8 points on Sunday, which also saw an all-time record for the market's all-share index.</p>
<p>Commercial International Bank, one of the sector's most actively traded stocks, is also listed in London through a global depository receipt (GDR) offering.</p>
<p>Misr International Bank/MIBANK is also planning a GDR. Other active banks include Nationale Societe Generale Bank and Egyptian American Bank.</p>
<p>-- Miral Fahmy +202 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
