<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405663" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel, PLO poised for Jerusalem showdown.</title>
<headline>Israel, PLO poised for Jerusalem showdown.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Heller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel was poised on Wednesday to approve the building of a new Jewish neighbourhood in Arab East Jerusalem despite international protests and warnings of Palestinian violence.</p>
<p>&quot;There are scenarios that say there will be riots and possibly the opening of fire -- we are not naive,&quot; Police Minister Avigdor Kahalani told Israel Army Radio.</p>
<p>Major-General Uzi Dayan, commander of Israeli forces in the West Bank, said the army had not sent reinforcements into the area but had &quot;concentrated troops in the necessary places&quot;.</p>
<p>A ministerial committee on Jerusalem was scheduled to convene at 1230 GMT to approve a plan to build 6,500 homes for Jews on Har Homa, called Jabal Abu Ghneim by Arabs, a tree-covered hill taken by Israel in the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
<p>&quot;The struggle for Jerusalem has begun,&quot; Kahalani said. &quot;When we decide (on Har Homa) today, we will make it clear once and for all that Jerusalem is the capital of the Jewish people.&quot;</p>
<p>Palestinians and Israeli leftists have warned the plan would be a blueprint for trouble and ignite Arab rage reminiscent of September clashes sparked by Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's opening of an entrance to a tunnel near Moslem holy sites in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Sixty-one Arabs and 15 Israelis were killed in the violence that almost destroyed the Israel-PLO peace process.</p>
<p>Israeli security sources said an army contingency plan in the event of renewed clashes called for the deployment of tanks and snipers in areas of the West Bank and Gaza still under military occupation.</p>
<p>The U.N. Security Council expressed concern on Tuesday over Israel's settlement policy in East Jerusalem and said it hoped &quot;restraint and wisdom would prevail so as not to undo the peace process&quot;, council president Njuguna Mahugu of Kenya told reporters.</p>
<p>Netanyahu, who has appealed to Palestinians not to resort to violence, said Israel would build in all of Jerusalem, including at Har Homa. He said the plans would include the construction of Arab homes in 10 East Jerusalem neighbourhoods.</p>
<p>Palestinians, who want East Jerusalem as the capital of a future state, said the plan would wreck the foundations of their peace deal with Israel and warned of clashes.</p>
<p>&quot;Netanyahu's statements torpedo the whole peace process. This is a violation of the peace accord and he has to pay the price for such measures,&quot; Palestinian President Yasser Arafat's aide Nabil Abu Radaineh told Reuters by telephone from Morocco.</p>
<p>&quot;Things are already hot in the West Bank and could blow up at any moment. All that's needed is a spark and Jabal Abu Ghneim could be that spark,&quot; Faisal al-Husseini, the top Palestinian Authority official in Jerusalem, said on Israel Television.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Israeli undercover soldiers killed a 60-year-old Palestinian and wounded three others in the village of Hizmeh north of Jerusalem after being cornered by stone-throwers, the army said.</p>
<p>Palestinians said the soldiers, dressed in civilian clothes, provoked residents of the village.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a crime that has been carried out by the secret units which continue to function as if there are no agreements or political negotiations,&quot; said Arafat aide Ahmed Tibi.</p>
<p>Israel handed over parts of the West Bank to Palestinian rule under peace deals signed since 1993 but Israeli soldiers still patrol other areas of the West Bank.</p>
<p>The two sides left the status of Jerusalem, one of the most sensitive issues in the Arab-Israel conflict, for talks on the final status of the West Bank and Gaza Strip which must be completed by 1999.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
