<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405654" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli PM briefs Egypt's Mubarak on Jerusalem plan.</title>
<headline>Israeli PM briefs Egypt's Mubarak on Jerusalem plan.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu briefed Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak by telephone on Wednesday about Israeli construction plans for Arab East Jerusalem, Netanyahu's spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Prime Minister Netanyahu brought Murbarak up to date on the government's building plans in Jerusalem and said it intends to construct about 2,000 housing units for Jews in the Har Homa neighbourhood on land which is largely private and under Jewish ownership,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;(The government) also intends to build in the next three years 3,000 housing units for Arabs in Jerusalem,&quot; he said, repeating a pledge made by Netanyahu.</p>
<p>Netanyahu telephoned Mubarak several hours before a ministerial committee on Jerusalem was expected to approve the plan, which has drawn international protests and Palestinians have condemned as a violation of their peace deals with Israel.</p>
<p>The plan calls for building 6,500 homes for Jews at Jabal Abu Ghneim, captured by Israel in the 1967 Middle East war and called Har Homa by the government. Israeli media reports have said the 2,000 units cited by Netanyahu's spokesman would be the first stage of the project.</p>
<p>Netanyahu told Mubarak that Israel wants to continue peace efforts and &quot;the prime minister added that it would be a grave mistake for anyone to use violence, which would endanger the peace process&quot;, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>In Gaza, Palestinian President Yasser Arafat declined to answer reporters' questions about the housing project.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
