<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405709" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton faces pressure to get tough with Mexico.</title>
<headline>Clinton faces pressure to get tough with Mexico.</headline>
<byline>Peter Bate</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Political pressure mounted on Tuesday for President Bill Clinton to send Mexico a tough message by denying it Washington's unqualified blessing for its efforts against drug trafficking.</p>
<p>The administration must announce by Saturday its verdicts on Mexico and 31 other countries in the process known as &quot;certification.&quot; Mexico has passed that annual test since 1986, when Congress mandated that the White House examine whether major drug producing or transit countries cooperate with U.S. efforts.</p>
<p>But U.S. officials were caught by surprise last week when Mexico dismissed its top anti-narcotics official, Gen. Jesus Gutierrez, charging that he had ties to a drug kingpin. Gutierrez was jailed on Tuesday after a Mexican judge found enough evidence for him to stand trial on drug corruption charges.</p>
<p>&quot;Until the arrest of the general, there was no question about Mexico's certification,&quot; said a White House official who requested anonymity. &quot;Now we're assessing its case.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a cooked deal ... this is not a political decision,&quot; Clinton's anti-drug czar, retired Gen. Barry McCaffrey, said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Mexico, the third largest U.S. trading partner, is also home to cartels that smuggle cocaine, heroin, methamphetamines and marijuana into U.S. territory.</p>
<p>Decertified countries face U.S. economic sanctions. Afghanistan, Burma, Colombia, Iran, Nigeria and Syria were blacklisted in 1996 and are expected to repeat that fate.</p>
<p>A third possibility is a &quot;vital national interests&quot; certification, a waiver of sanctions reserved for governments that fail to meet the standards for full recognition.</p>
<p>Under that cover, the United States can keep sending aid to a country and does not have to vote against its requests for loans from the World Bank and other multilateral lenders. It also allows the U.S. government to continue offering export credits and investment guarantees, without which U.S. sales to Mexico could drop and widen the bilateral trade gap in Mexico's favour.</p>
<p>Clinton was to receive a formal recommendation on Mexico from Secretary of State Madeleine Albright, who returned from a nine-nation tour on Tuesday. The White House said Albright would see Clinton on Wednesday as part of a White House meeting with visiting Chilean President Eduardo Frei. But it was not clear when she would forward her recommendation.</p>
<p>&quot;We are committed to cooperating with our friends in Latin America ... but we want them to cooperate with us as well,&quot; Clinton said at a White House anti-drugs event. &quot;We want to reduce our demand for drugs but we are determined to reduce the supply as well.&quot;</p>
<p>As the deadline for a decision approached, several Clinton allies in Congress urged him not to give Mexico an unqualified certification.</p>
<p>Joseph Biden of Delaware, ranking Democrat on the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, on Monday urged Clinton to grant only a &quot;vital national interests&quot; certification, and two Democratic senators from states with large Hispanic populations, California's Dianne Feinstein and New Jersey's Robert Torricelli, said on Tuesday he should be even tougher.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe the evidence is overwhelming and can lead to no decision other than the decertification of Mexico,&quot; Feinstein said in a letter to Clinton. &quot;It would send a strong signal to Mexico and the world that the United States will not tolerate lack of cooperation in the fight against narcotics, even from close friends and allies.&quot;</p>
<p>Torricelli wrote Clinton: &quot;While I understand the sensitivity of the issue demands that this country proceed delicately, I would ask that you consider sending a tough message to the Mexican government and drug traffickers.&quot;</p>
<p>Senate sources told Reuters that if Clinton fully certifies Mexico, influential senators including Feinstein and New York Republican Alfonse D'Amato would lead a congressional drive to overturn the decision. Under the law, Congress could pass a joint resolution to override the president's decision.</p>
<p>Late on Tuesday, Democratic House of Representatives Leader Richard Gephardt added his voice to the chorus of calls for a get-tough approach to Mexico, saying that the evidence did not support a full certification.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
