<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40587" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chase Securities picked for S.F. stadium financing.</title>
<headline>Chase Securities picked for S.F. stadium financing.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chase Securities Inc will arrange $140 million in financing for the construction of a $255 million ballpark for the San Francisco Giants baseball team, the team said on Monday.</p>
<p>Chase Securities, a subsidiary of Chase Manhattan Corp, will structure and arrange $140 million in syndicated bank credit facilities. The $140 million bank facility would later be replaced by a permanent financing, using the private placement of long-term securities, also arranged by Chase.</p>
<p>The Giants said the package represented the largest project financing ever for a major league baseball club.  </p>
<p>In related announcements, the Giants said Kajima International would be the lead project manager and developer, HOK Sports Facilities Group would be the lead architect, and Huber, Hunt and Nichols would be the lead contractor.</p>
<p>Chase Securities was selected from among more than a dozen financial institutions seeking to provide financing for the project. In addition to structuring the $140 million bank facility, Chase Securities will provide overall financial and project advisory services to the Giants.</p>
<p>The Giants said funding of the $255 million project would include:  </p>
<p>* $140 million from the syndicated bank financing arranged by Chase Securities.</p>
<p>* $100 million in naming rights, sponsorship rights, concession rights and charter seat sales.</p>
<p>* $10 million to $15 million in tax increment financing provided by the San Francisco Redevelopment Agency. These funds will be repaid by possessory interest tax revenues generated from games played at the park.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97911">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
