<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405855" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: BNP Equities cuts AGF rating to accumulate - manager.</title>
<headline>BNP Equities cuts AGF rating to accumulate - manager.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paris brokerage BNP Equities-du Bouzet has lowered its recommendation on French insurer AGF to &quot;accumulate&quot; from &quot;buy&quot; and removed it from its list of recommended stocks, one of its fund managers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The brokerage took the step because it believed the share now was &quot;correctly valued&quot;, he said. Since AGF's 30 percent share price rise since the start of the year, &quot;the share should now evolve in line with the market&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The share price is in line with our objective given the profitability we expect from AGF in 1997 and 1998,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>By 1415, the share was off 1.13 percent at 219.50 francs in volume of 934,090 shares traded.</p>
<p>The brokerage remained positive on AGF, saying two factors argued in favour of keeping it in investment portolios -- the difficulty of estimating the &quot;very probable&quot; appreciation of underlying capital gains and speculative interest surrounding the share.</p>
<p>&quot;The hypothesis of new consolidation developments in the sector&quot; could involve AGF, the manager said. Bouzet believes the group could be &quot;an ideal target for a major player who wants to take a position in the French market&quot;.</p>
<p>Speculation surrounding AGF's future has been fed by market talk German insurer Allianz might bid for the French group. On Tuesday, AGF said no discussions were under way with Allianz and that it had not been notified of anyone building a stake in it.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, AGF has refused to comment on a newspaper report on Wednesday that it may sell its 47 percent holding in reinsurer SAFR to Swiss reinsurance company Suisse Re. Trade in SAFR was suspended on Wednesay pending release of a statement.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8200318">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
