<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="405988" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: European Parliament chief demands French backdown.</title>
<headline>European Parliament chief demands French backdown.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The president of the European Parliament threatened on Wednesday to cancel a meeting with French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette after the minister said the parliament was &quot;not worthy of its name&quot;.</p>
<p>Jose-Maria Gil-Robles said in a statement the remarks were &quot;an unacceptable judgement on the European Parliament, its role and its dignity&quot; and he would not meet de Charette as planned on Wednesday afternoon unless he received a &quot;clarification&quot;.  </p>
<p>On Tuesday, President Jacques Chirac met Gil-Robles, who is on an inaugural visit to France, and accused the parliament of &quot;unacceptable interference&quot; in French affairs after it adopted a motion last week calling for the withdrawal of a disputed French bill to clamp down on illegal immigration.</p>
<p>De Charette took the attack a step further in a television interview on Wednesday, saying: &quot;Once again, I have to say it with regret...that the European Parliament shows that it is not yet a parliament worthy of the name.&quot;</p>
<p>Gil-Robles, a member of Spain's conservative Popular Party, said in his statement he &quot;would like to believe the terms used went beyond the minister's thoughts&quot;.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;Unless a clarification by Mr de Charette is forthcoming before the meeting scheduled today for 4.15 p.m. (1515 GMT), the president of the European Parliament considers there is no point in holding the meeting.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
