<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="406011" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Portugal's BPI 1996 profit rises 56 pct.</title>
<headline>Portugal's BPI 1996 profit rises 56 pct.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Banco Portugues de Investimento, Portugal's fourth biggest private bank, reported a 56 percent increase in 1996 profits to 15.1 billion escudos ($90 million) on Wednesday, in line with analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>The board decided to propose a gross dividend of 85 escudos per share, which represents a five percent increase over the 100 escudos paid in 1995, adjusted for a capital increase at the end of 1995.</p>
<p>BPI said its 1996 results were not directly comparable with those of 1995 because of the acquisition of state controlled bank Banco de Fomento e Exterior (BFE) in August 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;The consolidation of BFE took place from October 1, 1996, and so the results include BFE's accounts for the last quarter of 1996,&quot; a statement said.</p>
<p>BPI said goodwill of 47 billion escudos from the acquisition of BFE was amortised in its 1996 accounts by a transfer from reserves and that it would have no impact on future results.</p>
<p>BPI  raised its provisions sharply, well above the requirements of the Bank of Portugal, to 17.5 billion escudos, including a seven billion escudo adjustment due to the purchase of BFE.</p>
<p>The bank gave no figures for provisions for 1995.</p>
<p>BPI's assets rose 108 percent year-on-year to 2.89 trillion escudos ($17.2 billion) in 1996. Loans increased by 178 percent year-on-year to 1.16 trillion escudos ($6.9 billion).</p>
<p>BPI shares eased in early trade on Lisbon bourse to 2,555 escudos, down 24, in volume of 25,209 shares. $1=168.2 escudos</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
