<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="406047" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Aker Maritime posts healthy growth in 1996.</title>
<headline>Aker Maritime posts healthy growth in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwegian offshore services company Aker Maritime ASA on Wednesday posted profits before tax of 301 million crowns ($45.3 million), a rise of 70 percent on the year-earlier period.</p>
<p>The company, formed last November after Aker ASA spun off its Oil and Gas Technology division and merged it with offshore supplier Maritime Group, said the proforma comparative figure for 1995 was 177 million crowns.</p>
<p>Turnover for the period rose 33 percent to 10.83 billion crowns from 8.13 billion crowns. The figures included a gain of 89 million from the sale of shares in the Maritime Group to Aker ASA in connection with the establishment of Aker Maritime.</p>
<p>Extraordinary earnings of 57 million crowns came from the sale of the Maritime Seanor business area.</p>
<p>Aker Maritime said the growth in turnover was largely due to an increase in procurement in relation to large oil development projects in Norway. Operations in the United States also expanded and last year posted revenues of NOK 1 billion, it said in a statement.</p>
<p>However, it said it was now preparing to make changes in its operations in Norway to improve competitiveness following its failure to win tenders for two floating production systems at the end of 1996 and in early 1997.</p>
<p>Aker Maritime said it expected moderate growth in revenues and results in 1997.</p>
<p>--Oslo newsroom, +47 22 42 50 41 ($ = 6.651 Norwegian Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
