<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="406188" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgium's Union Miniere back in profit.</title>
<headline>Belgium's Union Miniere back in profit.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian non-ferrous metals firm Union Miniere emerged from a five-year trough on Thursday, announcing that in 1996 it made a profit and saw the prospect of even more in coming years.</p>
<p>The firm reported a group net consolidated profit of 391 million francs for calendar 1996 against a loss of 954 million the previous year. It was the first profit since 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel much better than last year,&quot; Chief Executive Officer Karel Vinck told reporters. &quot;The nice thing is that we have a net profit...and we are on target with our industrial plan. That gives us a good feeling,&quot;</p>
<p>Vinck said the company, which has not paid a share dividend since the 1990 book year, would again pay no dividend on the 1996 results.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;We are preparing the company to be in the condition to start the dividend policy again.&quot;</p>
<p>The company said the heady combination of the strong dollar, a sterling performance from its zinc refining arm, improving prices and a reducing debt burden had all helped lift it out of the red.</p>
<p>However, lower volumes in its transformation sector which specialises in adding value to non-ferous metals products, the continued drag of its recycling operation at Hoboken and the cost of restructuring its Daimond Boart diamond tools business had all proved a drain.</p>
<p>Vinck said the Hoboken plant was being replaced by a state of the art factory that would come on stream in 1998, and a hefty 342 million franc provision had been made in the 1996 results for Diamond Boart and its synthetic diamond business.</p>
<p>The outlook, he said, was looking better than it had done for years.</p>
<p>&quot;1997 will really be a key year...We expect the dollar to remain strong and zinc prices to be significantly better than in 1996,&quot; he said, adding that the firm expected zinc prices to average $1,200 a tonne during the year against $1,000 in 1995.</p>
<p>It will also be the third year of the four-year industrial plan than began in 1995 and that aims to have Union Miniere on a solid footing and climbing up the profitability ladder.</p>
<p>&quot;We will accelerate the achievement of the results foreseen by the industrial plan,&quot; Vinck said.</p>
<p>He added that unlike many other non-ferrous metals firms, Union Miniere was not penalised by low world copper prices.</p>
<p>The firm reported turnover in 1996 of 131 billion francs against 127.3 billion the previous year, with operating profit of 1.7 billion francs against 2.2 billion.</p>
<p>Net financial charges fell to 285 million francs from 786 million. The 1995 extraordinary loss of 2.2 billion francs dropped to just 924 million last year and current profit was 1.6 billion francs against 1.8 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, 1997 is expected to be a better year than in 1996, thereby confirming the high expectations of the group performance after the industrial plan has been fully implemented,&quot; UM said in a statement.</p>
<p>Vinck said that as proof of the firm's faith in the future, it had decided on Thursday to invest 600 million francs in expanding production of Cobalt Oxides at its plant in Olen. These are mainly used in rechargeable batteries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
