<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40617" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: General Acceptance in bank credit pact.</title>
<headline>General Acceptance in bank credit pact.</headline>
<dateline>BLOOMINGTON, Ind. 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Acceptance Corp, a consumer finance company providing installment loans for the sale of used automobiles to consumers with limited access to traditional financing sources, said Monday it has completed a $4.5 million revolving line of credit with a bank.</p>
<p>Borrowings under the line of credit, which carries interest at the bank's prime rate, are secured by the company's inventory of repossessed, purchased and trade-in vehicles, the company said. The bank was not identified.</p>
<p>The company plans to use the funds to finance the ongoing purchase of contracts receivable and vehicle inventory.  </p>
<p>General Acceptance also said that preliminary negotiations with its primary lender to renew and increase its line of credit from $100 million to $110 million have been completed, and the lender is in the process of obtaining internal approval for the terms of the arrangement.</p>
<p>It is expected that once renewed and increased, the line of credit will carry an interest rate of 350 to 375 basis points over one-month LIBOR, which would represent a 50 to 75 basis point increase over the current rate.</p>
<p>While no assurance can be given, funding under the increased line of credit should be available by the middle of October, 1996, General Acceptance said in a statement.</p>
<p>The company said it believes that the $110 million line of credit and a recently completed $4.5 million bank line of credit, will provide funding needed to permit the planned growth of its loan portfolio into the first quarter of 1997, while the company works toward its first securitization.</p>
<p>	     Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BLOOMINGTON, Ind."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
