<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="406177" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan Finance Ministry breakup might yield muddle.</title>
<headline>Japan Finance Ministry breakup might yield muddle.</headline>
<byline>Linda Sieg</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Breaking up is hard to do -- but Japan is giving it a try.</p>
<p>Ruling politicians are forging ahead with a plan to deprive the powerful Finance Ministry of its authority to inspect and supervise financial firms and bestow that role on a new agency.</p>
<p>Domestic attention has focused mainly on the likelihood that the ministry will retain considerable power under the new scheme, an outcome many analysts agree is probable.</p>
<p>Some analysts also worry, however, that the reform may result in more bureaucratic muddles, while doing little if anything to help financial supervisors meet the challenges posed by Japan's planned &quot;Big Bang&quot; deregulation, due by 2001.</p>
<p>Based on a pact reached last December by the three parties in Japan's loose ruling alliance, officials -- many seconded from the Finance Ministry itself -- are finalising draft legislation to set up an independent body under the Prime Minister's Office to oversee all financial institutions.</p>
<p>The officials face a March 11 deadline for submitting the legislation to the current session of parliament. The reform is expected to be implemented in the year from April 1, 1998.</p>
<p>The reform plan reflects a sharp drop in public confidence in the ability of the elite Finance Ministry -- tainted by scandals and alleged policy missteps -- to cope with the problems weighing down the nation's financial system.</p>
<p>Politicians, keen to wrest policy control from Japan's much-maligned but still powerful bureaucrats, seized on the ministry reform as a first step towards achieving that goal.</p>
<p>Such motivation, however, may not yield the best results for the financial system. &quot;The Finance Ministry was seen to be the naughty boy and this is its punishment, rather than a well thought out rationalisation,&quot;said David Threadgold, an analyst at BZW Securities. &quot;The problem is that 'divide and rule' is often a recipe for chaos.&quot;</p>
<p>Some analysts worry the reform will fail to clarify responsibility for cleaning up the mess left by failed financial institutions and thus delay official responses.</p>
<p>Financial daily Nihon Keizai Shimbun said on Wednesday that the prime minister, to whom the new body would report, would have ultimate responsibility for handling financial failures.</p>
<p>But in cases where a failure threatened the financial system, prior consultation with the finance minister would be mandated, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Politically, there was no discussion (of what that meant),&quot; said Makoto Utsumi, a former vice finance minister for international affairs. &quot;It's very hard to know what would happen and it's difficult to predict where responsibility is.&quot;</p>
<p>Some analysts also worry the new agency will do little to improve a financial surveillance system that critics say has been proved inept at uncovering problems at an early stage.</p>
<p>&quot;If you're headed for a 'Big Bang' and going to have a deregulated environment, you have to have sufficient supervision, an unobtrusive monitoring system, a great deal of electronic monitoring capacity and lots of regulators,&quot; said Brian Waterhouse, a financial analyst at James Capel Pacific.</p>
<p>&quot;But they don't appear to have made any effort to improve the resources that the inspecting body needs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Other analysts, however, said the new supervision and surveillance structure created by the planned reform need not create more confusion.</p>
<p>&quot;Ultimately, the key is not the regulatory structure but that the individuals involved are willing to work together and determined to address problems that arise,&quot; said Walter Altherr, an analyst at Jardine Fleming Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;If they have that willingness and determination, the organisational chart is of secondary importance,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Efficiency aside, analysts said any expectations that the Finance Ministry's clout would diminish much were misplaced.</p>
<p>The reform will deprive the ministry of the right to issue licences to financial firms, but leave it with authority over financial policy and the budget formation process as well as with responsibility for drafting legislation, officials said.</p>
<p>In addition, the new agency is expected to be staffed largely with Finance Ministry officials, although some limits may be placed on their ability to return to the ministry later.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be an independent agency in form, but I'd be very surprised if it's an independent agency in reality,&quot; said Ron Bevacqua, an economist at Merrill Lynch Japan. &quot;The idea that MOF will no longer be a player on the field as well as a referee is mistaken.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
