<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="406126" id="root" date="1997-02-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British Aerospace boasts of recovery as profits soar.</title>
<headline>British Aerospace boasts of recovery as profits soar.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Aerospace Plc announced a sharp jump in profits Wednesday, marking its recovery from a disastrous diversification into cars and real estate.</p>
<p>The company said pretax profits soared by more than 80 percent to 425 million pounds ($696 million) from 234 million ($383.6 million) as sales rose by 12 percent to 7.44 billion pounds ($12.2 billion).</p>
<p>Underlying profits before exceptional charges rose 38 percent to 456 million pounds ($747.5 million) from 330 million ($541 million), underpinned by a jump in operating profits from defence to 553 million pounds ($906.6 million) from 487 million ($798.4 million).</p>
<p>The company said the result was driven by record orders and strong margins after radical restructuring in recent years returned the group's focus to its core businesses of aerospace and defence.</p>
<p>The airline said a 1.9 billion pound ($3.1 billion) order from the British government for Nimrod maritime patrol aircraft helped boost its order book to an all-time high of 19.4 billion pounds ($31.8 billion) by the end of the year, compared with 17.1 billion ($28. 0 billion) a year ago.</p>
<p>The company's chief executive, Sir Richard Evans, said a further 1.2 billion pounds ($1.97 billion) of defence orders from Britain, Australia and Qatar had been booked in since the end of the year.</p>
<p>With a strong order book tucked under its arm, Evans said senior management could now concentrate on the consolidation of the European aerospace industry to match the might of U.S. rivals led by Boeing Co. and Lockheed Martin Corp.</p>
<p>Evans said in an interview that the priority for the European effort was the current move to get the four-nation Airbus Industrie consortium restructured as a single company.</p>
<p>&quot;We have always maintained despite all the speculation that goes on about strategic moves and all the rest of it that Airbus is the driver for what is going to happen in Europe,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
