<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="406548" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US FTC fines Mahle GmbH,Metal Leve $5 mln.</title>
<headline>US FTC fines Mahle GmbH,Metal Leve $5 mln.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Trade Commission said Thursday that Germany's Mahle GmbH and Brazil's Metal Leve S.A. have agreed to pay a record fine of over $5 million over Mahle's purchase of a controlling stake in Leve.</p>
<p>The two companies were fined for failing to give federal antitrust enforcers advance notice of the acquisition.</p>
<p>The FTC said Metal Leve has also agreed to quickly sell off its U.S. piston business, including two plants in South Carolina and a development center in Michigan, to prevent a monopoly in pistons used primarily in heavy duty diesel engines.  </p>
<p>&quot;Violation of the reporting requirements of the antitrust laws is a very serious matter,&quot; William Baer, Director of the FTC's Bureau of Competition, said. &quot;The reporting requirements serve as a critical early warning system to alert antitrust enforcers to potentially anticompetitive mergers.&quot;</p>
<p>The FTC said that the $5 million-plus penalty payment by Mahle and Metal Leve is a  record civil fine for this type of violation.</p>
<p>Baer said that Mahle's purchase of a 50.1 percent stake in Metal Leve would have raised piston prices by as much as $25 million a year if the FTC had not acted.  </p>
<p>&quot;The divestiture we are requiring here will prevent a monopoly from forming and should save diesel engine manufacturers and, ultimately their consumers, millions of dollars,&quot; Baer said in a statement.</p>
<p>Both Mahle GMBH and Metal Leve S.A. manufacture diesel engine parts, including pistons, through U.S. subsidiaries -- Mahle Inc, of Morristwon, Tenn. and Metal Leve Inc of Ann Arbor, Mich., respectively, the FTC said.</p>
<p>The FTC said in a statement its attorneys would allege in court that Mahle acquired 50.1 percent of Metal Leve for about $40 million on or before June 26 last year without notifying the FTC or the Justice Department despite knowing the deal posed &quot;serious anti-trust problems&quot;</p>
<p>The consent agreement does not admit to a violation of law but binds the companies involved not to break the law in future.</p>
<p>Once the settlement becomes final the divestiture would have to be completed within 10 days.</p>
<p>&quot;If that is not accomplished, then the FTC may appoint a trustee to divest the business,&quot; the FTC announced.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
