<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="406661" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: KPMG sues exiting partners, seeks arbitration.</title>
<headline>KPMG sues exiting partners, seeks arbitration.</headline>
<dateline>WILMINGTON, Del. 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>KPMG Peat Marwick LLP has sued four partners who resigned recently according to papers filed late Monday in the Delaware Chancery Court.</p>
<p>The suit was filed simultaneously with a related demand for arbitration on the partnership dispute.</p>
<p>KPMG alleges the partners are violating the terms of their partnership agreement by soliciting other KPMG partners and employees to join in a new competitive venture and raising capital to finance it.</p>
<p>&quot;Defendants have announced their intention to create a consulting business in direct competition with KPMG...(and) have been securing capital and financing,&quot; court papers say.</p>
<p>Named as defendants are Ted Fernandez, Ulysses Knotts, and Allan Frank, who resigned Jan 28 and stated their intention of opening a consulting business; and David Dungan who resigned Feb 20.</p>
<p>KPMG said the partners' resignations are not effective until six months after being submitted and that for two years they must comply with certain non-compete provisions.</p>
<p>KPMG also seeks reimbursement from the partners for &quot;the full amount of capital and the full value of resources that KPMG invested in order to develop the consulting practice.&quot;</p>
<p>Dungan could not be reached for comment. A spokeswoman for the other three partners said &quot;they denied the allegations&quot; of the lawsuit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WILMINGTON, Del."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
