<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="406857" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London freight - Grain trade increase but BFI down.</title>
<headline>London freight - Grain trade increase but BFI down.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The largely shapeless situation in the freight market was reflected by the BFI losing 4 points to 1,454 and the Baltic Handy index gaining a couple to 1,081.</p>
<p>Little was seen of caper activity but there was increased volume of grain trading and fresh enquiry on the Continent for handies and for both handies and panamaxes from Argentina and Brazil, with rates firmer in both areas.</p>
<p>GRAIN - In a week when caper fixtures have been scarce, Toepfer were reported to have booked Angeliki for 80,000 barley from two ports Continent to Red Sea for early March at $17.25. Brokers said this rate was a dollar down on last fixed.</p>
<p>Judging from Nidera's reported fixture of Ispat Tarang for about 60,000 heavy grain U.S. Gulf/Lisbon for mid March at close to $12.25, panamax rates are steadier. Last fixture in this trade was Hyphestos at the same rate, and for U.S. Gulf/Holland at $12.90. But Goldbeam failed the vessel they were said to have fixed on subjects for a mid-March stem of 54,000 heavy grain U.S. Gulf/Japan at $25.50 combo and are now indicating $24.50 no combo.</p>
<p>Halla quoted a fresh U.S. Gulf/Japan enquiry for end March/early April with rate ideas of $24.25 no combo.</p>
<p>Chartering activity has picked up from east coast south America. Toepfer was believed to have covered the Cobelfret-relet Feng Shan Hai for 50,000 wheat up river Plate plus Bahia Blanca or Necochea to Aqaba for mid March at $27.</p>
<p>Continental fixed a panamax (possibly Oristis Ermis 64,379 dwt) delivery Ponta da Madeira mid March for 2 laden legs redelivery Atlantic at $10,000 daily plus $170,000 bonus, having failed the 1977-built Velos 60,552 dwt delivery Jorf Lasfar for up to three laden legs at a reported $10,000 daily.</p>
<p>Handies featured prominently in a Plate/Brazil market and also from the continent, described by brokers as looking promising for owners. Cargill was said to have conceded the 1977-built Zara $17.00 for 25,000/5 wheat U.S. Gulf/Algeria, reckoned to be about a dollar better than last done, and tradigrain fixed a similar size Rouen/Tunisia on private terms, believed to be at a marginally higher level than last done.</p>
<p>Poseidon was reported to have covered an oats cargo from Uddevalla to east Mediterranean also on private terms.</p>
<p>New business included Dreyfus with 35,000 heavy grain U.S. Gulk/Portugal for March 7/15, Continental 28/32,000 heavy grain U.S. Gulf/Spanish Med March 4/11, 20/25,000 agriprods 54' Brazil/full Med March 15/29, and 55,000 50' up river and Necochea/east Med for March/April.</p>
<p>Pioneer needs a panamax delivery USEC for 2-3 laden legs Atlantic trading, and Cargill have 31,000 oilseeds Vancouver/Manzanillo, both for mid March.</p>
<p>MINERALS - Brokers said Japanese charterers were busy fixing and quoting fresh orders for panamaxes in the east. Showa was understood to have fixed a panamax on private terms for Port Kembla coal to Japan, having failed Western Trader 70,329 dwt which went instead to Shinwa from Japan for a Roberts Bank round at $11,800 daily.</p>
<p>Panamaxes are also believed to have been taken for coal trips by Daiichi Kalimantan/Philippines and by K Line Indonesia/Japan, both with mid-March deliveries. Yukong or Keoyang are said to have booked Samjohn Captain 65,000 dwt delivery Bin Qasim March trip via Goa to the Far East on private terms.</p>
<p>HANDIES - A number of larger geared vessels were booked from the Continent to the Far East. Anastasia 54,000 dwt was covered at about $13,500 daily, and Pacific Prince 43,000 dwt at about $12,500 daily. Albatross was thought to have fixed on private terms in this trade.</p>
<p>Other fixtures included Panormos 37,636 dwt covered by Ubt Skaw/U.S. Gulf at $6,350 daily and Calypso N 34,000 Continent/U.S. Gulf with Combac at $6,500 daily.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
