<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="406841" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British genetic committee checks cloning laws.</title>
<headline>British genetic committee checks cloning laws.</headline>
<byline>Maggie Fox</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A  government-appointed committee charged with montoring genetic issues held its first meeting on Thursday and decided to check that existing British laws to prevent cloning of human embryos were watertight.</p>
<p>The new Human Genetics Advisory Commission (HGAC) discussed the successful cloning of a sheep which has caused widespread concern because of the possibility the process could be use for the genetic production of carbon-copy humans.</p>
<p>In a statement, the HGAC said the cloning of human embryos by 'nuclear transfer' was forbidden in Britain under a law passed in 1990.</p>
<p>Nuclear transfer involves transferring the nucleus, which contains the DNA, of one cell into an egg. This creates a genetic twin. Cloning by splitting embryos can only be carried out under licence.</p>
<p>'It was decided that the chairman of HGAC would write to his counterpart on the Human Fertilisation and Embryology Authority confirm the adequacy of the existing law,' it said.</p>
<p>The government's science minister sought to reassure the public about the implications of cloning research, saying it was being closely watched and regulated.</p>
<p>Ian Taylor said the HGAC would be sure to keep the public informed.</p>
<p>&quot;For those who fear that science fiction will come true, they should be clear that a broad range of regulatory controls have been put in place to prevent what is undesirable becoming a reality,&quot; the minister said in a statement.</p>
<p>News that scientists in Scotland had cloned an adult sheep rattled nerves all the way from U.S. President Bill Clinton to Nobel Peace Prize winner Joseph Rotblat, with both urging close monitoring of such science.</p>
<p>The researchers who cloned the sheep admit it could now become possible to clone a human being, although they denounced anyone who would try.</p>
<p>&quot;The reporting of the remarkable breakthrough achieved at the Roslin Institute risked confusion between science and science fiction,&quot; Taylor said.</p>
<p>Sir Colin Campbell, a legal philosopher, chancellor of the University of Nottingham and chairman of the new committee, said it would have to communicate effectively with the public to prevent misunderstandings about genetics.</p>
<p>'There is no doubt that genetics will continue to be a major issue,' he said in the statement.</p>
<p>The committee also discussed the implications of genetic testing for insurance, employment and health care.</p>
<p>Insurance companies have stopped short of requiring testing for genetically linked diseases like Huntington's disease, which brings early death -- but British insurers now require people who have been tested to tell them the results.</p>
<p>There are fears that people with genes that could predispose them to disease will be discriminated against. The HGAC said it decided to set up a group to 'explore the complex issues with interested parties'.</p>
<p>It will report back at the next meeting on May 15 and will address the implications for individual privacy because privacy 'would be an underpinning issue in establishing confidence in the new science'.</p>
<p>The HGAC has 10 members including medical professors, doctors and a minister.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
