<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="406980" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>COTE D'IVOIRE: Ivorian cocoa areas get some relief from drought.</title>
<headline>Ivorian cocoa areas get some relief from drought.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bunce</byline>
<dateline>ABIDJAN 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rains spread inland from coastal Ivory Coast cocoa areas this week after February drought which has threatened to stress trees and reduce late mid-crop (April-Sept) potential, weather and crop analysts said.</p>
<p>Industry sources say the mid-crop is likely to determine whether the 1996/97 season harvest is in line with government projections of 950,000 tonnes or close to 1.1 million tonnes -- as some industry players predict.</p>
<p>&quot;The trees are still holding up but heavier rains will be needed in early March to ensure mid-crop prospects,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are plenty of flower pinheads (buds) on trees but rains are needed to prompt pollinating activity by insects.&quot;</p>
<p>Flowers would give pods maturing in August and September.</p>
<p>Weather data show little rainfall up to February 20 but another crop analyst returning to Abidjan along the coast this week drove for four hours through heavy rain showers.</p>
<p>The first heavy rains for three weeks fell as a thunderstorm over Abidjan on Thursday, following the appearance of clouds over the past 10 days.</p>
<p>&quot;Heavy showers have fallen in the past few days in coastal areas but northern Ivory Coast is still experiencing dry Harmattan weather conditions,&quot; said a national weather station spokesman.</p>
<p>Ivory Coast produced a record 1.2 million tonnes 1995/96 crop after a bumper 200,000 tonnes mid-crop.</p>
<p>Some industry forecasters raised 1996/97 crop forecasts after strong main crop arrivals. Mid-crop prospects are expected to be clearer by mid-March.</p>
<p>Upcountry buyers said rains had also fallen inland as far as Gagnoa. New grass could be seen growing through fire-cleared verges on remote roads suggesting rains in those areas.</p>
<p>Buyers north of Gagnoa said dry dusty condions had not yet cleared.</p>
<p>Crop analysts said a build-up of dust on leaves cutting photosynthesis would only be washed off if rain continued to fall.</p>
<p>&quot;If early March rains are good, trees will react well. There is no sign they have suffered any more than normal,&quot; one said. &quot;It is the dry season after all,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Official weather data for the second 10 days in February showed a total of 13.1 millimetres were recorded at 10 weather stations compared to 0.6 mm in the previous 10 days.</p>
<p>Rains were concentrated in coastal regions east of Abidjan with little falling in the commercial capital itself.</p>
<p>Data for the past week were not immediately available.</p>
<p>In the first and second 10 days of February in 1996 rainfall totalled 303 mm and 361 mm. Weather analysts said this year's totals were 21 percent of the long-term average after higher than normal January levels.</p>
<p>Rains have traditionally increased from little rainfall in January towards the main rainy season from April to June followed by a dry spell in July and August.</p>
<p>Deforestation has meant convection rainfall patterns are more uneven than in the past with more usually falling in areas with stands of trees left intact -- mostly western areas where new cocoa tree planting is concentrated.</p>
<p>Temperatures in cocoa growing countries usually range between a minimum of 18-21 Celsius and a maximum of 30-32C.</p>
<p>Temperatures in some Ivory Coast areas have touched 37C in February. Soil moisture levels had partly compensated for the heat after heavy December and light January showers, said crop analysts.</p>
<p>The data, from Ivory Coast's national weather station, showed the following rainfall for the second 10 days of February in key growing areas plus the commercial capital Abidjan:</p>
<p>Dalao 0 mm, Gagnoa 0 mm, San Pedro 0.1 mm, Tabou 0 mm and Man 0 mm, Dimbokro 0, Yamoussoukro 0 mm, Abidjan 2.7 mm, Sassandra 0 mm, Adiake 10.3 mm, Korhogo 0 mm.</p>
<p>-- Abidjan Newsroom + 225 21 90 90</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABIDJAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COTE D'IVOIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
