<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="406961" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: No scope for S.Africa easing at present - Stals.</title>
<headline>No scope for S.Africa easing at present - Stals.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals said on Thursday that a jump in money supply and private credit extension in January showed there was no scope for easing monetary policy at present.</p>
<p>But he cautioned against reading too much into one month's data.  </p>
<p>&quot;One should not over-react to this, and see what happens in February. But it certainly confirms that there is no room at this stage for relaxing on the monetary policy,&quot; he told Reuters by telephone from Pretoria.</p>
<p>&quot;We've certainly not seen a very convincing decline in the rates of increase in the monetary aggregates.&quot;  </p>
<p>South Africa's year-on-year broadly defined M3 money supply grew 16.89 percent in January, preliminary Reserve Bank figures showed. Annual private sector credit growth was 17.07 percent.</p>
<p>Both figures were considerably higher than the consensus of economists who had forecast 15.8 percent and 15.3 percent respectively.</p>
<p>Stals said the jump in money supply reflected the large inflow of foreign funds in January, which had boosted reserves. The big increase could also reflect, in part, statistical anomalies such as holiday dates.</p>
<p>He noted that M3 had not shown the normal seasonal decline last month with unadjusted M3 totalling 319.62 billion rand, virtually unchanged from December's 319.45 billion.</p>
<p>-- Ben Hirschler, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
