<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="407003" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe urged to address privatisation, deficit.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe urged to address privatisation, deficit.</headline>
<byline>Melanie Cheary</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwean President Robert Mugabe needs to offer clearly defined policies on privatisation and reducing the budget deficit when he addresses a foreign investment conference in London next week, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Mugabe leaves on Sunday for London and will lead a delegation of business and political representatives to the Zimbabwe Investment Conference on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe is revelling in a robust economy -- with a booming stock market, lower inflation and falling interest rates -- but analysts warn against the agriculture-based economy's over-reliance on good rains for growth and urge the development of strong fundamentals.</p>
<p>&quot;This economy is reacting to rain rather than fundamentals. There are no real strong fundamentals and so it will remain very volatile and be at the mercy of rain,&quot; said James Whittington, investment analyst at ING Barings Bank.</p>
<p>Analysts said Zimbabwe, eyeing growth of 4.9 to six percent this year after an estimated eight percent last year, could enjoy double digit growth if the budget deficit was halved and the many remaining parastatals privatised efficiently.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy really is booming and could see double digit growth if the deficit is reduced and privatisation given the go-ahead,&quot; Whittington told Reuters.</p>
<p>Others said that economic growth of eight percent was the best the country could relish before capacity became strained.</p>
<p>&quot;Eight percent could really put a limit to how far we could sustain it across a wider spectrum. Last year's growth was in the value of crops,&quot; said independent economist John Robertson.</p>
<p>But all analysts agreed that economic growth hinged on the government fine-tuning its economic policies.</p>
<p>&quot;The main problem is the budget deficit and if Mugabe can spell out how to bring it down that would allay a lot of fears,&quot; Whittington said.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe has set a 1997 budget deficit target of 8.5 percent of gross domestic product (GDP). Last year the deficit was 10.1 percent, failing to meet a target of 6.7 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Ideally it should be two or three percent, but if he (Mugabe) could halve it to about 5.5 percent that would give a strong message to investors,&quot; Whittington said.</p>
<p>Reducing the budget deficit would also assist in further reducing inflation.</p>
<p>Annual inflation is forecast at 16-18 percent this year. It fell to a seven-year low in November of 13.9 percent, before rising to 16.4 percent in December. In January it was 15.8 percent.</p>
<p>The downward trend led the central bank to cut its rediscount rate earlier this month to 23.5 percent from 27 percent. Commercial banks followed suit and cut lending rates.</p>
<p>Foreign investors would take heart from a honed privatisation policy because selling companies raises funds for government and attracts foreign investment.</p>
<p>But analysts cautioned that the government should privatise assets through open tenders and that, ideally, shares should be traded on the stock market where investors would at least have the security of being able to buy and sell their stakes freely.</p>
<p>&quot;Privatisation is an issue of interest to investors because it is a window on how the government views investment in general. But people are a bit confused at the moment because the policy has been misguided,&quot; Robertson said.</p>
<p>&quot;If (privatised stakes) don't go to the stock exchange then individual buyers have to be found and this is often done on a political basis, rather than on who has the money,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>While the government has already partly privatised the Zimbabwe Electricity Supply Authority (ZESA) and announced it wants a strategic equity partner for Zisco (Zimbabwe Iron and Steel Company), little progress had been made on privatisation.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a number of other companies that could be privatised and if they (government) send a strong signal that they'd do that, that would contribute to the bullish economy,&quot; Whittington said.</p>
<p>To date, the government has approved the privatisation of the Dairibord Zimbabwe Ltd, the Cotton Company of Zimbabwe, the Zimbabwe State Trading Corporation and the Commercial Bank of Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>But Air Zimbabwe, the National Railways and Zimbabwe Copper Mines as yet remain out of reach of private hands.</p>
<p>--Harare newsrooms +263-4 72 52 28/9--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
