<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="407136" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian poor rely on soup kitchens to survive.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian poor rely on soup kitchens to survive.</headline>
<byline>Thalia Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;No vacancies for free food&quot; warns a sign on the back door of a house in a cobbled street in the Bulgarian capital.</p>
<p>A group of mostly elderly men and women in neat but threadbare clothes are gathered outside in the rain, their eyes fixed anxiously on the door, ready to collect a lunch of soup, fruit, bread and cheese.</p>
<p>&quot;I have a 4,000 lev ($1.81) pension for a whole life of work. This is a humiliation,&quot; says one woman with tears in her eyes. &quot;The humiliation is even worse than starvation, but it's the only way we can survive.&quot;</p>
<p>Government corruption and refusal to carry out economic reforms finally caught up with Bulgaria's rulers this winter. Hyper-inflation has eroded salaries -- an average state wage of 20,000 levs a month is worth $9 -- and the United Nations estimates 90 percent of people now live below the poverty line.</p>
<p>The soup kitchen run by Bulgarian pensioner Donka Paprikova is one of about 30 around the city. Eight years ago, the bright-eyed 82-year-old set up a project with a few friends to care for the sick and bedridden in Sofia.</p>
<p>Last October, realising the number in need was growing by the day, she set up a soup kitchen. With some 70 volunteers, she feeds 200 people at the house twice a week and delivers meals to another 75 who are housebound.</p>
<p>&quot;Every day we have 50 newcomers and it breaks my heart but I have to turn them away,&quot; she told Reuters. Volunteers include doctors and even a trainee priest, and foreign embassies help out by bringing food. Thursday's chicken soup came from the U.S. embassy.</p>
<p>Paprikova's work with the needy started with a pensioners' club during the former communist era, which struggled for official approval from a state reluctant to recognise that there were needs for which the system did not provide.</p>
<p>She said she modelled her work on that of Indian missionary Mother Teresa in the slums of Calcutta. &quot;My idea is to help the poorest of the poor, and the sickest of the sick,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Her dream is to open a hospice for the terminally ill. The Sofia municipality has offered her a house, but when she took an engineer to look at it, he said it needed restoration work which would cost 90,000 German marks ($50,000).</p>
<p>Paprikova selected the 200 people she helps from the most needy cases at hospitals and social care centres.</p>
<p>&quot;The people queuing outside are not beggars, they are well-educated people, though with all their suffering you would never recognise them as doctors and teachers,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She said one volunteer had been horrified and embarrassed to recognise her former teacher in the lunch queue, and another had broken down in tears packing Christmas parcels because she could not afford oranges and bananas for her own grandchildren.</p>
<p>Prices are rising by the day and the near-bankrupt interim government is barely able to secure grain and oil supplies, let alone provide a social safety net.</p>
<p>Anger at the former Socialist government's handling of the economy sparked 30 days of mass protests which ended with agreement for general elections to be held on April 19.</p>
<p>No one expects political change to bring immediate economic relief but the international community is starting to mobilise aid for Bulgaria's plight.</p>
<p>The European Union has earmarked 20 million ecus ($23 million) to support 450,000 households with a per capita income of less than 3,250 levs a month, and residents of some 570 social institutions.</p>
<p>Paprikova and her 70 volunteers rely on donations of goods, money, and even surplus vegetables from peoples' gardens. &quot;It's not the rich who support us, but usually the poor, who do not have big incomes and expensive cars,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She said donations were falling as the crisis worsened and people no longer had money to spare.</p>
<p>&quot;Every month, people are getting poorer and poorer. With my pension I can't afford to buy even a loaf of bread every day,&quot; she said. &quot;My pension is worth the equivalent of $3 and now we have Western-style prices in the shops.&quot; ($=2,200 levs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
