<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="407308" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile pension funds diversify, sell power stocks.</title>
<headline>Chile pension funds diversify, sell power stocks.</headline>
<byline>Eduardo Coronado</byline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Facing falling returns, Chilean pension fund managers are looking to branch out abroad and move investments from slow-growth electricity stocks into brisker sectors including the retail and banking industries.</p>
<p>&quot;We no longer see the need to continue with a concentrated presence in the electricity sector. We are thinking of switching our stock investments towards other areas,&quot; Francisco Skinner, deputy investment manager at administrator Cuprum, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Newly launched retail stocks such as supermarket chain D&amp;S and department store Falabella have shown spectacular growth in recent months which has whet the appetite of the funds.</p>
<p>&quot;It's true that many funds have been selling shares in the electricity sector to move into others, like the retail sector,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>The funds, known by their Spanish initials as AFPs, are keento boost their returns which have fallen sharply in recent years mainly as a result of the lackluster performance of the Santiago bourse.  </p>
<p>As Chile's largest institutional investors, funds' portfolio movements are closely watched as a guide to swings in stock prices, said analysts.</p>
<p>D&amp;S's share price, the bolsa's best-performing new stock, has climbed nearly 70 percent since the start of the year. Falabella and rival department store Almacenes Paris have risen 17 percent and eight percent respectively in January.</p>
<p>Chile's selective blue chip IPSA index has risen 18 percent this year.  </p>
<p>Electricity shares, the funds' main stock investment for several years, are likely to have a rough ride this year for a variety of reasons, said marketwatchers.</p>
<p>&quot;The serious drought which has affected the central zone of the country this year, the fall in generating prices and tough competition...make us think that the sector will be quite difficult this year,&quot; said one financial analyst.</p>
<p>Outside the stock market, AFPs are looking to diversify by branching out into water and highway infrastructure projects and mining, said fund managers.</p>
<p>Funds are also planning to boost their investments abroad as a way of increasing their returns and reduce their dependence on economic swings in Chile, said Skinner.</p>
<p>&quot;This year we will diversify through foreign investment, basically in mutual funds and Latin American bonds,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Although most funds have announced similar intentions, moves to diversify within Chile and abroad will be slow.</p>
<p>Official figures show electricity shares represented 48 percent of AFPs' total stock investments in January.</p>
<p>((-- Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595x212))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150214">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
