<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="407459" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Sampoerna 1996 net at 394 bln rph.</title>
<headline>Sampoerna 1996 net at 394 bln rph.</headline>
<byline>Helen Lumban Gaol</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>PT Hanjaya Mandala Sampoerna, one of Indonesia's largest cigarette makers, said on Thursday it posted a net profit of 394 billion rupiah in 1996, lower than the targetted 423 billion rupiah which is said was due to losses in overseas operations.</p>
<p>Sampoerna's chief financial officer, Ekadharmajanto Kasih, told analysts during the company's annual public presentation that Sampoerna's profit totalled 394 billion rupiah in 1996 against 352.46 billion rupiah in 1995, but the amount was just below the original target.</p>
<p>Kasih said the decline was due to an unanticipated loss from its overseas operations. Sampoerna downgraded its 1996 profit target by about five percent to 423 billion rupiah last November.</p>
<p>&quot;Previously, we only expected losses from our overseas operations at about $10 million but in fact the actual loss reaches $14 million,&quot; Kasih said.</p>
<p>Sampoerna operates a number of cigarette companies and subsidiaries abroad.</p>
<p>Kasih said the difference in the accounting system in line with the rupiah's depreciation against the dollar and the higher cost of staff development also contributed to the decline.</p>
<p>He told the analysts the company had forecast its net profit to rise to 528.25 billion rupiah in 1997 and to 602.92 billion rupiah in 1998.</p>
<p>When asked about the company ability's to achieve the 1997 forecast after it failed to meet the 1996 target, Kasih said the company was quite upbeat.</p>
<p>He said he believed Sampoerna could achieve the target as the impact of higher cigarette prices would be felt in 1997, starting from the first and second quarter of this year.</p>
<p>Kasih also said sales volume would be higher and boost revenue as the market recovered from higher cigarette prices, due to both price boosts and a 1996 increase in excise tax.</p>
<p>&quot;These combined factors -- higher volume and higher prices -- will help the company achieve its 1997 target,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Sampoerna said it had net sales of 2.3 trillion rupiah in 1996, and expected net sales of 3.7 trillion rupiah in 1997 and 4.2 trillion rupiah in 1998.</p>
<p>Regarding Sampoerna's plan to use the $200 million notes raised in mid-1996 -- issued by a Sampoerna subsidiary -- to expand the business, Sampoerna's chief executive officer Putera Sampoerna said the company was holding negotiations with several companies overseas.</p>
<p>&quot;Our objective is to expand in Asian countries through joint-ventures,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sampoerna denied market rumours that the company would acquire cigarette makers Djarum and Bentoel.</p>
<p>&quot;To expand our domestic market share, we don't have to acquire cigarette companies, we can just increase our production capacity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The share price of Sampoerna closed 7.32 percent lower at 13,300 rupiah on a turnover of 3.8 million shares after falling to 12,800 rupiah in late morning trade.</p>
<p>An analyst with a Singapore-based firm said selling pressure on Sampoerna emerged after the cigarette firm announced its lower than expected 1996 results.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
