<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="407479" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish establishment keeps pressure on Islamists.</title>
<headline>Turkish establishment keeps pressure on Islamists.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Lyons</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Islamist Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan was locked in a war of nerves with Turkey's political establishment on Thursday, one day before a meeting between top ministers and the staunchly secularist army brass.</p>
<p>The Hurriyet daily carried a front-page report -- dismissed as untrue by Erbakan and President Suleyman Demirel's office -- that Demirel had warned the Islamist-led coalition against threatening Turkey's &quot;secularist, democratic (and) republican aims&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;If you continue with this attitude the regime will be in danger,&quot; the daily quoted the warning to Erbakan, the first Islamist leader of the officially secular republic.</p>
<p>Similar reports were carried in the rival Sabah newspaper. Both dailies are traditional organs of the secular political and business establishment.</p>
<p>Erbakan immediately denounced the reports as &quot;a lie&quot;, and the president's press office denied any such letter was sent. However, the comments attributed to Demirel echo a series of recent briefings he gave to newspaper editors and columnists.</p>
<p>&quot;Thankfully our government is working harmoniously. The censure motions helped to strengthen our government further,&quot; Erbakan later told reporters after talks with the president.</p>
<p>The government this week survived a censure motion challenge from two leftist parties who said the coalition was a threat to the country's secularism.</p>
<p>The reports aggravated political tensions, already running near fever pitch since the army sent tanks on manoeuvres through the Ankara district of Sincan on February 4 following an Islamist protest there attended by the Iranian ambassador.</p>
<p>The Foreign Ministry said on Thursday it was expelling Iran's consul to the eastern town of Erzurum, following his criticism of apparent anti-Iranian comments by a leading Turkish military official.</p>
<p>The announcement added to a diplomatic row between Tehran and Ankara, which protested to Iran earlier this month about the Iranian ambassador's comments at the Sincan rally.</p>
<p>Nightly civilian protests, launched initially against state corruption, have increasingly turned against Erbakan and his Islamist Welfare Party and show little sign of dying down.</p>
<p>&quot;Ankara is in confusion. Ankara is tense. Ankara is doomed to give birth to many things,&quot; commentator Ismet Berkan wrote in the daily Radikal. &quot;Ankara is full of rumour and speculation.&quot;</p>
<p>Such speculation is building toward Friday's regular session of the powerful National Security Council -- a vestige of earlier military rule -- that groups senior commanders and ministers.</p>
<p>Political analysts expect the council to issue a stern warning to Erbakan that mounting Islamist zeal threatens Turkey's secular and democratic institutions.</p>
<p>Few analysts, however, expect the kind of military intervention that twice before deposed then-prime minister Demirel.</p>
<p>&quot;Those in Ankara who are in any way close to the military know that they have no intention of mounting a coup. They want to put pressure on the government to change its behaviour,&quot; commentator and author Mehmet Ali Birand told Reuters.</p>
<p>Birand, who has extensive contacts with the armed forces, suggested the soldiers might be contented if Erbakan agreed to jettison one or more of his more zealous ministers.</p>
<p>Financial markets, always volatile, closed off 1.48 percent as participants settled in to wait out the National Security Council session. Volume was moderate.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is nervous. Nothing much can be expected until tomorrow's meeting is over,&quot; said on broker.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
