<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40746" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed should raise rates slightly - Shadow group.</title>
<headline>Fed should raise rates slightly - Shadow group.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Reserve should raise short-term interest rates by a small amount at its next policymaking meeting on September 24, members of the Shadow Open Market Committee said Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe it is appropriate now to take a slight pre-emptive tightening action,&quot; Michigan State University professor Robert Rasche told reporters.</p>
<p>The Shadow Open Market Committee is a group of academic and business economists who comment regularly on Fed policy.  </p>
<p>Rasche said the group does not see acceleration of inflation on the horizon but believes the Fed should act now to help push down inflation.</p>
<p>Allan Meltzer, a professor at Carnegie Mellon University, also backed a small increase in interest rates at the Fed's September 24 meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;They should tighten and reduce the growth of the monetary aggregates,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>At its meeting six months ago, the Shadow group recommended that the Fed hold policy steady. Meltzer said that since then inflation has failed to fall as expected while monetary growth has picked up.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
