<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="407513" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: San Francisco tobacco suit dismissed.</title>
<headline>San Francisco tobacco suit dismissed.</headline>
<dateline>OAKLAND, Calif. 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A federal judge has dismissed a lawsuit filed by the City and County of San Francisco and 10 other California counties against the tobacco industry, according to court papers made public Thursday.</p>
<p>The tobacco industry hailed the ruling as a victory in its fight against lawsuits seeking to force cigarette companies to repay states and municipalities for health care costs of smokers. It is believed to be the first ruling to totally dismiss a lawsuit of this type.</p>
<p>&quot;This decision drives a stake through the heart of this type of lawsuit,&quot; said Daniel Webb, an outside lawyer for Philip Morris Cos. Inc. &quot;I think it will be precedent setting and have a wide ranging impact,&quot; said Webb, a Chicago lawyer and former U.S. Attorney in Chicago.</p>
<p>Although anti-smoking lawyers said the ruling was a drawback, they remained optimistic about the more than 20 other cases pending around the country.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a retrograde decision,&quot; said Richard Daynard, chairman of the Tobacco Products Liablity Project at Northeastern University in Boston. &quot;I think most of the other courts will go the other way.&quot;</p>
<p>The ruling, dated Wednesday, was issued by U.S. District Judge D. Lowell Jensen in the U.S. District Court in the Northern District of California in Oakland. Although the judge dismissed the suit, he ruled that the plaintiffs' lawyers could refile an amended complaint.</p>
<p>San Francisco and the other counties are among a growing number of municipalities and states that have sued the tobacco industry to recoup Medicaid costs.</p>
<p>The attorneys general from 22 states have filed such suits. The first of the trials, which stems from a case brought by Mississippi, is scheduled for June.</p>
<p>The aim of the California suit is to recoup health care costs of smokers. The plaintiffs alleged that the tobacco companies engaged in a racketeering conspiracy to mislead plaintiffs and their residents about the harms of smoking and the addictive nature of nicotine.</p>
<p>Webb said the ruling was particularly important because Jensen held that for the plaintiffs to recover money spent on health care for individual smokers, they would have to prove that each of those injuries were actually caused by smoking.</p>
<p>Jensen also agreed with the tobacco industry's argument that the racketeering claims should be dismissed because of the remote nature of the plaintiffs' injuries.</p>
<p>The industry said that the U.S. Supreme Court has held that for racketeering claims to be sustained there has to be a direct relationship between the plaintiffs' injuries and the defendants' alleged conduct. It said that a plaintiff complaining of harm flowing from the misfortunes of a third person was too remote to recover.</p>
<p>Jensen found that the suit failed to meet the proximate cause requirement under the federal racketeering statute.</p>
<p>&quot;First, and most importantly under the present circumstances, it would be extremely difficult for the court to ascertain the amount of damages attributable to defendants' conduct, as there are many other factors that could affect plaintiff's smoking-related damages,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Although he granted the tobacco industry's motion to dismiss the complaint he denied its request to disqualify the plaintiffs' law firm Lieff, Cabraser, Heimann &amp; Bernstein.</p>
<p>A spokesperson at the law firm said the firm had not yet seen the ruling and did not have an immediate comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OAKLAND, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
