<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="407607" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. rail freight traffic up from year ago--AAR.</title>
<headline>U.S. rail freight traffic up from year ago--AAR.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sharp gains in loadings of containers and metallic ores helped push rail freight traffic in the latest week narrowly ahead of the comparable week last year, the Association of American Railroads said Thursday.</p>
<p>AAR said new carloadings on major railroads rose 1.8 percent in the week ended February 22 to 345,213 from 339,093 in the year-ago week.</p>
<p>The number of new trailers and containers rose six percent to 161,283 from 152,148 a year earlier. Container traffic itself rose 8.7 percent to 99,371 from 91,449 a year ago.  </p>
<p>AAR said traffic volume as measured in ton-miles rose 1.9 percent in the week to 27.2 billion ton-miles from 26.7 billion in the same week last year. A ton-mile equals one ton of freight hauled one mile.</p>
<p>AAR said traffic was up in about two-thirds of the major commodity groups, including the big increase of 11.6 percent in metallic ore loadings to 14,735 from 13,209 a year ago.</p>
<p>Coal carloadings, the largest category, increased 1.9 percent to 137,107 from 134,532 in the same week last year.</p>
<p>Loadings of chemicals increased 3.7 percent in the week to 30,388 from 29,311, and loadings of motor vehicles and equipment rose 3.9 percent to 22,168 from 21,339. Grain carloadings rose 0.7 percent to 26,546 from 26,352.</p>
<p>AAR also said traffic on Canada's two transcontinental railroads was mixed in the latest week. It said the number of new trailers and containers totaled 24,084, up 4.3 percent from the same week last year, while new carloadings totaled 53,977, a 1.2 percent drop from last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
