<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="407820" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Athens bourse fall overdue - analysts.</title>
<headline>Athens bourse fall overdue - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Dimitris Kontogiannis</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek stocks plunged 5.95 percent on Thursday after coming under heavy selling pressure and market watchers called it an overdue correction as the market lacked support from fundamentals.</p>
<p>The Athens stock exchange general share index tumbled 86.44 points to 1,367.16 points on heavy turnover of 30.831 billion drachmas. Losers led gainers 218 to 31 on 253 shares traded.</p>
<p>&quot;The market had overheated and this was a healthy correction. Foreign investors focusing on fundamentals were becoming itchy with the general share index above 1,400 points and were reducing exposure,&quot; said Yannis Protopapadakis, analyst at ING Barings.</p>
<p>With the general share index around 1,400 points, the bourse was trading at 14 to 15 times after-tax earnings. This corresponds roughly to an earnings yield of 6.7 to 7.1 percent compared to a 9.6 percent yield on 12-month T-bills, he said.</p>
<p>The 12-month T-bill has been the most popular debt instrument with Greek retail investors but it has lost some its lustre with its nominal rate now taxed and cut sharply by the finance ministry.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not think that we will see after-tax T-bill yields at such low levels this year,&quot; said Protopadakis who added that a retail-driven rally was always dangerous and unpredictable. &quot;But the 1,300 level is reasonable for the general share index.&quot;</p>
<p>Other analysts agreed that a market correction was expected and long overdue, predicting that the bourse would go through a consolidation.</p>
<p>They saw strong resistance in the area of 1,600 to 1,650 points and strong support at 1,200 points.</p>
<p>&quot;The bourse badly needed a correction,&quot; said the head of research at Carnegie International in London. &quot;The statement by the president of the capital market commission gave a convenient excuse to market players.&quot;</p>
<p>The president of the capital market commission, Stavros Thomadakis, said on Wednesday that the stock market's rally was a healthy upside correction in terms of volume and valuations but warned investors to avoid rumour-based investment decisions.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the statement was overall mild and balanced,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The analyst said the market outlook was positive but she expected a period of consolidation.</p>
<p>&quot;We may see several days of market weakness before a period of consolidation but the outlook is favourable,&quot; said the analyst who requested anonymity. &quot;The Athens bourse is in the final leg of its bull run.&quot;</p>
<p>But she warned of a speculative bubble in construction stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;Construction shares were oversold in late 1996 and fairly priced at the end of January,&quot; said the analyst. &quot;They are overbought at these levels.&quot;</p>
<p>The analyst predicted that a rotation toward small caps would take place later on.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we will see a rotation in small-caps later on,&quot; she said. &quot;This is usually the case when retail investors come in.&quot; -- Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
