<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="408152" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British MPs criticise small firm's big aid deal.</title>
<headline>British MPs criticise small firm's big aid deal.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The British Parliament's Public Accounts Committee on Thursday criticised the government's foreign aid department for appointing a small company to administer a project worth more than eight times its own annual turnover.</p>
<p>The committee said in a report that the Overseas Development Administration (ODA) only learned that TecQuipment Limited was such a modest enterprise when it ran into difficulties obtaining a bank guarantee for a 10 million pound loan it advanced.</p>
<p>The ODA agreed in September 1991 to give aid of 23.36 million pounds ($38.25 million) towards a 66.75 million pound project managed by TecQuipment to supply technical equipment for engineering faculties in 28 Turkish universities.</p>
<p>In the year to September 1988, immediately before the application for aid, TecQuipment had made a 402,000 pounds profit on turnover of just over eight million. Its net assets were little more than a million pounds.</p>
<p>&quot;We are disturbed that the Administration did not become aware of TecQuipment's modest financial position until they learned, after having approved the contract, that the company were having problems obtaining a bank guarantee,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>It noted that the guarantee was eventually provided by Fisons Plc, which then gained 10 million pounds in orders under the project.</p>
<p>It said the Administration had pointed out to it that provision of the guarantee could not have allowed Fisons to influence TecQuipment since such a guarantee cannot be withdrawn.</p>
<p>But the committee said it was &quot;concerned&quot; that orders for 23.4 million pounds, of which 3.3 million went to TecQuipment and 2.3 million to Fisons, were placed without competition.</p>
<p>&quot;We note the Administration's evidence that the education equipment sector is highly specialised, with a number of proprietary manufacturers,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nevertheless we expect all publicly-funded procurement to be conducted as far as possible on a competitive basis in order to protect value for money and to act as a safeguard against impropriety.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
