<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="408227" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NatWest down again after results.</title>
<headline>NatWest down again after results.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in National Westminster Bank Plc fell on Thursday, extending a recent retreat amid further reaction to Tuesday's results and as a report in the Guardian said the bank's own analyst was cautious on the stock</p>
<p>NatWest shares, which hit a record 845p on February 10 -- up some 23 percent since the end of 1996 -- were down 10-1/2p at 763-1/2 by 1145 GMT in active trade of 3.9 million shares.</p>
<p>Dealers said there had been a continued surplus of stock in the market. &quot;The market was still long, there has been some indigestion in the market, but they are now at a level where there has been some support,&quot; said one market-maker.  </p>
<p>NatWest shares rose sharply in the early weeks of this year after lagging the sector for much of 1996.</p>
<p>Separately the Guardian said NatWest Securities analyst Mark Eady put a &quot;hold&quot; rating on the stock and said there was better value elsewhere in the sector.</p>
<p>It said Eady had lowered his earnings estimates for NatWest, which on Tuesday posted a 27 percent rise in underlying pre-tax profit to 1.12 billion stg but warned that it expected growth to slow and it was taking a more cautious approach to lending.</p>
<p>Eady was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Others said NatWest and the rest of the banking sector was always likely to quieten down after the results season.</p>
<p>&quot;The sector has been extremely strong and it tends to go a bit quiet after the results,&quot; said one senior fund manager. &quot;Our view is that we are still happy with the stock and happy with the sector.&quot;</p>
<p>Among other bank stocks, Barclays Plc was down 1p at 11.26 stg and Lloyds TSB Plc was up 1-1/2p at 515-1/2.</p>
<p>-- David Holmes, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5106</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
