<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="408311" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan parliament approves new company law.</title>
<headline>Jordan parliament approves new company law.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan's parliament has approved a new company law which cancels a 15 percent tax on companies raising their capital bases by transferring money from reserves, officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>They said parliament approved on Wednesday the new companies law, part of a new package of economic reforms that is also expected to include a new customs law, a securities law, and a law to protect local industry from dumping.</p>
<p>The companies' law has to be sent for approval to parliament's upper chamber, the Senate, before it is enacted as a royal decree.</p>
<p>Prices in Jordan's blue-chip shares rose two weeks ago when parliament approved the section of the law scrapping the tax on capital raises. A number of leading companies have promised shareholders they intend to boost their capital with transfers from reserves, including free share offers, once the law was passed in its entirety.</p>
<p>Investment analysts say the move will also increase the supply of stock in firms that have currently reached a maximum foreign ownership ceiling.</p>
<p>The new law also scraps the state's issuing committee, which sets prices of new share issues.</p>
<p>- Amman Newsroom +9626 623 776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
