<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="408476" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Partial list of Grammy winners.</title>
<headline>Partial list of Grammy winners.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following is a partial list of winners in the 39th annual Grammy record industry awards:</p>
<p>Best Spoken Word or Non-Musical Album: Hillary Clinton, &quot;It Takes A Village.&quot;</p>
<p>Best Rock Album: &quot;Sheryl Crow, Sheryl Crow.&quot;</p>
<p>Best Rock Song: Tracy Chapman, &quot;Give Me One Reason&quot; (Track from &quot;New Beginning&quot;).</p>
<p>Best Rock Performance by a Duo or Group with Vocal: Dave Matthews Band, &quot;So Much to Say&quot; (Track from &quot;Crash&quot;).</p>
<p>Best Pop Duo or Group with Vocal: &quot;Free as a Bird&quot;, The Beatles (Track from &quot;Anthology 1&quot;). The Beatles, Best Short Form Video, &quot;Free as a Bird.&quot; The Beatles, Best Long Form Video, &quot;Anthology.&quot;</p>
<p>Best Pop Instrumental Performance: Bela Fleck &amp; The Flecktones, &quot;The Sinister Minister&quot; (Track from &quot;Live Art&quot;).</p>
<p>Best Traditional Pop Vocal Performance: Tony Bennett, &quot;Here's to the Ladies.&quot;</p>
<p>Best R&amp;B Album: The Tony Rich Project, &quot;Words.&quot;</p>
<p>Best R&amp;B song (songwriter's award): Babyface for &quot;Exhale (Shoop Shoop)&quot; performed by Whitney Houston (Track from &quot;Waiting to Exhale-Soundtrack&quot;).</p>
<p>Best R&amp;B Duo or Group Performance with Vocal: Fugees, &quot;Killing Me Softly With His Song&quot;, Fugees (Track From &quot;The Score&quot;).</p>
<p>Best Female R&amp;B Vocal Performance: Toni Braxton, &quot;You're Makin' Me High&quot; (Track from &quot;Secrets&quot;).</p>
<p>Best Contemporary Blues Album: Keb'Mo', &quot;Just Like You.&quot;</p>
<p>Best Classical Vocal Performance: Bryn Terfel, &quot;Opera Arias (Works of Mozart, Wagner, Borodin, etc.).&quot;</p>
<p>Best Instrumental Composition: Herbie Hancock and Jean Hancock, &quot;Manhattan (Island of Lights and Love)&quot; (Track from &quot;The New Standard&quot;).</p>
<p>Best Rap Solo Performance: LL Cool J, &quot;Hey Lover&quot; (Track from &quot;Mr. Smith&quot;).</p>
<p>Best Country Song (songwriter's award): Bill Mack for &quot;Blue&quot;, performed by LeAnn Rimes (Track from &quot;Blue&quot;).</p>
<p>Best Polka Album: Jimmy Sturr, &quot;Polka! All Night Long&quot;.</p>
<p>Best Spoken Comedy Album: Al Franken, &quot;Rush Limbaugh is a Big Fat Idiot.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
