<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="408575" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Tietmeyer warns of dangers to EMU success.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Tietmeyer warns of dangers to EMU success.</headline>
<byline>David Crossland</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer on Thursday painted a gloomy picture of prospects for European monetary union if two key requirements -- a stable single currency and lasting budget restraint -- are not met.</p>
<p>But Tietmeyer also said it was &quot;premature and unjustified&quot; to interpret the recent appreciation of the dollar against the mark as a harbinger of a weak single currency.</p>
<p>He reaffirmed a statement made by the Group of Seven leading industrial nations at a meeting in Berlin on February 8 that the sharp fall of the dollar in 1995 had been corrected.</p>
<p>&quot;Current exchange rate relations doubtless better reflect the fundamental economic data on both sides of the Atlantic,&quot; Tietmeyer said in a speech at a conference on monetary union hosted by U.S. investment bank Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>The comments had little impact on the dollar which remained around 1.69 marks in European trade.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer also said Germany was interested in the mark remaining a stable currency and wanted the euro to be similarly stable and strong.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope this view is shared by other European countries,&quot; Tietmeyer said in the speech, which focused on the risks of monetary union.</p>
<p>The single currency, or euro, is scheduled to be launched on January 1, 1999, and this year is the key year whose data will be used to decide which EU members take part at the start.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer maintained the Bundesbank's strict line on tough monetary requirements for EMU.</p>
<p>He said members' failure to maintain budgetary discipline could lead to wage conflicts, higher unemployment, a greater burden on welfare systems and political pressure on the future European Central Bank (ECB) to loosen monetary policy -- pressure the ECB may not be able to withstand in the long term.</p>
<p>He also said the euro must be perceived as credible and stable to ensure a smooth transition to the euro.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer warned that attempts to loosen the Maastricht Treaty criteria for monetary union would create the &quot;fatal illusion&quot; that states could relax their efforts to cut their budget deficits.</p>
<p>While most European Union (EU) member states had made progress on curbing inflation and stabilising exchange rates, &quot;substantial efforts&quot; were still needed to cut deficits and government debt to acceptable levels, he said.</p>
<p>After years of accumulating debt, state finances had been stretched so far that they could no longer react to economic downturns, Tietmeyer said. Meanwhile taxes had risen so high they were threatening to stifle innovation and cause job cuts.</p>
<p>&quot;Short-sighted decisions or a loosening of the fiscal Maastricht critieria would be ... the wrong signals.</p>
<p>&quot;That would stir up the fatal illusion that the fiscal situation was still bearable or would ease of its own accord in future. The pressure to reform, not least caused by the Maastricht process, would suddenly vanish.</p>
<p>&quot;Urgent adjustments would be shelved and burden the future even more. As a result the start of the euro would be laden with hard homemade problems.</p>
<p>Conflict at a later date would be &quot;preprogrammed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer also warned that a monetary union containing nations with different social systems and independent control of their budgets had greater potential forces pulling it apart than a nation state, especially in times of upheaval.</p>
<p>That made it important to ensure a &quot;high level of market flexibility and a common stability culture&quot; from the start.</p>
<p>&quot;We all hope and wish that the currency union will promote European integration economically as well as politically. But it can only do so if it is a lasting success,&quot; Tietmeyer said.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
