<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="408641" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS - French fourth-quarter GDP edges up 0.2 percent.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - French fourth-quarter GDP edges up 0.2 percent.</headline>
<byline>Christopher Noble</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's gross domestic product rose 0.2 percent in the fourth quarter of 1996 from the previous quarter, putting the country's depressed economy on a sounder base for its expected recovery this year.</p>
<p>The rise was slightly higher than economists' expectations but they said it was partly offset by a small downward revision to third quarter GDP growth, which rose 0.8 percent instead of an initially reported 0.9 percent.</p>
<p>A finance ministry official said the rise was in line with government expectations and made it more likely the country would reach its official 1997 growth target of 2.3 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;It reinforces our position,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>INSEE said full-year growth was 1.3 percent, in line with the government's official forecast, after growth of 2.2 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a nice surprise,&quot; said Herve Goulletquer, economist with Banques Populaires. &quot;All the conditions are present for stronger growth in 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>The government needs stronger growth this year to fulfil its plans to reduce the public deficit in preparation for European monetary union.</p>
<p>The finance ministry official said growth would have been much stronger at the end of last year if the effect of the number of working days and a sharp drop in car sales were stripped out. Car sales were hit by the end of a government purchase-incentive scheme which expired at the end of September.</p>
<p>Economists said they expected growth in 1997 to be driven in large part by exports and stock-building, a shift from 1996, which drew much of its strength from consumer spending.</p>
<p>Consumer spending rose an annual average of 2.3 percent in 1996 and contributed 1.4 percentage points to full-year growth.</p>
<p>But economists said the positive GDP figure and stronger economic data so far this year should not lead to euphoria.</p>
<p>&quot;I would stay on the cautious side,&quot; said Steven Englander, economist with Smith Barney in Paris, who said more data was needed to prove an economic recovery was here to stay.</p>
<p>Consumer sentiment remains mired at near all-time lows and unemployment is stuck at a record 12.7 percent. Englander said he still had some doubts about whether the economy would grow as much as the government expects.</p>
<p>Goulletquer, who had pencilled in 1997 growth of 2.2 percent before the report on Thursday, said an upward revision to 2.4 percent was possible, but no more.</p>
<p>INSEE said that in the fourth quarter, imports rose 1.3 percent but a 1.1 percent rise in exports cancelled most of that out and INSEE said trade's overall contribution to GDP was slightly negative.</p>
<p>Consumer spending, which dropped 0.5 percent, subtracted 0.3 percent from fourth-quarter growth, while investment was mildly positive for the quarter. Fourth-quarter growth was restrained, by less than a quarter of a percentage point, by the impact from the number of working days effect, INSEE added.</p>
<p>Stock-building contributed 0.4 percent growth to the fourth quarter while it subtracted 0.6 percent from full-year GDP growth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
