<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="408734" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Mama Cash and Angels good for small businesses.</title>
<headline>Mama Cash and Angels good for small businesses.</headline>
<byline>Amelia Torres</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Getting banks to lend money to start a small business can be an uphill struggle. Add to the equation that the business is run by an ethnic minority female and the financing doors will remain irrevocably locked.</p>
<p>In the Netherlands, however, they found a solution: The Mama Cash Foundation.</p>
<p>Mama Cash does not provide eagerly sought loans but does offer guarantees to persuade bankers to finance women seeking to start a company without enough collateral.</p>
<p>This and other &quot;good&quot; practices developed throughout the European Union are described in a report by bankers and representatives of small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) presented on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll be sparing no effort to support and help SMEs,&quot; Christos Papoutsis, the European commissioner responsible for small businesses, told a news conference.</p>
<p>British bank National Westminster showed it has as much imagination as the Dutch, creating the NatWest Angel Service, a meeting point for potential investors and companies in need of capital.</p>
<p>Mediocredito Centrale's rating agency for Italian SMEs, Caixa Geral de Depositos's tool for identifying successful enterprises in Portugal and business competitions for Irish students are other ideas worth copying, the report says.</p>
<p>Of the more than 16 million companies in the 15-nation EU, only 15,000 employ more than 1,000 people.</p>
<p>This means that small and mediumn-sized firms are critical in the struggle to create the jobs Europe needs to reduce its 11 percent unemployment rate.</p>
<p>But banks usually get chilly about lending to new entrepreneurs or charge much higher rates than to established companies. This is all the more problematic because the great majority of SMEs -- around 80 percent -- rely on bank overdrafts and loans as the primary source of funding.</p>
<p>&quot;Banks have to try and make an effort to improve the general financing offer,&quot; the chairman of French bank Banques Populaires Jacques Delmas-Marsalet also told the conference.</p>
<p>He said banks had to build up personal relationships with small corporate customers to create a &quot;climate of confidence&quot;.</p>
<p>But Delmas-Marsalet also called on companies to be more transparent as the SME market was difficult and risky.</p>
<p>The round table of bankers and SMEs was set up in 1993 to identify and propose solutions to financing problems encountered by businesses. It is currently composed of 22 members from SME organisations and 15 banks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
