<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="408761" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Impoverished Bulgarians pessimistic on economy.</title>
<headline>Impoverished Bulgarians pessimistic on economy.</headline>
<byline>Elisaveta Konstantinova</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgarians are pessimistic about the country's economic prospects and their own living standards this year, a survey conducted by the National Statistics Institute (NSI) showed.</p>
<p>&quot;Pessimism dominates all consumers' forecasts and their confidence index, being eroded by economic hardship, has fallen threefold in two years,&quot; head of NSI Business Statistics Department Teofana Genova told a news conference on Thursday.</p>
<p>Some 90 percent of 1,156 people surveyed said their financial state worsened in the past year and 83 percent expected inflation to rise this year.</p>
<p>Economists predicted February inflation near 100 percent, up from 44 percent in January.</p>
<p>The survey also said forty-eight percent of those polled said they could hardly make ends meet in their family budget, every fourth Bulgarian is in debt and 71 percent have postponed indefinitely purchases of goods other than food and clothing, such as cars, television sets or washing machines.</p>
<p>Of those surveyed, 3.4 percent were optimistic about their finances this year, and 14 percent expected them to remain the same.</p>
<p>Only three percent said their financial state improved and seven percent said it was unchanged in the past year, the survey showed.</p>
<p>The NSI said incomes fell 21 percent in the past year. Dock workers had the highest state enterprise wage at 60,000 levs, while the average state wage was 20,000 levs.</p>
<p>The consumer confidence index (CCI), used by international statistics agencies to describe financial well-being expectations of households based on the country's general economic performance, has fallen from minus 24 percent in 1995 to minus 69.2 percent this year, said Genova.</p>
<p>Businessmen interviewed by the NSI saw Bulgaria's business climate worsening and expected transport and retail trade to shrink further. They attributed the insecure economic environment to company insolvencies and banks' narrowing markets and shrinking demand, said the NSI. --  Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E71">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
