<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40882" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Aid agencies welcome easing of Burundi sanctions.</title>
<headline>Aid agencies welcome easing of Burundi sanctions.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bigg</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.N. aid officals on Monday welcomed a decision by African countries to ease sanctions against Burundi, saying it had saved a programme to vaccinate nearly 200,000 children.</p>
<p>&quot;I am pleased because everything UNICEF was requesting has been accepted. Now we can save our vaccination programme for 1996 and that is a positive thing,&quot; said Michel Sidibe, Burundi representative for the U.N. Children's Fund in Bujumbura.</p>
<p>He said vaccinations for 190,000 children had been under threat as UNICEF lacked fuel to keep vaccines cold.</p>
<p>Burundi was placed under sanctions by regional states after Tutsi leader Pierre Buyoya, a retired army major, seized power and ousted the Hutu president in an army coup on July 25.</p>
<p>A regional sanctions committee said it agreed at a meeting in Tanzania on Friday to allow U.N. flights to Burundi, road access to the land-locked nation for staff and permission to import some fuel.</p>
<p>It cleared U.N. agencies to import baby food and other essentials for infants and hospital patients subject to &quot;strict verification and control arrangements.&quot; It also allowed imports of emergency medical and laboratory supplies and kerosene to keep vaccines cold.</p>
<p>But it said the steps should not undermine the &quot;essence of sanctions&quot; and noted Tutsi military ruler Pierre Buyoya had not met three conditions for ending sanctions -- restoring parliament, lifting a ban on political parties and immediate talks with Hutu rebel groups.</p>
<p>Sanctions have forced the army-appointed government to ration fuel and increasing prices of home-grown food because of higher transport costs.</p>
<p>More than 150,000 people have been killed in Burundi in a civil war and massacres since 1993, fuelling fears of bloodshed on a scale similar to neighbouring Rwanda's genocide in 1994.</p>
<p>Keeping up the pressure, Hutu rebels for a fourth time in two weeks destroyed a pylon for power lines to the capital, according to a senior official at the national power company.</p>
<p>Most of Bujumbura has had no power for two weeks. The power company produces only enough electricity for hospitals, water pumping and schools in the lakeside capital.</p>
<p>Martin Griffiths, director of the U.N. Department for Humanitarian Affairs, told Reuters in Nairobi the sanctions changes were very positive.</p>
<p>He said agencies might go back to the committee if there were other shortages -- such as food -- but for the moment the two main problems of fuel and access had been resolved.</p>
<p>The U.N. World Food Programme (WFP) said it was concerned about agriculture because imports of fertiliser and seeds were still banned. WFP Director Jean-Luc Siblot said that could make the majority Hutu population more dependent on aid.</p>
<p>&quot;The embargo on fertilisers stands and it will have dramatic consequences on agricultural production soon,&quot; Siblot said. Thousands of tonnes of fertiliser and seeds destined for Burundi are impounded at Tanzania's port of Dar es Salaam.</p>
<p>Buyoya said on Saturday Julius Nyerere, the international mediator on Burundi, had agreed to organise a regional summit. But Tanzanian officials said no date had been set and it was doubtful that members of Buyoya's government would be invited.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
