<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="408940" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FOCUS-Mayne outlook clouded by Optus.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FOCUS-Mayne outlook clouded by Optus.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian transport and health care group Mayne Nickeless Ltd said on Thursday it aimed to sell its stake in the nation's second telecommunications carrier by July, saying it needed to get its hands on that &quot;bag of gold&quot;.</p>
<p>Bob Dalziel, managing director of Mayne Nickless, which has a 25 percent stake in Optus Communications Pty Ltd, estimated to be worth about A$1 billion, made the remark after Mayne reported what it characterised as a reasonable half-year net profit.  </p>
<p>Net earnings after abnormal items fell 13.8 percent to A$43.14 million for the six months to end December, but managing director Bob Dalziel said the result hid a rise in underlying profitability and he forecast a strong full-year result.</p>
<p>&quot;We are seeing ourselves well placed now to have a very strong year result,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>But the result and bullish outlook were overshadowed by the financing of Mayne's Optus investment, which cost nearly A$20 million in interest payments over the half year and has, in the words of one analyst, become a noose around the company's neck.  </p>
<p>Dalziel said he had assured ratings agencies Standard and Poor's and Moody's Investors Service that Mayne aimed to sell its stake by July and virtually ruled out a float of Optus by then.</p>
<p>Until Optus was dragged late last year into a legal battle for control of its pay-television associate, Optus Vision, Mayne planned to dispose of the stake via a market float of Optus.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the float is relaistic in the short term unless we want to do it while litigation is occurring ... because our goal is to exit our Optus investment by June, July,&quot; Dalziel said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
