<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="409254" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tobishima plan under positive consideration--Fuji.</title>
<headline>Tobishima plan under positive consideration--Fuji.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fuji Bank Ltd, the main creditor bank for debt-ridden Tobishima Corp, said on Thursday that it believed other creditor financial institutions were positively considering the construction company's restructuring programme.</p>
<p>A Fuji spokesman said, however, that they had not yet reached any conclusions about whether or not they would accept the restructuring programme.</p>
<p>They are expected to inform Tobishima of their conclusion by the end of March, he said.  </p>
<p>There are about 50 creditors, including banks and life insurance companies, the Fuji spokesman said.</p>
<p>Fuji said earlier this month that it &quot;actively&quot; supported a restructuring plan worked out by Tobishima, adding that it was sure other creditors would also agree to the plan.</p>
<p>Japanese business daily Nihon Keizai Shimbun said on Thursday that Yasuda Trust and Banking Co Ltd had already decided to write off problem loans worth a total of 300 billion yen, including loans extended to the Tobishima group, in the year to March 31, 1997.</p>
<p>Yasuda Trust was not immediately available for comment.  </p>
<p>Tobishima drew up the restructuring plan last October in order to try to resolve its financial difficulties. Under the plan, its creditors would be asked to reduce their claims against Tobishima for debts owed by its group companies to 100 billion yen from about 740 billion yen.</p>
<p>Fuji Bank also said in October that it planned to set aside loan loss reserves against its loans to Tobishima in its earnings for the year to March 31, 1997.</p>
<p>The Nihon Keizai has said that Fuji Bank is expected to set aside loan loss reserves worth 100 billion yen to 150 billion yen in its 1996/97 earnings, but the bank declined to comment.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot comment on (a write-off of) Tobishima-related loans as the creditors have not yet reached a conclusion,&quot; the Fuji Bank spokesman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Nihon Keizai also said on Thursday that Japan's top 20 banks are set to write off a total of five trillion yen worth of problem loans in the year to March 31, 1997, including loans to Tobishima.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
