<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="40933" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Post-election breakdown would mean new war-Bildt.</title>
<headline>Post-election breakdown would mean new war-Bildt.</headline>
<byline>Mark Heinrich</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Carl Bildt, the international peace coordinator in Bosnia, warned on Monday that war would break out again if ethnic nationalist parties refused to share power after elections on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;If we don't implement the constitution (prescribed by the 1995 Dayton peace treaty), we are lost, and so is peace,&quot; Bildt told a news conference focusing on preparations for the fraught elections and the precarious period afterwards.</p>
<p>Bildt, international High Representative in Bosnia, laid out a tight autumn timetable for creating Moslem-Serb-Croat governing bodies following elections devised to reverse the Balkan state's carve-up by war.</p>
<p>Voters are to choose members of a three-person collective presidency, countrywide House of Representatives, assemblies for the Moslem-Croat federation and Serb republic, and cantonal councils in each entity.</p>
<p>The post-election period will be crucial in the implementation of the Dayton treaty, with the expiry of the NATO peacekeeping mission on December 20 looming on the horizon.</p>
<p>Bildt was repeatedly challenged as to how he could expect the factions to share power now after having violating basic provisions of Dayton so far, such as barring the return of war refugees, in order to cement division.</p>
<p>He responded that the Moslem-Croat and Serb entities in Bosnia would enjoy considerable autonomy.</p>
<p>&quot;What is necessary to make the peace agreement work is to have effective and true power-sharing. If this does not work, peace will not last,&quot; the former Swedish premier said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the constitution is very clear. Bosnia will be the most decentralised state in existence in the world.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the Serbs, whose ultra-nationalist leaders have campaigned for total independence and union of their territory with Serbia in defiance of Dayton, had committed themselves to Dayton's goals in talks with him and other envoys.</p>
<p>Bildt said Bosnia was in such dire economic straits that not even the most isolationist leaders -- an allusion to the Serbs - - could afford to defy the world's will for long, cutting off their people from foreign aid.</p>
<p>Any recalcitrant faction still bent on subverting Dayton's implementation would face strong international sanctions, Bildt said, without elaborating.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have a package of incentives and disincentives to use against those blocking implementation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The main Serb, Moslem and Croat nationalist parties ruling respective domains in Bosnia have repeatedly broken pledges in the Dayton accord meant as a framework for reconciliation.</p>
<p>There is little freedom of movement, association or media -- all essentials of democracy. Moderate opposition parties have been hounded and voter registrations manipulated.</p>
<p>Bildt said he expected envoys of the five-member Contact Group of Big Powers to visit Bosnia frequently after the elections to &quot;demonstrate the decisiveness of the international community if it's called for&quot;.</p>
<p>But at least one of the governing principles described by Bildt raised the spectre of political paralysis.</p>
<p>He said the presidency would take decisions based on unanimity. One member could block a decision if he judged it to threaten the &quot;vital interests of his people&quot;.</p>
<p>Bildt said international peace troops would be needed in Bosnia for at least another year after the mandate of the current 53,000-strong NATO-led force runs out in December.</p>
<p>&quot;The follow-on force must be a deterrent force against anyone contemplating a (renewed) military option in Bosnia. It will be a vital part of creating a climate of confidence to make the constitution work&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
