<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="409409" id="root" date="1997-02-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: INSTANT VIEW - French Q4 GDP rose 0.2 pct.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - French Q4 GDP rose 0.2 pct.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are analysts' comments on a 0.2 percent rise in French fourth quarter gross domestic product announced on Thursday.</p>
<p>The rise followed a revised 0.8 percent increase in the third quarter and gave full-year growth of 1.3 percent. Economists polled by Reuters had forecast fourth-quarter growth as being flat.</p>
<p>PAUL HORNE, SMITH BARNEY</p>
<p>I think (the figures) are without surprise...The effect of the end of the &quot;Juppette&quot; incentive to buy cars was rather substantial on domestic demand and household consumption.</p>
<p>The big news now is how the first quarter is shaping up...January household consumption was pretty weak excluding the rebound factor from the car scheme.  </p>
<p>SONJA GIBBS, NOMURA INTERNATIONAL</p>
<p>Although it is stronger than expected the downward revision to the third quarter evens it out. In terms of market impact, it's very hard for any piece of data, let alone backward looking data, to have much effect in the light of Greenspan yesterday.</p>
<p>It is in line with the perception of a somewhat stronger trend; it was not nearly as weak as many had thought it would be. There are clear signs of export-led growth, a classic style of recovery, and the early signs of recovery in the first quarter are fairly evident.&quot;</p>
<p>TREVOR WILLIAMS, LLOYDS TSB GROUP</p>
<p>Generally what was expected.... We should now concentrate on the first quarter of this year. This quarter is looking better than the last quarter so far and I think the growth rate for this year that the authorities in France are projecting, around two and a quarter percent, is something which is attainable.  </p>
<p>PHILIPPE BROSSARD, ABN AMRO FINANCE</p>
<p>They're good numbers, a bit stronger than consensus. One rather surprising thing is that it seems consumer spending declined by less than the spending on manufactured goods series suggested.</p>
<p>Another positive factor was stock-building, which contributed 0.4 (percentage points) to fourth-quarter GDP. It reflects better sentiment in the business sector.</p>
<p>The figures set a nice basis, technically, for 1997 growth and this combined with the stronger spending we've already seen, is supportive for first-half growth. I'm happy with my 2.8 percent forecast (for 1997).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
