<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="409698" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: TENNIS-HINGIS IS CENTRE OF ATTENTION ON RETURN TO SLOVAKIA.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-HINGIS IS CENTRE OF ATTENTION ON RETURN TO SLOVAKIA.</headline>
<byline>Jan Krcmar</byline>
<dateline>KOSICE, Slovakia 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Martina Hingis returned to her birthplace on Friday to play Fed Cup tennis but spent much of her time fending off questions about her private life.</p>
<p>The 16-year-old Australian Open champion had not been back to Kosice in 13 years, since her parents split up. She later left Czechoslovakia for a new life in Switzerland with her mother.</p>
<p>Hingis appeared at Friday's draw for the weekend Fed Cup world group tie between Switzerland and Slovakia with her mother, coach and team captain Melanie, who has resumed using her maiden name of Molitorova.</p>
<p>Hingis's father Karol, a groundsman and youth coach at a local tennis club, greeted the world number two at Kosice airport on Thursday with a kiss and a hug but was not present on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I have seen my father several times in the past but I'm not here as a private person but as a member of the Swiss team and my prime interest is to play tennis,&quot; Martina said in fluent Czech in reply to Slovak journalists' questions.</p>
<p>Molitorova, described by Ivan Lendl as the best women's coach in the world, criticised the choice of Kosice for the world group two first-round tie.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think this was the best choice of venue,&quot; she told a news conference. &quot;I was against Kosice from the start.&quot;</p>
<p>Mother and daughter tried to avoid other personal questions but, asked by one persistent reporter whether they felt more Swiss, Czech or Slovak, Molitorova replied with frosty sarcasm: &quot;Like Africans.&quot;</p>
<p>Hingis will open the tie on Saturday against Slovak number two Katarina Studenikova, while Slovak number one Karina Habsudova faces Switzerland's Patty Schnyder.</p>
<p>In Sunday's doubles at the indoor Kosice sports hall, Hingis and Schnyder play Slovak team captain Radka Zrubakova and Habsudova.</p>
<p>&quot;This will be a tough match but I'm confident we can win,&quot; Molitorova said after the draw.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KOSICE, Slovakia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
