<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="409837" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: CZECH RULING COALITION AGREES TO DEREGULATE RENTS.</title>
<headline>CZECH RULING COALITION AGREES TO DEREGULATE RENTS.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech ruling coalition agreed on Thursday to fully deregulate almost all rent-controls on housing by 2000, Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus told a news conference.</p>
<p>Only a small segment for socially disadvantaged residents would be kept under rent controls after 2000, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We would want to finalise the (housing) deregulation in the year 2000,&quot; Klaus said. &quot;That is a quite ambitious aim.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that an across the board rise for 1997 in controlled rents, ahead of full deregulation, would be discussed in a cabinet session on Friday.</p>
<p>In 1998, rents would be fully deregulated in communities with less than 10,000 inhabitants.</p>
<p>The deregulation steps would be included in a package of social assistance measures, including state promotion of new housing construction, Klaus said.</p>
<p>He did not elaborate on the details of the programme.</p>
<p>The decision came during a meeting of leaders of the three parties which make up the centre-right coalition government.</p>
<p>The parties agreed to make a joint decision on housing and energy deregulation policy in the coalition agreement which formed the government following 1996 general elections.</p>
<p>Concrete steps of the plan still require formal approval by the government.</p>
<p>The coalition leaders continued their meeting late on Thursday to discuss electricity, heating, and gas price deregualtion.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8500011">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
