<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="409811" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: PRESS DIGEST - RUSSIA - FEB 28.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - RUSSIA - FEB 28.</headline>
<text>
<p>IZVESTIA</p>
<p>- Russia is dramatically losing its influence over members of the Commonwealth of Independent States, says Valery Serov, Russia's  deputy prime minister in charge of CIS affairs.</p>
<p>- Russia's gold output may drop significantly if the practice of underpaying gold producers continues.</p>
<p>SEVODNYA</p>
<p>- The Russian gas giant Gazprom is to sign today a $2,5 billion agreement with a consortium of foreign banks to finance building a new transEuropean pipeline.</p>
<p>- According to the new Russian tax code control over individual tax payers will be tightened.</p>
<p>NEZAVISIMAYA GAZETA</p>
<p>- Russian President Boris Yeltsin, recovering from illness, expressed his discontent not only with the government but with his imagemakers who have allowed an image of a disabled president to emerge.</p>
<p>ROSSIISKIYE VESTI</p>
<p>- Despite negative public opinion, tough economic situation and common sense, Russia is to go ahead with a plan to build a new high speed rail road connecting Moscow and St Petersburg.</p>
<p>PRAVDA-5</p>
<p>- Major personnel reshuffle in the government and close presidential surrounding, expected to take place soon, have one obvious aim -- to relieve President Yeltsin of personal responsibility for disintegration of the country and collapse of its economy and army.</p>
<p>MOSKOVSKY KOMSOMOLETS</p>
<p>- General Viktor Chechevatov who is tipped by many to become the new Russian defence minister, is known as a team member of Pavel Grachev, the former country's defence minister.</p>
<p>-- Svetlana Kovaleva, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
