<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="409829" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - BULGARIA - FEB 28.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - BULGARIA - FEB 28.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>TRUD</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's Prime Minister Stefan Sofianski said he had send a letter to the Paris Club of official creditors asking it to roll over to next year up to $50 million of the country's debt payments due this year.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's caretaker cabinet raised electricity and coal prices 2.57 times from March 1.</p>
<p>-- The government raised telephone charges nearly seven-fold from March 1.</p>
<p>-- The cabinet raised petrol prices by an average of 10 percent and diesel prices by 2.8 percent, effective today.</p>
<p>-- Receipts from sales in Bulgaria's state industrial sector fell a real 4.0 percent in January against the same month last year, the National Statistics Institute said.</p>
<p>-- 24 CHASA</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria will receive 100,000 tonnes of wheat from Poland, probably in exchange for future exports, Bulgaria's President Petar Stoyanov said.</p>
<p>-- The Bulgarian National Bank raised its central interest rate to 18 percent monthly from 16.50 percent, effective March 1, due to an increase of the weighted average effective monthly yield of short-term government securities auctioned in the past month.</p>
<p>-- Incomes of Bulgarians fell 21 percent in 1996, National Statistics Institute figures showed.</p>
<p>-- At least 20,000 Bulgarians are heroin addicts, a Medical Academy Psychiatry Department official said.</p>
<p>-- The state Bulgarian Telecommunications Company (BTC) posted 3.2 billion levs profit in 1996, BTC executive director Marian Dragostinov said.</p>
<p>PARI</p>
<p>-- The private Bulgarian Investment Bank (BIB) posted 700 million levs pre-tax profit in 1996, BIB's executive director Gerasimos Tsiaparas said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's private Credit Express Bank shareholders approved a capital rise to 2.2 billion levs from 800 million levs to meet central bank minimum capital requirements for a full banking licence, to go in force from March 31.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's interim cabinet has arranged with some banks to sell foreign currency directly to large fuel importers in a bid to sustain a lev stability on the local forex market, the newspaper said without quoting sources. -- Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 981 8569</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
