<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="409937" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bid target Wascana's strategy on track - CEO.</title>
<headline>Bid target Wascana's strategy on track - CEO.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Jones</byline>
<dateline>CALGARY, Alberta 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wascana Energy Inc., facing a hostile C$1.7 billion ($1.3 billion) takeover bid from Talisman Energy Inc., can build on strong 1996 financial results with even more impressive gains this year, Wascana's chief executive said on Friday.</p>
<p>Frank Proto, head of Wascana, said the Regina, Saskatchewan-based company's two-year-old turnaround strategy of aggressive oil and gas drilling and land buying in western Canada was well on track.</p>
<p>&quot;This really began in 1995, the first year that Wascana replaced its annual production through the drill bit and that momentum just continued to grow and build during 1996,&quot; Proto said in a conference call.</p>
<p>&quot;It shows that the plan we put in place is working. It shows that it's one of the well-executed plans and it's getting results for shareholders.&quot;</p>
<p>Before Calgary-based Talisman announced the bid on Feb. 12, Wascana had suffered with lackluster stock market performance, but had recently been touted by analysts as a turnaround story.</p>
<p>The company, known for its extensive heavy oil production in the province of Saskatchewan, on Thursday reported sharply improved financial and operating results for 1996.</p>
<p>With its talk of future prospects over the past two days, Wascana appeared to be serving notice that it may not simply roll over for Talisman.</p>
<p>However, Proto said he was unable to discuss the takeover situation -- including whether Wascana was actively seeking out prospective white knights -- until the firm received and reviewed Talisman's formal bid document.</p>
<p>&quot;To date, no offer has been received and our board of directors will be meeting after that offer has been received to make those kinds of decisions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Talisman plans to offer C$18.50 ($13.69) cash or 0.41 of a Talisman share for each share of Wascana and is expected to mail its offering circular on Monday.</p>
<p>It would be the largest takeover since 1994 in a Canadian oil and gas sector currently frought with merger frenzy.</p>
<p>Proto said he expected Wascana's oil production to average 65,000 barrels a day in 1997, up from 51,400 barrels a day in 1996. Natural gas output was projected to average 235 million cubic feet a day in 1997, up from 200 million cubic feet a day in 1996. He also predicted dramatic gains in earnings and cash flow in 1997.</p>
<p>Talisman spokesman Dave Mann said his firm would likely be in a position to respond on Monday to any impact on its bid from Wascana's financial results and forecasts.</p>
<p>Wascana stock on the Toronto Stock Exchange closed down C15 cents (11 cents) on Friday to C$18.45 ($13.65). Talisman shed C30 cents (22 cents) to close at C$44.45 ($32.89).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY, Alberta"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
