<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410069" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Best Russian shares slip, buyers look for value.</title>
<headline>Best Russian shares slip, buyers look for value.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most of Russia's best shares slipped on Friday in lighter trade as investors shopped around for value, but natural gas monopoly Gazprom showed gains, traders said.</p>
<p>The Russian Trading System RTS 23-share index fell to 329.97 from Thursday's close of 337.38 on a moderate total market volume of $37.70 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Share prices are shaking into place a little bit,&quot; said Jim Nail, head of research at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;The market stabilised and consolidated and now investors are looking for relative value.&quot;</p>
<p>There were few bids for best shares like oil giant LUKoil and Moscow electrical utility Mosenergo, Trinfiko's Alexander Gritzkevich said.</p>
<p>LUKoil edged down to $14.82 from $15.15 at Thursday's close and Mosenergo slipped to $1.393 from $1.421. National telecoms firm Rostelekom  nudged down to $3.930 from 3.990.</p>
<p>Grigory Pinsky, senior trader at Trinfiko, said Gazprom rose on Thursday's news that the company planned to purchase a 25 percent stake in national electrical utility United Energy System (UES).</p>
<p>Gazprom closed up at $0.680 from $0.627. UES slipped to $0.2280 from $0.2315.</p>
<p>&quot;Only Gazprom was rising against the market,&quot; Pinsky said, adding he thought the uptrend would continue through next week.</p>
<p>Traders said Gazprom rose on chairman Rem Vyakhirev's published comments that foreign investors would be allowed to buy its domestic shares -- although many dealers were sceptical and cited later Gazprom comments that this was not true.</p>
<p>Oil company Surgutneftegaz  ordinary shares also edged up, to $0.821 from $0.800.</p>
<p>--Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
