<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410059" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: FOCUS - Hungary c.bank will cover Postabank cash calls.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Hungary c.bank will cover Postabank cash calls.</headline>
<byline>Duncan Shiels</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's central bank (NBH) on Friday backed assurances by the Finance Ministry and Postabank officials that the Postabank was not in danger of collapse despite panic withdrawals by customers and said the NBH would be open at the weekend to provide cash coverage.</p>
<p>&quot;The National Bank of Hungary wishes to reinforce statements made today by Postabank Rt, the State Banking and Capital Markets Supervision and the Finance Ministry that Postabank's financial state and liquidity enables it to meet its obligations,&quot; the NBH said in a statement.</p>
<p>The statement added that due to the &quot;rather large movements of deposits&quot; that may be expected over the next few days the NBH will assure supplies of cash to commercial banks throughout the weekend.</p>
<p>Thousands of people queued outside branches of Postabank, one of Hungary's largest banks, on Friday to withdraw their money on rumours that the bank had been hit by big losses.</p>
<p>Postabank officials said earlier the branches would remain open on Saturday to deal with the rush.</p>
<p>&quot;This wave surprised, appalled us,&quot; said Postabank chairman Gabor Princz, adding that some of the branches may run out of money temporarily, and this may lead to conflicts with the clients, but the bank would be able to supply the branches with cash continuously.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope that people will cool in a few days, when they see that we are paying and there is no trouble,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On Budapest's OTC market on Friday, brokers were offering to buy ordinary Postabank shares at 10-15 percent of their face value Hungary's economic news agency MTI-Econews reported.</p>
<p>However, investors wanting to dump their holdings were probably unable to find takers, it added.</p>
<p>The face of value ordinary Postabank shares is 10,000 forints ($56.99).</p>
<p>The panic withdrawals from Postabank may have been triggered by the government's political opponents and by competitors, the Finance Ministry said earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;We have the fairly well-justified suspicion that this was an organised action against the bank,&quot; Finance Ministry political Secretary of State Laszlo Akar said.</p>
<p>&quot;This came after the agricultural demonstrations, in a time when the situation is tense,&quot; he said. &quot;You should think about if such large coincidences can happen.&quot;</p>
<p>Thousands of farmers blocked lanes on several of Hungary's main roads from Monday in a protest against tax burdens.</p>
<p>It was the most serious demonstration against the Socialist-Liberal government coalition since the election held in 1994.</p>
<p>But the ministry, banking authority officials and Postabank management all denied Postabank was in difficulty -- even with the run on deposits -- and told a hastily gathered news conference that Postabank will be able to pay out all its clients.</p>
<p>Imre Tarafas, chairman of the State Banking and Capital Markets Supervision, said Postabank's financial situation could not justify the panic withdrawals.</p>
<p>A regular supervision investigation at the bank in the second half of 1996 did not find any irregularities which could threaten the bank's safe operations and Postabank was able to pay out its depositors, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Postabank has assets of 70 billion forints which can be liquidated quickly and also further moveable assets,&quot; he said, adding he did not see a chance that the supervision should freeze Postabank's accounts.</p>
<p>Princz said Postabank kept retail deposits totalling 200 billion forints. He also said Postabank has created all the provisions needed for safe banking operations and still posted profits.</p>
<p>He added that Postabank boosted its assets by 40 percent last year, moving up from the number three to second position in Hungary, and had four million deposits in a country which has a population of slightly more than 10 million.</p>
<p>Princz said Postabank was aware of rumours circulating about its difficulties in the past few weeks.</p>
<p>He added that such rumours had appeared several times since the bank was founded nine years ago, but they had never experienced such panic withdrawal as now.</p>
<p>Gabor Princz said a competitor bank reduced its lending ceiling to Postabank on the interbank market recently -- a possible sign of falling confidence in the bank.</p>
<p>Other banking industry sources told Reuters they had heard reports that Postabank recently was trying to cut costs, including reducing its number of mobile phones, which may have been interpreted as a sign of financial trouble. ($ = 175.4 Hungarian Forints)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
