<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410098" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian stocks mixed, seen declining.</title>
<headline>Croatian stocks mixed, seen declining.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks were mixed in a meagre trade on Friday and market participants said slow trade and lower prices would dominate the following week.</p>
<p>&quot;There are fewer and fewer buyers and I think that most prices will keep sliding the next week,&quot; one trader with a large market share told Reuters.</p>
<p>Seven of 14 active issues rose, six fell and one was flat. Turnover dipped to 3.8 million kuna on a slightly smaller volume of 7,114 shares.</p>
<p>Traders said latest unrest in the neighbouring Bosnia helped weaken the demand. One man was killed and two dozen wounded in the worst incident since the end of war in the southern town of Mostar two weeks ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Situation in Bosnia regularly affects the situation on Croatian capital market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Friday's biggest decliner was confectioner Kras, dipping 45 kuna to 475 kuna on volume of 147 shares.</p>
<p>Another food firm Podravka, the most active stock at the moment, sold 3,165 units, closing five kuna higher at 310.</p>
<p>Fully-listed drugs company Pliva, which was absent form the market on Thursday, closed 10 kuna lower at 460 kuna on volume of 544 units.</p>
<p>Blue chip Zagrebacka Banka ordinary shares declined 20 kuna to 1,720 on volume of 783.</p>
<p>Hotelier Istraturist, adding 15 kuna to 220 on 603 units, led the gainers. The other four active hoteliers traded mixed with small changes in prices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
