<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410091" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo Zastava mulls JV with Hyundai Motor Company.</title>
<headline>Yugo Zastava mulls JV with Hyundai Motor Company.</headline>
<byline>Gordana Kukic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Zastava group, Yugoslavia's biggest manufacturing company, confirmed on Friday that it was negotiating a joint venture with the South Korean Hyundai car maker.</p>
<p>&quot;I have nothing to add to the statement issued by Hyundai Motor Company. I can just confirm we are negotiating on a joint venture,&quot; Srboljub Vasovic, Zastava Group chief executive, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Before the break-up of former Yugoslavia five years ago, Zastava, which makes Yugo cars, was one of the country's main hard-currency earners.</p>
<p>War-related sanctions and mismanagement have pushed the company to the verge of collapse, cutting production to 10,000 vehicles in 1996 from 200,000 in 1990.</p>
<p>It is searching for foreign investors to provide capital and to revitalise production.</p>
<p>&quot;The Zastava car plant is not for sale. We just want to capitalise and, on the basis of the amount of money invested, to establish proper business relation with foreign partners,&quot; said Slobodan Radovic, the Group's vice-president and marketing director.</p>
<p>He said Zastava was negotiating with two potential partners and both talks were in the same phase. &quot;We have already established general business plans and targets and it is up to to the foreign partners to decide,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Radovic, one of Zastava's negotiating team which visited South Korea in February, said the plant was expected to raise its output to 150,000 cars by the year 2001.</p>
<p>&quot;Our plan is to launch two new models and to modernise both the engine and the body of our latest Florida model launched in 1988,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He refused to give details of the level of investments but described them as significant, adding: &quot;Zastava is not cheap.&quot;</p>
<p>Hyundai this week issued a statement saying it was negotiating a joint venture with Zastava.</p>
<p>&quot;Further details of the joint venture will be released as soon as possible and it is anticipated this will be no later than the end of August 1997,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Industry analysts were doutbful that any foreign partner would be willing to invest in Yugoslavia while political, economic and legal conditions remained unstable.</p>
<p>&quot;No firm political decision has been taken yet to cut with the socialist past and embark on the path of reforms and market economy,&quot; one analyst who asked not to be named said.</p>
<p>-- Belgrade Newsroom ++381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
