<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410061" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELARUS: U.S. slams Belarus over democracy, human rights.</title>
<headline>U.S. slams Belarus over democracy, human rights.</headline>
<byline>Yuri Svirko</byline>
<dateline>MINSK 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States slammed Belarus on Friday for failing to preserve democracy and human rights and said it was telling investors to put money into nearby countries instead of the former Soviet republic.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States has consistently aimed to promote stability, democracy, a market-oriented economy and respect for internationally-recognised principles of human rights in Belarus,&quot; said a statement faxed to Reuters by the U.S. embassy in Minsk.</p>
<p>&quot;Belarus... increasingly isolated itself from the international community and reduced the scope for constructive relations with the United States,&quot; it said, adding that Washington would provide no further aid to Minsk.</p>
<p>The statement marks a further downturn in already strained relations between the two countries.</p>
<p>Washington has repeatedly criticised Belarus and last year granted asylum to two of its nationalist leaders who said they were escaping persecution by hardline President Alexander Lukashenko, in power since mid-1994.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. government will encourage U.S. investors to explore other nearby countries, due to the risks of doing business in a country lacking adequate checks and balances,&quot; the embassy's statement said.</p>
<p>Lukashenko, whose aim is to bring his country closer to Russia, won a referendum last November on a new constitution which granted him sweeping powers but which has been criticised by human rights bodies for being authoritarian.</p>
<p>Belarus' Foreign Minister Ivan Antonovich told a news conference during a two-day visit to neighbouring Ukraine that Minsk was preparing its reply to the U.S. State Department.</p>
<p>&quot;Some conclusions were based on lack of information,&quot; he said. &quot;We'll send an answer based on a tradition of good relations with the United States. Our relations have been developing normally.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier this month the Council of Europe said Belarus' new constitution failed to meet minimum standards of human rights. Europe's top security body, the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), has also urged Minsk to abide by democratic principles.</p>
<p>Since the referendum Lukashenko, who has kept tight state control over the economy by fixing prices and regulating the currency, has formed a hand-picked two-chamber parliament and has taken away mandates from opposition deputies.</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) suspended credits last year but the World Bank recently resumed its economic programme in the land-locked country of 10 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINSK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELARUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
