<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410144" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: FOCUS - Czech parties take steps to free prices.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Czech parties take steps to free prices.</headline>
<byline>Nigel Stephenson</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czech coalition parties have agreed steps to free up prices controlled since the Communist era in a move that analysts said was likely to raise inflation but reduce consumer spending.</p>
<p>The three ruling parties agreed late on Thursday to remove controls on housing rents by the year 2000 for all but the most socially disadvantaged.</p>
<p>The industry and trade ministry also said on Friday they had agreed to raise value added tax (VAT) on gas and electricity to 22 percent from five percent on July 1.</p>
<p>&quot;The minister (Vladimir Dlouhy) told me this morning that the agreement would be to raise (energy) prices by increasing the VAT,&quot; industry and trade spokesman Miroslav Konvalina said.</p>
<p>The government was meeting on Friday to discuss details of the rent increase, which will hit many Czechs still living in apartments with fixed low rents and energy bills subsidised by industrial users.</p>
<p>Deregulation remains one of the most sensitive political issues in the Czech Republic and as a key item of unfinished business in the country's transition to a market economy.</p>
<p>Some economists say artificially low prices leave Czechs with relatively high disposable incomes that fuel demand for consumer goods and contribute to a widening trade gap.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be some upward pressure on inflation,&quot; said Citibank economist Radek Maly, adding he expected an increase of between 50 and 100 percent in rents this year.</p>
<p>&quot;My forecast for inflation is around 8.7 percent, pretty much like last year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Average annual inflation last year was 8.8 percent and the central bank has cautioned against excessive rises in regulated prices, saying this could push inflation beyond forecasts.</p>
<p>Both the Civic Democratic Party (ODS) of Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus, the senior coalition party, and Dlouhy's pro-business Civic Democratic Alliance support an overall 35 percent rise in energy prices for this year but had been split before the talks on the VAT increase.</p>
<p>The ODS wants to raise taxes to boost budget coffers and the ODA wants the extra revenue to go to energy companies.</p>
<p>&quot;They are trying to boost budget revenues with higher energy taxes to cover the necessary social compensation for the rent hikes,&quot; said Zivnostenska Banka analyst Jindrich Weiss.</p>
<p>He expected an overall energy price rise of 30 percent and that this would add two percnetage points to 1997 inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;I would expect, based on this latest information, year-on-year inflation at the end of the year will be around nine percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It will mean a little bit lower consumption of other goods, it will put pressure on consumer psending but on the other hands there will be some transfer due to social compensation.&quot;</p>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Josef Lux of the centrist Christian Democrats, the third coalition group, told a news conference after the Thursday meeting that party leaders would meet within two weeks to discuss increases in household energy prices and rents.</p>
<p>The parties in the minority government agreed to make a joint decision on housing and energy deregulation policy in the coalition agreement under which the administration was formed after the 1996 general election.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
