<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410243" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Capitalist aficionados celebrate Cuban cigars.</title>
<headline>Capitalist aficionados celebrate Cuban cigars.</headline>
<byline>Frances Kerry</byline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Affluent capitalist cigar buffs are meeting in Havana this week to revere a luxury product made by one of the world's last remaining communist states.</p>
<p>Some 700 aficionados including about 100 U.S. citizens are attending celebrations to mark the 30th anniversary of a cigar many consider the finest you can get, the Cohiba.</p>
<p>The highlight of the event organised by Cuban state cigar export company Habanos S.A. is a $500-a-plate gala dinner at Havana's Tropicana nightclub on Friday night. Many with tickets were hoping President Fidel Castro would attend.</p>
<p>Guests -- foreign cigar importers, cigar aficionados, business people and specialist journalists -- travelled to the Vuelta Abajo plantations in western Pinar del Rio province, where gnarled farmers tend each tobacco leaf like porcelain.</p>
<p>On Friday morning, they toured the elegant colonial mansion in Havana where Cohiba cigars are painstakingly hand-rolled. The employees, mostly women, smiled as smartly clad guests peered over their classroom-style wooden desks. One said they earn less than $15 a month, about the price of one Cohiba cigar abroad.</p>
<p>Castro, who gave up smoking several years ago, ordered production of the Cohiba cigars for his personal use three decades ago. They used to be given as gifts to visiting foreign leaders but were made available commercially beginning in 1982.</p>
<p>&quot;The Cohiba is the unassailable symbol of the Havana cigar, it has romance, aroma,&quot; enthused David Tang, the Hong Kong-based owner of Pacific Cigar, which imports Cuban cigars to Asia. &quot;The Cohiba is the Ferrari of cigars.&quot;</p>
<p>The guests chomping on them this week include a sizeable U.S. contingent but not the clutch of Hollywood film stars such as Jack Nicholson and Arnold Schwarzenegger orginally billed by some foreign media as due to attend.</p>
<p>Nobody seemed quite sure if the big names were invited and declined because of the U.S. economic embargo that includes restrictions on travel by U.S. citizens to Cuba or if they were never invited in the first place.</p>
<p>John Kavulich, an American who heads a New York-based information centre called the U.S.-Cuba Trade and Economic Council, told reporters he believed the majority of the U.S. citizens attending were here legally -- either on &quot;hosted&quot; trips that they have not paid for or because they obtained licenses to visit, for example as journalists with cigar magazines.</p>
<p>Why go to the trouble and expense of attending?</p>
<p>&quot;Because cigar smokers are a different breed,&quot; Kavulich said. &quot;Like scuba divers who will go to the ends of the earth for the best dive, they will go anywhere for the best cigar, or the best cigar event, which at the moment is in Havana, Cuba,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Cuba has long produced what are viewed as the world's best cigars. They are currently the island's fifth largest export, earning more than $100 million a year.</p>
<p>This falls short of meeting world demand for Cuban cigars -- estimated at some 120 million cigars a year -- but is up from a low of about 50 million cigars produced in 1993, when Cuba was suffering the worst of an economic crisis caused by the demise of the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Output rose to some 70 million last year, Francisco Linares, president of Habanos S.A., said. Cuba aims to produce some 100 million cigars this year and steadily increase output to some 200 million by 2000, he added.</p>
<p>The revival has been partly due to pre-financing arrangements worth more than $30 million a year for input such as fertilisers and pesticides for the plantations, provided by importers against guaranted supplies of cigars. Companies with such arrangments include Spanish state tobacco monopoly Tabacalera S.A., France's Seita, Britain's Hunters &amp; Frankau and Hong Kong's Pacific Cigar.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
