<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410241" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Pemex union says content with petchem sale plans.</title>
<headline>Pemex union says content with petchem sale plans.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The mighty union of Mexico's state oil monopoly Petroleos Mexicanos (Pemex) is content with the nation's partial petrochemical privatization, but plans to ask for greater investment in maintenance, the union's spokesman Victor Garcia said on Friday.</p>
<p>The union's vocal opposition was one of the driving forces behind the government's retreat last year on plans to privatize the petrochemical industry.</p>
<p>Under pressure, it scrapped its plans for a full-scale sell-off, and decided to limit the privatization of its 10 plants to a minority stake.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have the peace of knowing we have preserved what for us is vital; the patrimony will not leave the hands of the people, the real owners of the nation's petroleum,&quot; Garcia told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>He added that any further privatization of the oil industry, long considered a stronghold of national pride, was unlikely because of &quot;how politicized the issue became.&quot;</p>
<p>The union holds five positions on Pemex's 11-member board of directors, and can mobilize the company's almost 130,000-member work force.  </p>
<p>This week the union signed wage accords with Pemex that guarantee four more years of the same collective contracts, he said. After 2000, the new petrochemical plants can decide whether or now to renew the contracts.</p>
<p>Garcia agreed with government predictions that private capital in the industry should boost output, and in turn greater demand for jobs.</p>
<p>Despite the union's acceptance of the petrochemical sale, the union's leader, Sen. Carlos Romero Deschamps, plans to ask for a portion of Pemex's almost 70 percent in taxes to be set aside for maintenance improvements.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have said the fiscal regime impedes growth...and we think five to ten percent (of taxes) or so ought to be saved for maintenance,&quot; Garcia said.</p>
<p>Pemex officials and analysts have agreed the company has neglected maintenance and technological improvements, specifically in its refining and petrochemical units. The company has instead focused its resources on boosting exploration efforts, analysts said.</p>
<p>((--Timna Tanners, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-7903))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
