<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="41036" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Nationalist parties dominate Bosnian elections.</title>
<headline>Nationalist parties dominate Bosnian elections.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bosnia's three main nationalist parties, all formed in the run-up to 1990 elections, are expected to dominate the country's September balloting.</p>
<p>The three parties made common cause against the Yugoslav communist party in 1990 elections, split in the run-up to Bosnian independence and became enemies during the Bosnian war.</p>
<p>Analysts say there are two main opposition parties worth watching on September 14.</p>
<p>PARTY OF DEMOCRATIC ACTION (SDA) - Moslem nationalist party, led by Alija Izetbegovic, which dominates most of the 51 percent of Bosnia held by Moslem-Croat federation. Izetbegovic formed the SDA in 1990 after being released from jail as a political prisoner. During the Bosnian war the SDA preached multi-ethnicity and the need to maintain the integrity of the country's borders as a single, sovereign state.</p>
<p>In peace, the SDA has done little to promote the multi- ethnic ideal whose banner it once waved. Control over police and state media on much of Moslem-Croat federation territory gives the SDA a huge advantage among Moslem voters in the elections.</p>
<p>Critics say the SDA is authoritarian at best and Moslem fundamentalist at worst.</p>
<p>SERB DEMOCRATIC PARTY (SDS) - Serb nationalist party which dominates the 49 percent of Bosnia known as the Serb republic.</p>
<p>The SDS was formed on July 12, 1990 and led by Radovan Karadzic for six years until he was forced from power by the international commnity on account of having been twice indicted for war crimes.</p>
<p>Karadzic was replaced as chairman of the SDS by Aleksa Buha. The party maintains a mono-ethnic, anti-Dayton, separatist stance which it expects Serb voters to ratify.</p>
<p>The SDS has used its tight hold on the police, media and economy to silence any political opposition.</p>
<p>Analysts believe the SDS will win the vote in the Serb republic but possibly by a low margin. If true, that could loosen its grip on the Bosnian Serb Parliament and lead to a softening of its policies.</p>
<p>CROAT DEMOCRATIC UNION (HDZ) - Croat nationalist party which dominates in the rocky western region of Bosnia known as Herceg Bosna.</p>
<p>The HDZ is the Bosnian wing of the nationalist party which has ruled neighbouring Croatia since 1990.</p>
<p>The Bosnian HDZ has its own party hierarchy but the real leaders are Croatian President Franjo Tudjman and Defence Minister Gojko Susak, a Bosnian Croat. A Bosnian Croat militia loyal to the HDZ and armed by Susak carved out the breakaway state of Herceg-Bosna during Bosnia's war and drove out non-Croat inhabitants, mainly Moslems.</p>
<p>The HDZ rules Herceg Bosna like an extra-territorial province of Croatia although the fief is to be abolished shortly through a U.S.-brokered deal aimed at reintegrating Bosnia.</p>
<p>Running on an anti-Moslem platform of Croat sovereignty, the HDZ seems poised to sweep the elections in Herceg Bosna.</p>
<p>PARTY FOR BOSNIA HERCEGOVINA (SBIH) - Main opposition party on Moslem-Croat federation territory, led by former Bosnian prime minister Haris Silajdzic.</p>
<p>The SBIH campaigns in favour of a unitary, multi-ethnic Bosnia but depends almost entirely on Silajdzic's personal popularity for its appeal. An Islamic scholar, Silajdzic is an articulate and convincing opponent of what some see as the SDA's drift towards Moslem fundamentalism.</p>
<p>Silajdzic has little hope of capturing the Moslem seat on the new collective Presidency but could draw enough votes from Izetbegovic to leave a Serb the top vote-getter and thereby Chairman of the body.</p>
<p>The former prime minister and his party are viewed as strong contenders for the 1998 elections.</p>
<p>SOCIALIST PARTY OF THE SERB REPUBLIC (SPRS) - Main opposition party in the Serb Republic. Headed by Zivko Radisic, a career politician and former communist party member, the SPRS is the Bosnian Serb affiliate of Slobodan Milosevic's Socialist Party in neighbouring Serbia. Milosevic spilt with the SDS over the Dayton peace deal, which he supported, and is thought to want a more reliable political party to deal with in the Serb republic.</p>
<p>Centred in Banja Luka and strongest to the west of Brcko, the party is counting on a strong vote from the several hundred thousand Bosnian Serb refugees living in Serbia who allegedly have been well-organized by Milosevic.</p>
<p>SPRS candidates have been harassed, attacked and removed from their jobs by the long arm of the SDS during pre-election campaigning.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
