<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410444" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks extend losing streak to third day on Greenspan effect.</title>
<headline>Stocks extend losing streak to third day on Greenspan effect.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks ended lower for the third day in a row Friday as the market remained under a cloud following Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan's comments about high stock prices and hints about an interest rate hike.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average closed down 47.33 points at 6,877.74. For the week, the index lost 53.88 points.</p>
<p>In the broader market, declining issues beat advances 1,454 to 1,027 on active volume of 508 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Many technology stocks were under selling pressure, but shares in some key leaders in the sector managed to rally.</p>
<p>But by and large, analysts said the market remained under a pall that was unlikely to lift before Greenspan's second round of testimony next Wednesday to the House of Representatives.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll have to see what happens after everybody absorbs his next comments,&quot; said Edgar Peters, chief investment strategist at PanAgora Asset Management Inc. &quot;I think we'll have a lot of sideways volatility for the time being.&quot;</p>
<p>For now, analysts said, the wind is clearly out of the stock market's sails, which leaves the sentiment-sensitive sectors like technology that bounded higher in January on heavy fund inflows and high optimism, particularly vulnerable.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Greenspan rattled the stock market as he spoke in surprisingly blunt terms of his concerns in his semi-annual report on the economy to the Senate, about the risks of inflation as well as the dramatic increase in stock prices.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there's still more to work out for the techs,&quot; said Grace Messner, vice president of equity management at Wilmington Trust. &quot;A lot of the stocks are still extremely expensive.&quot;</p>
<p>Networking stocks met with another session of stiff selling, as investors reassess the former high-flying group. Ascend Communications Inc. fell 4-3/4 to 52-1/4 and Bay Networks Inc. shed 1/4 to 19-1/8.</p>
<p>Industry leader Cisco Systems Inc. closed up 9/16 to 55-5/8, however, one of several blue-chip tech stocks to show signs of recovery.</p>
<p>Among the weakest Dow components was drug giant Merck &amp; Co., which lost 1-3/4 to 92-1/8. Other decliners among pharmaceutical stocks included Pfizer Inc., down 3/4 to 91-5/8 and American Home Products Corp., down 5/8 to 64.</p>
<p>J.P. Morgan &amp; Co. Inc. fell 2-1/8 to 105, and Citicorp fell 2-5/8 to 116-3/4.</p>
<p>Fleet Financial Group Inc. bucked the trend, however, rising 1-1/2 to 61 on speculation about a possible merger with NationsBank Corp.  Late in the day, Fleet said it knew of &quot;no corporate developments&quot; to account for its stock's activity. NationsBank, which fell 1-1/4 to 60, declined comment.</p>
<p>In individual issues, Cigna Corp. rose 1/4 to 152-7/8 after announcing an agreement to acquire Healthsource Inc. for $21.75 a share. Healthsource gained four to 20-7/8.</p>
<p>General Cigar Holdings Inc. jumped five to 23 in the cigar maker's debut on the NYSE following its six million share initial public offering.</p>
<p>Ford Motor Co. said it would sell up to 20 percent of its Hertz car rental unit through an initial public offering. Shares in Ford closed unchanged at 32-7/8.</p>
<p>Intuit Inc. fell 2-3/4 to 22-5/8 after the financial software company said it expects slowing sales for at least the next two quarters.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index fell 3.66 points to 1,309.00.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks lost 4.25 points at 790.82. The American Stock Exchange index slipped 0.93 to 594.24.</p>
<p>The NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks fell 2.38 to 415.51. The average share was down 25 cents.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 7,559.418 down 43.173 or 0.57 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
