<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410452" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Summit to acquire Collective Bancorp for $867 million.</title>
<headline>Summit to acquire Collective Bancorp for $867 million.</headline>
<byline>Cal Mankowski</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Summit Bancorp said Friday it agreed to buy rival Collective Bancorp Inc. for $867 million in stock, solidifying its role as the biggest banking company in New Jersey.</p>
<p>&quot;The acquisition of Collective further secures Summit's number one market share position in New Jersey, especially in the growing shore markets,&quot; Summit Chairman T. Joseph Semrod said in a statement announcing the deal.</p>
<p>&quot;The acquisition of Collective will afford Summit a strategic position in South Jersey that the company already enjoys in the northern and central regions of the state.&quot;</p>
<p>Summit, based in Princeton, N.J., has $23 billion in assets and $18 billion in deposits. Collective, a thrift holding company based in Egg Harbour City, N.J., has $5.5 billion in assets.</p>
<p>Analysts agreed that the move will solidfy Summit's leading position in the state but they said it may also make the company a more attractive takeover candidate in the rapidly consolidating banking and financial services industry.</p>
<p>&quot;This is definitely a positive for Summit. I like the transaction and I think it's perfectly in line with their strategy of making themselves the premier player in the New Jersey-Pennsylvania marketplace,&quot; Robert Bonelli, executive vice president of Ernst &amp; Co., said.</p>
<p>But the deal could make Summit an appealing target for another, bigger bank, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If I were an acquirer -- say NationsBank Corp. coming up from the South or someone coming from the Midwest -- and I wanted to have a New Jersey-Pennsylvania presence, beyond any shadow of a doubt it's Summit,&quot; Bonelli said.</p>
<p>Salomon Brothers analyst Michael Plodwick also said the acquisition would make Summit a more attractive target.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like the best franchise available in the region,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Summit, with 350 branches in New Jersey and eastern Pennsylvania, will add 82 branches in 15 New Jersey counties with the Colletive acquisition, which has been approved by the boards of both companies and is expected to close in the summer.</p>
<p>A Summit spokeswoman said the bank holding company planned to continue its growth in New Jersey through further acquisitions.</p>
<p>&quot;Our acquisition strategy has been and continues to be to pursue in-market acquisitions that will enhance our franchise,&quot; spokeswoman Barbara Horn said.</p>
<p>She added, however, that Summit has a policy of not commenting on particular deals that may be in the works.</p>
<p>Under the Collective deal, that company's shareholders will receive 0.895 share of Summit stock for each share of Collective in a tax-free swap.</p>
<p>Based on the closing price of $47.625 for Summit common stock Thursday, the transaction has a value of $42.51 per Collective share, or a total of about $867 million, according to the announcement.</p>
<p>Summit said it will incur a one-time after-tax restructuring charge of about $33 million in connection with the acquisition.</p>
<p>The company did not comment on the possibility of job losses resulting from the Collective deal.</p>
<p>Horn noted, however, that Summit currently has about 400 job openings, including mid-management positions. She also said the company was planning to open 70 branches inside supermarkets in the next 18 months.</p>
<p>Summit stock rose 25 cents to $47.75 in late New York Stock Exchange trading. Collective fell87.5 cents to $41.125 on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>The decline in Collective's stock was attributed at least in part to a run-up in the price apparently in anticipation of a deal, analysts said.</p>
<p>Summit grew out of the merger in which Princeton, N.J.-based UJB Financial Corp. acquired a New Jersey bank known as Summit in early 1996 and took the Summit name.</p>
<p>The company also has discount brokerage operations in New York and Connecticut.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
