<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410424" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey continues Iran gas bid despite row, US.</title>
<headline>Turkey continues Iran gas bid despite row, US.</headline>
<byline>Ercan Ersoy</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey is going ahead with a multi-billion-dollar project to buy Iranian gas despite a diplomatic spat with its neighbour and efforts by the United States to stop the deal, an energy official said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We need energy and natural gas. Iran is the nearest source for that,&quot; said Ugur Dogan, energy ministry undersecretary, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The project is going ahead as scheduled and the initial part of the pipeline construction will be started by Turkey and Iran simultaneously in April,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Turkey and Iran signed the 23-year, $23-billion agreement in August to transport gas from Iran through a $1.1-billion, 1,420-km (890-mile) pipeline which will eventually extend from Tabriz in Iran to the Turkish capital Ankara.</p>
<p>State pipeline concern Botas received 14 valid bids on Friday from mainly local companies for the initial 300-km (188-mile) section of the pipeline from the Iranian border to the eastern Turkish city of Erzurum. The lowest bid, made by a local consortium, was $117.6 million.</p>
<p>Iran and Turkey must each build the section of the pipeline through their territories separately to avoid breaching a U.S. ban in August ruling that investors putting more than $40 million in energy projects in Iran or Libya would be punished.</p>
<p>Iran was also working on a 270-km (169-mile) pipeline from Tabriz to the Turkish border to link up with the Turkish section.</p>
<p>Dogan said Turkish state minister Abdullah Gul and energy officials were told by the U.S. administration in talks last week in Washington that Turkey should seek gas from sources other than Iran, which it called a &quot;false security&quot; for Turkey.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. has some reservations about the Iranian deal and suggested we go for alternatives other than Iran,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But in view of our energy needs Iran is the most viable resource. But the political issue is another matter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Relations between Turkey and Iran have been strained since the army sent tanks on manoeuvres through the Ankara district of Sincan on February 4 following an Islamist protest there attended by the Iranian ambassador.</p>
<p>The foreign ministry said on Thursday it was expelling Iran's consul to the eastern town of Erzurum, following his criticism of apparent anti-Iranian comments by a leading Turkish military official.</p>
<p>The announcement added to a diplomatic row between Tehran and Ankara, which protested to Iran earlier this month about the Iranian ambassador's comments at the Sincan rally.</p>
<p>Iran and Turkey had agreed in December during a visit by Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani to Turkey that the two countries should boost political and economic relations benefiting from a rapprochement towards Iran from the Islamist-led coalition government, in power since June.</p>
<p>A foreign ministry official said if the Iranian deal annoys Washington further some difficulties might arise for Turkey's state pipeline company Botas when it goes out to international creditors for project loans.</p>
<p>But Botas officials said transporting gas through pipeline from Iran is some 30 percent cheaper than the alternative of buying it in liquefied natural gas (LNG) form from Algeria or other suppliers.</p>
<p>The gas agreement envisages Turkey initially buying two billion cubic metres (bcm) annually from 1998 through the pipeline for Erzurum city. The supplies will gradually reach 10 bcm by 2005. The pipeline will extend to Ankara later.</p>
<p>The initial supplies will consist of gas from Turkmenistan transited through Iran.</p>
<p>--Ankara Newsroom, 90-312-4462940</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
