<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410436" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Centennial shareholders left without market.</title>
<headline>Centennial shareholders left without market.</headline>
<byline>Michael Ellis</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Centennial Technologies Inc. investors were left scratching their heads Friday, wondering how to trade their shares after the company is delisted from the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Centennial shares fell 50 cents to $3 on volume of more than 4.8 million shares in their last day of trading on the NYSE.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying our best to find a new home,&quot; Centennial spokeswoman Cheryl Byrne told Reuters. &quot;We will make the appropriate announcements when we can.&quot;</p>
<p>The interim chief executive told Reuters earlier in the week that Centennial would not seek another stock exchange listing until after it had complete financial statements.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to me the onus is on the company in some way to line up some sort of avenue to trade the stock,&quot; said a partner at an investment management firm that tracks the company.</p>
<p>Both the American Stock Exchange and Nasdaq said they would not allow the stock to be traded based on the financial statements available publicly.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on what we've seen, the lack of reliable financial statements prevents us from even determining if they meet our listing qualifications,&quot; Cameron Brown, a Nasdaq spokeswoman, said.</p>
<p>Centennial said on Thursday that it would restate its financial statements for the last 3-1/2 fiscal years to show a net loss rather than a total net profit of $12.1 million.</p>
<p>The Billerica, Mass.-based maker of personal computer memory cards said it would take six to 12 weeks before it would be able to restate the statements, leaving many wondering how long before the company is relisted.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know if trading is halted for 12 weeks or six weeks until their financial statements are out,&quot; the investment management partner said. &quot;Maybe they just want to kind of disappear off into the sunset.&quot;</p>
<p>He said there was talk among brokers of Centennial possibly trading on the OTC Bulletin Board or the pink sheets. But no bulletin board market makers have applied to trade Centennial, Nasdaq's Brown said.</p>
<p>Centennial founder Emanuel Pinez was dismissed as chief executive earlier this month and subsequently charged by the Securities and Exchange Commission and the U.S. Attorney's office with insider trading and falsifying sales figures.</p>
<p>Pinez was denied bail and has been held in a Plymouth, Mass., jail. He has denied any wrongdoing.</p>
<p>Centennial's share price, which jumped more than fivefold in 1996, has slid from $55 at the beginning of the year to a recent low of $1.75.</p>
<p>An SEC source said Centennial would still be considered a public company subject to U.S. securities laws even if it did not trade on an exchange.</p>
<p>One holder of about 10,000 shares said he planned to keep his Centennial stock even if the NYSE delisting made it difficult to trade.</p>
<p>His hopes were raised by comments by Pinez's replacement, interim Chief Executive Lawrence Ramaekers, in an interview with Reuters earlier this week. Ramaekers said Centennial's sales were strong despite the turmoil surrounding the company and its customers were staying, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I got to believe the company is still viable,&quot; he said. &quot;I think there's a lot to be optimistic about.&quot;</p>
<p>Still, some brokers who follow the company wondered if the slew of shareholder lawsuits filed against the company would hobble its performance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
