<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410563" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TransTexas has new natgas field.</title>
<headline>TransTexas has new natgas field.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>TransTexas Gas Corp said Friday its O.H. Acom Gas Unit 1 well in Chambers County, Texas discovered a new natural gas field.</p>
<p>The well, which began flowing to sales on December 24, is flowing at a sustained production rate of 22.5 million cubic feet of natural gas and 334 barrels of condensate per day on a 32/64-inch choke with flowing tubing pressure of 4,000 pounds per square inch.</p>
<p>TransTexas said it expects the field to add additional natural gas production and reserves in the near to mid-term.  </p>
<p>The Acom Gas Unit 1 was drilled to a total depth of 10,752 feet and encountered net pay of 92 feet in the Frio formation, in a gross interval between 8,700 and 10,550 feet.</p>
<p>The company said development drilling in the field, where it has a 100 percent working interest, started in late December. The second well, the Acom Gas Unit 2 is now undergoing completion for production and the Acom Gas Unit 3 is drilling at 9,700 feet depth.</p>
<p>TransTexas said it has an immediate five well development drilling program in the new field and expects these development wells to each add incremental production similar to the initial discovery well. The second and third wells are expected to be flowing to sales by the end of March.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
