<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410501" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</title>
<headline>Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain and oilseed exports reported by USDA and private export sources.</p>
<p>CORN SALE - Private exporters reported the sale of 101,600 tonnes of U.S. corn to Japan for delivery during the 1996/97 marketing year, Agriculture Department said Friday.</p>
<p>CORN, CORN/SOY BLEND, RICE SALE - The CCC said it purchased a total of 32,380 tonnes of commodities under an invitation for supplies for export to North Korea. It bought 20,780 tonnes of U.S. yellow corn, 5,000 tonnes of corn/soy blend and 6,600 tonnes of milled rice. The commodities were for shipment before April 1.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDERS - Japan will re-tender for 20,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat and 20,000 of Canadian barley on March 6. The agency bought 180,000 tonnes of wheat and 60,000 of barley on Thursday, but it did not purchase 20,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat and 20,000 of Canadian barley due to price.</p>
<p>- Results were awaited on Peru's tender for 25,000 tonnes of optional-origin spring or hard red winter wheat for last-half April shipment, exporters said. One exporter said Argentina had been expected to make the sale, but results were pending.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDER - The European Union has not yet set a date for fixing the details of a tender to import 300,000 tonnes of high quality wheat at zero tariff, such as the split between durum and soft wheat, and the number and timing of tranches, a European Commission official said.</p>
<p>BARLEY TENDER - Jordan is currently negotiating a deal with Syria to buy at least 100,000 tonnes of black barley, traders said. A delegation headed by Jordan's Minister of Supply Munir Sobar left for Damascus on Wednesday to conclude the deal. Jordan's last deal with Syria was in December when it bought 100,000 tonnes at $138 per tonne FOT.  </p>
<p>MARKET TALK - Indications are that Egypt has bought between 60,000 and 70,000 tonnes U.S. hard red winter wheat on Wednesday in a private sale, several U.S. exporters said. One position of 30,000 to 35,000 tonnes was slated for last half June and the balance was set for last half July, they said.</p>
<p>... The Australian Wheat Board said Friday it had signed an agreement to sell a minimum of 900,000 tonnes of wheat to Japan's Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry and Fisheries during 1997.</p>
<p>((Chicago newsdesk 312-408 8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
