<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410533" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar ends mixed amid doubts about Europe plan.</title>
<headline>Dollar ends mixed amid doubts about Europe plan.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar ended weaker against the yen but modestly higher against the mark Friday amid growing doubts about Europe's plan to establish a single currency by 1999.</p>
<p>Talk of a delay in the timetable for a single currency spread through the market after Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi said in a television interview that Germany might ask that the start of the monetary union be rescheduled.</p>
<p>Though the German Finance Ministry later denied any plans to change the launch date, Prodi's comments weighed heavily on the market's psyche, sweeping the mark higher against the currencies of many of its European neighbours, particularly the Italian lira.</p>
<p>The lira fell to its lowest level against the mark in over three months, rising above the 1,000 per mark barrier despite reports that the Bank of Italy was actively selling marks for lire in an effort to defend its currency.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is clearly concerned about the timing to monetary union,&quot; said Dennis Pettit, foreign exchange manager at Long Term Credit Bank of Japan.</p>
<p>The mark tends to benefit at the expense of other European currencies when doubts about the planned single currency surface because it has less to gain from the project.</p>
<p>While traders bought the mark against other European currencies Friday, they sold the German currency against the yen, which benefitted from renewed hopes for a recovery in the Japanese economy.</p>
<p>Bank of Japan Governor Yasuo Matsushita said in a speech Friday that Japan's economy is gradually recovering.</p>
<p>He also noted that Japanese private consumption was on an upward trend and a recovery in capital spending was spreading to many areas of industry.</p>
<p>Buying of yen pushed the mark to its lowest level against the Japanese currency in eight months and led the dollar lower against the yen.</p>
<p>The dollar dipped below the 120 yen level for the first time in a month, ending the session at 120.23 yen against 120.67 late Thursday. The yen's gains against the mark helped the dollar edge up to 1.6903 marks against 1.6880 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Traders said they remained optimistic about the dollar despite Friday's mixed showing.</p>
<p>&quot;It's no reason to change the view that the dollar is going up,&quot; said Hans Boman, chief spot dealer at Swedbank.</p>
<p>In other trade, the Mexican peso ended higher against the dollar after the U.S. government recertified Mexico as an ally in the war on drugs.</p>
<p>The peso had come under pressure earlier in the week on fears that U.S. decertification would hurt the Mexican economy.</p>
<p>The dollar ended at 7.94 pesos, down from 8.00 pesos in early trade.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the dollar rose to close at 1.4783 Swiss francs against 1.4737 on Thursday. The British pound rose to settle at $1.6295 against $1.6257 late Thursday, and the dollar ended little changed at Canadian $1.3680 versus $1.3683.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
