<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410601" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FCOJ futures close lower, focus on nearby spread.</title>
<headline>FCOJ futures close lower, focus on nearby spread.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>FCOJ futures closed lower for the third consecutive session as speculators continued to roll long March positions into May ahead of first notice day Monday, analysts said.</p>
<p>The nearby spread narrowed to 2.70 cents from 3.05 cents. Open interest, meantime, fell 1,160 lots to 3,830 lots in March from the previous close.</p>
<p>May ended down 1.20 cents to 79.10 cents per lb, having ranged from 80.10 to 78.60 cents. Spot March settled 0.85 lower at 76.40 cents.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at a brisk 6,300 lots compared with Thursday's official volume of 5,004 lots.</p>
<p>High inventory and sluggish weekly movement coupled with a negative fundamental picture, could keep the market under considerable near-term pressure, analysts said.</p>
<p>Thursday, the Florida Citrus Processors Association put inventory at 147.314 million gallons and weekly movement at 4.946 million gallons, for the week ended February 22.</p>
<p>Support was seen between 74.00 cents and 72.00 cents in March. &quot;There will be more buying interest (in March) if the market gets below that level,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>May's downside target was pegged at 77.00 cents, with eventual support seen at 66.00 cents in May based on Elliott Wave theory.</p>
<p>((Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodity Desk 212-859-1646))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
