<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410604" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USDA takes CRP bids starting next week.</title>
<headline>USDA takes CRP bids starting next week.</headline>
<byline>Charles Abbott</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Farmer sign-up for the revamped Conservation Reserve was set to begin Monday amid concerns by conservation and agribusiness groups over whether the program would work properly.</p>
<p>The skeptics worried that too much land was eligible and time too short for the Agriculture Department to select the U.S. farm land that would benefit most from enrollment.  </p>
<p>Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman said Friday USDA would try to enroll as much land as it could, but &quot;I've never said we're going to necessarily enroll 22 million acres the first year.&quot;</p>
<p>Contracts on 22 million acres of land already in the reserve were due to expire September 30, setting the stage for a potentially vast turnover in enrollments. By law, up to 36.4 million acres of environmentally fragile land could be held in the reserve.  </p>
<p>&quot;This is going to be a few years in the making before you get up to 36 million,&quot; Glickman told reporters.</p>
<p>In a satellite hook-up with a convention of corn and soybean farmers, Glickman promised smooth handling of the sign-up and decision-making. He also told farmers there would be no one-year extension of current contracts -- &quot;not even an option in my book&quot; -- despite congressional suggestions.</p>
<p>Signup ends March 28. USDA officials set a goal of deciding by early June which land to accept.  </p>
<p>For the most part, USDA has declined to say how much land it would seek from the sign-up. It has projected that enrollment, now at about 33 million acres, would dip to 30.3 million acres in fiscal 1998 before rebounding to 34.1 million acres in fiscal 1999 and 36 million acres in 2000.</p>
<p>At a House Agriculture subcommittee hearing this week, the American Farmland Trust, a land preservation group, suggested a gradual start to rebuilding the reserve. Some eight million to 10 million acres could be enrolled this spring, it said, with another round of bids requested later in the year.</p>
<p>The Coalition for a Competitive Food and Agricultural System, a coalition of agribusiness groups, said several signups might be needed to identify land with the greatest need.</p>
<p>To be eligible, land must have an erodibility index of eight under a USDA formula or be in a priority conservation area. The goals of the reserve were to reduce soil erosion, protect water purity and enhance wildlife habitat. Bids will be rated under a formula that takes into account rental rates, location and environmental benefits.</p>
<p>Created in 1985, the Conservation Reserve pays farmers an annual rent for idling fragile land for 10 years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
