<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410728" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Commission plays down Anglo's Lonrho stake report.</title>
<headline>Commission plays down Anglo's Lonrho stake report.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission on Friday played down a press report saying the EU was set to ban Anglo American of South Africa Corp from keeping a 28-percent stake in Lonrho Plc, arguing it was too early to make any conclusions.</p>
<p>A Commission spokesman recalled reporters that the Commission's objections about Anglo taking control of Lonrho were well known even before the South African mining giant effectively increased its stake in November from an initial 10 percent.</p>
<p>It was up to Anglo to provide &quot;remedies&quot;, he said, declining to elaborate on what the company could propose to assuage the EU's worries about fair competition.</p>
<p>&quot;The ball is in their camp...we'll see if they can come up with remedies we can accept,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Financial Times said on Friday that the Commission was about to inform Anglo of its objections, but the spokesman said they were sent weeks ago.</p>
<p>The Commission has until May 5 to take a final decision, following the opening in December of an in-depth investigation into Anglo's stake in the British-based conglomerate.</p>
<p>It said at the time it feared Anglo's control of Lonrho could lead to a dominant position in the platinum and rhodium markets, two precious metals used in the manufacture of car catalytic converters to reduce gas emissions.</p>
<p>Industry sources and lawyers well versed in EU competition law say there are only two things Anglo could do: convince Lonrho to sell its platinum interests or reduce its shareholding.</p>
<p>In April last year, the Commission blocked the merger of the platinum interests of Lonrho and Gencor also of South Africa because the market would be dominated by a duopoly -- Anglo is the world's only other largest platinum producer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
