<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410774" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch shares end weak near lows, Unilever suffers.</title>
<headline>Dutch shares end weak near lows, Unilever suffers.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares ended weak on Friday, dragged down late by a drop on Wall Street to end near session lows. Brokers said the market was out of energy after recent upward sprint, with room for more losses next week.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is tired after a lot of good news,&quot; one said. &quot;The downmove isn't finished yet.&quot;</p>
<p>The AEX index closed down 9.69 points, 1.30 percent, at 737.46. The Midcap AMX index dropped 21.06, 1.88 percent, at 1100.53.</p>
<p>Unilever suffered a second day of stiff losses as more investors locked in profits and the stock, which has prospered on strong U.S. buying lately, was hit by worries there about the consumer products sector, dealers said.</p>
<p>Unilever shed 8.90 guilders to end at 361.80, almost five percent off a record high of 380.30 set on Wednesday.</p>
<p>ABN AMRO retreated further after Thursday's results, right on estimates, and amid lingering unease over a board resignation linked to an insider trading case, dealers said. The stock lost 3.70 guilders to 136.30.</p>
<p>On the rise were aluminium and steel concern Hoogovens, which gained 1.20 guilders after announcing the closure of a long-awaited deal with Belgian steel firm Boel, and airline KLM which added 1.50 guilders to 58.20.</p>
<p>KLM refused to confirm or deny that current talks with partner Northwest could lead to a divestment of its 18.8 percent stake in return for a long-term alliance commitment.</p>
<p>Electronics firm Getronics retreated despite posting a 35 percent rise in net profit in 1996. Getronics shares lost 3.00 guilders, 4.62 percent, as the results failed to hit high-end estimates.</p>
<p>Chemicals firms DSM and Akzo Nobel had conflicting fortunes, DSM rising 1.50 guilders on upgrades after its recent results and Akzo falling 5.50 after its own figures on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
