<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410868" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Joint chair again for India's two airlines.</title>
<headline>Joint chair again for India's two airlines.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's two national fleets are expected to move into an aggressive climb with the appointment of Indian Airlines chief PC Sen as chairman of both state companies.</p>
<p>Sen is managing director of Indian Airlines and already chairman of its board. His office said Thursday he would formally take over the Air India (AI) chair from the beginning of March.</p>
<p>Sen, an outspoken career civil servant and former Director General of Civil Aviation, has turned around the formerly troubled Indian Airlines against stiff private opposition.</p>
<p>There was speculation last year about Air Indian taking over Indian Airlines, but some commentators said the opposite should happen. Air India's operational chief remains Mr B Kumar. The two ailines had a joint chairman in business magnate R Modi until he resigned in December 1996.</p>
<p>One move which should emerge is a streamlining of operations links between the two airlines as far as overseas cargo and passenger traffic is concerned.</p>
<p>Indian Airlines' cargo capacity is mainly limited to the belly of its A300 and Boeing 737 passenger planes. Freight carried, including excess baggege, in the year to end-March 1996 totalled 93,430 tonnes. But its reach is still the biggest in India and could raise Air India's share of import and export cargo through the transit hubs which is dominated by foreign airlines.</p>
<p>Mr Sen is known to believe that a national airline should serve the whole country and not cherry-pick, reaching the remote routes such as the northeast. He has achieved a turnaround of the business, as well as meeting that &quot;social&quot; obligation and responding to overseas crises, where large numbers of Indian nationals may have been stranded.</p>
<p>Indian Airlines flies to 17 regional foreign destinations, including the Gulf and Far East, with a fleet of more than 50 Airbus 300s and 320s and Boeing 737s.</p>
<p>Air India's fleet at around 26, plus some wetleasing, has more or less equal numbers of Airbus 300s and Boeing 747s. A major fleet purchase decision between Airbus and Boeing has been in the pipeline since early last year. - Reuters Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax:5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
