<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="410916" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: INSTANT VIEW - Indian budget package.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - Indian budget package.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are analysts comments on the 1997/98 (April-March) Indian budget package announced by Finance Minister P. Chidambaram:</p>
<p>UDAY KOTAK, HEAD, KOTAK MAHINDRA</p>
<p>I think the budget is truly path-breaking. It has dramatically changed the norms of the way in which the government is looking at the financial industry and the capital markets.</p>
<p>The Finance Minister is giving very strong signals in the budget that he is very, very concerned at the way the stock markets have performed and a lot of measures which he has announced are extremely positive for the markets.  </p>
<p>ASHISH KACHOLI, HEAD OF RESEARCH, PRIME SECURITIES</p>
<p>I think it is a landmark budget. He is continuing the process of reform. The market will take this very positively, extremely bullishly.</p>
<p>He is putting money directly into the pockets of investors by cutting direct taxes. It will jump start investment.  </p>
<p>T.M.M. NAMBIAR, MANAGING DIRECTOR, ASSOCIATED CEMENTS</p>
<p>In general, budget is very positive -- especially the steps on reducing corporate tax and removal of the surcharge irritant and removal of double taxation on dividends.</p>
<p>We would have been happy to see the MAT go.</p>
<p>There are no specific steps in this budget that will help the cement sector. Port-based plants importing coal will get some relief following reduction of import duty to 10 percent from 20 percent.</p>
<p>GIRISH DESAI, HEAD OF RESEARCH, PRABHDAS LILLADHER</p>
<p>This is a path-breaking and market friendly budget with a number of incentives for the corporate sector. It will certainly boost economic activity.</p>
<p>It satisfies the market, industry and trade. However, it goes half-way on the insurance sector because it has not opened it to foreign firms.</p>
<p>I personally feel the market is in for a bull run.  </p>
<p>V.S. BAPNA, DIRECTOR, ISPAT INDUSTRIES</p>
<p>Overall, he (the finance minister) has done a good job. I think the slowdown (in Indian industry) will be arrested. The results should be visible in the next two to three months. It will fuel growth in the months to come.  </p>
<p>DINSHAW IRANI, HEAD OF RESEARCH LLOYDS SECURITIES</p>
<p>It is a very market-friendly budget but has not done enough for infrastructure or industrial growth. The market may rally, but I see it tapering off in six months. As of now he has kick-started the economy, but what we need is growth.  </p>
<p>V.S. PALEKAR, PRESIDENT OF BOMBAY CHAMBER OF COMMERCE AND INDUSTRY:</p>
<p>&quot;We were all pleasantly surprised. This will definitely change the languishing mood in the economy, in particular the reductions in corporate taxes, personal income tax and excise duties. These will help revive the capital markets, an urgent need.</p>
<p>But one disappointment is that nothing has been done to revive the primary markets.</p>
<p>There is also no mention of insurance privatisation which would have been a major step in boosting the economy.</p>
<p>The tax on services is also quite steep and given the importance of the services sector to the economy, the economy may be affected in the long run.</p>
<p>Overall we feel it is a pragmatic budget which has definitely made some moves to revive the economy.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>MUKESH GUPTA, MANAGING DIRECTOR, LLOYDS STEEL</p>
<p>This is one of the best budgets in recent times. The amendment on MAT is a welcome move. Positive steps include reduction in personal income tax, permission to buy back shares and raising of ceiling in shareholding by FIIs and OCBs to 30 percent from 24 percent.</p>
<p>The negative point of the budget is that excise duty on steel industry has been retained at 15 percent.  </p>
<p>S.M. DATTA, CHAIRMAN, CASTROL INDIA:</p>
<p>Basically, it is an excellent budget. He (Chidambaram) had limited leeway and he has made the most of it to have maximum impact on the economy as well as to indicate commitment to the Common Minimum Programme and the requirements of the World Trade Organisation.</p>
<p>Where reversal of the economy's slowdown is concerned, a good deal will depend on the rate of agricultural growth. The hope is that good agricultural growth will lead to a revival of demand which will stimulate economic growth.</p>
<p>One point to be noted as far as development is concerned, the onus of funding the plans has now shifted to the states. It all depends how they get things going.</p>
<p>Chidambaram is faced with the problem of improving both tax and non-tax revenues. He has shown buoyant revenues so far and hpoes that lower tax rates will lead to higher revenues.  </p>
<p>JAMSHYD GODREJ, MANAGING DIRECTOR, GODREJ AND BOYCE MANUFACTURING CO LTD.:</p>
<p>The budget is a good one. It is growth-oriented. The reduction in corporate and personal taxes is an excellent development. The modifications in customs duty and excise duty will lead to a spurt in demand.</p>
<p>The growth targets will be achieved by expanding economic activity over a wide spectrum. Many provisions and promises will improve the investment climate in years to come.</p>
<p>.  </p>
<p>BIR D SINGH, DIRECTOR &amp; EXECUTIVE VICE-PRESIDENT, VOLTAS LTD.:</p>
<p>The budget aims at broadbasing growth. Incentives in the form of lower personal and corporate taxes will result in better savings and investment climate. The fiscal deficit is still high at more than 4.5 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>In our air-conditioning industry, lower excise duties will help growth.</p>
<p>.  </p>
<p>R.K. PITAMBER, MANAGING DIRECTOR, MAHINDRA &amp; MAHINDRA LTD:</p>
<p>&quot;The move to reduce excise duties is welcome. But how is he going to neutralise revenue loss from this. I do not know how he's going to do this.</p>
<p>The move to abolish tax on dividends is also welcome. The move on MAT is also good and it seems we are moving towards an American system when you can offset your tax after five years.</p>
<p>I think the moves in this budget will stimulate demand for steel products, and generally the economy should pick up.</p>
<p>But on the infrastructure sector, he mentioned only telecommunications. There was nothing on roads, power or other sectors.</p>
<p>One of the things that's worrying me is the promise to amend FERA, the Companis Act, and the Land Ceiling Act. He made promises in the last budget but political circumstances prevented him from fulfilling these. Will this happen again?</p>
<p>I do not know how realistic the fiscal deficit projections are. We have to wait and see after the final figures are in.</p>
<p>But it will be great if he does keep to these figures.</p>
<p>I think industrial growth will get back to last year's figures by next year.</p>
<p>I think the tax on services is retrograde. This is going to hurt a lot of people.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>VINOD DOSHI, CHAIRMAN, THE PREMIER AUTOMOBILES LTD.:</p>
<p>My first guess is that the stockmarkets should be flying right now.</p>
<p>I think the budget is a very major step forward in various areas. Very clearly the reforms are now being brought down to the common man more and more.</p>
<p>It has taken some clear steps forward -- insurance, the convertibility of the rupee, a wide reduction in tax on salary income, dividend tax removal.</p>
<p>The most significant thing that he has done is income coming back from abroad at a 30 percent flat rate of tax with no questions asked. Since 77 percent of this will go to the states, he's asking chief ministers to go out and do things to attract this money back.</p>
<p>It's a masterstroke in my opinion.</p>
<p>.  </p>
<p>HARISH MARIWALA, MANAGING DIRECTOR, MARICO INDUSTRIES LTD.:</p>
<p>Overall, it's far bolder than expected. The direct tax proposals are a big step forward. Fiscal deficit under control is a pleasant surprise.</p>
<p>The reduction in customs and excise duty should spur investment. Dividend tax reduction should help capital markets.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>JOHN M. LIND, CHIEF EXECUTIVE OFFICER, HUGHES ISPAT LTD.:</p>
<p>The incentives for infrastructure development were as expected. There is a continuous progress towards the controlled liberalisation of the economy. On a positive note, I applaud the Finance Minister's efforts on tax reform.</p>
<p>However, I believe additional incentive for foreign investment could have been provided.</p>
<p>.  </p>
<p>M.J. SHAIKH ALI, DIRECTOR, THERMAX LTD.:</p>
<p>It's a positive budget, especially in the realm of direct taxes as also in increased allocations for the rural and social sector.</p>
<p>For capital goods, the Finance Minister has not been very kind. While the import duty for capital goods has come down to 20 percent the steel duty remains virtually unaffected, adversely affecting the domestic capital goods industry.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>NIRMAL BATLIBOI, MANAGING DIRECTOR, BATLIBOI &amp; CO. LTD:</p>
<p>Excellent budget overall. It sends out the right signals to growth. It continues the process of liberalisation. While I welcome all import duty reductions, I'm disappointed that steel duties were not reduced.</p>
<p>I welcome the reduction in taxes -- both corporate and individual.</p>
<p>.  </p>
<p>R.H.PATIL, MANAGING DIRECTOR, NATIONAL STOCK EXCHANGE:</p>
<p>Overall the budget is good and looks pragmatic.</p>
<p>The decision to abolish tax deducted at source on government securities is a good move and should boost trade in gilts. But for the retail market to take off we need a depository participant kind of arrangement where the bank holds gilts on behalf of the retail client.</p>
<p>The fiscal deficit figures are a puzzle to me given all these concessions on the revenue front. I don't know whether he is assuming a big spurt in revenue. I do not know how he can keep the tax-GDP ratio so low. We have to see the full budget document before coming to a conclusion.</p>
<p>The capital market will gain a lot. Whatever the market has been asking for has been given to it. Although MAT has not been abolished, he has given a tax benefit to be carried over.</p>
<p>There is no specific move for the primary market. But once the secondary market improves, automatically the primary market will revive.</p>
<p>We were looking for Sec 80M benefit for mutual funds. But once tax on dividends is gone, it is effectively the same.</p>
<p>Last year we saw FII inflows of $3 billion. This year we should see a 30 percent spurt to at least $4 billion.</p>
<p>.  </p>
<p>KANTIKUMAR R.PODAR, EX-PRESIDENT, FEDERATION OF INDIAN CHAMBERS OF COMMERCE AND INDUSTRY:</p>
<p>Excellent budget. I compliment the Finance Minister for meeting expectations of all sections of the community, viz., be it industry, business, common man and even the share market.</p>
<p>* Lowering of Income tax and Corporate tax as well as abolition of dividend tax are bold steps. It confirms his faith of better tax compliance by having moderate taxes. I am sure, countrymen will not let him down.</p>
<p>* A very practical solution has been found to the complex issue of MAT. It should satisfy by and large all sections of business and industry.</p>
<p>* Reduction of excise and customs duty has been done judiciously and should help industry. He has not compromised on the social sector. On the contrary has provided larger resources for most of them.</p>
<p>* Buy back of shares and increase in inter-corporate investment and lending limits is heartening.</p>
<p>* To contain deficit to 4.5 percent is very commendable and I am confident that this will be achieved with larger growth and good receipts from Voluntary Disclosure Scheme.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>K.B.DADISETH, CHAIRMAN, HINDUSTAN-LEVER LTD.:</p>
<p>Reduction and simplification of both corporate and personal tax rates are welcome measures and will lead to better compliance.</p>
<p>Focused measures to increase foreign institutional investment, abolition of surcharge on corporate tax, reduction in corporate tax, lowering of interest tax and abolition of double taxation of dividends will boost capital formartion and encourage savings and investment.</p>
<p>Modifiction of MAT in an innovative manner will ensure revenue needs while removing the hardships faced by industry and exporters.</p>
<p>Maintaining the fiscal defecit at five percent of the GDP in the previous year and expressing confidence to reduce it to 4.5 percent in the coming year shows a commendable degree of fiscal discipline.</p>
<p>Overall I am certain that in this year's budget the Finance Minister has not only carried forward the reform process, begun in 1991, but has provided a new momentum. This reconfirms the broad political consensus on the reform process. It will result in rapid and broad-based growth.</p>
<p>.  </p>
<p>MADAN GOPAL DAMANI, PRESIDENT OF THE BOMBAY STOCK EXCHANGE:</p>
<p>Both me and my markets are very happy. It has been duly recognised by the government at the highest levels that investors are very improtant for the growth of the economy.</p>
<p>This is the first time that so much has been done for investors in one budget. It is a bright future for industrial growth because of vibrant capital markets.</p>
<p>The markets have risen sharply today. What is more important is that it should be sustained.</p>
<p>The markets will continue to be buoyant and there is no doubt that the trend has been reversed by the budget.  </p>
<p>.</p>
<p>DINESH VYAS, MEMBER, CENTRAL BOARD OF DIRECT TAXES:</p>
<p>The move to reduce taxes, corporate and personal, are good and are bound to have a positive effect on the capital market.</p>
<p>Though the voluntary disclosure scheme looks necessary in the short term, I am not happy for the long term. Basically we are having a premium on dishonesty.</p>
<p>This is about the fifth time we are having such a scheme in the last 20 years. We are basically encouraging the people with black money.</p>
<p>The move to revive the capital market is motivated, with an eye on future public sector disinvestment.</p>
<p>The disappointment is that many promises (already made) are not fulfilled and fresh ones are given. Neither (of the changes promised in) the Companies Act nor FERA is yet in place. We were told the Income-Tax Act would be in place by December 1996.</p>
<p>Now we are told to wait until the monsoon session of Parliament. Similarly there is a promise on the Urban Land Ceiling Act. All these promises build up a rosy picture. But the real test of the budget lies in how far these will be implemented.</p>
<p>.  </p>
<p>V.N.DHOOT, MANAGING DIRECTOR, VIDEOCON INTERNATIONAL LIMITED:</p>
<p>The consumer durable industry will benefit as a result of the 10 per cent reduction in customs duty in electronic components. The industry will benefit after a period of long stagnation.</p>
<p>Infrastructure sectors like telecom, power and roads will receive a boost from the budget proposals.</p>
<p>The budget should have announced more incentives for exporters and definitive steps should have been accelerated towards attaining full convertibility. A definite formula should have been spelt out do away with the oil pool deficit.</p>
<p>Increase in fertiliser subsidy is welcome and the budget is a brilliant exercise in balancing amid difficult economic scenario.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>MR.ASHWANI WINDLASS,MANAGING DIRECTOR, HUTCHISON MAX TELECOM</p>
<p>Overall a very pragmatic budget.</p>
<p>It is the best budget that an emerging economy can think of, given the current economic challenges. Revival of the economic growth and focus of infrastructure augur well for telecom companies who have invested heavily and have huge potential for further investment.</p>
<p>One of the biggest threats to infrastructure including telecoms has been a less buoyant economy faced with recessionary trends and therefore questionable GDP growth.</p>
<p>He has made clean and sweeping changes in direct and indirect taxation while diluting protection required to sustain Indian industry in the overall reforms exercise. One hopes that in the details of the notifications,there is relief on cellular/paging hardware import and manufacturing duties.</p>
<p>.  </p>
<p>E.A. KSHIRSAGAR, DIRECTOR-IN-CHARGE, A.F. FERGUSON &amp; CO.:</p>
<p>Upbeat and friendly. It should prove a boon to the economy. The reduction of direct taxes both industrial and corporate are excellent. There is now or should be, no excuse for tax evasion.</p>
<p>Indirect taxes -- clear and even-handed.</p>
<p>.  </p>
<p>SHASHI RUIA, CHAIRMAN, ESSAR GROUP:</p>
<p>It is very encouraging that the Finance Minister has undoubtedly shown his will to maintain and carry forward the pace of econmic reforms.</p>
<p>This reflects the strong commitment on the part of the government of India in proving to the world that the Indian economic and social reforms are being accelerated.</p>
<p>The series of measures announced by the government focuses on growth of oil sector, energy exploration, refining sector and telecom sector through an excellent package relating to direct taxes and streamlining the Companies Act, along with FERA reforms, thus attempting to put Indian companies on a more solid global footing.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
