<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="411086" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: HA-LO says Montgomery Ward sales not predictable.</title>
<headline>HA-LO says Montgomery Ward sales not predictable.</headline>
<dateline>NILES, Ill. 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>HA-LO Industries Inc, which distributes specialty and premium advertising products, said Friday sales under an exclusive merchandising agreement with Montgomery Ward are &quot;not predictable.&quot;</p>
<p>HA-LO entered into an exclusive agreement in January 1995 to provide premium products to Montgomery Ward. In 1996, those sales were about $40 million.</p>
<p>Members of HA-LO management met with the newly appointed chief executive officer of Montgomery Ward this week, the company said.  </p>
<p>HA-LO said it was informed that Montgomery Ward is aggressively assembling a &quot;top flight team,&quot; which has not been entirely put in place. A senior vice president of marketing at Montgomery Ward, it added, has not yet been identified.</p>
<p>Until then, HA-LO said, sales under the exclusive merchandising agreement are not predictable.</p>
<p>HA-LO added that, based on operations in January and the first half of February, internal growth for 1997 with its other clients is expected to exceed the growth achieved in 1996.  </p>
<p>Internal growth, it added, will be particularly fueled by HA-LO's ability to expand the business of two recent acquisitions, Creative Concepts in Advertising and Market USA.</p>
<p>Also helping growth are an exclusive merchandise agreement with Champion Products Inc, a division of Sara Lee Corp, increased proposal activity and new sales representatives, as well as a new office in New York.</p>
<p>Additionally, HA-LO said it expects growth to be furthered by its active acquisition pipeline.</p>
<p>HA-LO said its sales grew to $255 million in 1996 from $36 million in 1993, its first full year as a public comanpy.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident that HA-LO has the capabilities and resources in place to continue its growth,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NILES, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
