<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="411390" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turk PM adviser says Erdemir sale too slow.</title>
<headline>Turk PM adviser says Erdemir sale too slow.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A top adviser to the Turkish government said on Friday the privatisation board should either make progress with the sale of the country's only flat steel producer Eregli Demir Celik Fabrikalari A.S. (Erdemir) or cancel it.</p>
<p>&quot;The Privatisation Administration (OIB) is acting very slowly. It needs to make decisions quicker over a company with such a wide circulation of shares. It should either cancel the tender or take a stance and get on with it,&quot; said Rusen Gezici, an adviser to Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan.</p>
<p>In a tender last month only two bids were received for a 30-40 percent stake in Erdemir, a profitable company and one of the most actively-traded concerns on the stock market.</p>
<p>The bidders, Rumeli Metal Sanayii A.S. and a group of investors from northern Turkey, have not yet met the privatisation board amid speculation the sale may be cancelled.</p>
<p>The first attempt at a block sale of Erdemir shares last year was cancelled in May to allow more time for potential investors to put in bids.</p>
<p>The government holds a 51.66 percent stake in Erdemir and plans to retain a golden share to ensure work continues on an improvement programme, to safeguard foreign debts guaranteed by the treasury and to protect workers' jobs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
