<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="411372" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish security council holds key meeting.</title>
<headline>Turkish security council holds key meeting.</headline>
<byline>Daren Butler</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's military commanders and political leaders gathered on Friday for much-awaited talks expected to focus on increasing strains between the Islamist-led government and the secular establishment.</p>
<p>Ministers and senior military officials arrived around 3.00 p.m. (1300 GMT) for the National Security Council meeting, which is chaired by President Suleyman Demirel.</p>
<p>Political analysts expect the council, dominated by secularist officers, to issue a warning to Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan and his Welfare Party (RP) that mounting Islamist zeal threatens Turkey's democratic institutions.</p>
<p>Hasan Ekinci, an official of the junior coalition partner True Path Party (DYP), said the session would reduce political tensions.</p>
<p>&quot;RP cannot behave like an opposition party...The task of governments is not to raise tension and stress. God willing, the RP leadership will be more careful after this,&quot; Ekinci told reporters before the talks started.</p>
<p>Turkish media have carried reports -- dismissed as untrue by Erbakan and the president's office -- that Demirel warned the Islamist-led coalition in a letter against threatening Turkey's &quot;secularist, democratic (and) republican aims&quot;.</p>
<p>The reports, echoing Demirel's recent briefings to newspaper editors, aggravated political tensions over the rising profile of Islamists in the Moslem but secular state.</p>
<p>Those strains have escalated since the army sent tanks on manoeuvres through the Ankara district of Sincan early in February following an Islamist protest there attended by the Iranian ambassador.</p>
<p>&quot;The fear that the rising tension of recent days will lead to the burning of bridges, however unlikely, has been enough to make everybody's hair stand on end in Ankara,&quot; wrote Bilal Cetin, columnist for the liberal daily Yeni Yuzyil.</p>
<p>Erbakan was set to speak on state television at 9.00 p.m. (1900 GMT) about the government's performance since coming to power.</p>
<p>Speaking after regular talks with Demirel on Thursday evening, Erbakan dismissed claims that the Islamist-secularist row was undermining his eight-month-old coalition with the True Path's pro-western leader Tansu Ciller.</p>
<p>&quot;Thankfully our government is working harmoniously. The censure motions helped to strengthen our government further,&quot; Erbakan told reporters after the talks.</p>
<p>His government this week survived a censure motion challenge from two leftist parties who said the coalition was a threat to the country's secularism. Next week it will face another censure motion debate in parliament proposed by the leading opposition party.</p>
<p>The military's displeasure at Erbakan's efforts to push ahead with Islam-based policies is not expected to result in anything like the three army interventions seen in Turkey since 1960, analysts said.</p>
<p>Financial markets remained steady in cautious trading ahead of the National Security Council meeting.</p>
<p>At the talks, armed forces chief General Ismail Hakki Karadayi was expected to make a speech criticising pro-sharia, or Islamic law, comments by Islamists and by the Iranian ambassador at the anti-Israel protest in Sincan.</p>
<p>Karadayi returned to Turkey on Thursday evening from a trip to Israel as part of strengthening military cooperation between the two countries which has angered Islamists both domestically and abroad, notably in Iran.</p>
<p>Relations between Ankara and Tehran have been soured over the Iranian ambassador's invovlement in the Sincan rally, which led to him being recalled to Iran.</p>
<p>In a sign of further bilateral strains, Turkey's Foreign Ministry said on Thursday it was expelling Iran's consul to the eastern town of Erzurum, following his criticism of reported anti-Iranian comments by a leading Turkish military official.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
