<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="411440" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. appears to lean toward certifying Mexico.</title>
<headline>U.S. appears to lean toward certifying Mexico.</headline>
<byline>Peter Bate</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-02-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top U.S. officials on Thursday voiced support for Mexican President Ernesto Zedillo, suggesting the Clinton administration was leaning toward certifying Mexico once again as an ally in the war on drugs.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton must decide by Saturday whether he will approve or disqualify Mexico and 31 other countries in an annual evaluation known as the &quot;certification&quot; process.</p>
<p>Mexico, the United States' third biggest trade partner, has always passed that test since it was instituted by law in 1986, despite U.S. concerns about government corruption.</p>
<p>By Thursday afternoon, Clinton had not received recommendations on the &quot;certification&quot; from Secretary of State Madeleine Albright, the White House said.</p>
<p>As the deadline for a decision drew closer, Attorney General Janet Reno and White House drug czar Gen. Barry McCaffrey both stood up for Zedillo on Thursday.</p>
<p>Reno said the Mexican president had done the right thing by acting quickly to fire his top anti-narcotics official last week for allegedly taking bribes from a drug kingpin.</p>
<p>&quot;And I respect (Zedillo) very much for what he has done, and we will continue to work with him to try to address the issues that he thinks are so vital to his country,&quot; she told reporters at a briefing.</p>
<p>McCaffrey, who heads the administration's fight against drugs, told a congressional panel that the U.S. government still had confidence in Mexico's political leadership despite the arrest of his counterpart, Gen. Jesus Gutierrez Rebollo.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe their senior leadership are honest,&quot; he told a House Government Reform subcommittee, advising lawmakers not to overreact against Mexico.</p>
<p>Gutierrez's arrest was particularly stinging for McCaffrey since he had publicly praised the Mexican general last month as an &quot;honest and no-nonsense field commander.&quot;</p>
<p>The Mexican drug czar only held office for about 10 weeks but during that time he was briefed about joint operations with the United States along the 2,000-mile (3,000 km) border.</p>
<p>U.S. officials later acknowledged they first learned about Gutierrez's firing and arrest through Mexican newspaper accounts, which were later confirmed by the Mexican government.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, other U.S. officials have praised Mexico this week, arguing that its government has shown the political will to fight against drugs.</p>
<p>Mexico, while admitting that it has a huge corruption problem, bristled at the idea of being graded by Washington.</p>
<p>Mexican Foreign Affairs Minister Jose Angel Gurria even suggested this week that &quot;decertification&quot; could fracture bilateral relations.</p>
<p>Countries that fail the test may be subject to U.S. economic and trade sanctions, and the prospect unsettled Mexican financial markets on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course (decertification) would affect cooperation in the fight against drug trafficking, and this is not good for the economy and nor is it good for the markets,&quot; Mexican Finance Minister Guillermo Ortiz said.</p>
<p>Two leading Democratic U.S. lawmakers have been pressing Clinton to &quot;decertify&quot; Mexico, charging that its government is unable and unwilling to deal effectively with drug traffickers.</p>
<p>House Democratic Leader Richard Gephardt of Missouri and California Sen. Dianne Feinstein, have even threatened to promote a joint resolution to try to overturn an eventual full certification for Mexico.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
