<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="41189" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Sept 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Sept 10.</headline>
<text>
<p>NIHON KEIZAI SHIMBUN</p>
<p>Toshiba Corp plans to set up a plant to produce large and medium-sized colour televisions in China from autumn next year in a joint venture with a Chinese state-run TV maker and a Japanese company. The venture will be capitalised at about $50 million and owned by 65 percent by the Toshiba group, five percent by Nichimen Corp and 30 percent by the Chinese firm. It will target annual output of one million sets.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Three of Japan's Big Four securities companies, including Nikko Securities Co Ltd and Daiwa Securities Co Ltd, are expected to see their parent current profit fall from a year earlier in the first half year to September 30, 1996, hit by slow recovery of stock market. Nomura Securities Co Ltd is the only one of the four expected see its parent current profit over the the same period a year ago. Only Kokusai Securities Co Ltd and Sanyo Securities Co Ltd of the 10 second-tier securities companies are expected to show a parent current profit in the first six months.  </p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Hoya Corp is expected to post record parent current profits of 18.5 billion yen in the year ending March 1997, up by 11 percent from last year, helped by sales of glass hard disk substrates.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Openbook Co Ltd, a Chiba-based personal computer information company, and 9003 Inc of Tokyo plan to merge on October 1 to become one of Japan's leading computer software developers. The new company is targeting sales of 1.8 billion yen in the business year starting next April.  </p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Mitsubishi Electric Corp and Sega Enterprises Ltd have set up a joint venture to offer games through the Internet from November. Capitalised at one billion yen, it will be owned 53 percent by Mitsubishi and 47 percent by Sega.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Daiei Inc plans to start a promotional campaign so coupons can be exchanged for cosmetics goods from Thursday. Customers will be able to exchange 10 stamps for a 2,000 yen shopping coupon, which can be used to buy any product in a Daiei store.  </p>
<p>Mitsubishi Heavy Industries Ltd has supplied a simulator facility for nuclear plant operations to the Russian Nuclear Power Plant Training Centre. The order is estimated to be valued at more than one billion yen.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Japan Airlines Co Ltd plans to merge its two communications-related subsidiaries to streamline operations on October 1. The companies are JAL Data Communications and Systems Co and JAL Creative Systems Co.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
