<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="411954" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian scientists want more &quot;Dolly&quot; clones.</title>
<headline>Australian scientists want more &quot;Dolly&quot; clones.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's official research body on Friday backed the use of cloning in animal breeding and said it hoped to have cloned livestock on farms in five years.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth Scientific and Industrial Research Organisation (CSIRO) hailed the technique used in Britain in the first-ever cloning of an adult animal -- a sheep named Dolly.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a great scientific advance and one that we welcome,&quot; said Kevin Ward, head of genetic animal research for the CSIRO.</p>
<p>News last Sunday of Dolly's creation ignited debate over the ethics of cloning, prompting U.S. President Bill Clinton to call for an official bioethics report on the development.</p>
<p>One commentator in Britain warned that unscrupulous doctors could go on to produce human &quot;Frankensteins&quot;.</p>
<p>But the CSIRO welcomed the new technology and said it could be used to duplicate elite farm animals in Australia within about five years, given the current pace of research.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the technology is in place, just not the fine detail,&quot; Ward told Reuters.</p>
<p>Australian researchers have been looking at cloning for a long time and have made several advances, he said.</p>
<p>Ward described the work of the British research team that produced Dolly as groundbreaking and said it would go a long way to furthering the CSIRO's own research.</p>
<p>Dolly was cloned from the egg cell of one ewe and a mammary gland cell from another.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100124">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
