<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="411918" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: U.K. oil/gas at record output in Jan - Royal Bank.</title>
<headline>U.K. oil/gas at record output in Jan - Royal Bank.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's combined oil and gas production reached a record level in January thanks to continuing growth in gas production, according to the latest Royal Bank of Scotland Oil and Gas Index.</p>
<p>It said combined output rose 1.2 percent on the month, with gas production up 3.9 percent to its highest level to date. Oil production fell for the second month in succession to stand at 2.68 million barrels per day (bpd) in January.</p>
<p>Oil production fell by over 21,000 bpd in January compared with December to average 2.68 million bpd. Although production was down on a monthly basis, over the year it was up by 4.0 percent, the Royal Bank said in its report published on Friday.</p>
<p>Output in the 12 months to January averaged 2.54 million bpd, a fall of 0.3 percent compared with the 12 months to January 1996.</p>
<p>Gas production rose again in January, reaching its highest level since the Index began in 1980. Output increased by 461 million cubic feet per day (mmcfd) compared with December.</p>
<p>On an annual basis, gas output was up by 978 mmcfd or 8.6 percent. Output in the 12 months to January averaged 8.411 mmcfd, an increase of 16.7 percent over the 12 months to January 1996.</p>
<p>Rising output and generally strong prices in January pushed oil and gas revenues to 60 million stg per day, the highest in cash terms since April 1985.</p>
<p>Stephen Boyle, head of business economics at the Royal Bank of Scotland, said he expected a further slight weakening in prices after falls below $20 a barrel in late January and in February.</p>
<p>&quot;Oil prices have now fallen substantially from their peak of just under $24 per barrel at the beginning of the year,&quot; he said in the report.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices are now below $20 for the first time since July 1996. This decline is much as we had expected, with the mild winter in the northern hemisphere combining with strengthening stocks and the return to the market of Iraqi crude. We believe some further modest weakening of prices is possible in the coming months.&quot;</p>
<p>But the report also said that the flattening of the forward curve for crude oil futures was likely to provide oil producers with incentive to hedge their production now, rather than when the price was higher because the relative value of forward prices is greater.</p>
<p>&quot;While there is room for further falls in price, renewed buying already exhibited in both spot and forward markets should underpin prices,&quot; the report concluded.</p>
<p>-- Kate Dourian, London newsroom +44 171 542 7629</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
