<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412146" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Janome sees bigger net on land sales, bank support.</title>
<headline>Janome sees bigger net on land sales, bank support.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Janome Sewing Machine Co Ltd said on Friday it expects its parent net profit to rise in the year to March 31 after selling land and a head-office building, writing off some of its loans, and receiving planned financial support from Asahi Bank Ltd.  </p>
<p>Janome will sell its headquarters and land in central Tokyo to a Tokyo-based property firm for 15.9 billion yen. of which 13.45 billion yen will be profit, Janome said in a statement.</p>
<p>Janome said it plans to obtain financial support from Asahi Bank, but it did not specify the nature or the amount of the support.</p>
<p>Janome said that this fiscal year to March 31 it would write off 21 billion yen of the 30 billion yen in loans it extended to Kabushiki Kaisha Nanatomi.</p>
<p>Janome said earlier on Friday that it would post a parent net profit of 900 million yen in 1996/97 against its earlier forecast of net profit of 100 million yen.</p>
<p>It posted a net loss of 112 million yen in 1995/96.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
