<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412221" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: RESEARCH ALERT - Salomon ups COSCO target.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - Salomon ups COSCO target.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Salomon Brothers said it expects COSCO Pacific Ltd's planned purchases of four container ports in China to boost the company's long-term growth, and it raises the 12 months target price to HK$11.00 from HK$8.50.</p>
<p>The U.S. brokerage said it maintains its recommendation of &quot;buy&quot; on COSCO because the impact of the ports acquisitions is not fully reflected in the current share price.</p>
<p>COSCO Pacific's management has indicated it intends to buy from parent COSCO Hong Kong (Group) four container ports in Qingdao, Shanghai, Zhangjiagang and Yantian in China, as part of its expansion plan, the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;The proposed ports acquisition which we estimate will cost US$150 million, is expected to result in external financing,&quot; said Pitzi Lau, vice president of equity research.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe an equity fund raising is more likely. Our analysis finds that with 100 percent equity or debt financing, COSCO Pacific's economic value should be improved,&quot; Lau said.</p>
<p>Based on an estimated 1997 profit of US$9.7 million and US$12 million profit for 1998, the return on investment should give a six percent yield for 1997 earnings and eight percent for 1998, it said.</p>
<p>Container throughput in China has also improved over the past few years with total throughput increased to 7.5 million TEUs in 1996, up 13 percent from 1995, the report said.</p>
<p>The growth of container business can be attributed to strong economic growth, increasing foreign investment and increasing containerisation of cargo, which has resulted in improved container-terminal infrastracuture, it said.</p>
<p>The rising level of intra-Asian trade, especially in China, is also expected to provide steady growth for the container leasing business and the use of container ports, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;In view of the non-dilutive impact of the acquisition of the Chinese ports, we have raised our 12 month target price from HK$8.50 to HK$11.00,&quot; Lau said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the growth of China ports will continue to support the company's share price,&quot; Lau said.</p>
<p>COSCO shares were down HK$0.25 to HK$10.65 at midday.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong News Room (852) 2843 6370</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
