<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412450" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel ready for violence over building plan.</title>
<headline>Israel ready for violence over building plan.</headline>
<byline>Colleen Siegel</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel braced for violence on Friday ahead of Moslem prayers Palestinians planned to hold at the Arab East Jerusalem hilltop where Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government is to build houses for Jews.</p>
<p>Palestinians organising the prayers said despite outrage at the new Israeli settlement on land they call Jabal Abu Ghneim and Israel calls Har Homa, they intended to keep order.</p>
<p>&quot;We are all interested that everything be done in a quiet way, in a responsible way...Violence does not help anyone,&quot; Mohammed Abu Tor told Israel's army radio.</p>
<p>Abu Tor, from Um Tuba village near the disputed hilltop, owned some of the land confiscated by Israel for the new neighbourhood of 6,500 homes.</p>
<p>Israel deployed large numbers of troops at the hill and 500 extra police in Jerusalem ahead of prayers at al-Aqsa mosque, Islam's third holiest shrine.</p>
<p>Israel captured East Jerusalem in the 1967 Middle East war and views all of the city as its capital. The Palestine Liberation Organisation (PLO) wants East Jerusalem as the capital of a future Palestinian state.</p>
<p>Israeli media said Netanyahu would be grilled by right-wing ministers at the weekly cabinet meeting over reports he had made a quid pro quo agreement with Palestinian President Yasser Arafat over the decision to build taken this week.</p>
<p>The Israeli newspaper Haaretz said on Thursday Netanyahu had an unwritten agreement with Arafat that Israel would increase the size of its next pullout from the West Bank in exchange for a promise to contain Palestinian reaction to the Har Homa plan.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's spokesman denied the report.</p>
<p>Arafat on Thursday attacked Israel's decision to build as a serious breach of the Palestinian-Israeli peace agreement. But he heeded U.S. warnings to keep the lid on violent protests.</p>
<p>Organisers of a protest at Har Homa on Thursday continually urged some 2,000 people not to throw stones or confront Israeli soldiers who barred their way at the foot of the hill.</p>
<p>Israeli Labour Minister Eli Ishai signed the official papers on Thursday that would put into effect the right-wing government's decision on Wednesday to approve the housing project, his spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;I estimate building of the new neighbourhood of Har Homa will begin in the coming two weeks,&quot; the spokesman quoted Ishai as saying at a signing ceremony.</p>
<p>Palestinian and Israeli analysts believe Arafat will not openly call for confrontation, particularly ahead of his scheduled meeting with Clinton next week.</p>
<p>Arafat cannot let Israeli settlement go unchallenged but neither he nor Netanyahu has an interest in a replay of last September's violence sparked by Israeli action in East Jerusalem, the analysts said.</p>
<p>Sixty-one Palestinians and 15 Israeli soldiers died in gun battles after Netanyahu opened a tourist tunnel near Islamic holy shrines in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Analysts say Netanyahu learned from that, noting that the Har Homa announcement was timed ahead of Arafat's White House visit. He also sought to soften the blow to Palestinians by announcing permission for 3,000 Arab housing starts in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The U.N. Security Council was to hold informal consultations on Friday on a request it meet on Israel's building plans. The Arab League said it would hold an emergency meeting of its permanent representatives on the plan on Sunday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
