<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412437" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Worst over in Japan jobless situation--govt.</title>
<headline>Worst over in Japan jobless situation--govt.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The worst is over in Japan's employment situation, but it is hard to see an improvement anytime soon, a senior official of the government's Management and Coordination Agency told reporters on Friday.</p>
<p>The agency announced that the seasonally adjusted unemployment rate was 3.3 percent in January, unchanged from December.</p>
<p>The number of people employed in the manufacturing sector rose 0.9 percent to 14.39 million in January, the first rise since last September, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The worst was over when the jobless rate rose to 3.5 percent last year, but it is difficult to expect a quick improvement in the job situation,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>The seasonally adjusted jobless rate hit a record high of 3.5 percent last May and June, but has been at either 3.4 percent or 3.3 percent since then.</p>
<p>&quot;The job situation has improved since last year, but we are not sure if it will keep improving as a planned rise in the consumption tax on April 1 could have some effect on the economy,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
