<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412545" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: INSTANT VIEW - French Jan unemployment up 18,100.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - French Jan unemployment up 18,100.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are analysts' comments on the rise of 18,100 in French unemployment to 3,099,800 in January reported by the labour ministry on Friday. The ILO unemployment rate remained at a record 12.7 percent.</p>
<p>Economists had been expecting a rise of up to 20,000.</p>
<p>DAVID NAUDE, ECONOMIST, JP MORGAN</p>
<p>It's pretty much as expected and confirms the upward trend is far from over despite dips in October and December.</p>
<p>However, we have to acknowledge as well that a big part of the rise is due to demographic trends and not just economic performance. The labour market has increased in 1995 and 1996.  </p>
<p>PATRICK MANGE, ECONOMIST, DEUTSCHE BANK</p>
<p>We're not surprised. It continues to rise and will probably do so for some time.</p>
<p>But together with the unemployment data there was the INSEE (statistics office) survey which again was more positive on the (industrialists') outlook.</p>
<p>We see the unemployment rate going up, possibly to 13 percent mid-year and then slowly coming back down to 12.7 or 12.6 percent. Over the year, unemployment will be up.</p>
<p>In my view employment incentives should be scrapped and payroll charges reduced.</p>
<p>PHILIPPE BROSSARD  ECONOMIST ABN-AMRO</p>
<p>It's a bit stronger (a rise) than I would have expected. It's a correction of what happened last time.</p>
<p>After two months it is rather encouraging that unemployment is almost at bottom and we may not see the 13 percent rate INSEE had forecast last December.</p>
<p>We had a lot of good news (from economic data) recently. This (the unemployment data) shows the good news is more for prospects rather than for the current situation. So there may still be some pressure on the Bank of France to try to do a bit more and try to narrow the gap with German rates.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 42 21 53 81</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
