<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412588" id="root" date="1997-02-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Enlargement, trade head EU-Russia summit talks.</title>
<headline>Enlargement, trade head EU-Russia summit talks.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Gaunt</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-02-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eastern Europe, trade and the fight against drugs and organised crime are set to top the agenda on Monday when the European Union and Russia hold their annual summit in Moscow.</p>
<p>Dutch Prime Minister Wim Kok and European Commission President Jacques Santer are to meet Russian President Boris Yeltsin, who had been due to travel to the Netherlands for the summit on February 3, but cancelled because of ill health.</p>
<p>While the proposed expansion of NATO into former Warsaw Pact countries is a dominant concern of Russia's relations with the West, Moscow has far fewer concerns when it comes to the EU's planned enlargement into eastern Europe.</p>
<p>But EU officials said Santer and Kok would be keen to keep things that way, emphasising that EU and NATO enlargement, though parallel processes, are independent.</p>
<p>&quot;There will have to be some noises so that they (the Russians) don't see too much of a link,&quot; said one EU official. The EU has promised 10 former eastern bloc countries -- Poland, Hungary, the Czech republic, Slovakia, Slovenia, Bulgaria, Romania, Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania -- eventual membership.</p>
<p>Officals said the EU would raise the issue of trade, both with the bloc itself and in a wider international context.</p>
<p>Russia and the EU have agreed a partnership and cooperation agreement designed to forge commercial and other links between the two and to liberalise trade. The agreement, however, has not been ratified.</p>
<p>Kok and Santer will urge the Russians to act, viewing the agreement as the basis for all EU-Russian dealings. They will, however, also accept some blame because not all EU countries have themselves ratified the deal.</p>
<p>The EU side will also push Moscow to prepare Russia fully for membership in the World Trade Organisation.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pushing very hard in that direction. We want them to fulfil the conditions,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>In a similar vein, the Western Europeans are expected to urge Yeltsin to continue with economic reforms, notably to improve Russia's ability to attract investment.</p>
<p>&quot;The investment climate must be reinforced,&quot; one EU official said, adding that Kok and Santer will ask Yeltsin what the EU can do to help him.</p>
<p>The two men are also expected to raise the issue of organised crime and illegal drugs, problems that appear high on the bloc's own agenda.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-02-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-02-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
