<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412659" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-FRENCH PHILOSOPHY DECISIVE, SAYS VILLEPREUX.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-FRENCH PHILOSOPHY DECISIVE, SAYS VILLEPREUX.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kitson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's extraordinary 23-20 win over England at Twickenham on Saturday was a question of mind over matter, according to French assistant coach Pierre Villepreux.</p>
<p>It may have been two converted tries and a penalty from Christophe Lamaison which transformed a 20-6 deficit, but Villepreux insisted afterwards that France's attitude had been the decisive factor.</p>
<p>&quot;Our philosophy won,&quot; said Villepreux, the former international turned coaching guru who has only recently been welcomed back into the French set-up. &quot;We played the rugby I like and we played it well. Mentally, we were superior.&quot;</p>
<p>Coach Jean-Claude Skrela agreed his men &quot;looked the fresher team in the second-half&quot; and acknowledged Lamaison's 18 points had transformed that potential into a momentous win.</p>
<p>&quot;We always had confidence in him as a goalkicker. He was a leading character in our win today but the whole team deserves praise.&quot;</p>
<p>England coach Jack Rowell, whose future in the role remains uncertain, hinted his side might have been guilty of easing up with victory apparently in sight.</p>
<p>&quot;We were 20-6 up, perhaps we thought the game was over,&quot; said Rowell, who described the finale as &quot;the worst 20 minutes of my life&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Mentally, we slackened off a bit. It was a hard lesson. We won't make the same mistake again.&quot;</p>
<p>Rowell, who hinted before the match his business commitments might prevent him accepting a new contract as coach, tried to play down the pre-match reports.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is made more complex by the game having gone professional,&quot; said Rowell, a successful industrialist. &quot;I'm sure the dust will settle and everything will be sorted out.&quot;</p>
<p>An RFU spokesman said Rowell had still to be offered a new two-year contract to take charge of England up to the 1999 World Cup.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
