<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="412716" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ATHLETICS-SLANEY, DEVERS POST BEST INDOOR TIMES FOR SEASON.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-SLANEY, DEVERS POST BEST INDOOR TIMES FOR SEASON.</headline>
<byline>Jerry Schwartz</byline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sprinter Gail Devers and ageless distance runner Mary Slaney qualified for next week's indoor world championships with times Saturday that ranked as the best in the world this year.</p>
<p>The two women claimed spots on the U.S. team that will compete next weekend in Paris with wins in the USA Indoor Track and Field Championships at the Georgia Dome.</p>
<p>Slaney's clocking of 4:03.08 in the 1,500 meters was the fastest indoor time in 12 years. Devers' clocking of 7.00 in the 60 meters bested her long-time rival Gwen Torrence, who finished second in 7.12</p>
<p>The 38-year-old Slaney finished more than 30 meters ahead of Suzy Hamilton, who was second in 4:08.83. &quot;I planned to go out hard,&quot; said Slaney, who led from the start. &quot;Sometimes if you sit in the pack, the pace gets slower and slower so it's only a race in the last 200 or 300 meters.&quot;</p>
<p>Torrence said she will not run in Paris next weekend despite qualifying for the team with her second-place finish.</p>
<p>Devers said she will run next weekend and hopes to defend her world indoor 60-meter title. &quot;I have some work to do, still,&quot; she said. &quot;I was too high and too long, but I'm going to work on it,&quot; Devers said of her quick start Saturday.</p>
<p>Another prominent American sprinter, Dennis Mitchell, missed his chance for the world championships after he finished tied for sixth place in the men's 60 meters.</p>
<p>Randall Evans, who won with a clocking of 6.49 seconds, and Tim Montgomery, second in 6.51, make up the American 60-meter team.</p>
<p>Mitchell won most of the top international 100-meter events last year but was disappointed in the Olympic 100 meters, finishing fourth. He had said Friday his indoor training this year had been difficult &quot;because it was a very long and a very hard outdoor season for me last year.&quot;</p>
<p>Torrence almost was disqualified from the meet after she failed to show up for a heat Friday in the 200 meters -- an event Torrence said she never planned to run. &quot;I don't know who declared me for the 200, but I never had any plans to run the 200 here. I never declared,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>After an appeal, Torrence was cleared to run the 60 meters and said later she was prepared to force her way onto the track. &quot;I was going to stay there until the referees pulled me off,&quot; she said. &quot;Let the crowd see them pull me off,&quot; the controversial Atlanta native said.</p>
<p>With Olympic gold medallist Michael Johnson playing the role of television announcer, the 400 meters went to Derek Mills in 46.09 seconds. Deon Minor finished second in 46.12.</p>
<p>Jearl Miles-Clark passed Natasha Kaiser-Brown before the second turn of the women's 400 meters and went on to win in 51.31.</p>
<p>Charles Austin, Olympic high jump gold medallist, claimed his second American indoor title with a jump of 2.31 meters. Isaac Hill claimed a spot on the American team with a jump of 2.29 meters.</p>
<p>In the women's high jump, Angela Bradburn added a fourth American indoor title to her wins in 1988, 1992 and 1994 with a jump of 1.92 meters.</p>
<p>Bradburn will be competing in the world championships for the third time. She will be joined on the American team by Karol Jenkins, who has never been to a world indoor championship and had never even made the U.S. indoor finals. Jenkins' jump of 1.89 meters was good enough for second place and a spot on the world team.</p>
<p>Allen Johnson, the Olympic gold medallist in the 110-meter hurdles, injured his left knee in a heat of the 60-meter hurdles and pulled up short of the finish line. Johnson, who had won this same meet a year ago, said the injury was not serious. &quot;It's still tender right above the knee,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Reginald Torian won the final and was joined on the American team by Duane Ross.</p>
<p>John Godina, Olympic silver medallist, waited until his last throw in the shot put to pass Mark Parlin. Godina's winning throw of 20.64 meters put him on the Paris team with Parlin, whose best was 20.55 meters.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to win and get a personal record,&quot; Godina said of next week world's championships. &quot;I have the ability to do it, it's just a matter of bringing it out.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
