<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413099" id="root" date="1997-03-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: INDIAN HEADLINE STOCKS - factors to watch - March 1.</title>
<headline>INDIAN HEADLINE STOCKS - factors to watch - March 1.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main factors affecting Indian stock markets on Saturday morning:</p>
<p>NEWS OUTLOOK:</p>
<p>**  Indian stock markets are expected to top smart gains on Saturday as bourses resume trade after government presented a budget that traders described as &quot;path-breaking&quot; and &quot;market-boosting.&quot;</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-share index of the premier Bombay Stock Exchange rallied 177.12 points, or 5.10 percent, to end at 3,651.91 in a day of wild swings.</p>
<p>**  Finance Minister P. Chidambaram who presented the 1997/98 (April-March) budget to Parliament late on Friday gave a pleasant surprise to the country's capital markets by fulfilling almost all expectations of traders and showed a strong commitment to the five-year old reform process.</p>
<p>**  Chidambaram announced a bold set of policy measures that met more than market hopes including sharp cuts in corporate and income taxes, allowing companies to buyback their shares and withdrawing a taxation on income from company dividends.</p>
<p>**  The Finance Minister abolised a 7.5 percent surcharge on corporate profits and a tax on income from dividends-- two longstanding business demands.</p>
<p>**  Chidambaram lowered a tax on domestic firms' profits to 35 percent from 40 percent, and on foreign firms' profits to 48 percent from 55 percent.</p>
<p>**  The government diluted a controversial minimum tax announced in the 1996/97 budget last year and raised the investment limit for foreign institutional investors in some firms to 30 percent from 24 percent</p>
<p>**  The Finance Minister who said India's personal tax rates were among the highest in devoloping Asian nations, said he was cutting the maximum marginal rate of income tax to 30 percent from 40 percent.</p>
<p>The three existing tax slab rates for personal income tax would now be slashed to 10, 20 and 30 percent from 15, 30 and 40 percent respectively.</p>
<p>**  The government also announced an amnesty plan under which Indians who declared their &quot;black money&quot; would be immune to income tax, wealth tax and foreign exchange penalties, irrespective of the source of the income. The money would now be taxed at 30 percent.</p>
<p>**  The Finance Minister lowered the peak rate of customs duties to 40 percent from the existing 50 percent and said duties on the import of capital goods would be cut to 20 percent from current 25 percent, to protect imports.</p>
<p>**  The state-run Indian Petrochemicals Corp Ltd will not have to cut prices of its major petrochemical products, as was widely feared, following the budget proposals, a top official said on Friday.</p>
<p>**  The budget proposals for fiscal 1997/98, running from April to March, will help India's largest private firm Reliance Industries Ltd, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
