<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413174" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: ALPINE SKIING-ALPHAND CLINCHES DOWNHILL TITLE.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-ALPHAND CLINCHES DOWNHILL TITLE.</headline>
<dateline>KVITFJELL, Norway 1997-03-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Luc Alphand clinched his third consecutive World Cup downhill title on Sunday after finishing fifth behind local favourite Lasse Kjus who won the race at his second attempt.</p>
<p>Frenchman Alphand, who had complained bitterly about being forced to race in what he believed were dangerous conditions on Saturday, locked up the downhill title when he finished ahead of his only challenger, Italy's Kristian Ghedina, who finished a disappointing 10th.</p>
<p>&quot;My goal today was to finish ahead of Ghedina,&quot; said Alphand, who also leads the super-G and overall rankings. &quot;I didn't take too many risks because it was just too important to finish the race.&quot;</p>
<p>Kjus was denied victory on Saturday when high winds forced officials to rule the race invalid just two skiers short of declaring it official.</p>
<p>The 26-year-old Norwegian was in superb form again on Sunday, storming down the icy 2,641-metre Olympiabakken course in one minute 27.12 seconds. Italy's Pietro Vitalini was second and Canada's Edi Podivinsky third.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no problem with the conditions, today  they were fair,&quot; Alphand said after Sunday's re-run.</p>
<p>&quot;My first goal of the season has been reached and now I will focus on super-G this afternoon and think about the overall after that.&quot;</p>
<p>With a victory, Alphand could clinch his second title in a day and strengthen his place at the top the overall standings.</p>
<p>Alphand's fifth place allowed him to widen the gap to 172 points over Norway's Kjetil Andre Aamodt.</p>
<p>Under dark early morning skies, Kjus claimed his third career downhill win and second in a row on the Olympic layout.</p>
<p>&quot;I wasn't mad yesterday when the race was cancelled because the conditions were unfair and it was a good decision,&quot; said Kjus, the reigning overall World Cup champion.</p>
<p>&quot;Because I knew yesterday was unfair I was able to forget about that race and focus on today.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no wind but the course was still very icy and the conditions difficult.&quot;</p>
<p>Having missed a month of the season because of a sinus infection, Kjus will not defend his overall crown.</p>
<p>Since his return to competition in January, Kjus has won a combined event in Kitzbuehel, was third in a super-G in Garmisch-Partenkirchen and claimed silver medals in the downhill, super-G and giant slalom at the world championships in Sestriere, Italy.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been a long, difficult season and it's great to win here because it will boost my morale for next season,&quot; said Kjus. &quot;This has been a difficult year with my sickness and to win here is a positive sign.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KVITFJELL, Norway"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
