<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413257" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BOXING-LEONARD STOPPED BY CAMACHO IN FIFTH ROUND OF COMEBACK.</title>
<headline>BOXING-LEONARD STOPPED BY CAMACHO IN FIFTH ROUND OF COMEBACK.</headline>
<byline>Richard Finn</byline>
<dateline>ATLANTIC CITY, New Jersey 1997-03-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sugar Ray Leonard could beat neither Hector &quot;Macho&quot; Camacho nor time Saturday, losing his comeback fight after a six-year layoff and then saying enough was enough.</p>
<p>&quot;I fought my heart out,&quot; the 40-year-old Leonard said after being stopped in the fifth round. &quot;For sure my career is definitely over for me in the ring. I'm through.&quot;</p>
<p>Leonard, who won world titles in five different weight divisions, ended with a 36-3-1 record, and as a loser in his last two fights.</p>
<p>Leonard was knocked down on the seat of his pants early in the fifth round and Camacho followed up by pinning him against the ropes with a flurry of 10 unanswered punches before referee Joe Cortez stopped the onslaught with 1:08 left in the round.</p>
<p>&quot;The referee did the right thing,&quot; said Leonard, who was bleeding from a cut above the left eye inflicted the round before. &quot;There was no sense in my getting hurt.&quot;</p>
<p>Camacho, 64-3-1, floored Leonard with two lefts. First a left hook and then a left uppercut sat Leonard down in the middle of the ring. Leonard rolled over on his knees and got up at the count of five, but the end was soon to come to one of the most celebrated boxing careers of recent times.</p>
<p>&quot;I knew it was a matter of time before he gave in to my punches,&quot; Camacho said. &quot;Now I know that I am the Macho Man.&quot;</p>
<p>Leonard had a history of making winning comebacks, having already retired three previous times. His most celebrated comeback had been in 1987, when after a three-year layout he outpointed Marvellous Marvin Hagler in a 12-round war.</p>
<p>But this time there was nothing left and Leonard said he knew it from the first moment.</p>
<p>&quot;In the first round I had no balance, nothing was happening at all,&quot; said Leonard. &quot;I just never got into it. I couldn't get myself established.</p>
<p>&quot;Every time I would reach in, I never got my balance that I once had,&quot; said Leonard. &quot;He had the step on me. I couldn't push off on my right leg.&quot;</p>
<p>Leonard confirmed that he had injured his right leg in training and said that he had taken four shots of novocaine for the injury right before the fight.</p>
<p>Leonard's advisor J.F. Brown said that the fighter had torn his right calf about a month ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Two weeks ago it popped again and that's where the rumours were that he was in the hospital -- and the rumours were true,&quot; Brown said. &quot;I should have cancelled the fight.&quot;</p>
<p>The return of Leonard, one of the most beloved and charismatic champions of recent times, stirred the interest and passion of 10,324 at the Atlantic City Convention Centre and a worldwide pay-for-view television audience.</p>
<p>When Leonard stepped into the ring, and back into the spotlight that he had left after being thoroughly whipped by Terry Norris in February of 1991, the crowd roared with approval.</p>
<p>Still, many fans were not so happy. Why would he return with his spot in boxing history already assured? He was already scheduled to be formally inducted on June 15 into the Boxing Hall of Fame in Canastota, New York, this year.</p>
<p>Leonard was betrayed by his age, the leg injury and ring rust against the 34-year-old Camacho, who kept his lightly regarded International Boxing Council middleweight crown.</p>
<p>Leonard was idle for the last six years while Camacho was fighting 27 times, winning all but twice. The difference showed.</p>
<p>Camacho, whose antics before the bout had included dropping his pants at the morning weigh-in and being carried into the ring dressed as a Roman emperor, had a decidedly more serious attitude during the fight.</p>
<p>Before the fight Leonard had refused to get involved in any speculation about his boxing future past Camacho, though others had talked about a possible rematch with Norris.</p>
<p>As soon as the final bell rang there was no more need for any more speculating. &quot;If there is ever an indication to stop, this is a pretty good indication,&quot; Leonard said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTIC CITY, New Jersey"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
