<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413362" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: State of emergency declared in riot-hit Albania.</title>
<headline>State of emergency declared in riot-hit Albania.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-03-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's parliament declared an immediate state of emergency on Sunday as insurrection born from the collapse of risky savings schemes spread through the south of the impoverished country.</p>
<p>President Sali Berisha vowed to use the &quot;iron hand&quot; of the law to quash the violence in a speech shortly after the declaration, approved by 118 votes to nil in a chamber dominated by his Democratic Party.</p>
<p>Stern-faced and with the Albanian flag at his shoulder, he accused former communists and unspecified foreign spy services of plotting to overthrow him.</p>
<p>&quot;Armed communist rebels helped and financed by foreign espionage services have started military actions to overthrow the government with force and establish their rule across the country,&quot; Berisha said in his televised address.</p>
<p>&quot;They will very soon feel the iron hand and the full punishment of the laws of this state,&quot; he declared.</p>
<p>Neither Berisha nor parliament spelled out how poorly-trained and ill-equipped security forces planned to tackle the insurgency, marked by the worst violence in the former Stalinist state since 40 deaths in food riots in 1991.</p>
<p>State television said deputies had voted to merge the Shik secret police force and the interior ministry under Shik chief Bashkim Gazidede but made no reference to any use of troops.</p>
<p>Parliament voted the state of emergency after armed rioters went on a rampage in the Adriatic town of Sarande, just across the sea from the Greek holiday island of Corfu.</p>
<p>Rioters seized arms after sacking the police headquarters, then torched buildings and looted shops and banks.</p>
<p>A Reuter correspondent saw thick, black smoke billow from the headquarters, a library and a bank in the town. Looters cruised the streets in cars, shooting into the air with stolen Kalashnikov assault rifles. No casualties were reported.</p>
<p>&quot;Our commanding officers have fled. We don't know what to do. People stole about 400 Kalashnikovs from police headquarters,&quot; an army lieutenant said.</p>
<p>The state-run news agency ATA reported other raids on arms depots in the area around the town of Fier, 35 km (20 miles) north of the tinderbox town of Vlore, where up to nine people were reported killed in gunbattles with Shik police on Friday.</p>
<p>Witnesses said police had also abandoned the town of Tepelene and reported automatic gunfire in Gjirokaster, near the Greek border. The source of the shooting was not clear.</p>
<p>The collapse of a string of risky, high-yield pyramid investment schemes in January unleashed a wave of unrest, mainly in the more prosperous south where thousands poured their meagre savings into locally-based funds.</p>
<p>Protesters have turned their fury on Berisha and his ruling party, accusing them of failure to control the funds.</p>
<p>Berisha sought to soothe tempers on Saturday by dismissing his deeply unpopular prime minister, Aleksander Meksi.</p>
<p>His move failed to satisfy protesters and the 11-party opposition Forum for Democracy, which called again on Sunday for the formation of a technocrat government and an early election.</p>
<p>One Forum figure, Democratic Alliance leader Neritan Ceka, said Albania risked civil war unless Berisha gave more ground.</p>
<p>The Forum has also urged Berisha to postpone his election to a second five-year term as president.</p>
<p>Berisha was certain to win the election in a parliamentary vote scheduled for 10 a.m. (0900 GMT) on Monday as his Democratic Party holds 122 seats in the 140-member chamber.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
