<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413436" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-HIH says '97 profit outlook very good.</title>
<headline>RTRS-HIH says '97 profit outlook very good.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Insurance firm HIH Winterthur International Ltd said on Monday the profit outlook in the 1997 calendar year was extremely positive and that it was assured of considerable premium growth.  </p>
<p>&quot;The outlook for 1997 is extremely positive,&quot; chief executive Ray Williams said in a statement accompanying the company's 1996 profit result.</p>
<p>&quot;Considerable premium growth is assured and, subject to movements in investment markets, the earnings impetus will be maintained,&quot; Williams said.</p>
<p>HIH Winterthur is about 48 percent owned by Winterthur Swiss Insurance Company.  </p>
<p>The company said its calendar 1996 net profit rose by 28 percent to A$61.5 million and it was now ranked as the second largest general insurer in Australia.</p>
<p>Gross earned premium rose by 44 percent in 1996 to A$1.346 billion and net earned premium rose by 46 percent to A$931.5 million. Investment income, excluding realised and unrealised capital movements, rose by 56 percent to A$96.1 million.</p>
<p>Williams said the company posted significant profit growth from a number of domestic operations and from its international portfolio, in particular the United Kingdom and New Zealand.  </p>
<p>&quot;This year will see benefits from a range of initiatives flow through and sustain the momentum,&quot; Williams said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sizeable contributions are expected from the expansion of our Australian bancassurance activities (the National Australia Bank alliance comes on stream from 1 July), from the United Kingdom and from our recently re-acquired California workers compensation business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
