<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413427" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>australia: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News-March 3.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News-March 3.</headline>
<text>
<p>Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard has indicated the Federal Government will take a slow approach on economic reform, signalling modest plans for reforms to the tax systems, industrial relations, fiscal policy, Federal-State finance relations and industry policy. Howard said the Government is committed to &quot;sensible&quot;, pragmatic change on a case-by-case basis. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>House prices in the upmarket inner city suburbs of both Sydney and Melbourne have benefited from the sharp fall in mortgage rates over the past six months, with some prices increasing by more than 30 per cent compared to a year ago. The increases in the two cities have triggered some speculation that there could be a repeat of the big price surge of the late 1980s. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The High Court will today decide whether to reopen a 1994 judgement on the landmark Theophanous case, which related to a defamation claim by Federal politician Andrew Theophanous and established a constitutional basis for a right to free speech for the frst time. The Federal Government will today argue that the case should be re-opened because it raises issues relating to the role of the courts and the Parliament. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The National Party Federal conference in Sydney at the weekend reaffirmed the National's support for Australia to remain a republic, with National Party leader and Deputy Prime Minister Tim Fischer telling the conference the republic issue was a &quot;tenth order issue&quot; which could become &quot;a first order issue if Australia tampers with its constitution without due consideration of all the ramifications&quot;. Page 4.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Papua New Guinea Prime Minister Sir Julius Chan has snubbed Canberra again, this time vowing to push ahead with his 'radical Bougainville initiative', which includes the hire of mercenaries, after confirming his Government is hoping to buy back RTZ-CRA's hare of the giant Bougainville copper mine. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Queensland Premier Rob Borbidge said yesterday his Government would go against the Australian Constitution and replace Senator Mal Colston with an independent Senator if he were to leave Federal Parliament because of allegations of expense rorts. Borbidge said he had received legal advice that Colston, elected on a Labor Party ticket, could be replaced by an independent. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard yesterday called on the States to search out new revenue building options aside from gambling, yet New South Wales Treasurer Michael Egan said the States had no other option but to turn to gambling revenue because of Federal cut. However, Queensland Premier Rob Borbidge backed Howard's call, saying the States themselves were developing their own gambling addiction, yet he also called for a review of Federal-State financial relations. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard yesterday suggested Federal Cabinet may act to stop a damages pay out to a terminally ill survivor of the 1964 collision between HMAS Voyager and HMAS Melbourne in fear the payout could flow on to hundreds of other crewmen. Page3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>New South Wales Urban Affairs Minister Craig Knowles has in principle backed a call by key planners, architects and academics for a major overhaul of Sydney's planning system to create a centralised authority that would be responsible for all major plannig developments that impact on the CBD. Lord Mayor Frank Sartor has also put his support behind the call. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a bid to call a stop to the long-running secessionist war in Bougainville, the Papua New Guinea government is looking to reopen the Bougainville copper mine, a plan that centres on an offer to buy out the stake of an Australian company, CRA, in Bougainille Copper Limited (BCL). Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>An announcement is expected soon of the sale of a million engines by Australian car maker Holden to Korean carmaker Daewoo -- a sale that would set a record for Australian-manufactured exports. The sale would be under a five-year contract worth between A$.7 billion and A$1.8 billion. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A technique trialled at St Vincent's Clinic in Sydney last week could prove to be an easier alternative for some prostate cancer patients than surgery or conventional radiotherapy. It involves injecting dozens of tinyradioactive pellets into the tumour. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard yesterday revealed figures showing that Australians lost A$9.4 billion in gambling in the last year, causing a debate over the social consequences of Australia's burgeoning gaming industry. The figures supplied to Howard showed an increase in gambling spending after the introduction of poker machines to Victoria and Queensland and the building of new casinos, including Melbourne's Crown Casino. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian-trained commander of the rebel forces in Papua New Guinea's Bougainville, General Sam Kaouna, has called on Australia for greater intervention in the Bougainville crisis, as guerrilla forces attacked a mercenary base in southern Bougainville, apparently using Australian helicopters, which breaches an agreement between the Australian and Papua New Guinea Governments. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Queensland Premier Rob Borbidge said yesterday he would reappoint an independent Senator to replace former Labor Senator Mal Colston, should Colston resign amid allegations of breaching his parliamentary privileges. The proposal by Borbidge caused a stir in the ALP, with the Party saying it would contest Borbidge's plan in the High Court. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A man in his 20s wielding a tomahawk was shot dead by police in Thomastown last night following reports of an attempted armed robbery on a pharmacy. The man, who is believed to have been shot inside the pharmacy, died of a bullet wound to the chest at Prston and Northcote Community Hospital around 10.45pm last night. Page A1.</p>
<p>-- Reuter Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
