<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413409" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ECUADOR: Majority of Ecuadorans back economic plan - poll.</title>
<headline>Majority of Ecuadorans back economic plan - poll.</headline>
<dateline>QUITO 1997-03-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The great majority of Ecuadorans back the economic measures announced Friday by interim President Fabian Alarcon, a private pollster said Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;In a poll we conducted minutes after Alarcon's speech, 63 percent considered the proposal was either good or very good,&quot; polling firm CEDATOS director Polibio Cordoba told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;This means there was an acceptance of the clear and moderate presentation made by the President.&quot;</p>
<p>The survey polled 322 persons in 10 of Ecuador's 21 provinces, with a 97 percent margin of error, he said.</p>
<p>The poll showed 32 percent of the Ecuadorans think the economy will get &quot;much better&quot;, 31 percent think it will be &quot;better,&quot; and 34 percent think there will be no change.</p>
<p>&quot;This rather shows there is a marked optimism in the population...The people's pessimism is over,&quot; said Cordoba.</p>
<p>Alarcon was named interim President last month by Congress after it removed Abdala Bucaram on grounds of &quot;mental incapacity.&quot; Alarcon announced on Friday a range of measures to close the fiscal gap and foster economic growth.</p>
<p>((-- Franz Bastidas, Quito Newsroom, 5932 25849))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="QUITO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ECUADOR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
