<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413553" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish generals serve notice on Islamist premier.</title>
<headline>Turkish generals serve notice on Islamist premier.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Lyons</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-03-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's generals have warned the ruling Islamists that they want a government crackdown on what they see as a wave of religious zeal threatening secular democracy.</p>
<p>The army brass used a nine-hour meeting of the National Security Council to demand Necmettin Erbakan, modern Turkey's first Islamist prime minister, get tough with the very religious radicals who make up a key portion of his constituency.</p>
<p>Turkish newspapers said on Sunday the military-dominated Council, guardian of the secular system and a vestige from an earlier era of army rule, presented in the meeting on Friday a detailed list of measures designed to rein in religious ferment.</p>
<p>But Erbakan sought to paper over the rift, telling his Welfare Party leadership the army and the politicians &quot;were in complete harmony&quot;.</p>
<p>The liberal daily Radikal said the army's demands included tighter supervision of religious instruction, surveillance and even closing of the often-secretive Islamic brotherhoods, or tarikats, and enforcement of restrictions on Islamic dress.</p>
<p>Other steps include limiting enrolment in religious training programmes, investigations of Islamist-owned businesses -- a key source of Welfare's funding -- and cutting off grants to Turkish students abroad who engage in Islamist activities.</p>
<p>&quot;The country's NSC is recommending the country's government take precautions against itself,&quot; said Radikal commentator Ismet Berkan.</p>
<p>The NSC said it would create a system to monitor progress on its wish-list under the direction of General Ilhan Kilic, the council's general secretary, Radikal said.</p>
<p>The burden of enforcing the measures will fall largely on Erbakan's justice minister, a provincial lawyer already under assault for catering to Islamic militancy, the paper said.</p>
<p>NSC meetings are closed to the press and participants made no comment beyond a joint communique issued after the meeting. Other newspapers carried lists similar to that in Radikal.</p>
<p>Erbakan's Islamist backers and his secularist coalition partner, Foreign Minister Tansu Ciller, were keen to play down the rift, declaring that the army would not mount a coup. But all politicians, and virtually any Turkish schoolchild, can reel off the three previous occasions when the army stepped into domestic politics.</p>
<p>&quot;The coup dossier has been closed,&quot; said the Islamist daily Yeni Safak in a frontpage headline.</p>
<p>&quot;Let no one have any expectation that democracy will be interrupted,&quot; Ciller told reporters on Saturday.</p>
<p>Erbakan, meanwhile, told leaders of his Welfare Party in Ankara he would be meeting other parliamentary factions later this week &quot;to expand further the atmosphere of tranquillity and security in the country&quot;.</p>
<p>However, there were few indications the top force commanders, none of whom made any comment after the marathon NSC meeting, were prepared to sit on their hands forever.</p>
<p>The army has intervened three times before when it felt events were spinning out of control. The most recent intervention, in 1980, followed years of left-right street violence but was ostensibly sparked by a pro-Islamist rally Erbakan led in the Anatolian city of Konya.</p>
<p>Friday's meeting capped months of escalating tensions over the increasingly Islamist policies of the coalition government and Turkey's secularist elite, bolstered by the armed forces.</p>
<p>Last month General Cevik Bir, the armed forces' second-in-command, used a visit to the United States to blast the Islamists and to vow not to permit any change in NATO-member Turkey's secular order.</p>
<p>And on February 4, army commanders sent a tank column on manoeuvres through an Islamist district of Ankara after an anti-Israel protest gave way to demands for the introduction of Koranic sharia law.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
