<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413502" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: N.Korea defector still wants to go to Seoul-radio.</title>
<headline>N.Korea defector still wants to go to Seoul-radio.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Korean defector Hwang Jang-yop, stuck for almost three weeks in Seoul's mission in Beijing, still wants to go to Seoul and not another country, South Korea's state radio reported on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Korean Broadcasting System radio quoted a senior Foreign Ministry official as saying there was no change in Hwang's asylum request. Hwang is the most senior Pyongyang official ever to flee North Korea.</p>
<p>&quot;Hwang has wanted to go to Seoul and there is no change in that stance,&quot; director-general of the ministry's Asia-Pacific Affairs Bureau Ryu Kwang-sok was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry officials could not immediately be reached for comment.</p>
<p>His remarks came in response to local media reports that the top Pyongyang ideologue, who walked into the South Korean mission on February 12 to seek political asylum, had implied he might opt for the United States as his final destination.</p>
<p>The reports were not clearly sourced.</p>
<p>South Korean efforts to persuade China to allow Hwang safe passage to Seoul have so far made no progress.</p>
<p>Hwang's defection has further strained ties between the two Koreas, technically at war for about half a century after their 1950-53 conflict ended only in a truce, but there have been signs in recent days that the crisis may be easing.</p>
<p>Pyongyang, which at first insisted that Hwang had been kidnapped by South Korean agents and demanded his return, last week appeared to accept his defection, vowing that if he had fled he would be stripped of his official posts.</p>
<p>And after stalling for some time, North Korea has at last sent a delegation to New York to discuss the possibility of opening talks on building a lasting peace on the divided peninsula.</p>
<p>The New York meeting, set for March 5, was called to brief North Korea on a joint proposal by the U.S. and South Korean presidents for four-way talks between the three countries plus Pyongyang's traditional ally, China.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
