<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413518" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Shum Yip debut seen strong on parent company ties.</title>
<headline>Shum Yip debut seen strong on parent company ties.</headline>
<byline>Donny Kwok</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-03-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strong ties to the Shenzhen municipal government and hopes of a big asset injection should ensure a strong trading debut by Shum Yip Investment Ltd on the Hong Kong stock market on Friday, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The shares are likely to trade above its grey market price (of about HK$3.00) in view of its strong subscription,&quot; said Anthony Mak, sales director at Vickers Ballas.</p>
<p>Shum Yip has offered 250 million shares at HK$1.85 (US$0.24) per share, with 175 million shares placed internationally and 75 million shares offered to the public in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>The company engages in property development and investment primarily in Shenzhen, in China across the border from Hong Kong. It also provides transportation services in China, and between Hong Kong and China.</p>
<p>The flotation is more than 300 times oversubscribed, sources said. Shum Yip is due to issue an official statement on the subscription results on March 4.</p>
<p>Analysts said the grey market price reflects a price to earnings multiple of 20 times, double the initial p/e ratio of 10 times to reflect prospects of an asset injection from Shum Yip's parent company.</p>
<p>&quot;Its parent (Shum Yip Holding Co Ltd) owns some of the quality infrastructure projects in Shenzhen and a possible injection of such assets will definitely boost a higher profit for the company,&quot; said Pamela Lam, analyst at Pacific Challenge Securities.</p>
<p>The company's parent, Shum Yip Holdings Co Ltd, acts as the trading and investment vehicle for the Shenzhen Municipal Government in Hong Kong, and also works to build economic ties between Shenzhen and overseas investors.</p>
<p>&quot;We are optimistic over its long-term prospects in view of strong support from Shenzhen municipal government,&quot; Lam said.</p>
<p>Many expect underwriters to exercise their option to require Shum Yip to issue a further 37.5 million shares to cover over-allotment.</p>
<p>Analysts said many investors were also hoping that Shum Yip would repeat the story of Shanghai Industrial Holdings Ltd, which has soared to HK$34 a share within one year of listing at HK$7.24 a share.</p>
<p>&quot;Many would expect the issue could mirror the successful Shanghai Industrial, whose share price surged from its listing in May last year,&quot; Lam said.</p>
<p>Shanghai Industrial is the Hong Kong-based investment arm of Shanghai municipal government.</p>
<p>Analysts said a switch in focus among Hong Kong investors to China-related stocks, so-called red-chips and H shares, following the recent blue-chip rally should also boost enthusiasm for the Shum Yip listing.</p>
<p>Analysts said they were optimistic about the Shenzhen economy because Hong Kong and Shenzhen would be linked even tighter after the sovereignty handover in July 1997.</p>
<p>Shum Yip said net proceeds would be used to develop intercity coach services in China, build a nationwide car rental business and use the balance to finance its existing property development projects and for general working capital.</p>
<p>After the listing, Shum Yim Investment's parent, Shum Yip Holdings, will hold 63 percent of the company.</p>
<p>Cheung Kong (Holdings) Ltd will hold 3.5 percent, a subsidiary of Peregrine Investments Holdings Ltd will hold three percent, 2.5 percent will be owned by KP Choi Ltd, two percent by Tai Ping Life Insurance Co Ltd and one percent will be held by Conch Development Ltd.</p>
<p>($1 = HK$7.74)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
