<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413639" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. military college holds disciplinary hearings.</title>
<headline>U.S. military college holds disciplinary hearings.</headline>
<dateline>CHARLESTON, S.C. 1997-03-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Citadel military college Saturday began disciplinary hearings for 11 cadets accused of participating in alleged hazing of some of the school's first women cadets, Citadel spokesman Terry Leedom said.</p>
<p>The hearings, closed to the public and the press, were expected to continue Sunday. No announcement on the outcome was expected until Wednesday.</p>
<p>Three cadets, two seniors and a junior, were charged with most serious violations that include physical violence, abusive treatment, failure to report hazing and poor judgment. They could be expelled if found guilty.</p>
<p>The eight other cadets face lesser charges, including failure to report hazing and sexual harassment.</p>
<p>Jeanie Mentavlos and Kim Messer, the two female cadets the men were accused of hazing, did not attend Saturday's hearings. Their attorneys, Tim Kulp and Paul Gibson, said in a letter to the school that they did not want the women there because their lawyers could not participate or record the hearings independently.</p>
<p>&quot;Our clients remain ready, willing, and able to offer sworn testimony in any judicial proceedings wherein witnesses are placed under oath, rights to counsel are fully recognised ... proceedings are open to the public and a reliable record of these proceedings is made,&quot; the letter said.</p>
<p>Messer and Mentavlos withdrew from the Citadel in January. The two women, who were among four women enrolled at the state-funded school after it changed its all-male admissions policy last summer, had alleged they were victims of severe hazing, physical violence and harassment.</p>
<p>Among other things, they claimed they were sprayed with fingernail polish remover and then set on fire.</p>
<p>The hearings had been scheduled for Feb. 22, but were postponed when parents and cadets complained about &quot;the extensive questioning&quot; by attorneys for the Justice Department, the school said in a statement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHARLESTON, S.C."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
