<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413651" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GE shows interest in Dow Jones - report.</title>
<headline>GE shows interest in Dow Jones - report.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Electric Co. would consider buying up to a 25 percent stake in the financial information company Dow Jones &amp; Co. Inc. to link it up with its television news operations, The New Yorker magazine says in its latest issue.</p>
<p>Citing an &quot;important&quot; GE executive, the report said the company would consider linking Dow Jones with news operations run by its NBC television unit.</p>
<p>The article also said privately held Bloomberg Inc.'s Michael Bloomberg had expressed interest in Dow Jones, especially its flagship newspaper, The Wall Street Journal.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an opportunity for G.E. if we could be a white knight for the company with the family,&quot; the magazine quoted the executive as saying. &quot;But it would work for G.E. only if Dow Jones should become a more profit-driven company.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman for General Electric declined to comment on the article and Dow Jones officials were not immediately available to comment.</p>
<p>The article, written by Ken Auletta, appears in the March 10 issue of the New Yorker, available on newstands Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;This executive speculated that G.E. could buy a 20-to-25-pecent stake and then link the Dow Jones news operations with NBC, CNBC, and the joint Microsoft/NBC effort, MSNBC,&quot; the article said. &quot;But, this executive makes clear, G.E. would want to see Dow Jones sell Telerate.&quot;</p>
<p>Dow Jones announced plans in January to spend $650 million to expand and revitalize its Telerate financial information services unit, whose name was recently changed to Dow Jones Markets.</p>
<p>More recently, reports have emerged that younger members of the family that controls Dow Jones were disatisfied with the plan and were pushing for management to improve shareholder value at the company.</p>
<p>A group of dissident shareholders led by investor Michael Price have called on the company to call off the $650 million investment in Telerate and consider disposing the unit.</p>
<p>In addition, The New Yorker article said Peter Kann, chairman and chief executive of Dow Jones, had met NBC's Robert Wright to discuss a possible joint venture.</p>
<p>&quot;Wright, looking at his vulnerability -- overseas business news -- proposed that they join forces 'outside the United States,'&quot; it said, citing an anonymous NBC official.</p>
<p>&quot;Kann, however, according to a well-placed Dow Jones source, wanted to focus on his company's weakest point -- television business news and distribution inside the United States,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;(He) proposed that they 'weave together the resources' of business-news operations of the Dow Jones New York television station and CNBC's national cable business-news channel.&quot;</p>
<p>It said Kann and Wright &quot;parted amicably&quot; without elaborating.</p>
<p>The article also said Michael Bloomberg had expressed interest in Dow Jones.</p>
<p>&quot;(Bloomberg) has focused on Dow Jones &amp; Co. and, in particular, on the Wall Street Journal, which he would love to own,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The article noted Bloomberg was reported recently to have said he would never pay the $1.6 billion Dow Jones paid when it bought Telerate, preferring to &quot;sit back and wait.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I asked Kenneth I. Burenga, the president and No. 2 official of Dow Jones -- and the acting chief executive officer of Telerate -- how he would sell his service to a prospective customer,&quot; the writer said in the article.</p>
<p>&quot;At first, Burenga invoked the sum -- $650 million -- that the board had just invested to improve Telerate's service,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In January, the U.S. magazine Business Week said Reuters Holdings Plc had expressed interest in either buying, merging or forming a joing venture with Dow Jones.</p>
<p>Reuters later declined to comment on what it called &quot;speculation&quot; and &quot;rumor&quot; while Dow Jones described the report as &quot;nonesense&quot; and &quot;pure speculation.&quot;</p>
<p>Bloomberg, Dow Jones and Reuters compete with each other in the financial news and information market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
