<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="413738" id="root" date="1997-03-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India preparing for full rupee convertibility.</title>
<headline>India preparing for full rupee convertibility.</headline>
<byline>Shyam Kumar</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-03-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's next big leap in the march towards a free market -- full convertibility of the rupee -- could come within three years, bankers and analysts said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;The fear that money will move out (following convertibility on the capital account) is dying out,&quot; Subir Biswas, senior manager (treasury) at ABN AMRO Bank, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be a historic step on the road to liberalisation,&quot; said a dealer at a French bank's Bombay treasury. &quot;Every finance minister will want it to happen in his tenure.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think for the first time we are confident we can meet some of the pre-conditions (for full convertibility),&quot; Finance Minister P. Chidambaram said after presenting the 1997/98 budget (April-March) on Friday.</p>
<p>Reserve Bank of India governor Chakravarty Rangarajan said full convertibility on the capital account required adequate reserves, a moderate fiscal deficit and an inflation rate comparable with industrialised nations.</p>
<p>Criticism of full convertibility in the past centred on fears of capital outflows. Indian businessmen are believed to have stashed away billions of dollars in overseas banks in contravention of India's Foreign Exchange Regulation Act (FERA).</p>
<p>&quot;As long as India is seen as a destination for investment, convertibility will only induce flows into the country,&quot; said a banker.</p>
<p>He said foreign institutional investors have been investing in Indian stock markets despite a lack of currency hedging products.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a lot of confidence in India already,&quot; said a treasurer at a foreign bank. He said the redemption of dollar-denominated India Development Bonds last month saw a large chunk of proceeds being reinvested within the country.</p>
<p>&quot;India's top companies would welcome full convertibility,&quot; said a finance manager at one of India's leading engineering firms. &quot;We will have to get ourselves rated and there won't be any government-fixed cap on external commercial borrowings.&quot;</p>
<p>Chidambaram said the outdated FERA would be replaced by a Foreign Exchange Management Act (FEMA). It will provide for introduction of capital convertibility in a phased manner and set limits on the extent to which the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) can buy and hold foreign exchange.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry also proposed establishment of a committee to prepare a &quot;road map&quot; for full convertibility. The committee is to submit its report by May 30, 1997.</p>
<p>Some bankers said the development of a domestic term money market and reference interest rates such as LIBOR should precede full convertibility, but others believed these were not a must.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not that others with full convertibility in the region have fully developed money markets,&quot; said a treasurer.</p>
<p>&quot;Full convertibility on the capital account will come in stages,&quot; he said. &quot;It won't be like a big bang.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
