<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414034" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-WIMBLEDON SALVAGE DRAW AT COVENTRY.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-WIMBLEDON SALVAGE DRAW AT COVENTRY.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wimbledon gained a hard earned 1-1 draw at relegation-threatened Coventry on Monday to maintain their challenge for a place in Europe next season.</p>
<p>The London side, playing their fourth game in nine days as they press for honours in three domestic competitions, took the lead in the 32nd minute through Efan Ekoku against the run of play.</p>
<p>Ekoku received a through-ball from Neil Ardley on the right flank, eluded a misjudged challenge by Gary Breen and drove his acute-angled shot in off the far post.</p>
<p>Coventry equalised five minutes later when Gary McAllister sent in a corner from the left and Dion Dublin scored with a glancing header.</p>
<p>Coventry, beaten 3-1 by leaders Manchester United on Saturday, dominated the game at their Highfield Road ground but had to settle for just one point, which left them 16th in the 20-strong premier league with 29 points from 29 games.</p>
<p>They are four points above the bottom three in the relegation zone but have played at least two games more than all their fellow strugglers.</p>
<p>Wimbledon, through to the semifinals of the League Cup and quarter-finals of the F.A. Cup, were happy to emerge with a point and remained sixth in the table.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
