<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414181" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LME metals sweep higher on firm nickel, funds.</title>
<headline>LME metals sweep higher on firm nickel, funds.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Base metal prices soared on Monday afternoon, inspired by strong gains in the jittery nickel market and an influx of speculative interest.</p>
<p>Zinc peaked at a 4-1/2 year high after breaching a key resistance level, while aluminium hit a near one-year high and copper approached last week's nine month high.</p>
<p>Nickel prices led the way, shooting up to a 9-1/2 month high of $8,320 per tonne on weekend news that workers at Russia's huge Norilsk complex had adopted a strike plan.</p>
<p>It settled near its highs at $8,310, a gain of $240 from Friday's kerb close. Traders said it was aiming at $8,400 next.</p>
<p>But the market would be watching closely for more news on the strike. Norilsk management said they could not meet union demands for repayment of salary arrears, but predicted workers would not stop production fully.</p>
<p>The LME's upward momentum was extended in the afternoon with U.S. funds coming onto the scene, attracted by some metals' proximity to technical break out points, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;When you have two or three strong metals, the euphoria usually spread to the others,&quot; said analyst Robin Bhar of brokers Brandeis.</p>
<p>Copper regained the $2,400 level and touched last week's high trade of $2,415 before settling at $2,408, a gain of $30 from Friday's close.</p>
<p>Aluminium posted an even stronger technical close of $1,690, a gain of $36 and the highest since March 21, 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that it closed above the previous high close of $1,680 is a bullish. Aluminium is also seeing good consumer interest,&quot; Bhar said.</p>
<p>Zinc also sped higher, punching briefly to a 4-1/2 year high when it touched $1,240. It ended just below at $1,239, a gain of $21 on the day.</p>
<p>A re-test of those highs may expose some buy stops and set off further sharp gains, analysts said.</p>
<p>Tuesday's LME stocks report will likely set the tone for the market's near term direction, with a small drawdown expected in copper and a larger decline forecast in aluminium.</p>
<p>The other base metals absorbed the positive tone, although their gains were less notable.</p>
<p>Lead was slightly firmer at $702, up $4, while tin racked up $70 to end at $5,860.</p>
<p>Alloy finished at $1,560 versus $1,540/45.</p>
<p>--Lida Poletz, London newsroom +44 171 542 2936</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
