<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414114" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: OLYMPICS-STOCKHOLM BID FIGHTS PUBLIC APATHY.</title>
<headline>OLYMPICS-STOCKHOLM BID FIGHTS PUBLIC APATHY.</headline>
<byline>Birgitta Forsberg</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stockholm Olympic bid organisers have been forced to fight a wave of public apathy and even downright hostility in order to sell the prospect of the 2004 Games to a nation not renowned for extroverts.</p>
<p>The Swedish capital's modest size, with 718,000 inhabitants perched at the edge of the Baltic Sea, means 75 percent of sports arenas are within a range of 1.5 km.</p>
<p>According to bid committee spokesman Finn Persson, if Stockholm is selected, the Olympic village and the Olympic stadium would only be 200 metres apart, closer than they have ever been.</p>
<p>The Olympic outdoor stadium for 70,000 spectators is scheduled for construction at Hammarbybacken, just south of the city centre.</p>
<p>Next to it the Olympic village will consist of a housing area, Hammarby Sjostad, which the local authorities had already planned to build.</p>
<p>From the village a five-minute ride on a tram would bring competitors to Stockholmsmassan, a large and sprawling conference trade centre where boxing, wrestling, fencing and judo would be held.</p>
<p>Basketball supporters would face a 35-minute commuter train ride to the neighboring town of Sodertalje.</p>
<p>Soccer fans, interested in the early rounds, will have to be more adventurous going 640 kms to Malmo in the very south, to nearby Helsingborg, to Gothenberg in the west and to Norrkoping 165 kms south of Stockholm.</p>
<p>Neither transportation nor housing will be a problem, according to Persson.</p>
<p>&quot;During the (annual) Water Festival, the city can handle 450,000 people moving around on one night and during the Olympics there will be 300,000 people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The city will be able to offer 33,000 hotel rooms, 9,500 spaces at camping grounds or chalets, 2,500 beds at hostels and 40,000 in private homes. The media will be housed in 10,000 university students' rooms.</p>
<p>Sweden's Olympic Committee expects 155,000 visitors a day, including spectators, sports teams and media. Spectators from abroad are expected to total 40,000.</p>
<p>Persson also believes Sweden's climate will be in Stockholm's favour, with around 19 hours of daylight during the height of the summer.</p>
<p>Not everybody shares Persson's enthusiasm.</p>
<p>Swedes squeezed by cuts in the traditionally generous welfare state and rising unemployment are worried about potential losses.</p>
<p>Critics point to the world  athletics championships held in Gothenberg in 1995, which proved a successful sports event but bankrupted organisers who were unable to control runaway costs and low attendances.</p>
<p>A survey by pollster Temo published on February 16 showed 47 percent of Swedes were against Stockholm hosting the Olympics, while 35 percent were for and 18 percent were undecided. But the positive side advanced, up from 30 percent in November.</p>
<p>Among the most outspoken critics is the Environmental Party, with 18 of the parliament's 349 seats. It dismisses the idea as too tough on the environment and, above all, too costly.</p>
<p>&quot;We are against the economic concept, which means that Stockholm city taxpayers are liable to pay all eventual losses,&quot; Ewa Larsson, a Green Party parliament member dealing with the issue, said.</p>
<p>The Swedish parliament has ruled that the government will guarantee a 2.5-billion-crown lottery, which is part of the 12 billion crown budget.</p>
<p>In addition, the central government will cover possible losses, which the city of Stockholm then will have to pay.</p>
<p>Larsson also pointed out that a court case is still pending about whether the city's government has a legal right to pledge to cover the losses.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
