<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414231" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dollar ends firm in Europe, supported by NAPM.</title>
<headline>Dollar ends firm in Europe, supported by NAPM.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar was firm and near session peaks at its European close, buoyed by a stronger-than-expected February report from the National Association of Purchasing Management (NAPM).</p>
<p>The NAPM index rose to 53.1 in February, stronger  than consensus estimates of a rise to 52.9 percent, and up from 52.0 in January.</p>
<p>&quot;February's NAPM was robust across the board - a strong 53.1 - which suggests the U.S. economy is still expanding,&quot; said Ernesto Ramirez, European economist at Bankers Trust.</p>
<p>The dollar increased from around 1.6910 marks ahead of the NAPM figure to just above 1.6930 marks after it was released. At 1604 GMT the dollar was trading at 1.6941/47 marks against 1.6878/84 in late dealings on Friday.</p>
<p>The dollar also received a fresh lift against the yen, firming to 120.87/0.92 yen at 1604 GMT from 120.50/55 in late Europe on Friday.</p>
<p>While overall the NAPM was robust, analysts said the unemployment index at 45.4 in February against 48.7 in January was weak. &quot;Unemployment, at 45.4 and down from 48.7, was weak. I think the treasury market was relieved by that number,&quot; said Ramirez at Bankers Trust.  </p>
<p>Analysts said asset markets, however, should remain nervous before Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan gives the second-leg of his Humphrey-Hawkins testimony before the House on Wednesday.</p>
<p>U.S. stocks slid 40 points at the open to 6837, helping push dollar/mark just below 1.69 marks before recovering as U.S. stocks cut losses.</p>
<p>Most of the dollar's gains against the mark held after the mark was hit in early dealings by reports of on German joblessness in February. The German unit's losses were limited, however, by concerns about EMU's timetable.  </p>
<p>The early dollar boost came as Sunday's Bild am Sonntag said German unemployment rose by 120,000 to a post-war record of 4.8 million last month. A rise of that magnitude would lift the jobless rate to 12.5 percent from 12.2 percent, the paper said.</p>
<p>February German jobless data is due on Thursday and is expected to be in sharp contrast to its U.S. equivalent Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;If German unemployment continues to rise at the pace suggested by this report then, we're going to see dollar/mark a lot higher,&quot; said Jesper Dannesboe, economist at ABN Amro.  </p>
<p>A vigorous verbal defence of the EMU timetable from a range of European officials helped calm early market jitters sparked after Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi on Friday said it was possible Germany might request a delay to EMU.</p>
<p>The lira and Italian bonds, already hurt by speculation of EMU delay, racked up even more losses after Prodi's remarks.</p>
<p>The lira had recovered in late Europe against the mark and stood at 999.25/9.75 lire at 1719 GMT after a low of 1003.60 lire.</p>
<p>Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer and European Monetary Institute president Alexandre Lamfalussy said earlier that EMU delay rumours were nonsense.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer said he would be delighted to have Italy join EMU if it met the economic criteria.</p>
<p>Later, French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette said no one should doubt France and Germany's determination to stick to their EMU plans.</p>
<p>Bundesbank council member Ernst Welteke said any delay in EMU would have the negative effect of giving a sharp boost to the German mark. In a speech prepared for delivery in the north city of Kiel, Welteke also said there was no provision in the Maastricht Treaty for delaying the single currency launch. -- Julia Meehan, London newsroom +4471 542 6701</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
