<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414269" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Arakis CEO says pipeline process to start.</title>
<headline>Arakis CEO says pipeline process to start.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Arakis Energy Corp, with a signed deal for its Sudan oil project now under its belt, planned this week to start finding construction companies to build a pipeline, the company's chief executive said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have got a very aggressive schedule. We're planning to go out for prequalifications within the next few days,&quot; Arakis's John McLeod said.</p>
<p>The prequalification will be held to hammer down a list of companies, or groups of firms, that have the ability to construct the 1,500-km line.  </p>
<p>Bidding for the project's construction was slated to start in April and construction by the end of this year, McLeod said.</p>
<p>He said the line, to extend to the Red Sea from the firm's oilfields in southern Sudan, would initially be equipped to ship 150,000 barrels of oil a day by the end of 1999, but woulds be expandable to 250,000 BPD.</p>
<p>McLeod confirmed earlier on Monday that Arakis and its partners in the US$1 billion project signed the final agreement for the development in Khartoum on Saturday.  </p>
<p>Under the 25-year agreement -- which was much anticipated by investors -- Arakis has 25 percent, China National Petroleum Corp 40 percent, Malaysia state oil company Petronas 30 percent and the Sudan government five percent.</p>
<p>The deal was initially announced in early December after more than a year of controversy and failed attempts to finance the project in the civil strife-torn African nation.</p>
<p>The consortium plans to develop the project through a joint operating company, which McLeod said would likely be ready to take over operatorship in June.</p>
<p>McLeod that that the company planned to begin easing into other projects, now that the Sudan development appeared to be well under way.</p>
<p>The company plans to drill a well in Oman in April.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking in other areas of the world. We're looking at late-stage exploration and early-stage development or a production enhancement-type project,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking at something that's close to cash flow or somewhere where you can...take a rig in, start drilling and start selling oil.&quot;</p>
<p>((Reuters Calgary Bureau (403) 531-1624))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
