<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414225" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Closing stock market indices.</title>
<headline>Closing stock market indices.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here is how major stock markets outside the United States ended on Monday.</p>
<p>LONDON - London's FTSE 100 share index fought off an early attack of Wall Street-inspired weakness to end little changed on Monday as investors tried to ignore fears of further losses across the Atlantic. The FTSE ended 1.2 points down at 4,307.1.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Germany's main DAX-30 index closes an uninspired bourse session just ahead, with any real buying interest held back by Wall Street's lower close on Friday and by the lack of any market-making news. The M-DAX index of mid-sized German shares meanwhile driven to new highs after technical break-out. The DAX-30 index of leading shares closed 4.22 points, or 0.13 percent, higher at 3,263.86. In post-boures trade the index fell 2.30 to 3,258.74.</p>
<p>PARIS - French shares drifted to close with moderate losses on Monday, lacking domestic momentum and taking their steer from softness on Wall Street. The CAC index had been supported by dollar strength since the opening, but faded as investment interest waned in the afternoon, leaving it vulnerable to New York's sway. The blue-chip CAC-40 index closed down 7.29 points or 0.28 percent at 2,600.26.</p>
<p>ZURICH - Swiss shares ended lower for the third session in a row, continuing what dealers described as a welcome consolidation after a stretch of strong gains. The All-share Swiss Performance Index (SPI) fell 13.57 points, or 0.48 percent, to close at 2,837.99.</p>
<p>TOKYO - Tokyo stocks finished down on Monday, but were able to recover somewhat from earlier lows as bargain-hunting offset some losses due to fresh selling interest in banking shares, brokers said. They said the direction of the market was unclear and participants were mostly sidelined. The 225-share Nikkei average lost 127.87 points, or 0.69 percent, to close at 18,429.13.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Property counters were back in the limelight on Monday after their recent dull performance, leading Hong Kong stocks to a strong close as investors anticipated a strong response to upcoming property sales. The Hang Seng Index closed on a gain of 108.56 points, or 0.81 percent, at 13,507.28.</p>
<p>SYDNEY - Australian shares slipped more than one percent on Monday as investors factored in the effects of a possible U.S. rate increase on local bonds, taking some of the gloss off the high yielding bank sector. The benchmark All Ordinaries index ended 28.7 points lower at 2,421.1.</p>
<p>JOHANNESBURG - South African industrials and all-shares thwart market expectations of a retracement in late afternoon and climb to close on mostly futures-driven trade. Those shares generally shrug off Wall Street's weakness last Friday and trade this week seen a tussle between bulls and bears. Industrial index adds 16.7 points to 8,261.0, all-shares rise 8.6 to 7,153.8 and golds off 2.9 to 1,562.9.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
