<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414325" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: IMF delays cash to Kenya over privatisation.</title>
<headline>IMF delays cash to Kenya over privatisation.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A second IMF disbursement of $37 million to Kenya under a soft-loans programme has been delayed for three months because of what the Fund sees as slow progress on privatisation, financial sources said on Monday.</p>
<p>Senior officials involved in Kenya's privatisation said an International Monetary Fund (IMF) review mission in December was not completed because a privatisation timetable for the Kenya Posts &amp; Telecommunications Corp (KP&amp;TC) was not presented.</p>
<p>The IMF in Nairobi said the outstanding issues were mainly structural and revolved around privatisation because donors did not want the Kenyan government to continue bailing out ailing parastatals.</p>
<p>&quot;What we want is to avoid budgetary funds being used to help out ailing parastatals,&quot; said an IMF official. &quot;We want to see faster progress towards privatising such concerns.&quot;</p>
<p>Last year, Kenya agreed a $220 million aid plan under the IMF soft-loans Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility (ESAF).</p>
<p>The first tranche of $37 million was issued early last year and the second tranche was due in November 1997. An IMF mission in August and follow-up in December failed to complete the review.</p>
<p>The IMF Nairobi office said questions on budgetary targets were fairly limited. An official said that although government expenditure in December was higher than forecast, revenues were also much higher than forecast.</p>
<p>He said the main worry was budget-busting in a government effort to import food for drought victims.</p>
<p>President Daniel arap Moi has already declared the drought a national disaster and appealed for international food aid.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope authorities can keep this (drought-related) expenditure to a minimum. They have appealed to donors who have pledged funds and food. Some of this food has actually arrived,&quot; the IMF official, who declined to be quoted by name, told Reuters.</p>
<p>A privatisation official said the government was keen to see an IMF review completed, and whenever the team returned the posts and telecommunications case would be presented. The IMF mission was due in February but had postponed its visit until late March, the official said.</p>
<p>The earliest the delayed disbursement could be expected was April, according to senior financial analysts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
