<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414329" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SUDAN: Sudan denies it received weapons from Iraq.</title>
<headline>Sudan denies it received weapons from Iraq.</headline>
<dateline>KHARTOUM 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sudan on Monday denied a Sudanese opposition report that it had received an arms shipment from Iraq.</p>
<p>The Sudanese opposition's rebel commander General Fathi Ahmed Ali said in the Eritrean capital Asmara on Friday that a ship loaded with Iraqi weapons from a storage depot in Yemen arrived in Port Sudan for the government last week.</p>
<p>Sudanese Culture and Information Minister Army Brigadier al-Tayeb Ibrahim Mohamad Khair said such reports were aimed at deceiving international public opinion.</p>
<p>&quot;The opposition elements are used to circulating false claims of arms shipments sent to Sudan by Iran, Qatar, Yemen and Iraq,&quot; Khair told the official Sudan news agency SUNA.</p>
<p>Ali told Reuters in Asmara on Friday that an opposition source who was working within the military command had told them of the ship carrying arms.</p>
<p>&quot;When they were offloading the ship, a bomb exploded and killed Colonel Abu Alama al-Bakhid Hassan and lightly injured Major General Abbas al-Sayeed, who is the area commander of Port Sudan,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was reported in Khartoum that the officer was killed during routine testing of weapons.&quot;</p>
<p>The opposition's military commander said Sudanese President Lieutenant-General Omar Hassan al-Bashir travelled to Port Sudan on the day of the blast, which was February 20.</p>
<p>He said the arms included 600 anti-tank weapons and were just a part of the Iraqi weapons being stored in Yemen.</p>
<p>Ali heads the military wing of the National Democratic Alliance, a coalition of opposition groups based in Asmara.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ERTRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KHARTOUM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SUDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
