<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="41432" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FCOJ futures end mostly higher in light trade.</title>
<headline>FCOJ futures end mostly higher in light trade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Frozen concentrated orange juice futures ended mainly higher in light trade Monday as mixed speculative and local buying continued to lift the market from lows reached last week.</p>
<p>&quot;It is still a correction to an oversold market,&quot; said Kevin Marshburn, an analyst with Fimat Futures.</p>
<p>Last Thursday, orange juice futures slid to to their lowest levels since November 1995, prompted by a weak technical outlook.</p>
<p>November FCOJ settled 1.60 cents higher at 107.45 cents after trading from 108.00 to 104.90. Spot September, which expires at 1200 EDT Tuesday, ended up 1.95 at 117.70, while back months finished 1.70 higher to 1.40 lower.</p>
<p>Fundamentally, traders said the approach of Hurricane Hortense may have helped buoy the market. A Smith Barney forecaster said Monday Hortense, moving through the Caribbean near Puerto Rico, could make landfall in south Florida.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now, the probability of Hortense pushing into the Gulf appears to be slim. The probability of it striking south or southwestern Florida is a bit better,&quot; said Basilio Lopez, a forecaster for Smith Barney in Chicago. &quot;This would affect citrus interests.&quot;</p>
<p>At 1400 EDT/1500 GMT, the storm was about 130 miles southeast of Ponce, Puerto Rico, as it drifted northwestward with sustained winds of 80 mph/130 kph.</p>
<p>Hortense remained a weak Category 1 hurricane, according to National Hurricane Center.</p>
<p>Volume was light at an estimated 2,000 lots.</p>
<p>--New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
