<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414431" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo 1997 sugar beet acreage seen well below plan.</title>
<headline>Yugo 1997 sugar beet acreage seen well below plan.</headline>
<byline>Gordana Kukic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbian farmers, only a week ahead of the start of the sugar beet campaign, are still boycotting production contracts and industry experts say it is unlikely the crop will be sown on the planned 100,000 hectares.</p>
<p>&quot;The sugar beet acreage this year will be well below the plan. It will for sure be even under 60,000 hectares,&quot; Ljiljana Vasic, head of the Association of Agricultural Cooperatives from the country's bread-basket of Vojvodina, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;At the best possible circumstances the sugar beet acreage could remain at the 1996 level of 70,000 hectares.&quot;</p>
<p>The association of agricultural cooperatives earlier appealed to its members not to sign any contracts on spring planting with processing firms if they were not paid what was owed to them.</p>
<p>The Serbian government owes farmers some 800 million dinars for 1996 crops, about 425 million of which is for sugar beet.</p>
<p>According to the government's plan, 25 percent of the outstanding debt will be paid in cash and another 200 million in exchange for fuel and fertilisers.</p>
<p>The government expects sugar, oil, tobacco and vine producers to secure the rest of the 400 million dinars in cash by selling their products.</p>
<p>The government has set mid-March as the deadline for clearing the sugar beet and sunflower debt.</p>
<p>&quot;Payments are very slow. We expected at least the government's cash payments to arrive by March 6. But the amount received is symbolic,&quot; Vasic said.</p>
<p>According to the Serbian association of agricultural cooperatives, only 43 million dinars out of the 200 million cash had been paid out by last Friday.</p>
<p>Vasic said farmers would continue to boycott production deals because they feared producers were unwilling to meet their obligations.</p>
<p>&quot;We know the state will make maximum efforts to meet the deadline but only few producers said they would respect the government decision. Sugar plants have even postponed the payment deadline to May 1,&quot; Vasic said.</p>
<p>The association of sugar producers, Jugosecer, quoting unofficial reports, said production deals for sugar beet had been concluded for only about 20,000 hectares.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a drastic fall compared to last year when production deals for about 50,000 hectares were concluded by the beginning of March,&quot; said Milan Patkovic, a Jugosecer official.</p>
<p>Time is quickly running out for sugar beet producers. Industry experts expected the full campaign to start next week thanks to good weather conditions.</p>
<p>Out of 2.37 million hectares planned for spring planting, 1.4 million was planned to be sown with maize, 100,000 with sugar beet, 200,000 with sunflower, 80,000 with soy, 255,000 with vegetables and 190,000 with fodder crops.</p>
<p>&quot;The spring campaign will start but the plan for sugar beet and soy production will not be met. The sunflower and maize area might increase due to lower production costs,&quot; Vasic said. --Belgrade Newsroom +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100128">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
