<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414524" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentina's Menem calls TV probe reporters &quot;liars&quot;.</title>
<headline>Argentina's Menem calls TV probe reporters &quot;liars&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Brown</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's President Carlos Menem said on Monday that reporters behind an investigation into grandiose building projects in his tiny hometown were &quot;miserable liars.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;These journalists are miserable liars. They made this (television) programme paid by some sector of the opposition,&quot; a visibly angry Menem said during a visit to the province of Cordoba.</p>
<p>The report on two houses, an airstrip and a zoo in Menem's hometown of Anillaco in the northwestern desert province of La Rioja, was taken off the air by private TV channel America 2 on Wednesday for fear of legal repercussions. It aired a day later amid a dispute about alleged censorship.</p>
<p>It raised questions about who paid for Menem's huge, pink ranch-style home in Anillaco, a nearby mountain refuge with heliport and artificial lake, a new full-length runway built by the air force -- for a town of just 850 -- and a zoo.</p>
<p>The 67-year-old president last week called it an &quot;absurd&quot; attempt to tarnish his &quot;image, honesty and morality,&quot; and said on Monday it was &quot;ridiculous to talk about impeachment because this president has done nothing wrong.&quot;</p>
<p>But the Radical and centre-left Frepaso opposition parties have sent delegations to La Rioja to investigate the allegations. Radical Party official Daniel Cohan returned from the province on Monday talking of &quot;problems and anomalies.&quot;</p>
<p>America 2's suspension of the programme &quot;Without Limits&quot; last week because of what it said were legal concerns about the investigation by Roman Lejtman, a radio journalist who is a fierce critic of the Peronist government, forced Menem to publicly deny his government leaned on the broadcasters.</p>
<p>&quot;My government has never put pressure on anybody to make them change the thrust of their programmes, information or commentaries,&quot; Menem said. Aides said he had been building his house for 12 years -- before he became president in 1989 -- while the airstrip was funded by private donations.</p>
<p>After apparently relenting and broadcasting the show late on Thursday, the America group's owner Eduardo Eurnekian then decided on Friday to scrap the series.</p>
<p>The episode has raised concerns about freedom of the press among Argentine journalists already fearful for their liberties since the murder a month ago of a photographer for the outspoken news magazine Noticias.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
