<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414682" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Malaysia spearheads single ASEAN cocoa contract.</title>
<headline>Malaysia spearheads single ASEAN cocoa contract.</headline>
<byline>K.T. Arasu</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia is spearheading a move to bridge the quality gap among Southeast Asian cocoa producers and pave the way for a single ASEAN contract, an industry official said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are hoping to standardise the quality of cocoa produced in the region which is quite diverse at the moment,&quot; the head of the Malaysian Cocoa Board, Mohamed Musa Jamil, said.</p>
<p>&quot;The difference in quality leads to price disparity,&quot; he said in a phone interview with Reuters in Jakarta -- the venue for a two-day meeting of cocoa producers from the Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) starting on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Representatives from the government and private sectors of ASEAN members -- Brunei, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam -- will attend the meeting.</p>
<p>Organisers said invitations had also been issued to Laos, Cambodia and Burma, which are awaiting entry to the grouping that links some of the world's fastest growing economies.</p>
<p>&quot;We are at the preliminary stage of establishing a single contract for ASEAN, which essentially looks to standardising the quality of beans produced in this region,&quot; Musa said.</p>
<p>&quot;It does not intend to fix prices...that's to be done by the sellers and buyers,&quot; he said. &quot;The underlying importance of the single contract is the emphasis on quality.&quot;</p>
<p>Indonesian industry sources said the move to establish the single contract, initiated and being coordinated by Malaysia, would make the region appear as one large seller, improving its bargaining position with overseas buyers.</p>
<p>They said the Philippines agreed with the move, but Indonesia, the world's third largest cocoa producer after the Ivory Coast and Ghana, was undecided.</p>
<p>&quot;Indonesia has been trying to improve the quality of its cocoa for some time and has found it tough because of the large number of smallholders cultivating the crop,&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>&quot;Though Indonesia is trying hard to improve quality, I don't think it would want to be bound by any programme,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Musa said Malaysia had not outlined specifics on the single contract move. If agreed to by other regional producers a seminar would be held to explain objectives.</p>
<p>&quot;At this stage, we are still discussing the possibility. There's no formal working paper presented on the subject,&quot; he said. &quot;If everyone is agreeable, then we will organise a seminar for people like traders to explain the proposal.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Malaysia's 1997 cocoa production was expected to remain unchanged at the 1996 level of 125,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Musa said total area under cocoa cultivation had shrunk to 215,000 hectares from 419,000 hectares in 1990 due largely to a switch to oil palm and shortage of manpower.</p>
<p>&quot;We now have a group of hardcore cocoa producers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Other than Malaysia and Indonesia, the main ASEAN cocoa producers are the Philippines and Thailand.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100144">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
