<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414790" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar closes firmly in U.S., nears 1.70 marks.</title>
<headline>Dollar closes firmly in U.S., nears 1.70 marks.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar closed firmer, boosted by mounting expectations for higher U.S. interest rates and continuing speculation that Europe's efforts to forge a single currency will fall short, dealers said.</p>
<p>Bundesbank council member Ernst Welteke said a weak German economy prevented German interest rate hikes, but added the weak mark and likely U.S. rate hikes ruled out German cuts.</p>
<p>&quot;The prospect of even more favorable interest rate differentials between the U.S. and Germany is very supportive for the dollar,&quot; said Seth Garrett, a director of foreign exchange at Credit Suisse First Boston.</p>
<p>Welteke also said further dollar/mark appreciation was undesirable and that a delay in the proposed European economic and monetary union (EMU) would boost the mark strongly.</p>
<p>Welteke's comments initially hurt the dollar, but investors later pushed the unit higher against the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;Welteke made a couple of comments, the first of which was bullish for the mark and the second seemed to offset it,&quot; said Dennis Pettit, foreign exchange manager at Long-Term Credit Bank of Japan.</p>
<p>The dollar rose to 1.6983/88 marks from 1.6920/23 at the U.S. open and to 121.25/30 yen from 120.73/78.</p>
<p>Another Bundesbank council member, Klaus-Dieter Kuehbacher, was quoted in the newspaper Berliner Zeitung saying he was not sure the proposed EMU would begin in 1999 as scheduled.</p>
<p>While those comments triggered sales of Spanish pesetas and Italian lire for marks, and possibly central bank intervention to trim the mark's gains, investors sold the German unit against the dollar and the Swiss franc, which are seen as safe havens from EMU uncertainty, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's questionable whether people will actually go back into marks or would the dollar be a smarter place to go,&quot; Garrett said.</p>
<p>Kuehbacher also questioned Germany's ability to meet the three-percent deficit-to-gross-domestic-product requirement in 1997, calling for higher taxes or spending cuts to close the government deficit.</p>
<p>Traders also cited a rumored leak of Germany's February employment report, due Thursday, for dollar/mark strength.</p>
<p>A German paper claimed the report would show German unemployment rising to 12.5 percent from 12.2 percent.</p>
<p>Two economic reports added to the evidence pointing to a Federal Reserve interest rate hike this Spring, dealers said.</p>
<p>That view gained supporters after Chairman Alan Greenspan last Wednesday told a Senate committee the central bank might tighten credit even before it saw rising inflation.</p>
<p>On Monday, the Commerce Department reported personal consumption rose 0.7 percent in January, while personal income rose 0.3 percent.</p>
<p>Another report from the National Association of Purchasing Management showed surprising strength and hints of inflation in the manufacturing sector.</p>
<p>The overall NAPM index rose to 53.1 in February from 52.0 in January, while the prices index rose to 55.1 from 51.4.</p>
<p>The dollar rose to 1.4773/83 Swiss francs at the close from 1.4755/65 at the open.</p>
<p>The British pound fell to $1.6160/70 from $1.6210/20.</p>
<p>The dollar fell to Canadian $1.3663/68 from C$1.3669/74.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar rose to $0.7878/83 from $0.7853/58.</p>
<p>(( --Chris Stetkiewicz, 212-859-1664 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
