<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414720" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thailand pleas for help among financial sector.</title>
<headline>Thailand pleas for help among financial sector.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Thailand has asked domestic financial institutions to support each other by avoiding calling back existing loans and lending new funds to finance firms which have liquidity problem, a senior finance executive said.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank today requested co-operation among financial institutions to help each other during this situation,&quot; Pakhawat Kovithvathanaphong, the president of Securities One, told reporters after a meeting with central bank officials.</p>
<p>The BOT late on Monday held an urgent meeting with local financial institutions to clarify and explain the bank's recent measures to help liquidity-strapped financial firms, he said.</p>
<p>Many financial firms are now facing liquidity crunch caused by a combination of problems such as bad loans from depressed property sector and the Bank of Thailand's decision to keep interest rates high to counter baht attack.</p>
<p>The situation was exacerbated by reluctance of commercial banks to lend to finance sector due to concerns over its future.</p>
<p>The Bank of Thailand on Monday told 10 finance firms to increase their capital immediately as they do not have sufficient provisions for doubtful loans and sub-standard assets.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
