<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414718" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai finance stocks seen tumbling on bourse.</title>
<headline>Thai finance stocks seen tumbling on bourse.</headline>
<byline>Rajan Moses</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most Thai finance and some of the bank stocks suspended on Monday by the Thai bourse should open limit down when trading in them is resumed after authorities reported the sectors had problems, analysts said.</p>
<p>The stock exchange suspended the bank and finance counters while it awaited a statement from the central bank and finance ministry on measures to boost the sagging finance industry.</p>
<p>The authorities later said that 10 finance companies, including three listed ones, would have to raise their capital immediately by 8.25 billion baht ($317 million) and that banks and finance firms must raise provisions to make up for sub-standard assets.</p>
<p>The bourse said the suspension of finance and bank counters was for the trading session on Monday, but it did not detail whether trading would resume on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This is no good for the market at all. The way it was handled. To suspend the stocks after some deals were done in early market trading and then cancel them,&quot; said the head of a foreign brokerage, who declined to be named.</p>
<p>The news of the suspension was released by the bourse some minutes after morning trading had resumed and it said deals already done in that time would be cancelled.</p>
<p>Other analysts said the fact that the central bank and other regulators had insisted before that there were no problems with the finance sector and then made a turn-about on Monday would be damaging to the finance and banking stocks.</p>
<p>Khanchit Assavasararn, an analyst at Vickers Ballas, said the authorities had now confirmed that the finance sector was in trouble.</p>
<p>&quot;The market could drop further short-term as this is like a confirmation that the finance sector is in trouble... But it is a good move that the finance ministry and the Bank of Thailand came out and addressed the problems,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless they can clarify their plans and successfully convince the public that they are doing right things and are on right track the market will continue to take this as negative news,&quot; Khanchit said.</p>
<p>But another analyst with a local brokerage differed.</p>
<p>He said: &quot;This has reduced the credibility of the Bank of Thailand, the stock exchange, the finance ministry and cannot be good for confidence in the market.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It would be expected that most finance companies and some bank stocks would go down the limit when suspension in their trading is lifted by the exchange,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The revelations by the authorities of the need to overcome liquidity problems among finance companies did not go down well at all with the stock market which ended a hefty 2.79 percent down or 20.32 points off at 707.24.</p>
<p>Punters, unimpressed by the negative news about the finance sector, even sold communications, energy and other stocks that were left to be traded on the bourse, brokers said.</p>
<p>The baht also declined as concerns over the finance sector problems permeated the money market, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Thai unit traded lower at 25.910-25.920 against the dollar late versus 25.890-25.900 early.</p>
<p>($1 = 26 baht)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
