<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414703" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan minister says not to meet with Dalai Lama.</title>
<headline>Taiwan minister says not to meet with Dalai Lama.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Chen</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan foreign minister John Chang, in another move to avoid angering rival China, said on Monday he would not meet with the Dalai Lama during the exiled Tibetan Buddhist leader's trip to the island.</p>
<p>The presidential office also denied a newspaper report that President Lee Tung-hui would meet with the Tibetan god-king during his six-day visit, scheduled for March 22.</p>
<p>Chang, who spoke to reporters after he left an unrelated meeting, said Taiwan should not over-politicise the Dalai Lama's visit or it could jeopardise already icy relations between Taipei and Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;As foreign minister, it is not appropriate for me to meet with the Dalai Lama,&quot; Chang said after reporters asked him whether a meeting would be possible.</p>
<p>&quot;This matter should not be overly politicised. Doing this will help cross-strait development,&quot; he said without elaboration.</p>
<p>But the China Times Express, in a report published on Monday, quoted an unnamed source as saying that a meeting had been &quot;tentatively set&quot; between President Lee and the Dalai Lama.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Lee's office denied the report.</p>
<p>&quot;No such meeting has been set,&quot; the spokesman said by telephone. He declined to say whether the office was arranging such a meeting.</p>
<p>The report also contradicted statements from the Buddhist Association of the Republic of China, a religious group that will host the Dalai Lama, that he would not meet Taiwanese political leaders, including President Lee.</p>
<p>China, which regards Taiwan as a renegade province, was angered last September when news emerged about the Dalai Lama's Taiwan visit. Beijing has repeatedly warned the island not to receive him.</p>
<p>Despite Beijing's objections, a poll conducted by Taiwan's China Times newspaper showed that nearly 60 percent of Taiwan people supported the Dalai Lama's visit, and only 22 percent believed the visit would worsen Taiwan-China relations.</p>
<p>The survey, published on Monday, was compiled by polling 818 people on February 15.</p>
<p>China has made strenuous efforts to neutralise the Dalai Lama's influence abroad since he went into exile in 1959. Chinese troops had moved in to replace the centuries-old Buddhist theocracy with control from Beijing in 1950.</p>
<p>The Dalai Lama, revered at home as a god-king, advocates non-violent resistance to Chinese domination and says he wants autonomy for Tibet.</p>
<p>Beijing has maintained that Tibet is an integral part of China, just as Taiwan must be brought under the mainland's eventual rule.</p>
<p>Taiwan, which split with China after a civil war in 1949, says it wants to re-unify with the mainland but insists it has the right to conduct foreign affairs during the current separation.</p>
<p>Cross-strait relations have been at a low point since 1995, when Lee made a private, but high-profile visit to the United States.</p>
<p>Lee's trip prompted China to indefinitely postpone semi-official talks and launch menacing missile tests near the island in March last year.</p>
<p>Beijing vows to attack Taiwan if the island tries to declare independence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
