<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="414966" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. says China meets air safety requirements.</title>
<headline>U.S. says China meets air safety requirements.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S.-China review team said Monday that China's aviation authority meets international safety standards, but more was needed to improve the authority's oversight capabilities.</p>
<p>The U.S. Federal Aviation Administration said the joint team began a safety review with the General Administration of Civil Aviation of China (CAAC) in 1995 to identify improvements needed in China's flight standards and maintenance.</p>
<p>It noted that Chinese civil air transport had grown by an average of 20 percent a year since 1980 -- 4.3 times more than the world average -- but the strain of the growth was evident in a rising accident rate.</p>
<p>The FAA said that China, prompted by increasing accidents, began to slow aviation growth in 1993 and to reform its civil aviation oversight programme, and the joint effort with the United States was part of that effort.</p>
<p>Acting FAA Administrator Barry Valentine said in a statement that &quot;this report recognises the important strides the CAAC has made to meet the growing demands on its aviation system.&quot;</p>
<p>But, he added, &quot;Both nations agree more needs to be done, and the FAA is committed to helping China improve its safety oversight capabilities.&quot;</p>
<p>Citing rapid aviation growth, the FAA added in a statement that &quot;the team cautioned that additional resources will be required for the CAAC to provide effective oversight of its air carriers in the future.&quot;</p>
<p>FAA officials said the assessments were of China's aviation oversight abilities and not an assessment of the safety of Chinese airlines.</p>
<p>Two Chinese airlines, Air China and China Eastern, fly to the United States and three U.S. carriers fly to China, United Airlines, a unit of UAL Corp., Northwest Airlines Corp., and the cargo carrier Federal Express Corp.</p>
<p>The U.S.-China assessment, based on International Civil Aviation Orgnaization standards, is similar to those the FAA makes of other foreign aviation authorities.</p>
<p>Among areas convered by the joint U.S.-China team were safety resources, aviation law and regulations, certification, inspector qualifications and training, and enforcement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
