<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="415031" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Attorney in Ohio muni case says will keep trying.</title>
<headline>Attorney in Ohio muni case says will keep trying.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The attorney representing a bondholder's challenge to Ohio's tax on the income of out-of-state municipal bonds said he will examine options to fight the practice in the wake of the U.S. Supreme Court decision on Monday not to hear the case.</p>
<p>Clint Krislov, a Chicago attorney representing Cleveland-area bondholder Serene Shaper, said he was disappointed with the high court's decision, but said he would look for another way to bring the matter up so that the court would be forced to hear it.</p>
<p>He also said filing a similar lawsuit in another state was also an option. According to Shaper's petition to the nation's highest court, 37 other states also tax income on out-of-state municipal bonds.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an issue that shouldn't go away,&quot; Krislov said. &quot;It's a pretty clear violation.&quot;</p>
<p>Shaper's petition to the U.S. Supreme Court argued that the issue of whether a state could under the commerce clause of the U.S. Constitution &quot;discriminatorily impose&quot; its income tax on other states' municipal bonds  &quot;is an issue of overwhelming timeliness and importance.&quot;</p>
<p>But to the Ohio Attorney General's office, which represented Ohio Department of Revenue in Shaper's lawsuit, the matter was closed by the high court's refusal to hear the case.</p>
<p>&quot;This issue is definately settled,&quot; said Chris Davey, communications director for the attorney general's office. &quot;There is no violation of the constitution's interstate commerce protection. The U.S. Supreme Court affirmed that.&quot;</p>
<p>Davey said the high court's refusal also ensures that Ohio will not lose $20 million annually that it collects from taxing out-of-state municipal bonds.</p>
<p>The U.S. Supreme Court's refusal marked the second time the high court has declined to take up the case. In October 1995, the court passed on the first part of the case which sought a declaratory judgment that Ohio's in-state tax exemption on municipal bonds was unconstitutional.</p>
<p>The second part of the case sought a refund of $6,000 in Ohio income taxes Shaper paid between 1988 and 1991 on interest earned from her out-of-state municipal bonds. The refund had been rejected by the Ohio revenue department, the state tax appeals board and finally by the Ohio Supreme Court last August.</p>
<p>The case troubled municipal market participants, including the state of Minnesota, which enacted a law in 1995 that outlined its intention to prospectively tax interest on in-state municipals should the U.S. Supreme Court rule in-state tax exemptions unconstitutional.</p>
<p>((--Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
