<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="415271" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Runaway train crashes in Pakistan killing 126.</title>
<headline>Runaway train crashes in Pakistan killing 126.</headline>
<byline>Asim Tanveer</byline>
<dateline>KHANEWAL, Pakistan 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least 126 people were killed in Pakistan on Monday when a runaway passenger express train crashed after being switched to a dead-end line to avert a head-on collision with another express.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a horrific accident. It's a major accident in which 126 people have been killed,&quot; said Punjab province chief minister Shahbaz Sharif, visiting victims at a hospital in the town of Khanewal near the scene of the crash.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif, who flew to the scene by helicopter, ordered an inquiry into the disaster, Pakistan's worst rail accident in seven years.</p>
<p>He told Khanewal's deputy commissioner to prepare an initial report within 24 hours and said railway officials would not be spared if they were found to have been negligent.</p>
<p>Hospital officials in Khanewal said 81 people had been injured, 25 of them seriously.</p>
<p>&quot;Suddenly the train started jerking,&quot; said a survivor named Saghir (one name) from the northwestern city of Peshawar. &quot;My wife said &quot;Oh God help, oh God help', and she fell on me.</p>
<p>&quot;It was pitch dark. People were screaming for help and there was chaos. People were stepping on dead bodies and could not understand what was going on,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Railway officials said the Zulfikar Express left Khanewal for Karachi but failed to halt at a junction, apparently because of brake failure, at about 4 a.m. (2300 GMT Sunday).</p>
<p>Controllers switched it to a dead-end line to stop it from smashing into the Karachi-Lahore express train on the single-track line and causing even greater carnage.</p>
<p>The diverted train hit the buffers at the end of the spur line near the village of Mirshah, about five km (three miles) from Khanewal, derailing the engine and five coaches.</p>
<p>The engine ploughed through the buffers into a sand barrier. Two of the coaches were completely crushed, witnesses said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the bodies are unrecognisable,&quot; Khanewal town police superintendent Mushtaq Warraich told Reuters.</p>
<p>One survivor, Muhammad Ashiq, was distraught, wailing and hitting his head with both hands. Seven members of his family died in the crash. They had been on their way to a wedding.</p>
<p>A woman passenger from Lahore, who suffered a fractured arm and leg, said: &quot;Suddenly there was jerking and the train went off the track. It felt like an earthquake had come.&quot;</p>
<p>Women from nearby villages gathered at the scene, wailing and beating their chests in mourning.</p>
<p>Khanewal residents thronged the hospital to donate blood after appeals broadcast over mosque loudspeakers. Private cars helped ambulances to ferry casualties to the hospital, about 12 km (eight miles) from the scene of the accident.</p>
<p>On January 21, an express train hit a school van at a level crossing at Gujar Khan, 60 km (37 miles) south of Islamabad, killing nine people, including six children and two teachers.</p>
<p>On January 3, 1990, a passenger train ploughed into a stationary freight train at Sangi railway station in Sindh province, killing 307 people and injuring 400.</p>
<p>On Saturday, the prime minister, who took office last month, toured earthquake-stricken parts of the southwestern province of Baluchistan, where about 60 people died on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KHANEWAL, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
