<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="415304" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Lehman sees India debt market developing.</title>
<headline>Lehman sees India debt market developing.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Global investment bank Lehman Brothers sees India's debt market developing and the evolution of derivatives, the bank's Asia chief said on Monday.</p>
<p>C. Daniel Tyree, chairman of Lehman Brothers Asia, told reporters that the development of a debt market and the growth of infrastructure was critical to India's economy.</p>
<p>&quot;The development of a debt market will provide an alternate route to funds,&quot; Tyree said. &quot;As Indian capital markets open up, swaps will develop and eventually futures and options will emerge.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;There is a clear acknowledgement that infrastructure is critical to India's development.&quot;</p>
<p>Even as Tyree spoke, a working group set up by the Indian government said companies should be allowed to issue derivatives, options and quasi-equity instruments.  </p>
<p>Tyree told Reuters Television separately in an interview that Finance Minister P. Chidambaram's proposal in the fiscal budget for 1997/98 to do groundwork towards moving to capital-account convertibility of the rupee was also a step in the right direction.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is the right step, it has to be done,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The government in the budget asked the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to set up a panel to &quot;lay out the road map towards capital account convertibility.&quot;</p>
<p>But Tyree cautioned that capital account convertibility must be carried out in a phased manner.</p>
<p>&quot;I think something like convertibility ought to be done in a thoughful way,&quot; he said. &quot;I think the next couple of years is a good time-frame.&quot;</p>
<p>Tyree told reporters that the policies proposed in the 1997/98 budget, which Chidambaram unveiled last Friday, would help India's capital markets appreciate in the long term.</p>
<p>&quot;But there will be corrections along the way,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lehman Brothers expanded its India operations on Monday by opening a new office in New Delhi which will serve as headquarters for the firm's investment banking and related activities in the sub-continent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
