<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="415367" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: World Bank asks Dhaka to draw up privatisation plan.</title>
<headline>World Bank asks Dhaka to draw up privatisation plan.</headline>
<byline>Shakeel Anwar</byline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The World Bank, pressing Bangladesh for speedier disinvestment of public enterprises, has asked the country's new government to draw up a separate policy on privatisation.</p>
<p>&quot;They (World Bank) are asking for a clear-cut policy paper immediately spelling out the goals, strategy, options and arrangements for privatisation,&quot; one Finance Ministry official told Reuters on Monday.</p>
<p>The World Bank, Dhaka's largest donor, called for the policy during a mid-year review last week of the government's economic performance since it took power in June.</p>
<p>The government of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, head of Awami League that returned to power last year after 21 years, made sweeping promises to pursue a free market economy and privatise state enterprises.</p>
<p>Bangladesh receives $1.7 billion on average annually from international donors to finance development and imports.</p>
<p>The official said the World Bank, which advises the government on economic policies on behalf of mostly Western donors, had asked that cabinet frame and approve the privatisation policy by May this year.</p>
<p>Government officials said the slow progress in the privatisation programme had been criticised by donors at the mid-term review meeting.</p>
<p>The World Bank, in a written report on the government's performance, expressed concern at what it called &quot;disappointing progress&quot; on privatisation.</p>
<p>The report, a copy of which was obtained by Reuters, called for &quot;strong political commitment&quot; to privatise.</p>
<p>The bank called for a comprehensive privatisation law to be enacted this month to strengthen the legal framework on disinvestment.</p>
<p>It also sought the immediate establishment of a cabinet committee, headed by the prime minister, to tackle privatisation, and suggested more power for the government's Privatisation Board.</p>
<p>The board listed 64 state-owned manufacturing units for disinvestment during 1996/97 fiscal year ending next June but the World Bank report said tenders had been called for only 24 units. Seven of those had been referred to the cabinet for approval.</p>
<p>Government officials said most of the state-owned enterprises were running at loss, draining about 25 billion taka ($600 million) a year from government coffers in subsidies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
