<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="415484" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wheelabrator, Waste Management core units -- WMX.</title>
<headline>Wheelabrator, Waste Management core units -- WMX.</headline>
<dateline>ST. PETERSBURG BEACH, Fla. 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>WMX Technologies Inc Chief Financial Officer John Sanford said the company sees its Wheelabrator Technologies Inc and Waste Management International Plc affiliates as core businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;Both Wheelabrator and Waste Management are core businesses for the company,&quot; Sanford said Monday at Raymond James investors conference here.  </p>
<p>Commenting on Wall Street speculation that the Oak Brook, Ill.-based waste handling company might divest its interests in the two affiliates, Sanford said, &quot;There is no simple way to spin them out without incurring many hundreds of millions of dollars in tax liability, and that doesn't create value for shareholders.&quot;  </p>
<p>As for speculation by some in the investment community that WMX could somehow restructure and return to an acquisition-oriented U.S. waste industry growth strategy, Sanford said &quot;That's virtually impossible given our size ... We are not planning on significant acquisitions.&quot;</p>
<p>Under pressure from major investors, including an investment group led by financier George Soros, WMX is in the midst of a restructuring that includes divesting $1.5 billion in assets, cutting 3,000 jobs and buying back 50 million shares of stock.  </p>
<p>The company is also seeking a new chief executive since the surprise resignation February 18 of Phillip Rooney, whose ouster the Soros group and other large investors had demanded.</p>
<p>Sanford declined to comment Monday in an interview with Reuters on a call made February 18 by Nell Minow, a principal in Lens Fund, for his resignation.  Lens is another large WMX investor.</p>
<p>Asked about the company's CEO search, Sanford said there is no firm timetable.  But, he said, &quot;If you look at what other companies have done, it's about a three- to six-month process.&quot;  </p>
<p>WMX, the largest U.S. trash hauler, plans to drive $300 million out of its cost base by 1999, Sanford said.  At the same time, however, he said, &quot;I do not believe that the cost structure is bloated.&quot;</p>
<p>Reiterating guidance issued earlier, Sanford said WMX is targeting three to five percent annual revenue growth.</p>
<p>He said the company expects revenues this year of about $9.4 billion, compared with $9.2 billion in 1996.  He said the company expects 1997 earnings of $1.75 per share, flat against 1996.</p>
<p>In 1998, he said WMX foresees earnings of $2.05 per share. After that the company expects annual profit growth &quot;in the low double digits.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that WMX will strive to maintain a low single A credit rating.</p>
<p>((--Kevin Drawbaugh, Reuters))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I92110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. PETERSBURG BEACH, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
