<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="415591" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Markets wait to pounce on unguarded EMU comments.</title>
<headline>Markets wait to pounce on unguarded EMU comments.</headline>
<byline>Abigail Levene</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Financial markets are lying in wait for Europe's policy-makers, ready to pounce on any unguarded comments as golden money-making opportunities.</p>
<p>And right now, the vexed question of European economic and monetary union (EMU) is the biggest money-spinner of all.</p>
<p>Politicians across Europe winced on Friday when Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi said it was possible Germany might request a delay to EMU. And the market's reaction?</p>
<p>&quot;Delighted -- a chance to make some money,&quot; said David Coleman, chief economist at CIBC Wood Gundy in London.</p>
<p>The lira and Italian bonds, already hurt by speculation of EMU delay, racked up yet more losses after Prodi's remark.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no doubt politicians are in an extremely difficult position,&quot; said Coleman. &quot;Publicly, they have to keep plugging the view that everything's fine in the garden, it will all come out right in the end, but privately they must have some doubts.&quot;</p>
<p>On a purely technical basis, traders and analysts say, there was clearly room for some unwinding of the popular convergence plays -- based on the premise that EMU will proceed as planned in 1999 -- which have swept the market for the best part of a year.</p>
<p>&quot;The only reason for being long the peripheral currencies is a strong belief that EMU will start on time, and once that is in doubt, the whole edifice in the forex markets begins to crumble,&quot; said an analyst at a British bank here.</p>
<p>Bond yield spreads tell the story vividly. In January of this year, 10-year Italian debt yielded around 170 basis points over German, with Spain's premium over Germany near 100.</p>
<p>That was effectively discounting Italian and Spanish EMU participation, and left the market hyper-exposed to news or official comments casting doubt on that scenario, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;At the beginning of the year there was widespread optimism that the political momentum behind EMU was very strong, and the wider membership story was a prevalent one and a very realistic one,&quot; said Ken Wattret, economist at Banque Paribas.</p>
<p>&quot;Within a month, we've seen divergence re-emerge and if anything we'd be looking for the situation to be biased towards continued divergence from here.&quot;</p>
<p>Italy's spread over Germany swelled to 201 basis points on Monday, its widest since November, with Spain's at 138.</p>
<p>Prodi swiftly &quot;clarified&quot; Friday's EMU-delay comment by saying there was no assumption the timetable would be put back.</p>
<p>German foreign minister Klaus Kinkel backed that on Sunday, attacking market speculation of EMU delay and saying &quot;opponents of the euro are continuing their irresponsible actions&quot;.</p>
<p>On Monday, Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer called talk of delay &quot;nonsense&quot;, while European Monetary Institute chief Alexandre Lamfalussy said the speculation was unfounded.</p>
<p>But official rebukes cut little ice with the markets.</p>
<p>&quot;For short-term traders, people who probably don't look at those currencies on a day-to-day basis, what makes sense is they jump on the bandwagon early and make some money,&quot; said Peter Wood, forex trader at Bank of Boston here.</p>
<p>Economic realities also give the lie to political pronouncements that monetary union is on track, say analysts.</p>
<p>Foremost in the market's mind is the dire economic situation in EMU-lynchpin Germany. Bild am Sonntag newspaper reported on Sunday that February unemployment rose by 120,000 to a new postwar record of 4.8 million, a rate of 12.5 percent.</p>
<p>And despite the chorus of denials which greet comments such as Prodi's, the market is growing suspicious of a covert campaign to soften it up for an announcement of EMU delay.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no smoke without fire,&quot; said CIBC's Coleman. &quot;I think there's a fair amount of truth behind the view that either Italy will have to be convinced to step out of the project or that the whole project itself will be delayed.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
