<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="41569" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France sees Poland in European Union by 2000.</title>
<headline>France sees Poland in European Union by 2000.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac will tell Polish leaders on a state visit to Warsaw this week that he sees Poland joining the European Union within a few years, his spokeswoman said on Monday.</p>
<p>An informed source said Chirac would set the goal of the former communist state joining the Union by the year 2000, with a transition period thereafter until its agriculture was fully integrated into the single market.</p>
<p>Spokeswoman Catherine Colonna told reporters: &quot;Poland is indisputably a quality candidate, given the considerable work that has already been achieved by this country..One can aim for a horizon of a few years.&quot;</p>
<p>She declined to name a date but said the president would do so when he addresses a joint session of the Polish parliament on Thursday during his first visit to one of the new democracies of central and eastern Europe.</p>
<p>Colonna also said France saw Poland opening negotiations to join NATO by the end of next year, following a summit of the Atlantic Alliance, central European candidates and east European partners, including Russia and Ukraine, early next year.</p>
<p>On EU accession, she said much would depend on the conclusion of the current inter-governmental conference (IGC) on reforming EU institutions, which is supposed to be wrapped up by the end of June 1997, but which is moving very slowly.</p>
<p>The EU has agreed to open negotiations with nine eastern and southern candidate nations six months after the end of the IGC.</p>
<p>But officials in Brussels say even the most ardent supporters of rapid enlargement believe the most likely batch of new members -- Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic -- are unlikely to gain admission before 2002.</p>
<p>By advocating an earlier date, diplomats said Chirac would highlight a shift in policy from his predecessor, Francois Mitterrand, who alienated many east Europeans by declaring after the fall of communism that it would be &quot;decades&quot; before they joined the EU.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
