<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="415710" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan invites consultants to study fair centre.</title>
<headline>Jordan invites consultants to study fair centre.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan is inviting international and local consultants to submit proposals for a feasibility study of an estimated $100 million international convention centre on a BOO or BOT basis, officials said on Monday.</p>
<p>Jordan Investment Corporation (JIC), the investment arm of the government and the state export promotion agency Jordan Export Development Corporation have set a closing date of March 31 for bids by consultants.</p>
<p>The feasibility study is a first step before attracting international investors to the project, which the government has already allocated a large piece of land on the existing convention grounds on the outskirts of Amman.</p>
<p>JIC hopes to finalise a deal with an interested party by year end who will both finance and construct and manage the convention centre, which under the terms of reference of the study must include shopping malls, hotels, panorama building.</p>
<p>Officials say the project's objective is to help Jordan establish itself a name as a regional conference and exhibition centre.</p>
<p>Jordan is now offering a number of projects to international investors on a BOO and BOT basis to attract foreign capital to develop projects it lacks the financial resources to undertake on its own.</p>
<p>-- Amman Newsroom +9626 623-776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
