<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="41582" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Dow gains, dollar underpin Belgian shares.</title>
<headline>Dow gains, dollar underpin Belgian shares.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Renewed gains on Wall Street in the afternoon and a firmer dollar helped keep the Belgian share market generally well supported on Monday, though in the days ahead interest was expected to focus more on individual stocks.</p>
<p>The Bel-20 index  .BFX closed 10.05 points or 0.58 percent higher at 1,745.67, above what some chartists saw as resistance at 1,740 level. The index peaked at 1,749.82 in the afternoon.</p>
<p>&quot;The undertone is positive, if rates stay at these levels. European markets are not very expensive and can go higher,&quot; one analyst said. Belgian share market volume amounted to a fairly modest 1.8 billion francs worth.  </p>
<p>Percentage leader was photo-processor Spector, which climbed 5.2 percent to 2,030 francs. The stock was suspended last Thursday and Friday when the company announced a 2.0 billion franc capital increase to finance acquisitions of a majority of Swiss photo group Porst and all of Interdiscount France.</p>
<p>Spector will carry out its capital increase by issuing preferential subscription rights to existing shareholders. Porst Holding will use its preferential rights to subscribe to 50.2 percent of the capital increase. It also intends to issue subordinated, convertible bonds with a warrant for an amount between 1.0 billion and 1.5 billion Belgian francs.  </p>
<p>&quot;It has become clear that because of (Spector's controlling shareholder) Fotoinvest's involvement in the deal Spector has a limited risk,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>Oil stock Petrofina and bank Kredietbank, both among stocks set to get higher weightings in the Bel-20 index on September 20, were the most heavily traded stocks again in value terms.</p>
<p>Petrofina rose 1.8 percent to 9,850 francs on a turnover of 15,247 shares, and Kredietbank climbed 1.1 percent to 9,810 francs with 14,278 shares changing hands.</p>
<p>-- Lorrayne Smith, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6812, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
