<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="415964" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: JOBS - Even European bonds can get the jobless blues.</title>
<headline>JOBS - Even European bonds can get the jobless blues.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Thorpe</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bond markets have so far reacted typically to soaring unemployment in Europe -- rising with each new worker that joins the dole queue.</p>
<p>A callous reaction maybe, but high unemployment in mature economies can often reflect poor economic conditions, benign inflation and low interest rates.</p>
<p>But if the queues get much longer, analysts expect even bond markets to start to get jittery. Worries about a delay to European economic and monetary union (EMU) will soon begin to offset the glow from a low interest rate environment.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has a fairly sanguine approach right now but you will see rising tensions as the year goes ahead,&quot; said Michael O'Hanlon, chief international economist at PaineWebber International in London.</p>
<p>Adrian Owens, European economist at Julius Baer Investments in London, agreed. &quot;If we see continued deterioration in labour markets in Europe it could encourage further talk of EMU delay and could have an impact on high yielding markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Unemployment hit its highest level in Germany in January since World War II. The situation in France and much of Europe is equally dire as economies remain sluggish. The EU jobless rate is now 10.8 percent.</p>
<p>Governments have been faced with swelling benefit costs just as they battle to cut budget deficits to meet the strict fiscal goals of EMU. When EMU begins in 1999, a government's deficit should be no higher than three percent of its gross domestic product and total indebtedness no more than 60 percent.</p>
<p>MARKET MOOD TIED INTO PERCEPTIONS OF POLITICAL WILL</p>
<p>But the political will to start EMU on time is strong and the main task for European bond markets through much of 1997 will be to decipher whether that will is strong enough to overlook deficits weighed down by high unemployment.</p>
<p>It will not be an easy task and the uncertainty will put outward pressure on spreads between benchmark German Bunds and other European debt, analysts said.</p>
<p>Stephen Lewis, chief economist at London Bond Broking here, said market perceptions will weigh heavily on whether Germany -- the driving force behind EMU -- can pull unemployment down from the post-war record 4.66 million registered in January.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the markets will be watching very closely to see where it ends up in March and April when weather effects are no longer taking their toll,&quot; Lewis said.</p>
<p>WHAT SCOPE FOR IMPROVEMENT?</p>
<p>The German government has said that unemployment will fall to an annual average rate of 4.2 million by spring, still allowing it to meet its 2.9 percent deficit-to-GDP target for 1997.</p>
<p>Lewis said anything more than an annual average unemployment rate of 4.12 to 4.13 million will push the German deficit above the 3.0 percent deficit-to-GDP level demanded by EMU.</p>
<p>Others argue unemployment will not fall much in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the cyclical recovery in economic activity we are still going to see a deteriorating employment picture,&quot; Owens, at Julius Baer said. &quot;Employment is a lagging indicator especially in somewhere like Germany where the economy is that much more rigid and labour markets are not as responsive as in the U.K. or U.S.&quot;</p>
<p>O'Hanlon, at PaineWebber, does expect unemployment to fall in Germany. Currency weakness will encourage export growth, a cut in the solidarity surcharge will foster business activity and the construction sector should get a boost from millennium building and low interest rates.</p>
<p>Even if unemployment does not fall appreciably and deficits are stretched, O'Hanlon said the political drive to get EMU started on time will encourage spread consolidation.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets have drawn the conclusion that EMU is going to happen on time because it will be flexible,&quot; said O'Hanlon. He said the Maastricht Treaty has some room for flexibility.</p>
<p>Whether spread consolidation was sustainable into 1998 is another question, he added.</p>
<p>Elections in France and Germany in 1998 are likely to focus heavily on the unemployment issue and there will be a great temptation for politicians to pull economic miracles out of their hats, O'Hanlon said.</p>
<p>&quot;The unemployment question is a very serious question for the long term sustainability of any EMU process,&quot; he said. &quot;There may be the political will to make it happen but the unemployment problem becomes a major issue.&quot;</p>
<p>-- International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
