<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="415908" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Waigel in talks with Nordic, Baltic counterparts.</title>
<headline>Waigel in talks with Nordic, Baltic counterparts.</headline>
<byline>Rolf Soderlind</byline>
<dateline>BERGEN, Norway 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Finance Minister Theo Waigel and most of his North European counterparts gathered in Norway's old Hanseatic city of Bergen on Monday to discuss economic cooperation around the Baltic Sea and preparations for European economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>The two-day informal meeting was drawing delegations from ten countries, only four of which are members of the European Union. It follows a similar conference held a year ago in Boltenhagen, a German resort on the Baltic Sea, at the initiative of Waigel.</p>
<p>Impressed by economic growth rates in Nordic countries and the pace of reform in Poland and the three Baltic States, Germany hopes a modern-day Hanseatic league in the region could eventually rival the Mediterranean as an economic force.</p>
<p>Waigel was due to hold talks with his Nordic counterparts from Norway, Sweden, Denmark and Iceland as well as Poland and the Baltic states of Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania, Norwegian officials said.</p>
<p>They said Finnish Finance Minister Sauli Niinistoe stayed at home because of illness.</p>
<p>The Bergen meeting comes at a time of uncertainty over whether Germany -- once the model pupil in the EMU school -- can manage to rein in its spending sufficiently to meet the tough fiscal targets laid down for EMU entry.</p>
<p>The single currency, or euro, is scheduled to be launched on January 1, 1999. But 1997 economic data will be used to decide which EU members take part at the start.</p>
<p>The Maastricht Treaty sets a budget deficit ceiling of 3.0 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) this year for candidate countries to qualify for the launch of the single currency.</p>
<p>The German government has projected a budget deficit target of 2.9 percent of GDP, but the question is if it can achieve it.</p>
<p>In Bonn, German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel on Sunday attacked what he called &quot;irresponsible&quot; market speculation that Germany was seeking a delay of EMU and strongly reaffirmed that Bonn wanted the project to start as scheduled.</p>
<p>Germany's troubles, which also include record unemployment of 4.66 million, contrast sharply with the booming economy of Norway, whose finance minister Jens Stoltenberg is hosting the Bergen talks.</p>
<p>Norway, the world's second largest oil exporter after Saudi Arabia, is projected to run up a budget surplus of 55.4 billion crowns ($8.2 billion) this year and would easily fulfil the Maastricht criteria.</p>
<p>The catch is Norwegians in a referendum in 1994 voted against joining the EU.</p>
<p>Iceland also has no plans to join, but Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania and Poland all want membership.</p>
<p>Denmark, an old EU member, has opted out of the EMU following a 1993 referendum.</p>
<p>Sweden and Finland, both of which joined the EU in January 1995, have different approaches with the Swedes being undecided on whether to join EMU and the Finns being officially in favour of monetary union.</p>
<p>($ = 6.760 Norwegian Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ICEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERGEN, Norway"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
