<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="415948" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek shares plunge in worst one day slide.</title>
<headline>Greek shares plunge in worst one day slide.</headline>
<byline>George Georgiopoulos</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Athens bourse plunged 7.45 percent on Monday, a record fall for a single day, as spooked investors sold shares across-the-board.</p>
<p>Monday's fall took investor losses over the past three sessions 1.2 trillion drachmas ($4.51 billion).</p>
<p>Stunned brokers debated whether the fall was caused by civil strife in neighbouring Albania, a capital market commission warning which many claim pulled the rug from under the market or simply valuation physics pointing to a correction.</p>
<p>After a powerful bull run early this year, hefty profits were there to be taken.</p>
<p>At the closing bell brokers were not sure what had hit them. The panic selloff brought the share index back to 1,206 points, down 17 percent in three sessions and the bulls nowhere to be seen.</p>
<p>&quot;I was giving sell orders to hit any bid,&quot; onw fund manager said.</p>
<p>In an avalanche of selling, investors pounded down even the very blue chips they were previously buying.</p>
<p>Investors were questioning what had gone wrong so fast, given Greece's brighter macroeconomic fundamentals.</p>
<p>Consumer inflation, down to 6.8 percent in January, was driving interest rates lower, making asset reallocation into equities a hot topic. The stock market which started the year with a bull run had gained more than 36 percent and still looked pumped up.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not convinced it was jitters on Albania. It's just an excuse. The country is neither a military danger nor a great trading partner. I think retail investors just wanted out,&quot; said analyst Yannis Protopapadakis at ING Barings.</p>
<p>Many claim it started last Wednesday after the capital market commissioner Stavros Thomadakis warned against rumour-based investment decisions. The statement spooked players and many started heading for the exit sign.</p>
<p>&quot;The Albania factor is just another excuse. Commissioner Thomadakis did the great damage. Without his statement we would have had a normal, orderly correction and not everybody running for the door,&quot; one portfolio strategist said.</p>
<p>The statement undermined market sentiment especially with retail investors. In turn, funds sensing a reversal also decided to sell.</p>
<p>Other fund managers pointed out that the intervention to calm the overheating market could have been more subtle. State bank portfolios could have increased the supply of stock to contain the rise.</p>
<p>&quot;I was expecting the market to stabilise around 1,200 points but I think this will happen around 1,120-1,150 points which is a 50 percent retracement. We'll see buyers come out there,&quot; said broker Alexander Moraitakis at Nuntius Securities.</p>
<p>In his view the Albanian flare-up, which has seen widespread civil protests sparked by a pyramid selling scandal, was not a serious reason and commissioner Thomadakis' statement was an excuse.</p>
<p>&quot;Share prices had risen too much. We had a violent correction, an overeaction in the market. No one person can say something that can force the bourse to lose 17 percent in three days. No one is more powerful than the market itself,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch analyst Mike Harris said at the end of last week the market was taking off too fast and getting ahead of itself.</p>
<p>The deterioration in market sentiment might affect government plans to float another chunk of state telecom OTE and an initial public offering in the Public Petroleum Corporation (DEP) this year, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The higher the diving board, the bigger the splash. But really, if Greece was suddenly in war with Turkey how far down would the market have fallen? I see hype and overeaction, calmer days will return soon,&quot; said a private banker.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
