<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="416086" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Air Canada unit gets deal with pilots' union.</title>
<headline>Air Canada unit gets deal with pilots' union.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1997-03-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Air Canada subsidiary AirBC said on Sunday that it reached a tentative agreement with the union that represents its 300 striking pilots.</p>
<p>&quot;That is correct,&quot; said AirBC spokeswoman Angela Mah when asked if the regional carrier had a deal with the Airline Pilots' Association (ALPA Canada). &quot;It was achieved shortly after noon (2200 GMT) today.&quot;</p>
<p>Mah told Reuters that the deal is subject to ratification by the union members. She said the ratification process is expected to be completed and AirBC's pilots back in the air by March 7.  </p>
<p>&quot;AirBC is expecting to have its planes flying by Friday, March 7,&quot; the company said in a released statement.</p>
<p>The regional air carrier would not give any details about the agreement except to say that it is mutually beneficial to both parties. It said no details of the agreement will be released during the ratification process.</p>
<p>The 900 pilots at Air Canada's regional airlines including AirBC, Air Ontario, Air Alliance, and Air Nova, have been on strike since January 10.</p>
<p>AirBC is the first regional airline to reach a tentative agreement. Negotiations with the other regionals are continuing, AirBC said.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that AirBC has reached an agreement is very positive,&quot; Mah said of the possibility of agreements for the other three regional carriers.</p>
<p>AirBC is Air Canada's regional airline in western Canada serving 26 cities across western Canada plus Seattle, Portland and Spokane in the United States.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
