<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="416138" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FORECAST-Boral half-year seen lower.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FORECAST-Boral half-year seen lower.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Morrison</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Building materials group Boral Ltd is expected to report a lower net profit before abnormals for the six months to December 31 on Wednesday, but the results should show signs of an improving housing market, analysts said.</p>
<p>Building material analysts contacted by Reuters forecast Boral to report a pre-abnormal net profit of between A$89 million and A$93 million for the 1996/97 half year, compared with A$120 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>Analysts said although the first half was likely to be down on a year ago it should be up on the 1995/96 second half.  </p>
<p>BZW Australia building material analyst Greg Burns forecasts Boral to report a pre-abnormal net profit of A$89 million for the December half.</p>
<p>&quot;Non-residentials are as strong as an ox, and it has been for many quarters, and housing, as far as approvals are concerned, bottomed in September,&quot; Burns told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;I just think the six months to December will not have enough good news in it to get too excited,&quot; Burns said.</p>
<p>ANZ Securities building materials analyst Sean Cooney estimates Boral to report a pre-abnormal net profit of A$93 million for the six month period.  </p>
<p>Cooney said Australian building material companies had been reporting disappointing results for some time and Boral was unlikely to any exception.</p>
<p>Last week Pioneer International Ltd reported a 18.3 percent fall in net profit for the 1996/97 first half.</p>
<p>&quot;Things have looked worst than some people have expected in Australia's housing market and because Boral has got a fairly significant exposure compared to the others, you expect it to be a bit more worse hit then the others,&quot; Cooney told Reuters.</p>
<p>ABN AMRO Hoare Govett analyst Fabian Babich forecast a net profit before abnormals of A$90 million for the first half.  </p>
<p>Merrill Lynch building materials analyst Michael Brown forecast a first half pre-abnormal net profit of A$90 million.</p>
<p>John North at J.B. Were &amp; Son also estimated Boral to report a pre-abnormal net profit of A$90 million.</p>
<p>Analysts said they expected Boral to pay a first half dividend of 7.5 cents.</p>
<p>In November, Boral said it would maintain a 7.5 cents per share dividend for the December half, the same amount it paid in the 1995/96 second half.</p>
<p>Boral paid a 10.5 cents dividend in the 1995/96 first half.  </p>
<p>Although analysts were in a narrow range for the first half result, forecasts for the 1996/97 full year varied from A$163.8 million to A$190 million for pre-abnormal net profit.</p>
<p>Boral reported a net profit before abnormals of A$170.9 million for the year to June 30, 1996.</p>
<p>Shares in the Sydney-based group have traded in a range between A$2.91 and A$3.70 since June 1996, when they were around A.</p>
<p>At 1.45 p.m. (0245 GMT), Boral shares were two cents lower at A$3.48.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
