<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="416117" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FOCUS-HIH enters new growth phase.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FOCUS-HIH enters new growth phase.</headline>
<byline>Michael Stapleton</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Insurance group HIH Winterthur International Holdings Ltd said on Monday it expected to see earnings growth from its operations in Australia, New Zealand, U.K. and America in the 1997 calendar year.</p>
<p>In addition, the company said it anticipated robust premiums growth, eventually translating into earnings growth, from its new businesses in China and Argentina and from its recent move into the bancassurance business in Australia.  </p>
<p>&quot;The outlook for 1997 is extremely positive,&quot; chief executive Ray Williams said in a statement accompanying the company's 1996 profit result.</p>
<p>&quot;Considerable premium growth is assured and, subject to movements in investment markets, the earnings impetus will be maintained,&quot; Williams said.</p>
<p>Earlier the company said its calendar 1996 net profit rose by 28 percent to A$61.5 million and it was now ranked as the second largest general insurer in Australia.  </p>
<p>Gross earned premium rose by 44 percent in 1996 to A$1.346 billion and net earned premium rose by 46 percent to A$931.5 million.</p>
<p>Investment income, excluding realised and unrealised capital movements, rose by 56 percent to A$96.1 million.</p>
<p>HIH Winterthur is 51 percent owned by Winterthur Swiss Insurance Company.</p>
<p>Williams told a media briefing California-based CareAmerica Compensation and Liability Insurance Co, which HIH re-purchased for US$59 million in January, would be &quot;earnings positive from day one.&quot;  </p>
<p>HIH sold the workers compensation unit, formerly known as Heath Cal, in 1994 to Care America in 1994 for US$93 million.</p>
<p>Williams said the company used a window of opportunity to sell the unit in 1994 and had taken advantage of a two-year slump in the workers compensation market in California to re-enter that market.</p>
<p>&quot;I've sene the results from CareAmerica for the last quarter which were not available at the time we negotiated the purchase and they're back in good solid profit,&quot; HIH's deputy chief executive, George Sturesteps said.  </p>
<p>Another important growth area for the company was its recent move into the bancassurance business through its acquisition of the Colonial Mutual's group's general insurance unit in January.</p>
<p>In a separate initiative, HIH has a deal to provide home and contents insurance to customers of National Australia Bank Ltd from July 1, 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been some studies undertaken that suggest you need to need to have a (bancassurance premium) book of around A$300 to A$400 million - we will certainly get close to that with our business,&quot; Williams said.  </p>
<p>HIH was looking to repeat its strong investment performance in 1997, Williams said, although the company had recently made a significant shift out of equities.</p>
<p>&quot;With the asset allocation we are actually down to about 18 percent now where as if you go back to the start of 1996 we were up as high as 28 percent in equities,&quot; said HIH general manager, investments, John Ballhausen.</p>
<p>&quot;The asset allocation reflects that there is some concern about there being a correction,&quot; Ballhausen said.  </p>
<p>Ballhausen said most of these funds had been shifted into fixed interest although the company was also becoming more bullish about the property market.</p>
<p>HIH shares closed three cents higher at A$3.12 on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
