<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="416132" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-KLZ Ltd sees stronger 2nd half.</title>
<headline>RTRS-KLZ Ltd sees stronger 2nd half.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Building materials and office supplies group KLZ Ltd said on Monday it expected earnings before interest, tax and abnormals (EBITA) in the second half of 1996/97 to be above the A$12 million achieved in the first half.</p>
<p>&quot;Directors believe that provided there is a continuation of the current economic and trading conditions KLZ's EBITA in the second half should exceed the A$12 million EBITA achieved in the first half,&quot; KLZ said in its first half results statement.</p>
<p>The statement confirmed figures released by the company on February 18.  </p>
<p>Earlier, KLZ said its net profit rose to A$9.21 million in the first half from A$4.25 million in the same half a year earlier. KLZ increased its interim dividend to eight cents per share from six cents per share.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook for the full year to June 30, 1997 is for a substantial increse in both the EBITA and the operating profit after tax of A$11.8 million achieved in 1995/96,&quot; KLZ said.</p>
<p>KLZ said it remained confident of meeting its annual meeting forecast of a full year dividend of 18 to 20 cents per share.  </p>
<p>KLZ said it was pleased with the result given difficult trading conditions in its printing and electronic components businesses.</p>
<p>It said the increase in first half EBITA was due to the inclusion of new electrical products units Arlec and Nexhaven for the full six months and earnings growth for the period.</p>
<p>KLZ's shares were unchanged at A$3.54 at 3.00 p.m. (0400 GMT).</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
