<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="416204" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: MSCI changes continue to weigh on Singapore stocks.</title>
<headline>MSCI changes continue to weigh on Singapore stocks.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Changes to be made to the weighting of Morgan Stanley Capital International (MSCII) Singapore Free Index announced last month continued to curb foreign tranches of Singapore stocks on Monday, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Free Index tracks companies' shares which may be held by foreigners.</p>
<p>Singapore's finance minister, Richard Hu's recent reiteration that there would be no relaxation to 1996 curbs to cool property speculation also dampened sentiment, dealers said. &quot;Morgan Stanley's weightage reduction and Hu's comments are all not so good news,&quot; said a dealer at a foreign bank.</p>
<p>The Straits Times Industrials Index reversed from negative territory in the last minutes to close marginally higher by 0.64 point at 2,196.34. The SES Foreign Index ended flat at 119.24.</p>
<p>Losers were led by foreign tranches of banks like OUB, UOB, DBS and OCBC which fell between Singapore $0.70 (US$0.49) and S$0.30.</p>
<p>&quot;Also, March is the corporate result season. Investors tend to be cautious,&quot; a dealer said, noting that electronic counter Amtek Engineering fell on expectations of weak results.</p>
<p>Amtek lost S$0.18 to S$2.70 on 719,000 shares.</p>
<p>The UOB-OTC index for mostly Malaysian shares fell 12.63 to 1,333.89.</p>
<p>US$1.00 = S$1.42</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
