<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="416382" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan MOF/BOJ to meet to discuss money market, FBs.</title>
<headline>Japan MOF/BOJ to meet to discuss money market, FBs.</headline>
<byline>Yoshiko Mori</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's powerful monetary authorities, the Ministry of Finance (MOF) and the Bank of Japan (BOJ), will meet as early as later this month to discuss issues in the money market, including short-term debt underwriting by the BOJ, a MOF official said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The subjects of the meeting include the sales method for Financing Bills (FBs), the legal status of money brokers and the Real Time Gross Settlement system,&quot; the MOF official told Reuters.</p>
<p>It has not yet been decided how often they will meet, he added.</p>
<p>Depending on the outcome of the meeting, it may point to a change in Japan's approach of influencing foreign exchange rates via quantitative currency intervention.</p>
<p>For decades, the BOJ has been proposing that 60-day government paper, called FBs, should be sold in the market, instead of the central bank buying most of the issue amount.</p>
<p>The BOJ argues that if FBs are designed for sale in the market, this would undoubtedly add to money market liquidity and the globalisation of the Tokyo financial market.</p>
<p>However, the MOF official said that the FBs should not be discussed only from the money-market perspective.  </p>
<p>MOF raises yen for market intervention through the issuance of FBs, which carry interest rates that are lower than prevailing market rates.</p>
<p>Due to the low yield, FBs are not always in great demand and the BOJ is obligated to buy most of the issues that are left unsold.</p>
<p>The FB rate is now at 0.375 percent or 0.125 percentage point below the discount rate, currently standing at a record low.</p>
<p>The outstanding volume of FBs totalled 25.20 trillion yen at the end of February.</p>
<p>Another MOF official said that if FB rates are set in line with the market, it would mean a heavier fiscal burden that may not be acceptable to taxpayers.</p>
<p>Helped by easy access to the intervention fund, Japan spent an estimated $64.73 billion to rein in the galloping yen in the two years to December 1996.</p>
<p>The BOJ has made no secret of its discontent over MOF's reliance on the central bank to finance intervention.</p>
<p>A BOJ spokesman said that the central bank's current stance has been reflected in recent remarks by its governor.</p>
<p>BOJ Governor Yasuo Matsushita said last month that the question of whether FBs are an appropriate way of raising funds for forex market intervention requires some consideration.</p>
<p>The question of FBs being underwritten by the central bank is not an issue to be looked at only in the context of the BOJ law, and provisions in the Budget law should also be taken into account, Matsushita said.</p>
<p>An article in the Budget law bars the BOJ from underwriting government long-term debt.</p>
<p>Under a proposed revision to the BOJ law, the BOJ would still be able to buy FBs.</p>
<p>But, despite the fact that FBs are a form of short-term debt, they are constantly rolled over, making the BOJ's FB purchases &quot;de facto&quot; underwriting of long-term government debt.</p>
<p>France and Germany have banned government underwriting of both short- and long-term debt as part of their moves toward European economic and monetary union and a European Central Bank.</p>
<p>In the United States, debt underwriting by the Federal Reserve has long been prohibited.</p>
<p>Senior BOJ officials said that history shows that government financial dependence on a central bank that can print money without any limitations has caused hyperinflation that has ultimately ruined nations.</p>
<p>---Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-3432-8676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
