<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="416358" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan's corporate capital spending seen edging up.</title>
<headline>Japan's corporate capital spending seen edging up.</headline>
<byline>Yoko Kobayashi</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Corporate capital spending, a key factor in the strength of Japan's economic recovery, will grow slightly in the next fiscal year but not enough to offset weak consumption, economists predicted on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength in corporate capital spending alone will not be enough to lead the recovery,&quot; said Kazuhiro Azekawa, an economist at Nippon Research Institute.</p>
<p>With turmoil in Tokyo financial markets having subsided for now, companies are going ahead with plans to raise capital spending, mainly for key items such as computers and telecoms equipment, to strengthen their positions before planned deregulation sharpens competition.</p>
<p>Economists said strong overseas demand and the weaker yen would also give a mild boost to capital spending.</p>
<p>But rising capital spending alone would not fully make up for weakness in domestic demand, another key factor in the recovery, in view of the April tax rise, marginal salary increases and less support from government stimulus measures.</p>
<p>Economists varied in their forecasts but the majority view was that capital spending would show a slight rise.</p>
<p>Azekawa said the institute expects capital spending to rise by 4.7 percent in the year starting on April 1 compared to the previous year. Japan Research Institute Inc's Hisashi Yamada said he expected growth of around three to four percent.</p>
<p>But a recent survey by financial daily Nihon Keizai Shimbun predicted 1997/98 corporate capital spending would grow by a 0.1 percent from the current year, despite slower spending in the information and communications sector.</p>
<p>Nippon Credit Bank Ltd predicted capital spending would drop by one percent in the early months of the year, although there was room for upward revisions later in the year.</p>
<p>The government has forecast that corporate capital spending in 1997/98 will grow by 7.4 percent, after estimated growth of 6.3 percent for this fiscal year.</p>
<p>&quot;I think many companies are completely at a loss as to what kind of capital spending plans to draw up, as there are so many uncertain factors,&quot; a government official said.</p>
<p>Japan is due to raise its consumption tax to five percent from three percent on April 1 and to end special income tax cuts so as to improve state finances. In addition, smaller firms are still staggering under the weight of debts dating from the economic &quot;bubble&quot; of the late 1980s.</p>
<p>In a recent report, the Bank of Japan (BOJ) said corporate balance sheets needed to be improved and that deregulation would provide incentives for companies to raise capital spending. More land transactions would help solve the balance sheet problem, the report said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, there are positive factors which could help fuel corporate capital spending, such as low interest rates, progress in inventory adjustments and the weaker yen.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone agrees that the economy will become sluggish temporarily in the April to June period. The key is what will happen to the economy from July onwards,&quot; Azekawa said.</p>
<p>Government officials are sticking to a rosy picture of recovery rebounding in the latter half of 1997/98 after an expected dip in consumption after the tax rise. But economists expect the recovery in consumption to be slow, hindering the expected rebound in the economy later in the fiscal year.</p>
<p>Others see export-led demand shrivelling with the return of a stronger yen and a slowdown in the U.S. economy.</p>
<p>&quot;Overseas demand will not grow at the current speed and (this) will only last for about a year,&quot; said Shunsuke Motani, an economist at Sphynx Investment Research.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
