<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="416641" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Bougainville rebels reject PNG mine buy-back.</title>
<headline>Bougainville rebels reject PNG mine buy-back.</headline>
<byline>Michael Perry</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Secessionist rebels on Bougainville island warned the Papua New Guinea government on Monday that the island's giant copper mine would remain closed until a political solution was reached in their conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;We closed the CRA mine in 1989 and it will remain so until a political agenda for the people of Bougainville is settled,&quot; said Moses Havini, Sydney-based spokesman for the Bougainville Interim Government, which represents the rebels.</p>
<p>Papua New Guinea Prime Minister Sir Julius Chan said on Sunday his government wanted to buy RTZ Corp Plc-CRA Ltd's controlling stake in the Panguna copper mine as part of a solution to the nine-year secessionist crisis on Bougainville.</p>
<p>He said the buy-back plan was part of a &quot;radical initiative&quot; to end the conflict, along with the recent hiring of African mercenaries as military advisers.</p>
<p>&quot;The original claims and dispute regarding this mine are at the heart of the Bougainville crisis and (are) critical to a fair and lasting solution,&quot; Chan said in a statement.</p>
<p>Chan said the buy-back scheme would result in compensation and a reconstruction package for local landowners.</p>
<p>Landowners disgruntled over royalty payments from the mine in central Bougainville sabotaged the mine in the late 1980s, with their wave of violence evolving into a secessionist revolt.</p>
<p>The crisis on Bougainville flared last week when the Papua New Guinea government confirmed it had hired mercenaries as advisors for local troops on a mission against the rebels.</p>
<p>The use of mercenaries attracted criticism from Australia, New Zealand, Britain and the United States.</p>
<p>Havini said Bougainville Revolutionary Army rebels had rejected Chan's buy-back scheme. &quot;Chan probably suffers from memory lapses. We have unsuccessfully tried to negotiate with the PNG government...for the last 25 years now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Right throughout this period not once did the PNG government and CRA come to the negotiating table with us.&quot;</p>
<p>CRA on Monday said it had not been formally contacted about the buy-back scheme, but expected to be approached soon.</p>
<p>&quot;CRA is obliged to consider any such approach on behalf of shareholders on its merits,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>Shares in Bougainville Copper Ltd, which operated the Panguna mine for 17 years until its closure, surged five cents or almost nine percent to 61 Australian cents (US$0.48) early on Monday on news of the buy-back scheme. The mine produced 166,000 tonnes of copper-in-concentrate in 1988.</p>
<p>CRA, the Australian arm of Anglo-Australia dual listed mining giant RTZ-CRA, owns 53.6 percent of Bougainville Copper, with the PNG government holding 19.1 percent.</p>
<p>But mining analysts said any resumption of mining would be at least three to four years away and would rely entirely on a political solution to the Bougainville crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;Rehabilitation would take quite a few years,&quot; said Peter O'Connor, mining analyst with Macquarie Equities. &quot;CRA has conservatively estimated that at at least three to four years.&quot;</p>
<p>CRA has estimated it would cost some A$450 million (US$350 million) to restart the mine.</p>
<p>&quot;The key risk is a political risk and at this stage CRA would be unlikely to even consider (reopening) it at this time,&quot; said O'Connor.</p>
<p>(AS1 = US$0.78)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
