<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="416626" id="root" date="1997-03-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: IMF's Camdessus pleased with Indian reforms.</title>
<headline>IMF's Camdessus pleased with Indian reforms.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>International Monetary Fund (IMF) managing director Michel Camdessus praised India's economic reforms and said he was pleased to see the country's commitment to liberalisation.</p>
<p>&quot;I am delighted to see that the government goes ahead with its strategies of liberalisation and opening and I am certain that this will be extremely good for your country,&quot; Camdessus told reporters in the southern city of Madras late on Sunday.</p>
<p>India began liberalising its economy in 1991 under former prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao, dismantling decades-old socialist controls.</p>
<p>Camdessus, who arrived in India late on Saturday on a four-day visit, said India figured high on his priority list and he wanted to assess how the IMF could play a greater role in its transformation process.</p>
<p>&quot;I am starting a new mandate at the IMF and I see it as extremely important to see your country,&quot; Camdessus said.</p>
<p>&quot;What are the prospects and how the IMF can accompany India in its momentous transformation and how India can continue contributing to all the missions of the IMF,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Camdessus also praised the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) for prudent management of the nation's monetary system but skirted questions on the Indian budget for the 1997/98 financial year (April/March), presented by Finance Minister P. Chidambaram to parliament last Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I heard about the budget, I have not read it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chidambaram cut taxes and slashed import duties in the budget. In two special trading sessions after the announcement, Indian stocks surged around 10 percent.</p>
<p>Camdessus said he would be meeting Chidambaram on a stopover in Delhi.</p>
<p>Camdessus denied the IMF was restructuring and said the changes were routine.</p>
<p>&quot;It (IMF) is permanently restructuring itself and adapting itself to its new missions, particularly to the challenges of globalisation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Camdessus was due to meet chief minister Pratap Singh Rane of Goa when he visits that state on Monday and Tuesday. Prabhakar Narvekar, who is retiring as deputy IMF managing director, is from Goa.</p>
<p>The IMF chief is also scheduled to meet Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda in New Delhi on Wednesday. He then travels to Hong Kong to address a major financial forum on March 7.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
