<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="416793" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US OPTIONS FOCUS/Two big trades highlight slow day.</title>
<headline>US OPTIONS FOCUS/Two big trades highlight slow day.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trading in individual equity options remained relatively thin Tuesday as investors favored the sidelines ahead of Congressional testimony Wednesday from Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan and the February unemployment report due Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been dead. It's really slow,&quot; one trader in Chicago said, adding that any market rally ahead of Greenspan and the economic data was unlikely.</p>
<p>Despite the sluggish action, a couple of sizable trades highlighted the activity, one in WorldCom Inc options and one in Trans World Airlines Inc options.  </p>
<p>The WorldCom March 25 call traded 5,360 contracts, making it the most active on the Pacific Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>WorldCom shares were down one at 25 on more than 6.5 million shares in late trading.</p>
<p>Most of the volume in the March 25 call was from one block of 5,000 contracts and one trader said an investor had bought those calls.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe it was a closing transaction,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>Michael Schwartz, a managing director at Oppenheimer &amp; Co, said the investor was most likely closing out a covered write position, buying back calls sold earlier.  </p>
<p>Few other WorldCom options were active.</p>
<p>&quot;It's pretty quiet,&quot; the trader said. &quot;There have been a lot of sellers but not a lot of options paper.&quot;</p>
<p>Among TWA options, the March 10 put traded 7,910 contracts at the American Stock Exchange. TWA options traded on the American, Pacific and New York Stock Exchange and on the Chicago Board Options Exchange.</p>
<p>TWA shares edged 1/8 higher to 6-1/16.</p>
<p>The March 10 put had open interest of 7,958, with 7,910 contracts having been added Monday.  </p>
<p>Schwartz said an investor most likely closed out that position.</p>
<p>&quot;Based upon the size of the transaction, he probably wouldn't have been able to execute it any better if he tried to buy the stock and then exercise&quot; the options, he explained.</p>
<p>((--Gregory Crawford, 312 408 8750))</p>
<p>((E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
