<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="41676" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India tax crackdown seen making little headway.</title>
<headline>India tax crackdown seen making little headway.</headline>
<byline>Narayanan Madhavan</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's tax evasion crackdown promised by Finance Minister P. Chidambaram is unlikely to help the government make much headway in its efforts to rein in a high fiscal deficit, economic analysts said on Sunday.</p>
<p>They said the answer to bridging high deficits was curbing government expenditure, improving efficiency of state-run companies and making more self- employed people pay taxes.</p>
<p>&quot;Tax evaders must be severely dealt with and they will be punished,&quot; Chidambaram told parliament on Friday in reply to a debate on the federal budget for 1996/97 (April-March).</p>
<p>&quot;We will become more and more strict,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mrityunjoy Athreya, a leading management consultant, told Reuters: &quot;That (a crackdown) upsets business confidence. Tax raids frighten the honest and do not scare the dishonest.&quot;</p>
<p>Officials say India has to curb its fiscal deficit and inflation, but must raise funds to build infrastructure facilities needed for high economic growth.</p>
<p>India is aiming for 6.6 percent growth in 1996/97, compared with 7.0 percent the previous year.</p>
<p>Chidambaram, who unveiled in July the first budget of Indian's centre-left coalition government, said it was the turn of taxpayers to respond after a steady easing of tax rates since 1991, when India launched its economic reform programme.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not a fully valid argument,&quot; Athreya said. &quot;I think tax rates in India are still high.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts say customs duties have been cut but individual tax rates are still high, starting at 20 percent on individuals with annual incomes as low as 40,000 rupees ($1,142).</p>
<p>Corporate tax, now 46 percent, should be cut to 30 percent, Athreya said.</p>
<p>Officials say inflation based on wholesale prices is around 5.0 percent after spending most of the past five years at around 10 percent. But a high fiscal deficit could push prices up again.</p>
<p>&quot;It is true that tax compliance is weak,&quot; former central bank governor R.N. Malhtotra told Reuters. But he said this alone was not enough.</p>
<p>&quot;The fiscal deficit is ultimately a balance between revenue and expenditure. I think it is necessary to tackle both,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Despite talk of a vast middle class market, estimated at between 200 and 400 million in a population of 930 million, the number of taxpayers at 10 million is far too low, analysts say.</p>
<p>Potential taxpayers, including the self-employed such as transport operators and affluent farmers are not taxed, they say.</p>
<p>&quot;A large number of people who are eligible for taxation are not paying taxes,&quot; Malhotra said.</p>
<p>While commodity taxes have been lowered, India must move further towards value- added taxation, now implemented only in a few industries, for effective taxation, Athreya said.</p>
<p>Chidambaram showed a resolve to widen the tax net in July when his budget imposed a controversial minimum tax on companies that earlier had avoided taxation by using a law that permitted exemption on profits if they were ploughed back as investment.</p>
<p>India's tax-to-GDP ratio is expected to rise to 10.5 percent this fiscal year, up from 10.1 percent in 1995/96, Chidambaram said on Friday. He said it must rise further.</p>
<p>The finance ministry wants to cut the fiscal deficit -- or budget deficit plus net government borrowings -- to 5.0 percent of GDP in 1996/97 from 5.9 percent the previous year. It aims to reduce it eventually to 4.0 percent but has given no time frame.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
