<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="41675" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India stocks need direction, Chidambaram holds key.</title>
<headline>India stocks need direction, Chidambaram holds key.</headline>
<byline>Ranjit Gangadharan</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's stock markets will be seeking direction this week, with brokers awaiting tax relief and other measures when Finance Minister P. Chidambaram wraps up a delayed budget debate, brokers said.</p>
<p>The country's bourses have lacked momentum after Chidambaram announced the 1996/97 budget proposals in July which included a minimum tax on profits of high- growth companies.</p>
<p>The 30-share index of the main Bombay Stock Exchange has lost about 280 points or 7.6 percent since the budget announcements on July 22. It closed at 3,508.07 on Friday.</p>
<p>In the first stage of his reply in parliament during a budget debate on Friday, Chidambaram announced a few incentives, including benefits for the mutual fund and debt markets, but brokers were muted in their response.</p>
<p>Traders want the finance minister to dilute the controversial minimum alternate tax on high-growth companies, and offer some excise relief to certain sectors of industry.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will be jerked,&quot; said Ramdeo Agarwal, research chief at broking firm Motilal Oswal, if these expectations were not met.</p>
<p>But brokers ruled out any sharp fall in prices.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's not going to collapse,&quot; said Uday Kotak, vice chairman at Kotak Mahindra Finance. &quot;Probably it will stay flat.&quot;</p>
<p>In parliament on Friday, Chidambaram stressed the need to boost India's capital markets, which include 24 stock exchanges serving more than 20 million investors.</p>
<p>&quot;While speculation is an unavoidable feature of any market, we must impart a certain stability to our markets so that the interests of millions of small investors are protected,&quot; Chidambaram said.</p>
<p>The finance minister removed a 30 percent ceiling on investment in debt instruments by foreign institutional investors and said they could float funds specifically dedicated to only debt.</p>
<p>He exempted investments in mutual funds from capital gains tax, raised the ceiling on tax-spared dividend and interest incomes to 15,000 rupees against 13,000 and doubled the limit to 1.0 million rupees for bank advances against shares.</p>
<p>&quot;What's causing some worry is clear signs that the economy is slowing,&quot; said Subra Subramanian, director at Hoare Govette (India) Securities Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;The slowdown will be more in the second half.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts expect corporate profits to grow at 15-20 percent in the first half of the financial year ending March 31, 1997 -- against nearly 30 percent in the year- ago period.</p>
<p>Last week the State Bank of India, the country's largest commercial bank, cut its prime lending rate to 15.5 percent from 16.0 percent to counter a slowing demand for funds.</p>
<p>Several other state-run banks are expected to announce similar cuts in lending rates soon.</p>
<p>Chidambaram's concessions will accelerate the issue of debt instruments, the latest fad for Indian investors seeking safer and better returns, brokers said.</p>
<p>On Monday, the Bombay Stock Exchange will begin trading in debt instruments, while several firms prepare to launch bonds or debentures that offer upwards of 16 percent in annual returns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
