<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="416970" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: CRICKET-KIWIS DRAW ONE-DAY SERIES VS ENGLAND.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-KIWIS DRAW ONE-DAY SERIES VS ENGLAND.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Brockett</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A resurgent New Zealand cricket team on Tuesday dashed England's hopes of a one-day series victory, bowling the tourists out for 200 after setting them 229 to win the fifth and decisive game.</p>
<p>The win means the Kiwis salvage a 2-2 draw in the five-match one-day series after England won the first two games and the third was tied in Napier last Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The team showed a lot of guts to come through what has been a difficult period,&quot; New Zealand captain Lee Germon said after the game.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we've come a long way to resurrecting the season.&quot;</p>
<p>Set 229 to win the match, England got away to a promising start. Paceman Geoff Allott clean bowled Mike Atherton with the third ball of the innings, but the England skipper was saved by a dubious no ball call from umpire Evan Watkin.</p>
<p>Television replays clearly showed Allott's foot was not fully over the no-ball line.</p>
<p>But England's good fortune was short-lived.</p>
<p>Allott soon had the prized wicket of Alec Stewart, who smashed a full toss straight to mid-on when he was on 18.</p>
<p>Atherton made the most of his reprieve, stroking 43 runs in effortless fashion until some sharp fielding saw him run out by keeper Lee Germon.</p>
<p>After Chris Harris enticed Nasser Hussain out of his crease to have him stumped by Germon for 20, England's hopes rested with Graham Thorpe.</p>
<p>The gritty left-hander came to the party, punishing anything loose to progress rapidly into the 30s. But persistent pressure form the New Zealand field saw wickets fall regularly at the other end.</p>
<p>Spinner Dipak Patel bowled Chris Silverwood for 4, Gavin Larsen had John Crawley lbw for 11, and Jack Russell, making his first appearance in the one-day series here, nicked a Nathan Astle ball to be cuaght behind for just two.</p>
<p>Craig White fell to Astle two balls later without scoring and when Robert Croft was run out for two, their chances of pulling off the win were remote.</p>
<p>Thorpe's innings came to an end when he was stumped by Germon off Larsen for 55. His half-century had come in 83 balls with two boundaries.</p>
<p>Gough was the last man out, caught on the cover fence for 16 in the 47th over.</p>
<p>England assistant coach John Emburey paid tribute to the New Zealand bowling attack, in which medium-pacers Larsen and Harris were again the most restrictive.</p>
<p>&quot;They really started to put the screws on and put the players under pressure. We made a few mistakes and started to get behind the clock,&quot; Emburey said.</p>
<p>New Zealand were able to post a defendable 228 after a dashing 94 from Astle. His sterling knock and two wickets earned him the man of the match award.</p>
<p>England comprehensively beat the Kiwis 2-0 in the three test matches in February and cruised almost effortlessly to a 2-0 lead in the five-match one-day series.</p>
<p>With their backs to the wall and mounting public frustration over the poor results, New Zealand revitalised their game. They tied the third match and won the last two in dramatic fashion to secure the 2-2 series draw and regain some lost pride.</p>
<p>They now face Sri Lanka in the first of two tests starting in Dunedin on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
