<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417095" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Urals seen firmer in slow Med, W.African crude trade.</title>
<headline>Urals seen firmer in slow Med, W.African crude trade.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mediterranean and West African crude markets remained mainly soft and sluggish in early talk on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But differentials for Russia's Urals crude were assessed at the firmer Dated Brent -94 cents cif Med done on Monday for a March 10/12 loader, traders said.</p>
<p>The improvement from levels of around Dated -$1.00/$1.10 seen recently was seen the result of slightly better buying interest.</p>
<p>But traders said fair value for Urals remained well down from another reported Monday deal arranged by two trading houses who said they had agreed to exchange a March 3-5 loader for Dated -85.</p>
<p>Some said the much stronger price for the March 3-5 loader appeared at first glance to be the result of pricing assessments by the seller and buyer for deliveries into Greece and Israel respectively.</p>
<p>Bullish factors for Urals include the closure of berthing on Tuesday at Russia's leading oil export terminal of Novorossiisk on the Black Sea and the closure on Monday of the 660,000 barrels per day (bpd) crude pipeline feeding the port for 128 hours of maintenance work.</p>
<p>More support came from news from shipping inspectors Petrak that Russian seaborne crude exports fell almost five percent, or</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
