<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417192" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Pay cap proposal dies at Laurentian Bank.</title>
<headline>Pay cap proposal dies at Laurentian Bank.</headline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A shareholder rights advocate's proposal that limits be set on bank executives' salaries died on the order paper at the Laurentian Bank of Canada annual meeting on Tuesday without a vote.</p>
<p>Yves Michaud, the activist who won the right in a Quebec court to put his proposals to a vote at the Royal Bank of Canada and National Bank of Canada, walked out of the Laurentian Bank meeting in protest before officially submitting his pay cap resolution.</p>
<p>As a result, the assembly did not have the opportunity to vote on the resolution.  </p>
<p>Michaud told reporters that he walked out of the meeting because Desjardins-Laurentian Financial Corp which owns 57.5 percent of Laurentian Bank, had indicated it would vote against his proposal.</p>
<p>Among his five resolutions, Michaud had proposed that the remuneration of the bank's highest-paid officer, including annual salary and bonuses, not exceed 20 times the average remuneration of the bank's employees.</p>
<p>Michaud said he was upset that Desjardins-Laurentian, which is controlled by Mouvement Desjardins, Quebec's largest credit union organization, would oppose his pay cap proposal.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Laurentian Bank's lobby of its majority shareholder bore fruit,&quot; Michaud said.</p>
<p>Although Michaud walked out of the meeting, he was able to make his point during a long speech that earned applause and provoked laughter from the gathering for his humorous turn of phrase.</p>
<p>After the meeting, Henri-Paul Rousseau, president and chief executive of Laurentian Bank, said the bank's board opposed Michaud's resolutions because much of what he was advocating is already policy at the bank.</p>
<p>&quot;A large part of what was proposed we are doing already,&quot; Rousseau said.</p>
<p>Michaud had also proposed that that low-interest personal loans to the bank's directors and senior officers no longer be offered, that bank directors be limited to terms of 10 years, and that the chairman be appointed by board members who are not bank personnel.</p>
<p>((Reuters Montreal bureau 514-985-2434))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
