<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417285" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Sarajevo Catholic church hit by bomb blast.</title>
<headline>Sarajevo Catholic church hit by bomb blast.</headline>
<byline>Sabina Cosic</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Roman Catholic church in downtown Sarajevo was rocked by an explosion early on Tuesday which damaged windows and nearby cars, witnesses said.</p>
<p>A bomb exploded at the back door of the church of Saint Joseph in the Marijin Dvor neighbourhood just after one a.m. (midnight GMT), shattering windows in two residential buildings nearby.</p>
<p>The blast was the latest in a series of attacks on Catholic churches in Bosnia's Moslem-Croat Federation which underscored rising ethnic tensions after a shooting incident in the southern town of Mostar last month.</p>
<p>Relations between the federation partners deteriorated when Croats opened fire on Moslems trying to visit a cemetery in the Croat-held part of Mostar. One Moslem man was shot dead in the February 10 incident.</p>
<p>A hand grenade was thrown at another Roman Catholic church and a convent in Sarajevo last week. A church in the central Bosnian town of Gornji Vakuf was mined and damaged as well.</p>
<p>Mostar was the scene of the worst fighting between Moslems and Croats in a 1993-94 war which left the town divided.</p>
<p>International efforts to reunite Mostar have failed and the federation has since been plagued by bitter political disputes.</p>
<p>The Croatian government protested to Bosnian Moslem authorities on Tuesday over the Sarajevo church attack.</p>
<p>The Croatian news agency HINA said Hido Biscevic, an aide to the Croatian foreign minister, met Bosnian Ambassador to Croatia Kasim Trnka to discuss various political issues.</p>
<p>&quot;Biscevic protested most strongly against the latest attack at the Church of St Joseph,&quot; HINA reported.</p>
<p>Croatia expected Bosnian Moslem authorities to &quot;take all political and other measures to stop pressure and violence against Croats in the Bosnian Federation and prevent frequent attacks against priests and facilities of the Roman Catholic church&quot;, Biscevic said.</p>
<p>Croatia was indignant at the fact that those who had committed acts of violence had not been brought to justice, and it expected more forceful action &quot;particularly in the light of the forthcoming visit of Pope John Paul to Sarajevo,&quot; he was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;Both Biscevic and Trnka stressed that it was necessary to stop negative tendencies in the relations between the two federal partners,&quot; HINA reported.</p>
<p>&quot;The Croatian side said it was determined to check individual harmful local criminal acts (by Croats) and Croatia was expecting the Moslem side to show the same resolve.&quot;</p>
<p>HINA said the Sarajevo Bosnian Croat branch of the ruling Croatian HDZ party held an urgent meeting on Tuesday to complain that Croats had no rights in Sarajevo.</p>
<p>Saying that in the last ten days three churches were bombed, graveyards tampered with, witnesses beaten up and Croat houses attacked, HDZ said fear and insecurity had grown among Sarajevo Croats.</p>
<p>The Pope had to cancel a planned visit to Sarajevo in 1994 when Serb siege forces refused to guarantee his safety.</p>
<p>Bosnian newspapers quoted the Catholic church information office for the upcoming papal visit as saying it had received threatening phone calls and had to shut down for a day.</p>
<p>Bosnian Moslem authorities pledged to step up security around Catholic churches and buildings after recent attacks.</p>
<p>The Moslem-Croat war ended with a U.S-brokered federation agreement in March 1994, but power-sharing and efforts to allow refugees to return home have run into obstacles on both sides.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
