<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417367" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Bosnia's local polls to be postponed again - sources.</title>
<headline>Bosnia's local polls to be postponed again - sources.</headline>
<byline>Sabina Cosic</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bosnia's hotly-contested municipal elections, originally proposed for July, will probably be postponed until September, Western officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;No firm date has been set, but it looks like the two days of elections in September will be 13th and 14th,&quot; an official said.</p>
<p>The local polls were originally supposed to be held in September 1996, along with general elections, but were postponed because of widespread election fraud over refugee registration.</p>
<p>The municipal vote was moved to November last year and then July of this year.</p>
<p>Western countries funding the election were pushing for a third postponement of the local polls to allow more time to organise refugee registration and international monitoring of the voting, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;A bit more time is needed to get all the issues sorted out -- getting the money on tap, getting the international supervisors into Bosnia and making sure the refugee registration process works well,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), which is supervising the elections, needs $50 to $55 million to organise the vote, the official said.</p>
<p>The next round of nationwide elections are set for 1998, a year after the scheduled municipal balloting in September.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the OSCE declined to confirm the postponement but said a statement would be issued on Thursday.</p>
<p>Bosnia's local polls are viewed as the country's last chance for reunification after a devastating 43-month war. The vote is supposed to enable refugees to elect authorities in their former towns and reverse the effects of wartime ethnic expulsions.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of people were uprooted by the war and their votes could change the leadership in municipalities ruled by officials attempting to seal their control over conquered territory.</p>
<p>Bosnian Serbs were charged with manipulating registration of people displaced inside the country, pushing them to vote in the towns where they had resettled.</p>
<p>Thousands of Serb refugees in neighbouring Yugoslavia were registered for voting in Bosnian towns where Moslems had held a pre-war majority but were expelled during the war.</p>
<p>In an attempt to prevent election fraud, the OSCE said it would place one international supervisor at each of 2,300 polling stations across the country.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
