<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417404" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish martial law ruler Jaruzelski seriously ill.</title>
<headline>Polish martial law ruler Jaruzelski seriously ill.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Wojciech Jaruzelski, who as communist ruler clamped martial law on Poland in 1981, is seriously ill in hospital with a thigh infection brought on by treatment with steroids, a hospital spokesman said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The patient's condition is regarded as serious,&quot; Janusz Bolewski, a professor of the Warsaw military hospital treating Jaruzelski, said in a statement issued to PAP news agency.</p>
<p>The statement said Jaruzelski, 73, would remain in the central clinical hospital of the Military Medical Academy for at least a dozen days.</p>
<p>It said Jaruzelski had been receiving long-term treatment with steroids, which had brought about erysipelas -- a skin infection -- on the under part of his left thigh.</p>
<p>&quot;If untreated this could even lead to the patient's death,&quot; Bolewski, the hospital spokesman, said in the statement.</p>
<p>The statement reported by PAP did not explain why Jaruzelski had been receiving steroids, which are used to treat a variety of conditions.</p>
<p>Jaruzelski imposed martial law in December 1981 to crush Solidarity, then the Soviet bloc's first free trade union, but in 1989 he presided over the communists' surrender of power.</p>
<p>Poland's parliament, dominated by ex-communists, voted last year that Jaruzelski and other communist leaders should not be prosecuted over martial law.</p>
<p>But he still faces trial in Gdansk over the fatal shootings by security forces in 1970, when he was defence minister, of dozens of demonstrators during protests sparked by food price rises.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
