<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417492" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile shares end mixed as market awaits Greenspan.</title>
<headline>Chile shares end mixed as market awaits Greenspan.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chilean stocks closed mixed in lighter-than-average activity on Tuesday as investors looked over company results and a slew of economic figures released during the day, dealers said.</p>
<p>The bolsa is seen opening weaker on Wednesday, with the focus centered on congressional testimony by Alan Greenspan, chairman of the U.S. Federal Reserve, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign investors are nervous about what Greenspan will say,&quot; said one trader. &quot;If they stay away, then the bolsa could sink further.&quot; The selective index ended 0.34 percent lower at 114.15 points.  </p>
<p>Traders said the bolsa, which has steadily lost ground in recent sessions, could find support at about 112 points.</p>
<p>The general index gained 0.01 percent at 5,324.79 points on trading of shares valued at eight billion pesos.</p>
<p>Investors welcomed industrial output and unemployment data that confirmed that the economy was slowing, while they attributed February's high inflation to one-time seasonal factors, traders said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
