<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417507" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks tumble at close amid rate fears.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks tumble at close amid rate fears.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican stocks on Tuesday closed sharply down for the fifth session in a row after forecasts of an impending surge in primary interest rates triggered a sell-off in late trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was frightful. The bourse took a battering, discounting the rates hike we'll see this evening,&quot; a Mexico City desk trader said.</p>
<p>The leading IPC share index ended down 40.23 points, or 1.06 percent, at 3,755.69. Trading volume picked up in late trade to 114.1 million shares.  </p>
<p>&quot;What happened was that the forecast increase in primary rates rose, and the peso sagged in late trade,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>Later Tuesday, Banco de Mexico is expected to assign bellwether 28-day Cetes at an average of 21.61 percent, up 302 basis points from its auction last week, according to Reuters survey of eight money market traders in Mexico City.</p>
<p>Benchmark 48-hour peso contracts meanwhile were 0.2 of a centavo softer at 7.9930/7.9970.  </p>
<p>Traders said Mexican stocks suffered amid a late slide on Wall Street, where investors succumbed to a bout of jitters ahead of congressional testimony on Wednesday by Alan Greenspan, the U.S. Federal Reserve chairman.</p>
<p>Still, it was local factors that weighed most heavily on Mexican share prices, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Dealers aren't too worried over Greenspan or the Dow. Besides, that would have hit ADRs,&quot; another desk trader said.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones closed off 0.96 percent at 6,852.72 points.</p>
<p>Telmex ADRs ended up 1/8 at 38-5/8, while media group Telmex gained one dollar to 25.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, Telmex L shares ended six centavos higher at 15.40 pesos, and Televisa CPO shares gained 3.30 pesos to 99.50 pesos.</p>
<p>Technical analysts said the IPC index ended near support, which they situated at 3,750 points.</p>
<p>&quot;The IPC failed to respect intermediate support at 3,770 points, and should it break through at 3,750 points, we could go down to 3,700,&quot; said Hctor Jimnez, an analyst at the Inverlat brokerage.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem here is that it fell at heavy volume,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>On the broad market, 109 stocks changed hands, of which decliners outnumbered gainers by 62 to 27.</p>
<p>Steelmaker Ahmsa, down 42 centavos to 16.90 pesos, was the most heavily traded decliner, though dealers said that mostly reflected a cross trade of more than 10 million shares.</p>
<p>Another leading decliner was Carso Global Telecom, off 1.40 pesos at 23.00 pesos.</p>
<p>Publishing firm Gfesa, up 18 centavos to 1.70 pesos, topped  the gainers' list after announcing a Bankers Trust subsidiary had formalized its acquisition of a minority shareholding in the company.</p>
<p>((--Karina Balderas, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9562))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
