<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417605" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - Mar 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - Mar 5.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE NEW ZEALAND HERALD</p>
<p>Free visits to the doctor for the under-fives, more funding for mental health and money to reduce hospital waiting lists will feature in the coalition government's first budget. The Treasurer, Winston Peters, signalled in the budget policy statement released on Tuesday that these new expenditure items would survive the rephasing of the coalition's $5 billion spending programme. However, although Peters indicated that education would also be a priority area, it is understood that the Minister of Education, Wyatt Creech, had hoped to do significantly better out of the budget round.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Auckland Warriors are unlikely to quickly tackle a sharemarket listing, despite plans by their chairman, Gerald Ryan, to float the rugby league team within two years. Ryan outlined the timetable on Tuesday after being given a mandate by the Auckland clubs to investigate options available for the beleaguered team. Brokers, however, were highly sceptical about the success of a stock exchange listing, given the Warriors' poor playing record.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Designing and manufacturing more than 2500 electronic baggage and cargo loading scales for use at more than 50 airports in 15 countries has won Auckland company Atrax Group (NZ) Ltd a Tradenz export commendation. Atrax machines are operating at international and domestic airports in China, Russia and India, as well as closer to home in Australia, South-east Asia and the Far East.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Brierley Investments will report a first-half net profit on Thursday of less than $115 million, sharply down from the 1996 interim of $170 million, analysts said on Tuesday. However, they placed little store on the result as a measure of the comapny's value, saying its reported profits were highly dependent on asset sales and there would be no significant gains from that source in the six month period which ended on December 31.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Fernz Corporation expects to make an announcement affecting its 28 percent holding in French-listed agro-industrial chemical company CFPI before the end of its May 31 financial year. The managing director, Kerry Hoggard, would not be specific but said moving to full ownership was possible, among other options. &quot;When you've got two public companies, both with about 30 percent of another public company something has to happen -- that's about as far as I can go with it at the moment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Moana Pacific Fisheries has reported a tax-paid profit of $4.03 million for the year to September 30, down nearly $2 million from the previous year's $6.93 million. Sales were flat at $99.35 million. Directors declared a dividend of 6.5 cents a share. The chairman, Graham Latimer, said the combined effects of increased government charges and the continuing high value of the New Zealand dollar had resulted in reduced earnings and lower profits.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Ravensdown Corporation subsidiary AEL Corporation has begun a bid to buy $1 million worth of shares in rival Bay of Plenty Co-operative. Last Christmas, BOP Co-op gained control of Southland-based fertiliser company Southfert after a bitter struggle with Ravensdown. The Ravensdown chairman, Jim Pringle, said the share buy-up would allow Ravensdown to look after its own shareholders who also had shares in BOP C-op following its purchase of Southfert.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Air New Zealand says it is still talking to several parties over the possible sale of its in-flight catering business. &quot;We are looking at whether or not to get out of the catering business. Obviously we still need a continuing supply of food in our aircraft. We are exploring a number of possibilities,&quot; an airline spokesman, Cameron Hill, said.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
