<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417694" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Six Asia-Pacific economies agree on closer contact.</title>
<headline>Six Asia-Pacific economies agree on closer contact.</headline>
<byline>Tsukasa Maekawa</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senior financial and central bank officials from five Asian economies and the United States agreed on Tuesday to closely cooperate to seek stability in currency and other markets in the region.</p>
<p>The first meeting of a &quot;Six Markets&quot; forum grouping Australia, China, Hong Kong, Japan, Singapore and the United States did not go much beyond an exchange of information on financial and currency markets.</p>
<p>But Takatoshi Kato, vice minister for international affairs at Japan's Finance Ministry, who chaired the meeting, left open the possibility of greater substance in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;We didn't discuss any specific scheme to cooperate because it was just the first meeting,&quot; Kato told a news conference. &quot;We do not know how the forum will develop in the future.&quot;</p>
<p>The group agreed to meet regularly and set its next session at sub-ministerial level in a year's time in Singapore.</p>
<p>Japanese Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka said earlier this week he hoped the new forum would be upgraded to include finance ministers and central bank chiefs in the future.</p>
<p>Kato said: &quot;We spent a lot of time exchanging information about each other's economies and financial markets and have recognised the importance of keeping close contacts to seek stability in those markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Japanese media have dubbed the forum &quot;G6&quot; or Group of Six, likening it to the Group of Seven (G7) industrial nations -- the United States, Japan, Germany, France, Britain, Italy and Canada -- which meets regularly to coordinate economic policy.</p>
<p>Japanese officials stressed the importance of having in the group both China, a growing economic powerhouse, and the United States, whose currency dominates the region.</p>
<p>Deputy Treasury Secretary Lawrence Summers, head of the U.S. delegation, said: &quot;China was a full participant in the group...I think it was useful for the members of the group to have the opportunity to engage in dialogue with the Chinese authorities.&quot;</p>
<p>Kato stressed the importance of the six markets including China and of closer contacts so that the participating economies can better cope with any financial crisis.</p>
<p>A Chinese participant said: &quot;Generally speaking the meeting was friendly. It was the first time for us to be heard and we had no experience to do this before. Everybody had their own ideas. It was fruitful. This is just a beginning.&quot;</p>
<p>The six participants' combined gross domestic product (GDP) accounts for nearly half the world's output, while 41 percent of the world's currency transactions are conducted in their markets and they hold 33 percent of the world's foreign currency reserves.</p>
<p>Summers said China participated actively in discussions on such issues as evolution of financial markets, possible regulatory changes, and the monetary and financial changes surrounding the idea of &quot;one country, two systems&quot;.</p>
<p>The phrase is used to refer to the British territory of Hong Kong, which reverts to Chinese rule in July.</p>
<p>Other topics discussed at the meeting included economic conditions and the supervisory and regulatory systems in financial markets in each of the six economies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
