<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417745" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Netanyahu targets Palestinian offices in Jerusalem.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu targets Palestinian offices in Jerusalem.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>to be served on Wednesday)</p>
<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, in a move coinciding with a Washington visit by Palestinian President Yasser Arafat, on Tuesday ordered the closure of four Palestinian offices in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>There was no immediate Palestinian comment but the moves are certain to anger the PLO at a time of high tensions following Israel's decision last week to build 6,500 new Jewish homes in East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>&quot;Police will begin to act tomorrow and issue closure orders against four offices which beyond any legal doubt have been proven to be offices of the Palestinian Authority,&quot; Netanyahu's spokesman said in a statement.</p>
<p>Under Israel-PLO peace deals, the Palestinian Authority in charge of parts of the West Bank and Gaza Strip cannot operate in Arab East Jerusalem, whose final status is to be decided in future peace talks.</p>
<p>The Public Security Ministry, in charge of national police, said only warning notices would be served at the offices on Wednesday. Army Radio said they would be given 48 hours to shut down on their own.</p>
<p>&quot;The timing and procedure (for closure) and the names of the institutions will be announced only nearer to the actual implementation,&quot; the ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's spokesman also declined to name the offices and said the prime minister ordered their closure on the recommendation of his adviser on terrorism, Meir Dagan.</p>
<p>In addition, Netanyahu instructed Police Minister Avigdor Kahalani to &quot;remove by the end of the week Palestinian security men operating in Jerusalem&quot;, the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime minister gave instructions to continue to examine if there are additional offices acting on behalf of the Palestinian Authority in Jerusalem,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's spokesman issued the statement only hours after Arafat told a news conference that he still regarded the right-wing Israeli leader as a peace partner despite the Jerusalem housing project</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
