<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417796" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton says time to address &quot;big&quot; issues.</title>
<headline>Clinton says time to address &quot;big&quot; issues.</headline>
<byline>Laurence McQuillan</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton, caught in an uproar over Democratic fund raising, said on Tuesday it was time to &quot;get on with the big business&quot; facing America but Republicans instead pressed for a probe by a special counsel.</p>
<p>Clinton and Vice President Al Gore, hounded by allegations of unseemly and possibly illegal fund-raising activities surrounding their re-election efforts, have professed their innocence but been unable to direct attention to other issues.</p>
<p>At the end of an Oval Office ceremony in which Clinton issued a directive banning federal money from being used for research on human cloning, he immediately was peppered with questions about fund raising and pending congressional probes.</p>
<p>&quot;I certainly have no objection to hearings,&quot; Clinton said. &quot;I've always assumed that they would occur.&quot;</p>
<p>He then noted that Congress and the White House has &quot;the public's business to get on with as well -- a lot of other issues that need to be dealt with.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Get on with the big business, get on with balancing the budget,&quot; said Clinton, who aides privately acknowledge has been increasingly frustrated with the media focus on an apparent scandal.</p>
<p>&quot;Get on with passing the education program. Get on with doing the other things that are out there for us to do,&quot; he said, adding, &quot;I'm going to do everything I can to facilitate that.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton and Gore have been trying to adopt a business-as-usual approach in recent months, but most of the subjects they have raised have been lost in the steady stream of revelations about fund-raising practices for the Democratic Party.</p>
<p>Congressional Republican leaders on Tuesday challenged Gore's claim that he did not violate any law when he made telephone calls from the White House soliciting campaign contributions.</p>
<p>They also reiterated their call for appointment of an independent counsel to investigate campaign financing irregularities.</p>
<p>&quot;The law is clear that you should not be raising money on federal property and federal buildings,&quot; Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott told reporters. &quot;It's there and if that's what happened then that itself would be enough to indicate that a special counsel should be appointed.&quot;</p>
<p>House Speaker Newt Gingrich charged the Clinton campaign has violated campaign reform laws &quot;on a grand scale.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This is not 'everybody does it.' This is the most systematic large-scale effort to get around the law that we've certainly seen since Watergate, and in its total effort I think is much bigger than Watergate was,&quot; Gingrich said.</p>
<p>Clinton has tried to distance himself from party operations -- noting on Tuesday that he was merely the &quot;titular head&quot; of the party. Internal White House documents, however, have shown an active and direct role by Clinton in the party's operations.</p>
<p>On Monday Gore was forced to hold a hastily called news conference to acknowledge that he made &quot;a few&quot; telephone calls from his White House office to potential contributors asking for donations to the Democratic National Committee (DNC).</p>
<p>Although other federal officials are forbidden to use government property for such calls, Gore said vice presidents are not covered by the law. He said the calls were charged to a Democratic National Committee credit card.</p>
<p>A Senate committee and a House panel are preparing to investigate campaign abuses, centering for the most part on Democratic fund raising.</p>
<p>Attorney General Janet Reno has rejected requests for a special independent counsel to investigate fund raising, saying it was not warranted at this point.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
