<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417713" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Technology 1996 profits seen stronger.</title>
<headline>Technology 1996 profits seen stronger.</headline>
<byline>Azhar Sukri</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian telecommunications firm Technology Resources Industries Bhd is expected to post a stronger set of corporate earnings for the year to December 31, 1996, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The results are very encouraging. They are better than last year, even though people have been saying we have been having management problems,&quot; said a source close to the company.</p>
<p>The company's pre-tax profit would be around 350 million ringgit, the source said.</p>
<p>Assuming the company's 1996 tax rate remains roughly similar to that of 1995, that translates to a net profit of around 270 million ringgit, which would be well above most analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>Analysts polled by Reuters said they expect net profits for 1996 to be between 230 and 262 million ringgit.</p>
<p>TRI is expected to release its results by Friday.</p>
<p>For the 1995 financial year, TRI posted pre-tax profit of 238.35 million ringgit and net earnings of 185 million ringgit.  </p>
<p>Technology Resources operates the country's largest cellular telephone network and is entering the fixed-line market by laying down fibre optic cables in collaboration with Germany's Deutsche Telekom.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm expecting a net profit figure of 262.4 million ringgit based on higher subscriber growth. That makes it a 'buy',&quot; said Chow Quee Yee, head of research at Yamaichi Advisory Services in Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>Technology Resources chairman Tajudin Ramli Said in February he expected the pre-tax profit figure to be &quot;very much better than that for the financial year 1995&quot;. Analysts took that to mean a pre-tax figure of around 270 to 285 million ringgit.</p>
<p>&quot;We still believe the market is underestimating its strengths both as the dominant cellular player and as a potential new fixed-line operator,&quot; said equity research house H.G. Asia in a recent report on the company.</p>
<p>Technology Resources has been dogged by talk of a management walkout and falling revenues due to increased competition.</p>
<p>But company officials have downplayed management changes and said that TRI maintains a strong market share.  </p>
<p>The company was also hit by a 44 million ringgit one-time bad debt charge due to fraud on its international roaming service. With that item greatly reduced, the company should have posted a much stronger showing in 1996, said analysts.</p>
<p>Simone Yeoh, an analyst at HSBC James Capel in Kuala Lumpur, forecasted the bad debt provision had dropped to 17 million ringgit.</p>
<p>But despite the bullish sentiment, several analysts were unsure about the company's immediate future.</p>
<p>Yeoh said she estimated the company's pre-tax profit to be 304.9 million, translating to a net profit of 243.9 million. She based this on falling call revenue per subscriber which she calculated fell to 83 ringgit per subscriber per month in 1996 from 89 ringgit per subscriber per month in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no compelling reason to buy Technology Resources at the moment, so I'm calling a 'hold' on the stock,&quot; she said. &quot;The sector has to stabilise.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
