<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417986" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FCOJ ends sharply up on technicals, Brazil strike.</title>
<headline>FCOJ ends sharply up on technicals, Brazil strike.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Frozen concentrated orange juice futures ended sharply higher on brisk speculative and fund buying, market sources said.</p>
<p>The benchmark May contract opened above the 18-day moving average of 82.57 at 82.60 cents a lb and continued to rack up gains throughout the session, piercing the recent high of 85.20 cents reached on Feb 20 by May delivery.</p>
<p>May settled 5.90 cents higher at 87.70 cents, traded 87.75 to 82.60 cents. Spot March went out 5.75 cents higher at 84.75 cents. The back months closed down 5.00 to 3.85 cents.</p>
<p>The last trading day for March juice is Monday. Both March and May have a 10.00-cent daily limit while the back months cannot move more than 5.00 cents in a session.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at a brisk 6,000 lots, up from Monday's official 3,507 lots.</p>
<p>Market sources said a potential strike at Brazi's Paranagua port contributed to gains. While the strike is not likely to hurt exports since the industry relies on the private sector, the failure of port officals and dockworkers to reach an agreement lent psychological support to the market, said Celeste Georgakis, vice president with Dean Witter.</p>
<p>Analysts agree that today's close signals a reversal of the recent downtrend in the near term but added that the longer-term outlook remains to the downside.</p>
<p>Florida is expected to produce a record 220 million 90-lb boxes in 1996/97, and the chances for a damaging freeze are becoming slim as winter retreats.</p>
<p>((Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodity Desk 212-859-1646))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
