<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417935" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Strong U.S. economy and Bundesbank remarks lift dollar.</title>
<headline>Strong U.S. economy and Bundesbank remarks lift dollar.</headline>
<byline>Alden Bentley</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar hit a new 34-month high against the German mark on Tuesday, extending a rally fuelled by expectations of a U.S. interest rate hike and signs that Germany's central bank would not oppose a stronger dollar.</p>
<p>The dollar soared to its previous 1997 high of 1.7050 marks in early European trade, buoyed by strong U.S. economic data on Monday, and talk that Germany's jobless rate may have surged to another post-war high in February.</p>
<p>A further boost came in New York on news of a 8.6 percent leap in January U.S. single-family home sales, which reinforced a belief that the Federal Reserve would soon raise interest rates to moderate economic growth.</p>
<p>The dollar continued climbing to 1.7162 marks, its highest since late April 1994, after Bundesbank Council member Guntram Palm said the dollar's recent advance was an &quot;appropriate&quot; correction from its record low in 1995 and that this view does not change with movements of just a few pfennigs.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sure the market is thinking: 'Well, how does 1.75 (marks) grab you?' That is the comment (Palm's) that got everybody's interest,&quot; said Stephen Jury, chief foreign exchange dealer at Union Bank of Switzerland, in New York.</p>
<p>The dollar fetched 1.7137 marks late Tuesday, up from 1.6970 marks late Monday.</p>
<p>The dollar also rose to 122.15 Japanese yen from 121.24 yen and to 1.4865 Swiss francs from 1.4775 Swiss.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the underlying elements of the economy that support the strong housing market are important when you talk about relative growth,&quot; said Bob Lynch, senior currency analyst at MMS International.</p>
<p>The weak German economy almost ensures that the Bundesbank will not raise interest rates soon, experts said.</p>
<p>The market is on heightened alert for higher U.S. interest rates after Fed Chairman Alan Greenspan told a Senate panel last Wednesday that the Fed could tighten credit even before solid signs of inflation emerge.</p>
<p>Higher rates would make U.S. investments more attractive.</p>
<p>However, traders mostly ignored Greenspan's comments to the Budget Committee of the House of Representatives on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Financial markets are waiting for the final session of the Fed chief's semi-annual Humphrey-Hawkins testimony before the House Banking Committee on Wednesday, expecting a replay of his performance last week.</p>
<p>&quot;We're poised to raise rates here,&quot; said James Powers, a vice president of corporate foreign exchange at Westdeutsche Landesbank Girozentrale, in New York. &quot;Greenspan said that obviously last week -- a possible preemptive rate hike, etc. and the economy chugging along well. The U.S. looks like a pretty good place to be in.&quot;</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the dollar rose to Canadian $1.3696 from C$1.3675 on Monday. The pound fell to $1.6138 from $1.6178.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
