<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="417910" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX electricity closes higher amid unit outages.</title>
<headline>NYMEX electricity closes higher amid unit outages.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX electricity futures settled up, but down from the day's highs, amid a spate of power plant outages, trade sources said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Palo Verde (PV) prices were particularly strong, due largely to news that restart of the 1,070 megawatt (MW) unit 2 at the San Onofre nuclear power plant in southern California would be further delayed.</p>
<p>But the rally was expected to be short-lived, with prices seen settling back down after more information on the unit's status is available.</p>
<p>&quot;This is, unfortunately, a dead time of year. You don't have hot weather, but you don't have cold, cold weather either,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>He noted most of the recent plant outages are typical two or three day tube leak events He noted most of the recent plant outages are typical two or three day tube leak events or regular planned maintenance, which is generally conducted during seasonal transitions.</p>
<p>The Nuclear Regulatory Commission said the San Onofre unit would restart March 13, but a spokesman for Southern California Edison Co said a timeframe for further repairs remained uncertain.</p>
<p>Other plant outages include the 1,221 MW Palo Verde 3 nuclear unit, a 750 MW Navajo coal-fired unit, a 750 MW unit at the Mohave coal-fired plant and a 300 MW coal-fired unit at the Reid Gardner plant in Nevada.</p>
<p>Units at the San Juan coal-fired plant in New Mexico and the Colstrip plant in Montana were also said to be down for repairs, but their status could not be officially confirmed.</p>
<p>Traders said a unit at the Jim Bridger coal-fired plant in Wyoming would shut for scheduled work later this week.</p>
<p>In addition, the 1,158 MW WNP-2 nuclear unit in Washington was expected to ramp down Wednesday night for an extended refueling outage due to last until early July.</p>
<p>The April California-Oregon border (COB) contract settled up 19 cents per megawatt hour (MWh) at $9.59, while the May contract was up 15 cents at $9.70.</p>
<p>Active forward-month COB contracts were up 5 cents a MWh.</p>
<p>April PV settled 40 cents higher at $13.55, while May gained 30 cents to close at $13.95.</p>
<p>Forward-month PV contracts were up 15 to 30 cents per MWh.</p>
<p>The latest six to 10-day forecast for the Northwest called for below normal temperatures and above normal precipitation.</p>
<p>In the Southwest, temperatures were expected to average near normal in northern sections and above normal in southern sections over the same period.</p>
<p>   ((--Los Angeles bureau +1 213 955 6761))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
