<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418017" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYS monitor wants bonanza used to pay down debt.</title>
<headline>NYS monitor wants bonanza used to pay down debt.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York State Comptroller on Tuesday recommended that a projected $1.6 billion windfall for fiscal 1997 be used to pay down debt and boost a fund that could be drawn upon in emergencies.</p>
<p>H. Carl McCall, who spoke at a gathering of the New York State Newspaper Publishers Association in Albany, also told reporters that the Pataki Administration's capital plan would raise backdoor borrowing, a criticism he has made previously.</p>
<p>Voters never got a chance to specifically approve about $21 billion of the state's approximately $30 billion of debt outstanding, and by 2001, the amount of bonds that would be borrowed without their explicit say so rises to $28.6 billion under the governor's plan, McCall said.</p>
<p>The state's top fiscal monitor estimated debt service will rise to almost $4 billion by 2001 to 2002 from $2.8 billion at present.</p>
<p>Gov George Pataki has proposed depositing about $65 million in the state's Rainy Day Fund, which could be used to help stabilize the state's finances if there were a downturn, but his plan fell short in McCall's eyes.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we could easily double that and at the same time look at a reduction in debt service,&quot; he said, though he noted that there is a limit on the maximum deposit the state can make, a number that he did not have at hand.</p>
<p>McCall declined to recommend how much of New York State's whopping surplus, which mainly comes from stunning profits earned by Wall Street's financial industry, should be directed towards debt service.</p>
<p>&quot;I have not put a number on the table, I'm just simply saying that that number ought to be put on the table by the governor in terms of a prudent way to manage our finances over a longer-term.&quot;</p>
<p>The fiscal monitor, a Democrat, who has weighed running for governor, again blasted Pataki for proposing huge new tax cuts, which if added to the ones already approved, would slash state revenues by $8 billion in 1998.</p>
<p>((--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
