<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="41802" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Gulf Arabs in tight spot after U.S. hits on Iraq.</title>
<headline>Gulf Arabs in tight spot after U.S. hits on Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Hilary Gush</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. attacks on Iraq have left Gulf Arab states trying to balance support for their powerful guardian against the desire to preserve the sovereignty of a fellow Arab country, diplomats said on Monday.</p>
<p>The chairman of a two-day meeting of Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC) foreign ministers said Saudi Arabia, Oman, Kuwait, Qatar, Bahrain and United Arab Emirates (UAE) differed with the United States over the strikes and were discussing the issue with Washington.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no disagreements but there are differences in opinion,&quot; Oman's Minister of State for Foreign Affairs Youssef bin Alawi bin Abdullah said after the meeting ended on Sunday.</p>
<p>The meeting made no formal mention of the barrage of 44 U.S. cruise missiles at southern Iraq last week. The chairman said the group felt &quot;there was no need&quot; to mention the attacks in their statement.</p>
<p>Diplomats said this signalled differences within the GCC itself and a fear of souring ties with the country they consider a protector since Baghdad's 1990 invasion of Kuwait.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the differences in opinion must have been so strong that that is why they did not say anything (about the U.S. strikes),&quot; said a diplomat.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact they did not make any comment reflects partly the desire for GCC unity and partly the desire to maintain good relations with the U.S. and other Western allies,&quot; the Western diplomat in Abu Dhabi said.</p>
<p>The United States said the missiles were a response to Iraqi military intervention in northern Iraq to help a Kurdish faction fighting a rival Kurdish group. But much of the Arab world condemned the attacks as infringing Iraq's sovereignty.</p>
<p>Many Gulf states considered the strikes unjustified as Iraq was acting internally and not threatening neighbours, diplomats said, although some states think any potential threaten by Iraqi President Saddam Hussein must be dealt with decisively.</p>
<p>The GCC was part of the U.S.-led coalition that ended Iraq's 1990-91 occupation of Kuwait. Kuwait said it fully understood the U.S. action.</p>
<p>With memories of the Iraqi invasion still vivid, the GCC could not denounce the attacks and harm ties with the United States, which many Gulf States consider the only power capable of defending them from Iraq and non-Arab Iran, diplomats said.</p>
<p>&quot;The statement was very carefully balanced. The GCC will continue to depend on the U.S. for military cooperation. The U.S. is a superpower, they can't oppose the U.S.,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>There are some 20,000 U.S. troops and 300 warplanes deployed in and around the Gulf, with some forces in Saudi Arabia and Kuwait.</p>
<p>But the GCC also does not want Iraq too weak to serve as a regional counterweight to Iran, diplomats said. The group's statement stressed the need to preserve Iraqi independence, sovereignty and territorial unity.</p>
<p>&quot;The Gulf states, especially the UAE, don't want to see the disintegration of Iraq because they need Iraq to counter Iran. They fear Iran,&quot; a Western diplomat in Abu Dhabi said.</p>
<p>Since the Gulf War, some Gulf Arab states have adopted a softer line on Iraq. Kuwait and Saudi Arabia refuse any direct contact with the Iraqi leader, but Qatar and Oman both have resident Iraqi ambassadors.</p>
<p>Last year, UAE President Sheikh Zaid bin Sultan al-Nahayan said the time had come to reconcile with Baghdad, urging United Nations sanctions be lifted to ease the Iraqis' suffering.</p>
<p>One diplomat said the United States was sensitive to GCC opinion and would be relieved by the careful foreign ministers' statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. considers this area a very important market for its military industry, and also obviously wants to ensure the smooth flow of oil. They (the U.S. and the GCC) are mutually dependent on each other,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BAHRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
