<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418179" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Made in France? Shun it, tabloid tells Belgians.</title>
<headline>Made in France? Shun it, tabloid tells Belgians.</headline>
<byline>Nieck Ammerlaan</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A popular Belgian daily on Tuesday called for a selective boycott of products made in France, but the government said no official ban was planned despite outrage over the closure of a Renault car plant near Brussels.</p>
<p>However, the Interior Ministry suspended an order for 150 Renault Megane cars for the Gendarmerie for a year.</p>
<p>Belgians should boycott products made by French companies in France to protest against the closure of the Renault Industrie Belgique assembly plant, the tabloid La Derniere Heure said.</p>
<p>The French car maker said lat week that it would close the Vilvoorde plant in July, costing 3,100 jobs.</p>
<p>The newspaper called for an &quot;intelligent boycott&quot; which would not affect products of French firms creating jobs in Belgium.</p>
<p>Outraged at Renault's decision to close a profitable and efficient plant, it said, &quot;There is only one answer to the financial terrorism of Renault's state shareholder: boycott!&quot;</p>
<p>The French state owns 46 percent of Renault SA.</p>
<p>A national cold-shouldering of Camembert cheese and Bordeaux wines was fine, but consumers should not blindly shun all French output since about 800 French companies represented in Belgium had created thousands of jobs.</p>
<p>The paper named financial services companies Axa and Paribas, brewer Alken-Maes and tyre group Michelin as examples of companies whose goods and services ought not to be boycotted.</p>
<p>Renault dealers in Belgium feared the worst.</p>
<p>&quot;We foresee a fall in the order of 10 percent in sales volumes as a direct consequence of the decision of Renault-France,&quot; Alberic Otten, manager of a Brussels Renault dealer, told the Belgian agency Belga.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene told BBC radio, &quot;(A boycott) is not something we have envisaged at the governmental level, but it is clear that the dossier is so emotional that you cannot exclude that public opinion and the trade unions will organise such a thing.&quot;</p>
<p>The town council of Namur on Tuesday said it decided to take Renault off the list of makers invited to tender for car purchases until the French company met &quot;the legimate demands of Renault workers in Vilvoorde&quot;.</p>
<p>It called on all public institutions and all Belgians to boycott Renault.</p>
<p>Michel de Virville, Renault senior vice-president in charge of personnel and external relations, told BBC radio from the Geneva car show that a boycott would be &quot;harmful for our business, but that's a possibility that we can accept&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We are convinced that Renault, given the appropriate decisions -- and this one is a tough but appropriate decision -- can be really very competitive and once again a very innovative company in car construction,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>France is Belgium's third largest trading partner in the European Union with 1996 exports to Belgium worth an estimated 505 billion Belgian francs ($14 billion).</p>
<p>In Belgium, Renault is a top three make and sold just under 44,000 cars in 1996, after Volkswagen with about 78,500 units and Peugeot with some 57,000. ($ = 35.22 Belgian Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I48110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
