<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418200" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Minister defends Renault, calls for talks.</title>
<headline>Minister defends Renault, calls for talks.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Industry Minister Franck Borotra on Tuesday defended a decision by car group Renault SA to shut a Belgian plant and axe thousands of jobs in France but also called for talks to limit the human impact of the plan.</p>
<p>Facing angry questions and loud protest from parliamentarians -- opposition Communist and Socialist deputies as well as from members of the majority Gaullist party -- Borotra told parliament during question time that Renault needed to cut its cost base in order to survive into the year 2000.</p>
<p>He said he had not been &quot;involved nor consulted&quot; about the decision by the &quot;independent&quot; management of the car group, in which the state still has 46 percent and has representatives on the supervisory board. He urged the group to renew talks with the authorities about the financing of the job reduction plan.</p>
<p>Last Wednesday, the government had decided not to act on a request by both Renault and PSA Peugeot Citroen that it backed a five-year early retirement plan which industry sources said would have led to 40,000 early retirements.</p>
<p>While it was Peugeot chairman Jacques Calvet who had publicly warned that he could not exclude forced lay-offs if the government failed to help, Louis Schweitzer of Renault bit the bullet first.</p>
<p>He announced the closure of the Vilvoorde plant in Belgium as well as 2,764 job losses in France within a week.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Calvet said during the Geneva car show he planned no plant closures but repeated he could not exclude lay-offs.</p>
<p>&quot;Contrary to what has been suggested, the Industry Minister was not involved nor consulted about the decision of the management of Renault,&quot; Borotra said during question time.</p>
<p>He said that at the request of the Prime Minister, he was asking Renault management to renew discussions with the authorities &quot;to put into place the necessary financial means for the industrial restructuring, as well as to find social solutions that limit the consequences of this restructuring.&quot;</p>
<p>But earlier he had told parliament, repeating his explanation a few times and calmly awaiting angry interruptions to fade away, that Renault needed to cut costs to survive.</p>
<p>&quot;If the company does not take measures to cut its costs and thus engage in the necessary restructuring, it will neither in 1997 nor in 1998 be able to return to equilibrium and on January 1, 2000, when we have to open the market to full world competition and in particular Asian countries, it will be too late...,&quot; Borotra said.</p>
<p>Renault is expected to report an operating loss on its car activities of some three billion francs in 1997, after 1.7 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Companies that are not able to face competition are in the end companies that will disappear,&quot; Borotra added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
