<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418211" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: U.S. welcomes possible compromise on NATO command.</title>
<headline>U.S. welcomes possible compromise on NATO command.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Responding to a German initiative, the United States opened the door on Tuesday to the possibility of giving up or sharing the command of southern NATO forces with Europe after a delay of perhaps five years.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a completely open mind,&quot; U.S. Defence Secretary William Cohen told reporters after German Defence Minister Volker Ruehe announced a tentative plan to resolve a U.S.-French row over whether an American officer should remain in charge of the forces based in Naples.</p>
<p>The divisive debate over France's demand to put a European in charge of the strategically important post had jeopardised an earlier by Paris that its military forces would rejoin NATO's military structure after an absence of over 30 years.</p>
<p>Ruehe said during a joint press conference with visiting Cohen that German, French, British, Spanish and Italian officials met on Tuesday to try and develop a European position on France's demand. U.S. sources said the meeting was in Bonn.</p>
<p>The United States had until now flatly refused to surrender the command to a European officer, and Ruehe suggested a face-saving deal for France was emerging in Europe to leave the command in U.S. hands now but reconsider the issue in five or six years, while strengthening European participation in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;When we say we would like to review, or plan to review, the situation in a number of years, we have a completely open mind,&quot; Cohen said following Ruehe's announcement.</p>
<p>&quot;And there are several possible outcomes: number one it (the command) will remain with the United States, number two it could rotate between the Europeans and the United States, and third, it could rotate among the Europeans,&quot; Cohen added.</p>
<p>Cohen said in response to questions that the United States was willing to review the matter in five, six or seven years, but suggested the command might still remain in U.S. hands.</p>
<p>A U.S. officer already commands all NATO forces in Europe from NATO's military headquarters Mons, Belgium, and an American also commands the southern region from Naples. The job of NATO's civilian secretary-general belongs to a European.</p>
<p>France has demanded that Europe play a more active role in NATO leadership in the post-Cold War world, but Washington has insisted that an American should remain at the helm in Naples because a preponderance of southern NATO forces are American.</p>
<p>NATO forces in the southern region include the powerful U.S. Sixth Fleet in the Mediterranean.</p>
<p>But Cohen stressed at the news conference that the United States was anxious for France to rejoin the military alliance and was willing to compromise.</p>
<p>&quot;We have developed a position which is already now being shared by the Italians and the Spanish, which after all belong to the south of Europe, and also by the British,&quot; Ruehe said.</p>
<p>He said the matter was still being discussed with the French and did not indicate what their position was.</p>
<p>Referring to the delay of five or six years, Ruehe said that &quot;from our point of view, this would be time to review the status quo. And in the meantime, we would try to strengthen the European participation in the command in the south, including the deputy (commander). And other measures that could be taken.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
