<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418251" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian bonds/futures.</title>
<headline>Italian bonds/futures.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian bond futures slid in late trading on Tuesday to close lower after investors took fright at remarks by Bundesbank council member Helmut Hesse who said a delay in the launch of EMU would force renegotiation of the Maastricht Treaty.</p>
<p>A statement by Italian opposition leader Silvio Berlusconi just before markets closed that he saw little chance of reaching agreement with the government on financial measures to help Italy into the single European currency also jangled nerves.</p>
<p>&quot;The reaction to Hesse's comments seemed a bit excessive but there is a lot of nervousness in the markets at the moment,&quot; said a London-based futures trader.  </p>
<p>Market watchers said support levels had little significance in view of the market's extreme volatility.</p>
<p>Another Bundesbank council member, Guntram Palm, said later that European monetary union would be likely to begin on schedule in 1999 with a large group of nations includsing Germany.</p>
<p>But his comments came to late to reassure the market. Palm said a postponement of EMU would cause more problems than it would solve.</p>
<p>Traders said the outlook for BTPs would be determined as much in Bonn and Frankfurt as in Rome.</p>
<p>Fears of a delay in the whole EMU process -- which would have unpredictable consequences for Italy's efforts to lick its state finances into shape -- have weighed heavily on Italian bond prices in recent days.</p>
<p>Milan newsroom +392-66102321</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
