<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418391" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: IMF mission due for crucial talks with Pakistan.</title>
<headline>IMF mission due for crucial talks with Pakistan.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Lyon</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>An IMF mission arrives in Islamabad on Wednesday at a time of concerns about Pakistan's ability to service its foreign debt later this year.</p>
<p>A source in the finance ministry said the International Monetary Fund team would stay until March 21 to complete a review of Pakistan's economic performance.</p>
<p>If satisfied, the IMF will release the next $122 million tranche of a standby loan in what would be an important signal to international investors that Pakistan's new government, led by Nawaz Sharif, is keeping in step with the IMF.</p>
<p>Bankers say Pakistan, with liquid reserves of just over $1 billion, faces debt payments of some $600 million in March, $250 million in each of April and May, and $500 million in June.</p>
<p>&quot;They have a very difficult foreign exchange situation,&quot; said one foreign banker, who asked not to be named. &quot;But the immediate danger of default doesn't loom that large.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Pakistan could not borrow its way out of trouble indefinitely. &quot;How long can you go on doing this unless the trade account and the current account turn around?&quot; he asked.</p>
<p>Sharif, elected in a landslide victory on February 3, has pledged to revive industry and stimulate export-led growth to get Pakistan out of its economic mess, but has yet to unveil policy details.</p>
<p>Some analysts have concluded that Sharif's priorities may be fatally at odds with the deficit-cutting goals of the IMF.</p>
<p>A report by Credit Lyonnais Securities Asia said last week default was a &quot;90 percent probability&quot; and criticised what it perceived as the government's populist strategy.</p>
<p>&quot;Revitalising domestic industry and the export sector through tax cuts and monetary expansion, which will lower interest rates, may well be the preferred choice for politicians who desire popularity more than a solution to their country's ills, but it is impractical in the extreme,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Such a strategy can lead to only one course of action -- an open and defiant default on Pakistan's external debts.&quot;</p>
<p>This week, a research report by brokerage house ING Barings said Pakistan may have averted an immediate foreign exchange crunch, but could fail to meet its debt payments in the second half of 1997 if it forfeited IMF support.</p>
<p>The report said Pakistan faced a &quot;very high probability of default&quot; in the second half. It needed about $3 billion to meet external obligations in July-December, which it was unlikely to be able to raise without the IMF's full backing.</p>
<p>ING Barings said Pakistan could meet its external payments until June. &quot;But we are concerned about the payments that fall due between July and December 1997,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>However, Ayesha Muzaffar, a senior analyst at James Capel Asia, said Pakistan had been staring at a possible default for the past year, but the danger was receding -- thanks in part to Sharif's appeal to Pakistanis to contribute funds in the form of donations or two-year deposits to help retire debt.</p>
<p>&quot;In the short term, they will be getting money out of the debt retirement scheme and replacing short-term debt with long-term debt,&quot; she said. &quot;But after June, an ESAF (enhanced structural adjustment facility) will be very important.&quot;</p>
<p>Pakistan wants to negotiate an ESAF with the IMF to gain access to cheaper funds than are available under the standby arrangement, which expires in September.</p>
<p>Despite doubts about whether an elected government would honour targets agreed by its predecessors, the IMF resumed the standby loan in December after a caretaker government promised to cut the budget deficit to four percent of gross domestic product in 1996/97 (July-June) from 6.3 percent in 1995/96.</p>
<p>The deficit target is likely to be the focus of the IMF mission's talks, given widespread reports that revenue collection has fallen seriously behind schedule.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
