<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418357" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Afghan commission hears French prisoner's case.</title>
<headline>Afghan commission hears French prisoner's case.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A commission of Afghanistan's Supreme Court on Tuesday discussed the case of two detained French aid workers and asked for a report about their condition, the state Kabul radio said.</p>
<p>The broadcast, monitored in Islamabad, said the commission heard a report from an interrogating officer and then ordered an inspection of the prisoners, Jose Daniel Llorente and Frederic Michel, by a special representative.</p>
<p>The two Frenchmen, who work for the private Paris-based charity Action Contre la Faim (ACF - Action Against Hunger), were detained late last month by the Taleban Islamic movement along with five Afghan staffers.</p>
<p>Taleban officials say the detainees are under investigation for &quot;immoral deeds&quot; in connection with a lunch given by ACF's women expatriate staff for Afghan women working for the group.</p>
<p>The Taleban say the men were at the party in the presence of unveiled Afghan women, an accusation ACF witnesses deny.</p>
<p>The French detainees told Reuters in an interview inside their jail cell on Thursday that they were in good health and not maltreated.</p>
<p>The Taleban, who captured Kabul in September and now control more than two-thirds of Afghanistan, have vowed to implement strict Islamic Sharia law, which they say forbids unveiled women from appearing before men outside the family.</p>
<p>In another related development, Kabul radio on Tuesday announced orders by the Taleban authorities to government employees telling them not to grow their hair long.</p>
<p>It also quoted orders forbidding Afghan and foreign visitors from bringing alcoholic drinks as well as audio and video cassettes into the country and from taking such cassettes out of Afghanistan.</p>
<p>It was not clear whether the ban on cassettes would also apply to journalists and cameramen working for foreign news organisations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
