<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418446" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: INDIAN HEADLINE STOCKS - factors to watch - March 4.</title>
<headline>INDIAN HEADLINE STOCKS - factors to watch - March 4.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main factors affecting Indian stock markets on Tuesday morning:</p>
<p>NEWS OUTLOOK:</p>
<p>**  A blue-ribbon panel on Monday recommended sweeping changes in laws governing Indian firms, saying some of them were &quot;antiquated&quot;. It also suggested that Indian companies move towards issuing a range of new financial instruments, and laid down guidelines that would let firms buy back their own shares.</p>
<p>	  The panel's report recommended that foreign companies be</p>
<p>allowed to issue Indian depositary receipts (GDRs) on the lines of European global depositary receipts (GDRs) where the underlying security is the equity or any other security of the foreign company.</p>
<p>	  It suggested that domestic companies should be allowed</p>
<p>to issue derivatives, options and quasi-equity instruments.</p>
<p>	  The group said it favoured allowing companies to buy</p>
<p>back their own shares subject to certain conditions.</p>
<p>**  Global investment bank Lehman Brothers said on Monday it expects India to achieve annual economic growth of seven percent and foresees the evolution of the country's debt market.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we are talking about something in the seven percent range which is a bit less than what I have heard from some others,&quot; C. Daniel Tyree, chairman of Lehman Brothers Asia, told Reuters television when asked for his forecast for India's 1997/98 (April-March) fiscal year.</p>
<p>**  Attractive new tax provisions in India's 1997/98 budget will fuel primary market activity and cause interest rates to drop, Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) president Madan Gopal Damani said.</p>
<p>	  &quot;There has been a sea change in the minds of the</p>
<p>people,&quot; Damani told a news conference. &quot;This is clearly shown in the number of trades pouring in after the post-budget session.&quot;</p>
<p>	  India's broking community responded enthusiastically to</p>
<p>the provisions of the budget, with the 30-share BSE index climbing to 4007.91 on Monday, before falling back to close with a small gain.</p>
<p>	  Damani said he expected the index to climb to 5,000</p>
<p>points by October, in time for Diwali, the Hindu festival of lights.</p>
<p>**  Indian share prices rocketed on Monday, with the BSE's top 30-share index reaching an eight-month high on favourable reaction to the government's pro-growth, pro-investment budget.</p>
<p>	  The index later fell on profit-taking but setbacks were</p>
<p>likely to be temporary, dealers said.</p>
<p>	  The breadth and focus of Finance Minister P.</p>
<p>Chidambaram's budget, handed down last Friday, boosted confidence in India and sent investors on a buying spree, traders said.</p>
<p>**  The 30-share index of the BSE closed with a net gain of 13.56 points, or 0.35 percent at 3,871.05, off 4,007.91-the intra-day high.</p>
<p>MARKETS:</p>
<p>**  The 50-stock National Stock Exchange index was up 0.43 percent, to 1,107.70.</p>
<p>**  The Delhi share index  rose 11.90 points to 823.73.</p>
<p>**  The Calcutta share index gained 2.65 points to 471.59.</p>
<p>**  The Madras share index jumped 108.07 points to 3,706.71.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
