<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418636" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico's &quot;Tiger&quot; Azcarraga calls it quits.</title>
<headline>Mexico's &quot;Tiger&quot; Azcarraga calls it quits.</headline>
<byline>David Luhnow</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY</dateline>
<text>
<p>In two decades at the helm of Mexico's Grupo Televisa SA, Emilio &quot;The Tiger&quot; Azcarraga led the company on a global march, making it the Spanish-speaking world's largest media firm.</p>
<p>Azcarraga, 66, who retired on Monday from the company his father helped found, was a hard-nosed dealmaker who knew what audiences wanted to see, a knack that earned him billions of dollars and made him one of Latin America's richest men.</p>
<p>Azcarraga's critics say the media magnate oversaw a company whose insipid programming and pro-government news kept many Mexicans blissfully unaware of their country's troubles and glorified the decades-long rule of the Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI).</p>
<p>Whatever his politics, there was no doubting his business acumen.</p>
<p>Although Televisa already dominated Mexico's media landscape when Azcarraga took over from his father, Emilio Azcarraga Vidaurrieta, in 1972, the company expanded its domain to eventually include four nationwide television networks, dozens of radio stations and magazines, music recording, cable television, several soccer teams and more.</p>
<p>Televisa has become one of the world's largest producers of programming, making what has become its staple export to the world: Latin soap operas.</p>
<p>The soaps, with titles like &quot;The Rich Also Cry,&quot; do not often have much to do with the average Mexican. Acknowledging this, Azcarraga has defended the programmes as a means of escape for poor Mexicans.</p>
<p>Social realism they are not. Televisa's soap operas eschew violence, corruption and sex, and even poor characters are usually played by light-skinned actresses.</p>
<p>The bulky billionaire did little to hide the cosy relationship his media company enjoyed with the government, which grants media licenses.</p>
<p>During a fund-raising banquet by former President Carlos Salinas in 1993, Azcarraga reportedly offered $50 million to help the PRI's re-election efforts.</p>
<p>Azcarraga did allow greater independence at Televisa in the last few years, giving wider coverage to opposition candidates and exposing some cases of government corruption.</p>
<p>Although he is seen as brash, Azcarraga shuns the public spotlight. He is famous for never having granted an interview since becoming head of Televisa.</p>
<p>There are even different theories as to why he is called &quot;The Tiger.&quot; Some say it is a reflection of his business instinct, while others say it came from a grey flash that crowned his otherwise black head of hair.</p>
<p>A more likely explanation may be that his father, Emilio Azcarraga Vidaurrieta, was known as &quot;The Lion.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
