<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418699" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Zinc to break above $1,550 by early 1998-Waterside.</title>
<headline>Zinc to break above $1,550 by early 1998-Waterside.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three months LME zinc is expected to surpass a medium-term target of $1,550 by early 1998, Waterside Futures said in its latest report.</p>
<p>An interim objective is $1,325, the report, which uses Elliott Wave analysis, added.</p>
<p>&quot;The complex nature of advances that began from $960 in 1995 suggests the final route towards $1,325 will be composed of several movements of new highs then declines,&quot; the Wavetrack report said.</p>
<p>In the shorter term, after prices attain a target of $1,279, they will retrace 38.2 percent to $1,173, it added.</p>
<p>&quot;Watch this to set the trading range for sideways activity for a little longer,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>In nickel, long-term patterns suggest a bull market that will take prices to $13,000.</p>
<p>&quot;The explosive nature of the rally from the December low is certainly the kind of activity that we expect to see at the beginning of a nickel bull market and patterns are unfolding impulsively,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;The recent hesitation at the $8,000-$8,200 area is no cause for concern yet and the market is likely to accelerate upwards immediately. No significant resistance is seen until $9,030,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>The market should then drop to a strong support level of $7,630 with the bull market resuming afterwards.</p>
<p>Copper will find short-term critical resistance at $2,416/17, which represents the next leg of the move that began at $1,745 in June 1996 and hit $2,160 less than three months later.</p>
<p>The current target is 61.8 percent of the initial $415 rise added to the previous top of $2,160.</p>
<p>Over the next several weeks, the market is expected to slide back towards $2,160 before eventually heading up to a longer term target of $2,830/50.</p>
<p>In aluminium, an interim move should conclude a five-wave pattern at around $2,228 by the end of the year.</p>
<p>The first wave concluded a move from last year's low around $1,300 up to $1,651 in January 1997, with the next movement a shallow retracement to $1,534. &quot;That action suggests a third phase of price advances is now underway. It is usually much larger than the first, hence targets towards $2,095,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>--Eric Onstad, London Newsroom +44 171 542-8065</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
