<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418634" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PJM sees power transmission price plan this week.</title>
<headline>PJM sees power transmission price plan this week.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Pennsylvania-New Jersey-Maryland (PJM) Interconnect pool said Monday it expects to have a plan later this week for implementing a fair method for assessing what its members can charge for use of their transmission lines.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope to come up with something in the next couple of days,&quot; said PJM spokesman Bruce Balmat.  </p>
<p>Friday, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) responded to a PJM request to evaluate two rival plans for calculating what it calls &quot;congestion&quot; tariffs, which would take effect when PJM opens up its transmission system to wholesale and eventually retail competition.</p>
<p>Transmission congestion in PJM could occur during periods of high energy demand and when a major high-voltage or generating station trips off line.  </p>
<p>One plan is sponsored by the Supporting Companies Group which is comprised of all PJM utility members except PECO Energy Co and calls for users to pay for congestion fees on particular transmission paths they move energy on.</p>
<p>The other plan, proposed by PECO, argues those charges should be paid for by all PJM pool users through a single fee.</p>
<p>&quot;We're neutral to each of the plan,&quot; Balmat said,</p>
<p>FERC said it supports the implementation of PECO's plan as a temporary measure, which became effective March 1, until the Supporting Companies Group on unresolved technical issues to make its plan workable.  </p>
<p>&quot;We believe that, ultimately, (PJM's) Supporting Companies Group's proposal will promote more efficient trading and will be more compatible with the type of competitive market mechanisms we are encouraging,&quot; FERC said in its order Friday.</p>
<p>In 1995, FERC called for utilities to devise plans to allow equal access on their transmission systems to other electricity suppliers including marketers and independent power producers.</p>
<p>The policy aimed to further the goal of more competition and lower rates in the domestic electricity industry.  </p>
<p>FERC said it intended to convene a technical conference  to faciliate in resolving issues in the tariff plan submitted by the Supporting Companies Group.</p>
<p>&quot;We're anxious to go ahead with FERC's decision. It's basically getting the information to the operators,&quot; Balmat said.</p>
<p>FERC ruling Friday on the PJM filing is part of a larger response to 11 other proposals on transmission tariffs in other networks around the country.</p>
<p>((--New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
