<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418766" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dog owners compete to show the perfect best friend.</title>
<headline>Dog owners compete to show the perfect best friend.</headline>
<byline>Paul Carrel</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of dogs and their owners will compete this week for the title of &quot;best at show&quot; at Crufts, the self-proclaimed &quot;greatest dog show in the world&quot;.</p>
<p>More than 15,000 exhibitors and 100,000 visitors will gather at Britain's National Exhibition Centre on Thursday for the start of the four-day event.</p>
<p>To a dog-owner, winning Crufts is the ultimate accolade.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a dream come true,&quot; said Patricia Bentley who last year won with her three-year old Cocker Spaniel, Albert.</p>
<p>&quot;I was delighted, it's something you only do once in a lifetime,&quot; she told Reuters. &quot;It is the most prestigious dog show in the world and to win is every exhibitor's dream.&quot;</p>
<p>Crufts is the World Cup, or Wimbledon championship, of the dog world, according to Brian Leonard, external affairs executive of the Kennel Club, which organises the show.</p>
<p>&quot;It's synonymous with quality. Whenever you get a cat show, or a parrot or pigeon show, it's always billed as the Crufts of the pigeon world' or whatever,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The competing dogs are divided into six groups: hounds, gun-dogs, terriers, utility (large companion dogs such as poodles and Dalmatians), working, and toys (such as Chihuahuas). The judges decide on a winner in each group and those six dogs go forward to compete for &quot;best of show&quot;. The winner receives the Keddell Memorial Trophy, a huge silver cup named after Robert Keddell, the show's manager from 1894 to 1924.</p>
<p>The competing dogs are whittled down by expert judges who look at their physique, temperament and handling until the best shines out.</p>
<p>The winning dog is easy to spot in the final contest, said Leonard.</p>
<p>&quot;You can tell the winning dog by the reaction of the crowd when the handler walks it into the ring. They just sit back and there is this &quot;aaah&quot; around the ring,&quot; he explained.</p>
<p>Crufts is a very British affair. Although the show boasts worldwide media coverage, British quarantine laws make it difficult for foreign dog-owners to enter their thoroughbreds.</p>
<p>Some British dog owners have become a little too eager to win at shows.</p>
<p>At a recent Northern Counties show one exhibitor secretly administered a sedative to a competitor's Chihuahua. At an Open Retriever stake held at Sandringham, the Queen's country home, another exhibitor was alleged to have mistreated her labrador.</p>
<p>Such behaviour was &quot;totally unacceptable&quot;, said Leonard, adding that the Kennel Club uses its disciplinary powers to ban any owners who resort to skulduggery, mistreat their dogs, or behave disrespectfully towards judges.</p>
<p>&quot;The dog has to be enjoying itself or else it will not show well,&quot; he said. &quot;The handler too has to be very relaxed. Any nerves will be transferred down the lead. It's a very close relationship.&quot;</p>
<p>So, after the recent success in cloning a sheep in Scotland, would the Kennel Club want to clone a Crufts winner?</p>
<p>&quot;No,&quot; said Leonard. &quot;What we're trying to do is breed better dogs and not to simply reproduce what we have already achieved.&quot;</p>
<p>What about cloning a winning Crufts handler?</p>
<p>&quot;Hopefully we're improving them all the time too by better training. But a certain amount of it comes from breeding,&quot; Leonard said with a laugh.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
