<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418874" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New Hampshire electricity deregulation stalled.</title>
<headline>New Hampshire electricity deregulation stalled.</headline>
<dateline>CONCORD, N.H. 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Public Service of New Hampshire stalled implementation of the state's electric deregulation plan by filing suit on Monday March 3 in federal district court to block a February 28 Public Utilities Commission order restructuring the utility.</p>
<p>Public Service of New Hampshire, whose parent company is Northeast Utilities of Connecticut, is the state's largest electric utility with 400,600 customers. PSNH is joined in the suit by three subsidiaries - Public Service Co of New Hampshire, North Atlantic Energy Corp and Northeast Utilities Service Co.  </p>
<p>On February 28, the PUC ordered Public Service of New Hampshire to divest its generating assets, swallow 40 percent of its past capital investments and lower prices 19 percent in 1998.</p>
<p>The order's stranded recovery estimates would force the utility to write off over $400 million worth of assets, the company said. The order would result in violation of some loan agreements and demand immediate repayment of more than $1 billion in debt, said PSNH spokesman Martin Murray.  </p>
<p>The PUC order could force PSNH into default of their loans and &quot;possibly&quot; to seek Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection, Murray said.</p>
<p>PSNH attorneys filed suit late on Monday to temporarily restrain implementation of the PUC order. The company also plans to file a lawsuit to in New Hampshire Superior Court to seek recovery of damages resulting from the order, company officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite all these necessary legal steps to protect investors of our companies, our customers and shareholders, I still believe a fair and equitable solution to these problems can be found,&quot; said Bernard M. Fox, NU chairman, president and chief executive officer in a released statement.</p>
<p>New Hampshire Gov. Jeanne Shaheen said negotiations between the state and PSNH to avoid the lawsuit broke down on Sunday. Shaheen said the state is prepared to wage a long legal battle with PSNH to enforce the PUC restructuring order, but she voiced optimism a fight can be avoided.</p>
<p>((--Boston bureau, 617-367-4106))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CONCORD, N.H."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
