<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418971" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Troubled Albania faces economic abyss - analysts.</title>
<headline>Troubled Albania faces economic abyss - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Knut Engelmann</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania, swept by violent unrest after the collapse of a series of fraudulent investment funds, is facing the economic abyss and it could take years for the impoverished country to recover, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The immediate consequences could be very dire. In the short-term, it could be complete chaos,&quot; Vladimir Gligorov, Albania expert at the Vienna Institute for Comparative Studies, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Albanian government introduced emergency rule on Monday in an effort to quell the violence that has swept Europe's poorest country. The unrest was sparked when five pyramid schemes, which relied on new investors to pay sky-high interest rates due on old deposits, collapsed last month.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of Albanians, many of whom had sold their homes to raise money in the final frenzy, were left out of pocket.</p>
<p>The schemes began to flourish after the country emerged from almost half a century of Stalinist isolation in 1991, boosted by the inflow of millions of dollars in remittances from Albanians living abroad illegally.</p>
<p>Analysts say naivety about market economis and lack of trust in the country's shaky banking system were also to blame.</p>
<p>&quot;Albania has had four very good years. Now there is this backlash. There has been mismanagement by the government, no doubt about it. But there are also local interests which have had a huge influence in stirring the pot,&quot; said a London-based international banker.</p>
<p>In the early 1990s, Albania was the darling of the world's financial bodies. Growth rates of more than ten percent a year, stable inflation and President Sali Berisha's free-market government impressed bankers and lured in foreign investors.</p>
<p>But analysts say that growth was almost completely confined to small-scale agriculture and low-value consumer products, while the country's obsolete industry died a slow death.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody was fooled,&quot; said Gligorov. &quot;Industry almost completely collapsed -- of course you can have infinite growth rates in such a situation. This actually should have warned people that something was wrong.&quot;</p>
<p>The local currency, the lek, is falling, while both inflation and unemployment in this country of 3.4 million are rising. The average monthly wage is little more than $65, and many farmers in Albania's rugged countryside eke out a living barely above poverty level.</p>
<p>&quot;Just looking at the figures right up to the crisis, it looks like a big disaster. The only thing that was coming in was money from abroad and smuggling,&quot; said Gligorov. &quot;This was a completely mismanaged country both from the inside and by the international community.&quot;</p>
<p>Foreign investment, estimated at a total of $250 million between 1992 and 1996, was largely confined to the construction and tourism industries.</p>
<p>&quot;This will simply dry out now. People are not even going to look at this country,&quot; Gligorov said. &quot;Now it's a country on the verge of civil war. It doesn't get any worse than that. You don't get in, you get out.&quot;</p>
<p>Italy, Greece and Austria were among the biggest investors, attracted mainly by a cheap labour force. One of the country's two-western style hotels in the capital Tirana was financed by an Austrian.</p>
<p>&quot;This crisis is doing immense damage to the entire country. For the second time in this decade, they're starting from below zero,&quot; said Horst Machu of the Austrian chamber of commerce.</p>
<p>The key question for foreign investors would now be whether a long-planned visit by an International Monetary Fund mission could go ahead and whether the organisation managed to strike a deal with the Albanian government, bankers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a complete disaster. It's put Albania back on the starting block. All the effort and goodwill has to start again from scratch,&quot; the London-based source said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
