<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="418917" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX ACCESS energy prices narrowly mixed Monday.</title>
<headline>NYMEX ACCESS energy prices narrowly mixed Monday.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX ACCESS energy futures were narrowly mixed in overnight Monday trade, with little fundamental news to direct the market, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's pretty dead and featureless,&quot; one ACCESS broker said, noting volume was extremely light in petroleum products futures.</p>
<p>At 1930 PST, heating oil futures for April traded down 0.03 cents a gallon from the daytime close of 53.18 cents.</p>
<p>Traders expected a stronger IPE market in London to give heating oil a slight lift later on ACCESS, traders said.</p>
<p>But at 1930 PST, the contract traded a razor-thin 37 lots for April, traders said. NYMEX gasoline on ACCESS traded up 0.17 cents to 61.94, with a mere six lots exchanged overnight.</p>
<p>&quot;People are waiting for (American Petroleum Institute) data tomorrow,&quot; a broker said, explaining the light activity.</p>
<p>Despite crude's late recovery in daytime markets, ACCESS traders saw the contract continuiing to weaken Tuesday, with support around $20 a barrel.</p>
<p>On ACCESS, crude drifted up two cents to $20.27 a barrel, with trade light at 188 lots in the front-month.</p>
<p>((David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles bureau +1 213 380 2014))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
