<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="419188" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: HUNTER DOUGLAS EYES ASIAN EXPANSION.</title>
<headline>HUNTER DOUGLAS EYES ASIAN EXPANSION.</headline>
<dateline>ROTTERDAM 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Window blinds maker Hunter Douglas said on Tuesday emerging markets of Asia and eastern Europe offered the best opportunities for further expansion as economic stagnation in western Europe was pressuring margins.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect Asia to contribute significantly to the group's (operating) results over the coming years,&quot; president and chief executive officer Ralph Sonnenberg told journalists.</p>
<p>He said the firm had started operations in Asia relatively late but was now heavily expanding production facilities there.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to play a leading part in all of our markets and geographically, we aim to reach a worldwide coverage based upon the buying purchase (of the population),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday, Hunter Douglas posted a 1996 net profit of 158.3 million guilders, up from 125.6 million in 1995.</p>
<p>For Hunter Douglas, he said the margins achievable in the region were one of the attractive features in operating in Asia, which generated an unchanged seven percent of turnover in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;In Asia, we have been mainly active in the construction sector, where margins are generally less than those on window coverings. Yet our margins in Asia are good as we offer rather unique products,&quot; Sonnenberg said.</p>
<p>He said the group continued to look for acquisitions, notably among smaller and middle sized companies, in order to complete its product line and distribution network.</p>
<p>Europe still accounted for the bulk of turnover (42 percent), closely followed by North America (39 percent). Australia and Latin America each generated six percent of the group's 2.23 billion guilder turnover in 1996.</p>
<p>As business in most western European markets was stagnating, the company was looking to eastern Europe for further expansion and build on its current 192 licence holders there.</p>
<p>But Sonnenberg said the company had instigated an action plan in Europe, which notably concerned its Dutch operations.</p>
<p>&quot;We will strenghten the management team, notably in the field of logistics. With the growing number of products carried, it has become increasingly difficult to control the logistic process,&quot; he said, adding there were also specific plans to cut costs at the group's Dutch, German and French operations.</p>
<p>Lower aluminium prices had a negative impact of some eight to ten million guilders on operational results, vice president Leen Reijtenbagh said, although this had been partially offset by a stronger dollar.</p>
<p>The dividend rose to 2.50 guilders from 2.25 in 1995.</p>
<p>Sonnenberg said the increased dividend reflected the group's current healthy state, as well as its optimism over developments in 1997 and thereafter.</p>
<p>He said Hunter Douglas targeted a reduction in its total debt to equity ratio to 1:1.</p>
<p>The group also proposed to split its common and preferred stock on a two to one basis to increase share liquidity.</p>
<p>From now, Hunter Douglas will report full earnings figures four times a year, instead of two.</p>
<p>Hunter Douglas shares were up 8.00 guilders at 154.00 by mid-afternoon on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Christine Lucassen, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROTTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
