<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="419210" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS - MARCH 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS - MARCH 4.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek financial press:</p>
<p>KATHIMERINI</p>
<p>--'Black Monday' on the Athens Stock Exchange as prices fell dramatically for the third session in a row. The general price index fell a record 7.45 percent, with thousands of orders to sell left unsatisied at the close of trading.</p>
<p>--Inflation will drop to 6.6 percent in February from 6.8 percent the previous month, sources at the national economy ministry said, adding that the positive development will contribute to the further fall in interest rates.</p>
<p>--The reduction of the working week along with a reduction in pay as a topic for discussion with unions and employers brought a strong reaction from the General Confederation of Workers of Greece (GSEE), which said their demand for a 35-hour working week - with no reduction in pay - still stood.</p>
<p>IMERISIA</p>
<p>--Panic selling seized the market for the third time yesterday with 94 share prices falling to the lowest limit. Governor of the National Bank of Greece Theodoros Karatzas met with 10 brokers to ask them to help defuse the situation.</p>
<p>--Wage-earners and pensioners will have the deadline for tax declarations extended to March 28, according to the latest government decision. Retailers and self-employed professionals must submit their forms between March 13-26.</p>
<p>--The rise in the mark yesterday put pressure on Mediterranean countries: the lira, peseta and escudo lost ground against the mark as the drachma slid against mark and Ecu, which led to a rise in the dollar against the drachma.</p>
<p>KERDOS</p>
<p>--The National Bank's Karatzas intervened yesterday in an attempt to restore calm on the market, conferring with ASE members on how to bring confidence back and lay the ground for a stable upward course.</p>
<p>--The National Bank Group's attempts towards the close of the session to restore confidence by buying its own and OTE's shares was limited in scope and not supported by other Groups and private investors.</p>
<p>--The environment, town planning and public works ministry has expressed concern that almost 100 technical firms are facing closure, due to the slump in activity.</p>
<p>EXPRESS</p>
<p>--The final form of Greek telecoms organisation OTE's second share float is being decided by the government. Latest reports say the recent developments on the bourse may mean a smaller package being offered.</p>
<p>NAFTEMBORIKI</p>
<p>--The government is pushing ahead with a previously-agreed trading hours framework despite objections from large department store and supermarket groups. --Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
