<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="419281" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: U.S. planned special plane for Iran rescue-Jane's.</title>
<headline>U.S. planned special plane for Iran rescue-Jane's.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States Air Force planned to use a specially modified transport plane to rescue hostages held in Iran in 1980, an influential defence publication said on Monday.</p>
<p>Jane's Defence Weekly said a Hercules transport aircraft was modified to land in an area less than the size of a soccer pitch and take off with the 53 hostages -- a total payload of 14 tonnes -- in just 50 metres (165 ft).</p>
<p>The magazine said it had obtained video footage of the prototype aircraft that was intended to be used after the first attempt to rescue the hostages from the U.S. embassy in Tehran in April 1980 went disastrously wrong.</p>
<p>The initial rescue attempt by the crack Delta Force ended in fiery disaster when a helicopter collided with a tanker aircraft on the ground in the Iranian desert. Eight Americans died and their bodies were left in the flaming wreckage.</p>
<p>Jane's said the second rescue programme, named &quot;Credible Sport&quot;, was then developed by Hercules manufacturer Lockheed at a cost of about $30 million.</p>
<p>The magazine's aviation editor Nick Cook said a normal C-130 Hercules, the transport workhorse of many Western air forces, was modified by fitting four anti-submarine rockets around the cockpit which were intended to bring the aircraft to a rapid halt.</p>
<p>But video footage of the aircraft being tested in October 1980 showed the rockets fired too soon.</p>
<p>&quot;The aircraft ploughed into the runway, ripping its right wing off. The crew miraculously avoided serious injury,&quot; Jane's said.</p>
<p>The U.S. hostages were eventually released in January 1981 after 444 days in captivity.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
