<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="419309" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-RESEARCH ALERT-QMC rated a &quot;buy&quot;.</title>
<headline>RTRS-RESEARCH ALERT-QMC rated a &quot;buy&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brisbane-based stockbroker Wilson HTM Ltd recommended Queensland Metals Corp Ltd (QMC) as a buy, reflecting potential growth in magnesium metal demand together with the group's patent technology advantages.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on the potential growth in magnesium metal demand and QMC's proprietary process technology, we rate QMC a buy,&quot; Wilson's director of resources research, Phil Hutchings said.</p>
<p>He said the upside in QMC came from the group's own Magmetal process which was forecast to produce magnesium metal at a world-competitive price.  </p>
<p>The basis of forecast high growth in magnesium metal demand came from the automotive industry with current world production of around 250,000 tonnes expected to grow to about 600,000 tonnes by 2004, Hutchings said.</p>
<p>&quot;The upside for QMC relates to environmental pressure to aggressively reduce vehicle weight for efficiency purposes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>This was combined with potential demand growth from higher vehicle ownership in emerging economies, he said.  </p>
<p>Construction of QMC's Magmetal demonstration plant is forecast to cost A$73 million and scheduled to start in May this year.</p>
<p>The Ford Motor Co has contributed an offtake agreement for 50 percent (45,000 tonnes a year) of proposed Magmetal production.</p>
<p>Hutchings said a full-scale commercial plant producing 90,000 tonnes annually is estimated to cost A$700 million with a 2-1/2 year construction period and scheduled for first production in 2002.  </p>
<p>QMC's share price at the time of Hutchings' report was prepared last Friday) was A$1.23.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, it closed at the same price, down five cents on Monday's close.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
