<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="419482" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China's Lu Thai Textile to issue B shares in H1.</title>
<headline>China's Lu Thai Textile to issue B shares in H1.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's Lu Thai Textile Co Ltd expects to issue 80-100 million foreign currency B shares in the first half of this year, company officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The B share issue will be launched in the first half,&quot; a company spokesman said by telephone from headquarters in Zibo city, eastern Shandong province.</p>
<p>&quot;The offer could be completed by end-April if good progress is made,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But the exact amount of B shares to be issued would have to be approved by the China Securities Regulatory Commission, he said.</p>
<p>Lu Thai Textile aims to raise 160-200 million yuan ($19-$24 million) through the initial public offer, he said. The shares would be listed on the Shenzhen Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The China Southern Securities Co has been named as the main domestic underwriter but an international coordinator had yet to be found, the official said.</p>
<p>The firm is among the 33 domestic companies approved to list B shares by the Securities Commission of the State Council.  </p>
<p>Funds raised would be used for production expansion, he said. The company aims to boost annual production capacity to 30,000 spindles and 20 million metres of yarn-dyed fabric, he said.</p>
<p>Lu Thai Textile Co is a joint venture between the Zibo No.7 Textile Factory and Thai Rung Textile Co of Thailand, a second company official said.</p>
<p>The company's gross output value reached 220 million yuan in 1996, up from 150 million yuan in 1995, she said.</p>
<p>It made 19.14 million yuan in post-tax profits in 1995, up from 17.66 million yuan in 1994, she said. The official did not provide profit figures for 1996.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
