<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="419554" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Cominco sees LME zinc price heading higher.</title>
<headline>Cominco sees LME zinc price heading higher.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zinc prices are likely to extend their current surging rally, particularly in the second half of this year when supplies become tight, a senior official at Canadian miner Cominco Ltd said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We do see a trend higher. I could see another US$100 getting added to the price from the current level without a lot of difficulty,&quot; Colin Blyth, managing director of Asia Pacific Cominco Metals pte Ltd, told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Zinc prices surged to a 4-1/2 year high on the London Metal Exchange on Monday and were indicated at a peak of $1,240/242 a tonne before closing $21 up on the day at $1,239.  </p>
<p>Blyth said a decline in stocks and rising consumption will fuel further gains in zinc prices.</p>
<p>Cominco expects zinc demand to outstrip supply by around 210,000 tonnes in 1997, while year-end stocks may slide to around 660,000 tonnes from 880,000 tonnes by the end of 1996.</p>
<p>He declined, however, to predict what price level the metal could reach.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there is a very good chance for a price increase further from today's level in the second half,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Blyth added that the thought zinc could consolidate at current levels for the time being.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think what you'll go through right now is a period of consolidation. There's no huge increase of physical demand right now,&quot; Blyth said.</p>
<p>-- Rene Pastor, Singapore Newsroom (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
