<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="419617" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Sony to launch PlayStation in Asia in mid-March.</title>
<headline>Sony to launch PlayStation in Asia in mid-March.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sony Corp's game unit Sony Computer Entertainment Inc said on Tuesday that it would launch its 32 bit PlayStation videogame machine in Asian markets outside Japan in the middle of March.</p>
<p>The game console will retail for 2,580 Hong Kong dollars ($333), the unit said in a statement.  </p>
<p>A Sony Computer Entertainment spokesman said the company hopes to sell 10,000 PlayStations in Hong Kong, Singapore, Thailand and Malaysia before the end of June.</p>
<p>The Asian model can also play video compact discs, which can store up to 74 minutes of video, the statement said.</p>
<p>The new model is more than twice as expensive as the regular PlayStation sold in the United States, which now retails for $149 after a price cut on Monday.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the new model, which will be sold only in the Asian market, is priced higher than existing models because it can also play video compact discs.  </p>
<p>Sony on Monday cut the U.S. price of its PlayStation by 25 percent to $149.</p>
<p>The move made the PlayStation $50 cheaper than the rival Nintendo 64 video game machine made by Nintendo Co Ltd .</p>
<p>Nintendo said on Monday it would not cut the price of its 64-bit game machine sold in the United States for now.</p>
<p>PlayStation currently has a nearly 50 percent share of the worldwide market for game machines of 32 bits or more, while Sega Enterprises Ltd holds 32.3 percent and Nintendo 18.0 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
