<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="419758" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - March 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - March 4.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights of stories in the Danish press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>BERLINGSKE TIDENDE</p>
<p>---Newly-appointed Conservative Party leader Per Stig Moeller seems set to ride out the current storm over his 30-year-old drunken-driving offence and continue in his post despite criticism for being evasive to the media about the matter last week. Internal unrest rumbles on within the party with senior officials criticised for their handling of the affair. Last month Moeller replaced former leader Hans Engell, who resigned after being found by police after a car accident with a blood-alcohol level well over the legal limit.</p>
<p>--On a visit to Poland, Danish prime minister Poul Nyrup Rasmussen urged the Polish government to ignore Russian protests against NATO's planned expansion to the east and press on with its efforts to join the alliance at the first possible opportunity.</p>
<p>BORSEN</p>
<p>--- Denmark's top three banks, Den Danske Bank, Unidanmark and BG Bank will have to spend 200-300 million crowns on adapting computer and other systems to cope with the introduction of the euro, the European common currency expected to be launched in some EU states in 1999. The expenditure is necessary despite uncertainty about Denmark's participation in EMU, which Danes voted to stay out of in a 1993 Maastricht referendum.</p>
<p>JYLLANDS POSTEN</p>
<p>--- Plans for Copenhagen Stock Exchange to extend daily floor trading hours to 17.00 (1600 GMT) from the present 15.30 (1430 GMT) closure are making good progress.</p>
<p>POLITIKEN</p>
<p>--- Copenhagen Transport is seriously looking into the feasibility of introducing waterbus services along the capital's harbour waterfront.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
