<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="41970" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hortense becomes hurricane, cleanup from Fran goes on.</title>
<headline>Hortense becomes hurricane, cleanup from Fran goes on.</headline>
<byline>Jim Loney</byline>
<dateline>WILMINGTON, N.C. 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tropical Storm Hortense became a hurricane on Monday south of the U.S. Virgin Islands as North Carolina residents faced a huge cleanup job after Hurricane Fran.</p>
<p>At 5 a.m. EDT (0900 GMT), Hortense became a hurricane, according to the National Hurricane Center in Miami, with winds of 80 miles per hour (128 kph).</p>
<p>It was moving west-northwest at seven mph (12 kph), said meteorologist Colin McAdie and was 120 miles (193 km) south of St. Croix in the U.S. Virgin Islands.</p>
<p>Hortense was on a track to pass over the island of Hispaniola, home of Haiti and the Dominican Republic &quot;sometime within the next day or two&quot; McAdie said.</p>
<p>In North Carolina, workers were replacing hundreds of miles (kilometres) of downed power lines, repairing roads and hauling away fallen trees and debris.</p>
<p>Washington, however, was bracing itself for the fallout from Fran as rising floodwaters in the Potomac River threatened the nation's capital on Sunday.</p>
<p>Flooded streets near the river caused the closing of the Vietnam War Memorial and residents of the metropolitan area awoke (on) Monday to a traffic nightmare of closed arterial roads and cancelled trains.</p>
<p>Across the river in Virginia, picturesque Oldtown Alexandria was shut down by flooding.</p>
<p>Fran dumped four inches (10 cm) of rain in the capital and up to 14 inches (35 cm) in outlying areas, forecasters predicted a flood surge of 13 to 15 feet (4-4.5 metres) in the wealthy Georgetown section of the city and up to 34 feet (10 metres) at Harpers Ferry, West Virginia.</p>
<p>Hurricane Fran cut a swathe of destruction from Cape Fear on the southeastern end of North Carolina, where it came ashore, to the northwest of the state.</p>
<p>At least 15 people were killed in the state, including a firefighter and Marine, &quot;and there may be more,&quot; Sara Kempin, a spokeswoman for North Carolina Emergency Management Center, said. Some drowned and others were killed when trees fell on their cars or houses, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;The devastation is widespread across coastal and inland counties, and I want to do all we can to help rebuild North Carolina and help our people get their lives back together,&quot; Gov. Jim Hunt said in a statement.</p>
<p>There were 728,667 customers still without power throughout the state, and electric utility crews from Georgia, Ohio, Kentucky, Tennessee and West Virginia were on hand to help restore power.</p>
<p>Airspace over the beaches hardest hit by Fran has been closed, since sightseers were deemed to be posing a hazard to airborne disaster relief crews.</p>
<p>&quot;A no-fly zone has been established from two miles offshore to two miles inland from the New River Inlet south to Holden Beach,&quot; William Dudley, state deputy secretary of Crime Control and Public Safety, said.</p>
<p>In Wrightsville Beach, a town on a barrier island off Wilmington, officials said safety concerns would keep residents from returning for at least three days.</p>
<p>On Topsail Island, north of Wilmington, rescue workers searched homes in North Topsail Beach for missing people.</p>
<p>The Wilmington (N.C.) City Council passed an emergency ordinance on Saturday to prevent price gouging, making it punishable by a $500 fine or 30 days in jail.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WILMINGTON, N.C."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
