<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="419704" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish Sise Cam exports seen lower in '97.</title>
<headline>Turkish Sise Cam exports seen lower in '97.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish glassware producer Sise Cam is aiming for $325 million from its exports in 1997, lower than $339 million realised last year, the company's general manager Adnan Caglayan said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have targeted $325 million worth of exports for 1997,&quot; he told a news conference in Istanbul. He did not say why the exports were expected to fall.</p>
<p>He said the company, the biggest in the sector, was planning investment worth $402 million this year after investments of $367 million completed in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;The investment in the next three years will rise to $1 billion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the investments this year would help company's production rise to 1.4 million tonnes of glass, 1.4 million tonnes of industrial raw material and 633,000 tonnes of soda ash.</p>
<p>He said revenues would reach 352 trillion lira.</p>
<p>He said Sise Cam would seek foreign partnerships &quot;on the eve of the year 2000&quot; in an effort to raise the share of foreign production deals in its total revenues to 10 percent.</p>
<p>He said the company would buy a 25 percent stake from Belgian company Solvay's purchase in December of 60 percent of Bulgaria's privatised soda ash producer SODI for $160 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore Sise Cam will own some 17 percent of SODI and will get 250,000 tonnes of its production, which will raise Sise Cam's soda ash production to one million tonnes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The company has set up an equally-owned chemical company, Oxyvit Kimya, with the Italian company Cromical to produce Vitamin-K, used as additive in animal fodder.</p>
<p>Sise Cam will also be involved in the production of certain glass-fibered plastics, used in construction, automobile, natural gas, electricity distribution and telecommunications sectors, with the German company Mitras. he said.</p>
<p>--Ankara Newsroom, 90-312-4462940</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
