<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="419715" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SYRIA: PRESS DIGEST - Syria -  March 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Syria -  March 4.</headline>
<dateline>DAMASCUS 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in Syrian newspapers on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>SYRIA TIMES</p>
<p>- President Hafez al-Assad sends message to Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi. Syria and Italy are concerned over Israel's settlement policy.</p>
<p>- Syrian Foreign Minister Farouq al-Shara says Syria wants peace talks based on Madrid land-for-peace terms of reference and that start from the point at which they stopped.</p>
<p>- Israel carries out further fortification in the Golan.</p>
<p>- Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak says settlement in Jerusalem complicates peace process.</p>
<p>TISHREEN</p>
<p>- Jordan and Egypt praise Syrian policy in the peace process.</p>
<p>- The Higher Investment Council discusses difficulties of work and ways to encourage investments in the country.</p>
<p>- French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette starts a tour in the region in an attempt to revive peace talks.</p>
<p>- Syrian Economy Minister Imadi heads a meeting to discuss plans to improve exports of the public sector.</p>
<p>- Italian company to establish a project with a Syrian investor to manufacture shoes.</p>
<p>AL-THAWRA</p>
<p>- Lebanon renews commitment to coordination with Syria and to resisting the Israeli occupation in the south.</p>
<p>- Policies of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu push the region toward explosion. U.S. President Bill Clinton says the settlement decision negatively affected the peace process.</p>
<p>- The state-owned Banyas Oil Refinery, some 250 km (150 miles) north of Damascus on the Syrian coast, achieves 110 percent of its annual production plan.</p>
<p>AL-BAATH</p>
<p>- Omani minister of culture arrives in Damascus carrying a message to Assad from Sultan Qaboos.</p>
<p>- Syrian Peoples Assembly (parliament) discusses health issues.</p>
<p>- Syrian parliament approves two loans from the Islamic Bank of around $25 million to finance the Tishreen Hospital project.</p>
<p>- Agricultural investment in Syria still weak, forming 3.2 percent of the total projects from 1991 to 1996. Only 48 projects were established under the investment law. The value of the projects was 21.5 billion Syrian pounds.</p>
<p>($1 = 50 pounds in the black market).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SYRIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAMASCUS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SYRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
