<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="419812" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: PRESS DIGEST - Austria - March 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Austria - March 4.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Tuesday morning's Austrian newspapers:</p>
<p>DER STANDARD</p>
<p>- Claus Peymann, German-born director of Vienna's Hofburg theater, said in a letter to the government that he intended not to seek a renewal of his contract when his current term expires in 1999.</p>
<p>- Austria's companies plan to increase total investment outlays by some nine percent this year, economic research institute Wifo said in a study. It added that the strong dollar and lire have helped the country's ailing tourism industry.</p>
<p>- Number of jobless in Austria fell by 12,000 to 289,000 in February, the paper claims.</p>
<p>- Austrian shares climb to 70-month high on Monday amid strong buying in technology group VA Technologie.</p>
<p>- Chamber of Labour says labour costs have to be reduced in order to boost employment.</p>
<p>- Economic researchers at Wifo say the economic environment is slowly improvement as more jobs become available in the construction industry and trade. More flexible working hours and longer shop opening hours are also helping to overcome fundamental weakness of economy, they add.</p>
<p>- Oil and chemicals group OMV is still searching for a partner for its plastics unit PCD.</p>
<p>- Machine maker Voest Alpine Industrieanlagenbau's 1996 sales jumped 65 percent to 9.2 billion schillings in 1996, the company said.</p>
<p>- Raiffeisen group will pool all its resources in its bid to buy 49 percent of postal savings bank PSK.</p>
<p>DIE PRESSE</p>
<p>- Austrian exports and the tourism industry are improving because of the strong dollar.</p>
<p>- Austrian Kontrollbank recommends the country's listed companies should replace their shares into no-par value shares in preparation for the introduction of Europe's single currency.</p>
<p>KURIER</p>
<p>- Planned changes to Austria's immigration laws have caused heated debate between the coalition government partners, the Social Democrats and the conservative People's Party.</p>
<p>- The state of Upper Austria reported a budget surplus of 1.5 billion schillings in 1996.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
