<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="419852" id="root" date="1997-03-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Analysts cool to Indofood acquisitions.</title>
<headline>Analysts cool to Indofood acquisitions.</headline>
<byline>Helen Lumban Gaol</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian noodle maker PT Indofood Sukses Makmur's internal acquisition plan has drawn a lukewarm reaction from investors who see no major benefits from the deal, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Share prices of Indofood have steadily decreased since the company announced details of its estimated 1.750 trillion rupiah ($760 million) acquisition plan on February 6.</p>
<p>Brokers said investors were concerned about the implications of a proposed rights issue to acquire some sister companies.</p>
<p>By late afternooon trade on Tuesday, Indofood's stock price was down 100 rupiah to 5,125 rupiah on turnover of 489,000 shares after falling to 5,100 earlier. The prices compare with a loftier 5,300 rupiah at the close on February 5.</p>
<p>&quot;The main purpose of the acquisition is unclear and the value of the acquisitions is too expensive,&quot; an analyst with a Japanese firm said.</p>
<p>But she expected Indofood to win shareholder approval for its plan at a March 17 meeting.</p>
<p>However, she said, the plan, as it currently stands, would not give significant benefit to shareholders.</p>
<p>Indofood has said that under the plan it will acquire six companies within the Salim Group, of which it is also a unit. The companies to be acquired include PT Salim Ivomas, which owns oil palm plantations, PT Intiboga Sejahtera, which produces cooking oil and fats, and palm oil trader PT Salim Oil Grains.</p>
<p>John Rachmat, a senior analyst at Schroeders Indonesia, has also questioned the acquisition plans.</p>
<p>&quot;I can see many investors are not happy with this plan. Why should Indofood have to dilute its image of a strong consumer product company to enter the commodity business?&quot; he asked.</p>
<p>He also said the company's reason for the acquisitions, which it describes as vertical integration, appeared weak because investors could not find either strong benefits or synergies from the plan.</p>
<p>Rachmat also said the acquisitions had high risks given the cost of the deal and a possible dilution to earnings per share.</p>
<p>&quot;From its price earnings ratio, Indofood does not offer any discount,&quot; he said, adding that usually the market expects a discount when unlisted companies are acquired.</p>
<p>Rachmat said that based on his valuation, Indofood's earnings per share in 1997, without the acquisition, would be at 264 rupiah compared to 265 rupiah after the acquisition.</p>
<p>&quot;The risk is high. Let's say if the acquired companies fail to achieve target growth of 20 percent as Indofood has said ... It means investors will suffer earnings per share dilution,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In the company's prospectus, Indofood said the acquisitions would cost an estimated 1.750 trillion rupiah, of which just over 70 percent would be financed by a rights issue and the rest through loans.</p>
<p>After the acquisitions are completed the company would focus on branded packed food and cooking oil.</p>
<p>Indofood said on Friday its 1997 consolidated net sales would exceed five trillion rupiah after the acquisitions are completed. ($1 = 2,300 rupiah)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42390">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
