<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="420022" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sun Co shutdown at Pa. refinery now seen unlikely.</title>
<headline>Sun Co shutdown at Pa. refinery now seen unlikely.</headline>
<byline>Matt Daily</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sun Co Inc, aided by recent cost-cutting measures and a rebound in East Coast refining margins, probably now will not mothball the Point Breeze side of its Philadelphia refinery, analysts said.</p>
<p>Sun threatened last autumn to close parts of the 130,000 barrel per day (bpd) facility by July 1997 if profit targets were not met.</p>
<p>Point Breeze, together with the nearby 177,000 bpd Girard Point plant, form one of the East Coast's largest refining complexes, with a combined workforce of about 1,000. About half those jobs were at risk from the Point Breeze closure.</p>
<p>&quot;They seem to have backed off the threat to close it,&quot; said Ravi Kamath, senior vice president of research at Jeffries &amp; Co in Houston. &quot;I think it was sort of a wake-up call. I don't think they're taking the closure very seriously,&quot; Kamath added.</p>
<p>A Sun Co spokesman said, however, that a final decision on whether to shut the Point Breeze facility will not be taken until the end of the second quarter.</p>
<p>Whatever the fate of the plant, it appears Sun's strategy -- to run higher-quality crudes to simplify refining and make lighter, higher-profit products -- is working so far.</p>
<p>&quot;They are making money (at Point Breeze) now,&quot; said Bruce Lanni, analyst with Oppenheimer &amp; Co in New York. &quot;There have been a number of (unprofitable) processing units shut down (in the Northeast operations).&quot;</p>
<p>The shutdown in January of a 30,000 bpd hydrocracker, used to remove sulphur from sour crude, helped Sun cut staffing at Point Breeze by 40 employees to 460.</p>
<p>Sun said last month it would save $50 million in 1997 due to improvements at its Philadelphia and Marcus Hook plants.</p>
<p>With expected savings of $20 million from the Northeast Marketing division and $35 million from reconfiguring its Puerto Rico refinery, the company forecast a total cost saving of $105 million this year.</p>
<p>Lanni expects Sun's stock to outperform other refiners in the coming months due to the emphasis on distillate output and the gains in East Coast retail margins in recent months.</p>
<p>Refining margins on the East Coast early in March were about $3.29 a barrel, according to Paul Ting, analyst with Salomon Brothers. That figure was up from the previous week, but below the $4.04 mark posted in the fourth quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>East Coast margins at the pump were, meanwhile, at $7.73 a barrel at the beginning of the month, according to Ting's data, well above the $4.69 reported for the fourth quarter of 1996 and above the third quarter's $7.04.</p>
<p>But some analysts are not as convinced that Sun's recent improvements will result in a higher share price.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think they've established a clear position in the marketplace,&quot; said Mark Gilman, analyst with UBS Securities, noting he would maintain his &quot;sell&quot; recommendation on the company's stock.</p>
<p>&quot;The improvements that they envision are not margin-oriented,&quot; Gilman said, since the changes mean production of more of the pricier products but also require the plants to run more expensive crude.</p>
<p>Sun's stock was trading at $27-3/8 a share in afternoon trade Wednesday on the New York Stock Exchange. The stock peaked at $32-5/8 in 1996 but slipped to a low at $21-7/8 in September as refining margins eroded.</p>
<p>The poor margins were a big part of Sun's 1996 losses at its Northeast refining units totalling $60 million which easily exceeded the $37 million lost by the segment in 1995.</p>
<p>But Sun is hoping to erase that legacy and keep Point Breeze open by cranking up profitable gasoline and distillate output at the plant by 30,000 bpd, and chemicals output by 3,000 bpd, while dropping less profitable asphalt production.</p>
<p>Sun also hopes a pact it signed with with the Oil Chemical and Atomic Workers union in January aimed at cutting 175 jobs at its 175,000 bpd Marcus Hook refinery will also boost profitability and its share price.</p>
<p>-- ((New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1633))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
