<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="420177" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oil drillers rally again on Gulf of Mexico bids.</title>
<headline>Oil drillers rally again on Gulf of Mexico bids.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil services companies rallied for the second day after a record number of bids were submitted for the latest Gulf of Mexico deepwater drilling round.</p>
<p>&quot;The oil services sector in general had been marked down in the first two months of this year on falling oil and gas prices, but what today's lease round shows is that capital spending by exploration and production companies is strong, and that is what drives demand for oil services companies and drillers,&quot; said Salomon Brothers analyst Mark Urness.  </p>
<p>Producers bid on 1,790 tracts in federal waters off the coast of Louisiana, compared with 1,381 bids in April 1996, the U.S. Minerals Management Service said Wednesday.</p>
<p>By 1300 EST/1800 GMT, the S&amp;P Oil Drilling Index was up 60.55 points, or 2.02 percent, at 3.062.56, compared with a 0.53 percent gain for the S&amp;P 500 index.</p>
<p>The drilling index rose from 2,872.97 to 3,002.01 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;What people have failed to realize is that we are at the start of a multi-year recovery for the drilling industry,&quot; said Salomon's Urness.  </p>
<p>Among individual stocks, Cliffs Drilling put on 5-1/2 to 51-1/2, Global Marine added 3/4 to 20-3/4, Diamond Offshore rose 2-5/8 to 63-3/8, and Falcon Drilling rallied 1-1/2 to 35-3/4. Some stocks were off their best morning prices.</p>
<p>Cliffs said it knew of no unusual reason for its rise.</p>
<p>&quot;We got hit the most on the way down and are rallying the most on the way back up,&quot; said a spokeswoman for the company.</p>
<p>Urness said day rates for the largest deepwater rigs were $125,000-$130,000, while jackup rig rates were $40,000, compared with $25,000 a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;There are 13 rigs being built for competitive use globally and the current fleet is 600 worldwide. But 20 rigs go out of commission each year, so the number of rigs being built is still contracting,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rigs ordered now would be delivered in three years, so there will still be a shortage through to the year 2000, the analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;Rates are still only only about 60 percent of what is needed to trigger a large increase in building,&quot; Urness said.</p>
<p>((--David Chance, New York Newsroom 212 859 1902))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
