<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="420140" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FDA backs Bristol's Maxipime for neutropenia.</title>
<headline>FDA backs Bristol's Maxipime for neutropenia.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bristol-Myers Squibb Co said on Wednesday a U.S. Food and Drug Administration advisory committee unanimously recommended its antibiotic Maxipime be approved to treat febrile neutropenia.</p>
<p>In a seven to zero vote, Bristol said the group recommended Maxipime, already approved to treat urinary tract infections, skin infections and pneumonia, be used to fight fevers in patients with compromised immune systems.  </p>
<p>If approved, the antibiotic would be used to treat patients who developed fevers when their white blood cell levels were lowered by chemotherapy or other immunosuppressant therapies, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although other antibiotics are used in this situation, this is the first drug to receive a recommendation for approval for this specific indication,&quot; Laurie Smeldone, vice-president of Bristol-Myer's anti-infective clinical research department.</p>
<p>The company estimated 1.5 million patients in the United States suffered from some form of febrile neutropenia.  </p>
<p>But analysts downplayed the importance of Bristol's announcement, because the drug brought in a relatively small amount of money for the giant pharmacueticals maker.</p>
<p>&quot;Maxapime is not that big a deal for Bristol,&quot; said James Keeney, an analyst at Rodman &amp; Renshaw. &quot;It had sales of roughly $61 million last year, about $3 million of which were in the United States. We're looking for it to show sales of about $85 million this year.&quot;</p>
<p>Alex Zisson, an analyst at Hambrecht &amp; Quist, said that because Maxipime was not costly, the new indication would not open doors to a huge market for Bristol.</p>
<p>&quot;Plus, a lot of other antibiotics are already used this way,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bristol-Myers shares rose 2-3/4 by late trading Wednesday to close at a new year high of 69, but analysts said the shares were propelled up by a rallying drug sector.</p>
<p>&quot;It's rotational,&quot; Keeney said. &quot;The drug stocks are retracing some ground here and so is the overall market. It is a shift into consumer non-cyclical stocks.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Mary Kelleher, New York newsdesk 212-859-1707))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
