<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="420382" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-UNITED RUN RIOT AS JUVE AND AJAX FALTER.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-UNITED RUN RIOT AS JUVE AND AJAX FALTER.</headline>
<byline>Gideon Long</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Manchester United all but booked a place in their first European Cup semifinal for 28 years when they swept aside Porto 4-0 on Wednesday night in the first leg of their quarter-final tie.</p>
<p>But while United were thriving, holders Juventus, who beat the English champions twice in the Champions' League phase of the competition, were held 1-1 in Norway by Rosenborg Trondheim, conquerors of AC Milan in December.</p>
<p>Borussia Dortmund took a decisive step towards the last four by beating Auxerre 3-1 while Ajax, champions in 1995 and beaten finalists last year, were held 1-1 in Amsterdam by Atletico Madrid.</p>
<p>Porto's 4-0 drubbing at Old Trafford was their first defeat of the current European campaign and only their second of the season in all competitions.</p>
<p>It was their first defeat away from home since March 23, 1996, when the lost 2-1 at Benfica in the Portuguese league.</p>
<p>United played with a confidence they lacked in the group phase late last year.</p>
<p>The first goal came when David Beckham's looping cross from the left flank was headed goalwards by Gary Pallister. Goalkeeper Hilario could only parry and Pallister's fellow centre-back David May bundled the ball over the line.</p>
<p>Eric Cantona made the score 2-0 when he took advantage of a mistake by Paulinho Santos to lash the ball under Hilario's body from 12 metres and Ryan Giggs added to the 21-year-old goalkeeper's nightmare when he squeezed a shot inside the near post to round off a superb move started by Cantona deep in United territory.</p>
<p>The Frenchman was again the provider for Cole to claim a coolly-taken United fourth.</p>
<p>Alex Ferguson's side will travel to Portugal in confident mood but nevertheless wary of historical precedents.</p>
<p>The last time these two sides met, in the Cup Winners' Cup quarter-finals 19 years ago, Porto won the first leg 4-0. They then almost threw the tie away at Old Trafford in the second leg, losing 5-2 to edge through 6-5 on aggregate.</p>
<p>Juventus, who -- like Porto -- came through the Champions' League phase undefeated, were badly hit by injuries and looking sluggish on a freezing night in Trondheim.</p>
<p>Rosenborg took a deserved lead six minutes into the second half when striker Trond Egil Soltvedt hooked the ball home after a goalmouth melee.</p>
<p>But as the capacity Norwegian crowd celebrated, Juve's makeshift attacking pairing of Michele Padovano and Christian Vieri combined and Vieri nodded home a simple header to give the Italians an invaluable away goal for the second leg in two weeks' time.</p>
<p>Juve will be keen to welcome back Alessandro Del Piero and Croat Alan Boksic for the return match in Turin.</p>
<p>Ajax, Juve's victims in last year's European Cup final, face the threat of elimination and the end of their disappointing season after their 1-1 home draw against the champions of Spain.</p>
<p>Argentine international Juan Esnaider put Atletico ahead with a header in the eighth minute before Patrick Kluivert equalised for the Dutch side early in the second half.</p>
<p>Kluivert received his second booking of the competition and will miss the second leg in Madrid.</p>
<p>Goals by Karlheinz Riedle, Rene Schneider and Andy Moeller gave Dortmund a valuable victory against Auxerre.</p>
<p>Riedle headed Dortmund's first from close range after a fine build-up from Joerg Heinrich and Swiss international striker Stephane Chapuisat, and Schneider, a first-half substitute for injured Wolfgang Feiersinger, scored a second header early in the second half.</p>
<p>Sabri Lamouchi reduced the deficit before Moeller gave the German champions a comfortable cushion for the away leg with a lethal finish eight minutes from time.</p>
<p>Dortmund's night was soured slightly by the dismissal of Stefan Reuter three minutes from time for a second bookable offence. The German international will miss the return match in France.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
