<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42045" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Stena Line says wants to work with P&amp;O.</title>
<headline>Stena Line says wants to work with P&amp;O.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish ferry company Stena Line wants to cooperate with British ferry operator the Peninsular &amp; Oriental Steam Navigation Co (P&amp;O), Stena Managing Director Bo Lerenius said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;No contact has yet been made but I suppose that we will start discussions with P&amp;O within three to four weeks,&quot; Lerenius told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;With the day's tough price situation some form of cooperation is desirable.&quot;</p>
<p>Lerenius said the type of cooperation between the two companies was not certain and he declined to elaborate further.</p>
<p>Cooperation between the two companies has been made possible as British authorities recently lifted a ban on cross-Channel ferry operators working together.</p>
<p>Lerenius said the precarious situation for the shipping industry began when Eurotunnel halved its prices before the summer's peak season. Eurotunnel has posed a serious challenge to ferry operators on the Dover-Calais route since its opening in late 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;We were very surprised by this but had no other choice other than to lower our prices as well,&quot; Lerenius said. &quot;Now we first and foremost want to have some kind of cooperation with P&amp;O that will bring down costs and give up better results.</p>
<p>&quot;We also want price levels to become more stable.&quot;</p>
<p>Lerenius said he was not surprised that the Eurotunnel more than doubled traffic on Le Shuttle, the Eurotunnel's train operating between England and France.</p>
<p>Traffic increased to 304,032 vehicles in August this year from 145,861 vehicles in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;We have also increased volumes steadily this year,&quot; he said. &quot;The problem now instead is the higher costs.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Peter Fellman, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1007</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
