<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="420417" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: SOCCER-JUVENTUS HELD TO DRAW IN NORWAY.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-JUVENTUS HELD TO DRAW IN NORWAY.</headline>
<dateline>TRONDHEIM, Norway 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Holders Juventus were held to a 1-1 draw by the Norwegian part-timers of Rosenborg in their European Cup quarter-final first leg on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Italian league leaders, badly hit by injuries and looking sluggish in the freezing Norwegian night, were unable to put on a convincing performance as they struggled with a physically powerful Rosenborg who continue to surprise in this year's competition.</p>
<p>Rosenborg took a deserved lead six minutes into the second half when striker Trond Egil Soltvedt hooked the ball home after a goalmouth melee.</p>
<p>But as the capacity Norwegian crowd celebrated, the makeshift attacking pairing of Michele Padovani and Christian Vieri combined and Vieri nodded home a simple header to equalise and give Juventus an invaluable away goal for the second leg in two weeks' time.</p>
<p>Rosenborg, who dramatically tipped AC Milan out of the cup in the Champions' League phase, were far from over-awed by the Italians, who will be cautiously optimistic of qualifying in Italy when star strikers Alessandro Del Piero and Croat Alan Boksic may be fit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TRONDHEIM, Norway"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
