<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="420490" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Pepper in demand, growers to launch futures market.</title>
<headline>Pepper in demand, growers to launch futures market.</headline>
<byline>Simon Gardner</byline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Considered a condiment fit for a king in days of yore, the world's most widely used spice is about to join such trader favourites as gold and frozen orange juice on the futures trading circuit.</p>
<p>A new India-based black pepper futures exchange could help shed light on the traditionally opaque world of pepper, at a time when supply shortages could boost prices by up to 15 percent over the next six months.</p>
<p>Poor pepper crops from a handful of the world's main producers could lead to higher prices of the spice on the supermarket shelf.</p>
<p>According to the International Pepper Community (IPC), this is no short-term price blip. World pepper demand will continue to outstrip supply for the next 10 to 15 years, an IPC official said.</p>
<p>Dave Marchington of trading house Chambers and Knight sees room for a further rise in black pepper prices. &quot;There is a general pepper shortage. $3,500 a ton by June 1997 wouldn't unduly surprise,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Black pepper traded in January around 10-year highs at $3,000 a metric ton.</p>
<p>TOP PRODUCERS CHOOSE KOCHI FOR FUTURES EXCHANGE</p>
<p>Leading producers India, Indonesia, Malaysia, Brazil and Thailand form the IPC and between them produce around 95 percent of the world's pepper.</p>
<p>The new pepper exchange will be based in the spice capital of the globe -- Kochi in southern India -- and will deliver to Brazil, Malaysia, Indonesia and Singapore.</p>
<p>India's Food Ministry said on Feb. 4 that the exchange was on schedule to start trading by April. But traders, who have seen the start date pushed back twice since the exchange was approved by the government last April, expect it to start up in May-June 1997.</p>
<p>Black pepper, or Piper Nigrum, is a climbing vine native to the southwest coast of India, and was a major impetus behind the 16th-century quest for a sea route to the East.</p>
<p>The pepper plant grows in slender clusters of pea-sized fruits, which are harvested when yellowish-red and boiled.</p>
<p>The berries turn black when boiled, and are then known as peppercorns. White pepper is made by removing the black outer covering of the peppercorn, and grinding the hardened pith.</p>
<p>Prices for standard grinding quality black pepper, referred to as Malabar (after India's Malabar coast) Garbled One (MG1), have risen by almost 50 percent since last June.</p>
<p>Black pepper prices reached an all-time high 10 years ago, when the spice traded at $4,500 a ton.</p>
<p>INDONESIA CROP SHORTAGE SENT PEPPER PRICE SOARING</p>
<p>Prices subsequently fell back, but black pepper prices have risen in recent months on the back of white pepper prices, after a crop shortage in key producer Indonesia sent white pepper prices soaring from $2,500 a ton a year ago to around $5,500 in January.</p>
<p>Ideal growing conditions for the pepper plant include a long rainy season, fairly high temperatures and partial shade for growth, but white pepper production requires an abundant water supply.</p>
<p>As a result, India only produces around 500 metric tons of white pepper a year, less than 1 percent of its total pepper output.</p>
<p>The pepper plant -- not to be confused with the red, hot chili peppers of the capsicum family so painfully familiar to fans of Indian and Mexican cuisine -- yields a wide variety of products.</p>
<p>Black peppercorns, white, ground and green pepper, pepper oil, pepper oleoresin used in balsams, and medicinal pepper, account for one-fourth of a world spice trade worth around $2 billion a year.</p>
<p>Other globally traded spices include paprika, cinnamon, cloves, ginger, tumeric and nutmeg.</p>
<p>The world's top pepper consumers are in North America, the European Union, the Middle East and North Africa.</p>
<p>Crop arrivals from leading producer countries are staggered. Malaysia's crop is scheduled to arrive in May, Indonesia's in August, and Brazil's in October-November.</p>
<p>But delays in crop arrivals squeeze a market where demand already exceeds supply, and world black pepper prices have risen by over 5 percent since the New Year on news of a delayed and diminished crop arrival from the world's biggest grower, India.</p>
<p>In a good year, India produces around 70,000 metric tons of black pepper, but its 1996 December-January crop arrival has been put back to February, and is forecast to total between 55,000 and 60,000 metric tons.</p>
<p>World pepper output totalled around 150,000 metric tons during 1996, worth an estimated $450 million based on current prices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
