<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="420444" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: CZECH SENATE BACKS RECONCILIATION PACT WITH GERMANY.</title>
<headline>CZECH SENATE BACKS RECONCILIATION PACT WITH GERMANY.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech Senate upper house of parliament gave final approval on Wednesday to a post-World War Two reconciliation pact with Germany, the Senate press department said.</p>
<p>The measure, already signed by both governments and approved by Germany's parliament and the Czech lower house, was approved by 54 votes to 25 after only a few hours of debate.</p>
<p>Earlier, President Vaclav Havel urged the upper house to approve the accord to ensure good relations with Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;I am guaranteeing you, that historians and politicians will devote time to the question of what we did for good relations with our large and influential neighbour, and through that for good relations in the whole of Europe,&quot; Havel told senators.</p>
<p>The Senate approved the pact without any preamble, as was attached to the resolution accompanying the declaration in the lower house.</p>
<p>In the declaration, Bonn expresses its regret for the 1938-45 occupation of the Czech lands and Prague its sorrow for brutality in the expulsion of ethnic Germans after the war.</p>
<p>The declaration also included German support for Czech membership of the European Union and NATO and finalising the accord was seen as a vital pre-requisite to Prague joining both organisations.</p>
<p>The accord has proved highly controversial in both countries. Relatives and supporters of the 2.5 million expelled Sudeten Germans have criticised it as it does not include any direct compensation for property they lost.</p>
<p>Czech Communists and ultra-nationalist Republicans have attacked the pact as a sell-out to Bonn. Other opponents have said it does not make clear that the Czech actions were based on legal agreements.</p>
<p>However, the accord was quickly approved by a large majority in the German parliament.</p>
<p>Debate in the Czech lower house dragged on for four days, with virulent attacks by Communist and Republican deputies before the accord was approved by a large majority.</p>
<p>The Czech government, which has only a minority in the lower house, has a strong majority in the Senate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
