<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="420561" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Caribs dirty tanker rates firm, West Africa active.</title>
<headline>Caribs dirty tanker rates firm, West Africa active.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Caribs/upcoast 70,000 tonne dirty tanker rates firmed to W167.5 on Wednesday, up some 10 points on tight prompt tonnage, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The enquiry is certainly out there...Charterers are having to pay last done or a bit more. It's a buoyant market right now,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>The West Africa-U.S. market was active, with million barrels vessels fixed at around W105 and very large crude carriers at a steady to firmer W72.5. &quot;The tone is quite positive with a good number of VLCCs and million barrel ships being fixed,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Middle East very large crude carrier (VLCC) rates were also steady, with journeys west assessed at W52.5/55, to Japan at W60 and to Singapore three vessels -- the Picardie, Autan and Eastern Strength -- were fixed for Chevron at W57.5 for between March 20 and 22.</p>
<p>In addition, BP fixed the Athos to lift 250,000 tonnes from the Iraqi port of Mina al-Bakr to Durban on March 26, also at W57.5. Last month about two million barrels of Iraqi crude arrived in South Africa after the Leonidas was delayed by engine trouble and Mobil cancelled its purchase for a U.S. Gulf refinery.</p>
<p>North Sea 130,000 tonne (million barrel) dirty tanker rates picked up on a shortage of vessels which were being diverted to West Africa.</p>
<p>Million barrel vessels rose to W102.5/105, while Aframax (80,000 tonne) rates were steady at W112.5/115 for modern ships and as low as W105 for older tankers, brokers said.</p>
<p>Cross-Mediterranean rates were steady in quiet activity, with 130,000 tonners at W100 and 80,000 tonners at W115.</p>
<p>The transatlantic sector was also quiet with VLCC rates continuing to be assessed around W65.</p>
<p>Cross-Med 25,000 fuel oil rates were slightly firmer at W215, with inter-U.K./cont steady at W205. --London newsroom +44 171 542 4088</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
