<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="420550" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London Transport starts Tube extension plan probe.</title>
<headline>London Transport starts Tube extension plan probe.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>London Transport confirmed on Wednesday it was investigating the planned extension of the Underground's Jubilee Line, but declined to comment on reports that the project was running behind schedule.</p>
<p>The Evening Standard newspaper reported that the 2.6 billion pound project -- already over budget -- would be delayed by at least six months past its scheduled March 1998 opening.</p>
<p>Work on the 16-kilometre extension, a highly-complex project that involved burrowing under London's famous Big Ben tower, began in 1993 and originally expected to cost 1.7 billion pounds.</p>
<p>The underground artery would link the centre of the capital to office developments such as Canary Wharf in east London.</p>
<p>&quot;We are holding further discussions within our team and with the Department of Transport,&quot; London Transport chairman Peter Ford said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope to be able to confirm very quickly the details of the likely opening date of the extension.&quot;</p>
<p>London's underground train system, known as the Tube, faces possible privatisation under the ruling Conservative Party, which has criticised its perceived decline in service and reduced its government funding.</p>
<p>But the opposition Labour Party, favourites to win the national election due by May 22, has said it is firmly committed to keeping the Tube in public hands.</p>
<p>A London Transport spokeswoman said the Jubilee Line investigation involved every area of the project, but she would not comment on the reports that the project would be delayed.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't possibly speculate before we get the results of the investigation,&quot; she said, adding that the authority hoped to have something to report by next week.</p>
<p>The project was now in the process of fitting equipment like ticket machines in the stations following the completion of tunnelling work, she said.</p>
<p>The extension hit a six-month snag in 1994 when the transport authority stopped work to evaluate problems at an unrelated project that used similar tunnelling technology.</p>
<p>-- Jeff Daeschner, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
