<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="420579" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Non-OPEC oil output growth speeds up-Reuters survey.</title>
<headline>Non-OPEC oil output growth speeds up-Reuters survey.</headline>
<byline>Mark Thompson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Growth in oil output from the world's main non-OPEC suppliers accelerated last year, rising 840,000 barrels per day (bpd) to 39.28 million bpd, a survey by Reuters found.</p>
<p>The increase in production was led by Latin America, Europe and Asia which recorded rises of eight, five and three percent respectively.</p>
<p>Output in 1995 grew 740,000 bpd to 38.44 million.</p>
<p>North America pumped nearly two percent more oil last year, while non-OPEC Middle East and African nations saw output rise by less than one percent after a strong performance in 1995.</p>
<p>Former Soviet states managed to brake the decline in production, which dropped by only one percent in 1996, half the fall registered in 1995.</p>
<p>The survey covers more than 90 percent of the oil pumped by suppliers other than Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) members and includes natural gas liquids, as well as crude, from most countries.</p>
<p>Steady growth in Mexican crude production more than compensated for lower output of Natural Gas Liquids (NGLs) in the second half of the year, and combined with higher Canadian volumes lifted the North American total despite a slight decline in the United States' contribution.</p>
<p>U.S. crude output fell to 6.42 million bpd from 6.52 million, down 1.5 percent, but NGLs rose four percent to 1.99 million bpd from 1.91 million in 1995.</p>
<p>Mexican crude and NGLs recovered strongly from 1995's storm affected figures, rising seven percent to 3.28 million bpd.</p>
<p>Canada posted a modest 50,000 bpd, or two percent rise, on the back of higher synthetic and conventional crude production.</p>
<p>Latin American volumes rose a net 214,000 bpd to 2.85 million bpd, with Brazil, Argentina and Colombia recording substantial gains.</p>
<p>Brazil saw its output jump by 12 percent to 809,000 bpd thanks largely to higher output in the Campos Basin.</p>
<p>Europe's total was boosted for the second year running by a sharp increase in Norwegian production which surged 245,000 bpd to a record 3.165 million bpd. British production was flat, while Danish output rose by nearly 12 percent to 208,000 bpd.</p>
<p>China was the pick of the Asian non-OPEC producers, its 180,000-bpd increase to 3.17 million bpd making up for weaker performances from India, Malaysia and Brunei.</p>
<p>Middle East and African production rose by 30,000 bpd to 3.811 million bpd thanks to a large rise in Angolan output which cancelled out losses from Egypt, Syria, Yemen and Cameroon.</p>
<p>Output from the former Soviet Union was stable at 6.811 million bpd as the slide in Russian production slowed and other states, particularly Kazakhstan, posted modest increases.</p>
<p>Figures in millions of barrels per day come mostly from national governments. Other sources include oil companies and the Paris-based International Energy Agency (IEA):</p>
<p>				 1996	    1995</p>
<p>North America</p>
<p>     United States	 8.410	   8.434</p>
<p>     Canada		  2.450	   2.398</p>
<p>     Mexico		  3.280	   3.060</p>
<p>    Subtotal		14.140	  13.892</p>
<p>Latin America</p>
<p>     Argentina	     0.786	   0.710</p>
<p>     Brazil		  0.809	   0.718</p>
<p>     Colombia		0.628	   0.583</p>
<p>     Ecuador		 0.384	   0.387</p>
<p>     Peru		    0.118	   0.123</p>
<p>     Trinidad and Tobago 0.130	   0.120</p>
<p>    Subtotal		 2.855	   2.641</p>
<p>Africa/Middle East</p>
<p>     Angola		  0.760	   0.650</p>
<p>     Cameroon		0.102	   0.120</p>
<p>     Congo		   0.250	   0.210</p>
<p>     Egypt		   0.854	   0.958</p>
<p>     Oman		    0.880	   0.855</p>
<p>     Syria		   0.600	   0.610</p>
<p>     Yemen		   0.365	   0.380</p>
<p>    Subtotal		 3.811	   3.783</p>
<p>Europe</p>
<p>     Britain		 2.570	   2.560</p>
<p>     Denmark		 0.208	   0.186</p>
<p>     Italy		   0.115	   0.110</p>
<p>     Norway		  3.165	   2.920</p>
<p>     Romania		 0.132	   0.135</p>
<p>    Subtotal		 6.190	   5.911</p>
<p>Ex-Soviet Union</p>
<p>     Azerbaijan	    0.191	   0.192</p>
<p>     Kazakhstan	    0.445	   0.412</p>
<p>     Russia		  6.050	   6.165</p>
<p>     Uzbekistan	    0.125	   0.115</p>
<p>    Subtotal		 6.811	   6.884</p>
<p>Asia</p>
<p>     Australia	     0.555	   0.510</p>
<p>     Brunei		  0.167	   0.175</p>
<p>     China		   3.170	   2.990</p>
<p>     India		   0.650	   0.670</p>
<p>     Malaysia		0.650	   0.710</p>
<p>     Papua New Guinea    0.105	   0.100</p>
<p>     Vietnam		 0.173	   0.170</p>
<p>    Subtotal		 5.470	   5.325</p>
<p>    Total		   39.277	  38.436</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 171 542 7930</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
