<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="420654" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African business confidence rises, but fragile.</title>
<headline>S.African business confidence rises, but fragile.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Business confidence is improving, with the manufacturing sector in particular hopeful of higher sales and output, but the mood remains nervous, the South African Chamber of Business (Sacob) said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Business confidence is on the rise but is still fragile,&quot; director of economic policy Ben van Rensburg told reporters after the group reported a 0.9 point rise in its confidence index to a four-month high of 113.2.</p>
<p>Van Rensburg said Sacob had raised its forecast of real South African gross domestic product (GDP) growth this year to 2.5 percent from 2.3 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We would like to see further evidence before we conclude whether it will be any higher than 2.5 percent...We are still talking about a 'soft landing' rather than any definitive upturn in the economy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals told Reuters on Tuesday that earlier forecasts of growth for 1997 of 2.0-2.5 percent were too low and growth could in fact come close to three percent, not much different from last year's 3.1 percent.</p>
<p>Aside from improving growth prospects -- underlined by an uptick in fourth quarter 1996 GDP -- van Rensburg said the positive mood had been fostered by a more stable rand, an improving trade balance, higher reserves and capital inflows.</p>
<p>Next week's 1997/98 budget would be a key factor in determing business mood in the year ahead, van Rensburg said.</p>
<p>Sacob's latest survey of manufacturers indicated that a large majority of respondents expected sales and production volumes to increase over the next 12 months.</p>
<p>A total of 77 percent of those questioned expected sales volumes to rise while 69 percent expected production volumes to increase.</p>
<p>&quot;Expectations in manufacturing are generally rosier than they were in December and January,&quot; said economist Penny Hawkins.</p>
<p>However, the improvement in manufacturing -- most notable among export-oriented industries -- had done little to boost employment prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not expecting any large employment growth in this sector,&quot; Hawkins said.</p>
<p>-- Ben Hirschler, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
