<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="420740" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>KYRGYZSTAN: Kyrgyz electricity firm sees privatisation plan.</title>
<headline>Kyrgyz electricity firm sees privatisation plan.</headline>
<dateline>BISHKEK 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kyrgyzstan's national electrical firm Kyrgyzenergoholding has forwarded its privatisation plan to the government and the scheme envisages attracting a strategic investor, possibly foreign, the company said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A news release described a four-step privatisation process for the company, which is a net exporter of electricity to Central Asian neighbours Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan.</p>
<p>The scheme would first involve setting up a joint stock company called Kyrgyzenergo and holding a specialised voucher auction for citizens.</p>
<p>Kyrgyzstan's voucher privatisation, in which citizens can swap vouchers for shares in enterprises, ends on June 30.</p>
<p>The next stage would entail selling off social infrastructure and small hydro-power stations and creating state joint-stock companies out of individual power stations and generation and transmission units.</p>
<p>The last stage would see a tender to attract a strategic investor, possibly foreign.</p>
<p>The state would retain a controlling share.</p>
<p>Foreign investment is key to the small, former Soviet republic's sector, and a state official told Reuters at least $650 million was needed to keep the national power grid in order.</p>
<p>Another $4 billion was needed to finalise construction of two hydro-power stations and around $70 million to renovate electricity transmission lines.</p>
<p>Kyrgyzstan, with 19 hydro-electric power stations and two thermal facilities, produces 12-14 billion kilowatt hours a year, making use of just nine percent of its huge energy potential, which is estimated at 142.5 billion kilowatt/hours.</p>
<p>--Almaty Newsroom, +7 3272 509410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KIRGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BISHKEK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KYRGYZSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
