<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="420792" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbia power industry to invest $2.6 bln by 2000.</title>
<headline>Serbia power industry to invest $2.6 bln by 2000.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbia's power company Elektroprivreda Srbije (EPS) plans to invest around $2.6 billion in the overhaul of its installations to the year 2000, Belgrade newspapers reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Although EPS' development plan envisages investments of $420 this year, more realistically this sum will amount to around $300 million, EPS deputy director Novica Maskovic was quoted as telling a meeting of the Serbian Chamber of Commerce power industry committee Tuesday.</p>
<p>Maskovic said worn-out installations had to be revitalised since out of 26, as many as 14 are more than two decades old with over 100,000 operating hours.</p>
<p>As a result electricity prices would have to be raised in March and again in June for EPS to achieve its development plans for 1997, Maskovic said but did not elaborate.</p>
<p>This was seen as an unpopular move in a country where average monthly wages are barely over $100.</p>
<p>Krsta Vukovic, EPS assistant general manager, said Serbia's power installations were in solid condition before the international trade embargo was imposed on Yugoslavia in 1992, but have been worn out over the past few years and are in desperate need of repair.</p>
<p>This winter more use was made of hydro-electric power plants which accounted for 39 percent in total electricity production, instead of the earlier 30 percent, thanks to good meteorological conditions, Vukovic said.</p>
<p>&quot;But we must not meet next winter without an overhaul,&quot; Vukovic added.</p>
<p>He said EPS would need around 1.5 billion dinars ($266 million) for overall maintenance this year, of which around 15 percent in hard currency.</p>
<p>&quot;We will try through compensation arrangements to employ local producers,&quot; he said but warned Yugoslav spare parts producers to lower their prices which are now up to 50 percent higher compared to foreign competition.</p>
<p>-- Amra Kevic, Belgrade newsroom +381 11 2224305</p>
<p>($1 = 5.6351 dinars)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
