<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="420893" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Nicaragua's stalled property talks seen restarting.</title>
<headline>Nicaragua's stalled property talks seen restarting.</headline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vice President Enrique Bolanos said on Wednesday Nicaragua's government was willing to restart stalled property talks with the leftist Sandinistas once the political environment has &quot;cooled down.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to wait until the iron has cooled down a bit but the truth is the will exists (to continue the talks),&quot; Bolanos, who heads the government delegation, told reporters.</p>
<p>The two sides began a series of meetings in late January to resolve the conflicts between the Sandinistas and current occupants of tens of thousands of properties confiscated by the 1979-1990 Sandinista government.</p>
<p>The issue also has been a source of friction in U.S.-Nicaraguan relations because hundreds of U.S. citizens have yet to have their property claims settled.</p>
<p>Bolanos said a date had not been specified to resume the talks, suspended indefinitely on Feb. 27 by the left-wing opposition Sandinista Front, which accused President Arnoldo Aleman of not presenting serious proposals.</p>
<p>While the talks initially raised hopes Nicaragua would solve its private property problem, which has scared away investors from Nicaragua for years, they soon bogged down over the government's demand for the Sandinistas to return or pay for confiscated properties in party hands.</p>
<p>Tensions boiled over the day after the talks were suspended when former Sandinista President Daniel Ortega, brandishing his party's slogan of &quot;Free homeland or death,&quot; called on Sandinista activists to prepare to rise up to resist the return of &quot;somocismo,&quot; referring to hated former dictator Anastasio Somoza who was toppled by the 1979 Sandinista revolution and had his properties confiscated.</p>
<p>Ortega, in his harshest attack on the new right-wing government since it took power on Jan. 10, accused it of preparing to return the properties to Somoza's family and former collaborators. Aleman has invited Somoza's family, most of whom live in the United States, to return to Nicaragua and pursue their land claims in Nicaraguan courts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
