<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421087" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>YEMEN: Yemen's opposition party to boycott elections.</title>
<headline>Yemen's opposition party to boycott elections.</headline>
<byline>Mohammed Sudam</byline>
<dateline>SANAA 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yemen's main opposition party on Wednesday announced it was boycotting next month's general elections, the first since the country's 1994 civil war.</p>
<p>Secretary-General of the Yemen Socialist Party (YSP) Ali Saleh Obad said the party decided at a meeting earlier in the day to boycott the April 27 elections because it failed to get official guarantees the ballot would be fair and free.</p>
<p>&quot;The YSP central committee decided not to take part in the vote because the two government coalition partners refused to heed demands for guarantees on the fairness of the ballot and other political and financial guarantees,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no going back on our decision,&quot; Obad said.</p>
<p>Yemeni President Ali Abdullah Saleh's General People's Congress (GPC) won a majority in the last elections followed by the Islamist Islah Party and the YSP.</p>
<p>The three parties governed Yemen until the YSP, some of whose leaders launched the civil war separatist campaign, was dismissed from the coalition.</p>
<p>Obad said of the 90 YSP central committee members present at the gathering, 57 voted against, one abstained and 32 were in favour of taking part in the election.</p>
<p>The YSP has 50 seats in the 301-strong parliament.</p>
<p>Government officials declined comment.</p>
<p>But a source close to the two ruling parties said they would cooperate with ... &quot;the 32 in the YSP who rejected the boycott decision to run in the election in the name of the YSP&quot;.</p>
<p>Saleh issued a decree on Monday night announcing the voting date as well as setting the period from March 20 to 29 for candidate registration.</p>
<p>Voter registration ended in August last year and official figures showed that 4.5 million men and women had registered out of 7.5 million eligible voters.</p>
<p>Saleh said last month his country planned to invite international observers to monitor the ballot to ensure its fairness after opposition objections to alleged irregularities in the voter registration.</p>
<p>International observers monitored the last poll in 1993 in which 22 parties took part.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANAA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YEMEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
