<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421045" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Quake insurance on the rise in Japan - Tokio Marine.</title>
<headline>Quake insurance on the rise in Japan - Tokio Marine.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The number of Japanese households with earthquake insurance has nearly doubled since the Kobe quake, the nation's largest non-life insurer said on Wednesday as a spate of tremors put meteorological experts on edge.</p>
<p>&quot;The rate of cover has almost doubled since the Kobe disaster...Nationwide 7.3 percent of families had household earthquake insurance policies in December 1994, a month before the Kobe quake, compared to 12.2 percent in June last year,&quot; said Tokio Marine and Fire Insurance spokeswoman Minami Imagi.</p>
<p>&quot;But the numbers are much higher in Tokyo -- in June last year 21.9 percent of Tokyo households were covered for earthquake damage, compared to 16 percent a month before Kobe,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;Swarms&quot; of low-frequency tremors measuring around three on the Richter scale that have hit the Izu Peninsula, some 100 km (60 miles) south of Tokyo, during the past three days have likely raised public awareness nationwide, Mitsui Marine and Fire Insurance spokesman Yuichi Sekiguchi said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to get many more calls from customers checking to see if they are already covered for earthquake damage because of media reports of possible eruptions in Izu,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Households living in the coastal belt stretching south from Toyko through Kanagawa Prefecture to the Izu Peninsula in Shizuoka Prefecture pay the highest earthquake insurance premiums in the country, Sekiguchi added.</p>
<p>&quot;The premiums are calculated on the basis of the damage from 375 major quakes over the last 500 years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Japan's Meteorological Agency is paying serious attention to the continuing swarm quakes in Izu, the agency's earthquake division chief Akio Yoshida said.</p>
<p>Nearly 3,800 tremors have shaken the area since Monday, according to agency statistics issued on Wednesday afternoon.</p>
<p>&quot;We have identified the tremors in the Izu peninsula this morning as low-frequency quakes. The Izu region is known for its seesawing between periods of inactivity and bursts of low-frequency tremors... We are viewing the situation very seriously,&quot; Yoshida said.</p>
<p>The agency on Wednesday cited movements of undersea &quot;magma&quot;, or molten rock, off the east coast of the peninsula as the cause of the low-frequency tremors.</p>
<p>Tokyo University earthquake researchers said the chances of a full-scale volcanic eruption had increased due to magma movements.</p>
<p>&quot;It's likely that magma, or perhaps steam, is moving closer to the surface of the seabed,&quot; university earthquake expert Yoshiaki Ida said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
