<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421077" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel says PLO must close offices before pullback.</title>
<headline>Israel says PLO must close offices before pullback.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Heller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A spokesman for Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said on Wednesday it would be impossible for Israel to carry out a West Bank pullback due this week unless four Palestinian offices in Arab East Jerusalem are shut down.</p>
<p>The PLO's top official in Jerusalem charged that Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's decision on Tuesday to close the offices was aimed at stirring conflict with the Palestinians.</p>
<p>The decision only hours before Netanyahu's trip to Cairo for talks with President Hosni Mubarak drew quick Egyptian condemnation but Netanyahu said later that Egypt did not think it warranted Palestinian violence.</p>
<p>&quot;What has become clear since we made the decision about Har Homa is that Egypt clearly opposes the position that this thing justifies violence or a retreat from the peace process,&quot; he told Israeli reporters after meeting Mubarak in Cairo.</p>
<p>Israel's decision to build 6,500 homes at Jerusalem's Har Homa district, for Arabs Jabal Abu Ghneim, has prompted widespread international condemnation.</p>
<p>David Bar-Illan, Netanyahu's media adviser, said Israel intended to meet a Friday deadline to pull troops back from mainly rural areas of the West Bank but first demanded &quot;reciprocity&quot; from the PLO.</p>
<p>&quot;It is impossible for the peace process to continue, for the redeployment and other obligations which Israel has, to continue without the closing of these offices,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The first step was to warn the Palestinian Authority to close these offices at this point,&quot; he said. &quot;This is the right time to do so -- before Israel does a further redeployment in the areas of Judea and Samaria (the West Bank).&quot;</p>
<p>Israel's Public Security Ministry said police, acting on Netanyahu's orders, were preparing to issue warnings to the offices to close on their own accord within 48 hours or be shut.</p>
<p>It did not name them but Arabic newspapers identified them as the Palestinian Mapping Office, the Palestinian Small Businesses Project, the Palestinian Institute for the Wounded and the National Islamic Committee Confronting Settlements.</p>
<p>Faisal al-Husseini, responsible for Jerusalem affairs in the Palestinian Authority, said the closure orders on the heels of Israel's plan to build 6,500 more Jewish homes in the eastern part of the city, were a deliberate provocation.</p>
<p>&quot;Although we see that these Israeli measures will cause an explosion, we are trying to save matters by contacting the Israelis and other countries to prevent this happening,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want to hear from the Israelis that they did not know what will happen like they did after the tunnel,&quot; he said. &quot;They know, they are certain and they are planning and are heading in that direction consciously and with their full will.&quot;</p>
<p>Sixty-one Palestinians and 15 Israeli soldiers were killed in clashes that erupted last September after Netanyahu opened a new entrance to an archaeological tunnel near Moslem holy sites in East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Bar-Illan said cabinet ministers would decide on Thursday on the scope of the pullback.</p>
<p>Radical secular and Islamic Palestinian groups on Wednesday urged the Palestinian Authority to suspend peace talks with Israel over its plans to build apartments in East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The Islamic Hamas, the Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine, and Democratic Front for the Liberation of Palestine and the Baghdad-based Arab Liberation Front, said the Palestinian Authority should &quot;stop its negotiations with the Zionist enemy to force it to retract its settlement decisions&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
