<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421187" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: White House ready to accept small Fed rate rise.</title>
<headline>White House ready to accept small Fed rate rise.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Rich Miller, Economics Correspondent</p>
<p>The Clinton administration has signalled that it is ready to acquiesce to a modest increase in interest rates should the Federal Reserve deem it necessary to contain inflation.</p>
<p>Administration officials have voiced optimism recently about the economic outlook and the ability of the economy to shrug off a small rate rise by the independent central bank.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the economy is poised on the precipice of recession or very slow growth,&quot; Commerce Undersecretary Everett Ehrlich told Reuters Financial Television in a recent intereview. &quot;I don't think that small changes in interest rates around the margins would change that,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Fed Chairman Alan Greenspan hinted last week that the central bank may need to raise rates in the coming months to keep inflation down and the economic expansion on track.</p>
<p>&quot;If we allow inflationary imbalances to start to emerge, history tells us that the end of the expansion is near at hand,&quot; Greenspan told the Senate Banking Committee.</p>
<p>He also signalled that any increase would not be as sharp as in 1994/95, when the central bank doubled short-term rates to keep the economy from overheating.</p>
<p>The Fed has not raised interest rates in more than two years and any increase would mark a reversal in policy. The central bank's next policy-making meeting is on March 25.</p>
<p>The federal funds rate, the rate that commercial banks charge each other for overnight loans, currently stands at 5.25 percent. The discount rate, which the Fed charges banks for money, is 5.00 percent. Neither has been changed since Jan. 31, 1996, when they were both cut by a quarter point.</p>
<p>White House budget chief Franklin Raines told bankers on Tuesday that any increase in short-term rates would have only a modest impact on the economy.</p>
<p>On its own, a short-term rate rise would have a &quot;modest negative effect,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But if it led to a drop in long-term rates, the impact would be neutral to positive, said Raines, who heads the White House's Office of Management and Budget.</p>
<p>Long-term rates on everything from home mortgages to corporate bonds occasionally fall in response to tighter credit by the Fed if investors believe that the central bank's action will succeed in keeping down inflation.</p>
<p>The Commerce Department's Ehrlich described U.S. inflation as &quot;very benign&quot; and said he saw no reason why the nearly six-year-old economic upswing cannot keep on going.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see why this expansion can't continue for some while,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Both the Clinton administration and the Fed have forecast modest growth for the economy for this year and next, with no recession on the horizon.</p>
<p>&quot;The most likely prospect is for continued sustainable economic growth accompanied by low and stable inflation,&quot; Greenspan told the House Budget Committee on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But, he added, it was &quot;crucial&quot; to keep inflation contained in the near term to ensure that comes about.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
