<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421176" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Grammys spark sales but music industry still blue.</title>
<headline>Grammys spark sales but music industry still blue.</headline>
<byline>Sue Zeidler</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>This year's Grammys sparked sales for the big winners and performers at the music awards but the $12 billion industry is still singing the blues.</p>
<p>Indeed, the glitzy Feb. 26 ceremony, which filled up New York's Madison Square Garden and drew thousands of industry professionals to the Big Apple for a week, renewed interest in the music business, where sales have sagged the past year.</p>
<p>But despite all the hoopla, U.S. album sales for the week ended March 2 were flat at 11 million units compared with the week before the show, according to Hartsdale, N.Y.-based Soundscan, which tracks music retail sales.</p>
<p>Several retailers reported little change in traffic.</p>
<p>&quot;If we noticed anything at all, it was slight. It was steady but nothing remarkable,&quot; said Elliott Cobb, treasurer of the 265-store, California-based Wherehouse Entertainment chain, which recently emerged from bankruptcy.</p>
<p>But other retailers said the event was a plus, particularly since the 39th annual Grammy awards endorsed an array of artists popular with several generations -- from 70-year-old Tony Bennett, winning the best traditional pop vocal performance award, to 14-year-old LeAnn Rimes, who was named best new artist of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;The Grammys have a big sales impact because it covers all the genres,&quot; said Dick Odette, vice president of merchandising for Musicland Stores Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a lot of exposure, even for the nominees. And if you're a performer on the show, that's even more of an accelerator,&quot; said Odette. &quot;A performance at the Grammys wins at the cash register.&quot;</p>
<p>Indeed, the awards show featured a gospel-oriented medley from the &quot;Waiting to Exhale&quot; soundtrack, performed by Whitney Houston, Mary Blige and Brandy, which showed a spike in sales. Sales of the soundtrack jumped to 8,000 units from 5,000 the week earlier.</p>
<p>Other big beneficiaries was Celine Dion's &quot;Falling Into You&quot;, which won best album of the year. Sales of the album, on Sony Corp.'s 550 Music label, soared to 119,232 from 80,575 units the week before, according to Soundscan.</p>
<p>The album has sold 7.1 million copies since its March 1996 release.</p>
<p>Sony was a big winner among the world's six major labels, boasting victories by Dion, as well as Bennett and rhythm and blues band The Fugees on its Columbia label.</p>
<p>The best song of the year award went to &quot;Change the World&quot; on Time Warner Inc.'s Reprise label by rock legend Eric Clapton.</p>
<p>Sales of &quot;Odelay&quot;, the hit album by alternative artist Beck, who won two Grammys this year, rose to 36,168 units from 18,964.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd expect sales to continue to stay strong based on post-Grammy media interest and exposure,&quot; said Dennis Dennehy, spokesman for Seagram Co.'s  Geffen label, which distributes Beck.</p>
<p>&quot;Beck picked up before the Grammys based on his nomination and then picked up again afterwards,&quot; said Henry Droz, who heads distribution for Seagram's Universal, which includes the Geffen label.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a pickup in overall music sales due to renewed public interest in music,&quot; said Droz. &quot;Aside from Beck, we didn't win that many Grammys, but our business picked up.</p>
<p>&quot;The Grammys always help business, sometimes a great deal and sometimes marginally. I'd call this year average.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
