<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421110" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Radicals press Arafat to halt talks with Israel.</title>
<headline>Radicals press Arafat to halt talks with Israel.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Radical secular and Islamic Palestinian groups urged the Palestinian Authority on Wednesday to suspend peace talks with Israel over its plans to build a new Jewish neighbourhood in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The Islamic Resistance Movement Hamas joined three secular factions opposed to Israeli-PLO peace moves in calling for a protest on Friday against Israeli plans to build 6,500 homes for Jews on Jabal Abu Ghneim, called by Israel Har Homa.</p>
<p>Hamas, the Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine, the Democratic Front for the Liberation of Palestine and the Baghdad-based Arab Liberation Front, said the Palestinian Authority should &quot;stop its negotiations with the Zionist enemy to force it to retract its settlement decisions&quot;.</p>
<p>Israel angered Palestinians last week by approving the new project which completes a circle of Jewish settlements which Israel began building around East Jerusalem and severs the city from the southern part of the West Bank.</p>
<p>Israel captured East Jerusalem along with the West Bank and the Gaza Strip in the 1967 Middle East war. In a move not recognised internationally, it later annexed East Jerusalem, declaring it part of an indivisible capital. Palestinians want East Jerusalem to be the capital of a future state.</p>
<p>Palestinians plan to demonstrate near the pine tree-covered hill on Friday to protest against the settlement project.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat has asked the United States, the U.N. Security Council and the Arab League to pressure Israel to refrain from carrying out the plans but stopped short of suspending peace talks.</p>
<p>Israel is due to carry out the first stage of further redeployment from rural areas in the West Bank later this week.</p>
<p>A Palestinian rights group also called on the Palestinian Authority to suspend peace talks with Israel and seek international arbitration.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the Israeli decision is a blatant violation of the terms of the Israeli-Palestinian agreement, we call upon the Palestinian Authority to immediately stop the negotiations with the Israeli government and...seek international arbitration,&quot; the Palestinian Independent Commission for Citzens' Rights said in a statement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
