<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421362" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss see gold as way out of foreign policy crisis.</title>
<headline>Swiss see gold as way out of foreign policy crisis.</headline>
<byline>Michael Shields</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>In a supreme historical irony, the Swiss on Wednesday held out gold -- the metal that helped bring the weight of world opinion down on them -- as the solution to the country's worst post-war foreign policy crisis.</p>
<p>It was Swiss purchases of gold from Nazi Germany, much of it looted from the lands and people Hitler's legions conquered, that put Switzerland under intense international pressure from critics who accuse it of coolly profiting from World War Two.</p>
<p>Now gold sales from official Swiss reserves are supposed to fund a humanitarian foundation designed to quash once and for all accusations that the Swiss have never made proper amends for their wartime gold purchases and anti-Jewish refugee policy.</p>
<p>Swiss President Arnold Koller announced the plan to a joint session of parliament convened to hear Berne's position on Switzerland's controversial role as financial centre whose economic collaboration was crucial to the Nazi war effort.</p>
<p>The irony of using dusty Swiss gold bars to help the world's downtrodden victims of human rights abuse, war, poverty and genocide was not lost of Switzerland's Jewish community.</p>
<p>&quot;That is what it amounts to, doesn't it,&quot; said Thomas Lyssy, vice president of the Swiss Jewish Federation (SIG), who praised Koller's courage in announcing the plan after months of bitter wrangling over Switzerland's chequered past.</p>
<p>&quot;If you can use Swiss gold for something positive, then you should do it,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Critics said Berne was yielding to foreign pressure, but Swiss officials insisted they were launching the plan -- the brainchild of Swiss National Bank Chairman Hans Meyer -- to underscore Switzerland's humanitarian traditions and their thanks that they escaped two devastating world wars.</p>
<p>&quot;I stress once again that this foundation is an act of free will on the part of our country and that we should therefore give it a broad purpose,&quot; Finance Minister Kaspar Villiger told reporters in Berne.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a big, courageous step. I am convinced this will have a positive impact,&quot; said Rainer Gut, chairman of Credit Suisse Group, one of Switzerland's biggest banks, although he said the problem was not yet gone entirely.</p>
<p>The Swiss National Bank (SNB) has acknowledged buying gold from Nazi Germany between 1939 and 1945 worth 1.2 billion Swiss francs at the time.</p>
<p>Besides using part of its gold stock for the new foundation, the SNB will also contribute 100 million francs ($67.5 million) to a Holocaust memorial fund launched last month by big banks.</p>
<p>The SNB said in December it no longer held any gold bars from Hitler's Reichsbank, but said it had made a profit of around 20 million francs in the transactions with Berlin.</p>
<p>A large part of the German deliveries passed on to other countries in the course of routine gold transactions between central banks during or after the war. The rest was used to help mint coins after the war.</p>
<p>Critics say SNB deals with the Reichsbank allowed Hitler to launder gold stolen from occupied countries and death camp prisoners into clean cash.</p>
<p>SNB Chairman Meyer has said it is difficult to understand today how the bank's World War Two-era directors believed German assurances that their gold was not stolen.</p>
<p>Switzerland bought huge supplies of gold from Germany even when the sales volume flowing to the SNB far outstripped Germany's pre-war holdings. This prompted the Allies to caution Switzerland that Germany was looting gold.</p>
<p>Allied claims to Swiss gold after the war were settled by the 1946 Washington Agreement, which has come under fire for dropping the issue after Berne paid the Allies 250 million francs, then worth about $60 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
