<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421373" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Church joins Belgian towns in anti-Renault drive.</title>
<headline>Church joins Belgian towns in anti-Renault drive.</headline>
<byline>Nieck Ammerlaan</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Belgian backlash against French carmaker Renault's decision to shut a plant near Brussels grew on Wednesday when the church added its voice to the protests, which on Tuesday saw the Interior Ministry suspend and order for 150 cars.</p>
<p>The bishopric of Vlaams-Brabant and Mechelen, in which the affected assembly plant is located, on Wednesday lashed out in a statement against the &quot;overriding principle of profit and competitiveness&quot; motivating such economic decisions.</p>
<p>Renault France said last Thursday, unexpectedly and without consulting the workforce, it would close its assembly plant at Vilvoorde near Brussels with the loss of 3,100 jobs.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene, who lives in Vilvoorde, immediately denounced the decision as unacceptable.</p>
<p>The government said on Monday it would take Renault to court for flouting of European Union and Belgian consultation rules.</p>
<p>&quot;I have a moral responsability too,&quot; Interior Minister Johan Vande Lanotte told Belgian television, commenting on Tuesday's decision to suspend an order for 150 Renault Meganes.</p>
<p>European Commission President Jacques Santer said on Wednesday Renault had not followed the spirit of EU law in how it went about closing the plant. But it was a matter for national governments or unions only to take Renault to court.</p>
<p>The town secretary of Sint-Katelijne-Waver told Belgian radio the town council would send a letter of protest to Renault headquarters in Paris, stop buying Renault cars and urge citizens to do the same.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the town of Brasschaat said, &quot;As long as Renault sticks to this unethical standpoint, we will not buy Renaults anymore and we will let Renault Paris know.&quot;</p>
<p>Spokesman Patrick de Vos of utility Electrabel said that in consultation with local electricity distributors the company was investigating ways of showing solidarity with Renault Vilvoorde staff.</p>
<p>&quot;We are studying attaching conditions to orders. An order will be granted when Renault decides to maintain production in Vilvoorde,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Renaults account for about 17 percent of car fleets at the companies involved.</p>
<p>Jean-Marie Dehousse, mayor of Liege, Belgium's fourth largest city, said in a statement Renault would be excluded from car orders while the closure of Vilvoorde was upheld. Renault supplies Liege's official cars.</p>
<p>The council of Namur on Tuesday decided to take Renault off the list of makers invited to tender for purchases. It called on all public institutions and all Belgians to boycott Renault.</p>
<p>The inhibitants of Vilvoorde observed five minutes silence on Wednesday morning out of solidarity with the Renault workers, some of whom distributed pamphlets during the weekly market.</p>
<p>In addition to the 3,100 jobs lost at Renault Vilvoorde, at least 1,000 jobs at suppliers and subcontractors will disappear.</p>
<p>Renault Paris defended its decision as appropriate and necessary for the survival of the group.</p>
<p>A Belgian newspaper on Tuesday called for boycott of imports from France.</p>
<p>France is Belgium's third largest trading partner in the European Union with 1996 exports to Belgium worth an estimated 505 billion Belgian francs ($14 billion).</p>
<p>Renault sold just under 44,000 cars in Belgium in 1996, after Volkswagen with about 78,500 and Peugeot with some 57,000.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Belgian auto club Automobiel Club VAB said its motorway service cars would patrol Belgian roads carrying a symbolic black flag, but it would not blackball Renault cars.</p>
<p>&quot;We will certainly help Renault drivers, we can't afford to leave those people out in the cold.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
