<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421377" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgium told after fact of Renault plant closure.</title>
<headline>Belgium told after fact of Renault plant closure.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene, fending off French criticism, said on Wednesday French car maker Renault had told him ahead of time of heavy losses and the need for drastic measures, but a decision to close its Belgian plant had reached him after the fact.</p>
<p>In a statement Dehaene said management told him of trouble at Renault on February 21, adding that the closure of the assembly plant at Vilvoorde near Brussels was an option.</p>
<p>Dehaene said that already he then told Renault &quot;this hypothesis&quot; should be ruled out and was totally unacceptable.</p>
<p>On Wednesday February 26 Dehaene was told by the Flemish regional government Renault had decided to close Vilvoorde.</p>
<p>The news was broken to the 3,100 Renault Industrie Belgique workers on February 27 and Dehaene, who lives in Vilvoorde, publicly condemned the decision as unacceptable.</p>
<p>A day later the government complained that Belgian and European Union information and consultation procedures had not been followed and decided to sue Renault.</p>
<p>In a radio interview French Industry Minister Franck Borotra defended Renault, saying the company had informed the French and Belgian governments of the decision to close Vilvoorde a few days before the official announcement.</p>
<p>But later he told parliament there had been gaps in the information supplied by Renault, adding that President Jacques Chirac and Prime Minister Alain Juppe &quot;were not in agreement with the method&quot; Renault used.</p>
<p>Renault chief executive officer Louis Schweitzer was summoned to a meeting with Juppe later on Wednesday afternoon.</p>
<p>The summons reflected an abrupt change in tactics by the French authorities, who had previously avoided criticism of the firm's decision to close the Vilvoorde plant.</p>
<p>It appeared to reflect concern about potential damage to France's image and interests in Belgium and beyond, and about the risk of industrial unrest spreading to France.</p>
<p>-- Nieck Ammerlaan, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6816, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
