<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42142" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain cool on extra Euro-summit.</title>
<headline>Britain cool on extra Euro-summit.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain made clear on Sunday its lack of enthusiasm for an extra European Council scheduled for just days before the ruling Conservative Party, deeply split over Europe, holds its annual conference.</p>
<p>EU foreign ministers, meeting informally in Tralee, Ireland over the weekend, set October 5 as the date for the extra summit, just three days before the Conservative conference.</p>
<p>The Dublin government, which currently holds the rotating EU presidency, had been asked to hold the meeting to review the progress of talks by the inter-governmental conference to discuss a revision of the EU treaty.</p>
<p>The review is supposed to be finished by the middle of next year to streamline the EU for the 21st century and an influx of countries from eastern Europe.</p>
<p>But British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind said he was not &quot;overwhelmed with enthusiasm&quot; at the prospect of an extra EU summit.</p>
<p>Speaking in London during talks with Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy, Rifkind said some of the ministers meeting at Tralee questioned whether the timing of the meeting was entirely appropriate.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very relaxed about it. If there is work to be done, if there are views that could be properly expressed and possible conclusions reached, let's go ahead with it,&quot; he said. But if there is a general consensus that it may not be necessary, I don't think we will lose too many tears.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain's relationship with Europe has opened deep splits in the Conservatives, with Major struggling to maintain party discipline with a parliamentary majority of just one seat.</p>
<p>Major must call a general election by next May and the party conference will be crucial in rallying his forces for a gruelling election campaign.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
