<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421433" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Naga leaders welcome peace talks offer.</title>
<headline>India's Naga leaders welcome peace talks offer.</headline>
<byline>Biswajyoti Das</byline>
<dateline>GUWAHATI, India 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leaders of tribal Nagas in northeastern India on Wednesday welcomed initiatives by Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda to hold peace talks with underground guerrillas to end a decades-old insurgency movement.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope for a workable and acceptable solution to the burning political problem of the Nagas,&quot; A. Makan, a leader of the Naga Tribal Council (NTC), told Reuters by telephone from Kohima, capital of the mountainous state of Nagaland.</p>
<p>The council is said to have links with three outlawed Naga guerrilla groups fighting for a homeland for some 1.5 million ethnic Nagas who live in Nagaland and the neighbouring state of Manipur near the Burmese border.</p>
<p>Deve Gowda told parliament on Tuesday that he had initiated talks with an outlawed Naga insurgent group to restore peace in the region.</p>
<p>He did not give details on his efforts, which he mentioned in the course of a long reply to a debate on national affairs, but appealed to insurgent leaders to hold unconditional talks.</p>
<p>More than 1,000 people have been killed in a five-year-old feud between Nagas and their rival Kukis, who represent tribes that have a history of head-hunting.</p>
<p>Many of the Naga rebel leaders live in self-imposed exile outside India. Naga tribal leaders said Deve Gowda is believed to have met some leaders of the Maoist National Socialist Council of Nagaland (NSCN) during a visit to Switzerland last month.</p>
<p>The NSCN has two factions, while a third group, the Federal Government of Nagaland, is also part of the guerrilla movement.</p>
<p>Yesiuone Yevei, chairman of the Naga Tribal Council, said all three insurgent groups were willing to meet for talks with New Delhi's leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;All the three groups want to share a common platform to pave the way for talks with the Centre (federal government),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>NTC leader Kenito Sema told Reuters: &quot;A message received from the NSCN leaders abroad said there will be political talks and authorised the tribal council to participate in it.&quot;</p>
<p>An Indian intelligence officer in Guwahati said the rebels were forced to accept peace talks after 11 of their top guerrillas were arrested last year by security forces.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUWAHATI, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
