<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421443" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Boeing sees SW Asia spending $16.6bn by 2016.</title>
<headline>Boeing sees SW Asia spending $16.6bn by 2016.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Boeing Co on Wednesday forecast southwest Asian countries will spend $16.6 billion on about 250 new airliners over the next 20 years, with India providing the bulk of the demand.</p>
<p>Dinesh Keskar, president of Boeing India, told a news conference that India would be the major buyer, although the forecast also covered Afghanistan, Bangladesh, Bhutan, Nepal, Pakistan and Sri Lanka.</p>
<p>&quot;My total forecast (for deliveries to the region over the next 20 years) is about 250 aircraft worth about $16 billion,&quot; Keskar said. In a detailed presentation he said the forecast was $16.6 billion.</p>
<p>The U.S. aircraft maker released its global market outlook in Seattle on Tuesday, and predicted the world's airlines will require 16,160 new jets for their fleets, costing $1.1 trillion over the next 20 years.</p>
<p>Elaborating on that report, Keskar said 58 percent of the increase in aircraft deliveries (measured in value terms) to southwest Asia would be accounted for by medium capacity airliners such as the Boeing 767 and 777 series.</p>
<p>There are wide price variations in this category and Keskar did not give the actual numbers of medium-sized airliners he expected to be delivered.</p>
<p>The small-sized aircraft segment, like Boeing's 737 series, will see 29 percent growth in the region, involving the delivery of some 100 new aircraft and expenditure of around $5.0 billion, he said.</p>
<p>Deliveries of large aircraft, like Boeing's 747-400s, to the region will grow 13 percent over the period, involving around 15 aircraft at a cost of $2.0 billion. Boeing expects Air India to be its main regional customer for jumbo-jets.</p>
<p>The aircraft maker expects to maintain close relations with Air India, Indian Airlines and private airlines such as Jet Airways, Sahara India Airlines, SKyline NEPC and Modiluft, Keskar said in press statement.</p>
<p>He said Boeing's 737 was the preferred and only choice of private jet operators in India. It expects its next generation 737-600 to be Indian Airlines' choice to replace its 737-200s.</p>
<p>Keskar also expected the 767 and 777 series to fulfil Indian Airlines' demand for 300-seater planes.</p>
<p>Keskar said he was confident that Air India will opt for the Boeing 777 as its medium capacity long range airplane.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BHUTAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NEPAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
