<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42165" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-AUSTRALIA SEMIS-Market slows, speads to widen.</title>
<headline>RTRS-AUSTRALIA SEMIS-Market slows, speads to widen.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>----------------(CHANGE ON WEEK TO Sept 9)---------------------</p>
<p> TCV			NSW T-CORP	     QTC</p>
<p>OCT 98  7.22 (+0.06) FEB 98  7.07 (+0.04) JUL 99  7.42 (+0.09) NOV 06  8.28 (-0.05) MAY 06  8.28 (-0.05) JUN 05  8.22 (-0.07)  SAFA		     WATC		     TASCOR</p>
<p>MAR 98  7.10</p>
<p>(unch ) APR 98 7.10 (+0.03) MAR 98 7.13 (+0.01)</p>
<p>JAN 03  8.05 (-0.07) JUL 05  8.22 (-0.07) JAN 01  7.87 (+0.13)</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>*Semi government activity quietens down after a couple of busy weeks, and spreads seen widening from here.</p>
<p>*Queensland budget due on Tuesday, Victoria on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Australian semi government securities came under some selling pressure in the later part of last week that saw the spreads to Commonwealth bonds edge out from their lows, traders said.</p>
<p>After a flurry of samurai and Eurobond activity over late August, trade was quieter although still reasonably active. The slowing of offshore issuance and swap related activty had removed some of the support seen for semis, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;After the activity of the last few weeks, it quietened down on Friday and it's quieter again today,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Semis were still generally narrower to Commonwealth bonds over the week, but the narrowest point in terms of spreads appeared to have passed, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Semi spreads were actually a little bit under pressure towards the end of last week again,&quot; a local investment house trader said.</p>
<p>Another spate of samurai activity could give semis renewed impetus to narrow, but with little talk of such issues at present the semis market was looking a bit sidelined and spreads were edging a bit wider.</p>
<p>The dual currency issues of late August had led semi-government spreads to bonds narrow as people bought them to use as cover for swap positions, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Then towards the middle part of last week you actually had most of the long (dated) semis travelling under swap, and in single digits in terms of the margin to bond, and that tended to see a little bit of liability swapping come through and some outright selling from domestic institutions as well,&quot; the investment house trader said.</p>
<p>Traders were not expecting any announcement of tenders this week, with the main news on the semis front being the release of the 1996/97 budgets for Queensland and Victoria on Tuesday and Wednesday respectively.</p>
<p>Lessening the impact of the budgets is the fact that both state borrowing authorities, Queensland Treasury Corporation (QTC) and the Treasury Corporation of Victoria (TCV), have already released their indicative funding requirements.</p>
<p>As well, Victorian forecasts for 1996/97 were contained in the Autumn Economic Statement delivered in May. Accordingly, traders said that they should have little market impact unless there were some major surprises.</p>
<p>While all semi-governments spreads had contracted together, traders said in a period of widening spreads Victorian stock may outperform others, because the government was using funds from privatisation and asset sales to reduce debt and funding needs.</p>
<p>&quot;I think what you tend to find is that with Victorian stocks, with the power stations sales and so forth going through, that it tends to be the other stocks that are under pressure rather than their own,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>----------------(SPREADS TO GOVERNMENT BONDS)--------------</p>
<p> TCV			NSW T-CORP	     QTC</p>
<p> OCT 98  +08  (- 08)  FEB 98  +08 (- 07)   JUL 99  +05 (- 04)</p>
<p> NOV 06  +15  (- 06)  MAY 06  +16 (- 06)   JUN 05  +15 (- 08)</p>
<p> SAFA		     WATC		     TASCOR</p>
<p> MAR 98  +11  (- 11)  APR 98  +11 (- 08)   MAR 98  +14 (- 10)</p>
<p> JAN 03  +09  (- 11)  JUL 05  +14 (- 09)   JAN 01  +26 (+ 06)</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
