<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421843" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bundesbank data shows German economy a bit stronger.</title>
<headline>Bundesbank data shows German economy a bit stronger.</headline>
<byline>Terence Gallagher</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bundesbank data released on Wednesday showed that the German economy was slightly stronger in the fourth quarter than previously believed.</p>
<p>But economists said the picture was still not one of a vigorous recovery -- which would help allay some fears over meeting criteria for a single European currency -- and the outlook for the current quarter remained slack as consumer demand was still subdued.</p>
<p>The central bank statistics showed a rise of 0.1 percent in gross domestic product (GDP) in the fourth quarter of 1996 from the previous quarter and of 2.2 percent from a year earlier. The growth rates were calculated by Reuters from the raw data.</p>
<p>Earlier Bundesbank figures two weeks ago had shown a 0.2 percent decline from the previous quarter and 1.6 percent year-on-year rise.</p>
<p>&quot;These data show the economy was not as weak as we thought. At least now it's not a fall but a marginal rise,&quot; said economist Holger Fahrinkrug at UBS in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>&quot;Still, even these numbers are highly uncertain. Seasonal adjustments are putting a bias on the data. The 2.2 percent in particular looks excessively strong,&quot; Fahrinkrug said.</p>
<p>Federal Statistics Office data on Wednesday put the fourth-quarter year-on-year rise at only 1.9 percent. The main strength of the new Bundesbank data results from downward revisions to earlier figures.</p>
<p>Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt said the flat fourth quarter was not a sign of a renewed period of economic weakness and the government stood by its forecast of 2.5 percent economic growth this year. Most private-sector economists predict lower growth of about 2.0 percent.</p>
<p>Slow growth and rising unemployment are boosting government outlays while cutting tax revenues.</p>
<p>The squeeze fuels fear that Germany might not meet the guidelines to qualify for the planned European single currency, a prospect that could scupper the entire project, scheduled to start in January 1999.</p>
<p>Some economists say the European Union's Maastricht Treaty gives leeway on the guidelines for economic and monetary union (EMU) but German officials have been among the most dogmatic advocates of a strict interpretation.</p>
<p>&quot;With these figures Germany won't meet the EMU criteria perfectly but that is enough for a start of EMU in 1999. With figures that close to the EMU criteria, EMU will go forward,&quot; said Christian Sobotta of LGT Asset Management in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Sobotta sees Germany's budget deficit at 3.1 percent of GDP in 1997, the key year for deciding the initial EMU members.</p>
<p>Many economists believe the economy remains sluggish in the current quarter, as witnessed by labour market weakness and a decline in industrial production in January. Industrial output fell 1.7 percent from December, mainly due to a sharp fall in construction output, the Economics Ministry reported.</p>
<p>But they say the strong dollar should help fuel German exports and reinforce growth starting in the second quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;We may see a flat first quarter. But thereafter we see similar strength as we saw last year, particularly in exports brought on by the weaker mark,&quot; said David Brickman of Yamaichi International.</p>
<p>&quot;But German consumption is particularly weak. That is something that is going to continue and offset the weaker mark,&quot; Brickman said.</p>
<p>Despite the overall sluggishness, economists see almost no chance of the Bundesbank cutting interest rates soon. Price rises have accelerated in recent months and the weakness of the mark is a potential inflationary factor.</p>
<p>&quot;The arguments in favour and against an interest rate decrease balance each other out. For the time being the Bundesbank is likely to continue its steady hand policy,&quot; said Hermann Remsperger of BHF-Bank.</p>
<p>The central bank holds its next policy-making council meeting on Thursday. Also due then are unemployment figures for February which economists expect to show another postwar record of 4.32 million on a seasonally adjusted basis, up about 20,000 from January.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
