<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="421857" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Waigel says progress was made on EMU in 1996.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Waigel says progress was made on EMU in 1996.</headline>
<byline>Terence Gallagher</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel on Wednesday said European nations had made great progress in 1996 toward meeting the guidelines to qualify for monetary union, but more had to be done to get a grip on public finances.</p>
<p>In a report approved by Chancellor Helmut Kohl's cabinet, Waigel said all European Union members except Greece were trying to meet the criteria, and the benefits could already be seen in more stable currencies, lower inflation and interest rates.</p>
<p>But with just one year to go before the decision is made on what countries will participate in European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) at its scheduled start in January 1999, the core problem remained how to reduce public deficits to three percent of economic output, the reference value in the Maastricht Treaty, he said.</p>
<p>Only four of the 15 EU members met that deficit target in 1996: Denmark, Ireland, Luxembourg and the Netherlands, the Finance Ministry report said. Six more countries had deficits under four percent, while the EU average was 4.4 percent.</p>
<p>Germany, whose participation in EMU is seen as indispensible to the success of the endeavour, itself failed to meet the debt and deficit criteria in 1996.</p>
<p>The decision on first-round EMU participants will be based on data for 1997.</p>
<p>The Federal Statistics Office on Wednesday revised downward its estimate of Germany's 1996 deficit to 3.8 percent of GDP from 3.9 percent. Bonn's debt is also about 61 percent of GDP, above the 60 percent target.</p>
<p>Germany is due to report in two weeks to European finance ministers on its progress in meeting the Maastricht goals.</p>
<p>It projects its 1997 deficit at 2.9 percent of GDP, but many economists and some officials in the Bundesbank are openly sceptical it can reach that goal.</p>
<p>European efforts to reduce outstanding government debt in 1996 also were unsatisfactory, the report said.</p>
<p>In a statement commenting on the report, Waigel said, &quot;The (German) government will strictly apply the convergence criteria when the European Council decides in the spring of 1998...what member states fulfil the necessary conditions for the introduction of the euro.&quot;</p>
<p>The report said the council should thoroughly scrutinise all budget data supplied by member states &quot;if there are doubts about the correctness of their compilation&quot;.</p>
<p>Ten countries fulfilled the criteria on inflation and interest rates in 1996, showing the bright side of the sluggish economy.</p>
<p>&quot;The weak economic environment in much of the European Union had a positive influence on inflationary expectations and interest rates, and on public-sector debt service, but it made it more difficult to reduce public deficits,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Increased stability in exchange rates also helped lower the risk premium in interest rates, further easing the debt-service burden in some former high-yield countries such as Portugal, Spain and Italy.</p>
<p>&quot;The assessment of the economic and fiscal policies of these countries on international financial markets has doubtless grown more positive,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>But the resulting influx of capital to these countries also gives rise to concerns about a reverse-flow if they do not maintain the pace of progress, it said.</p>
<p>On currency markets, the formerly weak lira, Swedish crown and Finnish markka became stable against the core-currencies, Germany, France and the Benelux. The peseta and escudo even appreciated, it said.</p>
<p>The British pound, Greek drachma and Swedish crown remain outside the exchange rate mechanism of the European monetary system, participation in which is a prerequisite for joining EMU, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
