<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42191" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Canberra committed to sell one-third Telstra.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Canberra committed to sell one-third Telstra.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Communications Minister Richard Alston said on Monday the government was committed to sell only one-third of state-owned telecommunications carrier Telstra Corp in its first term.</p>
<p>&quot;Our policy position is quite clear,&quot; Alston told parliament's upper house, the Senate. &quot;We are committed to selling one third of Telstra and no more.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;The coalition (government) will offer by way of a share float, if necessary in two tranches depending on market conditions, one-third of the Commonwealth's equity in Telstra,&quot; Alston said.</p>
<p>The government's plan to sell one-third of Telstra for about A$8 billion requires approval by the Senate, where the government does not have a majority.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard's Liberal-National government needs the support of at least two non-government senators to pass legislation.  </p>
<p>The Labor opposition and minor parties holding the Senate balance of power have pledged to vote against the sell-off.</p>
<p>The government hopes to gain the support of the two independent senators, Mal Colston and Brian Harradine.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
