<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="422058" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish bank refuses credit for Gdansk shipyard.</title>
<headline>Polish bank refuses credit for Gdansk shipyard.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's state-owned commercial bank Pekao SA refused to give the Gdansk shipyard a $100 million credit for the construction of five ships for a German owner, saying the terms of the contract were unsatisfactory.</p>
<p>&quot;In our opinion the deadlines for the construction of the ships are too optimistic and their budgets unrealistic,&quot; Pekao SA president Andrzej Dorosz told a news conference on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He said the contract envisaged that the construction of the five ships would have to be done in eight or nine months, while the shipyard's track record showed it usually took 13 months to finish such jobs.</p>
<p>Dorosz also said that fines Gdansk had agreed to pay for breaking the contract deadlines were too large.</p>
<p>Last month a consortium of Polish banks led by Bank Gdanski SA dealt a blow to the bankrupt Gdansk shipyard's struggle for survival by refusing a $100 million credit.</p>
<p>The Baltic coast yard, cradle of the Solidarity trade union which overthrew communism in 1989, was declared bankrupt last year after its debts reached 415 million zlotys ($134.8 million) and banks refused to credit its further operations.</p>
<p>Because the yard still had unfilled orders, part of the shipyard's assets and workforce were hived off to a new, debt-free New Gdansk Shipyard company to complete the contracts.</p>
<p>On January 15 the new yard signed a contract with Germany's Schoeller Holding Ltd for the construction of five container ships worth $27.5 million each, but it still needed to persuade banks to finance their construction.</p>
<p>-- Robert Bogdanski +48 22 653 9700 ($ = 3.079 Polish Zloty)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
