<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="422175" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Sri Lanka monk jailed in Australia for sex crimes.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka monk jailed in Australia for sex crimes.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH, Australia 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Sri Lankan Buddhist monk who sexually assaulted two women seeking spiritual guidance from him in Australia was jailed for four years on Wednesday, after which he will be deported.</p>
<p>Pannasarra Kahatapitiye was found guilty on February 23 of five charges of illegal sexual penetration and six of indecent assault on the two unidentified women aged 27 and 29.</p>
<p>The offences were committed in July and August 1995.</p>
<p>The women had gone to Kahatapitiye's temple in the Western Australia state capital of Perth to ask him to draw astrological charts for them, the court heard.</p>
<p>District court judge Alton Jackson told Kahatapitiye, 53, who had been in Australia on a temporary visitor's visa, that he had disgraced himself and his faith.</p>
<p>&quot;Sexual penetration is an invasion of privacy in the most personal manner, in this case aggravated by your position as a monk,&quot; Jackson said.</p>
<p>&quot;People are entitled to trust men and women of the cloth, and you have breached that trust. You are a disgrace to yourself and the Buddhist order,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
