<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42220" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ's Kiwi Airline says in voluntary liquidation.</title>
<headline>NZ's Kiwi Airline says in voluntary liquidation.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand's no-frills airline, Kiwi International Airlines, said on Monday it was going into voluntary liquidation.  </p>
<p>Kiwi said Auckland chartered accountants Price Waterhouse had been asked to appoint a liquidator to handle the liquidation.</p>
<p>Chief Executive Ewan Wilson said in a statement he was bitterly disappointed.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision to stop flying follows blow after blow after blow to Kiwi, the latest of which was the grounding of the Airbus A320 in Brisbane by (Singapore's) Region Air last weekend,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Wilson said the company and staff had made strenuous efforts to keep Kiwi operating over the past few weeks &quot;but the odds have overwhelmed us&quot;.</p>
<p>He said it would have been irresponsible not to have called in the liquidator.</p>
<p>The airline's 169 staff, already trimmed by 91 redundancies at the end of last month, were advised of the liquidation this afternoon. A small number would be retained to assist with the wind-up.  </p>
<p>Kiwi's Boeing 737, leased from European owners Aviareps/Air Atlanta Icelandic was due to depart to Australia just after an air traffic controllers' strike ended this afternoon.</p>
<p>The flight will not now depart and the plane will be grounded in Christchurch.</p>
<p>Kiwi's other plane, the Airbus A320 leased from Region, was in the air and flying from Brisbane, due to land in New Zealand early afternoon.  </p>
<p>Stranded passengers on both sides of the Tasman Sea would be required to pay an extra NZ$150 one-way fare as part of a deal obtained with Qantas Airways Ltd to help them return home. Other passengers will now become unsecured creditors.  </p>
<p>Kiwi won much publicity by introducing bargain &quot;nuts and cola&quot; class fares.</p>
<p>The two-year old airline headquartered in the central North Island town of Hamilton had been hurt by events such as the grounding of flights due to the volcanic ash cloud from Mount Ruapehu volcano, an air traffic controllers' curfew, fog and mechanical breakdowns.</p>
<p>Last month, it also acknowledged its expansion into Christchurch and Auckland was a mistake.</p>
<p>Kiwi started up from a travel business and expanded to a charter operation.  </p>
<p>Its successful operation prompted Air New Zealand to set up its own budget-charter operation, Freedom Air.</p>
<p>The airline, which booked a $1.2 million profit in its first 10 months of flying, had planned a NZ$15-20 million public float.  Kiwi had planned to eventually compete on domestic trunk routes. -- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
