<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="422263" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea president picks new economic team.</title>
<headline>S.Korea president picks new economic team.</headline>
<byline>Jean Yoon</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean President Kim Young-sam on Wednesday appointed a new finance minister in a sweeping cabinet reshuffle to deflect criticism of his handling of a slumping economy and a loans scandal.</p>
<p>Kim turned to political veteran Kang Kyong-shik, 60, to head the finance ministry and spearhead economic policy amid a severe export downturn in Asia's wounded &quot;tiger&quot; economy.</p>
<p>The president also switched his trade minister and five other ministers.</p>
<p>On Tuesday he replaced his prime minister and last week brought in a new presidential chief of staff along with three other top aides.</p>
<p>Outgoing finance minister Han Seung-soo has taken much of the blame for an economy battered by tumbling world prices for key exports, including computer chips.</p>
<p>He also presided over a banking crisis sparked by the failure of Hanbo Steel Co in a loans-for-kickbacks scandal that has landed three of Kim's closest associates in custody and shredded his image as a graft-buster.</p>
<p>The troubled steelmaker, a unit of Hanbo Group, was declared insolvent on January 23 after piling up $5.8 billion in loans to finance a new steel mill.</p>
<p>Kang served as finance minister in 1982-83 under the presidency of former military strongman Chun Doo Hwan and is currently a lawmaker with the ruling New Korea Party.</p>
<p>&quot;He is a very orthodox and stubborn policy maker,&quot; said Yeo Kyung-ho, head of research at Daewoo Securities, who added that Kang also had a reputation as an anti-corruption reformer.</p>
<p>&quot;I think he is the right person at this time to be in charge of that kind of post.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The reshuffle was carried out to overcome our economic difficulties and cleanse the atmosphere within the cabinet,&quot; a presidential Blue House statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;President Kim has shown his intention to cleanse the government by assigning administrative responsibility for the Hanbo default,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The president appointed Lim Chang-yuel to take over from Ahn Kwang-koo as trade minister.</p>
<p>Other changes included the ministers for Construction and Transportation, Science and Technology, Home Affairs, Justice, Culture and Sports.</p>
<p>The reshuffle was announced after the stock market closed, but the changes were widely anticipated and the leading market index ended the day slightly down.</p>
<p>The Hanbo debacle cast further gloom over an economy reeling from almost a month of wildcat strikes.</p>
<p>It turned public sentiment more firmly against President Kim, whose ruling party faced two key by-elections on Wednesday that will offer the first voter reaction to his sweeping administration changes.</p>
<p>Two seats in the cities of Suwon and Inchon were up for grabs. Initial signs were that turnout was low and voters were unmoved by Kim's efforts to burnish his image.</p>
<p>&quot;The new prime minister seems to be a good choice but I voted for the opposition for the first time,&quot; said shopowner Choi Soon-Young. &quot;The government has done a terrible job.&quot;</p>
<p>Economic analysts said they believed president Kim would not risk dramatic economic changes that could unsettle voters in a presidential election year.</p>
<p>Although Kim is barred by the constitution from seeking a second term, he is eager to be kingmaker.</p>
<p>&quot;Restructuring is unlikely,&quot; said Richard Samuelson, research head at SBC Warburg Securities. &quot;After all the scandals Kim doesn't have much appetite for more confrontation. He will spend a lot of time looking after his wounds.&quot;</p>
<p>Hank Morris, managing director of Coryo Securities, said Kang might try to give a short-term lift to the economy before the election with large infrastructure spending.</p>
<p>&quot;Spending will probably kick in during the summer in an attempt to get growth up before heading into election campaigning,&quot; Morris said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
