<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="422302" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Asian Sugar - China seen buying more cargoes.</title>
<headline>Asian Sugar - China seen buying more cargoes.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>China might buy a few more cargoes of sugar in the near term, and one trading firm was said to be in possession of a sugar cargo and in search of a Chinese buyer, industry sources said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;You may see a few more cargoes soon,&quot; one Hong Kong-based sugar source said.</p>
<p>Another sugar trader in Hong Kong said a trading firm in possession of a cargo of sugar had asked for help in finding a Chinese buyer. No further details were available.</p>
<p>China has bought about four cargoes of Thai sugar since February.</p>
<p>Japanese traders said on Wednesday they were monitoring how many tonnes of Thai raw sugar China would buy for tolling, and premiums were unlikely to ease further from the current level.</p>
<p>Thai raw sugar premiums gained slightly, with premiums for March/May delivery quoted at 0.30/0.45 cents per pound (bid/offer), against 0.25/0.35 cents a week earlier, over New York's Coffee, Sugar and Cocoa Exchange on a free on board (FOB) basis.</p>
<p>May/July deliveries were quoted at 0.30/0.40 cents, and July/September deliveries were at 0.50/no offer.</p>
<p>Traders said that short-covering by a major trade house was behind the slight gains in the March/May premiums.</p>
<p>&quot;If China steps up sugar buying, the premiums will jump upward immediately. I think the premiums are unlikely to drop further,&quot; a sugar trader at a major Japanese trade house said.</p>
<p>But China still held ample sugar stocks, and was expected to be a reluctant buyer until around June, traders said. Trade sources in Bangkok said on Tuesday that China bought another cargo of Thai raw sugar for prompt shipment, and Japan's Mitsui &amp; Co Ltd was one of the suppliers.</p>
<p>But a Mitsui official said they sold raws to a Hong Kong-based trader. &quot;We understand the raw sugar was re-shipped to China later for tolling,&quot; a Mitsui official said.</p>
<p>Japan's raw sugar imports in January totalled 112,212 tonnes, up 28.3 percent from a year earlier, Finance Ministry data released last Friday showed.</p>
<p>Some traders said accelerated buying by local end-users before Japan's consumption tax rises to five percent from three, effective from April 1, was partly behind the higher imports.</p>
<p>Domestic sugar prices in China were inching further up, partly due to earlier government reserve buying and because cane supplies were drying up as China neared the end of its crushing season, sugar sources in Hong Kong and China said.</p>
<p>Domestic sugar ex-factory in the China's southern producing area of Guangxi was heard at 3,950-4,000 yuan ($476-482) per tonne, up from last week's level of about 3,900 yuan a tonne.</p>
<p>China's crushing season would start winding down by the middle of March and cane supplies were already low in some factories, sugar sources said.</p>
<p>Some sugar traders said the domestic price of refined sugar would continue to edge up through March, with one estimate pegging the increase at between 50 and 100 yuan per tonne.</p>
<p>According to one senior sugar source, a one-off sugar buying spree by domestic traders to replenish depleted stocks would help push the price up slightly.</p>
<p>&quot;Each week, about 150,000 tonnes of sugar is sold in China on average, and this amount could go up for a week,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>($1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
<p>-- Mishi Saran in Hong Kong (852) 2843 6358</p>
<p>-- Eiichiro Tokumoto in Tokyo (813) 3432 7391</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100128">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100136">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
