<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="422357" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: London coffee seen up $30-$100 on New York rally.</title>
<headline>London coffee seen up $30-$100 on New York rally.</headline>
<byline>Rene Pastor</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>London robusta futures are seen jumping by between US$30-$100 a tonne later on Wednesday following a blistering overnight rally in New York, although regional coffee dealers said the market should soon peak.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it will be up $30-$40. It's very, very strong,&quot; a senior dealer for a U.S. commodity house told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It's due $100 up,&quot; the coffee dealer for a European trading house said, adding arabica futures in New York are likely to break through the key $2.00 a lb barrier soon on very tight arabica supplies.  </p>
<p>&quot;There simply isn't enough arabica coffee at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>The May contract on the CSCE in New York finished 10.40 U.S. cents up on Tuesday at 195.25 cents a lb.</p>
<p>The benchmark May contract in London could breach the $1,700 a tonne mark and eventually approach the $1,800 level over the next few days, Far East dealers said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, May futures rose to a high of $1,699 before settling at $1,698 a tonne.</p>
<p>But one trader with a Singapore-based commodity house said the strong rally in London may be topping out.</p>
<p>&quot;I really think the market's near the top,&quot; the dealer said.  </p>
<p>Vietnamese coffee prices are taking their cue from the surging international market.</p>
<p>Benchmark Grade 2 coffee, 8.0 percent black and broken, was quoted by regional dealers at around $1,400 a tonne FOB Saigon port, up from last week's $1,200-$1,300 on the same basis.</p>
<p>Indonesia's Grade 4 coffee, 80 defects, was seen by the same traders at between $1,450-$1,600 a tonne FOB Lampung compared with $1,400-$1,450 last week.</p>
<p>Regional traders said reports that Indonesian coffee houses may have bought 6,000 tonnes of Vietnamese coffee for re-export appear to be accurate.  </p>
<p>&quot;The deal would make sense,&quot; one trader said, adding the Indonesians can re-sell the coffee and make a profit considering the current high prices in the international market.</p>
<p>Another trader said he heard that a vessel with a capacity of 5,000 tonnes was recently chartered by Indonesian coffee exporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the report is true,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dealers said Vietnam has sold or committed anywhere from 150,000-200,000 tonnes of its 1996/97 (November/January) robusta coffee crop. Vietnam's 1996/97 coffee crop is estimated to have reached 250,000-270,000 tonnes.  </p>
<p>Regional trade houses said they were conducting their own surveys of the upcoming Indonesian coffee crop and that preliminary estimates of 320,000 tonnes of beans available for export this season remain unchanged.</p>
<p>The robusta coffee contract on the Singapore Commodity Exchange (SICOM) was untraded on Tuesday. Prices of SICOM's March contract were indicated at $1,566 a tonne.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
