<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="422334" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: S.E. Asian cocoa trading contract takes shape.</title>
<headline>S.E. Asian cocoa trading contract takes shape.</headline>
<byline>K.T. Arasu</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southeast Asian cocoa producers are confident their proposed regional trading contract will win global recognition as it would adhere to international standards, a spokesman for the group said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Government and private sector representatives from the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) agreed at a two-day meeting that ended on Wednesday on the need to set up the contract in a bid to reduce dependence on foreign pacts.</p>
<p>&quot;We respect their (Western) contracts and they will respect our contract,&quot; conference chairman Suharyo Husen of Indonesia's Agriculture Ministry told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;The ASEAN contract will adhere to international standards,&quot; he said, adding that there was no reason for Western buyers of cocoa from Southeast Asia to fear the move.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no reason for them (to be afraid),&quot; he said. &quot;Our focus (in the contract) will be quality control and international standards.&quot;</p>
<p>The move to set up the common contract is being spearheaded by Malaysia in a bid to bridge the quality gap among regional cocoa producers and narrow existing price disparities.</p>
<p>Conference delegates said the successful implementation of the contract hinges on the participation of Indonesia and Malaysia, the region's top two producers.</p>
<p>Indonesia has been asked to set up a committee comprising representatives from all ASEAN members -- Brunei, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam -- to study the formation of an arbitration body.</p>
<p>&quot;The expert committee will study the various aspects of the ASEAN contract. It will focus on not only trade but the legal aspects of each country,&quot; Suharyo said.</p>
<p>&quot;The formation of the committee is another step. Before, we were just collecting all the data,&quot; he said, adding that all ASEAN countries were committed to the proposed contract.</p>
<p>Suharyo said the committee would also look into whether cocoa producers from the region should use only the ASEAN contract in their trading or whether it could be an alternative to pacts existing in the London and New York commodity markets.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to know the views of this team...because this is a very sensitive matter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Suharyo said the common contract would help Southeast Asian producers enhance their competitiveness.</p>
<p>&quot;From the point of the producers, the common contract will improve our competitiveness from the quality point of view...and the prices will be higher because demand from the importing countries will be higher,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said higher prices would not necessarily cause foreign buyers to seek new sources as &quot;for the future buyers will look first at quality and then the price&quot;.</p>
<p>He acknowledged that cocoa beans from the key growing region of South Sulawesi faced problems in importing countries over quality. &quot;We will teach and train farmers to improve quality.&quot;</p>
<p>South Sulawesi accounts for nearly 60 percent of Indonesia's total production, which is expected to rise by 10 percent to between 319,000 and 330,000 tonnes this year over 1996.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100144">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
