<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="422409" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan readies law for sanctions on rogue states.</title>
<headline>Japan readies law for sanctions on rogue states.</headline>
<byline>Eugene Moosa</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan will soon adopt a law enabling the government to slap economic sanctions on rogue states even without the backing of U.N. Security Council resolutions, government officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The planned revision of the Foreign Exchange Control Law follows U.S. criticism of Japan's slowness in imposing sanctions against Iraq after its August 1990 invasion of Kuwait, government and Finance Ministry officials said.</p>
<p>The officials said Japan was reminded again of the lack of a legal basis for adopting sanctions without a U.N. resolution in 1994 when Stalinist North Korea went to the brink of triggering a major regional crisis.</p>
<p>North Korea had threatened to pull out of the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty over international inspections of its nuclear facilities.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto's cabinet sent the bill to Japan's parliament on Tuesday, government and Finance Ministry officials said on Wednesday. Parliament is expected to enact it by the end of May, they said.</p>
<p>The proposed revisions would enable the government to halt remittances to and from a foreign country, stop all trade in goods and services with it, and freeze its assets in Japan.</p>
<p>Under the current law, the government is required to wait until the Security Council passes a resolution or the signing of a full-fledged treaty before it can adopt such measures.</p>
<p>&quot;The new law does not mean Japan would unilaterally adopt such sanctions,&quot; one Finance Ministry source said. &quot;It means Japan would be able to quickly join in on international sanctions against a specific foreign country.&quot;</p>
<p>In one case, Iraqi authorities posing as Kuwaiti government officials tried to withdraw Kuwaiti investments from Tokyo in 1990 soon after Iraqi troops invaded Kuwait.</p>
<p>Since there was no law to prevent this, Hashimoto, then the finance minister, in effect stopped the withdrawals by issuing an &quot;administrative guidance&quot; order to banks and other institutions to scrutinise the authenticity of the person trying to make the withdrawals.</p>
<p>&quot;That was an expedient action, the sort of very Japanese thing to do at the time, because there was no other way to prevent such transactions,&quot; the Finance Ministry source said. &quot;Now there will be a law to stop all that.&quot;</p>
<p>The revisions are part of a package of &quot;Big Bang&quot; reforms announced by Hashimoto last November, aimed at deregulatiing Japan's financial markets by 2001.</p>
<p>Currently, Japan maintains economic sanctions against six countries -- Iraq, Libya, Somalia, Liberia, Angola and Rwanda -- all based on U.N. Security Council resolutions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
