<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42248" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - Sept 9.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - Sept 9.</headline>
<text>
<p>DAY'S TOP STORIES</p>
<p>- Former seccessionist warriors of the Moro National Liberation Front (MNLF) will participate as voters and candidates in Monday's historic elections to the Autonomous Region in Moslem Mindanao. (THE MANILA TIMES)</p>
<p>- The National Food Authority on Sunday belied reports they have been selling &quot;rotten&quot; imported rice, amid fears in central Luzon that the rice could lead to poisoning. (THE MANILA TIMES)</p>
<p>- An outbreak of cholera in Metro Manila continues and four people have died of the disease in the past week. (THE MANILA TIMES)</p>
<p>- The Moro Islamic Liberation Front (MILF) foresees an alliance with the communist New Peoples Army and even the extremist Abu Sayyaf in fighting the government. This was disclosed on Sunday by MILF military affairs chief Muhammad Al-Haj Murad and the group's vice-chairman for political affairs Gazzali Jaafar. (TODAY)</p>
<p>- Education secretary Ricardo Gloria appealed to Moslem rebels not to harm public school teachers doing their duties as poll registrars and clerks in the wake of mounting fears that violence could mark Monday's elections to the Autonomous Region in Moslem Mindanao. (TODAY)</p>
<p>- The House of Representatives is scheduled to pass this week the controversial beer and cigarette tax bill. (THE PHILIPPINE STAR)</p>
<p>				 ++++</p>
<p>BUSINESS</p>
<p>- Brother Mike Velarde, head of the evangelist El Shaddai group, has filed an application with the Securities and Exchange Commission for an initial public offering that will raise around 750 million pesos. (MALAYA)</p>
<p>- Solidbank has expressed interest in the privatisation of the state trading firm Philippine International Trading Corp (PITC), a PITC official said. (PHILIPPINE DAILY INQUIRER, MALAYA)</p>
<p>- The government's privatisation programme generated only 4.2 billion pesos, mostly from the sale of Fort Bonifacio properties, from January to June this year compared to 20 billion pesos in the same period last year, according to the Department of Finance. (THE PHILIPPINE JOURNAL)</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8934</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
