<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="422510" id="root" date="1997-03-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: FEATURE - Chongqing, from wartime capital to powerhouse.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Chongqing, from wartime capital to powerhouse.</headline>
<byline>Benjamin Kang Lim</byline>
<dateline>CHONGQING, China 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>This foggy, filthy, teeming city whose name means &quot;Double Jubilation&quot; will have something to celebrate this month when China decides to rank it as a metropolis along with Beijing and Shanghai.</p>
<p>&quot;Chongqing will develop rapidly in the next five years,&quot; Acting Mayor Pu Haiqing said in an interview.</p>
<p>The spark for that development will come this month when the National People's Congress, or parliament, decides at its annual session to ratify a proposal to make Chongqing into China's fourth provincial-rank city.</p>
<p>That means it will report directly to the cabinet, the State Council, instead of to the government of southwestern Sichuan province.</p>
<p>Pu and other city officials are confident the move will boost the political profile of the mega-city, and envisage an economic boom that would narrow the yawning gap between such impoverished inland provinces in the west and their wealthy coastal cousins in the east.</p>
<p>Pu forecast double-digit economic growth annually through the turn of the century.</p>
<p>For years after the communists swept to power in 1949, Chongqing -- wartime capital of the rival Nationalists from 1938 to 1945 -- took a back seat to Chengdu, capital of Sichuan province. That will change.</p>
<p>&quot;Things will become even better...In the past, the province was our boss. Now the party central is our boss,&quot; said Li Chuan, a 25-year-old worker in the city.</p>
<p>Under the move to upgrade Chongqing to become China's fourth municipality, Chongqing's population will double to 30 million and the area under its jurisdiction will more than triple to 80,000 sq km (30,000 sq miles) from 23,000 sq km (9,000 sq miles).</p>
<p>Like its provincial-level cousins -- the capital Beijing, the financial metropolis of Shanghai and the northern port city of Tianjin -- Chongqing will enjoy greater autonomy, a higher profile and attract more domestic and foreign investment.</p>
<p>SHOT IN ARM FOR POVERTY-STRICKEN PROVINCES</p>
<p>Chongqing's economic boom is expected to be a shot in the arm for the nearby poverty-stricken provinces of western China, icluding the Himalayan region of Tibet, the mainly Moslem region of Xinjiang and several other of China's poorest regions.</p>
<p>Already, Chongqing's economy is growing rapidly, with gross domestic product soaring to 117.5 billion yuan ($14.2 billion) in 1996 compared with 74 billion yuan ($8.9 billion) in 1995.</p>
<p>The industrialisation of Chongqing, formerly known as Chungking, took off after the late Nationalist leader Chiang Kai-shek chose the city as China's wartime capital.</p>
<p>Today, Chongqing has almost 10,000 factories employing about 1.2 million people. Industrial output was 72.9 billion yuan ($8.8 billion) in 1996.</p>
<p>The city is one of China's top nine steel makers, with production at 1.54 million tonnes in 1995.</p>
<p>Automobiles and motorcycles are also pillar industries -- ranked fourth nationwide. Motorcycle output totalled 2.19 million units in 1995, accounting for 28 percent of the national total.</p>
<p>CHINA'S DIRTIEST CITY</p>
<p>Chongqing has paid a hefty price for its economic boom and is China's dirtiest city.</p>
<p>&quot;Chongqing is not fit for human beings to live in,&quot; one resident said.</p>
<p>Paint peels off buildings more quickly than almost anywhere else due to acid rain -- providing work to thousands of jobless people who roam the city's streets armed with a can of paint on the lookout for business.</p>
<p>Not every one complains about the dirt spewed out by factories in the most industrialised city of western China -- or from the charcoal stoves of residents trying to heat their homes in winter.</p>
<p>&quot;First we have to keep warm during winter and fill our stomachs,&quot; another resident said when asked if the pollution bothered him.</p>
<p>Chongqing's shoe shiners also do brisk business, and say they polish an average of 600 pairs of shoes a month and rake in about 600 yuan ($72) -- a princely income by average Chinese standards.</p>
<p>Officials say Chongqing is trying to curb pollution, closing some factories to try to clean the air and banning car drivers from blowing their horns to stem the noise.</p>
<p>NO BICYCLES, ARMY OF STICKS</p>
<p>As a municipality, Chongqing will have the power to make its own decisions and handle its own finances without recourse to provincial authorities.</p>
<p>It will also become responsible for helping to resettle about one million villagers who must move to the environs of this port on the Yangtze river to make way for the gigantic Three Gorges dam -- the world's biggest water control project.</p>
<p>Those who are resettled will find a city unlike any other in China. Its hilly terrain means few bicycles ply the streets because they are just too steep.</p>
<p>Instead, Chongqing's streets teem with the &quot;bang bang jun&quot; -- or the army of sticks -- thousands of unemployed from failing factories or surplus farms who carry a pole and a rope and who stand on corners waiting for a chance to transport anything to anywhere.</p>
<p>They trot around the streets carrying merchandise from furniture to fruit.</p>
<p>And they can do it in intense heat. Chongqing is one of China's three &quot;furnaces&quot; -- cities where temperatures exceed 40 Celsius (104 Fahrenheit) in summer. The other two are Wuhan, capital of central Hubei province, and Nanjing, capital of eastern Jiangsu province.</p>
<p>In winter, the army of sticks must wend their way through Chongqing's notorious fog -- now thickened by smog -- that was Chongqing's best weapon against bombings by Japanese military aircraft during World War Two when the city had no air force and only a few anti-aircraft guns.</p>
<p>There is little chance that the parliament will refuse to give Chongqing its chance -- despite rumours that the provincial authorities may be opposed.</p>
<p>&quot;The upgrading of Chongqing will help promote the economic and social development fo the southwest area and the upper reaches of the Yangtze river,&quot; said Premier Li Peng as he presented the proposal to parliament last month. His word counts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHONGQING, China"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
