<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="422786" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BPA says Intertie limits may continue into spring.</title>
<headline>BPA says Intertie limits may continue into spring.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Western Systems Coordinating Council (WSCC) is unlikely to approve a &quot;spring&quot; plan for operating the Pacific Intertie ahead of the expiration of a yet-to-be-finalized &quot;winter&quot; plan, a spokeswoman for the Bonneville Power Administration (BPA) said Thursday.</p>
<p>BPA is meeting with a WSCC study group this week to discuss studies for springtime operation of the interstate power transmission system, but will not present a full report until a later date, she noted.</p>
<p>As a result, &quot;it will probably take some time for the study group to pass on a report to the board,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>A final decision from the WSCC on BPA's winter operating plan is expected later this month, but it will be in effect only through late April.</p>
<p>The winter plan would raise combined capacity of the lines by about 25 percent to 6,250 megawatts (MW) from a current maximum of 5,200 MW.</p>
<p>If a new spring plan has not cleared all necessary hurdles by the time the winter plan expires - and involved parties say that now appears unlikely - Intertie restrictions will revert back to 5,200 MW in late April.</p>
<p>&quot;With the fish flush coming we are kind of surprised by the length of time this is taking,&quot; said the BPA spokeswoman, referring to system operations needed on the Northwest hydroelectric dam system for springtime fish migration.</p>
<p>--D Beasley, Los Angeles bureau + 1 213 955 6761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
