<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="423261" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-PHILIPPOUSSIS, BRUGUERA ADVANCE IN ARIZONA.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-PHILIPPOUSSIS, BRUGUERA ADVANCE IN ARIZONA.</headline>
<dateline>SCOTTSDALE, Arizona 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hard-serving Mark Philippoussis rocketed past Bryan Shelton Wednesday and Sergi Bruguera, after 22 hours of flying, overcame jet lag and Jason Stoltenberg at the $328,000 Arizona men's tennis tournament.</p>
<p>&quot;It's one of those matches where you have to laugh,&quot; said Shelton, the 6-4 6-1 loser who watched 12 aces whiz by, including one clocked at 216 kph (134 mph) during the 55-minute bombing.</p>
<p>&quot;You feel like you just don't have a chance on his serve. I just tried to hold on for dear life. He was just too good tonight.&quot;</p>
<p>Philippoussis, nicknamed &quot;Scud&quot; because of serves that have been clocked as fast as 224 kph (139 mph), displayed the heavy artillery against the 20-year-old American.</p>
<p>The Australian won 24 of 25 first serves and lost just five points overall in eight service games. Shelton had little chance to pull off his second straight upset after ousting MaliVai Washington in the first round.</p>
<p>&quot;You just say, too good and go on,&quot; said Shelton. &quot;This guy has a lot of weapons and he uses them well. When he's playing well he's practically unbeatable.</p>
<p>Philippoussis will next face Byron Black of Zimbabwe, who ousted Australian Sandon Stolle 6-4 5-7 7-5 to follow up his first-round upset of top-seeded Marcelo Rios of Chile Monday.</p>
<p>In other second-round matches, eighth seed Richey Reneberg of the United States spoiled Argentine Hernan Gumy's 25th birthday 2-6 6-1 6-2, and French qualifier Jerome Golmard, ranked 125th in the world, ousted unseeded Ukrainian Andrei Medvedev 7-6 (8-6) 3-6 6-4.</p>
<p>In a first-round match, the travel-weary Bruguera defeated Stoltenberg 0-6 6-4 6-1. &quot;It was tough to move after 22 hours of flying, a nine-hour time change and you don't sleep very well,&quot; said the fatigued two-time French Open winner. &quot;I'm tired.&quot;</p>
<p>After bowing to Croatian Goran Ivanesevic in the Milan indoors final, the Spaniard flew from Milan to Barcelona to Madrid to Atlanta before finally landing in Phoenix on Monday night.</p>
<p>&quot;I got to bed about 11:30, slept for six hours and woke up four different times not knowing what time it was.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't expect too much today in the match going from indorrs to outdoors,&quot; he said. &quot;I've been playing for the last six weeks and been practicing indoors. I had no preparation.&quot;</p>
<p>But after sleep-walking through an opening-set drubbing, Bruguera began to find a rhythm on his brilliant topspin baseline game to level the match. He then rolled on to beat the Australian, improvng to 13-6 on the year.</p>
<p>Once as high as third in the world rankings, Bruguera slipped badly after tearing two ligaments in his right ankle in December of 1995. Currently, he is ranked 34th, an improvement of 47 spots in just three months.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year, it's true I had a tough time but I won the silver medal in the Olympics,&quot; he said. &quot;You can't take that away from me.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SCOTTSDALE, Arizona"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
