<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="423389" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reuters historical calendar - March 13.</title>
<headline>Reuters historical calendar - March 13.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the major events to have occurred on March 13 in history.</p>
<p>1569 - In the Third French Religious War, the Huguenots under Prince de Conde were defeated by the Catholics at the Battle of Jarnac. Conde died in the battle.</p>
<p>1781 - The German-born English astronomer Sir William Herschel discovered the planet Georgium Sidus, later known as Uranus.</p>
<p>1809 - King Gustavus IV of Sweden was overthrown in a coup d'etat and was succeeded by his uncle Charles XIII.</p>
<p>1813 - Sweden joined the Grand Alliance against Napoleon and his allies.</p>
<p>1848 - After demonstrations and riots in Vienna, Prince Metternich resigned as Chancellor.</p>
<p>1858 - Felice Orsini, Italian revolutionary, was executed for his part in the assassination attempt on Napoleon III of France.</p>
<p>1860 - Hugo Wolf, Austrian composer, born. Best known for his books of songs, notably &quot;Spanish Song Booe Song Book&quot;.</p>
<p>1865 - In the U.S., the Confederate Congress under President Jefferson Davis signed a bill allowing slaves to join the army in exchange for freedom.</p>
<p>1881 - Tsar Alexander II of Russia, hours after agreeing to call an assembly of Nobles, died after a bomb was thrown at him near the Winter Palace.</p>
<p>1900 - The British under Lord Frederick Roberts captured Bloemfontein in the Boer War.</p>
<p>1901 - Benjamin Harrison, 23rd president of the United States, died; he was the only president to succeed and be succeeded by the same man -- Grover Cleveland.</p>
<p>1915 - In World War One, the British under Haig were denied a breakthrough at the end of the Battle of Neuve-Chappelle. The Germans under Von Falkenhayn rushed more troops in and prevented a British advance.</p>
<p>1928 - The St. Francis dam 40 miles north of Los Angeles burst and flooded the valley; at least 450 people were drowned.</p>
<p>1938 - In Austria, Chancellor Seyss-Inquart introdued a law re-unifying Austria with the German Reich.</p>
<p>1938 - In France, Leon Blum became prime minister and formed the Popular Front ministry.</p>
<p>1940 - Hostilities between Russia and Finland ceased at noon.</p>
<p>1972 - Britain and China resumed full diplomatic relations after 22 years; Britain withdrew its consulate from Taiwan.</p>
<p>1972 - Clifford Irving admitted to a New York court that he had fabricated his autobiography of Howard Hughes, thus defrauding his publisher McGraw Hill.</p>
<p>1974 - The Charles de Gaulle airport in Paris was inaugurated.</p>
<p>1990 - The Soviet parliament voted to end the political monolopy of the Communist Party after 72 years.</p>
<p>1992 - Pravda, founded in 1912 by Lenin and official newspaper of the Soviet Communist Party, ceased publication due to lack of funds.</p>
<p>1995 - General Olusegun Obasanjo, the only Nigerian military ruler to have voluntarily handed over power to elected civilians, was arrested.</p>
<p>1995 - Odette Hallowes, one of Britain's war heroines, died. She became the first woman to be awarded the George Cross for gallantry for her work in occupied France in World War Two.</p>
<p>1995 - The U.N. social summit ended with 182 countries pledging to wipe out global poverty.</p>
<p>1996 - A man with four guns shot dead 16 children and a woman teacher in a &quot;slaughter of the innocents&quot; at a school in Dunblane, Scotland. He then turned a gun on himself.</p>
<p>1996 - Krzysztof Kieslowski, Polish film director, died. Famed for his &quot;Decalogue&quot; - ten films on the Ten Commandments - and his &quot;Three Colours&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
