<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="423382" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Dynamic Dow drives eurobourses, dlr dominant.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Dynamic Dow drives eurobourses, dlr dominant.</headline>
<byline>Peter Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>European bourses closed at record levels on Thursday boosted by another hike in the Dow and the dollar broke through the 1.72 mark level for the first time since spring 1994.</p>
<p>London, Paris, Frankfurt and several other European stock exchanges all scored new closing highs after bullish Wall Street opened in positive territory. It had put on about half a percent by the time most european bourses closed. Europe started the day jolted higher by an overnight 93-point rally in New York.</p>
<p>London's blue chip FTSE 100 index broke through 4,400 points for the first time and ended only just off that peak. Frankfurt had already ended floor trading up more than 50 points after chalking up a new record trading high of 3,426.54 points and Paris closed around 1.2 percent higher.</p>
<p>On the currency front, the dollar continued to defy gravity, quickly shrugging off a slightly stronger-than expected German employment report and rallying again to touch a fresh 34-month peak at 1.7202 marks before dopping back slightly.</p>
<p>Analysts said the German data did not have a great impact as it was sufficiently close to expectations for a bullish dollar market to take in its stride. But it still served to underline weaknesses in the German economy compared to the United States.</p>
<p>The initial cause of the day's bourse bonhomie were the latest comments by U.S. Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan, whose utterances and nuances are meticulously analysed for clues to credit policy.</p>
<p>Having earlier plunged equity markets into despair with perceived warnings that stocks are overvalued, Greenspan on Wednesday reversed some of the damage in statements to a congressional committee.</p>
<p>Instead of repeating last week's comment that Wall Street's ascent &quot;raised questions of sustainability&quot;, he said he did not believe in using monetary policy as a tool to influence share prices. This was interpreted as indicating the Fed would not hike rates simply to lasso the Wall Street bull.</p>
<p>The Dow powered ahead on his comments to end Wednesday 93.13 points higher at 6,946.</p>
<p>The blue chip FTSE 100 index has risen around 280 points or seven percent since the start of the year.</p>
<p>Of six leading corporates to announce annual results on Thursday, the market reacted positively to four.</p>
<p>Rolls-Royce Plc powered ahead after revealing its full-year figures. Profit figures also boosted betting and hotels firm Ladbroke Group Plc, industrial conglomerate BTR Plc and engineering group GKN Plc.</p>
<p>Pharmaceutical giant Glaxo Wellcome Plc headed lower after its results announcement, however, and Royal &amp; Sun Alliance Insurance Group Plc also lost ground after initially gaining on its results.</p>
<p>In Frankfurt German shares ended bourse trade at a new closing high but off session highs reached on the back of overnight Wall Street gains and the firmer dollar which, at around 1.72 marks, is positive for German exports. The DAX index reached a new record trading high at 3,426.54 points before slipping on profit-taking after the index rose more than 200 points in last two sessions.</p>
<p>And in Paris, France's CAC-40 index of leading shares also ended at a record closing level. Dealers said the bullish trend was supported by strong liquidity and favourable corporate results.</p>
<p>&quot;This sharp rise is certainly due to Wall Street and the dollar but also to Mr. Greenspan who reassured markets,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>French insurance company  AG was up strongly  amid renewed speculation about its future as a possible takeover target. But shares in carmaker Renault tumbled further as fallout continued from planned layoffs in Belgium and France.</p>
<p>German unemployment was a main focus of the currency markets. The adjusted total was in line with the 4.672 million leaked by German labour market sources on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Analysts said that while the mark may glean some support from the fact the higher number of jobless was not as bad as some recent newspaper speculation, the unemployment trend remained gloomy in contrast with the U.S. labour market.</p>
<p>The market is now eagerly awaiting U.S. February employment figures, due at 1330 GMT on Friday. Analysts polled by Reuters expect a 230,000 rise in non-farm payrolls during the month. The jobless rate is seen edging down to 5.3 percent from 5.4.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1645 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was quoted around 1.7168 marks and 121.20 yen, compared with 1.7128 and 121.56 late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS CLOSING INDICES</p>
<p>LONDON - The FTSE-100 index closed up 39.2  points, or 0.9 percent, at 4,399.3.</p>
<p>PARIS - The CAC-40 closed up 32.73, or 1.23 percent, to 2,698.92</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - The 30-share DAX index closed up 52.6, or 1.56 percent, at 3417.6</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold closed at $352.20, down from its London close on Wednesday of 352.65.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
