<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="423424" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: European physicals slow, March needs covered.</title>
<headline>European physicals slow, March needs covered.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>European base metal physical business continued to run at a low ebb, with most users having covered their requirements for this month, traders said on Thursday.</p>
<p>In some cases the ongoing high prices on the London Metal Exchange (LME) deterred all but essential hand-to-month buying.</p>
<p>But currency factors, notably for Continental users, were also restricting interest, with enquiries often resulting in no business being booked, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;German consumers have a problem because in mark terms tin is around 10.00 marks/kilo, which they see as high,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>That meant the residual 10 percent of business not tied up in long-term contracts and usually done on the spot market was just not taking place at present.</p>
<p>Spot premiums for tin remained around $30/40 for Chinese and Indonesian metal.</p>
<p>Similar conditions were seen in aluminium, where recent rises on the LME have stifled spot interest, but premiums remained fully steady, aluminium traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the start of March the physical market has gone very quiet,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>But looking ahead, premiums could well push up some $10 towards the latter half of March, due to covering against April positions.</p>
<p>Traders said there was very little Russian off-grade aluminium in Europe, with this metal largely moving across the Atlantic to take advantage of high U.S. spot premiums.</p>
<p>Russian A6 and A5 aluminium was indicated around $25/35 and $20/30 premium respectively.</p>
<p>Copper physicals continued slow, with the nearby contango and a narrower overall backwardation not yet prompting trade.</p>
<p>&quot;It is almost as if people do not expect it (the cash/March contango) to last,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Western cathodes continued to hold around $20/30 premium, while Russian discounts remained some $20/30.</p>
<p>--Martin Hayes, London Newsroom 44 171 542 8080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
