<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="423562" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Rebels not invited to East Zaire summit March 19.</title>
<headline>Rebels not invited to East Zaire summit March 19.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Kotch</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenya will host a summit on the conflict in eastern Zaire on March 19 but rebel leader Laurent Kabila is not invited, the Foreign Ministry said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Spokesman David Kikaya said Kenya had asked Zaire's ailing president, Mobutu Sese Seko, to attend the one-day talks with South Africa's Nelson Mandela and five other African heads of state.</p>
<p>&quot;The purpose of the summit is to advance the search for peace and a lasting solution in eastern Zaire,&quot; Kikaya told Reuters.</p>
<p>Kabila's rebels now control about a sixth of Africa's third-largest country and are closing in on Kisangani, headquarters in the east of Zaire's demoralised army.</p>
<p>With no sign that government troops have the will to resist, regional and Western diplomats predict further rebel successes and a high risk of &quot;Liberianisation&quot; of Zaire -- a breakup into mainly ethnic fiefdoms.</p>
<p>Kabila's Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire (ADFL) says it opposes the disintegration of the country and wants Mobutu to relinquish power peacefully to end the fighting.</p>
<p>Kabila's search for international recognition was crowned in Johannesburg on February 26 when he had an hour of talks with Mandela, his first public meeting with a head of state since he launched the rebellion last October.</p>
<p>Asked why Kabila was not invited to the Nairobi talks, Kikaya said the meeting was a summit of heads of state.</p>
<p>On Tuesday Kabila told reporters at his headquarters in Goma that he was not willing to meet Mobutu in Kenya because President Daniel arap Moi favoured the Zairean president.</p>
<p>Moi called on February 21 for a major African summit to be held in Nairobi on March 12. Later, Mandela announced he would meet Mobutu on March 19, either in Nairobi or the Zairean president's palace at Gbadolite.</p>
<p>&quot;The two summits have been amalgamated into the one here on the 19th,&quot; Kikaya said.</p>
<p>After his meeting with Mandela, Kabila said direct talks between the rebels and Mobutu were close but rejected a ceasefire before negotiations, as requested by a U.N. Security Council resolution on February 18.</p>
<p>Mobutu has led Zaire since 1965 but has spent most of the past eight months in Europe for prostate cancer treatment. He is currently in France and his attendance at the Nairobi summit is uncertain.</p>
<p>&quot;We have invited the president of Zaire but whether he comes in person is at his discretion,&quot; Kikaya said.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the presidents of Cameroon, Congo, Tanzania and Zimbabwe and the secretary-general of the Organisation of African Unity had also been invited by Moi.</p>
<p>The group excludes Rwanda and Uganda, Kabila's main regional supporters. Zaire accuses both countries of having troops with the rebels and the Security Council resolution lent weight to the accusation by calling for the withdrawal of all foreign forces in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>Zaire's government has said it will not attend another summit until foreign forces have left its soil and international monitors have supervised the withdrawal.</p>
<p>If Zaire maintains that position, the Nairobi summit would be held without either of the warring parties, sharply diminishing its utility.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
