<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="423648" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish prime minister calms spy scare.</title>
<headline>Polish prime minister calms spy scare.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz told parliament on Thursday not to get too alarmed about foreign secret agents trying to block Poland's path to NATO, playing down concerns raised by a fellow minister.</p>
<p>&quot;We should neither underestimate the dangers which could result from the actions of foreign services in Poland, especially before our entry into NATO, nor accord these dangers an exaggerated, even diabolical significance,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In a newspaper interview last month the minister in charge of security, Zbigniew Siemiatkowski, alleged Russian intelligence was preparing plans to try to discredit Poland and block its entry to NATO and the European Union.</p>
<p>These comments were political dynamite in a country whose previous prime minister Jozef Oleksy had to quit in early 1996 over security service allegations, which he denies, that he had informed for Russian agents.</p>
<p>Prosecutors later dropped their probe saying the evidence against Oleksy was too weak.</p>
<p>Parliamentarians demanded that Cimoszewicz, the ultimate head of the security service and, like Oleksy an ex-communist, give a full account of the dangers mentioned by Siemiatkowski.</p>
<p>Some demanded that he fire Siemiatkowski if the minister's alarming remarks were not substantiated.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz, careful to reveal no secrets, said Siemiatkowski had been speaking of potential dangers and his comments were based on facts.</p>
<p>He said the Polish security services knew what they were doing, adding: &quot;I assure the house that this situation is under control,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Poland expects, along with at least the Czech Republic and Hungary, to enter the Western pact in 1999, but Russian politicians have denounced NATO's planned inclusion of neighbouring Poland as a threat to its security.</p>
<p>An opinion poll published on Saturday showed that some two thirds of Poles believed their country's political and economic life is influenced by foreign intelligence services.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
