<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="423890" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - Mar 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - Mar 7.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE DOMINION</p>
<p>John Banks threatened to quit the Coalition Government unless Prime Minister Jim Bolger &quot;sorted out&quot; his deputy Winston Peters over a late-night fracas in Parliament. Banks said on Thursday that Peters had grabbed, shaken and threatened him outside the debating chamber on Wednesday night, and he had feared Peters would &quot;king-hit&quot; him. His version of events was backed by Alliance leader Jim Anderton, who saw the incident. Anderton has asked Speaker Doug Kidd to refer the incident to Parliament's privileges committee. ACT NZ leader Richard Prebble has also laid a complaint. Page 1.  </p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Legal action is being taken over the distribution by Labour MP Trevor Mallard of a tape that he says raises questions about NZ First MP Tukoroirangi Morgan's financial involvement with Aotearoa Television Network. Mallard said the 52-minute tape, left annonymously on his parliamentary desk on Wednesday, appeared to record a February 5 conversation between ATN director Morehu McDonald and shareholder and executive, Eric McPhee. Page 2.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>National MPs have been chosen to chair all but two of the 12 parliamentary select committees that met for the first time on Thursday. The two exceptions are ACT NZ MP Derek Quigley, who was elected to chair the foreign affairs, defence and trade committee, and New Zealand First MP Rana Waitai, who will chair the justice and law reform committee. Wrangling between government, Labour and Alliance MPs prevented the committees being established till this week. Page 2.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Brierley Investments has been hit hard by a loss at Australian retailer Vox and a much lower contribution from Air New Zealand -- pushing BIL's half-year profit to December 31 down 32 percent to $116.14 million after tax. Chief executive Paul Collins said the $24 million reduced contribution from Air New Zealand, in which BIL has a 42 percent stake, had a significant effect on the result, as did the A$13.9 million (NZ$15.4 million) loss from Australian Vox Retail Group. Page 19.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Brierley Investments on Thursday dispelled any notion that the company's 20 percent stake in Australian publisher John Fairfax was anything other than a long-term investment. The fairfax holding was bought for $503 million in December and now had a market value of $544 million. Page 19.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Rural services company Wrightson's half-year profit was slumped 78 percent to $1.25 million, knocked by a tough trading environment, extra restructuring costs and a loss on the sale of its bloodstock arm. Wrightson cut its interim dividend to 2.5 cents an ordinary share, down one cent from the previous half-year and halved its full-year profit forecast as a result. Page 19.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Taranki baker Yarrows has won a multi-million-dollar deal to supply a worldwide food chain. The company's Manaia factory will supply dough products to American-based sandwich giant Subway. Subway has more than 14,000 stores worldwide. Yarrows will supply dough, bread, cookies, muffins and pastries to Subway outlets in New Zealand, Australia, Singapore, Indonesia, Malaysia and Japan. Page 19.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Consumers were being used as &quot;money trees&quot; by electricity companies, Consumer Coalition on Energy spokesman David Murray said on Thursday. The coalition said household electricity prices have risen every quarter since 1991, far outstripping the consumers price index. But the arguments were rejected as &quot;narrow&quot; and &quot;spurious&quot; by Electricity Supply Association head Barrie Leay. Page 20.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Telecom has sweetened its offer to other telephone companies on the contentious issue of number portability. The inability of customers to take their numbers when they switch phone companies, but remain within the same free-calling area, is seen as a barrier to competition. Last December Telecom put a proposal to Clear Communications, BellSouth and Telstra, under which there would be an up-front charge of $30 when a customer switched networks, and then a charge of 0.7 cents a minute when calls were rerouted to another network. Telecom confirmed on Thursday that it had dropped the proposed per-minute charge to 0.5 cents. Page 20.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
