<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42386" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Southern Philippine polls peaceful - Misuari.</title>
<headline>Southern Philippine polls peaceful - Misuari.</headline>
<dateline>ZAMBOANGA, Philippines 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine rebel leader Nur Misuari formally entered mainstream political life on Monday by voting in elections where he is the sole candidate for the governorship of a Moslem autonomous regional government.</p>
<p>The former university professor turned revolutionary is running for the governorship of the Autonomous Region of Moslem Mindanao (ARMM), which covers just four southern provinces.</p>
<p>As the only candidate for governor, all Misuari needs is one vote -- either his own or that of one of his two wives -- to claim victory in the elections, poll officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;This vote symbolises our commitment to peace, democracy and progress for our people here in Mindanao and eventually for the entire country,&quot; said Misuari, who signed a peace deal with the government last week ending a 24-year separatist war in the southern Philippines.</p>
<p>In a live nationwide broadcast, Philippine television showed Misuari casting his ballot at a school in his home town of Jolo on the island of Sulu.</p>
<p>Misuari said he believed the elections would be the most peaceful in Philippine history and said there had been no trouble even in areas notorious for violence.</p>
<p>&quot;So far, some of the most volatile areas have proven to be very, very peaceful,&quot; Misuari told reporters.</p>
<p>It was expected to take a week for Manila to ratify the election results, one official said. Also at stake are the post of vice governor and all seats in a 21-member regional legislative assembly.</p>
<p>Under his peace deal with Manila, Misuari will also head a Southern Philippine Council for Peace and Development covering the whole of the main southern island of Mindanao and nearby islands.</p>
<p>The council, bitterly opposed by some southern Philippine Christians, is envisaged as the precursor of a much wider autonomous regional government covering 14 provinces on the main southern island of Mindanao and adjacent islands.</p>
<p>Misuari and the Moro National Liberation Front which he heads had previously refused to have anything to do with the ARMM, denouncing it as a sham.</p>
<p>But he agreed to stand for election now to demonstrate his administrative skills and to reassure Christians.</p>
<p>Many Christians have opposed the deal, fearing it would lead to MNLF political ascendancy in a region Moslems regard as their ancestral homeland but in which Christian settlers now dominate by a ratio of three to one.</p>
<p>Christian vigilante groups have been formed to oppose the pact by violence, but military officials dismiss them as insignificant.</p>
<p>The election will complete the return to the government fold of the quietly-spoken, low-key Misuari who launched a bloody revolt for Moslem self-rule in the Mindanao region in 1972.</p>
<p>The uprising cost more than 120,000 lives.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAMBOANGA, Philippines"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
