<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="423967" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korean stock market roiled by takeover frenzy.</title>
<headline>S.Korean stock market roiled by takeover frenzy.</headline>
<byline>Yeom Yoon-jeong</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two South Korean companies revealed on Thursday they were considering a grab for a leading department store chain in what would be the first major hostile takeover on the stock market.</p>
<p>The Midopa Department Store chain operates a flagship store in Seoul's most fashionable shopping district and has smaller branches elsewhere in the capital and other cities.</p>
<p>There had been rumours for months that South Korea's largest edible oil company was planning a corporate raid on the chain to get into the distribution business.</p>
<p>The rumours have sent Midopa's share price rocketing from a year low of 7,060 won ($8.14) to a high of 47,500 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Shindongbang Corp had denied the market talk, but on Thursday told the Korea Stock Exchange it was considering a takeover through a public tender offer.</p>
<p>Hours later, Korea Industrial Co stunned the market by announcing it too was thinking of making a similar bid for the retailer.</p>
<p>In a further twist, the president of Korea Industrial is a younger brother of the president of Shindongbang.</p>
<p>Hostile takeovers are virtually unheard of in South Korea, partly because they are considered unethical. Friendly takeovers through private contact with the owners have been the only real option.</p>
<p>However, predatory mergers and acquisitions are expected after the government implements new rules in April.</p>
<p>Takeovers will still not be easy. Under the new regulations, individuals or companies wanting to take over a firm must buy a controlling stake through a tender offer at the highest price reached by the targeted company's shares in the previous 12 months.</p>
<p>A 10 percent ceiling on individual stock holdings in listed companies, which previously made takeovers all but impossible, was lifted in January.</p>
<p>That has given a window of opportunity to would-be raiders before April.</p>
<p>&quot;As merger and acquisition rules will be stricter than expected, corporate raiders will try to complete their deals before April,&quot; said a securities watchdog official.</p>
<p>Traders speculated that Korea Industrial, an animal feed maker, was working with Shindongbang on the takeover.</p>
<p>But Shindongbang denied this.</p>
<p>&quot;The two companies are totally different enterprises and they have not negotiated any such deal,&quot; chief spokesman Yoo Seung-kwan said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;As we announced today, we will soon decide whether to buy a stake in Midopa or not.&quot;</p>
<p>Shares in Dainong Corp, Midopa's parent, went limit down to 10,100 won ($11.64).</p>
<p>&quot;We will closely watch the developments as 'consideration' doesn't mean they have decided on a hostile takeover,&quot; Park Sang-chul, managing director of Dainong Corp, said by telephone.</p>
<p>Analysts said Midopa would be an easy backdoor entry for Shindongbang into the lucrative distribution trade.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be much cheaper rather than starting a business from scratch, said Kim Min-tae, senior economist at LG Research and Economic Institute.</p>
<p>Greta Park, retail analyst at ING-Barings, said: &quot;If Shindongbang really has the intention to get into the retail business, this may be good news for Midopa.&quot;</p>
<p>Midopa closed 3,600 won down on Thursday at 41,500 won.</p>
<p>(Conversion $1 = 867.50)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
