<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="423987" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: South Africa's Mandela said seeking Malaysian oil.</title>
<headline>South Africa's Mandela said seeking Malaysian oil.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African President Nelson Mandela arrived in Malaysia on Thursday on the final leg of a four-nation Southeast Asian tour and is expected to ask Kuala Lumpur for oil.</p>
<p>Mandela, travelling with companion Graca Machel for the first time on a state visit, was received at the airport by Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad.</p>
<p>In addition to Machel, the widow of former Mozambique president Samora Machel, Mandela has brought with him a 115-member delegation of ministers, officials and businessmen.</p>
<p>South African Minerals and Energy Minister Penuell Maduna said in Singapore earlier on Thursday Pretoria would ask Malaysia to export crude oil.</p>
<p>He said he hoped talks with Malaysia would also open up additional possibilities for investment in South Africa's next oil refinery project.</p>
<p>Malaysia became the fourth-largest investor in South Africa last year -- behind more traditional partners Britain, Germany and the United States -- when the state oil firm Petronas bought 30 percent of listed South African company, Engen Oil.</p>
<p>In a speech at the end of his two-day visit in Singapore on Thursday, Mandela issued a passionate appeal to Asia to see southern Africa as a lucrative place in which to invest and a &quot;geographical anchor&quot; for trade with South America.</p>
<p>&quot;Southern Africa today constitutes one of the most exciting regions of the world; a region endowed with abundant mineral resources, a market of over 100 million people, great tourist potential, democracy and peace,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This region has the potential to be the geographic anchor of new relations among Asia, Africa and Latin America.&quot;</p>
<p>Mandela said he wanted to rebuild cultural and trade ties between two regions he said had been destroyed by European colonisation of Africa.</p>
<p>Mandela urged Asian investors to hurry to South Africa, where economic reforms had opened up &quot;massive mega-projects in mineral processing, petrochemical industries, telecommunications, car manufacturing, tourism, transportation and other infrastructure&quot;.</p>
<p>There were &quot;opportunities for large profit margins, the advantage of a sophisticated banking system, the availability of a developed communications network, the freedom to repatriate profits and the advantage of tax holidays in certain designated areas,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mandela, who has been to the Philippines, Brunei and Singapore on this tour, will meet Mahathir on Friday. They will also witness the signing of several agreements.</p>
<p>Malaysia established diplomatic relations with South Africa in November 1993 after the dismantling of apartheid and has been supportive of Mandela's national unity government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
