<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42397" id="root" date="1996-09-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: BTR sells Taiwan assets for T$2.7 bln - buyers.</title>
<headline>BTR sells Taiwan assets for T$2.7 bln - buyers.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Industrial conglomerate BTR Plc has sold off its majority stakes in Taiwan's Taita Chemical, Asia Polymer and China General Plastics, buyers of the shares said on Monday.  </p>
<p>The transactions, executed in contracts signed on Saturday, raised T$2.707 billion, the purchasing companies said in a mandatory notification to Taiwan's stock exchange. A copy of the notification was provided to Reuters.</p>
<p>The buyers identified themselves in the statement as Taiwan petrochemical firms Union Petrochemical and USI Far East.  </p>
<p>The reported value of the transactions was significantly smaller than the US$300 million that local Taiwan media, in reports on Monday, said the deal would raise.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for USI Far East confirmed that the total deal was worth US$300 million, explaining that the T$2.7 billion, or about US$98 million, comprised only the buyers' self-financed capital outlays.</p>
<p>&quot;The T$2.7 billion is self-owned capital. We will seek bank loans to complete the total US$300 million purchase price,&quot; said spokeswoman Chu Shu-yun.</p>
<p>The transactions would be completed by the end of 1996.  </p>
<p>BTR had held controlling 51 percent stakes in Taita and Asia Polymer and a 31 percent stake in China General Plastics, the notification said.</p>
<p>Taiwan media said BTR's effective stake in General Plastics was also 51 percent, with the balance held through affiliates.</p>
<p>In London, the Sunday Telegraph newspaper said on Sunday that BTR's new chief executive officer, Ian Strachan, would announce a selloff of Taiwan assets on Monday in a bid to raise two billion stg before 1998 by selling non-core businesses.</p>
<p>The London report said the sale of Taita Chemical, a polymer producer, would raise 200 million stg.  </p>
<p>Strachan would also announce the results of an internal strategic review, with BTR expected to be reorganised into six or seven divisions, the Sunday Telegraph said.</p>
<p>These will be based on its main product groups and will each be headed by executives.</p>
<p>The Sunday Telegraph said Strachan was expected to say BTR would concentrate on sales growth rather than improving profit margin and the 2.0 billion stg from disposals will be invested in capital expenditure and &quot;in-fill acquisitions&quot; to give businesses a global dimension.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25140">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I48100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
