<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424075" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Move grows to ban federal funds for aided suicide.</title>
<headline>Move grows to ban federal funds for aided suicide.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Religious and medical leaders Thursday asked Congress to ensure that federal funds were not used to pay for physician-assisted suicide, pulling lawmakers into an emotional debate over the right to die.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court in January heard arguments in a historic case regarding proposals to create a constitutional right for the terminally ill get to help in committing suicide. A decision is expected by late June.</p>
<p>Advocates are fighting legal battles to overturn bans on assisted suicide in some states. Oregon voters have approved physician-aided suicide, although the law has been tied up in the courts.</p>
<p>Oregon state officials in the past have raised the prospect of using federal Medicaid health care funds to carry out the law.</p>
<p>&quot;Federal health programmes are designed to support and enhance life, not destroy it,&quot; Cardinal Bernard Law, archbishop of Boston, said in testimony prepared for a House Commerce subcommittee hearing.</p>
<p>&quot;The rich and hallowed virtue of compassion is drained of meaning when it is invoked as a basis for destroying human life,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Law and others testifying against federal funding and to the overall idea of assisted suicide warned that the disabled and elderly could be pressured into ending their lives against their will.</p>
<p>An official of the 25,000-member Hemlock Society said her group tried unsuccessfuly to be allowed to attend the hearing.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously we feel that Medicaid and Medicare should be used&quot; for assisted suicide, said Hemlock Society spokeswoman Dori Zook. &quot;That certain congressmen do not want to see that is not a shock. It is a disappointment, but is not a shock.&quot;</p>
<p>The majority of witnesses scheduled to testify at the hearing opposed doctor-assisted suicide, which has never been allowed in the United States.</p>
<p>Legislation has been introduced in Congress to prohibit use of federal funds for such a purpose, but it was unclear whether it will be acted upon.</p>
<p>Florida Republican Representative Mike Bilirakis, chairman of the commerce subcommittee, said he did not believe federal funds should be used.</p>
<p>&quot;Many are questioning whether federal funds should pay the cost of physician-assisted suicide. I personally do not believe that most Americans would want their tax dollars to pay&quot; for that, he said in a statement.</p>
<p>The American Medical Association said Medicare and Medicaid beneficiaries accounted for nearly three-fourths of all deaths in the United States each year. Medicare provides health insurance for senior citizens, and Medicaid is a federal-state programme for the poor, elderly and disabled which pays more than half of U.S. nursing home bills.</p>
<p>&quot;The movement for legally sanctioning physician-assisted suicide is a sign of sofailure to address the compelx issues raised at the end of life. It is not a victory for personal rights,&quot; the AMA said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
