<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424128" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Albanian soldiers request asylum in Greece.</title>
<headline>Albanian soldiers request asylum in Greece.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seven Albanian soldiers requested political asylum in Greece on Thursday, the first to do so since Albanian rebels and the army clashed near the Greek border this week, a Greek defence ministry spokesman said.</p>
<p>The soldiers would be considered political refugees until the foreign and public order ministries decided whether to grant them asylum, spokesman Dimitris Katsoulis said.</p>
<p>Katsoulis had no details on the circumstances under which the soldiers turned themselves over. He said all of them had been on active duty inside Albania.</p>
<p>They were the first Albanian soldiers known to have asked for asylum in Greece since rebels clashed with the Albanian army just across the Greek border.</p>
<p>An Albanian military plane landed in Italy on Tuesday and two pilots asked for asylum.</p>
<p>Albania has been in chaos since the collapse of fraudulent saving schemes in January which devastated many families.</p>
<p>Troops have been enforcing emergency rule since Sunday to try to put down violence in southern Albania, including a number of towns and villages near the Greek border.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
