<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424160" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Mexico doesn't want landmines ban negotiated in UN.</title>
<headline>Mexico doesn't want landmines ban negotiated in UN.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico made clear on Thursday that for the sake of expediency, it preferred a global ban on landmines to be negotiated in the context of Canada's so-called &quot;Ottawa process&quot; rather than in the Conference on Disarmament.</p>
<p>The Ottawa process, an initiative which aims to reach a global ban on landmines by the end of 1997, was launched last October.</p>
<p>Western diplomats said that Mexico, a leading member of the non-aligned movement, stands alone in opposing the tackling of a landmines ban in the Geneva talks backed by the United Nations.</p>
<p>&quot;They are an obstacle,&quot; one Western diplomat told Reuters.</p>
<p>Antonio de Icaza, Mexico's ambassador, said in a speech that the Conference should concentrate on nuclear disarmament and said the landmines crisis required &quot;urgent solutions&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Swiftness is not this Conference's main virtue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope to conclude this year in the Ottawa process an international legally binding agreement to ban anti-personnel landmines...,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>China is still considering its position, but has said it is not &quot;dead-set&quot; against holding negotiations in the Geneva forum, while Russia -- another top mine producer and exporter -- has come on board, according to Western diplomats.</p>
<p>The United States has leaned on its southern neighbour to come around to negotiating a ban in the Conference on Disarmament, but has failed so far, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;The Americans have lobbied in Mexico City to try to get Mexico to take a more flexible line,&quot; one said. &quot;We were all hoping they would be more flexible, but apparently in vain.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;They are the only ones to come out firmly against this.&quot;</p>
<p>Many experts argue that for a ban to be universal, it should be negotiated in the Conference, whose members include China and Russia, two top mines producers and exporters.</p>
<p>Neither state is fully taking part in Canada's 50-country initiative, although Russia attended a January session held in Vienna as an observer.</p>
<p>Canada has called for the two processes to be complementary.</p>
<p>Pavel Grecu, Romania's envoy who currently chairs the forum, told delegates privately on Thursday that only one country opposed work on mines, a subject he called &quot;closest to reaching consensus,&quot; according to delegates.</p>
<p>&quot;It was clear he meant Mexico,&quot; one delegate said.</p>
<p>The Geneva forum last month adopted its 1997 agenda, which could encompass negotiations for a global ban on the use, stockpiling, production and transfer of landmines, which are blamed for the deaths of 25,000 people a year -- but consensus is required.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
