<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424129" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin pledges to restore order, shake up govt.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin pledges to restore order, shake up govt.</headline>
<byline>Timothy Heritage</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin, looking healthy and back in fighting form after illness, vowed in his annual state of the nation speech on Thursday to restore order in Russia and promised sweeping changes in his government.</p>
<p>In his longest and most important address since he had heart surgery in November, Yeltsin pledged to start a crusade against corruption, turn around the economy and deny the opposition the chance to force constitutional changes to weaken his powers.</p>
<p>&quot;Enough is enough...The time has come to restore order and I will do that,&quot; Yeltsin, 66, said in a clear and confident voice in a 25-minute speech which received a polite standing ovation from members of parliament gathered in the Kremlin.</p>
<p>&quot;The structure and composition of the government must be changed. Energetic and competent people will come...and I will announce these changes in the coming days.&quot;</p>
<p>Kremlin sources have said Yeltsin is likely to name his liberal chief-of-staff Anatoly Chubais as first deputy prime minister with a powerful brief overseeing economic reforms.</p>
<p>Interfax news agency said the president would sign a decree appointing Chubais, 41, on Friday.</p>
<p>Chubais himself said on Thursday that Yeltsin had not yet taken a decision on the move. He is regarded as a brilliant administrator but is hated by communists and nationalists for his earlier role in overseeing privatisation.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin accepted Yeltsin's criticisms and said he would announce a major restructuring of the government in the next few days -- but named no names.</p>
<p>&quot;We deserve such criticism,&quot; Chernomyrdin, who has been prime minister for over four years, told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;The time has come to concentrate on the most essential questions -- to change the style of the government's work, its structure and personal composition. We will act decisively and systematically,&quot; Chernomyrdin told the cabinet. His remarks reinforced expectations Chubais would join his team.</p>
<p>The 58-year-old premier called Chubais a &quot;high-calibre economist&quot; who would be an asset to the government team.</p>
<p>Grigory Yavlinsky, youthful leader of the liberal Yabloko party, told Ekho Moskvy radio station Chubais had already suggested some Yabloko deputies take ministerial posts. Yavlinsky said he himself would not join such a government.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's overall aim was to show he is firmly back in charge after spending the last eight months -- his entire second term so far -- out of action with heart trouble and pneumonia.</p>
<p>Looking thinner than before his illness but standing firmly on his feet, he passed the health test with flying colours.</p>
<p>But his political opponents said his speech repeated old, unfulfilled promises and offered no new recipes for solving the problems facing the nuclear power of almost 150 million people.</p>
<p>&quot;It was just a set of declarations, without any real decisions to back it...just promises and petty threats,&quot; Gennady Zyuganov, leader of the main opposition Communist Party, said.</p>
<p>Yeltsin faces many more tests of his long-term health, and his authority may soon be tested by a day of nationwide strikes planned for March 27 over unpaid wages.</p>
<p>He pulled no punches in criticising his government's failure to pay wages and pensions on time and painted a gloomy picture of Russia -- suggesting that problems only pile up without him.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia has entered the year of 1997 with a heavy burden of problems,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he hoped for a brighter future, the key to which was tight budgetary discipline and tax reforms to boost the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;In 2000 Russia will elect a new president. I want to pass on to my successor a country with a dynamically growing economy, an effective and fair social protection system, a country whose people look to the future with confidence,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Announcing a new crackdown on crime, something he has tried many times before, he said investigations must go right to the top. &quot;There must be no untouchables,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Also reasserting his authority, he rejected opposition demands for constitutional amendments to water down his vast powers and to try to remove him for health reasons.</p>
<p>Yeltsin acknowledged there were deep problems in the armed forces, whose backing remains important for Kremlin leaders, and said he would announce &quot;fundamental decisions&quot; soon to start reforms, including switching to a non-conscript army.</p>
<p>On foreign policy, Yeltsin attacked NATO's plans to expand into former communist-ruled and Soviet-dominated eastern Europe, calling them an attempt to &quot;squeeze&quot; Russia out of Europe and said the continent would pay a heavy price for them.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
