<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424296" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEPAL: Nepal premier resigns, communists eye power.</title>
<headline>Nepal premier resigns, communists eye power.</headline>
<byline>Gopal Sharma</byline>
<dateline>KATHMANDU 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nepal's communists began eyeing a second round in power on Thursday after Prime Minister Sher Bahadur Deuba resigned following the defeat of his 17-month-old coalition in a confidence vote.</p>
<p>King Birendra asked the coalition headed by Deuba's centrist Nepali Congress party to continue in power until the formation of a new council of ministers.</p>
<p>&quot;His majesty the king in accordance with the constitution of Nepal, 1990, has accepted the resignation tendered by Prime Minister Sher Bahadur Deuba on the grounds that a resolution tabled by him for the vote of confidence was defeated in the parliament,&quot; state radio quoted a palace communique as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;I accept the verdict gracefully and I will resign,&quot; Deuba told Reuters after the vote.</p>
<p>Deuba's government received 101 votes against a required minimum of 103 during voting in the 205-seat lower house on the motion, which he had moved to try to demonstrate the coalition's majority. A total of 92 deputies voted against.</p>
<p>The Nepali Congress party, which has 87 seats, lost its majority last December following a split in the ranks of one of its two partners, the Rashtriya Prajatantra Party (RPP), which had 19 seats.</p>
<p>The communist United Marxist-Leninist (UML) party and its allies control 94 votes in the parliament thrown up in November 1994, when the Himalayan kingdom held its second general elections after ushering in democracy in 1990.</p>
<p>The communist UML then formed a minority government.</p>
<p>But it was defeated in September 1995, when Deuba assumed power by cobbling together a three-party coalition with crucial support from the RPP, which was once close to the monarchy. Nepal now has British-style constitutional monarchy.</p>
<p>&quot;There is the possibility of a coalition between the RPP and UML,&quot; said Rajeswor Devakota, who belongs to an RPP faction oppposed to Deuba. The faction has five of RPP's 19 members, and did not take part in Thursday's voting.</p>
<p>UML's high-level standing committee met soon after Thursday's vote to try and form a new government.</p>
<p>&quot;All options are open,&quot; UML general secretary Madhav Kumar Nepal told Reuters. &quot;The possibility of a new coalition with any major party will be discussed (by the party),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The party's central committee was expected to meet shortly, he said.</p>
<p>Lawmakers said two of Deuba's Nepali Congress party lawmakers were not present for the crucial vote on Thursday. There was no official confirmation of their absence.</p>
<p>The Nepali Congress held a meeting of its deputies at Deuba's official residence. The Congress could try to form a new government under a new party leader, lawmakers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are thinking about possible alternatives,&quot; said Girija Prasad Koirala, president of the Nepali Congress. He did not give details.</p>
<p>Ninety-two MPs voted against the motion, but the higher number of votes won by Deuba was not enough as the constitution requires the government to prove a majority in the total strength of the house.</p>
<p>The next parliamentary elections are officially not due until 1999.</p>
<p>The Nepali Congress won power in the first general elections in 1990, but its government fell prematurely after a split in the party which was reduced to a minority.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NEPAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KATHMANDU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEPAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
