<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424401" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEPAL: Nepal's Deuba to seek confidence vote.</title>
<headline>Nepal's Deuba to seek confidence vote.</headline>
<dateline>KATHMANDU 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nepali Prime Minister Sher Bahadur Deuba will seek a crucial vote of confidence on Thursday in the lower house of parliament to keep his feeble 17-month-old coalition in office, officials said.</p>
<p>Parliament officials said Deuba, heading a fractious three-party centre-right coalition, would present a motion to demonstrate support for his minority government on the floor of the parliament around 11 a.m. (0515 GMT).</p>
<p>They said the speaker of the house would then schedule a debate and fix a time for the vote, likely to be held later in the day.</p>
<p>Deuba was voted to power in September 1995, replacing a communist government, but partners within the ruling coalition remain deeply divided over supporting him.</p>
<p>The constitution requires 103 votes to pass the motion in the 205-member House of Representatives.</p>
<p>On paper, the ruling coalition controls 111 members, including the speaker who does not normally vote. The communist opposition and its supporters have 94 votes.</p>
<p>The communists moved a no-confidence motion last December, hoping to cash in on a rift within the Rastriya Prajatantra Party (RPP), a key partner in Deuba's coalition that has 19 seats in parliament.</p>
<p>Deuba then slipped into a minority but remained in power as the censure motion against him fell short by two votes.</p>
<p>His Nepali Congress party, which commands 87 seats in parliament, is sharply critical of his performance, and 19 deputies have said they will abstain from parliament if he does not trim his 47-member cabinet. Deuba has promised a smaller cabinet after the vote.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NEPAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KATHMANDU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEPAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
