<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424407" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: INDIAN HEADLINE STOCKS - factors to watch - March 6.</title>
<headline>INDIAN HEADLINE STOCKS - factors to watch - March 6.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main factors affecting Indian stock markets on Thursday morning:</p>
<p>NEWS OUTLOOK:</p>
<p>** IMF Managing Director Michel Camdessus said on Wednesday that a slowdown in Indian trade seemed to indicate that the nation's economic reform programme was losing momentum.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears that the first wave of structural measures is losing a little bit of momentum as is shown by figures this year in trade,&quot; Camdessus, visiting India, told a news conference in the Indian capital, New Delhi.</p>
<p>Camdessus lauded path-breaking tax and import duty cuts proposed by Finance Minister P. Chidambaram in his budget last week for the year starting in April, but cautioned against monetary and fiscal policies that could stoke inflation.</p>
<p>He urged India to funnel resources out of subsidies, defence spending and unproductive expenditure into infrastructure, particularly in the agriculture sector, and to free oil prices from subsidies and state controls.</p>
<p>** Microsoft Corp chairman Bill Gates said on Wednesday that infrastructure improvements were crucial to India's plans to emerge as a software superpower in the next century.</p>
<p>Gates told a meeting of the heads of 500 Indian software firms in Bombay, India's commercial capital, that he wanted to exploit their employees' skills.</p>
<p>&quot;India has what it takes to participate in, even to shape, the future if it makes the necessary investments now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It must build a national telecommunications infrastructure, develop a robust domestic software industry, provide Internet connectivity for the consumer and invest in education.&quot;</p>
<p>Indian Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda, told a separate function to host Gates, that the government was planning a comprehensive manpower development programme for software exports, as well as mass awareness programmes about the information technology revolution.</p>
<p>&quot;We will intensify efforts to attract foreign investors into India,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>** Boeing said on Wednesday it was forecasting southwest Asian countries will spend $16.6 billion on about 250 250 new airliners over the next 20 years, with India providing the bulk of the demand.</p>
<p>Dinesh Keskar, president of Boeing India, told a news conference in Bombay that India would be the major buyer, although the forecast also covered Afghanistan, Bangladesh, Bhutan. Nepal, Pakistan and Sri Lanka.</p>
<p>** India's lower house of parliament on Wednesday approved a bill to allow the securities of state-run banks and financial institutions to be traded through share depositories, the United News of India (UNI) said.</p>
<p>** Hardy Oil and Gas Plc on Wednesday said it had bought a 15.5 percent stake in Hindustan Oil Exploration Co from India for a total of 2.9 million pounds.</p>
<p>MARKETS:</p>
<p>** The 30-share index of the Bombay Stock Exchange rose marginally by 3.62 points, to close at 3,940.99.</p>
<p>** The 50-stock National Stock Exchange 50-stock index gains 15.60 points, or 1.39 pct, to 1,132.90.</p>
<p>** The Delhi share index falls 9.65 points to 827.40, Calcutta eases 4.70 points to 474.65 and Madras ends 26.67 points lower at 3,690.26.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
