<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424509" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UKs Hogg to make statement on abattoir safety.</title>
<headline>UKs Hogg to make statement on abattoir safety.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Agriculture Minister Douglas Hogg is to make a statement to Parliament at 1530 GMT, following accusations that his department suppressed a damaging report on unhealthy conditions in the country's abattoirs.</p>
<p>Government sources said Hogg will deny that the report was deliberately withheld from the public.</p>
<p>The report by the government's Meat Hygiene Service, leaked to the Financial Times newspaper, concluded that the abattoirs were potential breeding grounds for the E-coli organism that killed at least 20 people through food poisoning in Scotland.</p>
<p>An aide to Prime Minister John Major said a summary of the report appeared last July in the Meat Hygiene Service's annual report. &quot;It is not a question of suppressing anything,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the Meat Hygiene Service, which has taken over the role of inspecting British abattoirs from local councils, has been in the process of establishing common standards, and has closed some abattoirs which fail to meet them.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a very great exercise over the past 2-1/2 years in assessing slaughterhouses, and uprating them in line with British and European Union standards,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7767</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
