<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424566" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Qatar says expanded Israel ties linked with peace.</title>
<headline>Qatar says expanded Israel ties linked with peace.</headline>
<byline>Suleiman al-Khalidi</byline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Qatar said on Thursday it would expand economic ties with Israel if it made progress in Middle East peace, but warned the Jewish state against using a big gas deal as a card to lure it into breaking Arab ranks.</p>
<p>&quot;We have told the Americans and Israelis that if there is progress in the peace process we will take a comparable step in developing ties between us and Israel,&quot; Qatar Foreign Minister Sheikh Hamad bin Jassim bin Jabr al-Thani told reporters in the Jordanian capital, Amman.</p>
<p>Qatar, along with Oman, has already raced ahead of other Gulf states in establishing open economic ties with Israel but stopped short of diplomatic relations pending the resolution of the Arab-Israeli conflict.</p>
<p>Israel has trade missions in the two countries and Oman has opened a trade representative office in Tel Aviv.</p>
<p>Sheikh Hamad emphasised that Qatar would not backtrack on previous commitments to develop ties with Israel if the peace process advanced. But he warned his country would keep brakes on economic ties with the Jewish state if Israel continued to obstruct implementing its peace accords with the Palestinians.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as the Israeli governent continues in adopting policies which we think will not lead to encouraging moving ahead in the peace path, Qatar will stop its activities in this front,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sheikh Hamad, who is accompanying the Qatari crown prince on a two-day visit to Jordan to improve ties and exchange views on the peace process, said Qatar's ties with Israel were linked to how far this helped Palestinians in regaining their rights.</p>
<p>&quot;If we find that our relationship with Israel is harming our brothers, then Qatar's duty is to stop this progress in ties,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sheikh Hamad also criticised Israel for trying to use a project to import Qatar gas by vessels to Israel, which has been shelved for the moment, as a carrot for normalising ties.</p>
<p>&quot;There are signals from Israel to review talks on this, but we see that this is only to bid for time and for media consumption, and we in Qatar are not accustomed nor do we accept to be used in such a way,&quot; Sheikh Hamad said.</p>
<p>U.S. gaint Enron signed a letter of intent with Qatar in January 1995 to produce five million tonnes of LNG a year from 2001, half of which would go to Israel and Jordan, with deliveries starting in the first quarter of the year 2001.</p>
<p>The project entailed setting up a $300 million regasification plant at Jordan's Red Sea port of Aqaba.</p>
<p>Although Israeli enthusiasm for the project has appeared to wane it has denied reports it abandoned the project in favour of cheaper gas supplies from Egypt. The Egyptian supplies were also thrown into doubt last year when Cairo signed an understanding to supply Turkey by undersea pipeline avoiding Israel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
