<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424667" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Senators say US air safety proposals lack funding.</title>
<headline>Senators say US air safety proposals lack funding.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two Republican senators called on President Clinton on Wednesday to match the recommendations of the White House Commission on Aviation Safety and Security with adequate funds to implement them.</p>
<p>Gorton, of Washington, was backed by Senator John McCain, of Arizona, who said he agreed with Gorton's view of the &quot;disconnect&quot; between the budget and the recommendations.</p>
<p>Aviation subcommittee chairman Gorton said at a hearing called to study the proposals made last month that he agreed with the recommendations, &quot;but we must not, however, have our hands tied with inadequate resources.&quot;</p>
<p>Gorton said &quot;I want to challenge the Clinton Administration to revise its budget for aviation safety and security so we may implement improvements.&quot;</p>
<p>The proposals included a system to match baggage with passengers, modernizing the air traffic control system and new inspections of ageing aircraft. But the recommendations, backed by Clinton, contained no spending proposals.</p>
<p>Gorton noted that Clinton's budget for fiscal '98 requested funds for additional safety and security inspectors and security-related capital needs, but premised them in large part on unspecified user fees.</p>
<p>He added, however, that Clinton's budget reduced the airport improvement program by $460 million, about one third of that appropriated by Congress last year.</p>
<p>McCain said &quot;The commission's report calls for significant federal investment, yet is short on details as to where these resources should come from.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that &quot;Funding and financial management are matters that are absolutely critical to the effort to improve aviation safety and security. Without adequate resources that are properly focused, there is little we can do to enhance the safety of flying.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
