<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424677" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: APL launches express intra-Asia service.</title>
<headline>APL launches express intra-Asia service.</headline>
<dateline>OAKLAND, Calif 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>APL Ltd said late on Wednesday that it would begin an express intra-Asia container service linking Japan directly with Hong Kong, Singapore and Malaysia, beginning March 17.</p>
<p>APL, which already serves these markets with long-haul, trans-Pacific services, said the &quot;Intra-Asia Express&quot; service would boost sailing frequency and vessel capacity for its intra-Asia customers.</p>
<p>Service to Malaysia would double to twice weekly. Weekly sailings for Hong Kong and Singapore would increase to three and weekly sailings for Japan would increase to five.</p>
<p>APL said it was launching the service through a space-chartering agreement with Wanhai Lines, a Taipei, Taiwan, company operating short-sea, intra-Asia trade lanes.</p>
<p>The agreement enabled APL to offer eight-day transit from Port Klang, Malaysia to Yokohama, Japan, or from Kobe to Singapore, and four-day transit from Kobe to Hong Kong or from Hong Kong to Tokyo.</p>
<p>APL, based in Oakland, California, said the decision to launch an intra-Asia express service arose in part because of greater demand by manufacturers in North Asia for raw materials and production in China and Southeast Asia and because rising incomes had increased the number of goods produced in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;These trends have made the intra-Asia trades the world's second largest market for container shipping services,&quot; APL's vice president for Intra-Asia based in Hong Kong, Torey Presti, said in a release.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OAKLAND, Calif"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
