<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424627" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks, bonds jump on Greenspan remarks, dollar mixed.</title>
<headline>Stocks, bonds jump on Greenspan remarks, dollar mixed.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stock prices and bonds surged on Wednesday as the latest remarks by Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan eased fears about an imminent interest rate hike.</p>
<p>The dollar extended its string of gains to a new 34-month high against the German mark but ended lower after signs of trade troubles with Japan.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average closed up 93.13 points, or 1.36 percent, at 6,945.85. In the broader market, advancing issues beat declines 1,593 to 911 on active volume of 528 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>In his comments, Greenspan, who last week issued several unusually blunt warnings regarding stock prices during his Senate appearance, appeared to soften his tone this time in testimony before the House of Representatives.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't view monetary policy as a tool to ... prick the stock market bubble, or something like that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Greenspan also repeated an assertion that the stock market was &quot;properly priced&quot; if Wall Street's assumptions about corporate profit growth proved correct.</p>
<p>The comments stood in contrast to last week, when Greenspan's testimony was peppered with reflections on speculative bubbles in the stock market. His testimony triggered an almost uninterrupted decline in stocks that pulled the Dow industrials down by 185 points in a week.</p>
<p>However, as he has often done in the past, Greenspan used the second session of his semi-annual report on the economy to soften his tone and markets responded with a bounce.</p>
<p>&quot;He did gingerly take a step back,&quot; said Hugh Johnson, chief investment officer at First Albany Corp. &quot;He helped us get over our jitters, and I think almost everybody is issuing a sigh of relief.&quot;</p>
<p>But even amid the strongest and broadest rally by stocks in three weeks, analysts cautioned that the debate on interest rates was far from over and a critical test still lay ahead with Friday's monthly payroll and wage report.</p>
<p>&quot;It's all going to boil down to Friday being a pivotal day,&quot; said Bill Meehan, an analyst at Prudential Securities. &quot;Unfortunately, no one can tell us what's going to happen then.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts believe that a very strong jobs report Friday could prompt the central bank to begin raising interest rates to stem inflationary pressures.</p>
<p>The bond market also rallied, with the key 30-year Treasury bond up more than half a point, which lowered its yield to 6.83 percent from Tuesday's close of 6.87 percent.</p>
<p>The dollar touched 1.7169 marks in Asia, its strongest since late April 1994. But the rally sputtered after a report showed Japan's trade surplus jumped in February.</p>
<p>The dollar ended at 121.15 Japanese yen, down from 122.15 yen late Tuesday. It settled at 1.7127 marks, slightly below Tuesday's 1.7137 marks.</p>
<p>Gold prices fell sharply on news of a Swiss plan to set up a fund to compensate victims of the Holocaust to be financed by selling Swiss gold reserves.</p>
<p>&quot;The Swiss news was only significant because it again says European central banks are now prepared to sell gold,&quot; CPM Group analyst Ted Kempf said.</p>
<p>April gold fell $6.10 to $354.50 an ounce at New York's Commodity Exchange after earlier dropping as low as $352.50.</p>
<p>Coffee prices on New York's Coffee, Sugar and Cocoa Exchange, in contrast, continued to soar, racing to their highest level since October 1994 and sailing through the widely watched $2 a pound mark.</p>
<p>May coffee rose 5.40 cents to $2.65 cents a pound after hitting $2.095 cents, the highest level since October 1994.</p>
<p>Overseas, London's FTSE closed 2.4 points higher at 4,360.1. In Tokyo, the 225-share Nikkei average closed down 291.27 points or 1.57 percent to 18,273.51.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
