<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424753" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: China asks for quick action on WTO entry.</title>
<headline>China asks for quick action on WTO entry.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>China is calling for quick action from major powers to admit it into the World Trade Organisation (WTO) but major hurdles remain to be overcome, trade diplomats and officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>They were speaking before a formal meeting of the WTO working party which for the past 10 years has been negotiating with Beijing on a &quot;protocol of accession&quot; -- a document setting out the agreed terms under which China would join.</p>
<p>China's chief negotiator, assistant foreign trade minister Long Yongtu, scheduled a news conference for after the meeting, the last in the latest round of talks.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese are asking us to move along as fast as we can, but there is still quite a gap between what the big powers want in terms of changes to China's current trade policies and what the Chinese seem ready to offer,&quot; said one WTO envoy.</p>
<p>Representatives of many of the 130 countries currently in the WTO have taken part this week in a concentrated push to move closer to the long-sought accord, discussing a possible accession text clause by clause with Chinese trade negotiators.</p>
<p>One trade source said the mood was &quot;pretty positive&quot; and that all essential elements were now incorporated in the protocol, although the texts of annexes setting out specific commitments in sensitive areas were still outstanding.</p>
<p>He said it was possible that a fresh round of negotiations could be set for later in the spring rather than in summer as originally planned.</p>
<p>But another trade diplomat said although Beijing had offered to lift restrictions in several key areas on the trading operations of foreign companies based in China over a three-to-five year period, a real breakthrough was still out of sight.</p>
<p>In Brussels, European Union Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan issued a statement saying membership &quot;on the right terms&quot; would be good for China and for the world trading system.</p>
<p>&quot;The time has come to turn the new mood of optimism into concrete progress on the ground. The EU believes that if all sides muster sufficient political will, the terms of China's accession could be agreed by the end of the year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But for this to happen, Brittan added: &quot;China must make bold and meaningful commitments to market reform in areas that are vital to the smooth functioning of the WTO.&quot;</p>
<p>Convincing offers from China, especially in the areas of trading rights, services and tariff and non-tariff measures, &quot;will prompt a positive and flexbile response from her trading partners,&quot; he declared.</p>
<p>U.S. officials in Geneva have declined to give any assessment of progress, but Under-Secretary of Commerce Stuart Eizenstat made clear in Shanghai on Wednesday that Washington was not ready to give Beijing a quick run into the WTO.</p>
<p>China has consistently argued -- unlike Russia which is also seeking WTO entry -- that it should be allowed in as a developing country, thus gaining a longer grace period to bring its laws into line with the trade body's rules.</p>
<p>But the United States and the EU say the size of China's economy is such that only terms closer to those expected of a developed power are acceptable.</p>
<p>Eizenstat said Washington recognised the problems facing China in the transition from a state-run to a market economy.</p>
<p>But he made clear China could not expect a long grace period for ending government subsidies to state-owned enterprises which supported up to two-thirds of the country's workforce.</p>
<p>&quot;There has to be some commitment that at some reasonable point these enterprises are going to be operated on market principles because otherwise it's unfair to our workers and the workers in Europe and elsewhere to compete against subsidised enterprises,&quot; the U.S. official said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
