<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424731" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French civil servants strike over wages.</title>
<headline>French civil servants strike over wages.</headline>
<byline>Lee Yanowitch</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>French civil servants went on strike over wage demands on Thursday, protesting against the government's refusal to make up for a salary freeze last year.</p>
<p>The call by seven trade unions for a 24-hour stoppage, the second in four months, was directed to some four million state employees, from teachers and street cleaners to hospital and postal workers.</p>
<p>But the impact on the public was blunted as public transport workers, engaged in their own wage talks after staging their own strikes, did not join the stoppage.</p>
<p>Several thousand protesters marched in Paris, Marseille, Nice, Nantes, Toulouse, Rennes, Le Mans and Bordeaux, where Prime Minister Alain Juppe is mayor. But the turnout in the Paris march fell far short of expectations and unions blamed it on light rain.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope the mobilisation will be sufficiently strong to convince the government to change its policy concerning civil servants,&quot; said Pascal Renaud, of the CFDT trade union.</p>
<p>Louis Viannet, head of the militant communist-led General Workers Confederation, told RMC radio the strike was &quot;an explosion of anger&quot; over falling purchasing power.</p>
<p>In the central city of Clermont Ferrand, a judge said police could intervene if striking transport workers refused to take down a blockade of the city bus depot.</p>
<p>Several schools stayed shut as up to half of teachers joined the stoppage, according to the main FEN teachers union.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is stubbornly refusing to negotiate and is misleading the public about our wages&quot; said FEN head Guy Le Neouannic.</p>
<p>Teachers' unions, also protesting against job cuts, have called another strike day for March 23.</p>
<p>State hospitals and postal services were also disrupted, but automation of telephone and electricity services meant the stoppage had little impact on consumers.</p>
<p>The strike by tax inspectors gave taxpayers one reason to smile: the Finance Ministry has put off to next Monday from Thursday the deadline for sending in tax returns.</p>
<p>The centre-right government, eager to show its European Union partners and financial markets that it is sticking firmly to budget restraints to comply with criteria for the single European currency, has rejected union demands for a &quot;catch-up&quot; for last year's wage freeze.</p>
<p>&quot;The government refuses to negotiate...although everyone admits there is a very serious problem with purchasing power,&quot; Viannet said. &quot;The government's stand towards civil servants encourages all bosses to tighten the screw on wages.&quot;</p>
<p>Unions have turned down a government offer of a 2.8 percent pay rise for 1997 and 1998, saying it will not compensate for the 1996 pay freeze.</p>
<p>They say wages are due to increase by one percent through 1996 and 1997 while prices are forecast to rise 3.6 percent.</p>
<p>The government disputes the figures, saying civil service wages will increase by 2.6 percent overall this year taking into account promotions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
