<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="424980" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREEK GENERAL NEWS - MARCH 6.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREEK GENERAL NEWS - MARCH 6.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek general press:</p>
<p>KATHIMERINI</p>
<p>--Greece's role in the Albanian crisis has been upgraded on an international level, with the EU presidency saying it is in constant contact with all EU capitals, but particularly Athens. EU Council of Minister President Hans Van Mierlo will be in Athens later today ahead of his meeting with Albanian President Sali Berisha in Tirana tomorrow.</p>
<p>--Dozens of Greek businesses in Albania have suffered damages and are now calling on the government for help in dealing with the acute problems brought by the uprising. Trade is at a standstill in the neighbouring country.</p>
<p>ELEFTHEROTYPIA</p>
<p>--The election of delegates to the conservative opposition party New Democracy's congress later this month saw all three front-runners saying they had the edge.</p>
<p>--Education Minister Gerasimos Arsenis received a rowdy welcome from university students as he arrived to speak on the future of universities.</p>
<p>TA NEA</p>
<p>--Parliament yesterday voted through the government's revised pay scale for civil servants, which will come into effect as of January 1, 1997. </p>
<p>--A possible wave of illegal immigrants from Albania and humanitarian aid for the neighbouring country were the focus of discussions at an inter-ministerial meeting last night. Greece is preparing special areas to receive large numbers of immigrants.</p>
<p>ELEFTHEROS TYPOS</p>
<p>--Delegates to the ND congress are keeping their cards close to their chests although the candidates are confident about the level of their support.</p>
<p>ETHNOS</p>
<p>--Greek doctors yesterday revealed a baby girl, born after complicated in vitro fertilisation procedures, complicated by the sterility of the father.</p>
<p>--Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
