<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="425099" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia warned to beware of Asia on superhighway.</title>
<headline>Australia warned to beware of Asia on superhighway.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-03-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia has been warned it risks being overtaken by its Asian rivals on the information superhighway unless it shifts into gear urgently.</p>
<p>A report released by a coalition of top Australian chief executives has found Singapore and Malaysia is leaping ahead in the &quot;on-line revolution&quot; in Asia, catching Australia napping.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a slumbering issue and it can't be allowed to stay asleep,&quot; said bank chief executive Don Mercer, president of the Australian Coalition of Service Industries.</p>
<p>The coalition commissioned the study out of fears Australia could fall behind in the emerging area of on-line commerce and trade, which is turning the Internet into a global marketplace.</p>
<p>The report notes Australia's relatively high cost of tapping into the Internet, a world-wide computer network with tens of millions of users. Its author also says &quot;ancient&quot; cables linking Australia to the rest of the world are clogged with traffic.</p>
<p>&quot;Our competitors in the global economy are already taking significant steps to embrace the on-line economy and, as first movers, may capture an important advantage,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nations failing to embrace the on-line economy are likely to see tradeable services supplied by offshore companies, high unemployment and lower economic growth,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Australia is seen as quick to adopt new technology with ambitions to become a regional business hub in Asia. Its two telecommunications carriers are spending a total of A$6.5 billion on rolling out broad-band cable across the country.</p>
<p>But cables linking Australia to the rest of the world are groaning, with Internet traffic out of Australia swelling 15 percent a month and local complaints that capacity on these cables is already scarce and too expensive, the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;If Australia does need more capacity, as seems likely, it will need to talk action urgently, as Asian competitors appear well positioned for a pre-emptive strike,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>The report's author, information technology expert Clem Doharty, said fibre-optic cables linking Australia and North America were &quot;ancient&quot; and thin compared with the thicker cables Asian nations were using to hook up with the West.</p>
<p>&quot;There are major cables linking Singapore, Malaysia, Hong Kong, Thailand to Europe and to North America,&quot; Doharty said.</p>
<p>No reliable figures are kept in Australia on the small but growing balance of trade on the Internet, where firms ranging from banks to book-sellers have already set up shop world-wide.</p>
<p>But the coalition's Mercer, who is chief executive of the Australia and New Zealand Banking Group, said Australia was widely believed to be trading in the red on the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;We are importing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>(A$1 = US$0.785)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
