<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="425035" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Glaxo Wellcome says sees 2 flat years ahead.</title>
<headline>Glaxo Wellcome says sees 2 flat years ahead.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's biggest drugs company Glaxo Wellcome Plc, which announced an 18 percent jump in pre-tax profit to 2.964 billion pounds last year, said on Thursday that it faced two years of flat earnings as it coped with key patent expiries.</p>
<p>Glaxo Wellcome said it hoped to &quot;at least maintain&quot; this level of earnings in 1997 and 1998 as it faced the expiry of U.S. and British patents on its biggest selling drug, anti-ulcerant Zantac, in July.  </p>
<p>Sales of Zantac fell by 14 percent last year to 1.931 billion pounds ($3.11 billion), and accounted for 23 percent of total sales compared with 43 percent in 1994.</p>
<p>The company said sales of newer products, launched since 1990, were taking up much of the slack left by Zantac. Sales of these products, which include asthma drugs Serevent and Flixotide, jumped by 50 percent last year to two billion pounds.</p>
<p>Other strong performers were the group's revived anti-HIV range, which saw sales leap by 100 percent to 500 million pounds, reflecting the growing success of combination therapy.</p>
<p>Glaxo Wellcome said it expected sales growth in 1997 and 1998 &quot;in low single digits,&quot; rising to &quot;double digits&quot; in 1999. It added that currency movements, notably the strength of sterling, &quot;could clearly have a significant effect&quot; on performance.&quot; ($1=.6202 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
