<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="425136" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ Deputy PM forced to apologise after &quot;scuffle&quot;.</title>
<headline>NZ Deputy PM forced to apologise after &quot;scuffle&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand Treasurer and Deputy Prime Minister Winston Peters was forced to apologise to a fellow politician on Thursday after a heated late-night dispute in a corridor of parliament.</p>
<p>Peters, in a radio interview, denied he had abused and assaulted conservative MP John Banks, as Banks alleged.</p>
<p>But he later acknowledged to parliament that they had had a dispute which had &quot;clearly upset&quot; Banks.</p>
<p>&quot;I wish to tender my apology to him unreservedly,&quot; Peters told parliament.</p>
<p>The flamboyant Maori politician became number two in the government last December when he steered his New Zealand First party into a coalition with the conservative National Party.</p>
<p>Peters is no stranger to controversy. At one point during protracted coalition talks late last year he missed a negotiating session after being involved in a 2 a.m. altercation with patrons of a Wellington restaurant.</p>
<p>Banks, a National Party MP and former cabinet minister, told Radio New Zealand: &quot;I was assaulted. I was grabbed by the shoulder and close to the scruff of the neck and given one hell of a good shake and push.&quot;</p>
<p>Banks complained to the speaker of parliament but said he considered the matter closed after Peters's apology.</p>
<p>Left-wing Alliance party leader Jim Anderton backed Banks' contention that Peters had scuffled with him.</p>
<p>&quot;He grabbed Mr Banks -- and by grabbing I mean he grabbed him quite strongly by the shoulder -- and was either shaking him or physically pushing him across the corridor,&quot; Anderton said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a very ugly incident.&quot;</p>
<p>Anderton also said Peters's colleague, Maori Affairs Minister Tau Henare, had physically prevented a Radio New Zealand reporter from tape-recording the incident. Henare apologised to the journalist.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
