<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="425199" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: High China diesel stocks spur call for import halt.</title>
<headline>High China diesel stocks spur call for import halt.</headline>
<byline>Ang Bee Lin</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's diesel imports should ease after recent big purchases raised stocks and prompted refiners to ask Beijing to stop issuing first quarter import licences, industry sources said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, refiners have asked the State Planning Commission to stop issuing first quarter import licences about two weeks ago, but state planners have yet to grant any aproval for the request,&quot; said a source at state-refiner Sinopec.</p>
<p>Chinese trade sources said state planners in Beijing were unlikely to grant the approval as inventories in China, while high, had not reached critical levels.</p>
<p>&quot;We are already approaching the end of the first quarter, most imports for March have already been done, it is quite futile to do so now,&quot; said an official at state trader Sinochem of the appeal to stop issuing licences.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is not so bad. Recent heavy imports have not caused any port congestions. It is just that inventories are high and domestic production has edged up marginally,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>State planners in Beijing could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>Chinese importers said current high inventory levels had deterred buyers from importing diesel in March.</p>
<p>&quot;China's demand is very scattered currently,&quot; said a trader in Singapore. &quot;The buying spree ahead of the Lunar New Year holidays in February have filled up their tanks.&quot;</p>
<p>Imports from November were assessed at 800,000 tonnes per month. But in March, imports were significantly less, estimated at under 400,000 tonnes, Sinochem traders in Hong Kong and Singapore told Reuters.</p>
<p>But China's diesel demand was expected to increase dramatically in 1997 as the country spears ahead with economic and industrial development, traders said.</p>
<p>Sinopec sources said China's domestic refineries would continue to raise deisel output as plans to increase the efficiency of domestic refineries were carried out.</p>
<p>They said diesel output was expected to rise by 10 percent this year, up from 4.1 million tonnes in 1996, to feed the booming appetite.</p>
<p>Demand is likely to hit 16 million tonnes in 1997, up by 10-15 percent from a year ago, one trade source in Beijing estimated.</p>
<p>Chinese sources said the policy to raise deisel output may be at the expense of fuel oil production and could trigger an increase in fuel oil imports.</p>
<p>China produced a total of 2.3 million tonnes of fuel oil in 1996 and demand is expected to reach nearly nine million tonnes in 1997, a similar increase of between 10-15 percent, the trade source in Beijing said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
