<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="425277" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Citatah active on private placement talk.</title>
<headline>Citatah active on private placement talk.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of Indonesian marble producer PT Citatah were actively traded on Thursday due to intense market talk of a possible private placement and rights issue, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Previously, there had been rumours of a possible private placement but then I also heard today that they might propose a rights issue,&quot; a broker with London-based securities house said.</p>
<p>The company officials were not available immediately for comment.</p>
<p>Local-led investors were seen actively buying on the counter which also boosted by the expectation of better-than-expected 1996 net profit, brokers said.  </p>
<p>In early afternoon session, Citatah rose 200 rupiah to 2,775 with some 8.5 million shares changing hands, after earlier rose 10.68 percent to 2,850 rupiah.</p>
<p>Previously Citatah director Taufik Johannes was quoted by Bisnis Indonesia daily on Tuesday as saying that its 1996 net profit was 25 billion rupiah and it had revised up a net profit target for 1997 at 33 billion rupiah.</p>
<p>The market consensus of Citatah's net profit in 1996 was 24 billion rupiah and 33.7 billion rupiah for 1997.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
