<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="425289" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs close higher on dealers' short-squeezing.</title>
<headline>JGBs close higher on dealers' short-squeezing.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key June 10-year Japanese government bond (JGB) futures contract closed sharply higher on Thursday as an unexpected rise caused dealers' short-squeezing.</p>
<p>The June ended up 0.45 at 125.35 in a hefty turnover of 67,373. Earlier, the contract broke above what many had considered a major resistance point at 125.00 and jumped to 125.40, its new high.</p>
<p>But dealers said they were uncertain what made the market bullish in the first place.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks to me as if the contract started to rise without any reason,&quot; said a &quot;Big Four&quot; senior dealer.  </p>
<p>&quot;But I'm certain that dealers who had sold the contract for hedging were squeezed eventually, and this caused such a steep rise,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A fall in Tokyo stocks, including bank shares, was supportive overall, but there were other possible reasons behind the rise, traders said.</p>
<p>Some attributed the rise to a view that the June looked cheap when compared with the previous benchmark March, which hit a record high of 126.83 in January.</p>
<p>Some others said short-covering on the March contract ahead of its expiry on Friday helped to raise the key June contract.  </p>
<p>Buyers of the March contract may have included those who intended to receive cash bonds at the expiry, they said.</p>
<p>There was a vague rumour that foreign hedge fund operators may have been such buyers.</p>
<p>There was another rumour saying that a life insurer had purchased cash JGBs this morning.</p>
<p>&quot;There was talk that a life insurer bought cash JGBs in small lots this morning,&quot; a city bank trader said.</p>
<p>But the amount of the purchases was said to be small compared with on Tuesday when JGBs fluctuated on cash bond selling by one life insurer which later bought on dips.  </p>
<p>A dealer at long-term bank's securities unit said: &quot;What people say is that buying by a life insurer boosted the market. The insurer was said to have bought government-guaranteed and municipal bonds with eight to nine years until maturity.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;But I didn't see such buying,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Traders said cash bonds followed rises in JGB futures most of the time, but the cash market saw a relatively solid ceiling on top.</p>
<p>The yield of key 182nd 10-year JGBs stood up 0.045 at 2.360 percent at 0726 GMT. The yield moved between 2.355 and 2.415 percent. -- Risa Maeda, Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-33432-8570</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
