<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="425303" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian trade sees pullback in sizzling coffee rally.</title>
<headline>Asian trade sees pullback in sizzling coffee rally.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The sizzling rally in world coffee prices appears overdone and London robusta futures were expected to retreat by between US$50 and $130 a tonne on profit-taking, Asian traders said on Thursday.</p>
<p>They New York arabica prices were expected to follow suit in profit-taking later in the day, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The rally is way too much overdone. It's due $120 down,&quot; the chief coffee dealer for a U.S. commodity trading house said.</p>
<p>Another trader for a European commodity house said: &quot;Nothing lasts forever. We should see it go down about $55-$130.&quot;  </p>
<p>Very tight supplies of coffee in Latin America and low stocks in consuming countries have sparked the rally.</p>
<p>London's benchmark May robusta contract soared on Wednesday to a new nine-month high of $1,820 a tonne before late profit-taking knocked it back down to $1,780, up $82 on the day.</p>
<p>New York May rallied to a 2-1/2 year peak at 209.50 U.S. cents a lb prior to settling at 200.65 cents.</p>
<p>U.S. coffee prices have now gained 30 cents, or 17 percent, over the last four days.  </p>
<p>&quot;Some sort of correction is reasonable to expect,&quot; a European trader said, adding that the pattern of &quot;forced liquidation&quot; seen in New York and London towards the end of trading on Wednesday may again be seen later on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;New York went up much faster than London so New York will go down much faster than London,&quot; another dealer said.</p>
<p>Some speculative fund managers appear to have decided to decide to cash in their profits, one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;At a certain stage, one guy said 'I have a nice profit, I'll take my profits.' The next guy decided to take their profits and this seems to have spread,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Some traders said any correction may be mild and short-lived as the bullish fundamentals of the coffee market remained intact.</p>
<p>&quot;We still have the same huge shortage of coffee coming up over the next 1-1/2 years,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't count on a big correction, the way the market has been behaving the past few days,&quot; another coffee trader said.</p>
<p>-- Rene Pastor, Singapore Newsroom (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
