<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42538" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Williams sees more acquisitions.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Williams sees more acquisitions.</headline>
<byline>Greg Mahlich</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>British fire protection and building products group Williams Holdings Plc announced a sharp jump in half-year profits on Tuesday after spending more than 200 million pounds on acquisitions and said it was looking for more deals.</p>
<p>The company said that improved market conditions for building products in North America would continue to help offset the effects of subdued European markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Order books in July and August have confirmed the trends of the first half with pleasing performances in the fire and security businesses, but clear evidence of continued challenging market conditions in continental Europe,&quot; chairman Sir Nigel Rudd said in a statement.</p>
<p>The group posted an 11.4 percent rise in first-half pre-tax profits to a record 114.9 million pounds ($178.5 million). Acquisitions cost 212.5 million pounds in the half-year, helping to boost sales by 14.6 percent to 877 million pounds.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a lot of (potential) acquisitions on the radar at the moment...There are lots of interesting companies both large and small,&quot; chief executive Roger Carr said.</p>
<p>But he said Williams would stick to its core businesses of fire protection, security and building products.</p>
<p>Williams' days as an old-fashioned diversified conglomerate were long gone, he said, which should ensure it is spared the investment stigma the term carries following recent problems and share price underperformance at British groups such as Hanson and BTR.</p>
<p>&quot;The (share) market has become more and more clear that our decision to focus this business a long time ago has actually opened up a visible gap between ourselves and what used to be considered our peer group,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the judgement on Williams is now different and the view as to where it is in developing this focus is reflected in the results.&quot;</p>
<p>The interim dividend was raised to 5.8 pence from 5.5 a year ago, on earnings per share up to 11 pence from 9.9.</p>
<p>Dealers said the results were in line with market expectations. The share price rose to 364 before retreating to its opening level of 358 by 1215 GMT in a generally firmer market.</p>
<p>Carr said the performance of the fire protection business was boosted by a mixture of organic and acquisitive growth, with particularly strong demand for specialist systems seen from aircraft manufacturers, including Boeing.</p>
<p>The division's operating profits rose to 40.5 million pounds from 31.5 million pounds last time. Sales were up 36 percent at 262.2 million pounds.</p>
<p>Security products brought in operating profits of 21.3 million pounds, up from 18.8 million last time, on sales up 12.5 percent at 118.8 million pounds.</p>
<p>Building products performance divided sharply between Europe and North America. Operating profits in North America rose to 22.9 million pounds from 19.2 million pounds on sales up 12.7 percent at 178.2 million pounds.</p>
<p>Carr said there were signs of a pick-up in consumer activity in Britain but demand in France and Germany remained depressed.</p>
<p>&quot;The UK has actually done quite well and businesses like Swish (curtain track), Rawlplug (fixings) and Vi-Spring beds have actually shown some remarkable growth.&quot;</p>
<p>But mainland Europe, and France and Germany in particular, told a different story. &quot;It's pretty dull and very challenging and I think it will be that way for the balance of this year.&quot; ($1=.6436 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
