<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="425334" id="root" date="1997-03-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Sales of German cars in Japan jump in February.</title>
<headline>Sales of German cars in Japan jump in February.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sales of German cars jumped in Japan in February as consumers were attracted by new models, industry officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Japan Automobile Importers' Association (JAIA) said on Thursday that sales of imported vehicles in Japan rose 8.6 percent in February from a year earlier to 36,759 units, and that sales of German cars rose a steep 25.8 percent from a year earlier to 17,813 units.</p>
<p>The association said strong demand for German compact cars and wagons meant that, excluding commercial vehicles, German cars accounted for about 52.8 percent of all imported cars sold in Japan in February, up from 44.3 percent a year earlier.</p>
<p>Sales of U.S.-made cars fell 33.9 percent from a year earlier to 7,547, mainly due to lower sales of Honda's U.S.-made Accord Wagons.</p>
<p>U.S. cars accounted for 22.4 percent of all imported cars sold in February, down from 35.7 percent a year earlier.</p>
<p>Sales of American-made Honda cars fell 38.7 percent from a year earlier to 2,939 cars, while U.S.-made Toyota cars fell 77.7 percent to 581 in February.</p>
<p>Honda is expected to move production of its popular Accord Wagon to Japan from the United States this summer because of slack demand in the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;German makers and also other European makers have been faster in introducing models, in particular, compact cars. That's one reason why they have been able to boost sales,&quot; JAIA planning manager Ken Kano said.</p>
<p>GM sales fell due to poor demand for all its models, including the Cavalier, except its Cadillac Seville.</p>
<p>The Cavalier is sold by Toyota with Toyota's brand name.</p>
<p>Overall sales of imported vehicles in the year to the end of March are expected to rise by nearly 10 percent over the 402,608 vehicles sold in 1995/96, partly helped by demand ahead of a sales tax increase on April 1, Kano said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
