<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42534" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: More Americans losing health insurance at work.</title>
<headline>More Americans losing health insurance at work.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite business's success in controlling their health insurance costs, more and more working Americans and their families are losing health insurance at work, according to a new study released Tuesday by the American Hospital Association (AHA).</p>
<p>As of 1990, some 77.7 percent of working people and their families got insurance on the job but that figure dropped to 73.9 percent in 1995 and is forecast to fall to 70.4 percent by the year 2002, according to the study, conducted by the respected consulting firm the Lewin Group.</p>
<p>In addition, people who do get insurance on the job are likely to pay a larger share of their medical costs, in keeping with the trend seen in the past few years, the study found.</p>
<p>Overall, the number of uninsured people in the United States will climb from 39.6 million in 1995 to 45.6 million by the year 2002, or 16.2 percent of the population, it found.</p>
<p>Currently about one in four of the uninsured -- about 10 million -- are children or teens.</p>
<p>When President Clinton began his ill-fated drive for universal health insurance, there were about 37 million uninsured Americans.</p>
<p>One modest health reform law has since been enacted, but the national debate over the uninsured has largely evaporated.</p>
<p>AHA president Dick Davdison told reporters at a briefing on the new study that his organisation would try to renew political debate over the uninsured, as well as promote solutions at a community level instead of through the federal government.</p>
<p>&quot;We would like our members to politely be in their (politicians and candidates) face,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hospitals provide about $16 billion a year worth of uncompensated medical care.</p>
<p>The trend toward less insurance coverage through the workplace has been under way for several years, and reflects the scarcity of insurance coverage in low-paid service sector jobs, more contract and part-time workers who do not get benefits and small businesses dropping coverage, or dropping affordable coverage of workers' families.</p>
<p>Although under the law a worker who loses or leaves a job can continue buying insurance under a programme called COBRA for 18 months, it is very expensive and only 18 percent of the workers eligible for COBRA choose it, the study found.</p>
<p>Some of those who did not opt for COBRA coverage -- which on average in 1995 cost $177 per month for an individual or $464 per month for a family -- got insurance at a new job or through a spouse but many entered the ranks of the uninsured.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
