<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42563" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Faith of small investor seen rocked by MGAM saga.</title>
<headline>Faith of small investor seen rocked by MGAM saga.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Brothers</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Revelations last week about the management of three Morgan Grenfell funds will rock British small investors who thought unit trusts were safe as houses, though some financiers say the impact will be short-lived.</p>
<p>The financial world was stunned last week by news that Morgan Grenfell had suspended trading in three of its highest profile funds, pending investigations into their management.</p>
<p>&quot;I can quite understand why somebody in their armchair who isn't particularly au fait with unit trusts is bound to be put off -- but I would be surprised if the effects lasted too long,&quot; said Ian Millward, nationwide investment management advisor at Chase de Vere Investments.</p>
<p>&quot;When you've had your name on the front pages and it's been bad press it will naturally deter people a little.&quot;</p>
<p>Independent financial advisors, who deal daily with small-scale investors, have been flooded with calls from people wanting reassurance.</p>
<p>But they say the actions of Deutsche Bank, Morgan Grenfell's powerful parent, since the crisis broke has soothed the anxious, stemming losses and shoring up the value of the funds.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the great benefits has been the financial strength of Deutsche, which has made a tremendous difference,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Without it the effect on the person in the street, many of whom invested in the Morgan Grenfell funds via personal equity plans, could have been very different.</p>
<p>Ironically Deutsche Bank's efforts may ultimately benefit those unit trusts that have similarly solid backing.</p>
<p>&quot;People may eventually look more towards the stronger-backed funds,&quot; Millward said.</p>
<p>&quot;People's faith in the brokers has been shaken.&quot; said Mark Pithers, investment manager at Old Mutual fund managers.</p>
<p>Brokers who have struggled to persuade their clients not to hide their money under the mattress are finding their own name is suffering, and are having to work hard to restore client confidence in unit trusts as a vehicle.</p>
<p>While inexperienced investors may go rushing back to their building societies for supposedly cast-iron security, the fact that their rates are so low is forcing &quot;Joe Public&quot; to look further afield.</p>
<p>The Morgan Grenfell experience may force them to recognise they are also taking on greater downside risk. This is despite the fact that advertisements for unit trusts often contain warnings that investment values can go down as well as up.</p>
<p>But Millward for one remains confident.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a pretty awful thing to happen but the unit trust has proved that it's robust, and Deutsche Bank has stepped in, so it isn't too bad,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>($1=.6436 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
