<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="425798" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: OLYMPICS-FOCUS-BUENOS AIRES, CAPE TOWN STAY IN 2004 OLYMPIC RACE.</title>
<headline>OLYMPICS-FOCUS-BUENOS AIRES, CAPE TOWN STAY IN 2004 OLYMPIC RACE.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>LAUSANNE, Switzerland 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Buenos Aires and Cape Town stayed in the race to make Olympic history on Friday when they were named in the International Olympic Committee (IOC)'s final short-list of candidates to host the 2004 Summer Games.</p>
<p>The Games have never been staged in Africa or South America. Although the two cities have fierce competition from the other short-listed candidates from Europe -- favourites Rome, Athens and Stockholm -- their names will now go into a vote of the IOC's session in September when the venue will be decided.</p>
<p>The IOC announced the short-list of five after studying a detailed technical report of all 11 bidding cities and hearing presentations from the candidates on Thursday.</p>
<p>Cape Town faced difficult questions about crime and possible political instability in the future but its delegation was confident of making the list.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a vote for Africa, not just South Africa,'' the country's IOC chief Sam Ramsamy said after listening to the announcement of the decision at Lausanne's Olympic museum.</p>
<p>&quot;It is recognition that we have reached the real democratic and non-racial world. If you had asked me five years ago whether we could have the 2004 Games, I would have said I didn't know. But we have made great progress and got our house in order. &quot;</p>
<p>The other candidates -- Istanbul, Lille, Rio de Janeiro, San Juan, Seville and St Petersburg -- were regarded as having weaker bids and left the museum disappointed. Some were clearly bitter.</p>
<p>&quot;Are we seeing here the emergence of a Christian crusaders' mentality?'' Istanbul official Erman Tuncer said. &quot;The two-billion strong Moslem community of the world is being excluded from the Olympics.''</p>
<p>Buenos Aires is regarded as having a better bid than Cape Town in terms of its facilities and organisation. But the political argument was so strong for South Africa it would have been a major surprise if Cape Town had been left out.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now the only city from South America (in the race) and we hope we have all South America behind us,'' said Hugo Porta, the former international rugby union player who is now Argentina's Sports Minister.</p>
<p>&quot;It is historic. It is time that the Olympic flame was in Latin America.''</p>
<p>Cape Town officials are confident they can dispel fears of crime and assured the IOC the country would remain stable when President Nelson Mandela leaves office in 1999. But it is likely to remain an issue before the IOC vote.</p>
<p>There is no doubt that some IOC members will be attracted by the idea of taking the Games to a new continent in the first years of the new millennium. The next Summer Games will be held in Sydney in the year 2000.</p>
<p>But Rome is still seen as the top favourite for the vote which will be held on September 5 in Lausanne, although Italy's IOC member and international athletics chief Primo Nebiolo played down the Italian capital's chances.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an adventure in two stages and we've just gone through the first one,'' he said. &quot;The second will be much tougher.''</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAUSANNE, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
