<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42576" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK water watchdog warns on &quot;damaging&quot; mergers.</title>
<headline>UK water watchdog warns on &quot;damaging&quot; mergers.</headline>
<byline>Paul Mylrea</byline>
<dateline>BIRMINGHAM, England 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of Britain's water industry regulator Ofwat gave a lukewarm response on Tuesday to mergers of water companies, calling them &quot;damaging&quot;, and warning they would eventually have to stop.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly I do see a point where we have to call a halt,&quot; Ofwat chief Ian Byatt told reporters at Britain's annual Science Festival here, held by the British Association.</p>
<p>&quot;Mergers between water companies are more damaging than takeovers...by somebody else because they reduce the ability of the regulator to make comparisons and more widely reduce the extent of competition between companies,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Byatt said as the industry regulator, he looked for more efficiency from a merger, entailing lower costs and therefore lower prices, along with better performance and maintaining visibility, perhaps through separate stock market listings.</p>
<p>So far, Northumbrian Water is the only one of the major water and sewage companies to succumb to a bid from another water group, France's Lyonnaise des Eaux.</p>
<p>In that situation, Byatt secured heavy price cuts from Lyonnaise in order for the merger to go ahead.</p>
<p>Two rival bids for South West Water, from Severn Trent Water and Wessex Water, are currently being considered by British competition authorities.</p>
<p>&quot;I have argued -- and the MMC (Monopolies and Mergers Commission) and the government have accepted -- that a substantial price cut...is a necessary part&quot; of the preconditions for a merger, Byatt said in a speech to the conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Where large companies wish to merge, the remedy must be large -- and there will be cases where I believe the merger should be prohibited altogether,&quot; he added in the speech.</p>
<p>Byatt also gave a caution to companies handing out excessive executive pay cheques and suggested shareholders were best placed to curb this largesse.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think all the companies have behaved very sensibly. They haven't shown good leadership and there is a price to pay,&quot; he said to reporters at the conference.</p>
<p>&quot;The real test is for shareholders to decide if (executives) are worth what they are paying them,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But Byatt also had criticism for the public, whose perceptions over the water industry were &quot;wrong.&quot;</p>
<p>He said there had been improvements in the water industry since privatisation in 1990 as standards of service, quality and profitability had improved.</p>
<p>But these benefits were hard to recognise, Byatt said, because higher environmental requirements had triggered rising prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Ill-considered environmental proposals could be very damaging to customers' pockets,&quot; Byatt said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BIRMINGHAM, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
