<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="425853" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: SOCCER-ROMARIO IN FIGHT AS MATCH ENDS IN CHAOS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ROMARIO IN FIGHT AS MATCH ENDS IN CHAOS.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil striker Romario was involved in a fight that resembled scenes from a kick-boxing film at the end of Flamengo's 7-0 win over Madureira.</p>
<p>The incident led to a free-for-all in which Flamengo coach and former Brazil international Junior ran onto the pitch and lunged feet first into a Madureira player.</p>
<p>Romario scored twice in Thursday's game, taking his total for Flamengo to 100. The tally includes a large number of goals scored in friendlies and games in the Rio de Janeiro championship, where many of the teams are of poor quality.</p>
<p>But Romario lost his temper in the 87th minute when he began arguing with rival defender Cafezinho.</p>
<p>The two swore at each other. Romario then aimed a kick at Cafezinho, the Madureira player retaliated and Romario then aimed two more higher kicks at his rival, both of which missed.</p>
<p>The two raised their fists before other players intervened, beginnning a brawl in which players, reporters and officials were involved.</p>
<p>At the end, Cafezinho and Junior were sent off and Romario was left with a swollen left eye.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
