<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="425935" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-BETIS AND ATLETICO BID FOR CHAMPIONS LEAGUE SPOT.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-BETIS AND ATLETICO BID FOR CHAMPIONS LEAGUE SPOT.</headline>
<dateline>SEVILLE, Spain 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>In other circumstances Sunday's Real Betis-Atletico Madrid fixture might have been a fairly routine clash between two sides already close to guaranteeing UEFA Cup berths for next season.</p>
<p>But the decision to award Spain two places in the money-spinning Champions' League, together with the recent poor form of second-placed Barcelona, has given the match a whole new dimension.</p>
<p>And both sides are on tip-top form.</p>
<p>Atletico achieved a 1-1 draw at Dutch giants Ajax on Wednesday, and could yet become Spain's third team in the premier continental competition by quallifying as holders.</p>
<p>The following day Betis went level on points with Barcelona by outplaying Sporting Gijon 4-2 in a postponed league fixture.</p>
<p>A daunting nine points ahead are leaders Real Madrid, who on current form already look out of reach.</p>
<p>But the fight for second place has really hotted up in the past month, and the four rival candidates are now within as many points of each other.</p>
<p>Three points behind Barcelona and Betis are Deportivo Coruna, who have enjoyed a renaissance under new coach Carlos Alberto Silva.</p>
<p>A further point back are Atletico, who have a game in hand.</p>
<p>So far Atletico have performed well in their marathon schedule of 10 league, cup and European games in just 35 days.</p>
<p>Just three days after the Betis game, Radomir Antic's side travel to Barcelona's Camp Nou stadium for the second leg of their Spanish Cup game.</p>
<p>Atletico's league-and-cup double last season could easily have turned on a Cup game at Betis.</p>
<p>With a 2-1 advantage from the first leg, Atletico goalkeeper Jose Molina should have been sent off for handling the ball outside the area early in the game. But the referee failed to act, and later missed a clear penalty committed on Betis striker Alfonso Perez.</p>
<p>Atletico went through with two goals from Lyuboslav Peneve -- who has since moved to Compostela.</p>
<p>The game ended with angry scenes at the Benito Villamarin, death threats from an Atletico official to Betis manager Lorenzo Serra Ferrer and vandalism in the Atletico dressing room.</p>
<p>Betis supporters are unlikely to forget the atmosphere of hostility surrounding that match.</p>
<p>And with Barcelona looking shaky, no one is likely to forget that Betis have an ideal chance to take second place.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEVILLE, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
