<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426026" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: QLT stock recovers, Japan buying seen.</title>
<headline>QLT stock recovers, Japan buying seen.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in QLT Phototherapeutics Inc rose Friday in a recovery from losses the day before and analysts said the buying was partly spurred by company presentations to investors in Japan.</p>
<p>The biotechnology company's shares were up 2.10 to 34.60 in Toronto after dropped 2.75 on Thursday.</p>
<p>QLT chief financial officer Kenneth Galbraith said the see-sawing was driven by normal institutional flows and not by the Japan roadshow. Institutions &quot;are just trading in and out of the stock...but we're still up about 20 percent for the year,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>But First Marathon analyst Cameron Groome said the company's publicity effort, which continues next week in Europe, likely was a boost to the stock.</p>
<p>QLT's drug Photofrin is a light-activated cancer treatment and the company has gained a strong following among institutional investors.</p>
<p>Research presented in Tokyo on Friday on so-called photo-dynamic therapy using Photofrin concluded it &quot;is a potential cure for certain early-stage superficial lung cancers and a cost-effective alternative to surgery.</p>
<p>Analysts said the findings were positive but in line with expectations. QLT hopes to win approval for broader applications later this year for the drug in the United States, where it was approved for palliative treatment of late-stage esophogeal cancer in 1995.</p>
<p>((Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
