<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426001" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-HOLDERS PSG FAIL TO BREAK DOWN AEK ATHENS BARRIER.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-HOLDERS PSG FAIL TO BREAK DOWN AEK ATHENS BARRIER.</headline>
<byline>Rex Gowar</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Cup Winners' Cup holders Paris St Germain were held to a goalless home draw by AEK Athens in the first leg of their quarter-final on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Greek side's goalkeeper Ilias Atmatsidis made three crucial saves from Latin American pair Leonardo and Julio Cesar Dely Valdes to dash PSG's hopes.</p>
<p>Atmatsidis pushed out a point blank header by Panama striker Dely Valdes from a cross by Brazil's Leonardo only 50 seconds into the match, denying off-form PSG the early boost they dearly wanted.</p>
<p>PSG, in deep crisis since January and humiliated by fourth division amateurs in the French Cup six days ago, have not won a match at their Parc des Princes home stadium since early November and have a mountain to climb in the second leg.</p>
<p>Dely Valdes had another header from a Leonardo corner saved on the goal-line by Atmatsidis in the 16th minute, while the goalkeeper dived to push away a Leonardo free kick in the 65th.</p>
<p>Earlier in the second half, when Leonardo went for a dangerous left-footed cross from the right to the far post by striker Patrice Loko a defender appeared to handle the ball but the referee dismissed the Brazilian's penalty claim.</p>
<p>&quot;We could have won, because that was a penalty, and things would be different,&quot; Leonardo said.</p>
<p>The home side, who found it harder to create chances as the match wore on, were whistled off the pitch by their fans and a banner with the word &quot;Shame&quot; was raised behind one of the goals.</p>
<p>The same defence that leaked four goals against Clermont in the French Cup third round match on Saturday which PSG lost on penalties, did not, however, look like conceding one to an unambitious AEK attack until the last 10 minutes.</p>
<p>Then striker Demis Nikolaidis almost hit a killer punch in a rare counter-attack. But despite breaking through, he was chanelled towards goalkeeper Bernard Lama by the centre-backs and his effort was stifled just inside the box.</p>
<p>Lama said: &quot;We were very tired at the end because we adopted a demanding system of play with long 40-metre runs.</p>
<p>&quot;We made the play, it's less tiring to stay in your 18 metres,&quot; he added, referring to the Greeks' defensive game.</p>
<p>PSG manager Ricardo said: &quot;I'm not discouraged. We didn't have too many options to change our game. They were all cooped up at the back.&quot;</p>
<p>Brazilian midfielder Rai said: &quot;I feel confident of qualifying because there (in Athens) they will be obliged to come out and play. We knew they were a very good team playing away.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
