<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42610" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: U.S. bases on Okinawa still a problem, PM says.</title>
<headline>U.S. bases on Okinawa still a problem, PM says.</headline>
<byline>Paul Eckert</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The huge U.S. military presence on the Japanese island of Okinawa remains a problem, Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto said on Tuesday after a meeting with the governor of the island, who wants a total U.S. pullout.</p>
<p>The session between Hashimoto and Okinawa Governor Masahide Ota was considered a key indicator on whether Hashimoto will call early general elections.</p>
<p>It came two days after residents of the island province called overwhelmingly in a referendum for a reduction in the U.S. presence.</p>
<p>Hashimoto must try to placate the Okinawans while not risking strains with the United States, which sees Okinawa as a critical spot for its forces.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe we have secured reliable relations with the Okinawa prefecture,&quot; Hashimoto told a news conference.</p>
<p>But he added, &quot;The Okinawa issues have not ended yet.&quot;</p>
<p>He announced that the central government would pump five billion yen ($46 million) into the Okinawan economy, the poorest region of Japan with average income half the level of Tokyo's.</p>
<p>He also said a special government commission would be appointed to work on reducing the scale of the forces.</p>
<p>Okinawa is home to three-quarters of U.S. military facilities in Japan and hosts about half of the 47,000 U.S. military personnel stationed in the country, although it constitutes less than one percent of Japan's total land area.</p>
<p>Okinawa Governor Ota has been leading the campaign to cut back or eliminate the U.S. bases.</p>
<p>&quot;I frankly told governor Ota that the government will do all it can to resolve the Okinawa issues,&quot; Hashimoto said.</p>
<p>The latest debate was sparked by the rape of an Okinawan schoolgirl by U.S. servicemen last September.</p>
<p>He told Hashimoto he needed more time to consider a response to a central government request that he force local landowners to renew leases for land used by the U.S. military.</p>
<p>A ruling by Japan's Supreme Court on August 28 which rejected Ota's appeal against the government's policy of expropriating private land in Okinawa for use by the U.S. military was expected to put pressure on Ota to compromise.</p>
<p>Okinawans have long resented the noise, aircraft accidents and crime associated with the heavy U.S. military presence, which they say has kept Okinawa from prospering.</p>
<p>Prior to Tuesday's meeting, Hashimoto's cabinet had begun discussing ways to prepare the ground for a deal between Okinawa and the central government.</p>
<p>In a trade-off that analysts expect to unfold in the coming weeks, Tokyo would win Okinawa's blessing for a continued U.S. military presence on the strategically located island and Ota would obtain some face-saving base cuts and a plan to strengthen the island economy.</p>
<p>Officials have floated plans to turn the island prefecture into a free-trade zone and cut the high airfares from mainland Japan, which make many overseas destinations cheaper to reach than subtropical Okinawa, located 1,600 km (1,000 miles) southwest of Tokyo.</p>
<p>Washington on Monday responded to the Sunday vote, in which 90 percent said they favoured a reduction in U.S. forces, saying it would cooperate with Japan in reducing the impact of the military there.</p>
<p>&quot;We seek to reduce the impact of the American military presence in Okinawa consistent with our responsibilities under the mutual security treaty that we have in place with the Japanese,&quot; said State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
