<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426228" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin pauses in cabinet changes, tackles Belarus.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin pauses in cabinet changes, tackles Belarus.</headline>
<byline>Anatoly Verbin</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin took a break on Friday from his drive to reshuffle the government and turned his attention to furthering integration between Russia and neighbouring Belarus.</p>
<p>But the main change expected from a promised cabinet shake-up -- drafting top Kremlin aide, liberal Anatoly Chubais, into the government as its number two -- seemed still on the cards.</p>
<p>Alexander Shokhin, first deputy speaker of the State Duma lower chamber of parliament, told RIA news agency Chubais' appointment was &quot;a decided matter&quot;, adding he expected an official announcement to be made later in the day.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's communist opponents reacted angrily to reports of Chubais' likely promotion. They loathe the youthful reformer for his role in Yeltsin's re-election campaign last summer and also accuse him of profiting from Russia's privatisation programme.</p>
<p>The Duma, dominated by the communists and their allies, passed a resolution by 232 votes to 15 attacking the government and supporting Russia's trade unions, which are planning to stage a day of protests on March 27.</p>
<p>&quot;When the government systematically fails to meet its obligations over payments of salaries, pensions and social allowances, the citizens of Russia have every right to resort to legal forms of social protest,&quot; the document said.</p>
<p>&quot;We, your representatives in the parliament, declare that on March 27, 1997 we will be with you, our voters.&quot;</p>
<p>Communist leader Gennady Zyuganov, who lost to Yeltsin in last July's presidential race, blasted the president's state of the nation address on Thursday as an attempt to foist more painful and unpopular radical reforms on the Russian people.</p>
<p>&quot;The address tried to bring back Gaidaronomics,&quot; Zyuganov told a news conference, referring to Yeltsin's former acting prime minister Yegor Gaidar who launched market reforms in 1992. Chubais was privatisation chief in Gaidar's government.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not obey any orders from Chubais, no matter what his position,&quot; he said, making clear the communists would work for a no-confidence vote in the cabinet if the reformer were appointed. Chubais is currently Kremlin chief-of-staff.</p>
<p>On Thursday Yeltsin marked his return to the helm of power after eight months of illness with a determined and strong speech in which he promised to reshuffle and streamline the government, install order and root out top-level corruption.</p>
<p>&quot;Enough is enough...The time has come to restore order and I will do that,&quot; Yeltsin said.</p>
<p>&quot;The structure and composition of the government must be changed. Energetic and competent people will come...and I will announce these changes in the coming days.&quot;</p>
<p>Kremlin sources said Chubais, 41, would become Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin's number two, taking sole responsibility as first deputy prime minister for supervising economic reforms.</p>
<p>Yeltsin turned his attention to Belarus on Friday when he welcomed its hardline president Alexander Lukashenko to the Kremlin for talks on bringing the two Slav states closer together in line with a deal they signed last April.</p>
<p>&quot;Commonwealth with Belarus is the common desire of our peoples and we will not deviate from this path,&quot; said Yeltsin, who looked energetic and fit, kissing Lukashenko on the cheek.</p>
<p>The two leaders signed a joint declaration that called for integration of their countries' customs, fiscal, transport and energy systems and synchronisation of economic reforms.</p>
<p>The declaration also touched on the sensitive issue of NATO's plans to admit several former Warsaw Pact countries, probably including Belarus's neighbour Poland, later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Our countries are united in their non-acceptance of NATO's plans for eastward expansion, which will create new lines of division in Europe and dangerous confrontation,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
