<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426226" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albanian rebels reject amnesty offer, keep guns.</title>
<headline>Albanian rebels reject amnesty offer, keep guns.</headline>
<byline>Steve Pagani</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rebels in control of the southern Albanian towns of Sarande and Vlore on Friday spurned an amnesty offered by President Sali Berisha and said they would refuse to surrender their weapons until he stepped down.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not giving up our weapons until Berisha resigns,&quot; Fuat Karali, a former police officer and now a member of the town's rebel council told a mass rally in the town square witnessed by a Reuters reporter.</p>
<p>Barricades were strengthened around the Adriatic coastal town of some 15,000 people, visible from the Greek holiday island of Corfu, and people were preparing for a long siege.</p>
<p>The message appeared the same from the port of Vlore, 160 km (110 miles) north of Sarande.</p>
<p>&quot;They said the amnesty will not satisfy them. They want President Berisha to resign and they want their money back,&quot; a Western reporter who reached the town on Thursday night told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>Thousands among Vlore's 80,000 people had invested their savings in a locally-based pyramid investment scheme which crumbled in January.</p>
<p>The demise of pyramid schemes at the beginning of the year sparked weeks of protests which erupted into anarchy last weekend as rioters went on the rampage, seizing arms from police and army depots and looting shops. At least 16 people have been reported killed in Vlore, many by wild shooting.</p>
<p>&quot;The town is divided between ordinary people and a mafia but they are united over calling for Berisha's resignation,&quot; the reporter in Vlore said. &quot;The opposition, though, still has some credibility here.&quot;</p>
<p>The government had reestablished control in the southern town of Gjirokaster, where trouble broke out at the weekend, a resident of the town said by telephone.</p>
<p>Berisha, who held talks with all political parties on Thursday, called a halt to a military push to crush the insurrection and offered an amnesty if insurgents surrendered their arms by six a.m. (0500 GMT) on Sunday.</p>
<p>The United States welcomed the announcement. U.S. Defence Secretary William Cohen, speaking in Rome, said the United States and Italy were prepared to work together to help resolve the situation.</p>
<p>&quot;This is primarily a political problem to be resolved and certainly not a military one but there has been a ceasefire and that is a very productive sign,&quot; Cohen told a news conference.</p>
<p>Italy has urged Berisha and the Albanian opposition to form a broad-based government to resolve the crisis.</p>
<p>The opposition Forum for Democracy, grouping 11 parties, said on Friday the meeting with Berisha on Thursday was just the first step towards a settlement.</p>
<p>&quot;This was a statement not an agreement. It was only a small step,&quot; Democratic Alliance leader Neritan Ceka said in a statement.</p>
<p>The Forum has called for an end to the state of emergency declared on Sunday and the establishment of a technocrat government to prepare for early elections.</p>
<p>Berisha on Friday held talks with Dutch Foreign Minister Hans Van Mierlo, whose country currently holds the EU's rotating chairmanship. Van Mierlo held talks on his way to Tirana on Thursday in Rome and Athens -- the two capitals most concerned by any flood of migrants if order breaks down in Albania.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands of impoverished Albanians made a mass exodus to Italy in 1991 after 45 years of Stalinist rule crumbled. Thousands more crossed illegally over the border into Greece to find work to help families back home.</p>
<p>Some 50 Albanians arrived by boat in southern Italy on Friday after another 29 made the crossing on Wednesday. Italy says it will send them back.</p>
<p>A delegation from the Council of Europe was also in Tirana and was holding talks with all political parties on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
