<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426361" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - March 8.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - March 8.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-03-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Sarajevo press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>OSLOBODJENJE</p>
<p>- Ruling Moslem Party of Democratic Action (SDA) supports the decision by the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) to postpone holding municipal elections in Bosnia for September, President of SDA's main board, Halid Genjac says.</p>
<p>- Bosnian Moslem co-prime minister Haris Silajdzic and international mediator for Bosnia's Moslem-Croat federation Christian Schwarz-Schilling agree that forming special ties between Bosnian Serb republic and Yugoslavia was an effort to destabilise Bosnia and peace process.</p>
<p>- Moslem chairman of Bosnia's collective presidency Alija Izetbegovic retires seven Bosnian army generals.</p>
<p>- The Office of High Representative Carl Bildt announces that the Sarajevo canton has paid its outstanding gas bill to a Russian gas company but that the Serb republic claims it was unable to pay its share.</p>
<p>DNEVNI AVAZ</p>
<p>- Agreement on special ties between Bosnian Serb republic and Yugoslavia is only a draft until parliament of Bosnia and Herzegovina ratifies it, Michael Steiner, deputy to the international High Representative for Bosnia, says.</p>
<p>- Friday's Vienna meeting on implementation of the international arbitration's decision on disputed Bosnian town of Brcko is organised mainly to mobilise potential donors for reconstruction of the town, spokesman for the Office of High Representative Carl Bildt says. -- Sarajevo newsroom, +387-71-663-864.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
