<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426571" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore seeking new growth markets beyond Asia.</title>
<headline>Singapore seeking new growth markets beyond Asia.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore is seeking new markets in Africa, Russia, Eastern Europe, the Middle East and Latin America to sustain long term growth of its economy, the Trade Development Board (TDB) said on Friday.</p>
<p>To help Singapore companies enter new markets, TDB's commmittee on international trade recommended that a special fund be set up jointly by the government, state-linked companies and the private sector.</p>
<p>Ong Chit Chung, chairman of the subcommittee on market development, said the fund for each new region could be between Singapore $100 million (US$70 million) and S$200 million.</p>
<p>Singapore's foray into Africa would focus on South Africa, while in Eastern Europe, the Czech Republic, Hungary, Poland and Slovenia offered the best potential for local firms, Ong said at a news conference.</p>
<p>A trade mission would visit Central Europe in May, followed by a two-month market study which would cover the major Eastern European economies.</p>
<p>The TDB would also set up a trade office in Moscow and was planning a trade and investment mission to Russia, signalling a shift in focus from the Far East to European Russia, where there was a larger consumer base and disposable income, he said.</p>
<p>Singapore's focus in Latin America would be on Brazil, Mexico, Chile, Argentina and Peru. Last year, Singapore's exports to the region rose by 23 percent to S$2.6 billion while imports grew by 27 percent to S$1.8 billion.</p>
<p>The TDB's plans in the Middle East this year would include trade missions to Turkey and Israel. Study missions to Egypt and Jordan were also being planned.</p>
<p>Bilateral trade between Singapore and the Middle East rose 21.2 percent to S$14.7 billion in 1996.</p>
<p>Singapore's external trade in 1996 totalled S$361.5 billion, up 5.1 percent from 1995. Its trade with the priority markets -- Southeast Asia, China and India -- recorded a 10-percent rise.</p>
<p>($1=S$1.432)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
