<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426581" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai markets ride finance storm, caution remains.</title>
<headline>Thai markets ride finance storm, caution remains.</headline>
<byline>Rajan Moses</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai financial markets ended a stormy week on a positive note on Friday as some investors appeared to digest a major revamp of the troubled finance sector and withdrawals from weak finance companies slowed.</p>
<p>But analysts cautioned that despite the turnaround after four successive days of hard knocks, the road ahead remained rocky.</p>
<p>&quot;It could well drag on for a few more months. We might see some Thai macroeconomic indicators improve, but this is a different microeconomic problem that will linger on until investors are totally convinced,&quot; said the head of research at a foreign brokerage who declined to be named.</p>
<p>The stock market finished up 2.19 percent as bargain hunters bought cheap banking and finance stocks that brokers said may have been oversold this week.</p>
<p>The baht firmed late, rising to 25.920/930 against the dollar from 25.948/970 earlier in the day.</p>
<p>&quot;In the afternoon, there was a lot more selling of dollars as the market became more settled in response to measures taken to help the finance sector. People feel the action might do good,&quot; said a Siam Commercial Bank dealer.</p>
<p>In a sweeping restructuring, Thai authorities on Monday ordered 10 finance firms, hard-hit by a liquidity crunch, to raise capital by a total of 8.25 billion baht ($317 million).</p>
<p>They also told banks and finance companies to raise provisions for bad loans, primarily to the depressed property sector, to 115 percent and 120 percent respectively from 100 percent.</p>
<p>Some analysts said a statement by IMF managing director Michel Camdessus expressing confidence in Thai authorities' handling of the economy had helped.</p>
<p>&quot;I see them taking steps to address one of the vulnerabilities of the Thai economy... I am confident that the measures and the programme for the future will have the potential to carry the economy back on track for sustainable growth,&quot; Camdessus said in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Camdessus's words were &quot;a strong and encouraging statement&quot;, a Hong-Kong based Peregrine Investment executive said.</p>
<p>A run on deposits this week from the troubled finance firms slowed to about 3.5 billion baht in withdrawals on Thursday compared with a total of 10.4 billion baht cleared on Tuesday and Wednesday, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market seems to have calmed down, and investors have come to realise that the measures imposed by the Bank of Thailand will eventually strengthen the sector,&quot; a central bank official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Analysts said the bitter pills prescribed to financial institutions would be hard to swallow, but had the potential to cure the illness.</p>
<p>&quot;The measures, especially on the sub-standard assets, will usher a long and painful adjustment period. But at the end, we think the authorities did the right thing,&quot; said Suphavudh Saicheau of Phatra Thanakit Plc, one of Thailand's biggest finance and securities firms.</p>
<p>&quot;Many finance firms might see zero profit for this year and next. And those small companies who cannot meet the requirement will eventually be taken over, leading to a more solid and healthy sector,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The troubles were exacerbated by slow economic growth and a liquidity crunch caused by the Bank of Thailand's policy of maintaining high interest rates to deter speculation in the baht, which was hit by devaluation rumours last month.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Amnuay Viravan said on Friday that his ministry would issue zero-coupon bonds to raise funds to help sick finance firms.</p>
<p>($1 = 26 baht)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
