<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426569" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China gives world rare glimpse of army.</title>
<headline>China gives world rare glimpse of army.</headline>
<byline>Benjamin Kang Lim</byline>
<dateline>YANGCUN, China 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>China gave the outside world a rare glimpse of its army on Friday in a move that visitors called a confidence-building exercise.</p>
<p>The People's Liberation Army allowed an inspection of one of its crack divisions, opening its doors to visiting delegates from the ASEAN Regional Forum -- a group that discusses regional security issues and is now meeting in Beijing.</p>
<p>A brass band from the 196th Infantry Division of the Tianjin Garrison played as delegates arrived at the barracks at Yangcun, between the Chinese capital Beijing and the port city of Tianjin.</p>
<p>Bayonet-carrying soldiers marched past a grandstand and young recruits showed off martial arts skills.</p>
<p>From a distance of 100 metres (328 feet), snipers fired at targets that sprung up Chinese characters with each hit, forming a slogan reading: &quot;Politically qualified, militarily tough, excellence in practice and strict discipline.&quot;</p>
<p>The same division -- which German Chancellor Helmut Kohl inspected in November 1995 -- also gave visitors a glimpse of its men firing 155 mm cannons at moving targets.</p>
<p>Soldiers then stormed a building in a mock attack.</p>
<p>Division Commander Senior Colonel Mu Shoujun gave the visitors, led by Philippine Undersecretary of Foreign Affairs Rodolfo Severino, a tour of the soldiers' living quarters.</p>
<p>Towering above the entrance to the barracks was a statue of revolutionary leader Mao Zedong, with an inscription reading: &quot;Always in the heart of the army&quot;.</p>
<p>Visitors were also shown an army farm that supplies produce to the troops and even sells surplus on the local market.</p>
<p>&quot;They're trying to give the impression that they are opening up. It's a good start,&quot; said a visitor who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;The depth of their sincerity is unknown, but it is building confidence,&quot; said the delegate, who is attending the three-day meeting.</p>
<p>Severino said the meeting was designed to reduce tension.</p>
<p>&quot;What we want to do is reduce the chances of miscalculation, increase predictability and therefore reduce suspicion and increase confidence,&quot; said Severino, who is co-chairing the meeting.</p>
<p>The ASEAN Regional Forum was initiated in 1992, allowing ASEAN -- Brunei, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam -- to discuss security issues with the United States, EU, Russia, China, Japan, South Korea, Australia, New Zealand, Laos, Cambodia and Papua New Guinea.</p>
<p>China's military build-up in recent years has caused anxiety among neighbours, but it vehemently denies it is a threat to Asia or the rest of the world.</p>
<p>China's three million-strong army -- the world's biggest -- ruffled feathers in the region in March 1996 when it conducted missile tests and war games near Taiwan, which Beijing regards as a renegade province.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="YANGCUN, China"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
