<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426645" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore backs U.S. move to cut phone costs.</title>
<headline>Singapore backs U.S. move to cut phone costs.</headline>
<byline>Chris Johnson</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore Telecommunications Ltd (SingTel) said on Friday it backed U.S. moves to cut payments between telephone companies for the completion of international calls.</p>
<p>But SingTel chief Lee Hsien Yang told reporters the company thought these payments -- formally called accounting rate settlements -- should be agreed internationally and not imposed unilaterally.</p>
<p>In December, the U.S. telephone industry regulator, the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), proposed cutting accounting rates drastically to reduce its own payouts under the arrangements, which are caused by an imbalance between incoming and outgoing U.S. calls.</p>
<p>Lee said Singapore was a slight net outpayer of settlements with roughly 10 percent more outgoing calls than incoming calls.</p>
<p>&quot;Generally Singapore Telecom supports a move to lower accounting rates because we feel that we would benefit from it,&quot; he said. &quot;Having said that, we have significant reservations on the manner of the FCC's benchmark which has been proposed.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We think the issue should be dealt with in the proper process and that it is not something that the U.S. can unilaterally impose on other countries and other companies of its own volition,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said SingTel already had the lowest accounting rates with the United States of any carrier in the region.</p>
<p>Analysts say one of the reasons for the current gross imbalance between the United States and the rest of the world is the spread of callback services, which allow customers to pay the lowest rates offered internationally for any telephone call.</p>
<p>For a small fee, these services, mainly U.S.-based, call back overseas customers and provide them with a U.S. dial-tone. They then bill the customer at the U.S. rate for the call instead of the usual rate in the caller's country.</p>
<p>According to SingTel's own figures, there are now roughly three times as many telephone calls made from the United States to Singapore as from Singapore to the United States.</p>
<p>Callbacks are legal in Singapore but are officially discouraged and their advertising in mass media is not allowed.</p>
<p>Lee denied SingTel wanted callback services to be banned but said they, and similar refile services, were at the heart of the U.S. call imbalance, which resulted in the U.S. paying out around US$5 billion a year in accounting rate settlements.</p>
<p>&quot;If these activities ceased to take place, the U.S. imbalance would also cease to exist,&quot; Lee told reporters. &quot;If the imbalance was so detrimental to the U.S. interest as the FCC makes out, perhaps it is also within the U.S. control to prevent these activities from taking place.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that the U.S. chooses to continue to promote and allow these activities perhaps indicates that commercially it is really a viable business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the whole FCC argument about its $5 billion outpayment fails to take cognition of the other aspects of the money which is being collected from customers. (They) are looking at the expense of this business and not looking at the revenue side of the business.</p>
<p>&quot;The suggestion that a poor old lady in Texas is subsidising Singapore Telecom...is not the entire truth,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
