<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426603" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Film on Filipina maid Balabagan causes furore.</title>
<headline>Film on Filipina maid Balabagan causes furore.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A film about a Filipina Moslem maid who escaped execution in the United Arab Emirates (UAE) failed to premiere after the Foreign Office ruled its screening could harm ties with the UAE, officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>Film director Joel Lamangan accused the state's Movie and Television Review and Classification Board (MTRCB) of abuse of power after it refused to release a permit for the public exhibition of the film, &quot;Sarah Balabagan Story&quot;.</p>
<p>The film is based on the story of teenager Balabagan, who was sentenced to death by a UAE court for stabbing to death her Arab employer in 1994. Balabagan claimed her employer had tried to rape her.</p>
<p>The sentence was reduced to one year in jail and 100 lashes after UAE President Sheikh Zaid bin Sultan al-Nahayan intervened. Balabagan received a hero's welcome when she returned to Manila last year.</p>
<p>Balabagan and the film's cast arrived at a Manila cinema on Thursday evening for the premiere, but left disappointed after being told the MTRCB had refused to release a permit for the film's screening.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a grave abuse of authority by the MTRCB... This is clear harassment,&quot; Lamangan said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our position is that showing the film could embarrass the UAE and thereby adversely affect the good relations between the UAE and the Philippines,&quot; a Foreign Office spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;It could also prejudice the interests of thousands of Filipinos working in the UAE,&quot; the spokesman added.</p>
<p>About 80,000 Filipinos work in the UAE.</p>
<p>Separately, a group of Moslems has petitioned a Manila court to halt the screening of the Balabagan film, calling the film &quot;a great disgrace and insult to the high morality of Moslem women&quot;.</p>
<p>The court has scheduled a hearing for Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
