<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426657" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Dragonair becomes OAA's 18th member.</title>
<headline>Dragonair becomes OAA's 18th member.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong Dragon Airlines (Dragonair) has become the 18th member of the Orient Airlines Association, the OAA said in a press statement.</p>
<p>Industry sources said that Dragonair's participation is also seen as significant as the move may eventually lead to mainland Chinese carriers becoming members.</p>
<p>At present none are members due to Taiwan's China Airlines participation in the OAA.</p>
<p>The sources noted that mainland China National Aviation Corporation Group holds about 36 percent in Dragonair with CITIC Pacific owning 28 percent. Swire Pacific Ltd and Cathay Pacific Airways Ltd together hold about 26 percent.</p>
<p>Leading Chinese carriers such as China Southern Airlines and China Eastern Airlines Corporation Ltd are seen as potential OAA candidates, the sources said.</p>
<p>The director general of the Manila-based OAA, Richard Stirland added that Dragonair's membership is a further move towards his goal of making the organisation totally representative of scheduled international transport in the region.</p>
<p>The OAA's other members are Air New Zealand Ltd, Air Nuigini, All Nippon Airways, Ansett Australia, Asiana Airlines, Cathay Pacific Airways Ltd, China Airlines, EVA Airways, Garuda Indonesia, Japan Airlines Co Ltd, Korean Air Lines Co Owe, Malaysia Airline System Bhd, Philippine Airlines, Qantas Airways, Royal Brunei Airlines, Singapore Airlines and Thai Airways International Ltd.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 8982 Fax + 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
