<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426649" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine sugar miller creditors form committee.</title>
<headline>Philippine sugar miller creditors form committee.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 32 banks which lent money to Victorias Milling Co, the country's largest miller, on Friday set up a committee to negotiate with the company.</p>
<p>&quot;The representatives of the creditors will in effect study and coordinate with the management of the company.&quot; the head of the committee, Jose Pastor Puno, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Puno, who is first vice president of PCIBank which is one of the creditors, said the committee would meet on Monday to consider the various alternatives.</p>
<p>An official of Philippine National Bank, who said the bank had lent short-term loans of 349.764 pesos to Victorias, said: &quot;I think we will see a long-term restructuring of the account.&quot;</p>
<p>An official of Land Bank of the Philippines, which gave loans of over 500 million pesos to Victorias, said the assets covered by the mortgage trust deed would be reappraised and that the expected value was enough to cover the creditors' exposure.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Victorias Milling officials met with representatives of the 32 banks and secured an &quot;agreement in principle&quot; on a 90-day moratorium on loans amounting to 4.423 billion pesos.</p>
<p>Victorias wanted a moratorium on the principal repayments.</p>
<p>Victorias said its financial problems were caused by a glut in the local sugar market but analysts said it was worsened by an aggressive expansion programme funded through debt.</p>
<p>Of the total outstanding loans of 4.423 billion pesos, 2.778 billion are short-term loans and analysts said these could cause problems as the company would not be in a position to repay them at maturity.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8934</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
