<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426743" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul stocks end higher, buying interest fizzles.</title>
<headline>Seoul stocks end higher, buying interest fizzles.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks closed higher on Friday on buying of small individual shares, induced by hopes of changes to the real-name system, brokers said.</p>
<p>But they said general investor interest fizzled on fears of weakening market fundamentals, including high interest rates.</p>
<p>The composite index closed 3.11 points higher at 681.22.</p>
<p>&quot;The initial fever chilled as investors realised the process of correcting the financial system would take some time,&quot; said a Hyundai Securities broker.</p>
<p>The yields on three-year corporates, South Korea's benchmark rates, rose to 12.53 percent on Friday from 12.50 on Thursday.  </p>
<p>Trading volume totalled 37.38 million shares, compared with 41.27 million on Thursday.</p>
<p>Gainers outpaced losers 478 to 336 with 105 unchanged.</p>
<p>Brokers said expectations that the foreign shareholding limit would be expanded from April waned as the government showed no signs of such moves.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will be dull next week if the expansion of the limit is delayed,&quot; said Choo Hee-yup of Dongwon Securities. &quot;Falling customer deposits with securities houses are also a cause of concern.&quot; Such deposits were now estimated at 2.81 trillion won, down from 3.05 trillion in mid-February.  </p>
<p>Shares in Shinhwa Co, a small telecommunications equipment producer, went limit-up after the company announced an ambitious sales plan. Shinhwa rose 1,400 won to its limit of 19,400.</p>
<p>The company said its sales would reach 180 billion won this year from 35 billion in 1996, helped by the development of a communication and tracking device for vehicles.</p>
<p>Shares in Woo Sung Food and Honam Food were halted for trading on news that the companies were selling parts of their operations to Coca-Cola Korea Bottling Co, a unit of Coca-Cola Co, the Korea Stock Exchange said.  </p>
<p>Woo Sung closed 1,900 won higher at 25,900, Honam rose 1,500 won to 27,500.</p>
<p>Kyung Dong City Gas, which began trading for the first time on Friday, rose 3,200 won to 43,200.</p>
<p>Brokers said foreign investors unwound bank shares because of a dim view of recovery in the banking industry, which was hit by the Hanbo Steel failure.</p>
<p>Foreigners were estimated to have sold about 700,000 bank shares, brokers said.</p>
<p>The won's weakness against the dollar also helped keep foreign investors in the sidelines, they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
