<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426730" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: NCR Corp sees growth in selected Asian countries up to 24 pct. [CORRECTED 10:35 GMT 8/3]</title>
<headline>NCR Corp sees growth in selected Asian countries up to 24 pct. [CORRECTED 10:35 GMT 8/3]</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S.-based information systems company NCR Corp said on Friday it expected its Asian-based businesses to grow at around twice the rate of the company globally.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect our world wide growth to be around nine to 12 percent over the next couple of years. The growth in Asia should be around double that,&quot; said Lars Nyberg, chairman and chief executive officer of NCR Corp.</p>
<p>Nyberg was referring to four high-growth Asian countries -- China, Indonesia, India and Korea -- not the entire geographic region. In particular, the comments do not apply to Japan, Australia and New Zealand, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>The company's automatic teller machines and database systems will emerge as its main sources of business in the Asia-Pacific region Nyberg told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;What we offer in this region will not be different to what we offer in other parts of the world,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nyberg gave no details of his projections for the company.</p>
<p>Nyberg was in Malaysia as part of NCR's involvement in the country's Multimedia Super Corridor project, which is to be Malaysia's information technology backbone.</p>
<p>NCR is part of an advisory panel of companies that will advise the Malaysian government on the implementation of a multi-purpose smart card and on electronic automation of government departments.</p>
<p>(Corrects to clarify comments by NCR chairman and CEO Lars Nyberg to show that prediction on Asian growth referred to four high-growth countries -- China, Indonesia, India and Korea -- not the entire geographic region).</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
