<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426853" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: PRESS DIGEST - Taiwan newspapers - March 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Taiwan newspapers - March 7.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Taiwan press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>Newspaper headlines</p>
<p>CHINA TIMES - National Assembly member nabbed in gangster crackdown.</p>
<p>Central bank governor Sheu Yuan-dong vows to maintain stable-to-loose monetary policy.</p>
<p>UNITED DAILY NEWS - Canada to release six Taiwan sailors in stowaway case.</p>
<p>Cooperative unions are among 11 industries to be incorporated into Labour Law in 1998.</p>
<p>LIBERTY TIMES - Central banker Sheu says central bank a bit concerned about stock market fever.</p>
<p>Taipei mayor Chen Shui-bian rejects &quot;reunification overture&quot; from visiting Beijing cultural group.</p>
<p>COMMERCIAL TIMES - Central bank says will keep monetary policy stable-to-loose, but not too loose.</p>
<p>Formosa group chairman Wang Yung-ching says will not build China power plant without government approval.</p>
<p>ECONOMIC DAILY NEWS - Privatisation for &quot;big three&quot; state-run commercial banks to be completed by 1998 at earliest.</p>
<p>Sheu Yuan-dong says foreign exchange rate at &quot;reasonable&quot; level.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
