<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="426952" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: FEATURE - Filipino politicians build their images.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Filipino politicians build their images.</headline>
<byline>Ruben Alabastro</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Secretary Roberto de Ocampo strides into a hotel and executes a roundhouse taekwondo kick to show he has the vigour to lead the Philippines into the 21st Century.</p>
<p>Senator and anti-graft fighter Miriam Santiago says she will do much more: if elected president, she will strap on bombs and dive into the legislature to rid the country of corrupt 20th Century politicians.</p>
<p>Far from being campaign gimmicks, de Ocampo's display of his martial arts skill and Santiago's explosions of bombast are part of serious image-building efforts by a clutch of politicians aspiring to rule one of Asia's most rambunctious democracies.</p>
<p>Fifteen months before presidential elections, at least a dozen men and women have been tipped in Manila's media as potential aspirants to the Philippines' most powerful office.</p>
<p>&quot;I think people know I have other means of persuasion at my disposal,&quot; de Ocampo, a taekwondo black belt, said when asked how the finance ministry was able to post double digit growth in tax collections during his term.</p>
<p>A Manila newspaper ran a front page picture showing the U.S.-educated de Ocampo unleashing a mean roundhouse in what may be an effort to dispel doubts that he is just a technocrat who knows nothing but economics, analysts say.</p>
<p>A WOMAN BORN FOR WAR</p>
<p>A former judge who says she &quot;eats death threats for breakfast&quot; and calls her critics &quot;certifiable idiots,&quot; Santiago cultivates an image of a woman born for war.</p>
<p>Popular among the country's young voters, she vows to sweep all crooks out of the government if she is elected.</p>
<p>&quot;I'll strap my anatomy with hand grenades and hurl myself into the first assembly attended by traditional politicians,&quot; she said in a recent television interview when asked the first thing she would do if she won the presidency.</p>
<p>&quot;That way, I'll probably be of genuine and authentic service to the Filipino community by giving way to the next generation.&quot;</p>
<p>Even President Fidel Ramos, who turns 69 this month, is not above showing his physical abilities to prove he is still as fit as anyone to lead the country into the next millenium.</p>
<p>Seeking to squelch rumours of his ill health, Ramos took reporters to the Presidential Palace pool recently and swam six laps -- 25 metres (80 feet) end to end -- with seeming ease.</p>
<p>Two days before he flew to India to begin a five-nation tour of Asia and the Middle East, Ramos also stripped to his shorts at a hospital and trudged on a treadmill to show he was ready for the hectic trip.</p>
<p>The swim and the treadmill walk coincided with speculation that Ramos may seek to amend the Constitution to allow him to seek a second term after his six-year tenure ends in June 1998.</p>
<p>Ramos denies any such plan, but the speculation persists.</p>
<p>Another presidential dreamer, House Speaker Jose de Venecia, recently received World Boxing Council super-flyweight champion Gerry Penalosa in his office. The next day newspapers showed him squaring off against the new sports idol, fists at the ready.</p>
<p>A DANCER AND A MAN WITH A 'PORNOGRAPHIC MEMORY'</p>
<p>Senator Gloria Macapagal-Arroyo, a graceful ballroom dancer, danced the boogie on stage when she ran for re-election in 1995. Her showmanship -- and her reputation as an economist -- drew 16 million votes, the most by any politician in any election here.</p>
<p>A favourite among the presidential hopefuls, Arroyo may dance all the way to the presidency next year, analysts say.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, an unsexy waistline may prevent Vice-President Joseph Estrada from executing a karate kick or doing a pirouette on stage, but the man widely seen as the candidate to beat in 1998 has other eye-catching methods.</p>
<p>Known for his shaky command of English, he endears himself to voters by deliberaly mangling the language.</p>
<p>For example, asked how he remembers people's names so easily, he says, &quot;I have a pornographic memory.&quot;</p>
<p>About the only potential candidate with no flair for theatrics is Defence Secretary Renato de Villa, a soft-spoken man with the reputation of being aloof and distant.</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing quirky about him is his being straight,&quot; his spokeswoman, Lulu Ilustre, told Reuters. &quot;Even to make him laugh is feat enough.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
