<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="427034" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ComEd Zion 2 nuke seen restarting mid-April.</title>
<headline>ComEd Zion 2 nuke seen restarting mid-April.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Commonwealth Edison Co said Friday its 1,040 megawatt (MW) Zion 2 nuclear unit will likely restart in mid-April after shutting last September for refueling.</p>
<p>The adjacent unit 1, also rated at 1,040 MW and shut since Feb 21, will likely return to service in early May following surveillance testing, company spokesman Gary Wald said.</p>
<p>Following the outage, the unit is expected to operate around 40 percent power until it goes off line in September for refueling.</p>
<p>Both units are located in Zion, Ill.  </p>
<p>Earlier this week, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) said it would meet with ComEd today to discuss improper procedures while Zion 1 was shutting down on Feb 21.</p>
<p>The NRC said three weeks of investigations began on Feb 25 over how a control room operator improperly moved control rods during the shutdown.</p>
<p>The NRC cited in a statement the apparent failure of management to review plant conditions before the rods were withdrawn by the operator.</p>
<p>ComEd was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>All four units at both the LaSalle and Zion nuclear plants were placed on the NRC's watchlist on Jan 29.</p>
<p>Separately, ComEd's 794 MW Dresden 3 unit is still scheduled to go off line March 30 for refueling, while the 789 MW Quad Cities 2 unit is still slated to restart in early May after shutting down March 1 for refueling.</p>
<p>ComEd is a subsidiary of Unicom Corp.</p>
<p>((--New York Power Desk +212-859-1628))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
