<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="427023" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Flooded Kentucky faces crest of Ohio River.</title>
<headline>Flooded Kentucky faces crest of Ohio River.</headline>
<byline>Michael Lindenberger</byline>
<dateline>LOUISVILLE, Ky 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Authorities offered free tetanus shots and ordered hundreds of thousands of Kentuckians to boil drinking water on Friday as dirty floodwaters from the rising Ohio River crept higher.</p>
<p>The swollen river was expected to crest on Friday evening at 16 feet (5 metres) above its normal flood stage at Louisville. The city was protected by massive flood walls that should hold back the river's highest crest since 1964.</p>
<p>Hundreds of homes were swamped in smaller towns along the Ohio River, the watery border between Kentucky and Indiana, where residents and National Guard troops scrambled to construct sandbag barriers and pump out the relentless floodwaters.</p>
<p>Nearly 200,000 residents across Kentucky were told to boil tap water before drinking it after floodwaters submerged at least 40 residential water systems. Tetanus and diptheria shots were offered free to those who have not been inoculated recently in flood-ravaged areas in Kentucky and in Cincinnati, Ohio.</p>
<p>&quot;The floodwaters were muddy at the very least, and possibly contaminated with other substances,&quot; said Mike Lynch of the Kentucky Disaster and Emergency Services.</p>
<p>Downstream from Louisville at West Point, Kentucky, two dozen stubborn residents stayed behind as swirling waters from the Ohio River engulfed the town.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people just don't want to come out,&quot; said Mililani Chun, spokesperson for the Hardin County Disaster and Emergency Services. &quot;Yesterday we were in a speedboat and we ran across a man who was fishing from his backyard.&quot;</p>
<p>Eddie Moore of the Westpoint Fire Department said an elderly woman he offered to rescue from her marooned home refused. &quot;She said she has lived through two floods before and she is going to live through this one,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The body of a woman motorist in western Kentucky who had been missing since Saturday was found when local floodwaters receded, raising Kentucky's death toll to 17. A total of 56 people have died in violent storms and flooding in the past week.</p>
<p>Forecasts for rain this weekend in hard-hit western Kentucky may worsen an already bad situation, officials said.</p>
<p>The Ohio was receding fairly rapidly in Cincinnati, but was not expected to crest downstream in Evansville, Indiana, until Tuesday. The river then feeds into the Mississippi River, which widens out and should not pose a flood danger.</p>
<p>In areas where the water had receded mud-caked homes and ruined possessions depressed residents who were gradually being allowed back to try to pick up the pieces of their lives.</p>
<p>After seeing her ruined home in hard-hit Falmouth, Kentucky, south of Cincinnati, Becky Butts told a television reporter, &quot;There's nothing left. We lost everything.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like a hurricane's gone through here,&quot; Ken Craycraft of Kentucky's Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources said of Falmouth and nearby Butler. Both towns were inundated up to roof-top level in a matter of hours when about a foot (30 cm) of rain soaked the region over the weekend, sending the Licking River roaring into the countryside.</p>
<p>The federal government added more than two dozen counties in Indiana and Kentucky to its disaster declaration, which provides residents with low-interest loans and other aid.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOUISVILLE, Ky"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
