<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42728" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Korea semiconductor group urges speedy tariff cut.</title>
<headline>Korea semiconductor group urges speedy tariff cut.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Korean Semiconductor Industry Association has asked the government to speed up the scheduled elimination of tariffs on imported chips, the group said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>South Korea has already committed itself to the World Trade Organisation to cut the tariffs from eight percent to four percent by 1998 and to zero by 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;The association, as a representative of Korean semiconductor producers, is asking the government to accelerate the elimination of tariffs on semiconductors,&quot; an association statement said.</p>
<p>An association official said South Korea, which plans to participate in the World Semiconductor Council led by the United States and Japan, must drop tariffs on semiconductors sooner rather than later.</p>
<p>&quot;The earlier elimination of tariffs would help expand the demand of semiconductors and would benefit the Korean economy,&quot; said association vice chairman Kim Chi-luck. &quot;Internationally, it will contribute to expanding global free trade.&quot;</p>
<p>He also said it would contribute to honing international competitiveness of South Korean electronics manufacturers which have relied on imports for 75 percent of their semiconductor demand.</p>
<p>South Korea ranks number three in the world dynamic random access memory (DRAM) chip production but lags in the non-memory chip fields such as micro-processors and application specific integrated circuits.</p>
<p>Semiconductors represent about 20 percent of South Korea's total exports but falling prices have hit the country's overseas shipments hard.</p>
<p>The state-funded Korea Institute for Industrial Economics and Trade forecast on Tuesday that semiconductor exports would fall to $16.5 billion this year from $22.1 billion last year. This is even lower than the trade ministry's revised forecast of $18 billion.</p>
<p>Yonhap news agency said South Korea's trade shortfall for the whole of 1996 might exceed $20 billion if semiconductor exports fell as the institute forecast.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
