<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="427269" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Amid EMU clamour, LIFFE traders say &quot;no way&quot;.</title>
<headline>Amid EMU clamour, LIFFE traders say &quot;no way&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Lisa Wilson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>European politicians are pushing for it, many economists say it could work, but dealers on the floor of one of the world's busiest financial exchanges say European economic and monetary union (EMU) doesn't have a chance.</p>
<p>The grand design to merge currencies from the Mediterranean to Northern Europe into the euro gets little support from traders at the London International Financial Futures and Options Exchange (LIFFE).</p>
<p>A Reuters survey of 20 LIFFE dealers showed on Friday that 12, or 60 percent, thought EMU would not start on schedule on January 1 1999. Four, or 20 percent, said it would meet the deadline but then fall apart shortly afterwards.</p>
<p>The remaining four traders thought EMU would go ahead on time and succeed.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole concept of monetary union is nonsensical,&quot; said one trader at a Japanese bank in London.</p>
<p>&quot;It's only a handful of Europhiles who think it's got any chance at all. We're all too different culturally, and with too different economies.&quot;</p>
<p>This contrasts sharply with the views expressed by leading economists around Europe.</p>
<p>A Reuters poll of 45 experts in February showed the average prediction for a timely start to EMU was 83 percent, unchanged from January and down from 86 percent in December.</p>
<p>Of course, the LIFFE traders polled are not impartial observers. Questions about EMU tend to get lost in the clamour of concerns that a single currency would cut the numbers of contracts traded on the floor of Europe's biggest futurtes and options market and thereby hit jobs.</p>
<p>Many also expressed concern that if Britain were outside monetary union, it would undermine London's position as Europe's main financial centre.</p>
<p>But the problems cited by LIFFE traders -- those who buy and sell the instruments of the financial markets -- are not merely prompted by the &quot;Europhobia&quot; -- prevalent among some British newspapers and politicians.</p>
<p>Italy came up again and again as the most problematic element in the EMU equation, according to traders.</p>
<p>Apart from worries that Italy would attempt to &quot;fudge&quot; the Maastricht economic requirements for entry and undermine the project, traders also cited such diverse elements as the Albanian troubles and the possibility of Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi being put on trial.</p>
<p>One trader at a U.S. bank said civil unrest in Albania could lead to a refugee crisis that would add to Italy's budget difficulties.</p>
<p>&quot;When a delay or postponement to EMU start getting talked about in the pits, it's always BTPs that get hammered,&quot; said a trader at a major British bank in reference to Italian government bonds. &quot;The markets are looking for a soft target, and Italy is always the weak link.&quot;</p>
<p>Germany was also a matter of concern. Several traders said German economic growth would thwart its attempts to meet the Maastricht criteria, while others said that if German Chancellor Helmut Kohl was not re-elected next year, the driving force behind EMU would disappear.</p>
<p>However, for those traders convinced that EMU would be viable from day one, political will was set to win over all other trials.</p>
<p>&quot;Germany and France won't allow EMU to fail,&quot; said a trader at a French bank in London. &quot;By hook or by crook, probably by crook, they will get it through somehow.&quot;</p>
<p>This was a view shared by traders who believed that EMU would go ahead on time, but would be weak at the start and crumble soon after.</p>
<p>A trader at a British brokerage said the drive towards a single currency was clouding politicians' judgement about how much austerity voters will accept in pursuit of a single currency.</p>
<p>&quot;You've got post-war record unemployment in Germany, and that sort of thing creates unrest,&quot; he said, taking a moment out of the hectic dealing in a pit where British interest rate futures are traded. &quot;After one fiscal cycle, social and political problems will show up across Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>A recent survey carried out by Germany's Der Speigel magazine showed that 77 percent of Germans want EMU delayed.</p>
<p>But European Commissioner Thibault de Silguy recently told a newspaper that talk of an EMU delay was &quot;playing with fire&quot; and could scuttle the currency's chances.</p>
<p>That was no surprise to the LIFFE floor.</p>
<p>&quot;If sentiment can kill EMU, then it's already dead down here,&quot; said another trader at a British brokerage.</p>
<p>-- International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6137</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
