<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="427361" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PLO slams Israel on pullback decision.</title>
<headline>PLO slams Israel on pullback decision.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinians on Friday condemned Israel's unilateral decision on a further troop withdrawal in the West Bank as insufficient and a violation of their peace accords.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat, on return to the Gaza Strip from a trip that included talks in Washington with U.S. President Bill Clinton, called it one-sided.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a big deceit operation. It came from one party, without consultation with us,&quot; Arafat told reporters.</p>
<p>Earlier, Saeb Erekat, minister of local government in the Palestinian Authority and a peace negotiator, told Israel Radio: &quot;I think we are facing a real crisis in the peace process now and when I say a real crisis I mean it.&quot;</p>
<p>Tayeb Abdel-Rahim, secretary general of Palestinian President Yasser Arafat's office said: &quot;This is a step which we consider a violation of the agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>After a seven-hour overnight debate Israel's cabinet on Friday voted 10-7 to back a proposal by Prime Minister Netanyahu to hand over another nine percent of the West Bank to the Palestinians, said a government spokeswoman.</p>
<p>Two percent is land exclusively under Israeli control; seven percent is land that had been patrolled by both Israel and the</p>
<p>The Palestinians were already enraged over Israel's decision last month to build a new Jewish settlement of 6,500 homes in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Abdel-Rahim said the Palestine Liberation Organisation in negotiations sealed in January on the three further Israeli West Bank withdrawals understood each would be 30 percent of the land now in Israeli hands.</p>
<p>&quot;The latest decision is a violation of the agreement and we do not accept it,&quot; Abdel-Rahim said. He told the radio the Authority's official response would be decided at a meeting of the cabinet later on Friday.</p>
<p>Erekat said: &quot;I will not say what we will do but we're urging the Israelis...that we should sit down, discuss the whole issue...We want to solve our problems by negotiations and now they're insisting on dictating to us and that's totally poisoning the atmosphere of the negotiations.&quot;</p>
<p>In a U.S.-brokered deal by which Israel handed over most of the West Bank town of Hebron to Palestinian rule in January, Israel agreed to carry out three further withdrawals.</p>
<p>The Jewish state insists the scope of the pullbacks are solely up to it.</p>
<p>In contrast to Palestinian reaction, the United States welcomed the Israeli move. &quot;We believe this decision is a demonstration of Israel's commitment to the peace process,&quot; State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said in a written statement.</p>
<p>The withdrawal, which Israeli Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai said would take at least 48 hours to implement. Under the Hebron accord, Israel must complete the third phase of redeployment by mid-1998.</p>
<p>Final borders are to be decided in permanent status talks scheduled to begin this month where Jerusalem's status is also to be negotiated.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
