<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="427524" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: State Dept., Cohen disagree on election delay.</title>
<headline>State Dept., Cohen disagree on election delay.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. State Department and Defence Secretary William Cohen on Thursday disagreed over the postponement of municipal elections in Bosnia.</p>
<p>The State Department, which fought hard to keep Bosnia's national elections from being delayed last year, said on Thursday it fully supported a decision to postpone municipal polls by two months.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course it's always disappointing when you have to postpone elections, but this is only a two-month postponement and we believe that the postponement will give us a greater chance to have free and fair elections,&quot; department spokesman Nicholas Burns told reporters.</p>
<p>Cohen, on an overseas trip in Bosnia, sharply criticised the delay, calling it another failure by outside civilian agencies to rejuvenate the war-shattered country.</p>
<p>&quot;I can only say it is disappointing. It will complicate matters,&quot; he told a news conference. &quot;I am disappointed with those who are responsible for setting up and acquiring the (election) monitors, the financial resources in order to allow the elections to go forward.&quot;</p>
<p>Cohen added, however, that the election delay would not interrupt the final departure of U.S. forces from Bosnia in mid-1998.</p>
<p>At the State Department, Burns said that American Robert Frowick, who oversees the election process for the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), concluded that &quot;because of logistical and technical complexities in conducting the elections, a delay of two months would be prudent and expand the chances these elections would be free and fair.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We thought carefully about his reasoning and we support him fully in this assessment.&quot;</p>
<p>The local polls were originally to be held in September 1996, along with general elections, but were postponed because of widespread election fraud over refugee registration to November 1996 and then to July this year.</p>
<p>Western countries funding the election had been pushing for a further postponement of the vote to allow more time to organise refugee registration and international monitoring.</p>
<p>The 54-member OSCE, Europe's top security body, is in charge of organising the elections, viewed as Bosnia's last chance for reunification after a devastating 43-month war.</p>
<p>Last year, Washington resisted pressure from many western countries and experts who argued that Bosnia's first post-war national elections should be delayed for many of the same general reasons that the municipal elections are being postponed.</p>
<p>Burns argued on Thursday that no two situaitons are alike and he said a two-month delay cannot to be compared to a delay of six months or a year, which is what he said people were talking about in terms of the national elections.</p>
<p>Beyond that, &quot;you have to put your confidence in the people in the field,&quot; Burns said, referring to Frowick.</p>
<p>Burns expressed confidence that there will be no subsequent delays. &quot;We took great care with this decision and we're confident the election can be held in September,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
