<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="427537" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: More Albanian refugees sail to Italy.</title>
<headline>More Albanian refugees sail to Italy.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of 46 Albanians fleeing unrest in the south of their country sailed a fishing boat to Italy on Friday and coastguards said two more groups of refugees had been sighted off shore.</p>
<p>The twin-masted fishing boat sailed from the Adriatic town of Vlore, the epicentre of the Albanian uprising, and was intercepted 25 miles north of the small port of Otranto on the heel of southern Italy.</p>
<p>Coastguards said it was carrying 24 men, 11 women and 11 children, all apparently relatives or friends.</p>
<p>One woman told the Italian news agency ANSA that the group left Vlore at around 7.30 p.m. on Thursday after watching Italian television news bulletins.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw the latest news and reports of tanks heading for Vlore and were afraid,&quot; she was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>They were taken to converted containers with barred windows in the port, a short distance from Vlore across the Adriatic.</p>
<p>Coastguards said a dinghy with 16 Albanians had also been intercepted by a navy patrol boat in international waters off Otranto while a motorboat had been sighted by police from land. Two coastguard vessels were sent out to escort it into port.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands of Albanians made a mass exodus to Italy in rusting freighters in 1991 after 45 years of Stalinist rule crumbled in Europe's poorest country.</p>
<p>Thousands more have followed in illegal immigration rackets and Italy stepped up security in the Adriatic this week, fearing anti-government armed unrest that has spread across southern Albania could unleash a new flood of immigrants.</p>
<p>A government official in the southern Puglia region, Giuseppe Mazzitello, said on Thursday that Italy would repatriate all Albanians entering the country illegally.</p>
<p>But several Albanians who have made the crossing since the insurrection have sought to stay their expulsion by asking for political asylum. Requests take up to a month to process.</p>
<p>Carabinieri paramilitary police said that of a group of 29 Albanians, including nine children, who arrived on a motorboat in Otranto on Wednesday, 25 asked on Thursday for political asylum.</p>
<p>The other four, one of whom was arrested for trafficking in immigrants, already had Italian residence permits.</p>
<p>Two Albanian pilots also asked for political asylum on Tuesday after flying their MiG-15 across the Adriatic from near the southern town of Gjirokaster.</p>
<p>Albania has denied assertions by the pilots that they had been ordered to shoot on civilians.</p>
<p>Italian media reported on Friday that Albania intended to seek the pilots' extradition but the Italian foreign and justice ministries said no formal request had so far been received.</p>
<p>Defence Minister Beniamino Andreatta, asked to comment on the pilots, said he did not believe they should be sent back.</p>
<p>&quot;Speaking entirely personally, my view is that if they fled, as they say, for reasons of conscience then it will not be possible to meet the Albanian request,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
