<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="427561" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: FORECAST - Big profit rise seen for Telecom.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Big profit rise seen for Telecom.</headline>
<byline>Richard Waddington</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investors expect Portugal Telecom to post net 1996 profit of at least 50 billion escudos next Wednesday with anything less likely to hurt the stock, analysts said.</p>
<p>The share price of the state-controlled telecommunications company has soared over 40 percent since the start of the year on a mix of optimism over its likely results, anticipation of the next phase of its privatisation set for later this year and the strong dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is looking for around 50 billion escudos. Anything significantly below that figure would be a bad surprise,&quot; said analyst Jose Antonio Goncalves of Tottadealer in Lisbon.</p>
<p>The signs are that investors will have little cause for complaint, with many analysts expecting a figure of around 52 billion escudos, up from 36.2 billion escudos in 1995.</p>
<p>A strong profit figure would help launch the company towards the further earnings growth of some 20 percent seen for 1997.</p>
<p>Despite the sharp rise in the share price in recent weeks, which has comfortably outstripped the performance of the overall bourse, analysts still rate the telecom stock as a buy.</p>
<p>The share was trading at 6,310 escudos on Friday, slightly below its Thursday close. But several analysts said that it could be around 7,000 by the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;We see it continuing to climb,&quot; said Jose Freire of ESR-Espirito Santo Research. ESR is predicting a net profit of 53 billion escudos for 1996, rising to 65 billion this year.</p>
<p>One London analyst, who asked not to be identified, said that she was looking for net profit in 1996 of 52 billion escudos. &quot;But I may be on the low-side,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She saw profit growing to 62.4 billion in 1997.</p>
<p>Portugal Telecom's price-earnings ratio of just under 20 may compare unfavourably with the overall rating of some 18 for the bourse as a whole, based on February figures. But the Lisbon bourse figures are depressed by the uncertain outlook for the banks which have a heavy weighting in the index, analysts said.</p>
<p>A big push for Portugal Telecom stock earlier this year came from news of far better than expected results for its mobile phone operation, TMN-Telecomunicacoes Moveis.</p>
<p>The company said that TMN made more than seven billion escudos last year, which was some 50 percent more than many analysts had been anticipating.</p>
<p>The results led many sector specialists to upgrade their views on the pace of growth in Portugal's mobile phone market, Goncalves said.</p>
<p>&quot;There seems no doubt that it is growing far more quickly than had been expected,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>($1=172.02 escudos)</p>
<p>--Lisbon bureau 3511-3150035</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
