<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="427584" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Uniwear sees Pex Euro.NM listing.</title>
<headline>Uniwear sees Pex Euro.NM listing.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian textile holding company Uniwear NV reiterated on Friday it will seek a secondary listing for British clothing maker Pex Plc on the Brussels segment of the Euro.NM small caps market, but said it had frozen its own plan for a secondary listing in London.</p>
<p>Uniwear has a 38 percent holding in Pex.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be making a secondary listing of Pex, making it the first British company to come to the Euro.NM,&quot; Uniwear chief executive officer Andrea Cattaneo Della Volta told a news conference.</p>
<p>He was presenting Uniwear's capital increase, which started on March 3 and runs to March 27, and its future plans.</p>
<p>The Belgian segment of the Euro.NM -- which is an initiative of the Brussels, Paris, Frankfurt and Amsterdam bourses -- is due to get its first listings later this month.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope (Pex) to be one of the first (companies) to be there,&quot; Cattaneo said.</p>
<p>Pex's secondary listing will be lead-managed by Belgian, Antwerp-based brokerage Smeets, Verbaet &amp; Co and one other brokerage, Cattaneo said.</p>
<p>Pex's Euro.NM listing plans were first announced last December.</p>
<p>Cattaneo said he favoured Euro.NM over the rival Easdaq European small cap market because it was built on tried technology, used by the Belgian, German and French exchanges, and also would raise Pex's profile in markets where the firm might seek to expand in the future.</p>
<p>Uniwear said last September it would also be seeking a secondary listing for its shares on either the London Stock Exchange or Alternative Investment Market (AIM).</p>
<p>Cattaneo said, however, the plan had been put on hold indefinitely. &quot;Since then we have seen there has been a re-appreciation of continental exchanges,&quot; he noted.</p>
<p>-- Nick Antonovics, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6817, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I44000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
