<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="427657" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Metra Sanitec aims for global reach - CEO.</title>
<headline>Metra Sanitec aims for global reach - CEO.</headline>
<byline>John Acher</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish engineering group Metra Oy Ab sees its Sanitec bathroom porcelain division's new Middle Eastern joint venture fitting its strategy to aim for a global reach, Metra president and CEO Georg Ehrnrooth said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It (Sanitec) is now becoming more global,&quot; he told a news conference on a new joint venture established with the Gargour family of Lebanon.</p>
<p>&quot;Our ambition is to develop Sanitec in its strong areas (and) expand its operations geographically,&quot; Ehrnrooth said.</p>
<p>The Middle East move was a further step to acquire capacity in &quot;competitive countries&quot; where &quot;competitively priced&quot; products could be manufactured for European markets, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are interested in rapidly growing markets, including Southeast Asia,&quot; he added, but did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Earlier Metra said Sanitec would invest 175 million markka in a 50-50 venture that would acquire control of sanitaryware and bathroom tile maker  Lecico with operations in Egypt and Lebanon generating annual net sales of $81 million.</p>
<p>Lecico's &quot;profitability is good,&quot; Ehrnrooth said.</p>
<p>He declined to give details, saying the Gargour family had not wanted them disclosed, but that Sanitec would report profits once it was a partner.</p>
<p>In 1996, Sanitec's net sales were 2.7 billion markka and the division made an operating profit of 353 million markka.</p>
<p>Ehrnrooth said Lecico exported about 36 percent of its output to Britain and France and to parts of Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;England has been a rather new market for us up to now. But Lecico has exports to (the U.K.) so we will get a four percent market share in England,&quot; Ehrnrooth said.</p>
<p>Sanitec is the market leader in Germany and holds second place in France and third place in Italy, he said.</p>
<p>Asked whether it was more important to grow in Europe from a base in the Middle East or to grow in the region itself, Ehrnrooth said: &quot;Both are important.&quot;</p>
<p>The acquisition brings to 11 the number of countries in which Sanitec has bathroom porcelain manufacturing operations.</p>
<p>Ehrnrooth played down the risks of doing business in Lebanon and said the Lecico plant there had managed to operate without major disturbances and that the Gargour family was evidently familiar with the market and well connected there.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that this country (Lebanon) will eventually have a big reconstruction project ahead of it and that this market will then become even more interesting,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Besides bathroom porcelain, Lecico manufactures wall tiles, a new business for Sanitec, Ehrnrooth said.</p>
<p>&quot;Tiles are not our core business, but they are important in these markets,&quot; he said, adding that Lecico commanded one fifth of the tile market in Egypt.</p>
<p>Lecico's Egyptian business was now building a bathroom ceramics plant that would have an output capacity of about one million units a year when completed next year, he said.</p>
<p>--Helsinki newsroom +358-9-680 50 235, e-mail news@reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
