<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="427649" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: New German futures contract gets warm reception.</title>
<headline>New German futures contract gets warm reception.</headline>
<byline>Scott Miller</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's electronic futures exchange DTB launched a new two-year debt futures contract on Friday to rave reviews from traders who see the product plugging a hole in the German futures yield curve.</p>
<p>Analysts said the contract, which is meant in part to improve Frankfurt's international financial standing, will quickly build liquidity because of increased trading of short dated instruments and a strong supply of underlying cash debt.</p>
<p>&quot;I am firmly convinced this contract will be a success,&quot; said Timo Klein, analyst at MMS International in Frankfurt. &quot;I can't see why investors won't take to it.&quot;</p>
<p>He and others said that within a couple of weeks, they see daily volume in the contract swelling to around 20,000 -- a level of liquidity sufficient to call the contract a success. Volume stood at around 8,400 on Friday afternoon.</p>
<p>The contract plugged what many considered a hole for futures trade on the German yield curve with contracts already available for 10-year, five-year, one-month and three-month euromark contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;If successful, as we ultimately expect, this would create a futures market wich more fully covers the yield curve than any country in the world other than the U.S.&quot; Deutsche Morgan Grenfell wrote in a bond market comentary on Friday.</p>
<p>Analysts attribute part of their optimism to strong underlying supply for two-year cash debt. Lack of cash market supply crippled the DTB's efforts to offer a 30-year Bund future in the spring of 1994, forcing the contract to eventually be discontinued.</p>
<p>Bonn started issuing two-year notes in September 1996 and planned in the first quarter of this year to issue about 10 billion marks worth of the debt.</p>
<p>&quot;The supply of two-year notes issues will help the futures contract,&quot; said Hans Nordstrom, trader at BMP Wertpapiere und Optionen GmbH.</p>
<p>Analysts also said the contract will gain interest in part because it is the only two-year bond futures contract in Europe.</p>
<p>The DTB said it hoped to ensure healthy volumes in the contract by naming six designated market makers who are obligated to continued price quotes and 17 designated brokers -- many of whom are foreign firms.</p>
<p>&quot;The DTB is hoping that the international focus of these financial institutions will prove the impetus for a buoyant market in the new product,&quot; the DTB said in a statement.</p>
<p>From a volatility standpoint, however, the new contract starts at a difficult time.</p>
<p>Many economists expect the Bundesbank to keep interest rates on hold for some time, reducing swings in the short-end of the yield curve and giving investors less reason to want to hedge their holdings.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom + 49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
