<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="427710" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany's Mobilcom sets IPO at 62.50 marks.</title>
<headline>Germany's Mobilcom sets IPO at 62.50 marks.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in the initial public offering of German mobile phone group Mobilcom AG will be offered to the public at 62.50 marks per share, main underwriter DG Bank said on Friday.  </p>
<p>The bank said in a statement that the issue was oversubscribed several times and that more than half of the volume of orders came from private investors.</p>
<p>The bookbuilding phase of its share listing began on Tuesday and ended on Thursday. Shares were offered to investors in a range of 52.50-62.50 marks.</p>
<p>Shares begin official trade on March 10 on Germany's new growth stock index, dubbed Neue Markt or new market, which is modelled after the Nasdaq index of the United States.</p>
<p>But they were already being handled in the so-called grey market in a trading range of 82-84 marks.</p>
<p>On the grey market, investors may place orders with brokers ahead of time that are completed once shares actually begin trading. This is a common practice ahead of an IPO.</p>
<p>MobilCom AG, which does not operate its own mobile phone network but leases capacity from other operators to repackage and resell phone services, will offer 640,000 common shares for sale to the public.</p>
<p>The shares have a face value of five marks, bringing the nominal value of the entire issue to 3.2 million marks.</p>
<p>DG Bank gave no details about plans for the greenshoe, or over-allotment, of 160,000 shares, which it said earlier this week could be issued if the offer is oversubscribed.</p>
<p>To promote the launch, MobilCom is promising investors a discount on their mobile telephone bill each year corresponding with the level of the MobilCom share on the day of its annual shareholders' meeting.</p>
<p>In addition, MobilCom customers will be able to call up a price for the DAX index and MobilCom shares on their mobile phones.</p>
<p>MobilCom had 1996 sales of around 309 million marks and group pre-tax profit on ordinary activities of 12.1 million marks. It expects pre-tax earnings to rise to 17.1 million marks this year.</p>
<p>Sales would rise less sharply to 314 million marks from 309 million marks and the company expects the number of subscribers to rise 50,000 to 210,000 by the end of the year.</p>
<p>-- Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
