<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="427863" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ford denies glass unit is up for sale.</title>
<headline>Ford denies glass unit is up for sale.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Ford Motor Co spokesman on Friday denied a published report that the automaker is again trying to sell its glass division.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no change in the status of the glass operations,&quot; said Ford spokesman Niel Golightly.</p>
<p>The Detroit News, citing unnamed company executives, reported Friday the automaker is once again shopping for buyers for the unprofitable business.</p>
<p>Ford has previously tried to sell the operations. The company took the glass unit off the sale block last year ahead of talks on a new labor contract after objections were raised from the United Auto Workers union.</p>
<p>Golightly said the glass division continues to be part of the ongoing review of the company's newly formed Automotive Products Operations, which is comprised of Ford's $14 billion automotive components businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;We are concentrating on making it competitive and successful and folding it into the APO organization,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The glass unit has a total of 4,500 workers, mostly in the U.S. It has six plants, four wholly owned facilities in the U.S., as well as joint ventures in China and Mexico.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
