<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="427864" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Airlines scramble to adjust fares in wake of tax.</title>
<headline>Airlines scramble to adjust fares in wake of tax.</headline>
<byline>Jessica Hall</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. airlines raised fares Friday morning, lowered fares Friday afternoon and still were scrambling to find middle ground by the end of the day as they tried to cope with a revived tax on air travel.</p>
<p>Domestic air fares remained in flux Friday afternoon, as some major airlines said they were still deciding whether to absorb the 10 percent excise tax themselves or pass the cost along to consumers.</p>
<p>The reinstated tax, signed into law by President Clinton last week, took effect Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to vary market by market. It will take a few days to settle,&quot; said Edward Starkman, an airline analyst with Dillon Read.</p>
<p>Most major airlines initially tried to add the entire 10 percent tax to exising fares, but Northwest Airlines Corp. bucked the trend by adding only 4 percent.</p>
<p>Northwest's action forced other carriers to scurry and re-evaluate their fares. AMR Corp.'s American Airlines quickly reversed course and decided to absorb the entire tax. Trans World Airlines Inc and UAL Corp.'s United Airlines said they were evaluting their options.</p>
<p>Southwest Airlines Co. absorbed the excise tax and launched a &quot;Friends Fly Free&quot; sale. But Southwest's gesture was partly a marketing ploy since the carrier quietly raised fares a few weeks ago, analysts said.</p>
<p>Intense competition and fare wars to attract leisure travelers has limited airlines' abilities to raise prices.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very fluid situation. At the end of the day, we're likely to see a 4 percent increase, except in Southwest's primary markets,&quot; said Samuel Buttrick, an analyst with PaineWebber.</p>
<p>&quot;But the ticket tax coming back puts an end to a massive windfall the industry has been enjoying,&quot; Buttrick said.</p>
<p>Since the tax lapsed on Dec. 31, the airlines have kept for themselves funds that would normally go to the Federal Aviation Administration. That extra revenue, strong demand and declining fuel prices means airlines' first quarter results will likely beat even the most optimistic Wall Street expectations, some analysts said.</p>
<p>But the sooner-than-expected return of the ticket tax ended that bonanza. Buttrick said he expects to trim his second and third quarter estimates.</p>
<p>Other analysts said they were relieved the airlines did not suffer an even more brutal blow.</p>
<p>&quot;I had expected an even more modest fare increase of about 2.5 percent, so I'm delighted with 4 percent. I expect the Northwest increase to stick,&quot; said Candace Browning, an analyst with Merrill Lynch.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
