<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428244" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. domestic air fares may rise when tax returns.</title>
<headline>U.S. domestic air fares may rise when tax returns.</headline>
<byline>Jessica Hall</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most U.S. domestic air fares will likely rise when a 10 percent federal ticket tax is reimposed on Friday, bringing to an end weeks of sale prices on many routes, industry experts said.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect the airlines to pass the increase on the traveling public as much as possible,&quot; said Ethan Simon, a spokesman for Woodside Travel Trust, a partnership of more than 130 travel agencies.  </p>
<p>Airlines will likely add all or part of the 10 percent tax to fares, Simon said. But the specific amount passed on to consumers will depend on competition on each route, he said. On the most competitive routes, airlines may completely absorb the tax in an effort to keep fares as low as possible.</p>
<p>One analyst, who declined to be named, said most major airlines plan to add the 10 percent tax to existing fares. Some smaller airlines will absorb the levy instead of passing the cost along to consumers, the analyst said.  </p>
<p>Unless airlines pass on the 10 percent tax, the levy would have a negative effect on their second and third quarter earnings and revenues, analysts said.</p>
<p>Airline officials declined to comment Thursday on whether they would pass along the tax. Federal restrictions prevent carriers from commenting on future fare actions.</p>
<p>Several major airlines, such as Continental Airlines Inc and Trans World Airlines Inc, ran advertisements this week urging consumers to buy tickets before the tax returned. Some airlines said they had experienced an increase in customer calls because of fare sales.  </p>
<p>Since the excise tax lapsed on December 31, airlines have reaped a windfall, keeping for themselves money that would normally go to funding the Federal Aviation Administration. When the tax lapsed last year, eight months passed before lawmakers reinstated it, giving an even bigger bonus to air carriers.</p>
<p>When the tax was reimposed last year, some carriers added the 10 percent to fares. But those fare increases were quickly rescinded when other carriers failed to match the rise. Carriers then raised fares more slowly during the autumn.</p>
<p>To be sure, the return of the excise tax on Friday could lead to a more permanent increase in fares because the industry is in the midst of the strong spring travel season, analysts said.</p>
<p>Airlines are better able to impose fare hikes during periods of high demand. Last year, the excise tax returned in late August, a time when travel volumes typically drop -- making it harder to pass along extra costs to consumers.</p>
<p>(( New York newsdesk 212-859-1610 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
