<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428222" id="root" date="1997-03-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Nord Resources sets sale of kaolin unit.</title>
<headline>Nord Resources sets sale of kaolin unit.</headline>
<dateline>DAYTON, Ohio 1997-03-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nord Resources Corp said Thursday it agreed to sell the operating assets of the kaolin mining and Norplex operations of 80 percent owned Nord Kaolin Company to Dry Branch Kaolin Co for $20 million, subject to adjustments and a royalty arrangement on the future sales of Norplex products.</p>
<p>As a result of the transaction, Nord said, it will have a non-recurring loss on disposal of these assets.</p>
<p>The transaction is subject to obtaining certain consents of third parties and regulatory approval. It is anticipated that closing will occur within 30 days.  </p>
<p>In addition to the purchase price, at closing, Nord Resources will be released from its guarantee obligations under certain equipment leases of NKC in the approximate amount of $12 million, the company said.</p>
<p>It said the sale of the kaolin operations provides Nord with significant additional liquidity and will allow the company to concentrate its time, resources and attention to the reopening of the mine in Sierra Leone owned by Nord's 50 percent owned affiliate, Sierra Rutile Ltd, and the expansion of the exploration and mining activities of Nord's affiliate, Nord Pacific Limited.</p>
<p>((-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAYTON, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
