<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428379" id="root" date="1997-03-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: ATHLETICS-KOFFA BRINGS FURTHER JOY TO GREECE.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-KOFFA BRINGS FURTHER JOY TO GREECE.</headline>
<byline>John Mehaffey</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ekaterina Koffa emulated her compatriot Haralambous Paradias by winning a world sprint title on Saturday at the end of an emotional week for Greece.</p>
<p>Koffa, running from lane six, edged out Jamaica's 1992 Olympic silver medallist Juliet Cuthbert by one- hundredth of a second in the women's 200 metres final on the second day of the world indoor championships.</p>
<p>It was the narrowest victory margin so far in the three-day championships and allowed Koffa to take her place on top of the victory podium the day after Paradias had won the men's 60 metres title.</p>
<p>Greek team members, already delighted by the International Olympic Committee's decision on Friday to put Athens on a shortlist of five candidates to stage the 2004 Games, celebrated noisily, draping Koffa in a Greek flag.</p>
<p>In five previous indoor championships, Greece have gathered just one silver medal.</p>
<p>&quot;The feeling is unbelievable,&quot; said Koffa. &quot;I don't think it's difficult to understand, it's the best feeling.</p>
<p>&quot;The sixth lane was the key to my victory, I think it's the best lane.&quot;</p>
<p>The men's 200 final went to American Kevin Little, also running from lane six.</p>
<p>Little, who has won two world indoor bronze medals, said: &quot;I think I just proved my worth today. I was fortunate to draw lane six.&quot;</p>
<p>Trinidad's Ato Boldon, favourite for the title, pulled up suddenly in the final straight and crumpled to the track.</p>
<p>His coach John Smith jumped down from the stands and watched anxiously as Boldon was carried from the track on a stretcher.</p>
<p>Boldon was later taken to hospital but Smith did not appear too worried.</p>
<p>&quot;Ato felt a contraction at the bottom of his left hamstring at the end of the curve,&quot; Smith said. &quot;I don't think that it's important, after two weeks he's going to recover.&quot;</p>
<p>Little, who clocked 20.40 seconds, said he had not been surprised by the result.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt I could not be beaten,&quot; he said. &quot;It's nice to have a superstar like Boldon in the race, it certainly takes the pressure off.&quot;</p>
<p>Second-placed Cuban Ivan Garcia was inititally disqualified for running out of lane but was reinstated after the track referee examined a video recording and decided the infraction had been committed by Boldon.</p>
<p>Moroccan Hicham el Guerrouj ran away with the men's 1,500, although his time of three minutes 35.31 seconds was well outside his own world record of 3:31.18 set early last month.</p>
<p>German Ridger Stenzel was well back in second place ahead of Kenya's 1992 Olympic 800 champion William Tanui.</p>
<p>&quot;It was an easy race for me,&quot; said el Guerrouj. &quot;I have had a sensational start to this year and I hope there's more to come. This could be my year.&quot;</p>
<p>Inna Lasovskaya of Russia took the women's triple jump with a leap of 15.01 metres, only two centimetres outside the world record.</p>
<p>&quot;Paris was always my favourite town and Bercy my favourite track,&quot; said Lasovakaya.</p>
<p>The women's 3,000 metres, the final track event of the evening, was won in a thrilling sprint finish by Romania's defending champion Gabriela Szabo who overhauled Irishwoman Sonia O'Sullivan over the final metres to win in 8:45.75.</p>
<p>Cuban Ivan Pedroso, whose season last year was disrupted by injury, won the men's long jump title while Olympic and world champion Stefka Kostadinova showed her competitive steel by winning a tense women's high jump final.</p>
<p>Kostadinova leaped a year's best of 2.02 then made three unsuccessful attempts on the world record of 2.07.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
