<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428473" id="root" date="1997-03-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: SPEED SKATING-CHINESE SKATERS BREAK 1,000 M RECORDS.</title>
<headline>SPEED SKATING-CHINESE SKATERS BREAK 1,000 M RECORDS.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-03-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's Li Jiajun broke the men's 1,000 metre short-track speedskating world record on Saturday while compatriot Wang Chunlu smashed the women's record at the same distance, the Xinhua news agency said.</p>
<p>Li, 1,000 metres world champion in 1996, clocked one minute 27.67 seconds to surpass the world record of 1:28.47 on the last day of the Chinese National Games, the agency said.</p>
<p>The previous record was set by New Zealand's Michael McMillen in Denver in 1992.</p>
<p>Two team mates from Li's northeastern home province of Jilin were among four skaters to beat the world mark in a blistering final, it said.</p>
<p>Wang Chunlu, who won 5,000 and 1,000 metres golds at the 1995 world championships, clocked one minute 31.88 seconds in the women's 1,000 metres semifinals to break the 1:34.07 world record, it said.</p>
<p>Wang, 20, who fell in the 500 metres final on Friday, went on to win the 1,000 metres final with a time of 1:39.09.</p>
<p>Semifinal skaters Sun Dandan and Wang Xidi also came in with times under the old world record, which had already been broken by two other competitors in earlier races, Xinhua said.</p>
<p>Before Saturday, the women's world record was held by Canadian Nathalie Lambert.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
