<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428582" id="root" date="1997-03-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: OSCE calls for extension of Albanian ceasefire.</title>
<headline>OSCE calls for extension of Albanian ceasefire.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-03-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of a European security mission seeking to mediate in the armed rebellion in southern Albania urged Tirana on Saturday to extend a 48-hour ceasefire to enable political talks to continue.</p>
<p>Former Austrian leader Franz Vranitzky, leading the mission of the Vienna-based Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), said he had urged President Sali Berisha to extend the truce, which is due to expire at 6 a.m. (0500 GMT) on Sunday.</p>
<p>Vranitzky told a news conference after &quot;very extensive&quot; talks with Berisha and opposition leaders that he expected a decision on his request at a further meeting with the Albanian leader later on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;We would be very glad if the ceasefire would be prolonged for a further 48 hours to give more opportunity for people to surrender weapons, and to intensify negotiations between the various political forces,&quot; Vranitzky said.</p>
<p>The president, backed by the opposition parties, announced the ceasefire on Friday after two days of clashes between troops and rebels who have taken over at least three towns in southern Albania.</p>
<p>The rebellion was sparked by popular anger over fraudulent pyramid savings schemes in which hundreds of thousands lost money, and has mushroomed into an anti-government uprising in the south.</p>
<p>The rebels are calling for Berisha to step down, new elections and compensation for those who lost money in the pyramid schemes.</p>
<p>Vranitzky said no progress could be made on measures to provide international financial aid to Albania and extend cooperation with European institutions such as the European Union until the violence was ended for good.</p>
<p>The OSCE mission was the latest in a series of Western initiatives to end the crisis in Albania, Europe's poorest country.</p>
<p>Reports from the south indicated the situation was still volatile, with gunmen in the rebel-held port of Sarende firing in the air to drive off crowds trying to board a ferry bound for Greece.</p>
<p>Vranitzky's mission appeared in trouble earlier this week when he acknowledged that Albanian officials had told him he was not welcome in the Balkan country.</p>
<p>His visit to Tirana followed that of Dutch Foreign Minister Hans Van Mierlo, representing the European Union presidency, who urged Berisha to refrain from violence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
