<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428531" id="root" date="1997-03-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: African team in Nigeria to promote human rights.</title>
<headline>African team in Nigeria to promote human rights.</headline>
<byline>James Jukwey</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-03-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>An African mission has arrived in Nigeria to promote human rights, but local rights activists said on Saturday the team was not objective and one opposition lawyer called the visit a waste of time.</p>
<p>The team from the Gambia-based African Commission on Human and Peoples' Rights, an Organisation of African Unity agency, is headed by the Ghanaian deputy chairman of the commission Professor Victor Dankwa. Others are former Togolese minister Koffi Amega and Essombe Joseph, a lawyer with the agency.</p>
<p>Dankwa said from Abuja that the team was meeting Nigerian officials there on Saturday to finalise its programme.</p>
<p>&quot;By the end of the day we will conclude the itinerary but we will meet for a whole day, tentatively on Tuesday, with the human rights groups in Nigeria,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>They have come only two weeks after two United Nations investigators called off a mission to probe the human rights situation in Nigeria because the authorities denied them access to jails and political detainees.</p>
<p>A senior government official earlier told Reuters from Abuja the team's mission was on &quot;a promotional basis only,&quot; adding: &quot;They are not a court to try Nigeria, but they are here to enlighten and educate NGOs and government officials dealing with human rights so as to promote respect for human rights in the country.&quot;</p>
<p>Local rights activists have condemned the mission, saying it lacked objectivity and that the government wanted to use it to counter whatever the U.N. mission would have written about Nigeria.</p>
<p>&quot;We will paint the actual picture when we meet them,&quot; said Clement Nwankwo, executive director of a leading rights group, the Constitutional Rights Project.</p>
<p>Nwankwo's group and the Civil Liberties Organisation had orginally been scheduled to meet the team on Saturday.</p>
<p>But radical opposition lawyer Gani Fawehimi who was also invited to meet the team declined to do so, saying the mission was a waste of time.</p>
<p>The team is due to stay until March 14 and apart from Abuja it will visit Lagos, Kano, Kaduna and Port Harcourt to talk to government officials, human rights groups and individuals.</p>
<p>Government officials said the team would see detainees including presidential claimant Moshood Abiola and 19 youths from the Ogoni minority tribe who are detained over the 1994 murder of four Ogoni chiefs.</p>
<p>The Ogoni youths face the death penalty like executed author Ken Saro-Wiwa, who was hanged with eight other Ogoni minority rights activists in 1995 over the same murders after a trial condemned internationally as flawed.</p>
<p>The umbrella opposition group NADECO on Friday sent a six-page letter to the annual session of the U.N. Human Rights Commission opening on Monday and urged it to speed up efforts to resolve Nigeria's crisis.</p>
<p>NADECO said Nigeria's 100 million people who live under military rule deserved a better situation concerning rights and democracy than they currently faced.</p>
<p>Nigeria is expected to be in the dock for alleged rights abuses at the six-week session of the U.N. Human Rights Commission.</p>
<p>Nigeria, ruled by the army for 25 years since independence in 1960, plunged into turmoil in 1993 when a presidential vote presumed to have been won by Abiola was annulled by the army. Abiola has been detained since 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GAMB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OAU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
