<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428603" id="root" date="1997-03-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUYANA: Guyanese pay last respects to dead leader Jagan.</title>
<headline>Guyanese pay last respects to dead leader Jagan.</headline>
<dateline>GEORGETOWN, Guyana 1997-03-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of Guyanese paid their last respects on Saturday to President Cheddi Jagan who died on Thursday, ending a political career that spanned five decades.</p>
<p>Jagan, a one-time Marxist whose rhetoric mellowed over the years, died from heart failure at Walter Reed Army hospital in Washington. He was 78.</p>
<p>Beginning at dawn on Saturday, long lines of people of all ages and social classes snaked around the palm trees in the gardens of the presidential palace and out into the main street.</p>
<p>Jagan's body, flown back from the United States late on Friday, lay in a half-open casket beneath a green and white canopy in the palace gardens.</p>
<p>People wept openly over the coffin where Jagan lay in a white &quot;guayabera&quot; shirt, his hands clasped at the waist.</p>
<p>The man whom U.S. President Bill Clinton on Thursday called &quot;a champion of the poor,&quot; was to be cremated on Tuesday at his birthplace Port Mourant, 90 miles (145 km) east of Georgetown.</p>
<p>Leaders from neighbouring countries and Caribbean islands were expected to attend the funeral.</p>
<p>Jagan, who died in the last year of a five year term, was immediately replaced by Prime Minister Samuel Hinds, 53, as interim president. Hinds will lead the former British colony until elections are held, probably around October. Elections are required under the Constitution before March, 1998.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GEORGETOWN, Guyana"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUYANA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
