<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428614" id="root" date="1997-03-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Violence shrouds Nicaraguan property dispute.</title>
<headline>Violence shrouds Nicaraguan property dispute.</headline>
<byline>David Koop</byline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nicaragua's conservative government and its left-wing Sandinista opposition, embroiled in a dispute over seized properties, blamed each other on Friday for promoting violence.</p>
<p>One person was killed and three wounded on Thursday in shooting between a peasant who was being evicted from a farm and police and the farm's owner.</p>
<p>Thousands of former owners are trying to recover property confiscated by the Sandinistas when they were in power from 1979-90. Talks to resolve the bitter disputes were suspended two weeks ago.</p>
<p>Bayardo Arce, head of the Sandinista team at the talks, blamed the violence on a wave of evictions launched by the government against people who benefitted from the Sandinista land redistribution.</p>
<p>&quot;What the government wants is to continue stimulating this aggressiveness,&quot; Arce said. &quot;It seems the government's aim is to keep walking over the bodies it leaves along the road.&quot;</p>
<p>Vice President Enrique Bolanos, who heads the government delegation, accused the Sandinistas of causing the violence by telling their activists to resist legal evictions.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to avoid these violent evictions that only produce death. The Sandinistas must return what must be returned and pay for what must be paid for,&quot; Bolanos told reporters.</p>
<p>The government has said it will give poor families who received confiscated properties legal titles to their land, but make wealthy Sandinistas return or pay for properties they obtained.</p>
<p>This proposal has sparked resistance among Sandinistas who said the government is opening the door for the family and collaborators of former dictator Anastasio Somoza, who was toppled by the 1979 Sandinista revolution, to reclaim their mansions and farms in Nicaragua.</p>
<p>&quot;Dialogue? For what? The dialogue can never be to return their property to the Somozas,&quot; Sandinista Congressman Victor Hugo Tinoco told reporters. &quot;We oppose this proposition. There will never be agreement on it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
