<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428612" id="root" date="1997-03-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Canadian, Cuban parliaments sign cooperation accord.</title>
<headline>Canadian, Cuban parliaments sign cooperation accord.</headline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Canadian parliament on Friday signed an agreement for cooperation with its Cuban counterpart that provides for exchanges of information and visits by parliamentarians to each other's countries.</p>
<p>The accord, in line with Canada's policy of seeking to encourage political and economic change in Cuba through dialogue and contact, was signed by visiting House of Commons (lower house) speaker Gilbert Parent and Ricardo Alarcon, president of Cuba's National Assembly.</p>
<p>Parent, who earlier on Friday met President Fidel Castro over lunch, told reporters the agreement was a step forward in relations between the two institutions.</p>
<p>Parent arrived on Friday morning and was leaving the communist-ruled country on Saturday evening.</p>
<p>Canada's policy of active engagement with Cuba is at odds with Washington, which seeks to isolate Cuba and maintains a 35-year economic embargo on the island. That difference in approach has been highlighted by Ottowa's sharp criticism of the year-old Helms-Burton law, which tightens the U.S. embargo and seeks to punish some foreign firms doing business in Cuba.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
