<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42861" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico guns for growth, but is its powder dry?.</title>
<headline>Mexico guns for growth, but is its powder dry?.</headline>
<byline>Henry Tricks</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>As President Ernesto Zedillo celebrates what he sees as the end of the nightmare of Mexico's 1994-5 economic crisis, economists are raising doubts about the country's growth prospects next year.</p>
<p>Facing rising social pressures, two local armed rebellions and what are expected to be bitterly contested mid-term elections next year, the government cannot afford to be deaf to the clamour for an economy that offers more jobs, higher salaries and better standards of living.</p>
<p>But can it produce? Though Mexico surprised economists with a strong 7.2 percent growth in the second quarter, the figure was largely arithmetical -- the comparison with a plunge in GDP in the second quarter of last year.</p>
<p>&quot;This year's growth partly looks strong because it is compared with the weakest year in half a century (1995),&quot; said Gray Newman, economist at HSBC James Capel. &quot;The stronger 1996 looks the more careful we have to be about 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>In a recent Reuters survey, economists forecast GDP growth of 4.08 percent in 1996. Newman said the government's forecast of at least 4.0 percent growth next year &quot;is a bit ambitious&quot;.</p>
<p>Declining dynamism in the export sector if the U.S. economy slows and the peso remains strong could undermine gross domestic product growth next year, analysts said.</p>
<p>Also, the amount of imports is likely to grow as demand in Mexico picks up, which will cut the net impact of the trade surplus on GDP growth.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is not going to do marvels for the economy,&quot; said Alonso Cervera, economist at Interacciones brokerage. &quot;What worries me is the challenge next year. Consumption and private sector investment will have to show Last week, Zedillo launched an offensive to convince the public his policies will bear fruit, saying in his State of the Nation address that the motor for boosting growth next year would be private investment, the continued dynamism of exports and &quot;the gradual revival of consumption.&quot;</p>
<p>Two days later, his helmsman on the economy, Finance Miniser Guillermo Ortiz indicated the government would spend where it could to spur the recovery, though the public sector's muscle is not what it used to be.</p>
<p>Ortiz noted that a budget surplus in the first half of 1996 meant Mexico would have extra funds equivalent to 1 percent of gross domestic product to spend in the second half.</p>
<p>Much of this came from increased oil revenues, he said, and the investment budget of state oil company Petreolos Mexicanos has been bumped up accordingly.</p>
<p>Ortiz also insisted he was not wedded to the &quot;dogma&quot; of strictly balanced budgets, and said Mexico may run a budget deficit in 1997, partly because of increased government spending on pension and health reform.</p>
<p>&quot;The focus of policy has moved from controlling inflation to growth,&quot; said Damian Fraser, director of equity research at Caspian in Mexico. But he said that did not give the government leeway to abandon prudence.</p>
<p>&quot;In no way can they dash for growth and forget about inflation. The markets would punish them severely.&quot;</p>
<p>One problem on government spending, economists say, is the fear currently running through the public sector of audits after recent high-profile government corruption scandals.</p>
<p>On the demand side, everyone -- the government included -- is only expecting a gradual rebound in consumption after Mexico's huge recession in 1995.</p>
<p>Sergio Martin, economist at ING Barings, said there was evidence that construction was starting to grow which indicated the beginning of a recovery in the domestic market. But he said it was not nearly at full strength.</p>
<p>&quot;In the train towards recovery, the domestic market and consumption are the last two wagons,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
