<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428788" id="root" date="1997-03-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Chief &quot;wise man&quot; says Germany to miss EMU targets.</title>
<headline>Chief &quot;wise man&quot; says Germany to miss EMU targets.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany will miss the Maastricht treaty's budget deficit and public debt goals in 1997, leading to a likely postponement of the planned 1999 start of European monetary union, a top government advisor said on Saturday.</p>
<p>In one of the most forthright calls by an advisor to date for a delay to the launch of the euro currency, Herbert Hax, head of the &quot;five wise men&quot; panel of economists, said that the stability of EMU was more important than its timetable.</p>
<p>Hax told the Bild am Sonntag newspaper Bonn would find it difficult this year to meet the Maastricht treaty's budget deficit limit of three percent of gross domestic product.</p>
<p>&quot;The government forecast is 2.9 percent, but there are others who predict over three percent,&quot; he told the paper.</p>
<p>&quot;If you take the stability criteria seriously, Germany will probably not be able to introduce the euro as planned in 1999.&quot;</p>
<p>He also said Germany would probably overstep the national debt limit of 60 percent of GDP in 1997.</p>
<p>Hax's comments carry special weight, because the five wise men's economic forecasts underpin government budget planning. The group last November forecast a budget deficit this year of 3.3 percent of GDP, down from a final 3.8 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel has said he would keep the budget deficit below three percent, but his fiscal plans assume economic growth of 2.5 percent in 1997 and average unemployment of just under four million.</p>
<p>Joblessness surged in January by half a million, and edged up again in February to a new post-war record of nearly 4.7 million. Although dole queues are expected to shorten during the spring, tax revenues and unemployment benefit costs are already tipping the fiscal arithmetic against Waigel.</p>
<p>Hax said that the German government and the European Union must make it clear now whether they intended to make use of the room for manoeuvre offered by Maastricht or put off EMU until state finances are in better shape.</p>
<p>&quot;Either you loosen the criteria, and you have to say so now, or Germany will have to get ready for the euro later,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately, the politicians have turned the possibility of a delay into a taboo. Through constant repetition one gets the impression that in no way can there be a postponement.</p>
<p>&quot;The truth is quite simple: Stability comes before the timetable. Germany and a group of other countries will probably not fulfil the convergence criteria before 1998. Only after that can the euro be introduced in all these countries.&quot;</p>
<p>That would mean that the euro would be launched in 2000. &quot;That would be better than if four or five countries march ahead,&quot; Hax said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
