<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428755" id="root" date="1997-03-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French Foreign Minister raps Renault on closure.</title>
<headline>French Foreign Minister raps Renault on closure.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette criticised Renault on Saturday for the way it decided to close a large Belgian car plant, saying the controversy showed progress was needed on European union.</p>
<p>&quot;A big company cannot consider that its employees are...'a throw-away product'. At the very least there has to be discussion, negotiation, before the decision,&quot; De Charette told the newspaper Le Figaro in an interview.</p>
<p>He said it was also necessary that &quot;rules for the labour debate be established at a level which corresponds to European reality.</p>
<p>&quot;This shows clearly that in reality the problem is not that there is too much Europe, but not enough.</p>
<p>&quot;The political, economic and monetary Europe must also be a people's Europe. Otherwise we are going to feed anti-European scepticism,&quot; De Charette said.</p>
<p>Renault workers staged brief strikes in several countries on Friday as the fallout over plans to close the large Belgian plant of Vilvoorde with the loss of 3,100 jobs spread, while Spain halted subsidies to the company.</p>
<p>Socialist Lionel Jospin, leader of France's biggest opposition force, said slow economic growth in Europe compared to the United States, and irregular tactics by South Korea were partly to blame for Renault's woes.</p>
<p>&quot;If U.S. industry functions better, it is also because there are growth rates which in the past 15 years have been much higher than in Europe. If there is not strong growth, there cannot be a flourishing car market,&quot; Jospin told Canal Plus television.</p>
<p>&quot;We signed an agreement with the Japanese in 1991, and today it is not completely respected. But we also have a new competitor -- South Korea. The European Union must tackle the problem of South Korean competition, which does not fall within the rules of international trade,&quot; Jospin added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
