<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428771" id="root" date="1997-03-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's Dini sees no risk of EMU delay.</title>
<headline>Italy's Dini sees no risk of EMU delay.</headline>
<dateline>VENICE, Italy 1997-03-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian Foreign Minister Lamberto Dini said on Saturday he saw no risk of a delay to the planned 1999 start of European Economic and Monetary Union but did not rule out a delay to the decision on who should qualify.</p>
<p>Dini, speaking to reporters at an Anglo-Italian seminar in Venice, said he did not think there was &quot;a risk of delay&quot; to EMU and did not see &quot;signs of delay at the moment&quot;.</p>
<p>The single currency is due to be launched on January 1, 1999 and a decision on which states will qualify as founder members is set to be made early next year.</p>
<p>&quot;Towards the end of the year we will be in a position to see whether the decisions on which countries will participate from the start will need to be put back a bit,&quot; Dini said.</p>
<p>Italy has pushed through a massive deficit-cutting 1997 budget and plans an extra package of finance measures to try to secure a place at the start of EMU despite fears in Germany that its rocky record on public finances could undermine EMU stability.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi has put his political credibility and that of his centre-left government on the line over Europe. Dini said that to fail to be in the first EMU group &quot;would be a big defeat which we cannot permit ourselves&quot;.</p>
<p>Prodi relies on support for a parliamentary majority from the hard-left Communist Refoundation party, which has opposed tax hikes and spending cuts in the forthcoming mini-budget.</p>
<p>But Dini said Europe was so important the government should take measures &quot;with or without the support of Communist Refoundation&quot;.</p>
<p>-- Rome newsroom +396 678 2501</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VENICE, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
