<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428740" id="root" date="1997-03-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USWC CARB gasoline rises with NYMEX, tight supply.</title>
<headline>USWC CARB gasoline rises with NYMEX, tight supply.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-03-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast CARB gasoline rose amid tight supplies and higher NYMEX markets Friday, brokers said.</p>
<p>West Coast gasoline remains tight, traders said, down 587,000 barrels as of February 28 with half-a-dozen of the region's refiners entering or still in maintenance, costing refiners about 300,000 bpd in throughput.</p>
<p>But traders said plants taken off line in January could begin start-up this coming week, including the crude unit at Mobil's 130,000 bpd crude Torrance, Calif., refinery and several unit's at Exxon's plant near San Francisco.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, heating oil for April delivery ended 0.65 cents a gallon higher on Friday, hitting 54.08 cents lifted by technical strength and forecasts of below-normal temperatures in the high-consumption Northeast U.S.</p>
<p>Front-month gasoline soe 1.19 cents to 65.67 cents.</p>
<p>Traders saw spot trade activity rising Monday and Tuesday ahead of pipeline commitment deadlines for third cycle March gasoline.</p>
<p>CARB gasoline in Los Angeles rose one cent to 76/77 cents a gallon, while San Francisco material climbed to 73/74 cents, narrowing the normal 2.50-cent spread between the two cities.</p>
<p>CARB diesel in L.A. was heard done at 74 cents, and the range was talked 72.50/74 cents, flat from yesterday.</p>
<p>((David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles bureau + 213 380 2015))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
