<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428998" id="root" date="1997-03-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA:  NATO'S SOLANA TO TRY AGAIN TO WIN MOSCOW ASSENT.</title>
<headline>NATO'S SOLANA TO TRY AGAIN TO WIN MOSCOW ASSENT.</headline>
<byline>Adam Tanner</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-03-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>NATO Secretary-General Javier Solana is scheduled to arrive in Moscow on Sunday to work out an agreement on future relations between Russia and NATO, which is planning to expand the Western alliance into eastern Europe.</p>
<p>During his brief visit Solana will hold an evening meeting with Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov, who has been a steadfast opponent of NATO expansion.</p>
<p>But Primakov in recent days has shown some flexibility in his response to NATO's plans to invite new members at a July summit -- expected to be Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been and are against the expansion. We are not going to change our position because NATO's expansion damages us,&quot; Primakov said in a speech on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;At the same time we do not have a veto right, and of course we will never repeat what has happened in 1968 Czechoslovakia,&quot; he said, referring to the Soviet decision to invade because it disagreed over the course of its ally's political reforms.</p>
<p>What Moscow was now seeking, he said, was a document from NATO that would help guarantee its security.</p>
<p>&quot;We want that the essence of this document would be non-advancement of NATO's military infrastructure to our territory,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Diplomats at NATO headquarters in Brussels say the two sides are working on such a document but differences remain.</p>
<p>&quot;There are now two draft texts -- one by Moscow, one by NATO. These two could be merged into a single one, though there would still be many brackets,&quot; said one alliance source.</p>
<p>Senior aides of Solana and Primakov have been working in Moscow this week preparing the ground for Sunday's meeting after Primakov, a former Russian spy-master, handed over several draft texts on different aspects of a deal in Brussels two weeks ago.</p>
<p>NATO sources say they expect during the Solana-Primakov meeting, the third this year, they would move to more substantive issues ahead of a summit in Helsinki on March 21 between Presidents Bill Clinton and Boris Yeltsin.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's return to active work in recent days after eight months of illness gives the West the potential of winning a decisive response from Moscow. Yet in his annual policy address on Thursday, the Russian president took a hard line against NATO.</p>
<p>&quot;NATO expansion can become a fateful decision which will cost the peoples of Europe very dear,&quot; he said, adding that building a security system in Europe without Russia was doomed to fail.</p>
<p>At a news conference on Friday Clinton voiced hope for progress during his two-day meting with Yeltsin, but said he expected to face &quot;tough&quot; issues.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect that the Helsinki meeting will be positive,&quot; he said. &quot;But you should understand that this is a tough debate and that they have reasons in their own psyche and circumstances that make it a difficult one.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton added NATO wants &quot;a special relationship with Russia and does not rule out even Russian membership in a common security alliance.&quot;</p>
<p>After his meetings in Moscow, NATO Secretary-General Solana is scheduled to leave on Monday on a tour of four former Soviet republics in Central Asia.</p>
<p>Primakov will visit the United States from March 15 to 17 for further talks ahead of the Clinton-Yeltsin summit.  REUTER ART</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
