<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="428930" id="root" date="1997-03-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: MOTOR RACING-COULTHARD BREAKS DROUGHT FOR MCLAREN.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-COULTHARD BREAKS DROUGHT FOR MCLAREN.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-03-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Briton David Coulthard won the season-opening Australian Grand Prix on Sunday to end a four-year drought for the McLaren team.</p>
<p>The 25-year-old driver finished 20 seconds ahead of the Ferrari of Michael Schumacher, with Finland's Mika Hakkinen third in the second McLaren a further two seconds back.</p>
<p>While it was a memorable day for McLaren team boss Ron Dennis, constructors' championship favourites Williams endured a dismal race, with both Jacques Villeneuve and Heinz-Harald Frentzen failing to finish at Albert Park.</p>
<p>World champion Damon Hill did not even start in what proved to be a deflating opening to his title defence when his Arrows broke down during the warm-up lap after losing power.</p>
<p>Drivers' championship favourite Villeneuve, who started from pole position after dominating qualifying, lasted until the first corner before his car left the track.</p>
<p>Frentzen challenged for the lead for much of the race before his Williams span off the track in the final few laps when he was in second place.</p>
<p>McLaren last won a grand prix when the late Ayrton Senna of Brazil triumphed in the 1993 Australian Grand Prix in Adelaide, a gap of 50 races.</p>
<p>Coulthard recorded his second grand prix win in his 42nd start, adding to his success in Portugal in 1995 with the Williams team.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
