<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42905" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-KEY ELEMENTS OF WEDNESDAY'S CHAMPIONS' LEAGUE MATCHES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-KEY ELEMENTS OF WEDNESDAY'S CHAMPIONS' LEAGUE MATCHES.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Analysis of key elements in Wednesday's European Cup Champions' League matches:</p>
<p>Group A</p>
<p>Auxerre (France) v Ajax Amsterdam (Netherlands)</p>
<p>Auxerre have lost several key players since they won the French league for the first time last season, including libero Laurent Blanc and striker Christophe Cocard. They will be without defender and captain Franck Silvestre, out for two months with a shoulder injury. Auxerre are fifth in the table.</p>
<p>Ajax, winners in 1995 and beaten finalists last season, seek a boost to morale after a wretched start to their Dutch league campaign. Top players Michael Reiziger, Finidi George, Edgar Davids and Nwankwo Kanu have been transferred since last season and the problems have been compounded by injuries to key men, such as experienced defender Danny Blind and striker Patrick Kluivert. Their European ambitions are afflicted by the absence through suspension of Blind, Richard Witschge, Nordin Wooter and Dani.</p>
<p>Grasshopper Zurich (Switzerland) v Glasgow Rangers (Scotland)</p>
<p>Grasshopper have been hit by injuries, notably to Euro 96 marksman Kubilay Turkyilmaz who turned in a lacklustre performance on his return against Lugano, and fellow striker Nestor Subiaz, a likely absentee. Defender Boris Smiljanic and midfielder Alexander Comisetti are out because of bookings. Bernt Haas is likely to come in for Smiljanic but trainer Christian Gross has yet to decide who will replace Camisetti.</p>
<p>Scottish premier league leaders Rangers have one injury doubt, with right back Alex Cleland needing continued treatment on a shin problem. Derek McInnes, who played in Saturday's 1-0 win at Motherwell, will be in contention for a midfield place alongside the likes of England's Paul Gascoigne and Dane Brian Laudrup. Scotland's Ally McCoist and Dutchman Peter van Vossen, on the substitutes' bench on Saturday, will be pushing for starting roles up front.</p>
<p>Group B</p>
<p>Atletico Madrid (Spain) v Steaua Bucharest (Romania)</p>
<p>Atletico's first game at the Vicente Calderon stadium since an invasion of worms at the ground in August but the pitch will not be Atletico's only problem. Influential playmaker Jose Luis Caminero and fellow midfielder Juan Vizcaino, whose absence was felt in Saturday's 3-1 loss at Compostela, are almost certainly out through injury. Czech midfielder Radek Bejbl and Argentine striker Juan Eduardo Esnaider were the only major close-season signings but on Saturday Esnaider was substituted after showing signs of losing his volatile temper and Bejbl was sent off.</p>
<p>Steaua Bucharest will be without three key players. Top scorer Adrian Ilie is banned for three games after being sent off in the preliminary round against Belgium's Club Brugge. Midfielder Iulian Filipescu is also suspended after receiving two bookings in previous matches and striker Marius Lacatus has a severe muscle strain and will be out for at least two weeks.</p>
<p>Borussia Dortmund (Germany) v Widzew Lodz (Poland)</p>
<p>Borussia Dortmund have lost Ghanaian striker Ibrahim Tanko, who tore a hamstring in Saturday's 1-0 win over Hansa Rostock. Fellow striker Karlheinz Riedle has a neck injury, leaving trainer Ottmar Hitzfeld little choice but to field out-of-form Swiss Stephane Chapuisat up front alongside Heiko Herrlich, who is still finding his form after returning this season from a long-term ankle injury. Hitzfeld may decide to give U.S. international striker Jovan Kirovski his debut. The defence is back to full strength after libero Matthias Sammer made a convincing return from injury against Rostock. Brazilian defender Julio Cesar suffered a knock on the knee but should play.</p>
<p>Widzew Lodz are looking to the quick reflexes and experience of goalkeeper Maciej Szczesny, who last season helped Legia Warsaw reach the European Cup quarter-finals. Widzew team manager Tadeusz Gapinski said the club had acquired Szczesny to bolster their defence for this European campaign. Widzew's attack, among the most potent in the Polish league, has lost Marek Koniarek, who now plays in the Austrian second division after finishing last season as top marksman in the Polish first division with 29 goals.</p>
<p>Group C</p>
<p>Rapid Vienna (Austria) v Fenerbahce (Turkey)</p>
<p>Rapid Vienna, beaten finalists in last season's European Cup Winners' Cup, boosted their confidence at the weekend with their first league victory of the season, an impressive 2-0 win over leaders Salzburg. They will be without Polish midfielder Krzysztof Ratajczyk, who fractured his ankle last Wednesday in a league match against Ried. But Bulgarian World Cup defender Trifon Ivanov will be available despite an eight-match suspension in the Austrian league.</p>
<p>Fenerbahce are on form and upbeat after beating bitter Istanbul rivals Galatasaray 4-0 in a weekend derby, Galatasaray's first defeat on home turf in four years. Fenerbahce are without Bulgarian striker Emil Kostadinov, out for the second match of a three-match suspension after being sent off against Israel's Maccabi Tel Aviv last month. International striker Saffet Sancakli, newly bought from Kocaelispor, will also be absent because he had not joined the club in time to be registered for the European competition.</p>
<p>Juventus (Italy) v Manchester United (England)</p>
<p>Juventus, reigning European Cup holders, were held 1-1 at Reggiana in their opening league game of the season on Sunday. They will be without defender Moreno Torricelli and Serb midfielder Vladmir Jugovic, both suspended. Experienced midfielder Antonio Conte, who missed Sunday's game through suspension, will probably replace Jugovic alongside Frenchmen Zinedine Zidane and Didier Dechamps. Sergio Porrini could replace Torricelli in defence. Croat Alen Boksic, Christian Vieri and Alessandro Del Piero are expected to form a three-pronged attack.</p>
<p>Manchester United hope England central defender Gary Pallister will be fit. Pallister twisted his knee at Derby last week and missed Saturday's 4-0 win over Leeds. His presence will be crucial if manager Alex Ferguson decides to play a three-man back line. Dutch forward Jordi Cruyff, Czech midfielder Karel Poborsky and Norwegian defender Ronny Johnsen have all joined United since the end of last season to give an already cosmopolitan side wider European experience.</p>
<p>Group D</p>
<p>Gothenburg (Sweden) v Rosenborg (Norway)</p>
<p>Swedish league leaders Gothenburg, who beat Degerfors 2-0 on Saturday, will be without midfielder Stefan Pettersson, who has a torn thigh muscle. International defender Teddy Lucic, out for two weeks with a buttock muscle injury, is also uncertain. Jesper Blomqvist, Pontus Erlingmark and Stefan Lindqvist have each received bookings. One more would rule them out of Gothenburg's next Champions' League match against Porto.</p>
<p>Rosenborg full-back Jon Olav Hjelde is injured. Midfielder Karl Oskar Fjoertoft could return but Rosenborg might well stick with the line-up which beat Start 2-1 at home on Saturday to clinch the Norwegian league title.</p>
<p>AC Milan (Italy) v Porto (Portugal)</p>
<p>AC Milan finished strongly to notch a 4-1 win over Verona in the first match of their Italian league title defence on Sunday. Their new Uruguayan coach Oscar Washington Tabarez faces a hard choice in attack, with Montenegrin Dejan Savicevic, Roberto Baggio, Marco Simone and Liberian George Weah in contention for three places. Savicevic, suspended for Sunday's game, may return at the expense of Baggio as Tabarez will be reluctant to drop in-form strikers Weah and Simone. With captain Franco Baresi out for at least a month with an ankle injury, Filippo Galli and Alessandro Costacurta will play in central defence. Frenchman Marcel Desailly, Croat Zvonimir Boban and Demetrio Albertini are the likely midfield line-up.</p>
<p>Porto will be without Austrian midfielder Arnold Wetl, a close-season signing from Sturm Graz who was not registered in time and cannot take part in European competition before January. Otherwise they are expected to field the side which brought the club their first win of the season, a 3-0 away win at Leiria on Saturday. But the Portuguese champions will need to improve on that performance, having taken the lead against lowly Leiria only after the home side were reduced to 10 men.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
