<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429073" id="root" date="1997-03-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania truce runs out as rebels hold south.</title>
<headline>Albania truce runs out as rebels hold south.</headline>
<byline>Ron Popeski</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-03-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>A ceasefire ordered by Albanian President Sali Berisha expired early on Sunday, with no word on whether it would be extended, as rebels maintained their hold over the south of the country.</p>
<p>The 48-hour truce expired at 6 a.m. (0500 GMT) on Sunday after European mediators appealed to Berisha to extend it to give more time for political parties to discuss a solution to the crisis and for people to hand in their weapons under a government amnesty.</p>
<p>Although Berisha was reported by former Austrian leader Franz Vranitzky on Saturday to be considering an extension, there was no word from the Albanian leader.</p>
<p>There was also no indication that government troops were preparing to move against rebels who have seized major towns in the south, and now are well armed after breaking into army munitions depots.</p>
<p>Berisha, with the support of opposition political parties, declared a 48-hour halt to government military actiion against the rebels on Friday, but the insurgents dismissed an amnesty offered by him and rejected his call to give up their weapons.</p>
<p>Civil unrest, sparked by the collapse of shady investment funds in January, has developed into an armed revolt demanding Berisha's resignation.</p>
<p>Rebels sezied the town of Gjirokaster, 30 km (20 miles) from the Greek border, on Saturday. They sent newly arrived government troops fleeing in disarray and ransacked a barracks.</p>
<p>&quot;The town has fallen to the people. Berisha's troops have turned tail and are in hiding,&quot; Omer Litse, a rebel leader, said.</p>
<p>Hundreds of rebels raced through the town in cars, firing into the air. People carried looted supplies of flour, rice and canned milk from state warehouses as rebel officers met to set up a council to organise the town's defence.</p>
<p>Gjirokaster, the main military base in the region, was the latest town in the south to fall to the rebels despite parliament's proclamation of a state of emergency. At least 20 people have been killed.</p>
<p>In Tirana, a Defence Ministry statement acknowledged that insurgents had attacked the Gjirokaster barracks, but said government troops had observed the ceasefire.</p>
<p>Vranitzky, head of an Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe delegation, told reporters Berisha was considering an extension of the ceasefire and ways of adapting his proposal to hold new elections.</p>
<p>&quot;He was very open to the idea and will give it very serious thought. He could even imagine that it could be longer than 48 hours,&quot; Vranitzky said after a second, unplanned round of talks with the Albanian leader.</p>
<p>He said Berisha was prepared to be flexible on the dates for fresh parliamentary elections. The president reissued a proposal to hold elections within 45 days, but opposition parties say polls are impossible under emergency rule.</p>
<p>Parliament, dominated by Berisha's Democratic Party after disputed elections last May, re-elected Berisha to a new five-year term last Monday.</p>
<p>Vranitzky's OSCE mission also met members of the Democratic Party and an 11-party opposition grouping committed to forming a broader-based government.</p>
<p>It was the latest of several Western attempts to mediate. Dutch Foreign Minister Hans Van Mierlo, representing the European Union presidency, urged Berisha on Friday to refrain from violence.</p>
<p>Italy evacuated 33 Italians and Albanians by helicopter from the port of Vlore, a flashpoint in the volatile south, on Saturday. But authorities in Rome said they would return asylum seekers to Albania.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
