<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429100" id="root" date="1997-03-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: FEATURE - Russian pollution capital fights back.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Russian pollution capital fights back.</headline>
<byline>Adam Tanner</byline>
<dateline>NIZHNY TAGIL, Russia 1997-03-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eduard Rossel, governor of the Urals' Sverdlovsk province, remembers his first swim in the river here as a particularly shocking experience.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought it was just dark water but then I realised that it was full of oily spots,&quot; he said about his 1958 dip. &quot;I took a look at my arms and they too were full of spots and I made a U-turn back.</p>
<p>&quot;My mother-in-law said 'What are you crazy, you could die from this,'&quot; Rossel said. &quot;I fully undressed and they poured boiling water all over me and rubbed off those oily spots.&quot;</p>
<p>Today, children swimming in Nizhny Tagil's river are less likely to suffer such trauma, and in winter they can look forward to playing in white rather than soot-blackened snow.</p>
<p>Long one of Russia's most polluted cities, Nizhny Tagil has finally started to clean up and it is beginning to show results.</p>
<p>&quot;Four years ago, factories were dumping 10 to 100 times more dangerous substances than today,&quot; said Natalia Yevdokimova of Clean House, a United States-funded environmental group. &quot;But now the anti-pollution process is only beginning.&quot;</p>
<p>At the start of the 1990s, Nizhny Tagil's vast but ageing steel, tank and metallurgy factories were pumping out 1,500 tonnes of air pollution per resident a year, said Angelia Savina, head of the city's ecology department. Now the amount is down to 450 tonnes per person.</p>
<p>THE CLEANSING EFFECT OF THE FREE MARKET</p>
<p>Environmentalists can thank the free market for much of the improvement; the end of state subsidies has forced firms to cut back sharply on output.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the drop is not because of our good work and exhortations to industry. Much is related to the fall in production,&quot; said Pavel Zhilin, head of the government's Regional Nature Preservation Committee.</p>
<p>&quot;For example, one cement factory put in pollution filters but then stopped production altogether, so its pollution fell to zero.&quot;</p>
<p>As production has fallen, the city has also started a pioneering five-year anti-pollution programme which, among other measures, levies a 1.5 percent tax on all production to be spent on environment and health-related problems.</p>
<p>At the huge metallurgy plant, the city's prime polluter, managers have shut down one particularly dangerous furnace complex and plan similiar moves with others.</p>
<p>&quot;The coke ovens of the Nizhny Tagil Metallurgy Plant pollute the atmosphere with benzpyrene, for example, a very strong cancerous agent,&quot; Viktor Danilov-Danilyan, Russia's top environmental official, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Nearby, the Vysokogorsky Mining and Ore Enrichment Plant is working out the final details on a $5.6 million World Bank loan to cover its 44-year-old waste pits, said deputy director Sergei Kurapov. Until then, when waste sand blows towards the centre, dangerous heavy metals will continue to pollute air and water.</p>
<p>LOCAL HEALTH STILL AT GREAT RISK</p>
<p>These efforts are too late for many residents of Nizhny Tagil's 406,000 residents, who are suffering from decades of exposure to dangerous and often cancerous chemicals.</p>
<p>The health of both adults and children has continued to worsen in recent years, with diseases affecting the lungs, skin, throat and blood on the increase, said Svetlana Chebotarkova, head of the city department of social hygiene.</p>
<p>&quot;These chemicals gather in the body over a period of many years and only then manifest themselves as disease,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The Vermont-based Institute for Sustainable Communities says that only four percent of all children in Nizhny Tagil are considered healthy.</p>
<p>The signs of environmental degradation are not hard to find. A distinct chemical smell permeates the city, and red, white and black smog blurs the horizon over the factories.</p>
<p>A view from a hill overlooking Nizhny Tagil shows a 10-km (six-mile) wide swathe of factories and smokestacks looming high above the city centre, with workers' quarters just beyond the factory gates.</p>
<p>Such conditions inspired the Soviet Union's first green demonstration in 1988. Previously city authorities had considered wide-scale industrialisation as the way to a bright communist future.</p>
<p>ENVIRONMENT A PRIORITY</p>
<p>Mayor Nikolai Didenko says the environment is now a top government priority. &quot;It's now less dangerous to live in the city, but like any industrial city, it is still dangerous,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Didenko and others look for inspiration to cities such as Chattanooga, Tennessee, a sister city famous for recovering from one of America's worst pollution blights in the 1960s.</p>
<p>Nizhny Tagil officials believe they can win the battle against pollution without giving up the industrial base as Chattanooga did. &quot;We must preserve our production to the maximum, as in Germany where they have the Ruhr Valley but it is ecologically acceptable,&quot; Didenko said.</p>
<p>Zhilin, whose agency monitors pollution levels, said the government can achieve such success by forcing industry to modernise and eliminate their most dangerous pollution sources.</p>
<p>Some environmentalists worry that preserving the city's industrial might will doom efforts to clean the environment, especially after the economy improves in future years.</p>
<p>There is a wide consensus that Nizhny Tagil still needs plenty of time and money before residents can enjoy truly clean air and water. &quot;Even if we invest $2 billion here, I don't think the city will be completely safe,&quot; Zhilin said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NIZHNY TAGIL, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
