<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429112" id="root" date="1997-03-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Castro says Cuba can expect nothing from U.S.</title>
<headline>Castro says Cuba can expect nothing from U.S.</headline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1997-03-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cuban President Fidel Castro, offering a gloomy view of relations with the United States, has said his country can expect &quot;nothing&quot; from the current or future U.S. administrations, according to remarks published on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;We can expect nothing from the United States,&quot; Castro was quoted as telling a meeting in Havana this week of Cuba's ambassadors from around the world.</p>
<p>&quot;We can expect nothing from this (U.S) administration, nor from those to come,&quot; he added in remarks published on Sunday by the Cuban Communist Youth newspaper Juventud Rebelde.</p>
<p>The remarks gave an unusually gloomy assessment of the current state of Cuba's relations with the United States and appeared to rule out any prospects of an improvement in the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>Castro briefed the ambassadors just days before the first anniversary of the Helms-Burton Law passed by the U.S. Congress last March, which seeks to tighten Washington's 35-year-old economic embargo against communist-ruled Cuba.</p>
<p>The Helms-Burton legislation was signed into law by President Bill Clinton partially in response to Cuba's shooting down on Feb. 24, 1996, of two small U.S.-registered planes flown by Cuban exiles.</p>
<p>The law specifically demanded Cuba dump Castro and abandon one-party socialism and also threatened penalties against foreign investors who &quot;traffick&quot; in expropriated, formerly U.S.-owned properties in Cuba.</p>
<p>The Cuban government, encouraged by strong international opposition to the Helms-Burton Law, launched a propaganda counter-offensive against the U.S. legislation.</p>
<p>It told its citizens the law aimed to return Cuba to the days of Cuban dictator Fulgencio Batista, who was overthrown by Castro in the 1959 Revolution.</p>
<p>&quot;Inside the country and outside, we have to keep on working, knowing that we have against us the most powerful enemy in the world,&quot; Castro told the Cuban ambassadors.</p>
<p>Cuban leaders have said the Helms-Burton law is hurting the Cuban economy but will not stop it from growing, nor halt foreign investment on the island.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
