<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429109" id="root" date="1997-03-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian minister blasts U.S. envoy.</title>
<headline>Colombian minister blasts U.S. envoy.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-03-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian Interior Minister Horacio Serpa branded U.S. envoy Myles Frechette a &quot;sick gringo&quot; as days of name-calling and rising tension between the two countries reached boiling point.</p>
<p>President Ernesto Samper condemned those Colombians who court favour with the U.S. ambassador, warning they would suffer the curse of the &quot;crocodile man&quot; -- a mythical creature used by Colombian mothers to frighten naughty children.</p>
<p>Serpa's verbal broadside on Saturday capped a week in which a congressman called Frechette a &quot;son-of-a-bitch&quot; and labour leaders burned the Stars and Stripes in the wake of a U.S. decision to &quot;decertify&quot; Colombia as an ally in the drug war for a second consecutive year.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Myles Frechette) is a diplomatic agent who has earned the contempt of all Colombians for a thousand good reasons,&quot; Serpa told townspeople as he accompanied Samper on a trip to Plato, in northern Magadalena province.</p>
<p>&quot;In an interview he (Frechette) said 'I prefer people to call me gringo',&quot; local media quoted Serpa as saying, referring to an interview published in the El Espectador newspaper on Saturday. &quot;Well that's fine, we'll carry on calling him that but in coastal dialect -- sick gringo.&quot;</p>
<p>Frechette has a reputation for meddling in Colombia's domestic politics and using carrot-and-stick tactics to bully the country's Congress into pushing through tougher anti-drug laws -- earning him the nicknames of the &quot;Viceroy&quot; and the &quot;Vampire&quot;.</p>
<p>Colombian-U.S. relations plummeted again 10 days ago when the United States blacklisted Colombia for the second consecutive year for failing to crack down hard enough on drug trafficking.</p>
<p>The ruling was widely regarded as a personal slight on Samper, who took office in August 1994 amid allegations he funded his election campaign with donations from the powerful Cali drug cartel.</p>
<p>He was cleared in a congressional inquiry last year but the United States has steadfastly refused to accept that verdict.</p>
<p>In an apparent reference to opposition politicians and businessmen who have tried to curry favour with the U.S. envoy and blamed Samper for Colombia's failure to regain certification, Samper told the meeting in Plato: &quot;Those Colombians who have paid homage to that agent (Frechette) will suffer the curse of the crocodile man.&quot;</p>
<p>In the lead-up to decertification, U.S. Assistant Secretary of State Robert Gelbard called Samper a &quot;truly corrupt president.&quot; Serpa, seen as Samper's staunchest defender in government, retaliated by calling Gelbard &quot;inept, rude and brazen.&quot;</p>
<p>Serpa's latest outburst seems to have been sparked by Frechette's admission in a series of media interviews that he received offers from the former Cali cartel leaders to turn evidence against Samper.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
