<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429215" id="root" date="1997-03-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan ex-AIDS expert faces trial on unheated blood.</title>
<headline>Japan ex-AIDS expert faces trial on unheated blood.</headline>
<byline>Yvonne Chang</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's former top AIDS expert will go on trial on Monday for a decade-long scandal involving the use of HIV-tainted blood products on haemophiliacs.</p>
<p>The high profile case involves allegations of a government cover-up, unethical links between big business and bureaucrats and whether an AIDS sufferer can be named in court.</p>
<p>Takeshi Abe, a doctor specialising in haemophilia, will be tried for allegedly using blood products that had not been heat-treated, knowing that the products could have been tainted with HIV, the human immunodeficiency virus that causes Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome (AIDS).</p>
<p>Abe, 80, was arrested in August 1996 on professional negligence charges when the mother of a haemophiliac who died after contracting AIDS through unheated blood products filed criminal charges against him.</p>
<p>Nearly 400 haemophiliacs treated with unheated blood in the 1980's have died of AIDS and AIDS-related complications.</p>
<p>AIDS activists say another 2,000 haemophliacs have AIDS.</p>
<p>&quot;Time won't resolve the pain. But I want to see if Abe expresses remorse,&quot; the patient's mother said last week.</p>
<p>Abe's lawyer, Junichiro Hironaka, said his client would plead not guilty and welcomed a trial so he could clear his name.</p>
<p>&quot;Dr. Abe said he wants a verdict proving him innocent as soon as possible,&quot; Hironaka told Reuters. &quot;Dr. Abe spent his lifetime doing what he thought best for the treatment of haemophiliacs. He said he has nothing to feel ashamed of.&quot;</p>
<p>In manouevering before the Tokyo District Court trial, Hironaka rejected a request that the victim not be named.</p>
<p>The mother made the request because she said there was &quot;rampant&quot; discrimination against the family of AIDS sufferers.</p>
<p>&quot;The victim's mother reportedly said that she would not be able to continue living if her son's name was read out in court,&quot; the Daily Yomiuri newspaper reported on Sunday.</p>
<p>Abe, vice president of Tokyo's Teikyo University, headed a research team set up by the Health Ministry in 1983 to investigate the source of AIDS infection in Japan.</p>
<p>The charges say Abe influenced the team's decision in March 1984 to favour the use of unheated blood products instead of using heated products, such as cryoprecipitate. The Health Ministry did not ban the unheated products until December 1985.</p>
<p>Abe claimed he had no choice but to use unheated products in the 1980s because cryoprecipitate was not easily available, and even if used, tended to dangerously clog blood vessels.</p>
<p>Hironaka said he would argue that no one in and outside Japan at the time used cryoprecipitate to treat haemophiliacs.</p>
<p>Over the next month, there will be separate trials of former Health Ministry official Akihito Matsumura and former top executives of Osaka-based pharmaceutical company Green Cross Corp who have been linked to the scandal.</p>
<p>Matsumura, who headed the ministry's Biologics and Antibiotics Division from 1984 to 1986, is accused of failing to order the recall of untreated blood products even though he knew the products could be contaminated with HIV.</p>
<p>Green Cross Corp, once one of Japan's top pharmaceutical firms, announced last month that it will be taken over by another Japanese pharmaceutical firm.</p>
<p>The Health Ministry for years maintained it could not find documents on the case, but last year revealed files from the 1983 study group indicating that ministry authorities were aware of the danger of HIV infection from unheated products.</p>
<p>In March 1996, Japanese haemophiliacs accepted a one-time payment of 45 million yen ($371,000) each, ending a seven-year legal battle against the state and five pharmaceutical firms, including Green Cross.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
