<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429251" id="root" date="1997-03-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PLO rejects Israeli redeployment plan.</title>
<headline>PLO rejects Israeli redeployment plan.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-03-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The PLO will reject officially in talks with Israel on Sunday Israeli plans to hand over nine percent of the West Bank in the first of three redeployments in the area, a Palestinian peace negotiator said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Israelis requested this meeting and we will submit our rejection officially,&quot; Saeb Erekat told Reuters a day after Palestinian President Yasser Arafat called the pullback, which the PLO had hoped would cover 30 percent of the West Bank, a trick.  </p>
<p>Erekat said he would be part of a Palestinian delegation led by Mahmoud Abbas, also known as Abu Mazen, due to meet Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy at a Jerusalem hotel later in the day.</p>
<p>&quot;We must decide the scope and the dimension of the redeployment together,&quot; Erekat said, accusing Israel of violating a September 1995 peace deal that laid the ground for three pullbacks from mainly rural areas of the West Bank by mid-1998.</p>
<p>Israel says a U.S. note that accompanied a subsequent accord signed in January this year left the scale of the withdrawals to its sole discretion.</p>
<p>Erekat acknowledged Israel might go ahead with the pullback, expected this week, without PLO agreement. But to do so, he said, would be tantamount to dictating peace terms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
