<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42923" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: MOTOR RACING-SCHUMACHER'S BROTHER TO JOIN HIM IN FORMULA ONE.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-SCHUMACHER'S BROTHER TO JOIN HIM IN FORMULA ONE.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The younger brother of Michael Schumacher is set to join the world motor racing champion on the Formula One grid next season, the German daily Bild reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Bild said 21-year-old Ralf Schumacher, currently leading the Formula 3000 standings, would sign for the Jordan team before the Portuguese Grand Prix in Estoril on September 22.</p>
<p>It quoted the Schumachers' manager Willi Weber as saying: &quot;We will announce a deal at the race in Estoril next week.&quot;</p>
<p>The McLaren team, powered by German Mercedes engines, have also shown interest in the younger Schumacher, who has test-driven for the team.</p>
<p>But Bild said McLaren boss Ron Dennis felt Ralf Schumacher was still too inexperienced to get a driver's contract.  </p>
<p>In England, Jordan team spokeswoman Louise Goodman said: &quot;It is just speculation. We have spoken with Schumacher's management, but have also talked to a number of other people.</p>
<p>&quot;No decisions have yet been reached about next year and the situation is still open.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
