<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429284" id="root" date="1997-03-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Velayati starts 10-day tour, to visit Saudi Arabia.</title>
<headline>Velayati starts 10-day tour, to visit Saudi Arabia.</headline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-03-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran's Foreign Minister Ali Akbar Velayati flew to Damascus on Sunday at the start of a 10-day tour of European, African, Middle Eastern and Gulf Arab states, including his country's powerful neighbour Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>State media said Velayati would invite heads of state of the member countries of the Organisation of the Islamic Conference (OIC) to a summit due to be held in Tehran in December.</p>
<p>The English-language Iran News newspaper said that after Syria Velayati would visit Turkey, Sudan, Uganda, the Czech Republic and Gulf Arab states, including Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>&quot;This will be Velayati's first visit to Saudi Arabia in four years, and as such is considered to be very significant,&quot; one official source told Iran News.</p>
<p>Iran and Saudi Arabia, both major oil exporters, have had often tense relations. Saudi Arabia and other Gulf states have accused their non-Arab neighbour of interfering in their internal affairs -- a charge Iran denies -- and voiced concern over its arms build-up.</p>
<p>Saudi officials have refused to confirm recent U.S. media reports that Iran was linked to the June bombing of a U.S. housing complex in the kingdom which killed 19 U.S. servicemen.</p>
<p>Iran, which has attacked U.S. and Western military presence in the region, has denied any involvement.</p>
<p>Ties between Iran and Saudi Arabia are usually strained over the annual Moslem pilgrimage to holy sites in the kingdom with Iran insisting on holding political rallies during haj in defiance of a Saudi ban. Haj this year falls in April.</p>
<p>The official news agency IRNA said Velayati would hold talks with officials in Sudan and Uganda &quot;in continuation of Iran's peace initiative&quot; to reconcile the two countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISLAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SYRIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
