<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429375" id="root" date="1997-03-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Bangladesh tribal refugees to return from India.</title>
<headline>Bangladesh tribal refugees to return from India.</headline>
<byline>Syed Sajjad Ali</byline>
<dateline>AGARTALA, India 1997-03-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>About 50,000 Bangladeshi tribal refugees, living in six relief camps in India's remote Tripura state, will start returning home in batches this month, officials said on Sunday.</p>
<p>An agreement was signed between Bangladesh officials and the representatives of the tribal refugees at the state capital of Agartala, bordering Bangladesh.</p>
<p>The refugees had crossed over to India from Bangladesh to escape an insurgency in the Chittagong Hill Tracts.</p>
<p>&quot;Five thousand refugees will return home in the first phase,&quot; said a statement signed jointly by A.S.M. Mobaidul Islam, director of special affairs in Bangladesh Prime Minister's office and Upendra Lal Chakma, president of Chittagong Hill Tracts Refugee Welfare Association.</p>
<p>The first phase will begin on March 28, it said.</p>
<p>The announcement followed a visit by a Bangladesh parliamentary delegation, led by Abul Hasanat Abdullah and a series of discussions with Chittagong Hill Tracts Refugees Welfare Association.</p>
<p>&quot;The second phase of repatriation will take place after the visit of refugee leaders in Chittagong Hill Tracts to study the rehabilitation process and situation in Chittagong Hill Tracts,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Chakma told reporters that both sides had reached an agreement on all issues.</p>
<p>&quot;Dhaka is keen to take back all the refugees of six south Tripura camps as early as possible,&quot; Abdullah told Reuters.</p>
<p>Abdullah is chairman of a national committee in Bangladesh trying to restore peace in the Hill Tracts, home to 13 tribes and some 300,000 Bengali-speaking settlers.</p>
<p>Bangladesh government and leaders of the rebel Shanti Bahini guerrillas held their first meeting in Dhaka in January but failed to reach any deal to halt the revolt. They decided to meet again on March 12.</p>
<p>The Shanti Bahini, made up mostly of Chakma tribesmen, has fought since 1973 for autonomy for the 5,500-sq-mile (14,200-sq-km) Hill Tracts, which border India and Burma.</p>
<p>The rebels accuse the settlers of stealing their land and destroying their culture. They want them expelled from the area.</p>
<p>More than 8,500 rebels, soldiers and civilians have been killed in the insurgency, which has forced about 50,000 tribespeople to seek refuge in India, Bangladeshi officials say.</p>
<p>Some 6,000 refugees returned to Bangladesh in 1994, but the process was stopped for unexplained reasons.</p>
<p>&quot;The (Tripura) state government will make all necessary arrangements for smooth repatriation,&quot; state relief commissioner Anil Mishra told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Indian government has so far spent 800 million rupees ($22.35 million) for the refugees in the six camps, Mishra said. ($1 = 35.8 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AGARTALA, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
