<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429397" id="root" date="1997-03-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian Renault workers protest at plant closure.</title>
<headline>Belgian Renault workers protest at plant closure.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some 3,500 people  marched through the streets of Vilvoorde, near Brussels on Sunday in a peaceful protest against the planned closure of the local Renault car assembly plant.</p>
<p>The march, supported by all political parties, involved mainly local families and young people worried that the area would lose its main livelihood with little prospect of alternative employment.</p>
<p>&quot;Vilvoorde is Renault and Renault is Vilvoorde,&quot; said one woman marcher.</p>
<p>On Friday, angry Belgian Renault workers hurled a car chassis across police barricades as they demonstrated outside the French embassy in Brussels.</p>
<p>They were trying to reverse a decision by Paris-based Renault to close its Vilvoorde plant with the loss of 3,100 jobs. Thousands more jobs could be lost among the plant's suppliers, dealers and repairers.</p>
<p>The French state holds a 46 percent stake in Renault and unions have charged that the company targeted the Belgian plant in its restructuring to avoid heavy job losses in France.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
