<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429345" id="root" date="1997-03-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German tax talks on hold as pit workers protest.</title>
<headline>German tax talks on hold as pit workers protest.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Busvine</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The fate of cross-party talks on crucial German tax reforms hung in the balance on Sunday after opposition Social Democrats (SPD) pulled out in sympathy with miners protesting at government plans to slash coal subsidies.</p>
<p>SPD leader Oskar Lafontaine, seizing on the mood of angry pit workers, said there was no sense in resuming talks on coalition plans to cut taxes unless ordinary workers came out better off from the start of 1998.    He called on Chancellor</p>
<p>Helmut Kohl's government to cancel plans to more than halve aid to coal mines in the Ruhr industrial belt and his own Saarland state which would put tens of thousands out of work.</p>
<p>&quot;The government's plans would plunge many cities and towns in the Ruhr and Saar into a deep crisis. That cannot happen. You can't treat miners like that,&quot; he said in a statement issued by his party on Sunday.</p>
<p>The SPD pulled out of the tax talks on Saturday and instead held an emergency &quot;coal conference&quot; in Duesseldorf, where 5,000 demonstrating miners chanted &quot;string up Kohl&quot;.</p>
<p>Miners union leader Hans Berger, met by chants of &quot;Judas&quot; for agreeing to meet Kohl again on Tuesday, managed only with difficulty to stop the crowd from getting out of hand.</p>
<p>&quot;Our answer can't be 'string him up' -- it must be 'vote him out',&quot; he told the miners. Germany is due to hold general elections in autumn 1998.</p>
<p>Miners had shut down Germany's 18 pits on Friday and their protests continued on Sunday in Saarland, where they occupied a mine and blocked roads to Luxembourg.</p>
<p>Wolfgang Schaeuble, parliamentary head of Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU), accused Lafontaine of putting party tactics before his responsibilities to the nation.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not tolerate any delay. The SPD must say now if it wants a quick reform to get businesses to invest and to create jobs,&quot; Schaeuble told Sunday's Welt am Sonntag newspaper.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel issued an ultimatum to the SPD to decide at its leadership meeting on Monday to return to the negotiating table, or else he would go it alone and legislate to cut 30 billion marks in taxes by 1999.</p>
<p>Waigel told the Bild am Sonntag newspaper that if the SPD used its majority in the Bundesrat upper house of parliament to block the legislation, &quot;it alone will bear responsibility for this crash course and all its results.&quot;</p>
<p>Lafontaine did not rule out a resumption of the talks, but did set conditions. He said the coalition must accept SPD demands for tax cuts to help ordinary families and reductions in Germany's notoriously high labour overheads.</p>
<p>&quot;If the government makes sensible proposals which would really help in the fight against unemployment, then the SPD is ready for further talks and immediate decisions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The dramatic worsening of the political climate could not have come at a more inconvenient time for Kohl, who said on Saturday that Germany's jobs crisis would not prevent Bonn making the grade for European monetary union (EMU) -- his pet project.</p>
<p>Dismissing mounting doubts that a weak economy and record post-war unemployment of 4.7 million would force government borrowing over the Maastricht treaty's limits, Kohl said Bonn would meet its commitments to join EMU on time in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;We will stick to both the agreed start date and the convergence criteria,&quot; Kohl said in Berlin.</p>
<p>Kohl spoke after his government's most senior economic advisor said Germany would miss the Maastricht targets both for the budget deficit and public debt this year.</p>
<p>Herbert Hax, head of the &quot;five wise men&quot; independent advisory panel, said the project should be delayed until Germany and other European states get their finances in order.</p>
<p>&quot;If you take the stability criteria seriously, Germany will probably not be able to introduce the euro as planned in 1999,&quot; Hax told Bild am Sonntag.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I11000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
