<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429449" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Growth in North America seen solid in '97 - study.</title>
<headline>Growth in North America seen solid in '97 - study.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite growing regional trade deficits in the United States, economic expansion in North America will continue to be firm through 1997 and into 1998, according to a three-nation study released on Monday.</p>
<p>The study, released by The Conference Board Inc, The Conference Board of Canada and Centro de Estudios Economicos del Sector Privado A.C. of Mexico, revealed that economic growth in North America should remain &quot;solid&quot; in 1997.  </p>
<p>Gail Fosler, senior vice president and chief economist of The Conference Board, said 1997 &quot;will be the first year since 1994 that the domestic markets in the U.S., Canada and Mexico will grow at significant rates simultaneously.&quot;</p>
<p>Growth in Mexico is expected to outpace that of its major economic neighbors, with an estimated Gross Domestic Product (GDP) increase of 4.8 percent in 1997, according to the study.</p>
<p>While the Latin American country is still recovering from its 1994 peso crisis, growth will be driven almost entirely by its domestic economy, it said.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, GDP in the United States is projected at 2.9 percent, mostly fueled by low interest rates and strong consumer and business confidence, the study said.</p>
<p>The Canadian economy is expected to expand at about the same pace as the United States, the study found.</p>
<p>&quot;Although driven largely by exports, Canada's domestic economy is showing some modest signs of life for the first time this decade,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>However, Fosler said the clear forecast for economic expansion in North America may could eventually cloud over.  </p>
<p>&quot;The key threats to growth are a growing U.S. trade deficit, arising from the strong dollar, and higher U.S. inflation and interest rates,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Higher interest rates in the U.S. could create a peak in industrial activity late in 1997, triggering slower U.S. growth and trouble for Canadian and Mexican exporters in 1998, the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;The economic outlook in 1997 poses the most difficult profit challenge for U.S. business since the late 1980s,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;This year will bring a reawakening of cyclical growth and inflation pressures which will compel the Federal Reserve to raise the federal funds rate by at least 75 basis points,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Faster-than-expected growth and a less accomodative Federal policy will push long-term bond yields up to has much as 7.7 percent by third-quarter 1997, the study found.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite higher inflation and a growing account deficit, however, the dollar will hold much of its recent gain in 1997 as weak economies and financial uncertainty in Germany and Japan undercut the relative strength of their currencies,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>(( -- Jeff Coelho, 212-859-1660 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
