<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="42941" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: PRESS DIGEST - CZECH REPUBLIC - SEPT 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - CZECH REPUBLIC - SEPT 10.</headline>
<text>
<p>PRAVO - Finance Minister Ivan Kocarnik expects an increase in heating prices of 35 percent next year.</p>
<p>- Consumer prices rose by only 0.2 percent in August over July. This marks a 9.6 percent increase over August 1995.</p>
<p>- Finland supports efforts by the Czech Republic to join the European Union and NATO according to Finnish President Martti Ahtisaari, who came to Prague yesterday on a three-day official visit.</p>
<p>- Germany's Deutsche Bank is issuing bonds in Czech crowns. The issue has a value of one billion crowns. Bayerische Vereinsbank issued a two-billion crown bond in Czech crowns last week.</p>
<p>- Industrial production increased by 15.6 percent as compared to July 1995. In the first seven months of 1996 industrial production increased by 9.1 percent.</p>
<p>- PPF will request the approval of the Ceska Pojistovna (CP) supervisory council for the transfer of 16 percent of Ceska Pojistovna shares from Investicni a Postovni Banka after PPF has come to an agreement with the National Property Fund that they will not oppose the transfer, according to the chairman of PPF's board of directors, Petr Kellner.</p>
<p>- Czechinvest, which is involved in drawing direct investment to the Czech Republic, opened its first branch office in the United States in Chicago on Monday. Czechinvest is the second company of its type from Central Europe which has begun operating in the USA.</p>
<p>- After an agreement with union leaders, Skoda Liaz has decided to lay off 170 of its 3000 employees. The reason for the layoff was the decrease in the production of lorries and spare parts.</p>
<p>- The State Market Regulation Fund will likely not purchase the amount of wheat it previously intended.  The fund has currently purchased 40,000 tonnes though it originally intended to purchase 460,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>- Inekon Group expects to post a gross profit of 300 million crowns for 1996.</p>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - According to Interior Minister Jan Ruml, a parliamentary commission to investigate the bankruptcy of Kreditni Banka is unnecessary.</p>
<p>- Ceska Rafinerske, which has a monopoly on fuel production in the Czech Republic, would face a decrease in profits in the event of a devaluation of the Czech crown.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus yesterday signed contracts to support and protect investment with his Malaysian counterpart in Kuala Lampur on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsdesk - 42-2-2324-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
