<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429527" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lightpath seeks Japanese investors.</title>
<headline>Lightpath seeks Japanese investors.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>LightPath Technology said it is looking for investment from Japanese optical firms like Nikon Corp, Minolta Co Ltd or Canon Inc as it expands into Asian markets.</p>
<p>LightPath earlier on Monday announced an alliance with Hikari Glass Co -- 40 percent owned by Nikon -- to speed acceptance of LightPath's gradium glass in Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;We would expect as we grow in Japan over the next 24 months an investment from someone like Nikon,&quot; Lightpath Chief Operating Officer Don Lawson told Reuters in an interview.  </p>
<p>Lawson said tentative contacts with several Japanese companies like Minolta and Canon had taken place about investment, but none had yet been made. The alliance does not yet include an investment by Hikari or Nikon in Lightpath.</p>
<p>LightPath, based in Albuquerque, New Mexico, invented gradium glass, which has unusual internal light-bending properties. These are particularly useful for putting the performance of a multi-lens system into a single lens.</p>
<p>Hikari makes lenses and prisms using novel manufacturing processes, including &quot;continuous flow&quot; -- a high volume, low-cost method that creates glass in its final form.</p>
<p>&quot;This alliance is a major leap forward for LightPath,&quot; said LightPath Chairman Leslie Danziger. &quot;This agreement provides LightPath much greater access to the expanding Asian optoelectronics market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>LightPath stock units are made up of common stock, and two classes of warrants.</p>
<p>The company opened its annual stockholders meeting Monday.</p>
<p>(( Nick Louth, New York Newsroom 212 859 1712))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37330">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
