<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429749" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: SOCCER SHOWCASE-PSV EMERGE FROM STALEMATE AS WINNERS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-PSV EMERGE FROM STALEMATE AS WINNERS.</headline>
<dateline>ROTTERDAM 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dutch league title chase entered its final furlong with PSV Eindhoven still favourites after their 0-0 draw with Feyenoord at Rotterdam on Sunday.</p>
<p>But while PSV will be satisfied to have left Rotterdam with their three-point lead at the top of the table intact, the Dutch media were unanimous in their condemnation of the relatively dull spectacle between this season's top two sides.</p>
<p>&quot;It was as if there was no title on offer, so unbearably dull was the match,&quot; the Algemeen Dagblad newspaper said.</p>
<p>Top-selling paper De Telegraaf asked who was to blame for the &quot;dull tactical chess game&quot; which drew only two saves of any note.</p>
<p>Feyenoord coach Arie Haan denied the game was as turgid as suggested, saying: &quot;I saw an exciting match and, to go by the reaction of the crowd, they did too.&quot;</p>
<p>Haan was upbeat about his side's prospects despite being held at home to an understrength PSV.</p>
<p>With third-placed Twente Enschede losing at lowly FC Groningen on Sunday the title fight now looks to be a two-horse race that will break Ajax Amsterdam's three year dominance.</p>
<p>&quot;We made things difficult for PSV who are a good side,&quot; Haan said. &quot;With ten matches left, we are only three points behind. Who will make the first mistake? The fight for the championship has only just begun.&quot;</p>
<p>PSV coach Dick Advocaat was perhaps more honest about the entertainment value of Sunday's clash.</p>
<p>&quot;At least it was nice weather,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROTTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
