<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429795" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: FORECAST - POLISH REPO/REVREPO SEEN DOWN BY END '97.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - POLISH REPO/REVREPO SEEN DOWN BY END '97.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Banks are mixed in their views on market liquidity at the end of this year, as they see drainage rates falling but some expect the central bank to hold repo operations, a Reuters poll of Poland's 26 biggest showed.</p>
<p>Banks predicted the National Bank of Poland's 14-day revrepo rate, last at 21.65 percent, would fall to 18.89 percent by year-end. The forecast is a mean average of banks' predictions ranging from 17.20 to 21.00 percent.</p>
<p>Last month banks saw the revrepo rate down to 17.84 percent.</p>
<p>Banks expected the reverse repo rate to stabilise this month at 21.65 percent with a range from 21.60 to 21.70 percent and to fall to 17.92 percent in March 1998 with a range from 15.00 to 21.75 percent.</p>
<p>Nine of the polled banks expected the central bank would stage both reverse repo and repo operations or only repos at the end of the year.</p>
<p>The repo rate at the end of 1997 was seen at 18.89 percent on average with a range of predictions from 17.20 to 21.00 percent.</p>
<p>Only four banks expected the central bank to do repos in March and their average rate prediction was 21.99 percent with a range of 21.65 to 22.64 percent. Banks saw the repo rate falling to 18.46 percent in 12 months time -- in March 1998 -- with a range of 16.20 to 20.50 percent.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
