<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429946" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire rebels say gold mines returning to work.</title>
<headline>Zaire rebels say gold mines returning to work.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Tostevin</byline>
<dateline>GOMA, Zaire 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rebels occupying most of eastern Zaire said on Monday that gold mines they hold had resumed production and could help to pay for their war to overthrow President Mobutu Sese Seko.</p>
<p>Substantial mineral reserves, mostly gold, lie in the stretch of eastern Zaire controlled by rebels of Laurent Kabila's Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire (ADFL).</p>
<p>The movement's economy commissioner, Mawapanga Mwana Nanga, told Reuters that two mines in the Kilo-Moto area over 500 km (300 miles) north of Goma are together producing around 19 kg of gold per month.</p>
<p>The Kimin mine at Mongwalu, 70 km (45 miles) northwest of Bunia, has been back in operation for almost a month after falling to the rebels in early January, Mawapanga said in the eastern border town of Goma.</p>
<p>That mine is part of the 2000-sq-km OKIMO concession, 84 km (50 miles) north of Bunia,  controlled by a Belgian-Canadian consortium.</p>
<p>Retreating soldiers of the ragged army loyal to Mobutu, who had personal connections with the mine, looted offices and staff quarters before retreating, but left the processing plant intact.</p>
<p>&quot;Kimin has been talking to Ashanti Goldfields about a possible $25 million investment to increase production from the current level of around 17 kg per month,&quot; said Mawapanga.</p>
<p>&quot;The Okimo mine in the same area was virtually closed and we hope that by proper management production will soon grow to 10 kg per month from two kg per month at present.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the rebels had not yet spoken to Barrick Gold Corporation which has rights to an 83,000 sq km concession in the region.</p>
<p>Despite potential mineral wealth which could have made it one of Africa's richest countries, Zaire has been impoverished by years of neglect, corruption and outbreaks of political and ethnic violence which have scared off potential investors.</p>
<p>&quot;Mining is still providing a small proportion of income at the moment but there is a lot of potential,&quot; said Mawapanga.</p>
<p>Mining sources said a threat hangs over the heads of companies with concessions in eastern Zaire that if they do not enter discussions with the rebels they will lose their mining rights.</p>
<p>Mawapanga said local investors were already expressing interest in the Kamituga gold mine 130 km (80 miles) southwest of Bukavu, which is part of the Sominki concession owned by an Anglo-Canadian consortium of Cluff Mining and Banro Resources Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;Sominki have apparently abandoned the mine and we don't want it to stay idle,&quot; said Mawapanga.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course we are still interested in talking to Sominki if they want to talk to us.&quot;</p>
<p>Apart from the industrial mines the remote forests and hills hide numerous alluvial gold deposits which are exploited on a small scale  -- and which the rebels are also see as a source of revenue.</p>
<p>&quot;At least two or three people a week are applying for buying permits, not only for gold but also for diamonds, now that we no longer demand a $100,000 fee but just the contribution from exports,&quot; Mawapanga said.</p>
<p>After beating back an army counter-offensive the rebels are now poised to assault Kisangani, the largest city in eastern Zaire, centre of alluvial diamond mining and Zaire's third largest city.</p>
<p>Further south rebel fighters have moved deep into the Shaba region which contains some of the world's richest unexploited deposits of copper and cobalt.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GOMA, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
