<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429959" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>TANZANIA: KLM says flowers boosting Tanzanian cargo.</title>
<headline>KLM says flowers boosting Tanzanian cargo.</headline>
<byline>Maja Wallengren</byline>
<dateline>DAR ES SALAAM 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>KLM Royal Dutch Airlines saw a 25 percent increase in cargo on its direct route to Tanzania in 1996 over the previous year, while passenger traffic rose by 10 percent, Dick van Nieuwenhuyzen, regional manager for Tanzania said.</p>
<p>In an interview on Monday he said KLM saw rising potential in the country's rapidly growing horticulture industry from the northern Arusha region surrounding Mount Kilimanjaro.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a total of about 60,000 passengers a year now and we have an average of 200 shipments of general cargo a month, especially horticulture products. One should not underestimate the potential of Tanzania's horticulture industry,&quot; van Nieuwenhuyzen told Reuters.</p>
<p>KLM flies directly to Kilimanjaro International airport twice a week from Amsterdam. The carrier flies three times a week to Dar es Salaam, twice via Kilimanjaro and once a week via Nairobi in Kenya.</p>
<p>However, from April KLM will start flying Amsterdam-Nairobi six times a week, of which two flights will be connected to Dar-Es-Salaam via KLM's joint venture partner Kenya Airways, he said.</p>
<p>While Nairobi will remain KLM's hub in east Africa, Nieuwenhuyzen said the market in Tanzania was now improving and there would be room for more flights.</p>
<p>&quot;The market in Tanzania has been limited, but it's picking up because the market is regulating itself now and tourism has increased.&quot;</p>
<p>But Nieuwenhuyzen said Tanzania's air cargo industry had also been growing in recent years and the airline was now shipping some 2,000 tonnes a year.</p>
<p>&quot;Over the last couple of years we've seen a steady growth in the cargo business and cargo is now taking up 25 percent of the business. There is a huge export of flowers out of Kilimanjaro,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said KLM was shipping about 60 cubic metres of expensive flower varieties directly from Kilimanjaro to Amsterdam every week, but the majority of flowers, mostly roses, were trucked to Nairobi.</p>
<p>While the flower exporters wanted to ship a far bigger portion of their cargo via Kilimanjaro airport, Nieuwenhuyzen said that due to a limited number of imports, KLM simply could not offer more space for air cargo.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole flower export market is limited to four big exporters and these exporters are now shipping five trucks of flowers to Nairobi each week, about 400 cubic metres.</p>
<p>&quot;Now the exporters are all expanding their greenhouses to provide a year-round industry and flowers for different seasons, but if you as an airline want to have a year-round business you also need sufficient inbound cargo,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said KLM had already been looking at the possibility of a special cargo flight from Kilimanjaro, but while imports were still lacking in order to make it viable, Nieuwenhuyzen would not rule out such a cargo route as a future option.</p>
<p>&quot;Trucking to Nairobi is expensive and time consuming, and involves extra handling which should not be needed,&quot; said Nieuwenhuyzen.</p>
<p>In addition to flowers, Tanzania is also exporting increasing loads of fish from the Mwanza area at Lake Victoria, a region which is also home to the country's rapidly developing mining industry.</p>
<p>&quot;Fish is a year-round business and on every flight. 52 weeks a year, I have fish&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of export possibilities...there are both gems and precious stones. We are seeing quite a steady flow of rock samples to Canada, for instance,&quot; he said. - Reuters Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax:5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAR ES SALAAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TANZANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
