<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="429924" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Tens of thousands of refugees flood Zaire town.</title>
<headline>Tens of thousands of refugees flood Zaire town.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Tostevin</byline>
<dateline>GOMA, Zaire 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tens of thousands of refugees flooded into an eastern Zaire town and rebels said they were advancing on Monday on the northeast capital of Kisangani, despite some resistance.</p>
<p>The U.N. World Food Programme (WFP) said the sudden influx overwhelmed the four aid workers in Ubundu, 100 km (60 miles) southeast of Kisangani, Zaire's third largest city and the main rebel target.</p>
<p>&quot;Tens of thousands of refugees poured into Ubundu over the weekend and there are possibly as many as 100,000 there now,&quot; said WFP spokeswoman Michele Quintaglie, adding only hundreds were in the town on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The refugees are in very bad shape, they need food and medicine so we are trying today to kick our operation into the highest gear possible,&quot; she said. Sixty-five tonnes of food arrived in Ubundu town on Thursday by rail from Kisangani.</p>
<p>&quot;The refugees fled Tingi Tingi before it fell to the rebels and our reports indicate they are afraid, are talking about leaving Ubundu and feel threatened by the rebel advance,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Tingi Tingi camp was abandoned by its 170,000 Rwandan and Burundian refugees 10 days ago before it fell to Laurent Kabila's Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo -Zaire (ADFL) rebel group.</p>
<p>Quintaglie said the WFP planned to send more staff and four tonnes of high protein biscuits into Ubundu. Its first airlift of food to the town was due on Monday but the plane was fogged in at Kisangani airport.</p>
<p>The Hutus, mostly refugees who fled Rwanda three years ago, live in fear of reprisals for the genocide of up to 800,000 Tutsis and moderate Hutus in Rwanda in 1994. They were forced ever deeper into Zaire by rebel advances since October.</p>
<p>When they left Tingi Tingi camp, the refugees included Hutu former Rwandan soldiers and extremist militiamen, who had a leading role in the genocide and have fought alongside Zairean troops.</p>
<p>A U.N. refugee agency spokesman said any mass return of the refugees to Rwanda and Burundi depended on a ceasefire, which on Saturday was ruled out by rebel leader Kabila who wants ailing President Mobutu Sese Seko first to open talks with him.</p>
<p>&quot;Militarily, the town (Kisangani) is completely surrounded. We are progressing from three axis despite some resistance,&quot; said Raphael Ngenda, ADFL information commissioner, on Monday</p>
<p>&quot;The alliance is already inside Kisangani because the people there support us totally,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>A regional military source told Reuters rebels were consolidating positions around Kisangani before an assault.</p>
<p>But a defence ministry spokesman in Kinshasa denied on Monday that Kisangani, on the Zaire river, had been surrounded.</p>
<p>&quot;If they have surrounded Kisangani, where exactly are they?&quot; he said. &quot;To the north and northeast they are around 100 km (60 miles) away. They may be within 50 km (30 miles) to the southeast.&quot;</p>
<p>The radio of the ADFL broadcasting from eastern Zaire said the government was deserting Kisangani, which was the base for its army's failed counter-offensive against the rebels.</p>
<p>No independent account of the situation around Kisangani was available but travellers from the area said there was no sign of rebels. The last fighting was reported on Wednesday about 40 km (25 miles) to the north.</p>
<p>Several sources in the city had said the surrounding bush was heavily mined and the three main approach roads were manned by government troops and mainly Serb mercenaries hired by Mobutu.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GOMA, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
