<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="430105" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - March 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - March 10.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the reports carried by Estonia's newspapers on Monday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- An Estonian fishing ship sank near the island of Osmussaar late on Thursday, one member of the three-man crew is still missing.</p>
<p>- Tallinn municipality will refer to the police 72 allegedly improper privatisation cases of central city apartments.</p>
<p>SONUMILEHT</p>
<p>- The opposition estimates that the new cabinet will last until autumn at least but it will mainly depend on the cabinet's own performance.</p>
<p>- British Defence Minister Michael Portillo expressed support to Estonia during a meeting with Estonian counterpart Andrus Oovel. Portillo is to visit Estonia in the near future.</p>
<p>- Estonia has appointed charges a d'affaires to Dublin and Athens. Another will soon be appointed to Beijing.</p>
<p>EESTI PAEVALEHT</p>
<p>- Prime minister designate Mart Siimann will probably change the agriculture and regional affairs ministers. New candidates have not yet been announced.</p>
<p>POSTIMEES</p>
<p>- An anonymous citizen returned to the National Art Museum two water-colours from among 141 stolen from the museum during 1995.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
