<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="430181" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil's appetite for chocolate eggs still growing.</title>
<headline>Brazil's appetite for chocolate eggs still growing.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Bulloch</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilians are expected to munch their way through 14,000 tonnes of Easter eggs and chocolate bunnies this year, eight percent up on last year's 13,000 tonnes, industry officials said.</p>
<p>The increase is continued confirmation an anti-inflationary plan which began in July 1994 is helping to fuel the country's sweet tooth, with overall chocolate production reaching 296,300 tonnes in 1996, up from just under 294,000 tonnes in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;The facts show how the 'real' plan has affected consumption of Brazilian chocolate,&quot; said Getulio Ursulino, president of Brazilian Chocolate, Cocoa, Sweets and Derivatives Association.</p>
<p>&quot;Five years ago, production was 213,000 tonnes, last year it was over 296,000 tonnes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Brazilians are not only scoffing down locally-made goodies but also imported products such as Ferrero Rocher and Kinder eggs, bringing total chocolate consumption to 312,700 tonnes in 1996, Ursulino said.</p>
<p>This year's 14,000 tonnes of Easter novelties will put Brazil in second place behind the U.K. in the world league of Easter egg consumers.</p>
<p>Companies such as Brazil's arm of Swiss food giant Nestle SA and Lacta, a Philip Morris Cos Inc company in Brazil, are both prepared to do battle in the Easter egg war.</p>
<p>Market leader Lacta, which last year held 28 percent of the Easter market according to the Nielsen market research organisation, is to make around 50 million Easter novelties, up 25 percent from 1996.</p>
<p>The company has employed 2,700 temporary workers, 1,200 of which are to help in production and more than 1,500 to work on the sales side.</p>
<p>Nestle is to produce 12 million eggs against eight million in 1996 and is hoping to see its market share rise to 25 percent from 19 percent in 1996, said Felipe Buckup, Nestle's chocolate group manager in Brazil.</p>
<p>&quot;The &quot;real&quot; plan is really helping a lot as many people now have access to chocolate who didn't have before,&quot; Buckup said.</p>
<p>The company is even exporting 100,000 eggs to Argentina for the first time.</p>
<p>&quot;We are giving priority however to the internal Brazilian market,&quot; Buckup said.</p>
<p>As well as increasing production, both companies are widening their ranges with different types of chocolate.</p>
<p>Following the success of imported Kinder eggs which have small toys inside the chocolate shell, Lacta is also launching the Lego egg which contains a Lego toy while Nestle is hatching the Magic egg with a finger puppet based on Disney characters.</p>
<p>Department stores and supermarkets are virtually turned into Easter egg grottoes in the month before the holiday as makeshift frames on shop ceilings are laden with eggs.</p>
<p>Demand has been so great in recent years that many late-comers have had to be content either with buying broken eggs or accepting the inflated prices of the &quot;Easter egg touts&quot; who buy up huge quantities of eggs and then resell at a profit when supplies dry up.</p>
<p>-- Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 5074151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
