<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43027" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: InnerDyne backs street estimates.</title>
<headline>InnerDyne backs street estimates.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>InnerDyne Inc president William Mavity said on Tuesday that the company is comfortable with street estimates of a loss of $0.05 per share for the third quarter and a loss of $0.23 per share for the year.</p>
<p>&quot;We're comfortable with that estimate of a $0.05 per share loss for the quarter and comfortable, at this point in time, with the $0.23 (year) loss,&quot; told Reuters after a Dain Bosworth healthcare conference presentation.</p>
<p>In 1995, the company posted a loss of $0.32 per share for year. For the 1995 third quarter, it lost $0.07 per share.  </p>
<p>Mavity said he expects Boston Scientific Corp to decide in the next 12 months whether or not it will use InterDyne's codings with Boston Scientific's implantable medical devices. That could represent a significant contract for InterDyne, providing it with an entry into the use of stents to treat vascular disease.</p>
<p>&quot;The ultimate decision to fully exercise the agrement is based on a milestone which I can't describe to you,&quot; he said. &quot;It involves disclosing a lot of their business strategy which they're very sensitive to.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We're making good progress on it. We would hope they'd make the decision in the next 12 months, but the agreement involves some payments along the way, so we'll see some revenues from that agreement in the third quarter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Chicago newsdesk 312 408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
