<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="430395" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwait Airways sell-off study due in August.</title>
<headline>Kuwait Airways sell-off study due in August.</headline>
<byline>Ashraf Fouad</byline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Preliminary plans for the privatisation of Kuwait Airways Corp (KAC) could be ready in August but the actual move would still require several approvals and a political decision, the state-owned company said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a committee with a time frame to complete its work in six months...The preliminary study (to privatise KAC) will be ready in August,&quot; KAC Chairman Ahmad al-Meshari told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the committee comprises officials from KAC and the Kuwait Investment Authority, the state's investment arm which is involved in a programme to shed government holdings in dozens of firms.</p>
<p>&quot;By August the final picture will be clear,&quot; said Meshari.</p>
<p>The final form of privatising the national flag carrier, whose assets were estimated at 723 million dinars ($2.39 billion) at end of 1996, then requires parliamentary and other approvals and &quot;the political decision&quot;, added Meshari.</p>
<p>&quot;What has been achieved so far is a draft law to transform KAC to become a closed shareholder company with all the shares held by the state,&quot; he said of the first stage to prepare the firm for privatisation.</p>
<p>Meshari said the joint committee was studying the final financial shape of KAC prior to privatisation, the state's stake in the privatised airline and other issues.</p>
<p>Some experts have said Kuwaiti utilities and services companies could benefit from allowing specialised foreign firms to take a stake in companies once privatised.</p>
<p>&quot;I prefer that (the privatised KAC) be owned by the Kuwaiti private sector. Then if there is transfer of technology needed then we can buy it or rent it,&quot; said Meshari when asked about his view of foreign partnership with KAC.</p>
<p>In the first half of the 1996/1997 fiscal year to December 1996, KAC had total income of 98.5 million dinars compared with expenditures of 111 million dinars. Some 9.1 million dinars of the deficit were spent on debt servicing, Meshari said.</p>
<p>KAC spends about 20 million dinars a year on financing a debt of 230 million dinars. It made a loss of 35 million dinars in the year ending June 1996 compared with 27.9 million in 1995/96.</p>
<p>According to KAC figures for the first half of 1996/97, the airline carried 1.14 million passengers which earned it 84 percent of its total income. Cargo, accounting for 14 percent of the total, brought in 11.6 million dinars.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
