<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43031" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMF to consider gold sales plan Friday.</title>
<headline>IMF to consider gold sales plan Friday.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Rich Miller, Economics Correspondent</p>
<p>The IMF board meets on Friday to discuss ways to help the world's poorest nations but it remains unclear whether it will endorse a controversial proposal to sell off some of its gold to help in the process.</p>
<p>Supporters said they expect the International Monetary Fund to back the sale of gold if that proves necessary in the future to finance IMF initiatives to help the world's poor.</p>
<p>But opponents said the most that is likely is an agreement to examine the possibility of gold sales, among other financing alternatives, in the future if that is needed.</p>
<p>IMF management, backed by the United States, Britain and most other member nations, has proposed selling around five percent of its more than 100 million ounces of gold to help finance its Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility (ESAF).</p>
<p>The proposal to buttress the ESAF, which lends money to the world's poorest nations at virtually no interest charge, dovetails with another multilateral initiative to provide debt relief to some of those same countries.</p>
<p>International monetary sources said IMF managment has assured member nations that any gold sales would be carried out in such a way as to minimize their impact on the market.</p>
<p>Under IMF rules, 85 percent of the total voting power of the agency's member countries is required before gold can be sold.</p>
<p>Germany has led the opposition to the IMF gold sales plan, arguing that such a move would set a bad precedent and that the gold should only be used in the case of financial emergencies.</p>
<p>&quot;Our position is that we will not agree to sales of gold,&quot; a German source said.</p>
<p>Italy and Switzerland also oppose gold sales. Together with Germany, they hold 12.32 percent of the votes of the IMF.</p>
<p>While that on its own is not enough to block the proposal, opponents of the plan said they expect enough other countries to abstain from voting on the scheme to deny supporters the needed 85 percent majority.</p>
<p>They see no urgency in deciding on the gold sales issue as the ESAF has enough money to continue in operation to 1999 or beyond.</p>
<p>ESAF also has enough money to finance at least one multilateral debt reduction program, probably for Uganda, without an agreement on additional funding methods, they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
