<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="430308" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan plane said skipping &quot;third place&quot; detour.</title>
<headline>Taiwan plane said skipping &quot;third place&quot; detour.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Taiwan airliner hijacked to China on Monday was returning directly to Taiwan rather than detouring through Hong Kong or another &quot;third place&quot;, a striking break with past practice, executives said.</p>
<p>&quot;The aircraft will fly out of Xiamen and Shantou, overfly the midpoint of the Taiwan strait and then fly directly into Taipei,&quot; said Lee Chung-ning, general manager of Far East Air Transport whose Boeing 757 was hijacked earlier in the day.  </p>
<p>Lee said skipping a detour through Hong Kong or Macau was suggested by China's government in the interest of convenience. &quot;It was requested by the air traffic controllers in Xiamen that the plane fly directly to Taiwan,&quot; Lee said.</p>
<p>In the 12 previous instances of mainland aircraft being hijacked to Taiwan, those aircraft were obliged by Taipei to return to China by way of the air space of a &quot;third place&quot;, always Hong Kong or Macau, so as to preserve Taiwan's decades-old ban on direct flights across the Taiwan strait.</p>
<p>Taiwan media interpreted the direct return on Monday of Far East Air Transport's Boeing 757 as a bid by the communist authorities in Beijing to establish a direct-flight precedent that would undermine the ban.</p>
<p>Since a civil war split them in 1949, Beijing has regarded Nationalist-ruled Taiwan as a renegade province that must be brought under mainland sovereignty. Taiwan has resisted by banning all official contacts with the mainland authorities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MACAO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
