<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="430451" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: No charges will be filed in prison sex tape.</title>
<headline>No charges will be filed in prison sex tape.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>No criminal charges will be filed as the result of a prison videotape showing mass murderer Richard Speck having sex with another inmate and appearing to ingest a drug, it was announced Monday.</p>
<p>Illinois Atty. Gen James Ryan said investigators had determined that the statute of limitations had expired on any prosecution in the production of the tape and that there was insufficient evidence to proceed against anyone in its subsequent distribution.</p>
<p>Speck, who stabbed eight student nurses to death in Chicago in 1966, died in prison of natural causes in 1991. The tape, aired on television, showed him disrobing in the presence of another male inmate, engaging in sexual activity and ingesting something that looked like cocaine.</p>
<p>The tape caused a public outry and resulted in an investigation into how the tape -- and the acts depicted on it -- could have been possible inside a high security prison. The investigation shed no light on whether guards or other inmates were involved in making the tape.</p>
<p>In another matter, Ryan announced that a county grand jury at Pontiac, Illinois, had indicted two former and one current prison guard for having sex with female inmates at the Dwight Correctional Centre in northern Illinois.</p>
<p>The three were charged with official misconduct.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
