<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="430450" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. calls on Albania rebels to lay down arms.</title>
<headline>U.S. calls on Albania rebels to lay down arms.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Monday welcomed a deal by Albanian President Sali Berisha with opposition politicians and called on rebels in the south of the country to lay down their arms.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns was speaking as Berisha met leaders of his own Democratic Party and the opposition to form an interim government due to oversee early general elections due by June under Sunday's accord.</p>
<p>&quot;We join our European partners in welcoming the agreement,&quot; Burns told a news briefing.</p>
<p>&quot;We now strongly urge all parties in Albania to implement this agreement, to implement the amnesty, the ceasefire and to work towards a formation of the new government.&quot;</p>
<p>Burns said violence had no place in the political process.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore, we urge the opposition forces, particularly those in the southern part of Albania, to take advantage of this agreement, to lay down their arms, and to work within the democratic process to pursue their political goals,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rebel leaders from one key town, Vlore, agreed Monday to lay down their arms after talks with Italian diplomats, but there were reports that the revolt sparked by the collapse of pyramid investment schemes was spreading to other towns.</p>
<p>Burns urged both government and opposition in the Balkan country to respect human rights, including the right to free speech.</p>
<p>He said Washington was encouraged by Berisha's apparent decision Monday to begin to lift the state of emergency in Albania and hoped that would lead to removal of censorship.</p>
<p>He also urged the Albanian army and police to observe the ceasefire and to exercise &quot;maximum restraint&quot; in dealing with the rebels.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
