<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="430460" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Death of U.S. rapper re-ignites rap criticism.</title>
<headline>Death of U.S. rapper re-ignites rap criticism.</headline>
<byline>Sue Zeidler</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The brutal murder of rap star Notorious B.I.G. sent shock waves through the music industry on Monday, with critics saying the death was another example of rap music's violent side and music executives calling it a tragedy.</p>
<p>&quot;The death of Notorious B.I.G. is a tragic reminder of the real impact of gangsta rap on our lives,&quot; said C. DeLores Tucker, chairwoman of the National Political Congress of Black Women and an outspoken opponent of gangsta rap.</p>
<p>&quot;Gangsta rap glorifies violence. Unfortunately, Notorious B.I.G. died an untimely death. We hope his death will serve as a wake-up call to everyone,&quot; said Tucker, who has urged Seagram Co Ltd shareholders to dump their shares because Seagram's Universal music division distributes music by rap label Death Row Records.</p>
<p>Notorious B.I.G., whose real name was Christopher Wallace, was leaving a party early on Sunday when multiple rounds of gunfire erupted from a passing vehicle. His death at age 24 followed the fatal shooting of fellow rap star Tupac Shakur in Las Vegas in September.</p>
<p>No arrests have been made in Shakur's death and police are having difficulty finding witnesses to Notorious B.I.G.'s slaying, apparently due to fear of retaliation.</p>
<p>Music industry executives said the death of Notorious B.I.G. underscores the message at the heart of rap music.</p>
<p>&quot;He rapped about the life he knew and he knew its hazards,&quot; said Hilary Rosen, president and chief operating officer of the Recording Industry Association of America.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not the fault of the music. The issues of poverty, education and hopelessness are the root causes of violence that we need to scrutinize,&quot; Rosen said. &quot;The music community has lost a gifted and hugely popular artist. it's tragic, it's frightening.&quot;</p>
<p>The titles of Notorious B.I.G.'s first album, &quot;Ready to Die&quot; and his upcoming album &quot;Life After Death&quot;, due out March 25 on Bertelsmann AG's Arista's/Bad Boy Entertainment joint venture label, serve as eerie reminders of the musician's violent life and tragic end.</p>
<p>Notorious B.I.G., Shakur and Marion &quot;Suge&quot; Knight, the head of Death Row records, typify the fast-lane and often dangerous life associated with gangsta-rap stardom.</p>
<p>Brooklyn native Notorious B.I.G., who was 6 foot 3 inches (190 cm) tall and weighed 380 pounds (172 kg), credited his music career for turning him around from his days as a drug dealer.</p>
<p>Knight was sentenced last month to nine years in prison for violating his probation from an assault conviction when he and Shakur fought with a reputed gang member in Las Vegas hours before Shakur's murder in September.</p>
<p>Knight, 31, was driving in the car in which Shakur was riding when he was shot from another vehicle.</p>
<p>&quot;While it's easy to generalize and demonize the lyrical extremes of rap music, we need to realize that a great deal of this music reflects very real social ills -- from violence to drugs to racism - that will not go away by censoring the music or pretending these conditions don't exist,&quot; said Michael Greene, president of the National Academy or Recording Arts and Sciences, which hosts the Grammys.</p>
<p>Music industry sources expect that sales of the album will soar following Notorious B.I.G.'s death.</p>
<p>&quot;It must be incumbent on all of us to recognize the difference between those who document these conditions and those who profit by exploiting them,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
