<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="430570" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: High Heinz EPS growth may not last - analysts.</title>
<headline>High Heinz EPS growth may not last - analysts.</headline>
<dateline>PITTSBURGH 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>H.J. Heinz Co plans to restructure in an effort to achieve double-digit earnings growth, but analysts said Monday they were skeptical that such growth could be sustained over a long period of time in an overall sluggish U.S. food industry.</p>
<p>&quot;Can they hit the numbers for perhaps the next two (fiscal) years?  No problem,&quot; said Steven Galbraith at Sanford C. Bernstein. &quot;After that I think (the businesses) can grow by eight to 10 percent.  I think 10 to 12 percent is a stretch.</p>
<p>&quot;They've done a decent job with what they have...I don't think any of the businesses will see dramatic growth.&quot;  </p>
<p>Heinz officials have said for months the company will restructure to focus on its six core businesses and achieve double-digit growth but have not disclosed details.</p>
<p>The six core segments are ketchup and condiments, tuna, weight control, pet food, infant food and food service.</p>
<p>Heinz is expected to reveal the details of its restructuring plan Friday before analysts in San Francisco. The company also is scheduled to release fiscal third quarter earnings that day.</p>
<p>Wall Street's estimate for the third quarter ended January 31 is $0.47 per share versus $0.42 last year.  </p>
<p>For the full fiscal year '97, Wall Street's estimate is $1.91 versus $1.75 in fiscal '96.</p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal, quoting unnamed sources, reported Monday that Heinz is expected to take a pretax charge of more than $500 million in its fiscal fourth quarter ended April 30 and cut its 43,000-person workforce by six percent as part of the restructuring.  The report also said the company will likely announce Friday that it will sell ancillary businesses in the coming year, including poultry and ice cream units in New Zealand, and close manufacturing facilities in North America and Europe to cut costs.  </p>
<p>A Heinz spokeswoman declined to confirm any details. &quot;We're not confirming anything at this point...we'll have more to say on Friday,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>But analysts said the report was not surprising because Heinz officials have indicated those businesses could be sold. William Johnson, Heinz's president, told Reuters in January the company was looking at selling ancillary units, including poultry and ice cream.  Analysts also said Heinz's restructuring falls in line with its competitors', who also are selling businesses and cutting costs to stay competitive in an industry growing by just one percent annually.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it's a big surprise.  They're looking at businesses that account for five percent of sales. If you look at the food industry, they all want to grow 10 to 12 percent a year,&quot; said William Leach at Donaldson Lufkin &amp; Jenrette.</p>
<p>&quot;But the industry is growing at one percent a year...I think Heinz can achieve double-digit growth in the short term but not in the longer term.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said food producers have been unable to effectively raise prices the past several years, which will make it difficult for them to achieve double-digit growth.  </p>
<p>Morever, Galbraith said Heinz could be encumbered by focusing on six core businesses, rather than one or two like many of its competitors.  &quot;If you look at other companies, they're focusing on one or two...whereas Heinz has six,&quot; he said.  &quot;That can be good so you don't get blown away in one area, but it can make it more difficult to get a good growth rate.&quot;</p>
<p>Heinz shares were up 3/8 to 44-1/8 in afternoon trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>((Kerri Selland))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PITTSBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
