<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="430726" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: &quot;High noon&quot; approaches for French summertime plan.</title>
<headline>&quot;High noon&quot; approaches for French summertime plan.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>France looks likely to face defeat on Tuesday in its efforts to persuade the European Transport Council to back its plan to scrap the twice-yearly adjustment of clocks.</p>
<p>Diplomats on all sides said on Monday the French faced total isolation 14-1, in a dossier subject to qualified majority voting, for their stance on the proposed eighth summertime directive, albeit with a &quot;sympathetic ear&quot; lent by the British delegation.</p>
<p>Before ministers tackle the summertime question, EU officials said they were due to reach political agreement on a proposal for a directive amending Council Directive 92/14/EEC on limits to aircraft operations.</p>
<p>The move will update the list of aircraft in the existing directive's annex and aims to allow member states operating airport systems to limit or exclude the operation of certain older, noiser types of aircraft.</p>
<p>Next up for ministers is a discussion on taxing aviation fuels, which are not currently subject to duty but which some countries want to tax. Discussions will centre on a Dutch presidency draft resolution, which it hopes will win sufficient support from transport ministers to allow it to proceed to ECOFIN ministers.</p>
<p>Officials said that transport ministers should also reach agreement of the terms of reference for future work on Community involvement with the European Organisation for the Safety of Air Navigation (Eurocontrol) and with regard to the set-up of a European civil aviation safety body.</p>
<p>Next up is a Netherlands favourite, a resolution on the development of road transport telematics. The Dutch want a political signal from the Council on common techincal specifications for an electronic fee-collection system, to allow them get on with their plans to develop a road-pricing system.</p>
<p>The Dutch then plan to coax ministers towards a political accord for a common position on a draft regulation amending Regulation 3821/85 and Directive 85/599.</p>
<p>This concerns new technical standards for truck drivers' tachographs to prevent the recorders being fiddled with and to allow the authorities to check more easily.</p>
<p>Officials said ministers in December reached an informal consensus on the year 2000 as the start date for introducing the new technology but remained divided over the date for retro-fitting existing rigs with the new technology.</p>
<p>Recent truck strikes in Spain and France mean ministers are likely to tread with care when it comes to the question of adding costs to truckers' operations although one diplomat said on Monday that the extra cost of the new kit would be small.</p>
<p>The next agenda item deals with a proposed regulation to formalise existing aid measures to encourage combined transport operations (Pilot Actions for Combined Transport or PACT).</p>
<p>The Commission Decision 93/45/EEC provided funding for the period 1992-1996 and the draft regulation would set funding for the next five years at between 18 million and 35 million Ecus.</p>
<p>Tuesday's discussion will be an orientation debate.</p>
<p>Ministers will then move onto the Commission's &quot;Eurovignette&quot; proposal. Here they face presidency questions on the maximum allowable charge and whether to include differentiation according to trucks' environmental characteristics, the possibilities of reductions in usage charges for transporters in some countries and the possibility of levying additional charges on Alpine routes, notably the Brenner pass.</p>
<p>Eurovignette talks are now informally but inextricably linked with the ongoing EU/Swiss talks on closer road and air transport links between the two sides, a file which is to come up at lunch.</p>
<p>Ahead of the talks, predictions voiced in news briefings from diplomats on various sides of the debate tended towards the &quot;nothing yet -- progress due within the next few months&quot; type.</p>
<p>Four main questions separate the sides, as the Commission will make clear in its briefing of ministers, these concern the details of a two-way safety clause in the agreement and the extent of rail capacity provided by Switzerland's planned upgrade of its combined rail services.</p>
<p>Far more controversial however, are two inter-linked issues which concern the system planned by the Swiss for charging trucks to use their roads and the EU's demand for immediate access to serve the Swiss territory itself.</p>
<p>Finally, European Transport Commissioner Neil Kinnock will present two reports on progress with transport-related research and development work and with his plans for public/private funding partnerships for funding transport projects.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
