<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="431003" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hoechst unit gets Anzemet FDA approvable letters.</title>
<headline>Hoechst unit gets Anzemet FDA approvable letters.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo. 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hoechst Marion Roussel, a unit of Hoechst AG, said it received approvable letters from the U.S. Food and Drug Administration for oral and intravenous formulations of Anzemet for prevention of nausea and vomiting in patients undergoing single or repeated courses of emetogenic cancer chemotherapy.</p>
<p>The intravenous formulation of Anzemet will also be indicated for prevention and treatment of postoperative nausea and vomiting; the oral formulation will be indicated for the prevention of the same problem, the company said.  </p>
<p>&quot;This action represents a major closing hurdle in the FDA regulatory review process for new products and essentially clears the way for final marketing approval of Anzemet,&quot; the company said, adding, &quot;Final labeling is under negotiation, and the requisite plant inspections have been completed.&quot;</p>
<p>Hoechst Marion Roussel, with global headquarters in Frankfurt, Germany, and North American headquarters in Kansas City, Mo., is a member of the Hoechst Group.</p>
<p>((--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
