<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43121" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dow ends off, renewed inflation fears hit bonds.</title>
<headline>Dow ends off, renewed inflation fears hit bonds.</headline>
<byline>Betty Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. blue chips ended slightly lower on profit-taking after a two-day rally, pressured by a bond market selloff that was triggered by a Fed governor's inflation warning.</p>
<p>&quot;The bond market is clearly on the weak side and the stock market is struggling,&quot; said Marshall Acuff of Smith Barney. He thinks recent strength was overdone prior to the profit warnings rush. &quot;I think investors will be reminded daily of the mortality of portfolios with negative preannouncements.&quot;</p>
<p>The Dow industrials fell seven to about 5727.  </p>
<p>The Dow surged 127 points over past two sessions as Friday's Augyst payrolls report allayed Wall Street's worst inflation fears.</p>
<p>Broader market measures nudged higher, with the Nasdaq Composite up one to 1149 and the S&amp;P 500 index barely stronger at about 664.</p>
<p>NYSE winners and losers were about even as volume picked up from the sluggish summer pace to about 371 million shares.</p>
<p>Technicians were encouraged by the tape action given stiff selling in bonds. The long bond lost 1/2 point, boosting its yield to 7.11 percent.  </p>
<p>Bonds headed south after Fed Gov. Janet Yellen told Reuters, &quot;We're in an inflationary danger zone. ... There's definitely a chance inflation will rise.&quot; She stressed that there were uncertainties regarding the economy and that the outlook for inflation and growth were not completely clear.</p>
<p>Her cautious comments suggested she might be willing to support a small, quarter percentage point rise in interest rates at the Fed's next policy-making meeting Sept. 24.</p>
<p>Stocks &quot;have rallied in the past two days. So far this first day of a pullback looks awfully good given what's happening to bonds,&quot; said Ralph Bloch of Raymond James.  </p>
<p>Bloch, Raymond James' chief technical analyst, did not see a steep stock selloff in the near-term. &quot;Usually, you don't have a big chop on the downside with readings like this on breadth and the leading group -- technology. Any pullback will be shallow and short-lived.&quot;</p>
<p>He was encouraged by Tuesday's NYSE volume pickup. &quot;I've been saying that if this market has any chance of getting legs, volume better pick up.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We have the Beige Book tomorrow, producer prices Thursday and consumer prices Friday. If the numbers are benign I think this market goes higher,&quot; Bloch said.  </p>
<p>The Philadelphia Stock Exchange's semiconductor index rose fractionally to 161.65 ahead of a key industry barometer. The August book-to-bill report, due later today, is expected to be between 0.86 and 0.92, up from July's 0.85. The report measures new orders for computer chips against shipments.</p>
<p>Leading chip maker Intel rose 13/16 to 84-5/16.</p>
<p>Analysts said tech stocks would get an added boost if the book-to-bill comes in on-target or unexpectedly stronger.</p>
<p>Topping the NYSE actives list was ITT Corp, which lost 14 percent or 7-7/8 points to 48-1/8. It warned quarterly results will be below forecasts because of gaming revenue shortfalls.  </p>
<p>Bear Stearns, Donaldson Lufkin &amp; Jenrette and Smith Barney downgraded their ratings on ITT.</p>
<p>Ford Motor Co lost 3/8 to 31-5/8, pulling off a 30-1/8 session low, after forecasting its second-half loss in Latin America will be roughly twice as large as its first-half loss of $130 million in the region. Brazil makes up the largest portion of Ford's Latin American operations.</p>
<p>Shares of General Motors Corp, which also has substantial Brazilian operations, lost 3/8 to 47-7/8. Chrysler Corp, which recently announced a $315 million plan for its first Brazilian assembly plant, was off 1/2 to 28-1/4.  </p>
<p>Gap Inc added 1-1/4 to 31-5/8. Goldman Sachs upgraded Gap to the firm's priority list from its recommended list.</p>
<p>International Business Machines Corp rose 1/2 to 118-1/8 after IBM said strong customer demand for its new models of mainframe computers has been so strong that it may sell out all it can make this year.</p>
<p>Praegitzer Industries Inc, a circuit board maker, tumbled 26 percent or 3-8/16 to 9-13/16 after warning first-quarter earnings would fall short of expectations. It cited product mix changes and higher-than-expected expenses related to the integration of its acquisition of Trend Circuits Inc.  </p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite rose 0.72 to 1149.43.</p>
<p>The S&amp;P 500 index rose 0.05 to 663.81.</p>
<p>(Figures official as of 1645 EDT/2045 GMT)</p>
<p>-- Wall Street desk, 212 859 1721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
