<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="431267" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Boston Market may be biggest winner in burger war.</title>
<headline>Boston Market may be biggest winner in burger war.</headline>
<byline>Isadore Barmash</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forget the much-hyped burger war between MacDonald's and Burger King. The looming threat for the Big Beef chains isn't each other -- it's the sudden rise of chicken on the fast food scene.</p>
<p>Leading the charge is Boston Chicken Corp., the Golden, Colo.-based chain of 1,000-home-style Boston Market restaurants, which is breaking out as the hot, new restaurant chain of the late 1990s.</p>
<p>In recent weeks, the company has been heavily promoting on television its latest inducement --  a full chicken for only $1 extra when the customer buys an entre starting at $12.99.</p>
<p>At that price, there is rich appeal for working people who don't have time to prepare meals. The chain has more of a home-cooked look and flavor than hamburgers and fries, more appealing to families in a hurry.</p>
<p>The low price strategy was only a test, according to Karen Rugen, the company's communications director. But the promotion has been running long enough to have an effect, and analysts cite competition from Boston Market as a factor in McDonald's recent price cuts. While the big burger chains have been experiencing no growth in store sales, Boston Market has been rising.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate that the average weekly sales during the (1996) fourth quarter increased approximately 6 percent to the $25,000-$25,500 range,&quot; said Steven Rockwell, restaurant analyst for Alex Brown &amp; Sons in Baltimore.</p>
<p>The rise in average store sales, along with rapid store openings, propelled the company to a 65 percent jump in revenues last year, to $265 million.</p>
<p>The key to Boston Market's rise has been an understanding of the home market, aided by a management team heavy with former Blockbuster Video executives, including Saad J. Nadhir, Boston Chicken's co-chairman and president; Scott Beck, co-chairman and chief executive, and Jeffry J. Shearer, vice chairman. Starting in 1992, they acquired the then Boston-based chain of 35 restaurants and touched off an expansion explosion.</p>
<p>Like Blockbuster, the group has implemented a strategy of gaining dominance in each market they enter, rather than spreading themselves too thin. Today they operate in only 60 markets but blanket all of them, allowing cheaper advertising costs and other operating efficiencies.</p>
<p>Another company ploy was to expand the menu from strictly chicken to include turkey, ham and meatloaf on the basis that people really wouldn't like to eat chicken seven days a week. To get that message across, the top team decided to change the name of all its restaurants to Boston Market from Boston Chicken.</p>
<p>With the strategy in place, the company, whose corporate name is still Boston Chicken Inc., plans to ramp up quickly, with as many as 4,000 new stores over the next five years.</p>
<p>Already, Boston Market is &quot;the dominant brand in the home-meal replacement segment,&quot;  said Alex Brown's Rockwell.</p>
<p>But there is still room to grow, the company says, as it takes up more of the traditional fast-food market. As if to indicate how far Boston Chicken might eventually climb, the company points out that it serves a growing market of &quot;quick-serve&quot; home meals -- a developing segment that can grow to &quot;as much as $25 billion to $100 billion annually.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that this brand positioning, coupled with lifestyles that leave less and less time for preparing 'real' food at home, has allowed us to dominate the fresh, convenient meals segment of the 'quick serve' restaurant category,&quot; the company said in a statement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
