<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="431375" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: BIS declines comment on Verplaetse presidency.</title>
<headline>BIS declines comment on Verplaetse presidency.</headline>
<dateline>BASLE, Switzerland 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank for International Settlements (BIS) declined to comment on a Belgian newsagency report that Alfons Verplaetse, governor of the Belgian central bank, will become its next president.</p>
<p>A Belgian news agency reported that Verplaetse would take the position in July.</p>
<p>&quot;We decline to comment on this report. The BIS board of directors has not yet met today,&quot; a BIS spokesman said.</p>
<p>The BIS board is made up of governors of the Group of 10 (G10) central banks. Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer is head of the G10 central bank governors' committee, which meets at the BIS monthly.</p>
<p>The G10 in fact is 11 countries: the U.S., Japan, Germany, Canada, Belgium, the Netherlands, Britain, France, Italy, Sweden and Switzerland.</p>
<p>Current BIS president Wim Duisenberg, president of the Dutch central bank, was due to step down at the end of June when he becomes European Monetary Institute (EMI), succeeding Alexandre Lamfalussy. EMI is the forerunner of the European Central Bank (ECB).</p>
<p>Traditionally, the presidency of the BIS is held by a central bank of one of the smaller European G10 countries.</p>
<p>Duisenberg has been president of the BIS twice, the first man to hold the position for two terms.</p>
<p>Duisenberg was initially president and chairman of BIS from 1988 to December 1990. But from 1991 to 1994 the position of BIS president was held by Bengt Dennis, governor of Sweden's Riksbank.</p>
<p>In December 1993 Duisenberg was again elected president and chairman of BIS for three years.</p>
<p>-- Peter Nielsen, Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BASLE, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
