<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="431503" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Political turmoil ups Turk banks' borrowing costs.</title>
<headline>Political turmoil ups Turk banks' borrowing costs.</headline>
<byline>Servet Yildirim</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Increased political tension and uncertainty over the fate of Islamist Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan's troubled government are pushing up the cost of foreign borrowing for Turkish banks, bankers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The cost of political turmoil in the past couple of weeks is 30 to 40 basis points,&quot; said a senior official at a state bank.</p>
<p>Political strains were exacerbated this month when Turkey's secularist military demanded the Islamist-led coalition government rein in an increase in Islamist zeal since Erbakan came to power last June.</p>
<p>Turkish bankers say foreign creditors are cautious about the recent political developments and lack of progress in key economic indicators. Inflation is running at around 80 percent and the public deficit is over 10 percent of the country's gross domestic product.</p>
<p>&quot;Japanese banks particularly are very cautious. They refuse to increase their country limits for Turkish banks and some of them are even narrowing,&quot; a senior private banker said.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is not very different in Europe and the United States,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Further developments in the government-military row were expected to become clearer on Thursday when the cabinet was likely to discuss measures against militant Islamists.</p>
<p>The coalition's junior partner said it would work to persuade the Islamist wing of the government to put the measures into force.</p>
<p>Despite increased concerns, Turkish banks are still able to raise funds through syndicated loans.</p>
<p>&quot;Some leading banks, like Akbank, Garanti, Isbank, Kocbank, Yapi Kredi and TEB, can easily find one-year loans at costs below 100 basis points over LIBOR,&quot; the private banker said.</p>
<p>Private Kocbank has mandated four Western banks to arrange a one-year $75 million loan at an all-in cost of 80 basis points (bp) over LIBOR.</p>
<p>Garanti Bankasi has launched a $150 million syndicated loan with an all-in cost of LIBOR plus 85 bp.</p>
<p>&quot;Garanti could have borrowed at a margin of 60 bp instead of 85 if the political environment had been stable,&quot; the private banker said. Garanti had secured another $150 million loan in September at an all-in cost of 70 bp over LIBOR.</p>
<p>Turkish Eximbank is planning a one-year loan worth more than $100 million, banking sources say.</p>
<p>Bankers say some foreign banks are awaiting the start of Turkey's talks with the International Monetary Fund. State Minister Ufuk Soylemez has said the talks will be held in late March or early April.</p>
<p>The government has shown no signs of seeking a stand-by accord with the IMF, but bankers said any such deal would ease Turkish banks' efforts to borrow in the international markets.</p>
<p>Standard and Poor's assigned last week the speculative-grade category of single Bpi to seven leading Turkish banks, saying the huge government budget gap and rising interest burden leave Turkish banks at the mercy of the state's monetary policies and vulnerable to potential payment problems.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
