<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="431658" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Metway says half result not indicative.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Metway says half result not indicative.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Metway Bank Ltd said on Monday a 162 percent rise in net profit for six months to December 31 was not indicative of the newly enlarged bank as the result included just one month from merger partners Suncorp and QIDC.</p>
<p>&quot;While directors were pleased with the increased profit and dividend, the could not be taken as a benchmark for the new group as they represented six months' operations for Metway and one month only for Suncorp and QIDC (Queensland Industry Development Corp),&quot; Metway said in its first half results statement.  </p>
<p>Earlier, Metway reported a 121 percent rise in operating profit for the half to A$73 million and a net profit of A$34 million. There was an pre-tax abnormal loss of A$23 million from write-off costs of a discontinued software project.</p>
<p>Metway increased its interim dividend to 18 cents from 11 cents. Earnings per share rose to 14.99 cents from 7.14 cents per share.</p>
<p>Metway Chairman John Lamble said operations in the second half would continue to be affected by competition in the housing and business loan markets, placing more pressure on net interest margins.  </p>
<p>Metway said the software project responsible for the abnormal loss was discontinued to help the move to a single banking system.</p>
<p>Metway said the general insurance activities of the Suncorp Group contributed A$23 million to operating profit before income tax and abnormals during its one month of operations within Metway.</p>
<p>&quot;A significant portion of this contribution arose from unrealised gains in the market value of investments.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The underlying results for general insurance are satisfactory and a little ahead of budget,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>Metway's banking operations, which included one month of Suncorp's and QIDC's banking activities, contributed A$49 million to pre-tax and abnormals profit, up from A$33 million in the previous comparable period.</p>
<p>Metway managing director Steve Jones said he was confident good results would be achieved in the coming year.</p>
<p>But he said it would take the group 12 months for the results of the integration of the various merger partners to be seen.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are well placed to build on this position by providing additional and more competitive services across our combined customer base,&quot; Jones said in the statement.</p>
<p>Metway Bank's shares were up four cents at A$5.70 at 2.20 p.m. (0320 GMT)</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
