<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43163" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. debt futures end down, await late-week data.</title>
<headline>U.S. debt futures end down, await late-week data.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. debt futures languished much of the session to finish lower, never recovering from a Fed official's comments reported earlier in the day.</p>
<p>Federal Reserve Governor Janet Yellen was quoted as saying the U.S. was in an inflationary danger zone and the labor market was quite tight.</p>
<p>Debt futures immediately retreated from early mild gains to trade lower for the rest of the session. December Treasury bond futures slipped to a low of 106-17/32, but closed slightly above that level. Eurodollars closed lower but midrange on late shortcovering.  </p>
<p>&quot;It was a quiet, uneventful close,&quot; a Eurodollar futures trader said. &quot;We settled in the middle of the range today so we're ready to go either way tomorrow,&quot; he said. He pegged Dec support at 93.80 and March support at 93.64.</p>
<p>Overall, traders called the mood indecisive as key inflation data nears Thursday and Friday.</p>
<p>Thursday's Producer Price Index was forecast up 0.1 percent both overall and excluding food and energy sectors. In July, the overall rate was unchanged and the core rate rose 0.1 percent. Friday's overall and core consumer prices were seen up 0.2 percent, versus 0.3-percent rises in July.  </p>
<p>In view of the Fed's September 24 policy meeting just around the corner, traders said they were eager to get the inflation data. The most recent significant news, the August jobs report on Friday, threw the market into turmoil.</p>
<p>A flurry of data released just after the Yellen comments on Tuesday had little impact on the market.</p>
<p>U.S. July wholesale inventories rose 0.1 pct, Richmond Fed manufacturing shipments index rose to 16 in Aug from -7 in July, the second-quarter current account gap widened to $38.78 billion and second-quarter non-farm productivity was revised to up 0.5 pct.  </p>
<p>Early in the session U.S. adjusted weekly chain store sales were reported off 1.7 percent, according to the BTM/Schroders survey. Another private retail sales survey later in the session, the Redbook Retail Sales Index, pegged sales up 0.1 percent for the first week in September compared with the August.</p>
<p>December T-bonds ended down 18/32 to 106-21/32, T-notes fell 8/32 to 105-24/32, muni-bonds lost 10/32 to 111-21/32, December Eurodollars ended down one basis point to 93.94, and T-bills fell one to 94.54. --Derivatives Desk 312-408-8750 E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
