<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="431638" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Ross says Solomon Is mine on track.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Ross says Solomon Is mine on track.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ross Mining NL said on Monday that it expected its Gold Ridge mine project in the Solomon Islands, which is facing a legal challenge from local villagers, to pour its first gold on schedule in 12 months.</p>
<p>Indigenous landowners in the Solomon Islands planned to begin legal action on Monday to block development of the mine, Australian law firm Slater and Gordon, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Slater and Gordon said it had been retained by landowners in the mine lease area and downstream on the Teteri River in the hopes of buying time to negotiate before their villages were relocated and the river destroyed by sediment.  </p>
<p>&quot;We still believe the project is on schedule for first gold pour in March 1998,&quot; a Ross Mining director, John Lawton, told Reuters.</p>
<p>However, Slater and Gordon said in a constitutional challenge by the landowners seeks to overturn the pending agreement between the Solomon Islands government and Ross Mining, claiming it does not provide reasonable compensation.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition, the proposed agreement requires landowners in the lease area to indemnify Ross Mining NL against any compensation claims by other landowners,&quot; Slater and Gordon said.  </p>
<p>Ross Mining had hoped to obtain the required government mining lease by March 12 to begin construction of the mine, estimated to cost A$61.6 million.</p>
<p>Lawton said the company had taken the position that it would receive the license this week, but could not rule out potential delays due to the legal actions.</p>
<p>Ross Mining in a statement to the Australian Stock Exchange, where the company is listed, said it has &quot;dealt extensively with the issues of landowners' compensation and environment conforming with Australian Best Practice&quot; standards.  </p>
<p>Gold Ridge is projected by Ross to produce about 100,000 ounces a year for at least 10 years at a cash cost averaging less than A$300 an ounce.</p>
<p>Of 180 landowners in the immediate mine area, 175 have reached an agreement with Ross over land rights, Lawton said.</p>
<p>-- James Regan Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SOLIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
