<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="431767" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korean parties agree to pass labour bill.</title>
<headline>S.Korean parties agree to pass labour bill.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's three main political parties overcame last-minute hitches on Monday and agreed to pass a new labour bill, a parliamentary official said.</p>
<p>A parliamentary session will open at 5.30 p.m. (0830 GMT) to vote on legislation to replace a controversial law that sparked nearly one month of labour strikes after it was rammed through parliament last December 26.  </p>
<p>The ruling New Korea Party and the opposition National Congress for New Politics and United Liberal Democratic Party cobbled together a compromise on the bill on Saturday.</p>
<p>But at the last moment, opposition groups insisted they would only support the law if the ruling camp also agreed to revise another controversial bill restoring powers to the domestic intelligence agency. The New Korea Party agreed to the opposition demand, the parliamentary official said.</p>
<p>The bill on the Agency for National Security Planning was railroaded through the National Assembly along with the labour law in a dawn session while opposition deputies slept.</p>
<p>There was also squabbling over an opposition demand for live television coverage of planned parliamentary hearings into a loans scandal that has rocked the nation and tarnished President Kim Young-sam's image.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
