<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="431734" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta share prices close up but off highs.</title>
<headline>Jakarta share prices close up but off highs.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta share prices ended higher but off highs on Monday on bargain-hunting in some blue-chips combined with active buying of banking stocks, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Jakarta Composite Index closed 4.24 points, or 0.62 percent, higher at 688.05 points after touching an intra-day high of 688.73 points. Gainers led losers by 74 to 44, with 66 counters unchanged.</p>
<p>Blue-chips such as telecommunications firm Telkom cigarette maker Sampoerna and noodle maker Indofood were among the target of bargain-hunters.  </p>
<p>Brokers said the market was expected to be firmer on Tuesday as buying interest in firstliners was seen likely to continue.</p>
<p>&quot;Some blue-chips are still at bargain levels. It will attract further buying on Tuesday, I believe,&quot; a broker with a foreign firm said.</p>
<p>Shares of banking stocks were active during the day with Bank PDFCI leading rises in the sector, brokers said.</p>
<p>Bank PDFCI was the most active stock with about 9.2 million shares changing hands, rising 400 rupiah to 3,200 rupiah following a report that Bank Indonesia plans to sell its stake in several banks including PDFCI.  </p>
<p>Bank Papan Sejahtera and Bank Ficorinvest were active on the same report, brokers said.</p>
<p>Buying interest in other banks such as Bank Negara Indonesia, Bank International Indonesia and Bank Lippo were high on perceptions that their prices were cheap, brokers said.</p>
<p>In contrast to other blue chips, sentiment on cigarette maker Gudang Garam and cement maker Semen Gresik was weak, brokers said.  </p>
<p>Gudang Garam closed 325 rupiah lower at 10,325 on a volume of 591,000 shares after a report in the Media Indonesia newspaper that a company official had alledgely stolen 24 billion rupiah.</p>
<p>Semen Gresik fell 75 rupiah to 6,350 rupiah on 689,500 shares. An analyst with a Hong Kong-based brokerage said it was due to recent reports the company had changed its depreciation policy and officials said it might affect 1996 results.</p>
<p>&quot;It sparked selling in Semen Gresik in anticipation of its 1996 net results. Some investors switched their portfolios to other cement stocks,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
