<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="431888" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: U.S. repatriates suspected MIA remains from Cambodia.</title>
<headline>U.S. repatriates suspected MIA remains from Cambodia.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. military on Monday repatriated the remains of what investigators suspect was an American pilot who went missing over eastern Cambodia more than a quarter of a century ago.</p>
<p>The remains, believed to be those of a pilot who went missing in a single-seater OV10 aircraft in 1971 during the Vietnam War, will be taken to the United States for forensic tests.</p>
<p>They were carried in a flag-draped metal casket onto a C-130 transport plane by members of four different wings of the U.S. armed forces at Phnom Penh's Pochentong Airport.</p>
<p>Major Barbara Claypool, public affairs officer at the Hawaii-based Joint Task Force-Full Accounting (JTF-AF), said the remains were found in the eastern province of Kratie during a joint Cambodia-U.S. search between February 6 and March 6.</p>
<p>She gave no more details but U.S. Charge d'Affaires Bob Porter said in a short address that search teams had been led to the spot by a local woman.</p>
<p>Claypool said identification could take as little as six months or much longer, depending on the condition of the remains.</p>
<p>Claypool said the Pentagon still listed 2,128 U.S. citizens as missing in action (MIA) in Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos and China from the Indochina War, which ended in 1975. She said 76 people were listed as MIA from Cambodia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
