<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="431937" id="root" date="1997-03-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan plans eventual 20 pct car tariff in WTO bid.</title>
<headline>Taiwan plans eventual 20 pct car tariff in WTO bid.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-03-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's economics ministry said on Monday it would lower import tariffs for passenger cars to 20 percent or less from 30 percent within nine years after entry into the World Trade Organisation.</p>
<p>&quot;In recent negotiations with various WTO member countries, we have agreed to gradually lower our passenger car tariffs to 20 percent nine years after our WTO entry from the current 30 percent,&quot; Paul Chung, a director of the ministry's Industrial Development Bureau, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Taiwan hopes to enter the WTO in 1997 but faces an external obstacle as rival China has said it must gain membership first.  </p>
<p>Chung said the 20 percent bottom line was a concession from an offer to lower passenger car tariffs to 25 percent five years after WTO entry but that Taiwan's trading partners want more.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite this our counterparts still are not satisfied,&quot; Chung said. &quot;They want a further cut to 15 percent. We will have to negotiate further about that.&quot;</p>
<p>In February, Taiwan lifted a decades-old ban on car imports from Japan to conform with WTO's non-discriminatory principles, saying it would allow imports of 7,700 Japanese cars in 1997.</p>
<p>Taiwan would raise the annual quota for Japan to 10,000 cars after its entry into the WTO, officials said at the time.</p>
<p>Cars are among one of Taiwan's most restricted industries, with the government maintaining high import tariffs to protect the island's 11 domestic carmakers.</p>
<p>In late 1996, Taiwan agreed to allow the import of 7,000 South Korean cars in 1997, a total that also would rise after Taiwan enters the WTO.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
