<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="432264" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Jostens to take $3.0 million Q1 charge.</title>
<headline>Jostens to take $3.0 million Q1 charge.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jostens Inc said Tuesday it expects to take a one-time charge of about $3.0 million in the first quarter to cover costs associated with a plant consolidation.</p>
<p>Jostens said it will combine its two graduation announcement production facilities as part of its overall business strategy to create greater operating efficiencies.</p>
<p>The company will close its Porterville, Calif., facility and consolidate its operations into one existing plant in Shelbyville, Tenn.  </p>
<p>About 35 percent of Porterville's workload has already been transferred successfully to Shelbyville.  The consolidation is scheduled to be complete by September.</p>
<p>Jostens said the consolidation will enable it to improve plant productivity and reduce overhead costs.</p>
<p>Approximately 200 new positions will be created in Shelbyville, about equal with the number eliminated in Porterville.</p>
<p>Severance and outplacement services will be offered to eligible employees affected by the plant closing, Jostens said. Porterville employees also will have the opportunity to apply for positions at the Shelbyville plant or other Jostens facilities.</p>
<p>Jostens products and services include yearbooks, class rings, graduation products, school photography and business service and achievement awards.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I49100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
