<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="432319" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Midwest industry limited by capacity - Chicago Fed.</title>
<headline>Midwest industry limited by capacity - Chicago Fed.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Economic growth in the U.S. Midwest has slowed somewhat over the past month, due in part to limited manufacturing capacity, according to an official at the Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago.</p>
<p>The Chicago Fed Midwest Manufacturing Index (CFMMI) declined to 124.3 in January from 124.4 in December.  </p>
<p>The bank attributed much of the modest decline in the index to a temporary pause in steel-related activity.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem is that the steel plants have been operating at very high capacity levels and you are going to get outages ... when plants are operating at such high levels,&quot; said Chicago Fed senior economist William Strauss in an interview with Reuters Financial Television on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Capacity limitations have helped temper manufacturing activity recently, keeping the Midwest from &quot;growing out of control,&quot; said Strauss.</p>
<p>The resource sector, which includes food processing, chemicals and pretoleum sectors, has experienced the greatest growth over the past year, he said.</p>
<p>However, Strauss said an increase in petroleum production could actually &quot;lower oil prices because of the gains that have been added by the different petroleum producers in the Midwest.&quot;</p>
<p>Strauss noted that the unemployment rate in the Midwest has signaled some concern.&quot;Here in the Midwest ... our unemployment rates our substantially below the national average,&quot; he said. &quot;We have been very, very concerned about that translating into wage pressures,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1660 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
