<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="432478" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: CRICKET-TAYLOR GIVEN 80 PERCENT CHANCE OF PLAYING IN TEST.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-TAYLOR GIVEN 80 PERCENT CHANCE OF PLAYING IN TEST.</headline>
<dateline>ZWIDE, South Africa 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia captain Mark Taylor has an 80 percent chance of playing in the second test match against South Africa starting on Friday, team physiotherapist Erroll Alcott said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Taylor has been suffering from a back injury since Friday morning when he was forced to pull out of his team's three-day match against Border in East London.</p>
<p>A series of back problems resulted in an operation last year that kept him out of the game for two months but the current problem does not appear to be related to the last injury.</p>
<p>&quot;He has full mobility in the back but it's not quite right,&quot; Alcott told reporters before the Australians' one-day game against an Eastern Province Invitation XI here on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Mark wanted to play today but I didn't recommend it. There is obviously still a problem but I would say he has an 80 percent chance of being fit and playing in the test. He will have a light net session tomorrow (Wednesday) and then a heavier workout on Thursday.&quot;</p>
<p>Taylor said he would rule himself out of contention if he were not fully fit by Thursday. &quot;I won't leave it until the morning of the match. That wouldn't be right,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Australia won the first test against South Africa by an innings and 196 runs in Johannesburg last week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZWIDE, South Africa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
