<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="432546" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: RADIO ROMANIA AFTERNOON HEADLINES AT 2 PM.</title>
<headline>RADIO ROMANIA AFTERNOON HEADLINES AT 2 PM.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Radio Romania news:</p>
<p>* President Emil Constantinescu met the Czech foreign and defence ministers during his two-day official visit to Prague.</p>
<p>* Constantinescu hailed Radio Free Europe's (RFE) contribution to the fall of communism during a news conference at the RFE headquarters in Prague.</p>
<p>RFE should continue to exist to allow a better knowledge of the problems the Central and East European countries face in their transition towards a market economy, Constantinescu said.</p>
<p>* Constantinescu praised the Romanian people for its confidence in the country's president and prime minister despite painful costs of reforms.</p>
<p>* The cabinet holds an extraordinary meeting to discuss the 1997 state budget law which is expected to be handed to parliament next Monday.</p>
<p>* The private advertising company Creative Media caused losses worth $6.0 million to the state television, said Valerian Stan, head of the government's control body.</p>
<p>* The lower Chamber of Deputies passed the government's ordinance to allow prices to be adjusted regularly, according to the local leu exchange rate to the dollar.</p>
<p>* Five workers died on Tuesday at the Calafat thermal power plant when a crane broke and collapsed from 30 metre high.</p>
<p>* Transport Minister Traian Baseascu awarded Romanian athlete Gabriela Szabo a 10 million lei prize for winning the world title for the 3,000 metres run.</p>
<p>* Basescu sacked Radu Farmus, head of the Bucharest metro utility, for illegaly increasing the employees' wages by 30 percent.</p>
<p>($= 7,744 lei) -- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
