<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="432575" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: FULL TEXT - GENERALE BANK 1996 EARNINGS STATEMENT.</title>
<headline>FULL TEXT - GENERALE BANK 1996 EARNINGS STATEMENT.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following is the full text of a statement from Generale Bank about 1996 earnings.</p>
<p>Generale Bank Group Net profit up by 10.4%</p>
<p>steady growth in net profit maintained</p>
<p>new acquisitions consolidated</p>
<p>successful capital increase</p>
<p>new organisational structure</p>
<p>The Generale Bank group's consolidated net profit for 1996 was BFr 15.098 billion, an increase of BFr 1.428 billion, or 10.4%, on 1995.</p>
<p>In view of the increased profit, the Board of Directors will submit a proposal to the Annual General Meeting of 24 April 1997 to approve a dividend payment of BFr 526.67 per share compared to BFr 513.33 in 1995. This means a consolidated pay-out ratio of 58% compared to 56.9% last year.</p>
<p>The net dividend is increased from BFr 385 in 1995 to BFr 395 in 1996; for shares with a VVPR strip, the dividend is increased from BFr 436.33 to BFr 447.67.</p>
<p>Changes to companies consolidated</p>
<p>The consolidated income statement for 1996 includes Generale Bank Nederland (GBN) and Fimagest for the first time. GBN was already consolidated in the balance sheet in 1995. GMIC is no longer included in the list of consolidated companies. Generale Bank acquired a 34% stake in Meeschaert-Rouselle, a French broking house, in October 1996. This company has been equity accounted.</p>
<p>Consolidated income statement</p>
<p>Gross income, ie overall receipts, was us 16.5% to BFr 132 billion. Interest income increased by 15.6% and non- interest income by 18%. The interest margin in Belgian francs fell slightly in 1996 due to the reduction in interest rates and fierce competition. In contrast, loans to individuals and the volume of savings and current accounts increased sharply. The increase in non-interest income was mainly due to the rise (more than 30%) in commission received - including income on trading and insurance activities and reinvestment penalties - and the increase in capital gains realised on the portfolio. If there had not been any changes to the companies consolidated, gross income would have increased by 7.8% - interest income by 5.1% and non-interest income by 4.3%.</p>
<p>At BFr 79 billion, general expenses were up by 15.9%. This item includes staff costs and other operating expenses, which rose by 15.1% and 17.8% respectively. This increase was largely due to the consolidation of GBN and Fimagest. Assuming no changes to the companies consolidated, staff costs were up by 5.1% and other operating expenses by 4.3%.</p>
<p>The group's cost income ratio improved slightly to 59.8%, compared to 60.1% in 1995.</p>
<p>Gross profit - gross income less general expenses - rose 17.3% to BFr 53 billion. Disregarding changes to the companies consolidated, gross profit was up 12.1%.</p>
<p>At BFr 22 billion, depreciation, write-downs and provisions increase by 9.3%. This was due to the following factors:</p>
<p>- a provision of some BFr 2 billion for further modernisation of branch work stations and the introduction of the Euro</p>
<p>- no change in the level of provisions for credit risks</p>
<p>- a substantial amount transferred to general unallocated reserves</p>
<p>- a write-back on provisions for early retirement</p>
<p>this write-back was offset by an allocation to &quot;extraordinary charges&quot; to cover the costs of staff leaving before retirement age.</p>
<p>Generale Bank maintained its prudent loan policy. Virtually all capital gains realised during the year were used for the provisions referred to above.</p>
<p>Tax paid increased by 30% to BFr 10.5 billion.</p>
<p>After tax and deduction of minority interests, the group's net profit stood at BFr 15.1 billion, up 10.4% on the previous year.</p>
<p>After the capital increase ROE was 12.8%. This was the fifth year in a row that the group achieved its strategic target of ROE of at least 12.5%. Taking account of the time at which the capital increase occurred (October 1996) rather than the period for which holders of new shares were entitled to a dividend (twelve months), net earning per share were BFr 982 and ROE 13.24%.</p>
<p>Consolidated balance sheet</p>
<p>Total assets increased by 17% to BFr 5,544 billion.</p>
<p>Lending to the private sector increased to BFr 2,060 billion, a rise of almost 17%. The volume of short-term credit facilities to individual and corporate customers and home loans increased, both in Belgium and abroad.</p>
<p>The amount due from banks increased by almost 20% and stands at Bfr 1,975 billion.</p>
<p>Lending to the public sector increased by 14.2% to BFr 1,171 billion.</p>
<p>At more than BFr 2,900 billion, customer deposits and bank savings certificates were up by 7.5%. Savings and current accounts were as popular as ever, due to the low interest rates. There was a further sharp increase in amounts invested in collective investment undertakings managed by the Generale Bank group. At BFr 981 billion as at the end of December, the amounts invested were 17% higher than at the end of 1995.</p>
<p>Own funds after appropriation stood at BFr 129 billion; this was an increase of 20.2%. As a result of the capital increase in October 1996, own funds increased by BFr 15.4 billion. If we include subordinated loans and perpetuals, broadly defined own funds were BFr 256 billion, an increase of almost 10%.</p>
<p>Calculated in accordance with the provisions of the new Capital Adequacy Directive, the Generale Bank group posted a good risk-weighted RAR of 10.66% - the required minimum is 8%.</p>
<p>New organisational structure</p>
<p>In order to make the most of the recent acquisitions and the introduction of the Euro, the Generale Bank group has restructured its internal organisation. The new organisational structure is based on the principle that integration will apply where this offers added value, but that the entities will retain sufficient autonomy to react to our customers' specific regional or national requirements. The restructuring also includes changes in responsibilities within the Executive Committee. Each of the six members is responsible for specific functions, business lines and territories.</p>
<p>General economic situation in 1996.</p>
<p>In 1996 both long and short rates in Belgium were at their lowest levels since the sixties. Since the long rate is still slightly higher than the German long rate, the BFr yield curve was steeper than the DM curve - it was in fact steeper than it has been since 1965. This resulted in an improvement in the interest margin, especially in the first quarter. The fall in the long rate early in the year made it possible to realise capital gains on the bond portfolio.</p>
<p>After zigzagging somewhat during the second and third quarters, the long rate continued on its downward trend as from September. This squeezed the interest margin slightly.</p>
<p>Despite cuts in government spending, interest rate trends had a favourable impact on corporate investment and consumer spending, which resulted in a significant increase in loans to individuals. In spite of the gradual recovery in economic activity, the number of bankruptcies reached record levels.</p>
<p>Uncertainty about future interest rate trends prompted many savers to &quot;wait and see&quot;, which resulted in a sharp increase in short-term deposits.</p>
<p>The economic situation in the countries neighbouring on Belgium was very similar to the national picture. Interest rates continued to fall and there was a recovery in economic growth in all the countries concerned, albeit very hesitant due to government cutbacks and the prospect of the single currency. Holland and the UK posted the highest growth figures.</p>
<p>In South-east Asia the economy started to falter, but the basic growth prospects remain good.</p>
<p>END</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
