<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="432640" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK govt ups protection for Lloyd's policyholders.</title>
<headline>UK govt ups protection for Lloyd's policyholders.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The British government said on Tuesday it will strengthen protection for policyholders of Lloyd's of London insurance market.</p>
<p>Trade Minister Anthony Nelson said he has introduced a test which requires Lloyd's members to show they can cover an additional margin of solvency over and above that already required.</p>
<p>If any members, or Names, are unable to demonstrate such net assets, Lloyd's will be required to show that it has assets, mainly in the Central Fund, to cover the total of individuals' shortfalls. Failure to do so will trigger the government's intervention powers.</p>
<p>&quot;The additional test reflects better the fact that members of Lloyd's are not responsible for each other's losses, while recognising that Lloyd's does have centrally held assets that can be used to cover any shortfalls,&quot; Nelson said.</p>
<p>The new requirement will take effect from the end of the year.</p>
<p>To date, Lloyd's has to prove it has assets that can cover the liabilites of each member of the insurance market. It must also maintain sufficient assets to cover all liabilities and a minimum margin of solvency.</p>
<p>The extra margin that will be required will be calculated on the basis of a set level of each member's net assets over and above that required to cover their liabilities.</p>
<p>&quot;It will provide policyholders with an additional degree of protection against adverse developments and will also encourage a prompt response should financial difficulties ever begin to develop at Lloyd's in the future,&quot; Nelson said.</p>
<p>-- Mike Peacock, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
