<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="432768" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKMENISTAN: Turkmens aim new energy law at foreign investors.</title>
<headline>Turkmens aim new energy law at foreign investors.</headline>
<dateline>ASHGABAT 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkmenistan has streamlined its licensing system for companies wishing to develop the former Soviet republic's oil and gas riches with a new law designed to attract foreign investment, an energy official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The new law will allow us to get rid of procedures which delayed agreements and which scared off many foreign investors in the past,&quot; Gochmurad Nazdzhanov, Turkmenistan's minister for oil, gas and mineral resources, told reporters in the capital Ashgabat.</p>
<p>The new law states that licences for hydrocarbons will be issued by the desert nation's cabinet of ministers, either in the form of a competitive tender or through direct negotiations, Nazdzhanov said.</p>
<p>Licences to prospect for hydrocarbons will be issued for up to six years, with an option to renew for a further four years. Production licences will be issued for up to 20 years, with the possibility to extend the licence by a further five years.</p>
<p>-- Almaty Newsroom +7 3272 509410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURKM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ASHGABAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKMENISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
