<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="432920" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - March 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - March 11.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Belgrade press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>NASA BORBA</p>
<p>- Serbian government presents working version of new draft law on media. Financial and other assistance from abroad will have to be denoted on all copies of newspapers and magazines and announced in all radio and TV programmes.</p>
<p>- Zajedno (Together) coalition leader Zoran Djindjic leading ahead of Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic, according to opinion poll conducted by Mark-plan agency.</p>
<p>- Belgrade University protest committee decides to continue street protests until rector Dragutin Velickovic's resignation is accepted by the university council.</p>
<p>- Is a conflict brewing in the Serbian government over privatisation? Two &quot;official versions&quot; of new law on privatisation.</p>
<p>- Serbia's oil company Naftna Industrija Srbije debt of around $180 million for gas to Russia's Gazprom to be transformed into shares in future 650-kilometer gas pipeline to Serbia to be built over the next four years.</p>
<p>- &quot;There is enough wheat until the next harvest. Certain quantities wil be imported until April to reduce the price of wheat and flour on the domestic market,&quot; says Serbian deputy prime minister Nedeljko Sipovac.</p>
<p>POLITIKA</p>
<p>- Spring agriculture works in Serbia begin with sugar beet planting, preparations under way for maize, sunflower and soyabean sowing.</p>
<p>- New Serbian law on privatisation can be expected by late spring. Shaky firms should be privatised under special programmes, each public enterprise a separate case.</p>
<p>- Large investments impossible with low prices, energy experts agree at symposium on the development of energy in Yugoslavia. Yugoslav energy sector will have to secure $20 billion by itself over the next 25 years.</p>
<p>- Yugoslav truck manufacturer Fabrika Automobila Priboj plans to export 19 million German marks worth of products in 1997 to partly cover costs of imports.</p>
<p>- Yugoslav roads full of second-hand cars from Europe, with license plates from Bosnia or Eastern Slavonia in Croatia, and drivers from Serbia. -- Belgrade newsroom +381 11 2224305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
