<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="433080" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: New poll has left-winger leading Mexico City race.</title>
<headline>New poll has left-winger leading Mexico City race.</headline>
<byline>Michael Stott</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A left-wing veteran would win an easy victory as Mexico City's first elected mayor in a big upset for President Ernesto Zedillo's party if the election were held now, a new opinion poll showed.</p>
<p>The poll by the Indemerc/Louis Harris organisation, which has a good track record on predicting Mexican elections, showed aging radical Cuauhtemoc Cardenas nine percentage points clear of his nearest rival for the top Mexico City job.  </p>
<p>Voters in this huge, polluted metropolis will choose their first-ever elected mayor July 6 in Mexico's most closely watched political contest this year.</p>
<p>Hitherto, the city has been run by a presidential nominee plucked from the ranks of the Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI), which has ruled Mexico for the last 68 years.</p>
<p>The right-wing National Action Party (PAN) had been leading polls to win the capital -- until it chose Carlos Castillo Peraza, a dry academic and former party leader, as its candidate.  </p>
<p>Voters had hoped that Diego Fernandez de Cevallos, a fiery lawyer who has won huge popularity with attacks on the PRI, would run for the PAN. Polls showed Fernandez would win easily, but he refused to stand for reasons he has not fully explained.</p>
<p>&quot;We knew Diego Fernandez weighed very heavily in PAN voters' minds,&quot; Indemerc/Louis Harris said in a commentary. &quot;This is confirmed since Carlos Castillo could not keep up the PAN's strength and it fell in a dramatic fashion&quot;.  </p>
<p>In the firm's last survey a month ago before candidates were selected, the PAN led Cardenas's Party of the Democratic Revolution (PRD) by 12 percentage points, with the PRI trailing hopelessly behind.</p>
<p>But after the parties chose their candidates, the positions were reversed. This month's poll, taken between March 8 and 10, showed Cardenas leading with 30 percent against 21 percent for Castillo and 19 percent for the PRI's Alfredo del Mazo.</p>
<p>Indemerc/Louis Harris said that 24 percent of those polled were undecided or did not reply.  </p>
<p>But using their own patented method to predict how those voters would behave on polling day, the group said the PRD's share of the vote would increase to 40 percent, compared to 28.9 percent for the PAN and 22.85 percent for the PRI.</p>
<p>Cardenas, a 62-year-old radical who twice failed to win the presidency, enjoys widespread sympathy among many Mexicans. They remember the hugely popular 1934-40 administration of his father, President Lazaro Cardenas, and also believe electoral fraud cheated Cuauhtemoc of a presidential win in 1988.</p>
<p>Despite electoral reforms championed by Zedillo, voters remain suspicious that the mayor's election will not be clean. Fifty-one percent of the 800 people surveyed predicted &quot;total fraud&quot; or a &quot;high level of fraud&quot;.</p>
<p>The poll had a margin of error of 3.5 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
