<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="433065" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil trade deficit not troubling - ministry.</title>
<headline>Brazil trade deficit not troubling - ministry.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's $2.03 billion trade gap for the first two months of 1997 is not of concern because of strong foreign capital inflows, domestic investment growth and a large impending harvest, a senior official said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are quite calm,&quot; said Jose Roberto Mendonca de Barros, economic policy secretary at the Finance Ministry.</p>
<p>Mendonca de Barros said that at $8.862 billion, imports in January and February had risen sharply compared with the same period a year before and that exports of $6.831 billion were weak.  </p>
<p>But he noted that growth in domestic industry investment and economic recovery were fueling import growth and that exports were &quot;traditionally weak&quot; at the beginning of the year.</p>
<p>The economic policy secretary also noted that foreign direct investment (FDI) in February, a slow month because of the Carnival holiday, was a little bit over $300 million. In the first week of March, another $300 million in FDI flowed in.  </p>
<p>He said the indications were that there would be no problems financing Brazil's current account gap in 1997 through long-term capital.</p>
<p>As for future monthly trade balances, Mendonca de Barros declined to make a forecast. But he said agricultural exports, in particular of soybeans, were looking promising.</p>
<p>&quot;The agricultural prospects, starting in March, are as good as they can be,&quot; he said, pointing to the Agriculture Ministry's latest forecast of a record 81 million tonne grains and oilseeds crop for 1996/97.  </p>
<p>&quot;The increase in the crop is very high and there has also been a good improvement in international prices,&quot; Mendonca de Barros said.</p>
<p>Mendonca de Barros said domestic investment by industry, which was reflected in raw material and capital goods imports, would fuel future productivity and thus exports.</p>
<p>And he noted that some consumer goods imports in early 1997, especially of television sets, were based on orders placed as far back as last August. Brazilian distributors had expected Christmas sales to be much better than they actually were, and by now would have been replenishing their depleted stocks, he explained.</p>
<p>Mendonca de Barros stressed repeatedly that the government was keen to encourage domestic investment and to decrease the government's role as a consumer, thus freeing up savings.</p>
<p>He said the concern for boosting investment was the other side of the coin of Brasilia's fight to balance the public books.</p>
<p>&quot;This year is vital for the revival of investment, which is key, along with our fiscal efforts, to the continuation of economic stability,&quot; Mendonca de Barros said.</p>
<p>((-- Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom 55-61-2230358))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
