<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="433112" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Fate of Peruvian hostage talks thrown into doubt.</title>
<headline>Fate of Peruvian hostage talks thrown into doubt.</headline>
<byline>Roger Atwood</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Talks to end Peru's 84-day hostage crisis hung in doubt on Tuesday after the government abruptly cancelled the next round of negotiations and gave no hint as to when it might be ready to talk again.</p>
<p>Government negotiator Domingo Palermo charged Marxist rebels holding 72 hostages with trying to backtrack on commitments they had already made and called off the 10th round of talks that were set for Monday.</p>
<p>The announcement made a peaceful solution to the siege at the Japanese ambassador's home in Lima look even further away, nearly three months after the rebels blasted into the home during a cocktail party and took all the guests hostage.</p>
<p>The exact reasons for the government's move were not known, but a statement by Palermo suggested serious obstacles rather than just a snag.</p>
<p>Palermo said he saw &quot;an attempt to reverse the valuable advances achieved so far&quot; on the part of the rebels and that &quot;conditions for renewing the preliminary conversations are not yet sufficiently defined.&quot;</p>
<p>The rebels boycotted talks last week after accusing the government of pretending to negotiate in good faith while secretly planning to take the residence by storm via a secret tunnel being built underneath it.</p>
<p>Hours of talks over the weekend between a mediation committee and the rebels at the mined and booby-trapped mansion appeared to get talks back on track -- only to be dashed by Palermo's announcement.</p>
<p>In Tokyo, Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto said he was concerned by the sudden cancellation and that his bad premonitions about the progress of events in Lima had been born out.</p>
<p>&quot;I had a feeling that there would be consequences. And so there were,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At the grand, walled mansion, the hostages could be heard singing songs late on Monday while police loudspeakers played saxophone tunes by Kenny G and traditional Andean flute music.</p>
<p>The rebels of the Cuban-inspired Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA), who are demanding freedom for about 400 comrades from jail, could also be heard singing revolutionary hymns, people near the residence said.</p>
<p>With a negotiated solution apparently still a long way off, concern has been growing about the physical and mental health of the hostages.</p>
<p>Lima's Channel 15 reported on Monday night that Bolivian Ambassador Jorge Gumucio had &quot;an attack of hysteria&quot; recently and calmed down only after being shouted at by one of the rebels.</p>
<p>Three doctors have been seen walking into the residence in separate visits in the last few days, and Lima news reports said at least 21 hostages were suffering serious health problems.</p>
<p>Despite the lack of progress in talks, a poll broadcast on local television showed 57 percent of Lima residents opposed to a violent takeover by the government. The opinion poll of 403 people was by the agency Imagen.</p>
<p>&quot;The opportunity for a violent incursion has, in my opinion, already passed. That option had its strongest moment right in the beginning,&quot; police general Hector Jhon Caro, a former chief of the anti-terrorism police, said.</p>
<p>&quot;Still, it is not beyond the realm of possibility as a last option,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>The MRTA released most of their captives within a few days of the takeover but are still holding 72, including President Alberto Fujimori's brother Pedro, the Japanese ambassador and an all-star list of Japanese businessmen.</p>
<p>Fujimori, apparently trying to lower the siege's profile a bit, has made no public comment in recent days. He dodged questions about it during a trip on Monday to flood-hit villages in the mountain district of Cuzco, where he passed out blankets and flood to peasants and donned a traditional Andean poncho.</p>
<p>The MRTA was in pessimistic mood on Monday, publishing a communique from its office in Hamburg claiming the siege would not end soon because of the government's refusal to consider its main demand for the release of some of it comrades.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no glimpse of a solution to the conflict because of the government's intransigence,&quot; read a statement sent to Reuters via e-mail.</p>
<p>&quot;The MRTA has made known its decision to contribute to a political solution to this crisis, but at the same time we reaffirm the that this solution involves the freeing of our comrades,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
