<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="433236" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korean party leader kicks off presidential race.</title>
<headline>S.Korean party leader kicks off presidential race.</headline>
<byline>Moon Ihlwan</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's ruling party chairman Lee Hong-koo on Tuesday kicked off a race for the presidency by challenging other party elders to policy debates.</p>
<p>Lee, due to step down as party chairman on Thursday, told reporters he would campaign to win the party's nomination for presidential elections in December.</p>
<p>&quot;The time has come to make a choice,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I will concentrate my efforts on providing new leadership for the people and revitalising the party to win the presidential elections.</p>
<p>&quot;Selection of a new leader must be different from the method in the past. We should break away from politics of money and factional forces. It should be through active policy debates.&quot;</p>
<p>Nine party leaders are thought to be in the running to replace President Kim Young-sam after his five year term expires next February. But Lee, widely seen as a protege of Kim, is the first to make public his presidential ambitions.</p>
<p>Political analysts said Kim, barred by the constitution from seeking a second term, would try to influence the battle among the candidates from behind the scenes.</p>
<p>However Kim promised a free race for his party's presidential nominee last month when he apologised for the forced passage of a labour law and a loans scandal that badly damaged his political credibility.</p>
<p>The analysts said Lee's move would encourage other presidential aspirants to come forward.</p>
<p>Candidates have been reluctant to declare their ambition too early and make Kim a lame duck.</p>
<p>&quot;In the one-term presidential system, the lame-duck phenomenon is unavoidable in the last year of any presidency,&quot; said Moon Chung-in, political science professor at Seoul's Yonsei University.</p>
<p>Moon said Kim's political dominance had prevented party elders from expanding their power bases.</p>
<p>&quot;The most pressing task for President Kim is to make sure his ruling party wins the election,&quot; he said. &quot;An early race for the presidency will help foster a national-level leader,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lee lacks his own influence at the grass roots of the party but commands respect as an intellectual. Educated at Yale, he was a professor of politics, ambassador to Britain and prime minister before becoming party chairman.</p>
<p>Lee was tipped as the front-runner to win the ruling party's mandate until nearly a month of strikes sparked by the forced passage of a controversial labour law last December cost him his job as party chairman.</p>
<p>Led by Lee, ruling party members rammed the bill through the National Assembly in a dawn session while opposition deputies slept. Kim was forced to send it back to parliament, and on Monday a revised bill was passed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
