<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="433456" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYS Senate backs phasing out clothing sales taxes.</title>
<headline>NYS Senate backs phasing out clothing sales taxes.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Republican-led New York State Senate on Tuesday proposed phasing out clothing sales taxes as part of a huge new program to help create jobs by slashing business taxes by $2.5 billion over five years.</p>
<p>A one-week experiment from January 18 to 24, which was pushed by the Democrat-controlled Assembly, and backed by many localities, including New York City, proved popular with voters. But Gov George Pataki has said that it would be difficult to start phasing out the state's four percent sales tax in fiscal 1998.</p>
<p>New York City Mayor Rudolph Giuliani has been seeking Albany's permission to eliminate the city's four percent sales tax, as he argues that that the present high rates make the city retailers less competitive than those in neighboring states that either have no or lower sales taxes.</p>
<p>As part of his plan, the Senate Majority Leader, Joseph Bruno, R-Troy, proposed suspending clothing sales taxes for two, one-week periods in fiscal 1998, which starts on April 1, and phasing the tax out at a rate of one percent a year for the next four years.</p>
<p>The first, one-week period would aim to boost back-to-school sales during the week of August 23, while the second would seek to raise post-holiday sales, running from January, 27 to 23, in 1998. The proposal eventually would cost the state around $550 million in lost revenues.</p>
<p>Bruno opened the door to allowing local governments to start eliminating such clothing sales taxes. &quot;The localities would also have the option of instituting the two-week suspension as well as the phase-out of their sales tax on clothing,&quot; he added, in prepared remarks.</p>
<p>Asked by reporters in Albany if New York City would be able to drop its share of the sales tax this year, the Senate Majority Leader said: &quot;That's part of what we will be discussing with the city members and the others that surround it and our conference...We wouldn't be precluding anything from happening without proper hearing, proper discussion, proper input.&quot;</p>
<p>If New York City were to go ahead, this might pressure surrounding counties to follow suit.</p>
<p>&quot;That's why people in elected office have a responsibility to do what's best for their constituency, and that's why we are not mandating that localities do anything other than what the elected officials see as what's in the best interest in their constituiency,&quot; Bruno told reporters, when asked about this possibility.</p>
<p>((--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
