<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="433505" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYC HHC to sell $300 mln of variable rate bonds.</title>
<headline>NYC HHC to sell $300 mln of variable rate bonds.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York City Health and Hospitals Corp on Tuesday said that it planned to sell around $300 million of tax-exempt, variable rate bonds as soon as early April.</p>
<p>This will be the first time the corporation that runs the city's hospitals has sold debt since 1993, when it sold around $550 million of bonds, said Todd Hixson, senior director of capital management for the Health and Hospitals Corp.  </p>
<p>PaineWebber was selected to lead the syndicate for the new offering, and it and Morgan Stanley will remarket the bonds so that the rates are set every week according to what the market demands, the official explained. Morgan Stanley also is on the underwriting team, as is Artemis Capital.</p>
<p>Hixson said that the potential to save on interest costs led the corporation to decide to sell variable rate bonds instead of the fixed-rate debt it used last time. &quot;It's cheap and its flexible in terms of using the proceeds.&quot; The funds raised by the 1993 offering lasted longer than expected as some projects were determined to be too expensive.</p>
<p>The Health and Hospitals Corporation plans to use the new bonds to pay for projects outlined in its three-year capital plan, including renovating and modernizing some of its faciliites, including upgrading elevators and air conditioners, and continuing with a new information system on patient care.</p>
<p>But a sales date has yet to be finalized. &quot;We're hoping for early April, no later than the middle of April,&quot; Hixson said.</p>
<p>((--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
