<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="433723" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian diamond trade overcomes woes in 1996.</title>
<headline>Belgian diamond trade overcomes woes in 1996.</headline>
<byline>Bert Lauwers</byline>
<dateline>ANTWERP, Belgium 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Diamonds remained Belgium's best friend last year as the country maintained its dominant position in the world's trade despite a series of setbacks hitting the sector.</p>
<p>&quot;1996 was a very restless year for the international diamond market,&quot; the Diamond High Council (DHC) said in its annual report.</p>
<p>&quot;And yet we continue to grab another piece of business year after year,&quot; said DHC general manager Marc Van den Abeelen.</p>
<p>&quot;The competition has not succeeded in catching up on us despite their continuous attacks...but we have to stay vigilant,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>But despite some unfavourable conditions, total turnover for the Antwerp-based trade rose 12 percent in weight to 399.7 million carats and 11 percent in value terms to $23 billion.</p>
<p>Imports rose three percent in weight to 217.2 million carats and by 13 percent in value to $11.6 billion. Exports increased 26 percent in weight to 182.5 million carats and nine percent in value to $11.6 billion.</p>
<p>The DHC said many diamond traders had feared that the London-based De Beers Central Selling Organisation (CSO) would lose control over the market, which would have caused serious damage to confidence in diamonds.</p>
<p>It said there was a sigh of relief when CSO and Russia signed a memorandum of understanding early last year, but the market is still awaiting a final deal between CSO and Russia.</p>
<p>&quot;For the stability of the market it would be good to have the contract, to guarantee stable prices,&quot; Van den Abeelen said.</p>
<p>De Beers, the main stabilising factor in the diamond business, has had an iron grip on trading in rough stones through CSO. Most of the diamonds sold by the CSO to polishing centres such as Antwerp come from De Beers itself.</p>
<p>Tension also rose last year when Australian Argyle, owned by Anglo-Australian mining groups RTZ-CRA and Ashton Mining Ltd, decided in June not to renew its sales contract with CSO.</p>
<p>&quot;Fortunately any possible negative consequence of this decision on the world market was limited,&quot; DHC said.</p>
<p>Van den Abeelen said Argyle had not dumped diamonds on the market like many traders had feared but had brought higher-quality goods on the market.</p>
<p>&quot;It was in fact more De Beers which dumped smaller stones during a number of sights (auctions) last year which dragged prices of smaller goods down,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The diamond market also had to cope with some unfavourable factors last year including a price rise by De Beers for rough diamonds last July, consumers' resistance to price increases and shrinking profit margins as a result, DHC said.</p>
<p>Antwerp imported 210 million carats of rough gems, confirming its position as the biggest market next to CSO.</p>
<p>But CSO's share of supply to Antwerp fell to 33 from 37 percent and increased to 67 percent for the outside market, maily Zaire and Liberia. Rough stones were mainly sent to India.</p>
<p>The supply of Russian diamonds continued to increase despite the provisional agreement with CSO.</p>
<p>The United States remained Antwerp's main export market for polished diamonds, followed by Hong Kong and Japan, which has been suffering from recession for several years and is now shifting to some cheaper categories.</p>
<p>&quot;I fear that it will not get much better in Japan in the future,&quot; Van den Abeelen said.</p>
<p>He said that the trend continued to be favourable in the first few months of this year as the economy was improving slightly in its main markets, the U.S. and South East Asia.</p>
<p>Antwerp, which has about 1,200 diamond companies, accounts for about 56 percent of world trade in diamonds, and more than seven percent of total exports from Belgium.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6815, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANTWERP, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
