<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="433845" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Merrill Lynch-private banking booming, Asia leads.</title>
<headline>Merrill Lynch-private banking booming, Asia leads.</headline>
<byline>Elif Kaban</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Merrill Lynch Bank's international private banking business is booming with Southeast Asia emerging as the number one region in the world in terms of individual wealth creation, a top bank official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Michael Giles, chairman of Merrill Lynch International Banks in London, said in an interview in Zurich that he expected private assets managed by the bank globally to grow by an average annual 20 percent in the next five years.</p>
<p>The bank estimates worldwide growth in the private banking industry at more than 10 percent a year, he added.</p>
<p>The total volume of private wealth managed by Merrill Lynch stands at around $50 billion, Giles told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said emerging markets led by the Far East were taking the lead in new private wealth creation.</p>
<p>&quot;Southeast Asia is the fastest growing area for us in terms of private banking. Our business is growing in every one of these markets, particularly in China,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The emergence of China is creating entrepreneurial wealth not only in China but in the whole of Southeast Asia,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Giles did not give a breakdown for the business in Asia. In Hong Kong, he said there had been some flight of private wealth out of the British colony ahead of China's takeover on July 1 but that this had been much less than anticipated.</p>
<p>Europe and Latin America currently had the biggest slice of Merrill Lynch's global private banking business with 40 percent share each, but emerging markets were set to take the lead soon.</p>
<p>&quot;The growth rates in private wealth creation will continue to be higher in emerging markets than in traditional European markets,&quot; Giles said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're already growing in these markets and expect to continue to grow. Our growth rate on the international side is constantly greater than the domestic (U.S.) side. We expect higher growth rates in the international private banking business for the foreseeable future than our U.S. business.&quot;</p>
<p>Giles said Middle East was another growth area for the bank mainly because of low to non-existent tax rates in the region, while the growth rate in the United States was slowing down.</p>
<p>Russia and the former Soviet republics were also generating increasing volumes of liquid private wealth, but Merrill Lynch remained cautious about these markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia is not a priority for us and not a source of business for us right now because of problems of due-diligence,&quot; Giles said.</p>
<p>Client profiles were changing, with entrepreneurs in emerging markets contributing to a growing share of the wealth creation in the world, he said.</p>
<p>He said the world's super-rich were getting more and more demanding and sophisticated in an increasingly competitive environment. Client segmentation in terms of risk profiles and origins of funds as well as database management would become major competitive issues for the industry in the coming years.</p>
<p>&quot;We have less of the old, multi-generational wealth, the 200 years' worth of passing on the account. But that's fine. That wealth tends to be much more passive. Our client base tends to be more new wealth and entrepreneurial wealth,&quot; Giles said.</p>
<p>Globally, Giles said Merrill Lynch ranked after three top Swiss banks (Swiss Bank Corp, Credit Suisse and Union Bank of Switzerland ), J.P. Morgan, Citibank and Chase/Chemical in private banking.</p>
<p>Private banking concentrates on &quot;high net-worth individuals&quot; -- people with liquid assets, or easily available cash, of at least $500,000.</p>
<p>Accountancy and consulting firm Price Waterhouse estimates the global market for these super-rich people at somewhere between $17 and $20 trillion.</p>
<p>Of this, probably between $4 and $6 trillion is estimated to be in Europe, both domestic and offshore.</p>
<p>--- Reuters Zurich Newsroom +41-1-631 73 40</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
