<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="433970" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Powerfin, Tractebel merger seen at 3-for-1.</title>
<headline>Powerfin, Tractebel merger seen at 3-for-1.</headline>
<byline>Geert De Clercq</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>If Belgian utility holding company Tractebel finally swallows up its unit Powerfin later this month, it will probably propose a 3-for-1 merger, analysts said.</p>
<p>But they added the offer might have to be sweetened to counter minority shareholder opposition.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking at the market prices, a swap of one Tractebel share for three Powerfin seems logical, but that would not be very generous for Powerfin shareholders,&quot; Vincent Neefs of Antwerp brokerage Smeets, Verbaet et Cie said.</p>
<p>Tractebel and its controlling shareholder Societe Generale de Belgique (SGB) have been looking into the possibility of a Tractebel-Powerfin merger since September 1996, when SGB boosted its Tractebel stake to 65 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts had expected the deal to be sealed last year, but it was put off in December when Tractebel said it wanted to have the two companies' 1996 accounts before making a decision.</p>
<p>A Tractebel spokesman declined to say if the group had now decided whether or not to go ahead with the merger.</p>
<p>Both groups have board meetings on March 18 which will approve 1996 earnings and debate the merger plan.</p>
<p>Analysts have little doubt it will go ahead, although they expect some Powerfin minority shareholders will be disgruntled about having to sell a growth share like Powerfin. But saying no to Tractebel could be difficult, as there was always the ultimate threat of a delisting after the merger.</p>
<p>&quot;One cannot rule out the possibility that Powerfin would be delisted,&quot; BBL analyst Jean-Marie Caucheteux said.</p>
<p>Tractebel holds 63.05 percent of Powerfin.</p>
<p>Powerfin's main asset is its 26 percent stake in Electrabel, which has a virtual monopoly on Belgian electricity production and generates the bulk of Powerfin profits.</p>
<p>But the group is better known for its ambitious foreign expansion drive, started five years ago.</p>
<p>By the year 2004, Powerfin wants to produce as much electricity abroad as the 13,000 megawatts Electrabel produces in Belgium.</p>
<p>Powerfin currently operates power plants in Northern Ireland, Portugal, the U.S., Germany, Hungary and Chile and has projects in many other countries, including Oman, Italy, India, Kazakhstan and Malaysia.</p>
<p>&quot;The Electrabel shares alone held by Powerfin are worth 4,900 francs per share. I cannot quite imagine that all of Powerfin's foreign activities are worth just 200 francs per share,&quot; said Dewaay, Servais analyst Danny Wittenberg.</p>
<p>Powerfin's net asset value per share is at least 5,600 francs, he added.</p>
<p>Wittenberg said that a 3-for-1 merger would become more attractive if Tractebel shares were to rise to about 17,000 francs, or if Powerfin gave an exceptional dividend before the merger.</p>
<p>In early trade on Tuesday Tractebel was quoted down 50 francs at 15,425 and Powerfin 10 francs higher at 5,130.</p>
<p>Given the merger plan, analysts expect the Tractebel group will be inclined to publish poor 1996 earnings for Powerfin in order to make Powerfin look less attractive.</p>
<p>They also expect the Powerfin 1996 annual report to focus on the difficulties, rather than the profit potential, of investing in foreign energy projects.</p>
<p>Reuters 3000 consensus estimates show that 14 analysts expect Powerfin's 1996 earnings to grow 4.1 percent.</p>
<p>But Wittenberg expected current earnings would actually fall slightly to 7.5 billion francs. In 1995, Powerfin earned a 7.71 billion franc group net profit.</p>
<p>Tractebel's 1996 profit is seen rising 4.94 percent, an EFP poll of 17 analysts on Reuters 3000 showed.</p>
<p>-- Geert De Clercq, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6813, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
