<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43398" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: No timeframe on proposed JCI sale -- MD.</title>
<headline>No timeframe on proposed JCI sale -- MD.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Although negotiations on the sale of a controlling stake in JCI Ltd to South African black business were ongoing, no timeframe could be put on the proposed deal, JCI managing director Bill Nairn said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Following a presentation of JCI's 1996 year end results, Nairn said it was &quot;impossible&quot; to say how soon all or part of Anglo American Corp of South Africa Ltd and De Beers Consolidated Mines Ltd's stake in JCI would be sold.</p>
<p>He said, however, that management was enthusiastic about the proposed benefits JCI could derive from having controlling black shareholders, and was seeking to facilitate a speedy resolution.</p>
<p>Nairn said a number of groups had already had discussions with Anglo and that JCI was also involved in the talks.</p>
<p>&quot;When groups approach Anglo, we are making it a priority to get involved and share our vision with them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nairn said interested parties included Real Africa Investments Ltd, New Africa Investments Ltd, the National Empowerment Consortium (NEC), Capital Alliance and African Renaissance Holdings.</p>
<p>The future of JCI has moved into the spotlight following last month's landmark deal under which Anglo and De Beers will sell the bulk of their stake in sister company Johnnies Industrial Corp to the NEC, a consortium of black investors.</p>
<p>&quot;The conclusion of the Johnnic deal is welcomed and I believe it will add impetus to discussions already underway about JCI,&quot; Nairn said.</p>
<p>-- Nicole Mordant, Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
