<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="434006" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Dini warns Prodi not to abuse trust on budget.</title>
<headline>Dini warns Prodi not to abuse trust on budget.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian foreign minister Lamberto Dini warned Prime Minister Romano Prodi in a newspaper interview on Tuesday not to abuse his loyalty by trying to sell him done deals with the hard-left Communist Refoundation party.</p>
<p>&quot;I've already screamed loudly a couple of times,&quot; Dini, himself a former prime minister and leader of the Italian Renewal party, told Il Foglio daily newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;Prodi cannot always sell us an agreement already worked out with Communist Refoundation. They must be careful not to abuse my sense of loyalty. There can be some surprises,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dini said the government was already imposing a draconian Eurotax and now it was talking about a mini-budget of &quot;only six trillion lire ($3.5 billion) &quot; based on advances on severance pay &quot;which a rigorous person like Treasury Minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi cannot accept.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Anyway, I can't accept it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The government is expected to unveil a 1997 mini-budget in coming weeks.</p>
<p>But the hard-left Communist Refoundation, which holds the balance of power in the lower house of parliament, opposes cuts in public spending or tax hikes and is unhappy over additional budget trimming measures.</p>
<p>It has threatened to withdraw its support if the government cuts a deal with the opposition.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +392 66129507 ($ = 1690 Italian Lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
