<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43400" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerian share index steady in active trade.</title>
<headline>Nigerian share index steady in active trade.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Nigerian share index closed barely changed in active Wednesday trading in which the newly- listed Guaranty Trust Bank made big gains.</p>
<p>The all-share index closed at 6,175.01 from 6,175.00 on Monday.</p>
<p>Guaranty Trust Bank rose the maximum five percent allowed after it's listing on Monday, closing 52 kobo higher at 11.02 naira. Other big banks ended the day unchanged. AIICO Insurance closed 15 kobo higher at 5.60 naira.</p>
<p>Petroleum marketing companies showed the steady gains which in recent months have characterised the sector. Agip closed 10 kobo higher at 12.50 naira. Also gaining 10 kobo were: African Petroleum at 28.40 naira, Mobil at 35.60 naira and Texaco at 23.73 naira. Unipetrol closed five kobo higher at 34.55 naira.</p>
<p>West African Portland Cement Company rose 16 kobo to 28.28 naira, while Cement Company of Northern Nigeria went ex-dividend at 2.34 naira, down 43 kobo.</p>
<p>Seven-Up Bottling Company closed three kobo down at 2.10 naira. Cadbury was three kobo higher at 23.63 naira. Northern Nigerian Flour Mills went ex-dividend, down 50 kobo to 9.11 naira.</p>
<p>Conglomerate CFAO showed no signs of stopping its slide. Shares dropped 17 kobo to 5.68 nair. In the same sector PZ Industries rose 10 kobo to 33.00 naira.</p>
<p>Guinness Breweries fell 10 kobo to 9.55 naira, however Nigerian Breweries held steady at 13.60 naira after a long downward run.</p>
<p>Delta Glass fell 10 kobo to 6.20 naira. Studio Press dropped 14 kobo to 1.25 naira. Van Leer containers rose 12 kobo to 11.92. Dunlop Nigeria fell five kobo to 12.30 naira. First Aluminium fell seven kobo to 5.32 naira.</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 2631943</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
