<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="434029" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - Mar 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - Mar 11.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Bangladesh press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE DAILY STAR</p>
<p>Former Finance Minister and a senior opposition lawmaker, Saifur Rahman, on Tuesday criticised the government for mishandling with the share market affairs and &quot;mismanagement of the economy&quot;.</p>
<p>Demarcation of about 41 kms of Indo-Bangladesh land boundary was yet to completed, said Indian Foreign Affairs Minister I K Gujral.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>The former Soviet Union President Mikhail Gorvachev has expressed his desire to start a Grameen Bank type poverty alleviation programme in Russian Federation.</p>
<p>Former President H M Ersahd on Monday said the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) of former Prime Minister Begum Khaleda Zia had forced him to prolong martial law by not taking part in a proposed election in 1984.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>BANGLADESH OBSERVER</p>
<p>Parliament on Monday passed a bill to ammend the Bank Company Act to make it more effective to deal with loan defaulters.</p>
<p>The Election Commission has constituted a four-member Electoral Reforms Commission.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>FINANCIAL EXPRESS</p>
<p>Finance Minister S A M S Kibria on Monday said emotion must be discarded in acting or reacting on national economic issues.</p>
<p>Traders in the kerb market demonstrated on Monday outside the Dhaka bourse demanding withdrawl of a circular asking the listed companies not to effect any transfer of shares without the related transaction sheet.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
