<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="434195" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Zeneca drops fungal disease drug.</title>
<headline>Zeneca drops fungal disease drug.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>British drug group Zeneca Group Plc said on Tuesday it had dropped the development of a drug for serious fungal diseases because of problems with the way the drug works.</p>
<p>Chief executive David Barnes told a news conference that Zeneca's partner on the drug, Japan's Mochida Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, would continue its own development programme using lower doses and different indications for the product.</p>
<p>Barnes said Zeneca, which announced record 1996 earnings earlier Tuesday, took six new compounds into development last year.  </p>
<p>He said this brought the total of new prodcuts in development to 18, excluding products awaiting marketing approval such as Seroquel for schizophrenia and Zomig for migraine.</p>
<p>Barnes said an anti-cancer drug, Faslodex, had been taken into late-stage studies for treatment of advanced breast cancer, and had started intermediate, or Phase II, trials for benign gynaecological disease.  </p>
<p>Finance director John Mayo said Tomudex, a drug which has already been approved in 11 countries for treatment of colo-rectal cancer, &quot;has shown equivalence on survival and efficacy to the current standard therapy,&quot; citing mature data from recent trials published in Italy on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Good efficacy, together with health economic benefits and less side effects, should mean that Tomudex has an important role to play in the treatment of colo-rectal cancer,&quot; Mayo said.</p>
<p>Zeneca's managemtent said one of its aims was to become the world's number one cancer company through its pipeline of drugs and the Salick cancer care company based in the U.S.</p>
<p>Zeneca is currently number two in terms of cancer drug sales, behind Bristol Myers Squibb Co of the U.S.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
