<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43448" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Women from mass grave identified in factory morgue.</title>
<headline>Women from mass grave identified in factory morgue.</headline>
<byline>Elly Biles</byline>
<dateline>USTIKOLINA, Bosnia 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Doctors working in a bombed-out Bosnian factory converted into a makeshift morgue on Tuesday identified the remains of 17 women and an old man said to have been executed by separatist Serbs in 1992.</p>
<p>The victims were exhumed last weekend from several common graves on a wooded slope near the eastern town of Gorazde, on territory returned by the Serbs to the Bosnian government under the 1995 Dayton peace treaty.</p>
<p>Twenty-two disintegrating corpses were laid out on a dank floor in a devastated factory in the village of Ustikolina and Bosnian government forensic scientists had identified 18 with the help of relatives by late Tuesday.</p>
<p>Each body was inspected on a table consisting of two large barrels with an old door laid across them. Sunlight filtered through a huge window from which the glass was smashed out long ago.</p>
<p>&quot;I have found bullet holes in the skulls of two sisters, six and nine years old, and similar wounds on a 16-month-old baby found buried with her mother,&quot; pathologist Zdenko Cihlarz told Reuters Television.</p>
<p>He spoke wearily after identifying an 81-year-old man, Muradif Subasic, with the assistance of his 46-year-old son Hakija, who stood at the doctor's side.</p>
<p>Hakija could not speak after Cihlarz found a familiar wristwatch in the rotting trouser pocket of his father.</p>
<p>Eight female bodies were stretched out nearby on plastic sheeting, most covered by blankets in which they had been hastily buried and which had since fused to their decaying skin.</p>
<p>Women's skirts and scarves were still evident on the four-year-old corpses, both children and adults.</p>
<p>The factory is close to a former front line between the Serbs and mostly Moslem Bosnian government army. A sign warning of land mines stands on the approach to the factory.</p>
<p>Investigators were led to the grave sites last week by an elderly Moslem man who said he had secretly dug one of them for his wife, daughter and granddaughter after they were shot in a wartime massacre by Serb paramilitaries.</p>
<p>The man told Reuters he had risked his life crossing front lines during the war to find the bodies strewn in a wood and buried them as a minimally dignified farewell.</p>
<p>The victims were among a group of Moslem women and children villagers caught hiding in the forest by Serb forces on May 9, 1992 as they were marching menfolk away from a captured hamlet.</p>
<p>Government investigators said 28 grave sites containing executed women and children are believed to be scattered along the ravine.</p>
<p>Moslems who have resettled in the area said they were all burned out of their homes by Serbs in May 1992.</p>
<p>The International Criminal Tribunal on former Yugoslavia, based in The Hague, has indicted 75 people for atrocities against civilians and prisoners in Bosnia and Croatia in 1991- 95. The majority of indictees are Serbs.</p>
<p>Tribunal investigators recently excavated several mass graves of Moslems slaughtered by the Serb conquerors of the eastern town of Srebrenica in mid-1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="USTIKOLINA, Bosnia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
