<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43449" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Prague, Washington sign bilateral open skies deal.</title>
<headline>Prague, Washington sign bilateral open skies deal.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE, Czech Republic</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States and the Czech Republic on Tuesday signed an air transport agreement which Washington said is a model &quot;open skies&quot; deal with a former Communist state.</p>
<p>&quot;The agreement provides U.S. airlines with immediate open route rights and with limited third-country code-share rights by September 1997,&quot; the U.S. embassy in Prague said in a statement. Code-sharing allows passengers to fly on two airlines with a single ticket.</p>
<p>U.S. Ambassador to Prague Jenonne Walker and Czech Transport Minister Martin Riman signed the deal in a ceremony at the ambassador's residence.</p>
<p>The code sharing allows U.S. airlines to cooperate with Czech and third-country air carriers to provide more frequent service between the U.S. and the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>Reciprocal open skies rights are to be fully phased in by the autumn of 1999, the embassy added.</p>
<p>&quot;When its provisions are completely phased in by November, 1999, this accord will be a model 'open skies' agreement -- the first of its kind between the U.S. and a post-Communist state,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The Czech national airline Ceske Aerolinie a.s. (CSA) earlier this year completed a code sharing deal with U.S. carrier Continental Airlines.</p>
<p>The deal allows CSA to offer westbound passengers access to Continental's routes through Newark, N.J., airport as its primary North American destination, where Continental will use CSA through Prague on some eastbound destinations.</p>
<p>Delta Airlines is the most active U.S. carrier with scheduled flights to and from Prague's Ruzyne International Airport, the country's primary gateway which is undergoing a major expansion.</p>
<p>The embassy said the agreement would also aid cooperation in aviation security, plus expand tourism and greater cultural exchange between the U.S. and the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>The deal was negotiated between the U.S. State Department and Department of Transportation along with the Czech Foreign Ministry, Transport Ministry, Czech National Bank, and airline industry representatives from both countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE, Czech Republic"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
