<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="434578" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: WSP sets agreed buy of consultant Graham.</title>
<headline>WSP sets agreed buy of consultant Graham.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>British consulting engineers WSP Holdings Plc said on Tuesday that it had agreed the purchase of civil engineering specialists Graham Consulting Group Ltd.</p>
<p>In a statement the company said the total consideration for the buy would be 3.596 billion stg, with 1.98 billion paid in cash and the remainder via the issue of new shares to Graham.  </p>
<p>&quot;The directors' aim has been to position WSP as a significant &quot;brand name&quot; engineering consultancy capable of challenging for the largest projects. The merger will...add substantially to the group's civil engineering capability as well as overseas presence,&quot; the statement added.</p>
<p>Graham had turnover of 20 million stg in the nine months to the end of 1996, WSP noted, with about a third of this earned overseas. It has 540 employees in the UK and will take the combined group total to 1,300.</p>
<p>WSP said its own pre-tax profits rose 28 percent to 2.3 million stg in 1996 on turnover up 11 percent to 28.2 million stg.</p>
<p>Its earnings per share rose 15 percent to 5.4 pence and it raised its dividend by 9.0 percent to 2.4 pence.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
