<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43470" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia says might accept 1997 NATO summit invite.</title>
<headline>Russia says might accept 1997 NATO summit invite.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia expressed interest on Tuesday in attending a summit of NATO and East European states next year.</p>
<p>Moscow may take up a suggestion by French President Jacques Chirac to join the gathering, a foreign ministry spokesman said, Itar-Tass news agency reported.</p>
<p>Spokesman Gennady Tarasov said the Paris initiative &quot;aroused interest in Moscow and we are closely studying its possibilities&quot;.</p>
<p>He added that Moscow welcomed efforts to make the Western defence alliance a stabilising factor in Europe.</p>
<p>Russia would carefully consider any formal invitation to an alliance meeting, Tarasov said. &quot;A positive answer to such an invitation might be given,&quot;</p>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin, who faces heart surgery later this month, and German Chancellor Helmut Kohl agreed at informal talks near Moscow on Saturday to try to resolve by next year a dispute over NATO's plans to admit former Soviet-bloc states in Central and Eastern Europe. Moscow opposes the plans.</p>
<p>Chirac proposed in an August 29 speech in Paris that the 16 NATO members, the central and east European states which are candidates for membership and all other countries, including Russia, which have links with NATO should meet next year.</p>
<p>The summit, which French officials have said could take place early in 1997, would mark the reform of NATO, the emergence of a European defence identity within the Atlantic Alliance and the launch of a new pan-European security set-up.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher said in the German city of Stuttgart on Friday that NATO leaders would meet next spring or early summer to decide on new members and approve a charter defining the alliance's relationship with Russia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
