<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="434730" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korean unions vow new fight against labour law.</title>
<headline>S.Korean unions vow new fight against labour law.</headline>
<byline>Jane Lee</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean labour unions on Tuesday repeated a threat to organise strikes in protest against a new labour law, but economic analysts said workers had lost their appetite for industrial action.</p>
<p>&quot;We will fight the law and could strike again until our demands are met,&quot; said Chung Sung-hee, spokesman for the Korean Confederation of Trade Unions.</p>
<p>The confederation spearheaded almost one month of strikes after an earlier labour bill was rammed through parliament on December 26.</p>
<p>Parliament on Monday passed a revised version of the bill watering-down key clauses, including one making layoffs easier. The new law also allows more than one union organisation, a move that offers legitimacy to the militant confederation.</p>
<p>A confederation statement on Monday denounced &quot;poisonous provisions, which debase worker living standards&quot;.</p>
<p>It was referring to clauses that will allow layoffs from 1999, bring in flexible working hours immediately and permit management to replace strikers from within the company.</p>
<p>But analysts doubted the confederation could pull off another nationwide strike.</p>
<p>&quot;No one believes unions have enough fighting power left,&quot; said Steven Lee, an analyst at Shinyoung Securities.</p>
<p>Citizens' groups, usually staunch backers of organised labour, said the confederation faced an uphill battle to get any further labour law revisions.</p>
<p>&quot;The new law was passed with opposition and ruling party approval, so it will be more difficult for the union to fight it,&quot; said Yi Dae-hoon of the People's Solidarity for Participatory Democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;The confederation needs the participation of ordinary workers to make a strike successful. But workers will be too busy negotiating their wages to spare time to fight a political battle against parliament.&quot;</p>
<p>South Korea's annual wage talks traditionally begin around April or May.</p>
<p>Strikes this year cost 3.28 billion in lost production.</p>
<p>The new bill permits multiple unions at a national level right away, and in individual companies by 2002.</p>
<p>Although this gives the confederation the right to register, it would not get official sanction in its present form. This is because it now illegally represents teachers, who are barred from union membership, and workers on a company level within the giant Hyundai Group.</p>
<p>Chung said the confederation, which claims a membership of 500,000, has no intention of conforming with the law but will still try to register.</p>
<p>&quot;The Korean people have shown their support for our union by joining the strikes and we are already recognised internationally,&quot; said Chung.</p>
<p>Currently, the only legal union umbrella body is the Federation of Korean Trade Unions, which claims a membership of 1.2 million.</p>
<p>Lee Kwang-taek, a specialist in labour law at Seoul's Kookmin University, said the confederation may now pick up support from federation affiliates.</p>
<p>Militant workers criticise the federation as being a government stooge.</p>
<p>&quot;At least 80 bank unions have left the federation and are expected to join the confederation,&quot; said Lee.</p>
<p>The central Bank of Korea declared in January it was leaving the federation, accusing the body of failing to muster enough support for January's strikes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
