<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="434751" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China feed firms in price war for market share.</title>
<headline>China feed firms in price war for market share.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two of eastern China's biggest animal feed makers have launched a price war to vie for bigger shares of the domestic market, officials at both companies said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not going to make a profit,&quot; said an official with Hope Group, one of China's biggest private companies. &quot;Our main purpose is to grab more market share.&quot;</p>
<p>Hope Group began slashing feed prices early this week by between 10 percent and 25 percent, he said.</p>
<p>An official with Dajiang (Group) Co Ltd, which is 42 percent owned by Thailand's Chiatai Group, said the company had cut feed prices by an average of eight percent in February.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Hope Group) followed us,&quot; the Dajiang official told Reuters. &quot;We cut prices a month earlier than Hope, and the idea was to take more market share from Hope.&quot;</p>
<p>China produced 45 million tonnes feed in 1996, with Dajiang accounting for two percent and Hope five percent, the Dajiang official said. Both companies sell the bulk of their products in Zhejiang and Jiangsu provinces and in Shanghai.</p>
<p>After the price cuts, Dajiang's wholesale prices remain three to four percent above Hope's, the Dajiang official said.  </p>
<p>&quot;But the quality of our products is better than theirs,&quot; he said. Sales doubled in the first month after the cuts, he added.</p>
<p>Hope Group president Liu Yongxing was quoted in the official Chinese press earlier this week saying his company welcomed competition.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe we have enough power to take part in competition,&quot; he said. &quot;This price battle will cost us 100 million yuan ($12 million).&quot;</p>
<p>Both companies declined to reveal their profit figures for 1996, but said a decline in the price of corn, the main raw material for animal feed, had increased their margins.</p>
<p>The average domestic market price of corn in China fell to 1,300 yuan per tonne in 1996 from 1,600 yuan in 1995, the Dajiang official said.</p>
<p>($1=8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42210">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
