<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="434790" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China says battles won against crime, war goes on.</title>
<headline>China says battles won against crime, war goes on.</headline>
<byline>Mure Dickie</byline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's top judge and prosecutor on Tuesday hailed new victories in the war on crime but said hostile foreign forces, criminal gangs and widespread corruption made the law-enforcement situation appear grim.</p>
<p>China's courts dealt with 5.26 million cases of all kinds in 1996, up 15.82 percent from the year earlier, said Ren Jianxin, president of the Supreme Court</p>
<p>Judges sentenced 211,900 people to penalties ranging from five years in jail to death as courts across the nation cracked down on criminals, Ren said in a speech to the annual session of the National People's Congress, or parliament.</p>
<p>Prosecutors boosted the number of arrests made by around 17 percent last year, but much remained to be done to rein in a tide of lawbreaking, said Procurator General Zhang Siqing.</p>
<p>&quot;Violent crime, narcotics offences and gang and mafia-style criminal activity remain very rampant and the law enforcement situation cannot be considered optimistic,&quot; Zhang told nearly 3,000 congress members in Beijing's Great Hall of the People.</p>
<p>&quot;Hostile foreign forces are intensifying efforts to Westernise and split us,&quot; he said, in an apparent reference to recent bombings and assassination attempts by pro-independence activists in the western regions of Tibet and Xinjiang.</p>
<p>Chinese officials have accused Western nations of backing separatists in the remote and often restive regions.</p>
<p>&quot;Subversion and sabotage by enemy elements at home and abroad as well as nationality separatism and illegal religious activities all appear to be spreading,&quot; Zhang said.</p>
<p>Neither he nor top judge Ren made any mention of the most recent crime to grab the attention of residents in Beijing, who have long considered their city one of the world's safest.</p>
<p>Police in the capital have been on high alert since an explosion from a homemade bomb ripped through a public bus in one of Beijing's busiest commercial districts last week.</p>
<p>Sources said at least two people were killed by the bomb, which followed similar attacks in far-western Xinjiang region that killed nine and injured 74.</p>
<p>Crime has been far less of a hot topic at this year's congress than it was in 1995, when delegates were still reeling from the recent murder of a senior legislator, but both judge and prosecutor made clear they planned no let up.</p>
<p>Beijing's much-vaunted anti-graft crusade had netted thousands of officials who tried to barter bureaucratic clout for personal gain, Ren said.</p>
<p>Convictions against Communist Party and government officials and administrators for bribe-taking, favouritism and misuse of public funds had risen 4.38 percent to 65,424, he said in a speech peppered with court statistics.</p>
<p>Financial corruption, almost unknown under the strict communist rule of China's late Chairman Mao Zedong, has boomed as market-style reforms launched by his successor Deng Xiaoping have loosened social controls.</p>
<p>Beijing leaders have made clear that reinforcing social stability and cracking down on graft are priorities in the period following Deng's death on February 19.</p>
<p>Favouritism, bribe taking and malpractice among law enforcers remained serious, and the number of investigations launched by prosecutors into such cases had soared 26.9 percent to 2,592, Zhang said.</p>
<p>While the prosecutor crowed the success of investigations of a Beijing government secretary and mayoral assistant, he made no mention of action against the capital's former Communist Party boss, Chen Xitong, who was dismissed in a graft scandal in 1995.</p>
<p>A top city official said last year that communist leaders -- and not prosecutors -- would decide whether to charge Chen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
