<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="434830" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai cabinet approves big budget cuts for 1996/97.</title>
<headline>Thai cabinet approves big budget cuts for 1996/97.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Thai cabinet on Tuesday approved a proposal by Finance Minister Amnuay Viravan to trim the 1996/1997 (October/September) budget by 106 billion baht ($4.11 billion) as part of a policy to rein in the current account deficit.</p>
<p>Virat Wattanasiritham, secretary general of the National Economic and Social Development Board (NESDB), said the budget cuts were slightly higher than an earlier 99 billion baht target submitted to the cabinet last month.  </p>
<p>Virat said the approved budget cuts would affect about 20 infrastructure projects of state enterprises which have been asked to delay their investment, especially those requiring major foreign borrowing.</p>
<p>He did not detail projects involved but officials said earlier that they included electricity and public housing projects, and a requirement for national carrier Thai Airways International Plc to expand its fleet by leasing aircraft instead of buying them.</p>
<p>&quot;The cuts should save Thailand about 24.7 billion baht in foreign exchange that state enterprises would have to borrow,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Virat, head of Thailand's official long-term economic think tank, said the budget cuts would slow gross domestic product growth this year to 6.7-6.8 percent from 7.1 percent targeted by the central bank earlier and 6.7 percent growth in 1996.</p>
<p>However, he added that the austerity measures would help narrow the current account deficit to about 7.1-7.2 percent of GDP this year from 7.9 percent seen by the central bank a few months ago and an actual 8.0 percent deficit in 1996.  </p>
<p>Central bank governor Rerngchai Marakanond said on Saturday he was confident that the spending cuts and other prudent economic measures would help trim the deficit to less than 7.5 percent of GDP this year.</p>
<p>(US$1 = 25.8 baht)</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662)-6520642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
