<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="434896" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: LME copper, aluminium stocks tipped to fall - trade.</title>
<headline>LME copper, aluminium stocks tipped to fall - trade.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>London Metal Exchange (LME) copper and aluminium inventories are seen falling later on Tuesday, dealers said.</p>
<p>Singapore-based dealers forecast copper stocks would dip between 2,000-4,000 tonnes while aluminium inventories are likely to drop by 2,000-5,000 tonnes when the LME report is issued at 0900 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;Copper should be down by 3,000 to 4,000 tonnes. Aluminium should also be down by around 5,000 tonnes,&quot; a dealer for a European metal trading company said.  </p>
<p>Another trader said, however, that copper stocks will probably decline by only 2,000 tonnes and will not duplicate the surprise 6,225 tonne fall in the previous LME report last Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think aluminium will go down by 2,000 to 3,000 tonnes,&quot; one dealer for a metal trading company added.</p>
<p>Far East dealers said there should also be another drawdown in copper stocks at the LME's Singapore warehouse.</p>
<p>&quot;I know there's stuff coming out,&quot; one trader said, adding the amount will probably reach a few hundred tonnes.  </p>
<p>The volume of copper in the LME's warehouse in the city-state reached 53,075 tonnes in its stocks report on Friday, down 1,650 tonnes from the previous report last Tuesday.</p>
<p>Three-month copper was quoted by the trade at about US$2,345/50 a tonne at 0300 GMT, against the late quote in London on Monday of $2,337/42 a tonne.</p>
<p>Three-month aluminium was seen by regional dealers at around $1,644/49 a tonne at 0300 GMT, a shade lower than the late quote in London yesterday of $1,652/55 a tonne.</p>
<p>-- Rene Pastor, Singapore Newsroom (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
