<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="434986" id="root" date="1997-03-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: PRESS DIGEST - Norway - March 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Norway - March 11.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in Norwegian papers this morning:</p>
<p>AFTENPOSTEN</p>
<p>-It will become more expensive to receive treatment for a cold if the government gets its way. It is weighing a proposal under which a visit to the doctor for minor illnesses would cost more than is the case today. But if you are seriously ill your visit to the doctor would become more subsidised than before by the government.</p>
<p>-Virtually all, or 99 percent, of all heroin confiscated in Norway last year was smuggled into the country by foreigners, including criminals from former Yugoslavia and Turkey, police say.</p>
<p>-In the Arctic city of Tromsoe, as many as 27 people went snow-bathing yesterday to claim a world record.</p>
<p>-An increasing number of Russian prostitutes are offering their services to men in the Norwegian province of Finnmark, which borders Russia's Kola peninsula in the Arctic.</p>
<p>DAGENS NAERINGSLIV</p>
<p>-Norwegian investors stand to gain nearly four billion crowns after the discovery of a ship wreck in the sea off Equador. The Spanish ship La Capitana Jesus Maria sank in 1654 and divers in an expedition partly sponsored by Norwegian investors have now started salvaging gold coins from the wreck.</p>
<p>-The ethics council of Norway's securities brokerage association has fined R.S. Platou Securities 150,000 crowns for its role in a controversial share issue at offshore company NAT.</p>
<p>-Motorcycles have become popular in Norway with as many as 46,562 bikes registered in the country at the end of last year. About 7,500 new registrations were made in 1996, up 3,000 from 1995, but most of the new registrations were used bikes imported primarily from the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
