<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="435091" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: PRESS DIGEST - Canada - March 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Canada - March 12.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the headlines from selected Canadian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE GLOBE AND MAIL:</p>
<p>- Klein collects huge majority: Albertans tell Premier they like the way he eliminated province's C$3.4-billion deficit.</p>
<p>- Canadian viewers get more control: CRTC changes rules of TV game.</p>
<p>- Parking tickets strip up suspects: 3 held in daring jewelry robbery.</p>
<p>- Yeltsin moves to trim bloated cabinet: Chubais big winner as President aims for smaller, more energetic team.</p>
<p>- Battle for Jerusalem doesn't use bullets: Identity cards, housing are weapons in fight for contested capital.</p>
<p>- Albania slowly disintegrating into north-south civil clash.</p>
<p>REPORT ON BUSINESS:</p>
<p>- U.S. vultures pick at Eaton's: New York firms have 20-30 percent of distressed retailer's C$150-million trade debt, sources say.</p>
<p>- Alberta Stock Exchange shuts down as software fails again: 'I apologize profusely,' president says.</p>
<p>- Atlantic retailers win sales tax battle: Senate committee votes not to force tax inclusive pricing.</p>
<p>- Papua witch doctor to put hex on Vancouver Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>THE FINANCIAL POST:</p>
<p>- Vultures close in on Eaton's debt: Bids by U.S. funds for C$160 million owing have climbed towards 90 cents on the dollar, sparking predictions two banks will sell this week.</p>
<p>- Tories rout Martin tax plan.</p>
<p>- Wascana deal blow to Talisman.</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
