<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43533" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Chechnya deal brings peace, but at what cost?.</title>
<headline>Chechnya deal brings peace, but at what cost?.</headline>
<byline>Oleg Shchedrov</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The peace deal struck by Moscow envoy Alexander Lebed with separatist rebels in Chechnya has halted fighting, but the ex-paratroop general's critics say that politically it has taken Moscow back to square one.</p>
<p>The deal signed on August 31 allows for a withdrawal of most Russian troops, leaving in place the separatists they were sent to crush 21 months ago.</p>
<p>&quot;I view these documents as an act of capitulation before, let's put it this way, armed bandits,&quot; Moscow Mayor Yuri Luzhkov said after Lebed announced details of the agreement which he signed with rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov.</p>
<p>Under the deal, the troops sent to the southern region in December 1994 are to withdraw in exchange for a five-year deferral of a decision on the most difficult issue of the conflict -- Chechnya's future political status.</p>
<p>The rebels want complete independence from Russia but Moscow has ruled this out.</p>
<p>&quot;The fighting has stopped, documents have been signed,&quot; said Lebed, who was handed the task of restoring peace by President Boris Yeltsin. &quot;Let anyone come and say that this was wrong or illegal.&quot;</p>
<p>Lebed's mission has created hope for a lasting peace after the deaths of tens of thousands of people. The Russian public has cheered him as the first top official to say publicly that Moscow could not defeat the rebels militarily.</p>
<p>But despite the thunder of applause, there is a bitter aftertaste and many questions remain unanswered.</p>
<p>Under rebel pressure, a clause in the deal making the Russian constitution the basis for talks on Chechnya's future was replaced by mention of &quot;international law and respect for people's right for self-determination&quot;.</p>
<p>For the first time, the rebel leadership is referred to in the deal as &quot;the government of the Chechen Republic&quot;, a title reserved earlier for the Moscow-installed regional authority of Doku Zavgayev. The latter is not mentioned at all.</p>
<p>Opponents say these changes pave the way for Chechen independence and Zavgayev has accused Lebed of surrendering the region to the rebels.</p>
<p>Critics have reacted angrily to steps taken by the separatists to toughen their grip on Chechnya as the Russian troops and civil administration starts withdrawing.</p>
<p>Rebels are displacing local administrations loyal to Moscow and introducing the Islamic laws of Shariat. They make no secret of their continued desire to break away from Russia.</p>
<p>Rebel Leader Zelimkhan Yandarbiyev said in a newspaper interview at the weekend that he saw the five-year deferral on a political solution as a time-out for Russia to find a face-saving way to let Chechnya go.</p>
<p>Russian leaders, including Yeltsin, have kept a distance from Lebed, saying the political price must still be weighed up.</p>
<p>The ex-general has shrugged off the criticism and the rebels' victory cries.</p>
<p>He says the rebels will in time be happy to have the status of a Russian region enjoying strong autonomy and will not want to face the inevitable uncertainties of being a separate small state sandwiched between a hostile Russia and Georgia.</p>
<p>Tatarstan, another Russian region, solved a similar dilemma peacefully in 1995 by opting to stay in Russia with strong autonomy. Its independent-minded leader, Mintimer Shaimiyev, is now among staunch supporters of Russian federalism.</p>
<p>Lebed says northern Chehcnya and some central areas where Zavgayev is strong have never been under separatist control and that Yandarbiyev will have to make a deal with the pro-Moscow north to maintain peace.</p>
<p>Whatever lies ahead, the current power setup in Chechnya resembles the one in December 1994 when Yeltsin sent troops in.</p>
<p>&quot;When they sent us here, they said we have to free Chechnya of the separatists who defy Moscow's orders and whom many people in the region detest,&quot; an angry paratroop officer told Russian Television.</p>
<p>&quot;We are leaving behind the same separatists who defy Moscow and who, they say, are detested by many here,&quot; he added. &quot;I only ask why were we here, why have tens of thousands of people died?&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
