<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43568" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Sept 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Sept 10.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Croatian newspapers on Tuesday.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- Croatia and Yugoslavia establish full diplomatic relations.</p>
<p>- I have saved the state and family budgets, says in an interview the Education and Sports minister, Ljilja Vokic commenting on the fact that books are now free for all primary school pupils.</p>
<p>- We would like to see a third of the positions awarded to us apart from religious and cultural rights, says Jozo Leutar, heading the Croatian Democratic Union of Bosnia-Herzegovina (HDZ BiH) party slate.</p>
<p>- Will AID, the Bosnian Moslem secret police endanger the integration of Bosnia? A commentary by Alenko Zornija.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- Government changes terms of loans for winter sowings, estimated to require some 800 million kuna. Farmers already wondering what the purchase price of next year's wheat crop will be.</p>
<p>- PM Zlatko Matesa says current Finance and Economy Ministers not leaving office, although there may be a slight cabinet reshuffle by year end.</p>
<p>- Croatian cars crossing the Serbian border will have to pay 90 German marks insurance and leave their license plates behind.</p>
<p>- Agriculture Minister warns cattle breeders to ensure enough fodder so as to prevent a rise in meat prices. Croatia to ban maize exports.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- Pensions are to rise, said the Finance Minister Bozo Prka at yesterday's regular government's press conference. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
