<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="435717" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products - gas oil and fuel oil ease.</title>
<headline>Med oil products - gas oil and fuel oil ease.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mediterranean oil products were mixed on Wednesday, traders said.</p>
<p>Gas oil looked a touch softer with more material on offer. A trio of Russian gas oil deals were done all around fob high quotes +25 cents for March 19-21, 20-22 and 21-23 delivery.</p>
<p>&quot;We've certainly lost ground from the +$1.75 done last week,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Non-Russian 0.2 pct cargoes met limited interest and offers from two sellers of high fob quotes +$4, from the +$3-3.50 heard yesterday. Diesel saw at least two cargoes looking for homes with prices talked unchanged at high cif EN590 quotes -50 cents.</p>
<p>Better availability of low sulphur fuel oil cargoes pushed prices down in the Med by some $3. Offers of $102 cif were heard for reasonably prompt delivery.</p>
<p>&quot;The physical is still drifting down,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Data showing Italian utility Enel used 21.5 percent less low sulphur fuel oil in February than in the previous year and forecasts it would cut fuel oil purchases by some 13 percent this year cast a bearish tinge on the market.</p>
<p>High sulphur fuel oil cargoes continued to flood out of the Med towards higher prices in the Far East. Portugal and Malta announced buying tenders.</p>
<p>But traders said there were still ample high sulphur supplies and prices were stable.</p>
<p>Gasoline was fairly steady as lack of demand was balanced out by lower supply due to refinery turnarounds in the region.</p>
<p>An Italian buyer reported he had picked up a northern cargo at quotes cif lo cif -$1 basis Naples at the start of the week, but that his requirements were now balanced for March.</p>
<p>Naphtha was still deemed as tight with traders assessing bids and offers at $193/$197 cif Med.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom, +44 171 542 7714.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
