<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="435773" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Sports News - Mar 13.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Sports News - Mar 13.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Australian cricket player Steve Waugh does not believe the South African team will defeat the Australians in the current test series being played in South Africa. Australia won its eighth consecutive game in defeating an Eastern Province Invitation XI in a limited overs match in Zwide. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>One Super League club has been investigated for breaking player anti-tampering rules. A fine of up to $500,000 may be imposed if the club is found to have a case to answer by Super League chief executive John Ribot. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A 200 metre breast-stroke world record by Adelaide's Ryan Mitchell, set at the national short-course championships in December 1996, has been challenged by the International Swimming Federation (FINA). FINA claims the swim did not meet official criteria. Page 18.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Australian tennis player Mark Philippoussis yesterday defeated former Wimbledon champion Andre Agassi 7-6 (7-5) 7-6 (7-5), in the first round of the Champions Cup tournament held in Indian Wells, Los Angeles. The tournament carries over $A2.93 million inprize money. Page 48.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A floating weed in the Sydney International Regatta Course in Penrith, New South Wales is threatening the staging of events leading up to the 2000 Olympic Games. National rowing selection trials were disrupted last week due to build-up of the weed. Page 7.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Leading Australian surf champions will compete together in a new competition this year. Ironmen and women from the two rival competitions and overseas athletes have been contracted for the World Oceanman series. Page 47.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>The Melbourne Cricket Ground Trust will support construction of a proposed Victoria Stadium at the Dockyards despite a possible loss of millions of dollars in lost revenue with the development of a new stadium. The Australian Football League also indicated that the Waverley Park ground would not necessarily be demolished. Page B8.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Two Australian Football League players last night were the first players to be fined a percentage of their annual earnings after minor misdemeanours from games last weekend. The new system aims to make financial penalties from the AFL tribunal more equitable. Page B8.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The final round of the St George triathlon grand prix will be relocated due to dangerous surf conditions caused by tropical cyclone Justin. The triathlon was to have been held at Surfers Paradise this weekend. Page B6.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE HERALD SUN</p>
<p>Australian swimmer Susie O'Neill will not compete in the 200 metre freestyle event at the Pan-Pac trials in Adelaide this week because she believes that teenager Natasha Bowron may defeat her. Page 73.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Former England cricket captain Graham Gooch believes the current England cricket side does not have a sufficient bowling attack and may find it difficult to bowl Australia out. Gooch believes Australia is the world's strongest cricket side. Page 78.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian basketball player Shane Heal has been given permission by his American team, the Minnesota Timberwolves, to play for Australia against the Croatian national team and the Oceania qualifying series against New Zealand. However, this is dependent on the success of the Timberwolves in the National Basketball Association playoffs. Page 73.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>Former Super League player Jack Elsegood will make a decision on his playing future today as he considers an offer from the Australian Rugby League club, Sydney City. Elsegood was banned from playing in the Super League premiership after a Supreme Court njunction last month. Page 88.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian sprinter Dean Capobianco will defend himself against positive drug test allegations by the International Amateur Athletics Federation this weekend in Monte Carlo. He faces a four year ban from athletic competition if found guilty of taking th anabolic steroid Stanozolol in May 1996. Page 87.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian sprinter Melinda Gainsford-Taylor has returned to Australia after being disqualified at the world indoor athletics championships in Paris for running outside her lane. She considers her disqualification only a minor setback and will be concentating on outdoor events in the future. Page 83.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
