<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="435842" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African opposition praise for Manuel budget.</title>
<headline>S.African opposition praise for Manuel budget.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African opposition parties offered cautious praise to Finance Minister Trevor Manuel on his maiden budget on Wednesday, but said it might hit the middle classes.</p>
<p>The white-led National Party (NP) and the white separatist Freedom Front said the budget, which offered tax relief mainly to people earning less than 60,000 rand a year, penalised better-off sections of the population.</p>
<p>The tax burden on individuals would increase considerably as a result of insufficient compensation for fiscal drag while the burden of direct taxation shifted to middle and higher income earners, the NP said in a statement.</p>
<p>Many individuals would also be hit hard by the sharp increase in tax on company cars while farmers would be squeezed by the abrupt abolition of the diesel refund system.</p>
<p>&quot;The budget demonstrates a shocking insensitivity towards individuals in the middle and higher income groups,&quot; the NP said.</p>
<p>The Freedom Front also criticised the lack of investment spending by government.</p>
<p>&quot;It is evident that the government's capital expenditure as percentage of GDP will decrease from 8.3 percent to seven percent. This figure should rise and not decline...It simply means that government dissaves and makes no contribution to economic growth,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Gavin Woods, chief finance spokesman for Mangosuthu Buthelezi's Inkatha Freedom Party, said: &quot;At first glance it is a welcome budget, very appropriate.</p>
<p>&quot;The minister has done well in a number of important regards including the consistency between policy and the actual budget...tax relief for the people who needed it most,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Woods said, however, Manuel had not gone far enough to entrench the macroeconomic strategy published last June.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a good budget. It's going to make most South Africans feel happy. The disappointment is not about direction but about degree,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ken Andrew, finance spokesman for the liberal Democratic Party, said &quot;there are many good aspects, but there are stings in the tail&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I am concerned that it does not do sufficient to encourage growth. There is no encouragement for savings and the reduction in capital expenditure by 17 percent in real terms is really problematic,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Stanley Mogoba, new leader of the Pan Africanist Congress, said it was time to bite the bullet and implement tougher measures to close the gap between the rich and poor.</p>
<p>&quot;On the whole it was a good budget and a real effort to deal with the problems. But we need to do more in the areas of housing and crime prevention,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Labour Minister Tito Mboweni, who is also the head of policy for the ruling African National Congress, told Reuters that Manuel's budget, the first by an ANC minister, should prove to investors abroad that the government was serious about fiscal discipline.</p>
<p>&quot;People were saying we could not deliver on the goals of the macroeconomic framework. Well, here it is,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Parliamentary newsroom +27-21-403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
