<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="435813" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria lays treason charges on Soyinka, 11 others.</title>
<headline>Nigeria lays treason charges on Soyinka, 11 others.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria's military government on Wednesday charged exiled Nobel laureate Wole Soyinka and 11 others with the capital offence of treason over recent bomb blasts in the country.</p>
<p>Court officials said some of the charged were leaders of the opposition in exile but that those in the country were brought to court.</p>
<p>They said Magistrate E.A. Lufadeju adjourned the case to May 9.</p>
<p>The accused face a two-count charge of &quot;conspiracy to levy war against the federal military government of Nigeria&quot; and &quot;causing explosions in various parts of Nigeria.&quot;</p>
<p>The charge sheet listed among those charged as Anthony Enahoro, the leader of NADECO-Abroad, the exiled wing of the opposition group NADECO and Frederick Fasehun, president of the Campaign for Democracy pressure group as well as former finance minister Olu Falae.</p>
<p>The last two have been detained since December after a spate of bomb explosions hit army buses, killing at least three soldiers and wounding several dozens.</p>
<p>The plea they entered in court was not immediately known.</p>
<p>Court officials said they were been defended by radical opposition lawyer Gani Fawehinmi, who was recently released from detention.</p>
<p>Nigeria has been in crisis since 1993 when the army annulled an election to restore democracy. Soyinka and some of those charged with him have campaigned to have the poll recognised as legitimate and the winner installed president.</p>
<p>Soyinka fled Nigeria more than two years ago to Europe and the United States, where he has campaigned against the military government of General Sani Abacha.</p>
<p>NADECO's local wing has denied having any hand in the bomb explosions and while Soyinka has also denied any involvement he refused in an interview with BBC radio to condemn the bombings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
