<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="435838" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenya's central bank launches floating-rate bonds.</title>
<headline>Kenya's central bank launches floating-rate bonds.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Central Bank of Kenya on Tuesday launched a five billion shillings ($92.59 million) issue of one-year floating-rate treasury bonds, a measure aimed at restructuring government debt from short-term to medium-term.</p>
<p>Bank officials said the bonds, priced at par, would offer a floating coupon 0.25 percentage point above the main 91-day treasury bill.</p>
<p>&quot;Over 68 percent of Kenya's domestic debt is short-term with a maturity of less than three months, which has put undue pressure on the exchequer in terms of payments for redemptions,&quot; Finance Minister Musalia Mudavadi told a news conference.</p>
<p>This issue is the second of floating-rate bonds. The first issue, in January, aimed to raise five billion shillings but was seriously undersubscribed with only 63 offers totalling 17.61 million shillings.</p>
<p>The new issue, unlike the first, can be traded on the Nairobi Stock Exchange. The bonds will be the second debt instrument traded on the exchange, following listing of East African Development Bank corporate bonds.</p>
<p>The new government bonds mature on April 4, 1997. There will be further issues each quarter from now on -- April 4, July 1, October 1 and January 1. ($=54 shillings)</p>
<p>--Wambui Chege, Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
