<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43595" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Banco de Mexico reserves, assets rise.</title>
<headline>Banco de Mexico reserves, assets rise.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Banco de Mexico said Tuesday its net international assets as of September 6, 1996, were $3.851 billion, compared with $3.701 billion on August 30. The central bank said that its net international reserves as of September 6 were $15.528 billion, compared with $15.444 billion as of August 30.  </p>
<p>It said the increase of $150 million in international assets was due to:</p>
<p>- Revenues from operations with state oil firm Petroleos Mexicanos (Pemex) worth $166 million</p>
<p>- Foreign exchange outgoings from other operations worth a net $11 million.</p>
<p>- A net sale of currency to the federal government worth $5 million to cover external debt service.</p>
<p>Banco de Mexico said the monetary base shrank by 1.625 billion pesos due to lower demand for notes and coins following last week's payment of fortnightly salaries.</p>
<p>The balance of the federal government's current account at the central bank rose by 3.088 billion pesos, mainly as the result of tax collection.</p>
<p>The central bank said it compensated for the monetary contraction caused by the increase in the government's current account balance by increasing credit to financial institutions by 801 million pesos.</p>
<p>The following tables detail Banco de Mexico's assets and net domestic credit. All figures are in billions of pesos, unless otherwise indicated.</p>
<p>				Sept 6	 Aug 30</p>
<p>Monetary Base	     59.359	 60.984</p>
<p>International Assets</p>
<p>   Pesos		    29.176	 28.061</p>
<p>   U.S. Dlrs (blns)	3.851	  3.701</p>
<p>Net Domestic Credit     30.183	 32.923</p>
<p>*Net International Assets are defined as gross international assets minus central bank liabilities with the IMF and assets of less than a six month duration from other central banks.</p>
<p>--Mexico City newsroom (525) 728-9559</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
