<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="436107" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuela TEM demand been higher than supply - Casas.</title>
<headline>Venezuela TEM demand been higher than supply - Casas.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Demand for Venezuelan Central Bank short term securities, called TEMs, has been higher than the supply, which has helped push down interest rates, Central Bank president Antonio Casas Gonzalez said.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't been able to offer more...due to the losses they bring the Central Bank,&quot; Casas told the Senate Finance Commission.</p>
<p>TEMs are issued by the Central Bank in open market operations and, unlike most countries where government backed Treasury bills are used, are financed by the Central Bank.  </p>
<p>Yields on six month TEMs, which act as a benchmark for wider interest rates, fell two basis points in Wednesday's regular auction to 14.33 percent on high bolivar liquidity, TEM traders said.</p>
<p>Casas added that last week's uncharacteristic volatility of the bolivar had in part been due to low interest rates, &quot;but also the general economic panorama.&quot;</p>
<p>Last week was marked by persistent rumors of coups, President Rafael Caldera's failing health and investor concern about rising inflation on the back of a 75 percent average public pay wage increase.</p>
<p>But Casas re-iterated the current foreign exchange bands system would not be changed.</p>
<p>&quot;We think they proved successful in 1996 and also in the first months of this year,&quot; he said. &quot;We'll keep the bands as they have been established.&quot;</p>
<p>((-- John Paul Rathbone, Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
