<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="436375" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Other Philippine sugar mills also suffering-govt.</title>
<headline>Other Philippine sugar mills also suffering-govt.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cash-strapped Victorias Milling Co is not the only Philippine sugar mill facing financial problems, but its woes are the most acute, Sugar Regulatory Administration (SRA) chief Wilson Gamboa said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;A few sugar centrals are also suffering (financial difficulties) but not in the degree and acuteness of Victorias,&quot; Gamboa said in an interview with reporters. He did not identify the other mills.</p>
<p>Officials of the Philippine Sugar Millers Association could not immediately be reached for comment on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Traders said there are at least 33 sugar mills operating in the country.</p>
<p>Victorias, the Philippines largest sugar miller, sought a debt moratorium on the principal payment of its $168 million debt last week due to a cash flow problem, which it said was caused by the steep drop in local sugar prices.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe it (Victorias) will survive its present predicament which is just temporary,&quot; Gamboa said, adding the firm has high sugar stocks inventory and an efficient infrastructure.</p>
<p>In a letter to the House of Representatives, Gamboa said the industry has to undertake wrenching reforms to meet increasing competition.</p>
<p>The Philippine sugar industry is &quot;characterised by obsolence, antiquated farm practices, and the habits of its players that resist or cannot even seem to adopt to the inevitability of change,&quot; Gamboa said in his letter dated February 18, a copy of which was released to reporters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Because of our inefficiency and high production cost, liberalised importation came as a relief to the domestic market but destructive to the industry,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sugar used to be the country's largest export.</p>
<p>Gamboa said there is still hope for the sector. &quot;Provided it reconciles with reality, the sugar industry is a sunshine industry...with domestic consumption growing cumulatively at four percent annually,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Manila newsroom (632) 841-89-36, fax 817-62-67</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100136">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
