<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="436335" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Nobody's perfect, says bulk-fighting Miss Universe.</title>
<headline>Nobody's perfect, says bulk-fighting Miss Universe.</headline>
<byline>Nick Edwards</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nobody's perfect, not even internation beauty queens, said reigning Miss Universe Alicia Machado, who has been hounded by the media as much for her increasing bulk as for her beauty.</p>
<p>&quot;No person in the world is perfect. Everybody in the world has some defects,&quot; she told Reuters in an interview on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Machado, who was crowned Miss Universe last May, acknowledged in September that she had gained about five kg (11 lbs).</p>
<p>Pageant organisers dubbed her &quot;the eating machine&quot; for her expanding waistline, and breakfast cereal maker Kellogg Co. took her image off boxes of its low-fat cereal Special K.</p>
<p>Throughout her 10-month reign as a goodwill ambassador for her native Venezuela and one of the world's most beautiful women, Machado has been forced to fight off incessant media queries about her appearance.</p>
<p>But Machado harbors no bitterness against the media despite her ordeal and dismisses suggestions that she has a weight &quot;problem&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;With weight or no weight, I am me,&quot; she told Reuters as she arrived in Singapore to visit contestants in the Miss Universe Singapore pageant, due to be decided on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I gained weight, about eight or nine kilos, but I'm 20 years old and I can take off the weight when I want. It's no problem,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>In fact, the aspiring actress said all the extra attention may turn out to be a boon for her career, keeping her in the media spotlight throughout her one-year reign.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been great and I have many, many opportunities (for TV shows and movies).&quot;</p>
<p>But the experience also has helped her gain an appreciation for the pressures women face to keep their figures, pressure which she said drives some to literally starve themselves to death for fear of getting fat.</p>
<p>&quot;Many, many ladies died from being anorexic last year. This is ridiculous,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
