<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="436539" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Republican-led House asks for new Clinton budget.</title>
<headline>Republican-led House asks for new Clinton budget.</headline>
<byline>Jackie Frank</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Republican-controlled House Wednesday called on President Clinton to send up a new balanced budget, a move Democrats charged was a ploy to divert attention from the slow pace of budget talks.</p>
<p>Voting closely on party lines, the House approved the non-binding resolution 231 to 197. It tells the president to resubmit his fiscal 1998 budget with changes Republicans said are necessary to bring the deficit down to zero by 2002.</p>
<p>The resolution does not force the president to act and has not been scheduled for action in the Senate.</p>
<p>Top administration officials said this week they have no intention of drafting a new budget and insisted their current proposal not only balances the budget but in 2002 will result in the first budget surplus in 32 years.</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry said that Congress and the administration were getting into serious budget issues.</p>
<p>&quot;There's some more active dialogue back and forth and people are beginning to try to shape the outcome of deliberations on the budget ... It's less sharp in tone than has occurred in the past,&quot; he said at the regular press briefing.</p>
<p>Although no formal talks have been held, administration and congressional staff members have discussed policy changes necessary to bring the deficit under control, Republican sources said.</p>
<p>House Budget Committee Chairman John Kasich, Republican of Ohio, acknowledged to the full House that such talks were taking place.</p>
<p>However, Congress is unlikely to meet its own deadline for passage of a budget by April 15. House Majority Leader Dick Armey said it will probably happen in May. Rarely has Congress approved a budget on time and the delay have provided fodder for political battles over the years.</p>
<p>Texas Representative Charles Stenholm, a leader of a conservative Democratic group known as the &quot;Blue Dogs,&quot; was one of several in his party who argued on the House floor that the day's debate was &quot;meaningless.&quot;</p>
<p>Countering the charges, Republican Mike Parker of Mississippi said it was designed to send a message to the president that his budget will have to use the same conservative assumptions of economic growth as Republicans must use in coming up with the plan that will ultimately face the full House.</p>
<p>The arcane difference in estimating how well the economy will perform five years out has major political impact this year. Republicans, who have virtually locked themselves into using the less optimistic congressional forecasts, will be forced to come up with deeper spending cuts and higher taxes if their budget is to balance.</p>
<p>So far they have resisted calls to produce their own plan for spending cuts and taxes.</p>
<p>&quot;Isn't it ironic, the majority party is demanding the president submit a second budget when they haven't yet submitted any budget,&quot; Democrat Lynn Woolsey of California commented during the debate.</p>
<p>Kasich said it was necessary for both sides to use the same arithmetic to produce their plans. Republicans charged that Clinton's plan also puts off most spending cuts until he is out of office. But the White House countered that the policy changes would be enacted during Clinton's tenure, but take time to show results.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
