<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="436735" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US House Leader Armey proposes 17 percent flat tax.</title>
<headline>US House Leader Armey proposes 17 percent flat tax.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>House Majority Leader Dick Armey on Wednesday proposed a flat income tax that would start at 20 percent in the first two years and then drop to 17 percent afterward.</p>
<p>Armey said the revenue cut for the first year would amount to about $30 billion. The Texas Republican, who has introduced legislation for a flat tax in the last two sessions of Congress, said: &quot;I intend to champion this.&quot;</p>
<p>The legislation, co-sponsored by Sen. Richard Shelby, an Alabama Republican, will be introduced in both chambers under the number for the current income tax form -- 1040.  </p>
<p>Under the proposal, individuals and businesses would pay the same rate and all deductions and credits would be eliminated.</p>
<p>Spending caps and expectations for higher economic growth due to the flat tax would allow the budget to reach balance by 2002, a summary of the proposal said.</p>
<p>The plan would allow a personal exemption from the income tax of $33,800 for a family of four, $23,200 for a couple and $11,600 for a single person.</p>
<p>Currently, the highest income tax rate is 39.6 percent and the lowest is 15 percent, an aide to Armey said.  </p>
<p>The 17 percent flat tax would not amount to an across-the-board increase for the people at the low end of the current income tax scale because they would be eligible for larger personal exemptions from the tax, the aide said.</p>
<p>All business income would be taxed at one rate, and no deductions would be permitted for fringe benefits, interest or payments to owners, a summary of the proposal said.</p>
<p>The bill would also sunset every federal program except entitlements such as Social Security, Medicare, veterans' benefits and federal retirement to force Congress to reexamine the programs, the proposal summary said.  </p>
<p>Rep. Bill Archer, the chairman of the House Ways and Means Committee, where tax legislation originates, &quot;welcomes the majority leader's initiative&quot; on the flat tax, a spokesman for Archer said. But Archer, a Texas Republican, &quot;differs with Mr. Armey on the exact solution,&quot; the spokesman added.</p>
<p>Armey said he could not predict what the size of the overall tax cut would be that Republicans want to enact this year, in the context of balancing the budget.</p>
<p>&quot;I know that as we work this out we will have a tax component, it will be significant,&quot; Armey said.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a balanced budget and a significant tax reduction, what the exact numbers are I can't project,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
