<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="436747" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Edison cuts its annual hydropower forecast.</title>
<headline>Edison cuts its annual hydropower forecast.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southern California Edison Co trimmed its preliminary forecast for hydropower output this year to around 5,600 gigawatt hour (GWh) after a dry February, the company's chief hydrologist said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Based on early-February runoff forecasts, Edison estimated hydropower output as high as 6,500 GWh this year, compared with a long-term average of 4,700 to 4,800 GWh.</p>
<p>In 1996, Edison produced around 5,800 GWh of hydropower.</p>
<p>Tuesday, the California Department of Water Resources released an early-March forecast for April-July runoff on the San Joaquin River of 145 percent of normal levels, compared with an early-February estimate of 180 percent.</p>
<p>Most of Edison's hydro projects are on the San Joaquin, in the central and southern Sierra mountains.</p>
<p>Statewide April-July runoff was forecast at 115 percent of normal, while runoff for the entire water year (Oct 1, 1996-Sep 30, 1997) was assessed at 170 percent.</p>
<p>The discrepancy was attributed to the severe rainstorms which hit California in early January.</p>
<p>&quot;This year the timing (of runoff) was thrown off by the warm rains that melted some snow,&quot; the Edison hydrologist noted.</p>
<p>Early indications are that March will also be a dry month for California, although conditions can always shift, he cautioned.</p>
<p>April 1 is seen as the peak date for measuring snowpack and assessing spring runoff volumes.</p>
<p>--D Beasley, Los Angeles bureau + 1 213 955 6761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1610107">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
