<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="436855" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Boeing confident of EU merger approval.</title>
<headline>Boeing confident of EU merger approval.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Busvine</byline>
<dateline>COLOGNE, Germany 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Boeing Corp head Phil Condit said on Wednesday he was confident European Union regulators would eventually approve his company's $50 billion merger with McDonnell-Douglas .</p>
<p>The Boeing president and chief executive, who met EU competition commissioner Karel van Miert in Brussels on Tuesday, described their talks as &quot;good&quot; and said he expected Brussels to reach a favourable conclusion after a months-long review of the merger.</p>
<p>&quot;It was one of those meetings where I stated where I was coming from, and he described to me the process that they would go through -- and that of course is a complete review,&quot; Condit told a news conference during an economic conference here.</p>
<p>&quot;That is of course exactly what we expected,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Asked whether he expected the review to come out in favour of the merger Condit said: &quot;That's exactly right.&quot;</p>
<p>Van Miert is expected to announce next week that the Commission would extend its initial one-month investigation into the competitive impact of the U.S. merger on the European aircraft industry.</p>
<p>Concerns over the impact of the merger -- which would create a company controlling around three-fifths of the world passenger aircraft market -- have been expressed by some members of Europe's competing Airbus consortium.</p>
<p>Airbus, the world's second largest civil aircraft maker, joins together France's Aerospatiale , British Aerospace , Germany's Daimler-Benz Aerospace AG and CASA of Spain.</p>
<p>Wednesday's Financial Times, however, quoted Van Miert as saying that problems with the Boeing merger &quot;still remain&quot;.</p>
<p>The Commission is expected to start an in-depth probe into the alliance by March 19, when it concludes its preliminary one-month investigation.</p>
<p>Condit, speaking in Brussels on Tuesday, shrugged off those concerns, saying the world market was already dominated by Boeing and Airbus. McDonnell-Douglas, with a market share of three percent in passenger jets was &quot;not a significant player&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of changes in market share this (deal) does almost nothing. Best estimates, I think by both Airbus and ourselves, are that neither of our market share changes all that much,&quot; Condit said.</p>
<p>Boeing has said it is expecting to clear all regulatory hurdles on both sides of the Atlantic by July. The alliance announced in December was also filed with the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.</p>
<p>Boeing has scrapped plans to build a super-large passenger jet, while Airbus is seeking partners to develop its planned $8 billion, 550-seater A3XX aircraft. Condit said, however, he would be interested in principle in working on such a project with Airbus -- if it looked viable.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether it's practicable, is there a market for it, can you make a good financial business plan -- those are issues that obviously would have to be looked at before we make that into a reality,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>One leading U.S. airline executive attending the conference said he believed such an aircraft would only have a limited application.</p>
<p>Gordon Bethune, chairman and chief executive of Continental Airlines Inc, said that with business class passengers subsidising seats in economy class, it would be hard to make operating a big aircraft carrying more budget travellers profitable.</p>
<p>In addition, smaller planes travelling at high speed on long-haul routes would tend to take away executive travellers from slower super-jumbo aircraft.</p>
<p>Development costs, he said, would be &quot;astronomically high&quot; and returns minimal. &quot;Only if you have the government behind you and it's not your money would you build such a plane.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOGNE, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
