<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="436871" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German trade opens with push to get online.</title>
<headline>German trade opens with push to get online.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>HANOVER, Germany 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Throwing open the doors to the world's largest information technology fair, politicians and industry leaders on Wednesday urged German businesses to think globally and act locally to usher in the information society.</p>
<p>With fewer than three percent of mid-sized companies hooked up to the global Internet, Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt warned that German businesses risked becoming isolated in a world economy that was becoming ever more intertwined.</p>
<p>Mired in its worst jobs crisis since the end of World War Two, promoting new technology and services has become a key plank in the government's economic policies.</p>
<p>&quot;We must actively shape Germany's transition from the industrial age into the information age. Jobs and prosperity for future generations depend on setting the right course now,&quot; said Rexrodt at the opening ceremonies for the CeBIT technology fair in Hanover.</p>
<p>Many Germans were frightened of the changes brought about by the rapid expansion of new technologies, which he said could lead to a divide of information haves and have-nots, but warned that no one could ignore the changes taking place.</p>
<p>&quot;Whoever drops out of the network of globalisation will not save what they have, but will lose and fall behind,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>This was also reflected in statements during the day by leading executives from the telecommunications, computer and electronics industries.</p>
<p>&quot;If Germany wants to play a leading role technologically in the future we need a responsible and simultaneously open attitude towards new technologies,&quot; said Josef Brauner, head of the German subsidiary of consumer electronics giant Sony.</p>
<p>More than 650,000 computer freaks and entrepreneurs are set to descend on the CeBIT trade fair over the next six days where over 6,800 exhibitors are displaying high-tech gadgets that offer a peek at life on the Infobahn.</p>
<p>Twenty-three huge halls provide 352,623 square metres of exhibition space packed with whirring virtual reality machines, the latest high-speed digital telecommunications and wide-eyed young businesses betting on this brave new world.</p>
<p>Steve Case, the head of America Online, which boasts nearly eight million subscribers, said the popularity of on-line services in the United States was drawing couch potatoes away from television to explore cyberspace.</p>
<p>&quot;We really do believe that this is a new medium that will be as important as the television or even telephones,&quot; he told a news conference ahead of the fair opening.</p>
<p>With Europe less than a year from the full deregulation of its telecommunications markets, new phone companies were using the trade fair as a platform to urge further steps to promote competition against for state monopolies.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the last CeBIT that will take place in the era of monopolies,&quot; said Peter Mihatsch, board member of industry and technology group Mannesmann AG, which is quickly becoming the main challenger to Deutsche Telekom AG.</p>
<p>The Internet was also making it possible for once far-away countries to compete with the leading industrial nations in key services such as the development of software with programmers who work for much lower wages than in the U.S. or Europe.</p>
<p>Beni Prasad Verma, Indian communications minister, said in a speech at the CeBIT opening that his country had added more than six million phone lines over the past four years and was wiring all provincial governments to the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;India is quickly becoming a software paradise,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year 104 of the Fortune 500 companies filled their software requirements by subcontracting work to India and in the current year the Indian software industry will probably achieve sales of $2 billion.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOVER, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
