<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="436915" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German SPD official believes EMU will come on time.</title>
<headline>German SPD official believes EMU will come on time.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The parliamentary leader of Germany's opposition Social Democrats, Rudolf Scharping, said on Wednesday he believed Germany would qualify for European monetary union (EMU) and that it would come about on schedule.</p>
<p>But Scharping said at a lunch for foreign journalists that a great deal of work still had to be done to convince sceptical Germans of the &quot;supreme importance of monetary union&quot;.</p>
<p>The SPD flirted briefly with a more critical line on the planned single currency last year but has since committed itself firmly to EMU.</p>
<p>Even now, Lower Saxony state premier Gerhard Schroeder, a possible chancellery candidate for the SPD in the October 1998 general election, argues that it would be better to postpone EMU than have a weak single currency, keeping alive speculation that the SPD might run an anti-euro election campaign.</p>
<p>Scharping said he believed Germany would fulfil the economic criteria to qualify for monetary union and that it was pointless to start speculating now that it might not.</p>
<p>&quot;I would urge that we should not have a debate now about the criteria or the timeframe, but that we should look at the situation in the autumn or the winter and then introduce the common currency, with a view to stability, on January 1, 1999.&quot;</p>
<p>Scharping said it was important to realise that the creation of a single currency was important to give the European Union greater weight to resist currency market fluctuations, stemming from the dollar or the yen, which cost Germany jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;To delay the project would destroy the project of monetary union and bring unforeseen political and economic risks,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps we should ask what all the disadvantages will be if the euro does not come about,&quot; he said. &quot;The risks are much greater if it does not happen.&quot;</p>
<p>But he also said that the stability of the single currency could only be guaranteed by coordinating economic policies, and not merely by coordinating fiscal policies.</p>
<p>-- Kevin Liffey, Bonn newsroom +49-228-26097160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
