<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="436916" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Analysts see Hoechst credibility damaged over HMR.</title>
<headline>Analysts see Hoechst credibility damaged over HMR.</headline>
<byline>Svea Herbst-Bayliss</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>German drugs and chemicals group Hoechst AG fell from grace on Wednesday as analysts downgraded recommendations for the group following poorer than expected results and news its drugs unit would not be floated.</p>
<p>Investors made clear their disappointment with a company that had become a particular favourite since a new chairman launched a massive restructuring effort three years ago, letting its shares fall as much as 12 percent in bourse trade.</p>
<p>&quot;It simply hailed bad news at Hoechst today,&quot; said Deutsche Morgan Grenfell analyst Katharina Uhlenbrock.</p>
<p>The bad news was effectively divided into worse than expected results -- which had already sent shares plunging five percent on Tuesday -- and disappointment about the fact Hoechst would keep its drugs business in the parent group.</p>
<p>&quot;Its the listing news that did it,&quot; one analyst said after being briefed on results by the company.</p>
<p>Hoechst chairman Juergen Dormann, one of Germany's biggest proponents of shareholder value, had helped drive the share price higher over the last twelve months amid suggestions, however vague, that the drugs unit would be floated.</p>
<p>Since December however, when Hoechst managed to move its struggling speciality chemicals unit into a joint venture with Swiss group Clariant AG, industry sources had hinted that plans for the HMR flotation had changed.</p>
<p>As Hoechst showed it could effectively sell off the other parts, leaving itself as a purer life sciences group, including drugs and the agricultural business, the need to rush HMR to market had disappeared.</p>
<p>While analysts said they had begun suspecting the shift in thinking, several had predicted a very negative market reaction once Hoechst actually announced the step.</p>
<p>&quot;This came as the ultimate sledgehammer,&quot; exclaimed one dealer with another adding that Hoechst's decision to shelve the plans &quot;came as a complete slap in the face,&quot; given that the markets had been so convinced the step would take place.</p>
<p>Although Dormann stressed the step did not signal a change in strategy and that the situation would pick up soon, his words offered little relief to battered shares.</p>
<p>For analysts the package of news prompted a serious review with Deutsche Morgan Grenfell already downgrading its recommendation to neutral from overweight.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook is really not that great and I think we will be seeing a lot of reductions in forecasts,&quot; said Tony Cox, analyst at Dresdner Kleinwort Benson in London.</p>
<p>Gone now are the heady days of last November when news Hoechst planned to list its shares on the New York bourse managed to completely overshadow a weak operating performance. &quot;There was nothing to deflect attention from the bad news today,&quot; said Ronald Koehler, analyst at BHF Bank in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Dormann assured a news conference that it made more sense to keep the drugs business within the group so that Hoechst would be very flexible, able to to seize opportunities, including possible mergers and takeovers. But analysts were not convinced.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be very hard for the company to keep share market speculation alive,&quot; Koehler added.</p>
<p>More importantly, analysts and traders said Hoechst had seriously damaged its credibility. Surprised by a fourth quarter loss of 383 million marks ($224 million), Deutsche's Uhlenbrock said &quot;losses don't occur overnight,&quot; and added, &quot;these numbers signal a real loss of face for Hoechst.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said they could see the share falling as low as 65 marks in coming days even though the 68 level had strong support today.</p>
<p>At a news conference, broad irritation became palpable as journalists repeatedly demanded to know how Hoechst executives were able to sound an optimistic note late last year and then be report losses in the next weeks.</p>
<p>Hoechst officials sought to put the best spin on events, saying all steps were being taken to improve the situation and that the share price would surely rise soon.</p>
<p>($ = 1.707 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
