<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="437197" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian, Pakistani prime ministers to meet in Male.</title>
<headline>Indian, Pakistani prime ministers to meet in Male.</headline>
<byline>Jawed Naqvi</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda will meet his Pakistani counterpart, Nawaz Sharif, on the sidelines of a regional summit in May, Foreign Minister Inder Kumar Gujral said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Gujral said the two prime ministers would meet during a summit meeting of the South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation (SAARC) in the Maldives.</p>
<p>Gujral told reporters the two nations' foreign secretaries were set to meet in New Delhi at the end of March, and that he expected to meet Pakistani Foreign Minister Gohar Ayub Khan on the sidelines of a meeting of the foreign ministers of the Non-Aligned Movement in April.</p>
<p>The foreign secretaries' meeting from March 28 to 31 would mark the resumption of bilateral peace talks which broke off in January 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;I am expecting his excellency, the foreign minister of Pakistan, to be with us at the time of the Non-Aligned meeting and that we will seek the opportunity to sit together,&quot; Gujral said.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime ministers will also be meeting in Male at the time of the SAARC summit,&quot; Gujral said.</p>
<p>A Pakistan Foreign Ministry spokesman said it was premature to say the two prime ministers would have bilateral talks in Male. He said Pakistan had not yet received a formal invitation from the Maldives to attend the South Asian summit.</p>
<p>Despite the breakdown in the official talks, Indian and Pakistani leaders have been meeting on the sidelines of international conferences.</p>
<p>Pakistani President Farooq Khan Leghari met then prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao during the SAARC summit in New Delhi in May 1995 when they discussed but failed to make any headway on their dispute over Kashmir.</p>
<p>&quot;The foreign secretaries' meeting will be the first focused effort to actually resume the stalled talks,&quot; an Indian official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Leghari had opposed India's plans at that time to hold elections in the Himalayan state of Jammu and Kashmir, but New Delhi went ahead with the polls any way.</p>
<p>Two-thirds of Kashmir is ruled by India and the rest by Pakistan. More than 20,000 people have died in Jammu and Kashmir since 1990 when simmering discontent against New Delhi's rule there turned into an amred insurrection.</p>
<p>The deadlock was broken after an exchange of conciliatory messages last month between Deve Gowda and the new Pakistani prime minister, whose nations have fought three wars, two of them Kashmir.</p>
<p>Gujral said earlier that India was prepared to discuss all outstanding issues with Pakistan but he declined on Wednesday to give details.</p>
<p>New Delhi regards all of Kashmir as an integral part of the Indian union.</p>
<p>But Islamabad, which denies New Delhi's charges of training and arming the rebels, wants the mainly Moslem Kashmiris to be allowed to vote in a U.N.-mandated plebiscite on whether to join Islamic Pakistan or Hindu-majority India.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALDR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
