<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="437150" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norway firms raise dividend despite lower earnings.</title>
<headline>Norway firms raise dividend despite lower earnings.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 20 largest companies listed on the Oslo bourse have proposed dividends for 1996 amounting to 6.7 billion crowns, 16 percent higher than in 1995 despite lower earnings, the financial daily Finansavisen said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The companies, which have a market capitalisation of around 250 billion crowns, together posted net profits in 1996 of 22.1 billion crowns, of which 6.727 billion crowns was proposed as dividends to shareholders.</p>
<p>&quot;That represents a pay out ratio of 30 percent,&quot; Finansavisen said.</p>
<p>For the 1995 period, the same companies paid out dividends of 5.794 billion crowns on total profits after tax of 25 billion crowns, to give a pay out ratio of 23 percent, the daily said.</p>
<p>But, Finansavisen said, the direct return -- measured as the relationship between dividend and share price -- on Norwegian shares has decreased between 1996 and 1997. If share prices increase at a faster rate than dividend, the direct return to investors is reduced.</p>
<p>&quot;Share prices rose on average by 30 percent on the Oslo bourse in 1996, and the total dividend of the largest companies increased by 16 percent, therefore the direct return to investors is lower,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on these figures, the direct return among the largest companies is now 2.7 percent against 3.1 percent in 1995.&quot;</p>
<p>The paper added that foreign -- especially British and American -- companies distributed around 50 percent of profits to shareholders.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore there is still a long way to go before critical Norwegian investors will be pleased with the level of Norwegian dividens,&quot; Finansavisen said.</p>
<p>--Oslo newsroom, +47 22 42 50 41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
