<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="437281" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Power from poultry dung to make its mark in Europe.</title>
<headline>Power from poultry dung to make its mark in Europe.</headline>
<byline>William Maclean</byline>
<dateline>EYE, England</dateline>
<text>
<p>It lacks the wholesome appeal of sun, sea and wind, but Simon Fraser's renewable energy business is starting to give off the sweet smell of success.</p>
<p>The British businessman's unusual power stations turn a foul-smelling agricultural menace -- poultry dung -- into electricity by a combustion process he says benefits both environment and balance sheet.</p>
<p>His Fibrowatt company plans to build a string of plants across Europe through local joint ventures to help satisfy the continent's growing appetite for clean, green power.</p>
<p>&quot;Wherever there's poultry, there's a great future,&quot; said Richard Parker, manager of a 12.7 MegaWatt (MW) power station fuelled by chicken and turkey dung at Eye, a village 120 km (75 miles) northeast of London.</p>
<p>&quot;We've had visitors from Ireland, eastern Europe, Thailand, India, everywhere, asking how we do it.&quot;</p>
<p>Fibrowatt is carrying out a 115 million pound ($243 million) expansion in Italy and plans further plants in France, Germany and Ireland. The Fibrowatt chairman and his minority U.S. partners are also targeting Asia, already the source of a steady stream of enquiries from like-minded entrepreneurs, and the United States.</p>
<p>The Eye plant, the world's first commercial electricity generating power station that burns poultry litter, makes enough power for 12,500 homes. It uses 130,000 tons of litter a year taken from 12.5 million chickens at 100 nearby broiler farms -- enough waste, Fibrowatt says, to cover 25 football fields to a height of seven feet.</p>
<p>Chicken litter is normally stored in the open air to be used in the ploughing season as manure. It causes a bad stench, the leaching of nitrates and other pollutants into the water supply, and damages the atmosphere by releasing methane.</p>
<p>&quot;We are almost immune from the 'Not In My Back Yard' syndrome -- certainly more immune than other types of renewable technology,&quot; said Rupert Fraser, managing director and Simon Fraser's son.</p>
<p>&quot;We are able to demonstrate to local communities that our plants are beneficial to the environment because they take away piles of manure from the roadside and reduce levels of noxious gases.&quot;</p>
<p>The company says its stations' emissions of carbon dioxide and equivalent &quot;greenhouse&quot; gasses are 25 percent of those produced by a similar-sized coal-fired plant. The process generates no waste products and instead produces commercially marketable ash fertiliser.</p>
<p>Fibrowatt also has a 13.5 megawatt plant at Glanford 180 km (110 miles) further north. Its third British plant, a 38.5 megawatt, 69 million pound ($111 million) project under contruction at Thetford, west of Eye, will be Europe's largest generator of electricity from biomass combustion.</p>
<p>U.S. firm Catamount Energy, a unit of Central Vermont Public Service Corp., has taken a 44 percent stake in the Thetford project which is expected to open by July 1998.</p>
<p>Foster Wheeler Energy Ltd, a unit of U.S. energy engineering giant Foster Wheeler Corp., has a 20 percent stake in Fibrowatt, a link-up analysts say has helped Fraser raise the total 116.5 million pounds ($188 million) to pay for its three British plants.</p>
<p>The power stations have long term contracts for litter supplies and subsidised electricity sales lasting for their financing periods under a government programme aimed at promoting renewable energy.</p>
<p>Fraser says that by the time the subsidies for Eye and Glanford are lifted in December 1998 they will be able to trade profitably by taking advantage of the deregulation of Britain's electricty market set to take place in April 1998.</p>
<p>Fibrowatt is banking on the likelihood that businesses will want to advertise they are using green energy and will pay more for its supply. Other European Union countries are expected to deregulate electricity markets in the next decade.</p>
<p>In Italy, Fibrowatt has been awarded electricity supply contracts for its three planned plants at Venice, Verona and Cesena under joint venture arrangements with state-owned utility Enel, and has signed contracts with 800 chicken farmers for the supply of litter.</p>
<p>Fibrowatt sees good opportunities in France because poultry farmers there are under pressure from water authorities to clean up nitrate pollution from droppings.</p>
<p>Biomass forms only a small part of the renewable energy programme in Britain and Fibrowatt acknowledges its plants are probably viable only in areas of high poultry production.</p>
<p>Fibrowatt has yet to rival wind and solar power for environmental correctness -- largely because its process relies on the product of intensive agriculture. But experts say the project is commendable because it diversifies the location of power production and uses up waste, a key aim of renewables.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EYE, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
