<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="437375" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Pro-European British MPs launch fight-back.</title>
<headline>Pro-European British MPs launch fight-back.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pro-European members of parliament launched a twin-pronged attack on their anti-European colleagues on Wednesday, warning that 3.5 million jobs could be at risk if Britain left the European Union.</p>
<p>The European Movement followed up an advertisement in The Times, signed by 97 MPs from all parties, with a poster campaign intended to highlight the benefits of Britain's EU membership.</p>
<p>&quot;British businesses recognise the importance of access to the single market to their success and to jobs in this country,&quot; said Giles Radice, an MP of the main opposition Labour party and chairman of the European Movement.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who flirt with withdrawal from the EU are toying with the jobs of millions of people,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The European Movement arrived at the estimate of 3.5 million jobs -- 14.7 percent of Britain's total of 25 million -- because exports to the other 14 EU nations represent 14.7 percent of Britain's total output of goods and services.</p>
<p>Radice is convinced there is a pro-European majority in parliament but admits it has been slow to counter the arguments of Euro-sceptics opposed to further integration, who have largely succeeded in dominating the political debate on Europe.</p>
<p>Although most Euro-sceptics insist they do not want Britain to pull out of the EU, Radice said their stance would ineluctably lead in time to withdrawal.</p>
<p>&quot;We're calling their bluff,&quot; he told reporters. &quot;The reality is that they are advocating policies that would lead to withdrawal or at least total isolation.&quot;</p>
<p>The advertisement in The Times -- part of the European Movement's &quot;Europe 97&quot; campaign -- said contemplating withdrawal would be a disaster for Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;It is crucial for our future prosperity, security and influence in the world that we remain a full and committed member of the European Union,&quot; the MPs, including former foreign secretary Douglas Hurd, wrote.</p>
<p>The advert followed a warning by 23 leading businessmen, published in a letter to Tuesday's Financial Times, of the damage that &quot;extreme Euro-scepticism&quot; was causing British companies in Europe.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Trade Secretary Ian Lang said he had written to European social affairs Commissioner Padraig Flynn to complain about his proposals for compulsory workforce consultation in the wake of French car maker Renault SA's sudden decision to close a big plant in Belgium with the loss of 3,000 jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;New regulations on business can only destroy European jobs when the priority has to be to create them,&quot; Lang, who plans to carry the same message to Germany on Thursday, told reporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
