<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="437372" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INTERVIEW-Telewest says digital may slow it.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Telewest says digital may slow it.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Telewest Communications Plc, poised to be knocked off the top spot as Britain's biggest cable operator, said on Wednesday that providing multi-channel digital TV may slow plans to build out its network.</p>
<p>Finance director Charles Burdick told Reuters that the company was considering a number of alternatives to fund its planned digital services.</p>
<p>Telewest, which earlier reported wider-than-expected annual pretax losses of 249.90 million stg, has already secured a 1.2 billion stg debt facility, from which it has drawn about 100 million stg to date.  </p>
<p>Burdick said the company was considering &quot;cherry picking&quot; or slowing down some of its main network build in 1998 and 1999 as digital comes on stream in force and was also considering possible alternative financing.</p>
<p>Telewest said its network construction programme, due to be fully rolled out by the turn of the century, was 65 percent complete and the group said it was continuing to improve its service and offerings to existing and potential customers.</p>
<p>Capital expenditure over the year rose 31 percent to 515.6 million stg and Burdick said that Telewest expected to spend a similar amount in the new financial year.  </p>
<p>&quot;This year will be another year of substantial build,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>To improve margins, Telewest is in talks with several firms including Fibreway, which first sunk cables into the UK's canal network in 1994, BRT, the old British Rail Telecoms network owned by Racal Electronics Plc and NTL about building a fibre optic network to link up its seven franchise areas.</p>
<p>Telewest wants to escape dependence on dominant players such as British Telecommunications Plc and Cable and Wireless Plc's Mercury, which currently provide expensive links, and is investing 50 million stg in the venture it hopes to complete this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We think that this will improve our business telephony margins and our residential margins by two or three percent,&quot; Burdick said, although he added that pressure on retail prices might offset the gains.</p>
<p>However, with the introduction of digital in the final quarter of 1997, savings can be achieved by using the interfranchise network to provide digital signals from one central point instead of seven.</p>
<p>Burdick said he expected margins, which were in excess of 70 percent for residential telephony, to remain constant. &quot;We expect (margins), with a combination of market forces, to stay constant at these very high levels,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Telewest said average monthly revenue per cable television subscriber edged up to 22.95 stg from 21.11 stg in 1995, although average residential telephony revenue billed per line slipped to 20.26 stg from 20.69 stg because of a tariff price war with BT.</p>
<p>&quot;Any negative revenue impact will be mitigated by the increasing trend of customer call volumes, falling interconnect charges and line rental increases,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>In business telephony, the average revenue per line fell eight percent to 54.5 stg in 1996 because of price competition.</p>
<p>Telewest, along with other cable companies, has been placed on CreditWatch with negative implications by Standard &amp; Poor's credit rating agency because of slower than anticipated network buildouts and competitive pressures from rivals such as BT and satellite broadcaster British Sky Broadcasting Group Plc .</p>
<p>Higher-than-expected capital expenditure and debt levels and a delay in operating cash flow generation in the industry has concerned the agency.</p>
<p>But Burdick said Telewest had the best credit rating of all cable companies at BB plus and had had a &quot;very productive meeting&quot; with S&amp;P.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to have a response as a company and industry at the end of the month,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cable and Wireless Communications, a new merger between C&amp;W's Mercury and three other cable operators, will take Telewest's place as Britain's biggest cable operator if it is completed on schedule this spring.</p>
<p>-- Kirstin Ridley, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7987</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
