<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43738" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan, Okinawa raise hopes of easing US bases row.</title>
<headline>Japan, Okinawa raise hopes of easing US bases row.</headline>
<byline>Paul Eckert</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A festering dispute over the huge U.S. military presence on the Japanese island of Okinawa remains unsolved, Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto said on Tuesday after meeting with Okinawa Governor Masahide Ota.</p>
<p>But Hashimoto's offer of substantial development funds and redoubled efforts to transfer bases to other parts of Japan in his talks with Ota, who has called for a total U.S. pullout, improved the prospects of solving the bitter row, both politicians said.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe we have secured reliable relations with the Okinawa prefecture,&quot; Hashimoto told a news conference.</p>
<p>But asked whether the apparent easing of a year-long standoff with Okinawa cleared the way for early general elections as predicted by many observers, he added: &quot;The Okinawa issues have not ended yet.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone must understand just how critical the Okinawa question is,&quot; said Hashimoto. The prime minister need not call polls until mid-1997, but is expected to hold elections as early as next month.</p>
<p>Ota told a separate news conference that his encounter with Hashimoto &quot;offers extremely bright prospects&quot; for Okinawa, which had long chafed under the heavy U.S. military presence.</p>
<p>&quot;Compared to last year, I believe the government has become more serious about our requests to trim bases and to deal with Okinawa's unemployment and development problems,&quot; Ota said.</p>
<p>Hashimoto announced at the meeting that the central government would pump five billion yen ($46 million) into the Okinawan economy, the poorest region of Japan with average income half the level of Tokyo's.</p>
<p>He also said a special government commission would be appointed to work on reducing the scale of the forces and developing long-term development schemes for the island.</p>
<p>Hashimoto offered no new initiatives on consolidating the bases, which became a target of Okinawan protest after the rape of an Okinawan schoolgirl by U.S. servicemen last September.</p>
<p>He instead reiterated his commitment to a plan announced in April to placate the Okinawans without risking strains with the United States, which sees Okinawa as a strategic location in a region fraught with potential conflicts.</p>
<p>&quot;I frankly told governor Ota that the government will do all it can to resolve the Okinawa issues,&quot; Hashimoto said.</p>
<p>The closely watched talks came two days after residents of Okinawa voted overwhelmingly in a referendum for a reduction in the U.S. presence.</p>
<p>Okinawa is home to three-quarters of the U.S. military facilities in Japan and hosts about half of the 47,000 U.S. military personnel stationed in the country, although it constitutes less than one percent of Japan's total land area.</p>
<p>Okinawans have long resented the noise, aircraft accidents and crime associated with the heavy U.S. presence.</p>
<p>Ota told reporters that he needed more time to consider a response to a central government request that he force local landowners to renew leases for land used by the U.S. military.</p>
<p>A ruling by Japan's Supreme Court on August 28 that rejected Ota's appeal against the government's policy of expropriating private land in Okinawa for use by the U.S. military was expected to put pressure on Ota to compromise.</p>
<p>Washington on Monday responded to the Sunday vote, in which 90 percent said they favoured a reduction in U.S. forces, saying it would cooperate with Japan in reducing the impact of the military there.</p>
<p>&quot;We seek to reduce the impact of the American military presence in Okinawa consistent with our responsibilities under the mutual security treaty that we have in place with the Japanese,&quot; said State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
