<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="437321" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: ING ON LOOKOUT TO BUY INSURERS IN U.S..</title>
<headline>ING ON LOOKOUT TO BUY INSURERS IN U.S..</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch financial services group ING NV said on Wednesday its priority would be to acquire an insurer in the United States rather than a bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The insurance market has our priority at the moment,&quot; said ING board member Cees Maas during a press conference in which he unveiled more details on ING's intended bourse listing in New York in June.</p>
<p>&quot;We are actively looking around (for takeovers) as we want to play a strong role in the American insurance market,&quot; Maas said. He saw strong growth ahead in the market for pension and life insurance products.</p>
<p>ING said the intended listing in the U.S. would enable the group to finance mergers and acquisitions in the United States with shares.</p>
<p>&quot;The payment of an acquisition with your own shares is usually more attractive due to tax-advantages,&quot; Maas said.</p>
<p>ING said it was currently not in talks with any party in the U.S. on a possible takeover. &quot;But things can change quickly,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>ING said it wanted to expand its shareholder base through the listing in the U.S., as about 13 percent of all its shares were owned by U.S. and Canadian investors.</p>
<p>A total of 52 percent of all ING shares are owned by Dutch investors, mainly institutions, but a substantional amount is in the hands of private investors.</p>
<p>ING said in a statement it wanted to increase its visibility in the U.S.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. is the largest capital market in the world and the listing facilitates ING Group's future access to this market,&quot; ING said.</p>
<p>-- Wendy Braanker, Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
