<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="437402" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: WORLD BONDS - Record low JGB yields nearing trough.</title>
<headline>WORLD BONDS - Record low JGB yields nearing trough.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Scott</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese government bond yields are well underpinned at their present record lows, but have limited scope to fall further, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>They expected 10-year yields to drift up towards 2.70 percent by the end of the year from their present 2.30 percent, but possible yen appreciation may offer interim support.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say JGBs are looking pretty toppy,&quot; said Sonja Gibbs, senior bond strategist at Nomura International here.</p>
<p>&quot;But there's no reason for yields to sky-rocket. I'm looking for 10-year yields to drift up to 2.70 percent by year end.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said some investors were still adding JGBs to their portfolios, despite the meagre yields, in anticipation of an appreciation in the yen, or in a bid to avoid volatility in U.S. Treasuries.</p>
<p>&quot;There's very little prospect of much more JGB price appreciation,&quot; said Gibbs. &quot;But we are seeing clients increasing their holdings on the basis of a negative correlation between Japan and other markets.&quot;</p>
<p>The cash benchmark 182nd JGB yield fell to another record low of 2.290 percent soon after Tokyo midday trade on Wednesday. Dealers said the rally was mainly due to expectations that investors may increase JGB buying from April.</p>
<p>By 1232 GMT, the 182nd JGB yield was at 2.30 percent in London.</p>
<p>Kirit Shah, chief strategist at Sanwa International, agreed investors should not chase the JGB rally from here as the market was in danger of being a touch complacent.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is saying, yes, there's good data, but the consumption tax will lead to a slowdown in growth so there's no need to worry. But I think that's a bit too complacent.&quot;</p>
<p>Consumption tax is due to ris eto five percent from three percent on April 1, as part of a drive to curb state borrowing.</p>
<p>He suggested it was an opportune time to take profits as the last stage of the rally approached.</p>
<p>Shah said the belief the market has seen the back of the bearish trend in the yen would, however, help to underpin JGBs.</p>
<p>&quot;Most people believe the bearish scenario for the yen is over and that it will be range-bound between 120 to 125 (dollar/yen),&quot; he said. &quot;So from an asset allocation perspective ...yen bonds may benefit a bit.&quot;</p>
<p>By 1234 GMT the dollar/yen rate was at 122.68/78, compared with 121.78/85 late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Gibbs agreed potential yen appreciation may encourage investors to buy JGBs, as may equity market weakness. She suggested investors be in the 10-year sector.</p>
<p>&quot;We recommend switching out of 20-years into 10-years. I wouldn't be in the short end...or the super-long end,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Adam Chester, international bond strategist at Yamaichi International here, agreed the 10-year sector was the best bet.</p>
<p>&quot;The 10-year sector is most favoured, given the potential for further outperformance of cash versus futures,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said he expected the yield curve to flatten further, with gains expected to continue to be led from the long end, and was more optimistic on the scope for a further fall in bond yields.</p>
<p>&quot;Near term, we could make a little more progress,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gibbs said she expected little fall-out from Thursday's fourth quarter gross domestic product (GDP) release. According to a Reuters survey, economists expect GDP to rise 0.8 percent quarter-on-quarter, versus a 0.1 percent rise in Q3.</p>
<p>Gibbs added JGBs would also fair relatively well should the U.S. Federal Reserve raise interest rates at the upcoming March 25 Federal Open Market Committee meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;There'd be some consternation if the U.S. raises rates on March 25, but I think Japan would be fairly resilient to that,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>-- International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 8682</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
