<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="437567" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AgriBioTech sees Q3 earns below estimate.</title>
<headline>AgriBioTech sees Q3 earns below estimate.</headline>
<dateline>LAS VEGAS 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>AgriBioTech Inc Wednesday said that while it still expects the current fiscal third quarter to be its first profitable quarter, the profit is expected to be less than the only analyst's estimate of $2.5 million.</p>
<p>The company said heavy flooding occurred in two of its primary distribution areas, Northern California and Kentucky, plus surrounding states.  It is too early in the season to determine whether opportunities are lost for the year or simply shifted to the fourth fiscal quarter ending June 30, 1997, the company said.  </p>
<p>In addition, Johnny Thomas, chief executive officer and president of AgriBioTech, said he purchased 100,000 shares at $3 per share and Byron Ford, vice president, purchased 10,000 shares at $3.22 per share.</p>
<p>Thomas exercised certain of his employee options exercisable at $3 per share through June 30, 2005.  Ford purchased his shares in the open market.  Thomas exercised options early in order to facilitate the company's acquisition plans.</p>
<p>The company's projected schedule, as of this date, is to approximately double its trailing revenue base from about $57 million annualized to about $100 million to $120 million annualized by Sept. 30, 1997.  Management expects that most of this growth will be financed from debt and exercise of existing options and warrants.</p>
<p>Although there can be no assurances that additional acquisitions will be concluded, negotiations with acquisition candidates are proceeding on schedule, the company said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS VEGAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
