<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="437605" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Two weeks before Oscars - nominees act humble.</title>
<headline>Two weeks before Oscars - nominees act humble.</headline>
<byline>Steve James</byline>
<dateline>BEVERLY HILLS, Calif. 1997-03-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hollywood put on its humble face Tuesday as Oscar nominees expressed humility at being honoured for the movie industry's biggest awards.</p>
<p>At a luncheon for nominees before the March 24 Academy Awards ceremony, several stars expressed how being nominated was honour enough and winning an Oscar was not important.</p>
<p>But a few, like Kristin Scott Thomas, who is up for best actress for &quot;The English Patient&quot;, were refreshingly honest.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd love to win,&quot; she told reporters at the Beverly Hilton. &quot;I feel like a child of six and I'm over the moon.&quot;</p>
<p>And Barbara Hershey, nominated for a best supporting actress Oscar for &quot;Portrait of a Lady,&quot; was equally frank. &quot;Honestly, I'd love to win,&quot; she said. &quot;I am shocked at how much being nominated means.&quot;</p>
<p>Scott Thomas summed up the uncharacteristic humility in Tinseltown at this time of the year. The English actress said she had been at a photo shoot the day before with her son.</p>
<p>When she asked him what he thought of it, his reply was close to describing the feeling in Oscar-crazed Hollywood.</p>
<p>&quot;'Mommy, everyone has to say they love you and that you look beautiful,'&quot; Scott Thomas said with a wry grin.</p>
<p>Also at the luncheon was one of her rivals for best actress -- Frances McDormand -- who was nominated for her role as a small-town police officer in &quot;Fargo&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;This is all pretty overwhelming,&quot; she said. &quot;I lead a pretty simple life in New York.&quot;</p>
<p>After the Oscar ballyhoo has died down, McDormand said she was anxious to return to the stage. &quot;I haven't done a play for three and a half years and I can't be away so long.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a different set of muscles (from acting in films) and mine are atrophying,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Billy Bob Thornton, who has been nominated for best actor and best adapted screenplay for &quot;Sling Blade&quot;, brought a touch of good ol' boy earthiness to the glittering event.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel like the ugly guy who got a date for the prom,&quot; he said in his southern drawl.</p>
<p>Asked by reporters if he would be wearing the same black T-shirt, jeans and John Deere baseball cap to the Academy Awards show, he laughed: &quot;They won't let me. I asked but they said 'Show a little class.'&quot;</p>
<p>Three nominees for best supporting actor were on hand -- James Woods for &quot;Ghosts of Mississippi&quot;, Armin Mueller-Stahl for &quot;Shine&quot; and Cuba Gooding Jr., for &quot;Jerry Maguire&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;All corny stuff aside, all the people in my category are friends or people I admire, so being nominated is good,&quot; said Woods, who plays a racist killer in the film.</p>
<p>He said he felt he had more chance this time compared to 10 years ago &quot;When I was nominated (for best actor in &quot;Salvador&quot;) against Paul Newman on his eighth try.</p>
<p>&quot;It was like going to the guillotine then, and all we could do was practice our smiles.&quot;</p>
<p>German actor Mueller-Stahl said tongue-in-cheek: &quot;I am proud and every day I get a little bit more famous.&quot;</p>
<p>Gooding, who played a football player represented by sports agent Tom Cruise, was asked how it felt to have one of his lines &quot;Show me the money!&quot; turn into a catch-phrase.</p>
<p>&quot;It's sort of cool. When people get it, it validates you for your next character and I sure have validation now!&quot;</p>
<p>His life had changed so drastically, he said, &quot;now people ask how I pronounce my first name!&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEVERLY HILLS, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
