<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43774" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia palm oil rebounds towards the close.</title>
<headline>Malaysia palm oil rebounds towards the close.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palm oil prices ended the day slightly higher after an erratic day with news of a Pakistani rupee currency devaluation triggering a sell-off in early afternoon trading, traders said.</p>
<p>Players were also waiting the outcome of the Indian tender today. &quot;Results of India's STC was unknown even though the market has closed here,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>India's STC is tendering on Tuesday for 12,000 tonnes of RBD palm olein in two shipments of 6,000 tonnes each, traders said, confirming an earlier report.  </p>
<p>The first shipment of 6,000 tonnes is for first-half October shipment and the second for last-half November shipment, they said. STC in New Delhi declined to comment.</p>
<p>The trader said early afternoon sentiment was hit by news that Pakistan had devalued its rupee currency.</p>
<p>The State (central) Bank Of Pakistan on Tuesday devalued the rupee 3.79 percent to 36.9700/37.1549 to the dollar from 35.6200/35.7981 fixed on August 29.</p>
<p>&quot;There was some panic selling initially following the rupee devaluation but the market is gaining momentum and slowly absorbing (the losses),&quot; the trader said.  </p>
<p>&quot;With the devaluation, Pakistan has to pay more to buy palm oil which means it is likely to reduce imports,&quot; he said. Third month, November futures fell to a low of 1,197 ringgit a tonne due to news of the Pakistani currency devaluation.</p>
<p>But traders said the market found some technical support at lower levels and prices managed to close slightly higher.</p>
<p>By the session close, November futures were up seven ringgit at 1,213 ringgit ($484.62) a tonne.</p>
<p>&quot;Selling was well absorbed. The market regained its strength in late dealing and some technical buying was seen at around 1,200 ringgit,&quot; another trader said.  </p>
<p>November futures contract will trade in the range of 1,200 and 1,250 in the short term.</p>
<p>Trading was volatile and turnover was 2,945 lots against 2,635 on Monday.</p>
<p>The physical sector also fell in line with the futures sector, with interest confined to selected oils and nearby CPOs, traders said.</p>
<p>Among physicals, interest was among nearby CPOs with Sept (south) crude palm oil quoting sellers at 1,230 ringgit a tonne after trading from 1,225 to 1,215. Sept (south) saw bids at 1,222.50. </p>
<p>Sept (central) was offered at 1,220 with bids at 1,212.50. Sept (north) saw offers at 1,215 and bids at 1,205.</p>
<p>Oct (south) crude palm oil was offered at 1,235 ringgit with bids at 1,225. Oct (central) saw offers at 1,225 and bids at 1,217.50 and Nov (north) at 1,245 with bids at 1,235.</p>
<p>In refined products, Sept RBD palmoil was offered at $530 a tonne FOB Malaysia, and Oct/Nov/Dec at $527.50.</p>
<p>Sept palm olein saw offers at $567.50, Oct at $562.50 and Nov/Dec at $550.  Oct was dealt at $555 and $557.50, and Nov/Dec at $547.50 and $545. Sept RBD palm stearin was offered at $420, Oct at $425 and Oct/Nov/Dec palm fatty acid distillate saw sellers at $342.50.-Tan Lee Lee (603-2308911)($1=2.5030)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
