<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43777" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thailand, Burma to build deep seaport.</title>
<headline>Thailand, Burma to build deep seaport.</headline>
<byline>Suthep Chawla</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand and Burma plan to jointly invest in a Burmese deep seaport that will link up with a major industrial estate now being studied, a senior official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Somchet Thinaphong, governor of the Industrial Estate Authority of Thailand (IEAT), told Reuters in an interview that his agency would join Italian-Thai Development Plc and Rangoon in building the Tavoy deep seaport in southern Burma. Tavoy is opposite the western Thai province of Kanchanaburi.</p>
<p>&quot;IEAT is conducting a feasibility study with Italian-Thai Development and the study is expected to be completed in three months,&quot; Somchet said.</p>
<p>He declined to estimate the deep seaport's investment cost.</p>
<p>Italian-Thai is currently building a $149 million international airport at Mandalay, 560 kms (350 miles) north of Rangoon, that is due to be finished by 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;The deep seaport will speed up movement of goods between the two countries and help Thailand save transportation fuel as there would be no need for ships to make de-tour trips via Singapore,&quot; said Italian-Thai's vice president Chatichai Chutima.</p>
<p>The Tavoy port project is part of a package to develop the Thai provinces of Chumphon, Prachuap Khiri Khan, Phetchaburi, Ratchaburi, Kanchanaburi and Samut Songkram.</p>
<p>The six provinces are covered by the Western Seaboard Development Project, in which a deep seaport has been operational in Prachuap Khiri Khan and downstream petrochemical plants and infrastructure are to be built, Somchet said.</p>
<p>Somchet said the plan for developing the provinces was modelled after Thailand's eastern and southern seaboard projects.</p>
<p>&quot;The area will provide a big opportunity for investors,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
