<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="437783" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-OPINION - Louthean on Australian Mining-Ranger's Gold Coast.</title>
<headline>RTRS-OPINION - Louthean on Australian Mining-Ranger's Gold Coast.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Ross Louthean*</p>
<p>Guy Travers and Rod Marston now must be spending a lot of time reading international geological data and news and gazing at world maps.</p>
<p>They are founding directors of Ranger Minerals NL, now on the verge of becoming the third biggest gold producer in the booming West African nation of Ghana, the original Gold Coast.</p>
<p>Their pathfinding role and their detective work on proving up the major Damang ore system on the northern end of Ghana's famous Tarwkwa belt has achieved results that many Australian companies which stayed at home would envy.</p>
<p>Apart from board decision-making they believe the role of mine development and operations now should be in the hands of the operation's administration, miners and millers.</p>
<p>LOOKING FOR THE NEXT MINE</p>
<p>Their prime role now is to find the next mine, wherever.</p>
<p>Ranger's well credentialled exploration team provided the right stuff that took a private company out of the safe haven of Australia into the jungles of Ghana to find a big mine.</p>
<p>This was at a time when Jim Askew, also putting Golden Shamrock Mines Ltd into Ghana and, like the Ranger Minerals board, was getting a cold shoulder from Australian stockbrokers and fund managers.</p>
<p>The perceptions of Africa in the 1980s and early 1990s in Australia was poor, coloured in part by some disastrous early ventures into this vast continent by some flamboyant and poorly equipped Australian juniors in the 1980s.</p>
<p>But that all changed as Africa, and Ghana in particular, came into vogue through improved politics, better development and taxation incentives than on the home front and the scope for elephantine mineral discoveries.</p>
<p>The big Ghana-based African gold producer Ashanti Goldfields Ltd snapped up Askew's Golden Shamrock from under the noses of Australian investors. No doubt miners around the world have looked at Ranger Minerals with its big Damang gold deposit in the Abosso gold field as something they'd like in their portfolio.</p>
<p>NO EASY FRONT FOR ANY RAIDERS</p>
<p>But while Ranger Minerals may not be totally takeover proof there is no easy front-door key for raiders as directors and management retain 32 percent equity in the company.</p>
<p>The others, Australian funds and investors and North American funds, have had a fair to good run, particularly those who were either seed capitalists or in the float when it launched late in 1993.</p>
<p>Ranger Minerals has 90 percent equity in the Abosso leases, with the Ghana Government holding its mandatory 10 percent - a free carried position.</p>
<p>The company listed with the predominant underwriting coming from Perth broker Paterson Ord Minnett, initially raising $20 million. The money went into drilling and there was a rapid rate of discovery and a subsequent realisation by the sharemarket that Ranger may be on to something important.</p>
<p>Ranger had earlier been prime backer of Orion Resources NL, a company that went on to become a major partner in the Yilgarn Star gold mine and surrounding properties. Ranger's shares appreciated through this holding and the emergence of Abosso as a potential gold mine.</p>
<p>The company was able to sell its Orion block prior to it passing into the control of Sons of Gwalia Ltd  SWG.AX. With a healthy share price Ranger in recent years has raised a total of A$103 million, including the Orion sale, which only swelled the issued capital base from an original 51 million to 62 million shares.</p>
<p>FIRST ABOSSO GOLD POUR COULD TAKE PLACE IN OCTOBER</p>
<p>A visit by mining analysts and fund managers last month showed the physical advances being made at Abosso where the first gold pour could take place in October.</p>
<p>The preliminary in-house design of the optimal pit, based on the latest measured indicated resource estimated of 22.9 million tonnes at 3.1 grams/tonne provides the operation with a mineable reserve of 21.2 million tonnes at 3.2 g/t (for 2.07 million oz based on a 94.6 percent recovery.) Using a milling rate of three million tonnes per annum this gives a seven year mining life. Few doubt that the Damang open cut is the starting point, for there is more ore at depth and prospects like Rex, 12 km south, is emerging.</p>
<p>The final pit design for the Damang deposit should be completed this quarter in preparation for trial mining in August.</p>
<p>Ranger Minerals proposes to have at least 400,000 tonnes of ore stockpiled when the ball mills begin rotating. There is a new measured and indicated resource of 22.9 million tonnes at 3.1 grams/tonne, using a diluted cut-off grade of one g/t.</p>
<p>In the meantime, preparation, of the various loan documents for drawdown of the $US80 million debt facility was reportedly well advanced. A condition for the debt facility is for the operating company for Ranger Minerals and the Ghanaian</p>
<p>Government, Abosso Goldfields Ltd, to hedge at least 750,000 ounces to protect cash flow in the first three years of operation.</p>
<p>A study late last year by Paterson Ord Minnett estimated Ranger could produce 284,000 ounces at a cash cost of $US210/oz from milling three million tonnes per annum. Ranger's 1996 annual report said that a mill recovery of 94.8 percent could see the operation produce between 270-290,000 oz per annum.</p>
<p>An interesting facet is that in grade terms the Damang mine fairs very well with counterpart mines in Australia. It ranks in grade versus oz per vertical metre somewhere between Sons of Gwalia's Gwalia mine and Great Central Mines NL's Bronzewing operations.</p>
<p>Outside of the mining world Ranger Minerals's managing director Guy Travers is not as well known as his television daughter. However, he has carved a significant niche for himself in the annals of modern gold mining history.</p>
<p>Guy's daughter Kylie has appeared as a central character in the Models Inc series and has been feted in the media as the girl from Kalgoorlie who hit the big time.</p>
<p>DEPTH OF EXPERIENCE IN RANGER'S TEAM</p>
<p>In his early years, geologist Travers lived in Kalgoorlie and was part of the team which produced a definitive geological appraisal on Kalgoorlie's famous Golden Mile.</p>
<p>This was a study that helped geoscientists who transformed the forest of old headframes into today's Super Pit, and undoubtedly helped others with models for seeking gold elsewhere on Western Australia's Eastern Goldfields.</p>
<p>Leading this study team was Roy Woodall who became the exploration director for Western Mining Corporation (now WMC Ltd) and spearheaded developments including the remarkable Olympic Dam discovery and the evolution of Kambalda.</p>
<p>After 18 years Travers left a key position with WMC to start up Aurex Pty Ltd, forerunner of Ranger Minerals.</p>
<p>Aurex generated several projects and got Ranger's mining life started with tailings retreatment in Fiji and at the New Occidental workings at Cobar in New South Wales.</p>
<p>Rod Marston, who held a senior position with the Geological Survey of WA joined Travers and became one of the founding directors of Ranger when it listed late in 1993.</p>
<p>Another key member of the team was another former WMC geologist Paul Woolrich who walked the railway line in the Abosso Goldfield and helped piece together the picture of geologic potential.</p>
<p>While a member of Woodall's team, Woolrich supervised the drilling out of the Goodall gold deposit in the Northern Territory, since mined out by WMC.</p>
<p>The big rural-based group Wesfarmers Ltd was the biggest shareholder outside of the original directors and executives and it has had board representation.</p>
<p>The company' s just appointed chief operating officer, David Crawford, comes out of the Wesfarmers camp.</p>
<p>Crawford who will ply between Ghana and the company's headquarters in the leafy Perth suburb of Mount Pleasant, will oversee management of development and subsequent operations at the Damang mine.</p>
<p>Another of the early hands playing an important backroom role is accountant director John Christie who, in his earlier years was an administrator for Anaconda Australia, the nickel mining and exploration subsidiary of the US Anaconda group eventually absorbed by Atlantic Richfield.</p>
<p>Company chairman Ian Trahar has held the position since inception. He is a senior WA executive for Citibank and is a director of industrial companies Avatar Industries Ltd and KLZ Ltd, formerly Kalamazoo Holdings Ltd.</p>
<p>*Ross Louthean is editory of Paydirt and publisher of Gold Mining Journal and the Australian Mines Handbook.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 93731800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
