<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="437779" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia Yield Spreads - Underperform pre-jobs.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia Yield Spreads - Underperform pre-jobs.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian bond yield spread differentials widened to the dollar bloc, reversing some of Tuesday's narrowing trend as the market held fire ahead of the February Australian labour force report on Thursday.  </p>
<p>Leading indicators of employment growth remain modest and do not suggest a significant improvement in the labour market for the next few months, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Weak labour market data could cause the 10-year bond spread (to the U.S.) to tighten in to 120 basis points in the short term,&quot; said Su-Lin Ong, fixed rate analysts at Hambros Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Nevertheless, the spread should widen in subsequent months to 150 basis points as evidence of stronger growth fuels speculation of a rate hike later this year,&quot; she added.  </p>
<p>Medium forecasts centre on a 10,000 increase in employment, but this will not have an impact on the unemployment rate, which is expected to remain unchanged at 8.6 percent, according to a Reuters survey of economists.</p>
<p>Today's local underperformance was despite U.S. Treasuries remaining under a cloud amid jitters over a policy tightening when the Federal Open Market Committee meets on March 25.</p>
<p>However, the largest spread widening on the day was against New Zealand debt, which was underpinned by a rally in N.Z. bill futures.  </p>
<p>This was partly in reaction to the closing out of the March bilds contract and also in anticipation of the RBNZ taking a relatively benign stance when it announces its six monthly economic forecasts on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- Colin Brinsden 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
