<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="437899" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine sugar glut seen easing with import ban.</title>
<headline>Philippine sugar glut seen easing with import ban.</headline>
<byline>Dolly Aglay</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippine sugar sector, still buried under a mountain of cheap sugar imports, gained a reprieve on Wednesday when the government extended an import ban to July.</p>
<p>&quot;We have extended the sugar import ban to July, at which time we expect the glut to have eased,&quot; Sugar Regulatory Administration (SRA) chief Wilson Gamboa told reporters at a news conference.</p>
<p>In October last year, Gamboa asked traders and millers to stop sugar imports up to this month to deplete large stocks filling the country's warehouses.</p>
<p>Gamboa said he expected the sugar glut to be eliminated by June or July as a result of the import ban and the U.S. government's increasing its quota for Philippine sugar imports by 27,411 tonnes for the 1996-1997 (Sept-Aug) crop year.</p>
<p>The U.S. had pegged the Philippines' sugar quota at 219,000 tonnes at the start of the current crop year.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the U.S. announced it would increase its total sugar imports in the current crop year by 200,000 tonnes. It had earlier set total sugar imports at 1.7 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Philippine sugar millers and planters welcomed the two developments.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a good development to the industry on condition the government also suspends the present 35 percent margin of preference, or tariff discount, on refined sugar coming from Southeast Asian countries,&quot; said Vicente Castro, assistant executive director of the Philippine Sugar Millers Association.</p>
<p>Philippine sugar millers and planters have asked the government to suspend the tariff discount on sugar from Association of South East Asian Nations (ASEAN) members, which is expected to drop from the present 65 percent to 52.5 percent.</p>
<p>The tariff on sugar from non-ASEAN countries is scheduled to drop from 100 percent to 80 percent by July 1 as part of Manila's commitment to the World Trade Organisation.</p>
<p>Early this year, Agriculture Secretary Salvador Escudero had asked the Philippine Tariff Commission to raise the tariff on imported sugar to 133 percent from 100 percent from January 1 to June 30, 1997, and to 100 percent from 80 percent from July 1 to August 31.</p>
<p>The commission has yet to act on Escudero's request.</p>
<p>The domestic sugar glut resulted from the importation of 1.023 million tonnes of sugar from neighbouring countries in crop year 1995-1996 (Sept-Aug) against production shortfalls of 500,000 tonnes, Gamboa said.</p>
<p>Domestic sugar prices dropped to 480 pesos ($18.25) three months ago from 800 to 900 pesos at the start of 1996 because of the surge in supply between December 1996 and March 1997, the peak milling months in the Philippines when at least 1.2 million tonnes of sugar was added to existing supply.</p>
<p>Gamboa said Philippine sugar millers, including the trading arm of financially troubled Victorias Milling Corp, still have around 100,000 tonnes of unsold sugar stocks in their warehouses.</p>
<p>He said the SRA will consult local sugar producers before it approves the release of the sugar in the market.</p>
<p>The state-run National Food Authority has allocated four billion pesos to buy sugar at a floor price of 610 pesos per 50-kilo bag to prop up prices since February 25.</p>
<p>($1=26.30 pesos)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100136">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
