<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="437955" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan pension fund body suspends deals with Nomura.</title>
<headline>Japan pension fund body suspends deals with Nomura.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Pension Welfare Service Public Corp, an affiliate of the Health Ministry, said on Wednesday it had temporarily suspended its Japanese government bond dealings with Nomura Securities Co Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;We are temporarily suspending new deals in Japanese government bonds with Nomura,&quot; said an official at the pension fund body.</p>
<p>Nomura has come under fire since admitting last week that two of its executives were involved in suspected illegal deals. The Securities and Exchange Surveillance Commission (SESC) has launched a probe into the incident.</p>
<p>The pension body will not take further steps until the results of the SESC's investigation are made public, he added.</p>
<p>As a result of the business suspension, the pension fund body will look to other securities houses and banks when it decides to invest its money in Japanese government bonds, he said.</p>
<p>Nomura said last week that two of its directors had made deals that appeared to be &quot;discretionary&quot; transactions, meaning they were done without the client's knowledge, and moved profits raised from Nomura's own funds into a corporate client's account, practices banned under Japan's securities law. Media reports have linked the corporate client with a former &quot;sokaiya&quot; racketeer.</p>
<p>--Tokyo treasury desk +81-3-3432-1396</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
