<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="438054" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia's Suharto says no room for dissent.</title>
<headline>Indonesia's Suharto says no room for dissent.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Suharto said there was no room for political dissent in Indonesia and that critics of his government did not understand the country's political system, the Jakarta Post newspaper reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There are people who analyse our 1945 Constitution using a foreign frame of mind,&quot; Suharto told a meeting of senior government officials on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Suharto said critics did not understand the role of the People's Consultative Assembly (MPR), the majority of whose members are appointed, which formally elects the president every five years and approves the broad guidelines of state policy.</p>
<p>&quot;The assembly elects a figure it believes is capable of carrying out prepared guidelines of state policy. This implies there should be no opposition to any policy as they have been approved by representatives of all the people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The 1,000-member MPR consists of the 500-member House of Representatives (DPR) and 500 representatives from various government and community bodies appointed by the president.</p>
<p>The MPR has re-elected Suharto five straight times since he was first chosen as president by the body in 1968. The former army general first took power after the military crushed an attempted coup in September 1965 blamed on the Indonesian Communist Party (PKI).</p>
<p>Suharto also warned that the globalisation of information and economic activity was, in some ways, posing a &quot;tremendous threat&quot; to the nation's unity.</p>
<p>&quot;The free flow of global information has brought people in all countries closer to those in others. This enables people to receive foreign values that can erode their sense of nationalism,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;So extreme is the impact of foreign influences in some people they no longer care about maintaining their nation's unity,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Suharto's comments come amid a continuing crackdown on dissent which foreign diplomats say was probably ordered by Suharto, who recently threatened to &quot;clobber&quot; anyone who tried to unseat him by unconstitutional means.</p>
<p>Three leaders of the unrecognised United Democratic Party of Indonesia (PUDI), including its chairman, sacked legislator Sri Bintang Pamungkas, were detained last week on subversion charges which carry the maximum penalty of death.</p>
<p>PUDI had urged people to boycott the May general election.</p>
<p>Bintang had also decried Suharto's likely re-election as president by a new MPR in March 1998.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
