<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="438328" id="root" date="1997-03-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - British chocolate makers gear up for Easter season.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - British chocolate makers gear up for Easter season.</headline>
<byline>Helen Jones</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>British chocolate manufacturers are gearing up for what is expected to be their best Easter ever.</p>
<p>But they're also trying to snare new consumers by branching out from the usual edible bunnies with items such as macho Easter eggs and chocolate beer.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the Easter chocolate market be worth a total of 300 million pounds ($483.8 million) this year compared with 260 million pounds last year,&quot; Tony Bilsborough, a spokesman for Cadbury told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Easter season, which begins as soon as Valentine's Day is over, is the most important period for the industry and sees supermarket shelves laden with traditional chocolate eggs, as well as novelty shapes such as ducks and rabbits.</p>
<p>&quot;The chocolate market is very seasonal and revolves around Christmas, Valentine's Day and Easter. Manufacturers are aggressively marketing their products to get as much out of these peak periods as possible to balance lower sales in the summer,&quot; said Yvette Murphy, features editor of the trade publication The Grocer.</p>
<p>London department store Selfridges stocks around 120 different types of eggs and novelties to satisfy British chocoholics.</p>
<p>Britons consume an average of eight kg (17.6 lbs) of chocolate a year, according to Cadbury, which launched Britain's first milk chocolate 100 years ago.</p>
<p>Cadbury's most popular Easter line is the Cadbury Creme Egg -- a confection of milk chocolate and fondant filling. Although it is only available for a three-month period, last year sales were worth almost 60 million pounds.</p>
<p>The company says that if all the Creme Eggs it makes in one year were stacked on top of each other, the pile would be 900 times higher than Mount Everest.</p>
<p>Confectionery retailer Thornton's has launched a &quot;Diamond Easter Egg&quot; promotion to increase public interest in the market. It will hide 25,000 pounds worth of diamonds in 11 eggs across its nation-wide chain of stores. The biggest -- a 23 carat diamond worth 15,000 pounds -- will be made into an item of jewellery for the winner.</p>
<p>Thornton's is also selling chocolate eggs onto which a name or message can be iced.</p>
<p>&quot;We iced 1.5 million of them last year and it kept the shop staff very busy,&quot; said a spokeswoman.</p>
<p>MOVES TO BROADEN THE MARKET</p>
<p>All British chocolate manufacturers are attempting to broaden the Easter market beyond gifts for children. Thornton's said its iced eggs are very popular with adults and that some requests for messages can be quite risqu.</p>
<p>Other manufacturers have launched Easter eggs with plain packaging and not a fluffy duck in sight which are aimed directly at men and teenage boys.</p>
<p>&quot;We have launched one-kilogram bars of chocolate attached to Easter eggs. They are very chunky and macho and there is no way that a man could feel embarrassed about receiving one,&quot; said Cadbury's Bilsborough.</p>
<p>At the other end of the market, luxury store Harrods is selling a two-and-a-half-foot(76 cm)-high rabbit made of finest Belgian chocolate -- yours for a mere 295 pounds.</p>
<p>&quot;High-quality chocolate has a sophisticated taste and is nothing like the mass-produced product,&quot; said Alan Porter of French chocolate firm Valrhona.</p>
<p>Chocolatier Hans Tschirren, whose family has been hand-making chocolate in Switzerland since 1919, said, &quot;It melts like butter in your mouth. It neither clings stickily to the palate, feels gritty on the tongue nor leaves any after-taste.&quot;</p>
<p>The finest chocolate -- which is made from a higher percentage of cocoa than cheaper chocolate brands -- even has its own fan club. The Chocolate Society was set up seven years ago by a group of chocolate lovers to promote high quality products.</p>
<p>&quot;We now have five-and-a-half thousand members who come to regular tastings and spread the word about the wonders of chocolate. We are not chocoholics but are passionate about good chocolate,&quot; said Nicola Porter, one of the Society's directors.</p>
<p>But luxury chocolate comes at a price -- Harrods sells hand-made Swiss chocolates for 6.50 pounds per half lb.</p>
<p>Consumers in Harrods are snapping them up to give to friends and relatives as Easter gifts.</p>
<p>Michael King, on holiday in London from New York said: &quot;I have bought six boxes as gifts. I guess they are pretty expensive, but the chocolate is very good and they are decorated with the Harrods logo so it makes them kind of extra special.&quot;</p>
<p>And for dedicated chocoholics for whom Easter Eggs are just not enough, London-based brewery Young's is launching a chocolate beer made from malt and chocolate essence in time for Easter.</p>
<p>&quot;It really tastes of chocolate and has done very well in consumer tests&quot;, said brewery spokesman Michael Hardman.</p>
<p>($ = 0.620 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
