<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43832" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippines set for sustained growth, says ADB.</title>
<headline>Philippines set for sustained growth, says ADB.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Asian Development Bank said on Tuesday that the Philippines is set for sustained 6-7 percent annual growth for the next few years but warned it needed to address several important issues.  </p>
<p>In a review of the Philippine economy, the Manila-based multilateral lending institution said privatisations had boosted government revenues since 1993 but these funds were now drying up.</p>
<p>&quot;Replacing these revenue losses by more enduring sources of revenues is a key challenge facing the government,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>It added that the government was addressing this with a comprehensive tax reform package now working its way through the legislature.</p>
<p>The report also expressed concern at the government's management of its foreign exchange rate.</p>
<p>&quot;The nominal effective exchange rate of the peso has remained remarkably steady since 1993 but the real effective exchange rate has appreciated by about 13 percent,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;... The appreciation of the peso could put further pressure on the trade balance,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>The report also complained of major errors in Philippine balance of payments data for 1995, when the government announced a surplus of $645 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The balance of payments data for 1995 has unusually large negative errors and omissions of about $2.3 billion on the capital account,&quot; the bank said.</p>
<p>&quot;Excluding these errors and omissions, net capital inflows in 1995 amount to about $4.9 billion, marginally higher than the $4.75 billion inflows in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;Including the errors and omissions, however, the net capital inflows amount to only about $2.6 billion, or about 45 percent lower than the 1994 level,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>It said the errors could have arisen from the conversion of foreign currency deposits (FCD) in private banks into Philippine pesos.</p>
<p>Peso conversions or withdrawals from FCD accounts are recorded as current account receipts under Philippine balance of payments recording practices, it said.</p>
<p>Exporters may be placing their receipts in FCD accounts before converting them into pesos. This would then lead to a double counting of receipts as they are also taken from records of the Customs Department, the bank report said.</p>
<p>It said the Philippine Central Bank had made adjustments to avoid double-counting but that other sources of error could still be present in the data.</p>
<p>&quot;The extent of this possible underestimation of the current account deficit is not known,&quot; the bank said.</p>
<p>--Manila newsroom (632) 841-8936</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
