<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="438460" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US high-yield bonds queasy on Treas, stock selling.</title>
<headline>US high-yield bonds queasy on Treas, stock selling.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deep losses in the U.S. Treasury and stock markets on Thursday nurtured a queasy tone in the high-yield bond market, while issuers injected several large new issues, dealers said.</p>
<p>Telecommunication deals, including $300 million in two-tranches from WinStar Communications Inc and $200 million from Ionica Plc, were forced to either jack-up yields or add contingent warrants to entice investors, sources said.</p>
<p>Investment grade issuance approached the $1 billion mark, meanwhile, as issuers moved to capture Treasury yields while they were still below seven percent, dealers said.  </p>
<p>Secondary corporate spreads were somewhat tighter on the whole, they added, with accounts opting for the sidelines as Treasuries reacted to anticipated higher interest rates.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year bond dropped nearly one point following a jump in retail sales data and hawkish comments from Chicago Federal Reserve Bank President Michael Moskow. The Dow Jones Industrial Average, meanwhile, fell 160 points.</p>
<p>Back in high-yields, WinStar (rated CCC-plus) sold $100 million 14.5 percent eight-year senior deferred interest notes at par, while WinStar Equipment set $200 million 12.5 percent seven-year guaranteed senior secured notes, also at par.  </p>
<p>Yield talk on both tranches was increased on Wednesday. A separate $150 million senior subordinated deferred interest notes was chopped off the deal on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Bids for WinStar's new notes fell to 99-1/2 by mid-session, traders said.</p>
<p>Ionica's $200 million 15 percent 10-year senior discount note offering apparently won more favor in the secondary market, but not before the addition of contingent warrants for five percent of the company.</p>
<p>The issue gained about one point to a 48-1/4 bid, 48-3/4 offer market near the close from an issued price of 47.688.  </p>
<p>George Edwards, portfolio manager with Prudential Investments, said secondary activity was a a minimum on Thursday, but expected the weakness to translate to wider spreads on tightly priced paper in the near term.</p>
<p>&quot;An awful lot of new deals away from communications have been priced tightly and those will probably trade down to a discount just because there isn't a lot of give in that spread and they'll almost have to track Treasuries,&quot; Edwards said, adding that price movements may be 1/4 to 1/2 point.</p>
<p>In other new issuance, Booth Creek Ski Holdings Inc issued $110 million 12.5 percent 10-year senior notes at par.  </p>
<p>Quality Food Centers Inc increased its 10-year senior subordinated note deal to $150 million from $125 million and priced the debt at par to yield 200 basis points over.</p>
<p>High-yield secondary names were 1/4 to 3/8 point lower on a broad basis amid unenthusiastic activity, traders and managers said. Traders said the day was marked with low bids with no offerings or &quot;less serious&quot; bids out to test waters.</p>
<p>Reflecting that sentiment, Brooks Fiber Properties Inc's zero coupon bonds were seen at 66-1/4 bid compared with Wednesday's bid level of 67.</p>
<p>Investment grade prices were socked with Treasuries but traders cuffed spreads two to three basis points tighter on average. Still, activity was dull with focus on new issues.</p>
<p>From Northwest Airlines Inc, dealers priced $150 million seven- and 10-year notes as 8-3/8s to yield 175 basis points off the curve and another $100 million 10-year notes as 8.70s to yield 200 basis points over.</p>
<p>Northwest is a Ba2/BB-minus crossover name, traders said.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Archer Daniels Midland Co issued $350 million 7-1/2 percent 30-year bonds to yield 55 basis points over and Fifth Third Capital Trust I sold $200 million 8.136 percent 30-year capital securities to yield 110 basis points over.</p>
<p>((--Al Yoon, 212-859-1672))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
