<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="438790" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: FULL TEXT - KREDIETBANK 1996 EARNINGS STATEMENT.</title>
<headline>FULL TEXT - KREDIETBANK 1996 EARNINGS STATEMENT.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following is the full text of a statement about 1996 earnings from Kredietbank .</p>
<p>13 March 1997</p>
<p>Embargo: until Thursday, 13 March 1997 at 4.40 p.m.</p>
<p>Kredietbank profit up 13.5 %</p>
<p>For the 1996 financial year, the consolidated profit of the Kredietbank went up by BEF 1 561 million or 13.5 %, reaching BEF 13 112 million.</p>
<p>A proposal will be submitted to the General Meeting of 24 April to pay out a net dividend on ordinary shares of BEF 265, compared with one of BEF 235 for 1995. Consequently, for the VVPR shares, a dividend of BEF 300.33 will be proposed.</p>
<p>The Board of Directors has decided to give shareholders the option of receiving their dividends in cash or in the form of new shares. The latter option will enable the bank to strengthen its solvency with a view to financing its continued expansion. Accounting for the increase in profit are the outstanding results achieved both in the markets and by the establishments abroad, as well as the growth in commission receivable in respect of securities transactions and the sale of insurance. The operating result was 31.1 % higher. However, much larger allocations were made to the internal reserve for latent risks and to provisions for liabilities and charges. These provisions are aimed at absorbing the extraordinary expenditure associated with the introduction of the euro, the adjustment of computer programs for the year 2000 end the early retirement of employees under the social plan. Income taxes were up by more than 80 %. From the very first year, the acquisition of the Bank van Roeselare has had a positive impact on earnings per share. Own funds after profit appropriation, in combination with the fund for general banking risks, grew by BEF 8.8 billion to BEF 108.2 billion.</p>
<p>At 11.5 %, the overall risk asset ratio (CAD) was well above the 8 % norm laid down by  the supervisory authorities.</p>
<p>Return on equity went up from 13.8 % to 14.3 %. The bank's sound solvency and creditable profitability are reflected in the excellent ratings it has been awarded.</p>
<p>Consolidated balance sheet</p>
<p>At the consolidated level, total assets increased by 17.8 % and came to over BEF 3 623 billion. This can be ascribed only in part to the inclusion of the Bank van Roeselare in the scope of consolidation, considering that autonomous growth amounted to 14.4 %. Once again, the international activities underwent brisk expansion. Excluding loans and advances to credit institutions, foreign assets rose 28.2 %.</p>
<p>Loans and advances - not represented by securities - to credit institutions went up by 19.2 %, whereas amounts owed to credit institutions increased by only 11.2 %. Accordingly, the net call on banks declined from BEF 119 billion to BEF 51 billion.</p>
<p>Payments credit increased by BEF 215 billion or 21.4 % to BEF 1 221 billion. Domestic lending was up 10.4 %. Mortgage credit outstanding rose BEF 26.8 billion to BEF 189 billion, a 16.5 % increase (12.6 %, if the Bank van Roeselare is left out of account). Instalment credit remained unchanged from 1995 and, if the scope of consolidation had stayed the same, would even have edged down. Credit to Belgian businesses went up by 9.5 %, compared with a 7.3 % rise in 1995. Lending to borrowers abroad increased by 49.1 %. Given that less than 10 % of this can be attributed to higher exchange rates, real growth came to around 40 %. International lending accounted for 34.9 % of total credit outstanding, compared with 28.5 % a year earlier.</p>
<p>The securities portfolio went up by BEF 103 billion or 11.3 % to reach BEF 1 015 billion. Holdings of short-term Belgian government paper were reduced in favour of longer-term Belgian government funds. On balance, the portfolio of Belgian government paper and funds grew by BEF 37 billion or 6.4 %. The trading portfolio of fixed-yield securities represented an amount of BEF 70.5 billion, twice as much as in 1995. Of this, BEF 54 billion was accounted for by securities issued by public authorities.</p>
<p>Customers' deposits and debts represented by securities went up by BEF 337 billion to BEF 1 939 billion (a 21 % increase). Deposits on savings books grew by BEF 66 billion or 20 %, reaching BEF 396 billion. Savings certificates posted an advance of just BEF 15.2 billion, a 4.3% increase.</p>
<p>If the scope of consolidation had remained unaltered, savings book deposits would have grown by 14.3 % and savings certificates would have declined by 3.3 %. This reflects customers' preference for short-term investments when interest rates are low. Foreign currency deposits and debts represented by securities denominated in foreign exchange rose 33.3 %.</p>
<p>After profit appropriation, own funds showed a 10 % increase, having gone up to BEF 96.2 billion.</p>
<p>Thanks to the BEF 8.8 billion increase in own funds and the BEF 29 billion increase in subordinated liabilities, along with a more or less unchanged fund for general banking risks, capital resources expanded, reaching BEF 238.6 billion.</p>
<p>Consolidated profit and loss account</p>
<p>Gross income from the exercise of normal business activities was up 20 % on the previous financial year. Of this increase, 44 % was accounted for by higher net interest income and 56 % by higher profit on financial transactions and increased commission income. The rise in net interest income can be explained by the inclusion of the Bank van Roeselare in the scope of consolidation and by the growth in interest earnings on activities denominated in foreign currency. Profit on financial transactions was 59 % higher. The result achieved from foreign exchange dealing and trading in securities and other financial instruments more than doubled, rising from BEF 3 479 million to BEF 7 370 million, while the increase in profit on the disposal of investment securities was limited.</p>
<p>Other commission and operating income was boosted by, among other things, the higher income from the sale of investment funds, BEVEKs and SICAVs. The broader range of products on offer in this field would thus appear to have been successful. Commission earned on insurance business likewise increased.</p>
<p>Operating charges were up 13 % on the year-earlier figure. Nevertheless, cost pressure eased to 57.5 %, compared with 61 % for 1995, thanks to the greater growth in gross income.</p>
<p>After discounting the effect of the inclusion in the scope of consolidation of the Bank van Roeselare, the increase in operating charges boils down to 8.7 %. If the scope of consolidation had remained the same, staff charges would have gone up by 7 %, partly because of the severance pay disbursed by the parent company to personnel leaving the bank before retirement under the social plan.</p>
<p>Total depreciation, write-downs and provisions came to BEF 15 540 million in 1996, BEF 3 955 million more than in 1995. Depreciation in respect of tangible and intangible fixed assets was up 30 %. Besides depreciation on buildings and higher depreciation charges in respect of machines relating to the on-going branch automation project, this account heading also includes depreciation of initial consolidation differences on new acquisitions. As from the 1996 financial year, software purchased for long-term use is to be capitalized and depreciated over a period of five years. The decision to enter these amounts on the assets side of the balance sheet was prompted by a Commission for Accounting Standards recommendation published in the Bulletin (No. 35) of October 1995.</p>
<p>Write-downs on and provisions for credit risks increased by 13.1 % to BEF 7 312 million. Because actual write-downs on domestic and foreign borrowers exhibited a downward trend, the increase can be attributed to a higher allocation to the internal reserve for latent risks. Net allocations to provisions for liabilities and charges were more than twice as high as in 1995, the reason being the substantial costs the parent company in particular can expect to incur over the next few years. At group level, provisions in the amount of nearly BEF 1 billion were set aside to deal with the estimated expense of the changeover to the euro and adjustments that need to be made in respect of the millennium. These provisions are taxed and will make it possible to absorb spending in excess of BEF 1.6 billion, which should more than suffice. Provisions for amounts that will have to be paid to employees leaving the group before retirement age likewise had to be raised substantially.</p>
<p>The extraordinary result relates to profit posted on the sale of financial fixed assets.</p>
<p>Taxation went up by BEF 2 324 million to BEF 5 214 million, with more than BEF 2 billion of the increase being accounted for by the higher tax levied on profit for the financial year.</p>
<p>Profit for the financial year, including the results achieved by companies consolidated according to the equity method, went up by 13.6 % to BEF 13 742 million. Group interests in consolidated net profit came to BEF 13 112 million, 13.5 % more than for the previous financial year.</p>
<p>Non-consolidated annual accounts</p>
<p>For the Kredietbank NV, the increase in the main components of the balance sheet and profit and loss account was smaller than that achieved at the consolidated level, which was boosted by the inclusion of the Bank van Roeselare. Total assets rose 14.5 %.</p>
<p>Payments credit at parent-company level went up by 12.5 %, customers' deposits and debts represented by securities by 17.1 %. Gross income climbed 15.5 %, whilst the 7.7 % increase in operating charges was likewise lower than the average for the group. The net profit for the financial year was 12.1 % higher, and came to BEF 10 459 million, of which, on the basis of the proposed appropriation of profit, BEF 5 208 million will be paid out by way of dividend.</p>
<p>Kredietbank</p>
<p>Havenlaan 2</p>
<p>1080 Brussels</p>
<p>Communication Department Divisional Manager:</p>
<p>Piet Jaspaert</p>
<p>Tel: (02) 422 85 78</p>
<p>Press Officer:</p>
<p>Viviane Huybrecht</p>
<p>Tel.: (02) 422 85 45 Fax: (02) 422 81 60</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
