<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="438759" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIAN PENSIONERS QUEUE FOR EU HANDOUTS.</title>
<headline>BULGARIAN PENSIONERS QUEUE FOR EU HANDOUTS.</headline>
<byline>Thalia Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Elderly and jobless Bulgarians, hardest hit by the country's economic collapse, crammed into social security offices on Thursday to apply for a European Union handout.</p>
<p>Municipal employees arriving for work at Krasno Selo district struggled through the crush to get to their offices. Most of the people crowding round doorways in a narrow corridor said they were there for a third day.</p>
<p>Pensioner Delcho Manolov said things had got worse, not better, since mass protests toppled the ex-communist Socialist government last month, and blamed the interim cabinet governing until April 19 general elections.</p>
<p>&quot;It's true the communists stole a lot but these people who came in after them have raised all the prices,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The only hope I can see is to get the Tsar (exiled King Simeon) back. He's obviously a nice man and we wouldn't need a parliament so that's 240 fewer politicians to pay salaries to.&quot;</p>
<p>Manolov said his monthly pension was 7,000 levs ($4.30). A loaf of bread costs 500 levs or more and a litre of milk 800 levs. &quot;I couldn't pay the electricity bill last month and I haven't bought clothes for years. Look at these rags, they're my best clothes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Annual inflation last month soared to 1,839 percent from 476.6 percent in January as the lev plunged to historic lows of 3,000 to the dollar.</p>
<p>The interim cabinet raised state salaries from March 1, so that the minimum monthly wage is now 17,600 levs. A doctor earns 56,840 levs before tax.</p>
<p>Dancho Hristov said he had been unemployed for a month, and his wife's small teacher's salary had to keep him and his son, who was also out of work. He said he would not be eligible for state benefit until he had been out of work for a year.</p>
<p>&quot;Our parents help with home-produced food and we collect waste paper to sell, but the money is still barely enough for a loaf of bread a day,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The European Union has granted 20 million ecus ($23 million) to support 500,000 low-income households, which is the poorest 20 percent, and 63,000 residents of some 570 social institutions.</p>
<p>Applications for the 10 ecus monthly payout for the next four months will take a month to process. &quot;It's not much use in 30 days, we need the aid right now,&quot; Manolov said.</p>
<p>An International Monetary Fund mission is in Sofia sifting through the economic wreckage and discussing a new reform and funding agreement.</p>
<p>The IMF's Europe One department director, Michael Deppler, said on Wednesday he would need guarantees that the government to be elected next month would stick to any new programme.</p>
<p>Opinion polls show the Union of Democratic Forces winning a majority in the new parliament, but with memories of their campaign to topple the Socialists fading and prices continuing to rise, the majority may be smaller than they had hoped.</p>
<p>An alliance of the ethnic Turks' Movement for Rights and Freedoms, and former president Zhelyu Zhelev's Liberal Democratic Alternative is shaping up to form a significant third force.</p>
<p>The Fund wants Bulgaria to set up a restrictive fixed exchange rate regime, to prevent uncontrolled printing of money and restore confidence in the lev.</p>
<p>The government is still operating without a 1997 state budget. Various prominent economists have visited in the past month to offer their advice, but at the other end of the scale, the economics are rather simpler.</p>
<p>&quot;My pension is 8,300 levs, and my heating alone is 8,000, and if you add electricity and telephone, you see I don't have money for food,&quot; said one neatly-dressed pensioner near the front of the queue. ($=1,600 levs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
