<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="438829" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Big oil exchanges plan 24-hour global market.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Big oil exchanges plan 24-hour global market.</headline>
<byline>Mark Thompson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The world's two leading oil exchanges are studying ways to develop a global 24-hour energy market with a view to boosting trading volumes while promising big cost savings for their members and the oil industry.</p>
<p>Close cooperation between rivals the International Petroleum Exchange (IPE) in London and the New York Mercantile Exchange (NYMEX) would almost certainly stifle an infant oil futures market in Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;We are planning to set up a common electronic trading system where you can trade energy products whether in the U.S. or in London on one common platform which you can access on a 24-hour basis,&quot; said the IPE's head of product development Richard Ward.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying to set up a global energy market.&quot;</p>
<p>Ward was speaking after NYMEX and the IPE issued a joint statement confirming detailed discussions would start soon on ways of developing a common out-of-hours trading system, among other areas of cooperation.</p>
<p>The talks, due to bear fruit by late summer, would  also explore joint systems development, marketing and cross-margining -- reducing the cash traders have to pay up front for spread trades between the exchanges' contracts.</p>
<p>A full-scale merger was not on the cards, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The overall objective behind this cooperation is to grow both exchanges volumes,&quot; Ward said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have entered into this with the belief that there are real benefits to be accrued for the members and therefore for the customers.&quot;</p>
<p>Both exchanges offer oil producers, traders and refiners the oppportunity to hedge price risk on crude oil and refined products such as heating oil and gasoline.</p>
<p>IPE daily trading volumes on Brent during the last 12 months have averaged over 40,000 lots, equivalent to 40 million barrels of crude or over half of world demand.</p>
<p>North Sea Brent Blend crude is widely traded on the international spot market and therefore regarded as the best benchmark for world prices.</p>
<p>A link-up with NYMEX would almost certainly boost IPE volumes.</p>
<p>But at the Singapore International Monetary Exchange (SIMEX), which carries a Brent contract under a five-year pact with the London exchange, brokers see see a threat to Asia's only oil futures market.</p>
<p>&quot;It all sounds pretty ominous,&quot; said a senior SIMEX broker.</p>
<p>And SIMEX could obstruct the IPE's ambitions by refusing to clear its link with NYMEX.</p>
<p>SIMEX said on Thursday its agreement with the IPE gaive it trading rights on Brent during Singapore hours.</p>
<p>The IPE's Ward rejected suggestions the IPE was aiming to drop its Asian partner.</p>
<p>&quot;We want the SIMEX agreement to succeed... Clearly we need to have the agreement of all the interested parties to be able to progress this -- we do not want to end up with an adversarial relationship with any exchange,&quot; Ward said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
