<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="438956" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerian stocks stronger despite naira slide.</title>
<headline>Nigerian stocks stronger despite naira slide.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares appreciated further at the Nigerian stock market on Thursday despite a fall in the naira exchange rate against the dollar, traders said.</p>
<p>The all-share index closed at 8081.82 from 8009.50 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Traders said the 5.88 percent naira devaluation announced on Wednesday had no effect on shares which continued to strengthen on demand pressure.</p>
<p>&quot;Excess liquidity in the economy has been positive for equities so far this year, but it is now putting pressure on the naira at the weekly foreign exchange market,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>The central bank said on Wednesday that 85 naira would now fetch one dollar at its autonomous foreign exchange market.</p>
<p>Bank officials estimated some 111 billion naira was in circulation, putting pressure on interest rates and forcing speculators to buy foreign currency.</p>
<p>Traders said demand pressure sent most equities closing higher on Thursday.</p>
<p>Lever Brothers was among big beneficiaries, up 50 kobo at 23.30 naira, as was Guinness which rose by the maximum five percent or 38 kobo to 7.98 naira.</p>
<p>Similar gains were made in the banking sector. Afribank was 7.25 naira, adding 25 kobo, nearly three percent.</p>
<p>First Bank remained the sector's most prized stock at 16.30 naira, up 40 kobo.</p>
<p>Petroleum marketers finished in their regular strong fashion, buoyed by growing interest in them.</p>
<p>African Petroleum jumped to 57.80 naira with a 38 kobo gain while National OIl at 59.70 naira, Total at 72.50 naira and Unipetrol at 75.00 naira, all rose by 20 kobo each.</p>
<p>Investors continued buying insurance shares in anticipation of capital appreciation and increased shareholding, traders said.</p>
<p>Law, Union and Rock closed six kobo more at 1.70 naira, Niger Insurance finished five kobo up at 4.40 naira, the same as UNIC which ended at 4.95 naira.</p>
<p>Thursday's main loser was packaging firm Avon Crowncaps, down six kobo to 2.85 naira on lack of interest.</p>
<p>($=80 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 263 03 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
