<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="439032" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Convoy of Westerners leave Tirana in confusion.</title>
<headline>Convoy of Westerners leave Tirana in confusion.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>About 100 Westerners were evacuated in confusion from Tirana to the port of Durres in a British-organised convoy of cars and minibuses on Thursday as Albania slid towards anarchy.</p>
<p>&quot;This convoy has now arrived safely at the port of Durres on the Albanian coast and we are hoping to evacuate them from there to Italy,&quot; a British foreign office spokesman said in London.</p>
<p>He said the convoy consisted of 65 British nationals, 52 people of other nationalities, 11 Commonwealth citizens and three from Ireland.</p>
<p>A British embassy spokesman in Tirana had asked 120 British and other nationals to assemble at the British embassy with passports and minimum luggage for evacuation from a British naval vessel.</p>
<p>But 15 minutes after the convoy left Tirana's embassy quarter in the late afternoon, with automatic fire rattling periodically in the distance, half the vehicles had returned after losing their way en route to the port of Durres.</p>
<p>They eventually resumed their 40-km (25-mile) journey after a series of frantic calls on mobile telephones.</p>
<p>At least three evacuees - women from the Czech embassy - decided to remain as they said they had no assurances the road to the port was safe or that they would be met once they go there.</p>
<p>Some embassies chose to postpone their departure, saying they viewed the conditions as too dangerous and uncertain.</p>
<p>A second convoy of Western residents was scheduled to leave for Durres on Friday morning.</p>
<p>Britain's Foreign Office had earlier issued a message to British residents advising of the evacuation because of deteriorating security and the closure of the airport.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a final warning, and there is no guarantee of any subsequent evacuation being arranged by civil or military means,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>In Tirana, British embassy official Patrick Owens said that the original plan had been to fly people out in transport planes before the airport closed.</p>
<p>He told Reuters the Albanian government had been unable to guarantee the safety of the aircraft or the evacuees.</p>
<p>&quot;We asked for a military guard, but they were unable to provide it,&quot; Owens said.</p>
<p>The United States has already ordered 160 of its government employees and their families to leave Albania, where armed rebels are demanding the resignation of President Sali Berisha. It has urged another 2,000 Americans to go.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
