<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="439125" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Budapest bourse closed lower after one day of rise.</title>
<headline>Budapest bourse closed lower after one day of rise.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Budapest Stock Exchange closed lower on Thursday moving in harmony with European bourses after days of opposite trend, traders said.</p>
<p>They added, however, that the Hungarian market's fall, which followed by one day of rise, stemmed mainly from the fact that Wednesday's recovery was not convincingly strong.</p>
<p>The BUX index finished at 5,118.60 points, down 69.29.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't dare to say that the market fell only because foreign markets declined,&quot; said Andrea Keresztesi of ABN-AMRO Hoare Govett. &quot;Probably domestic investors thought (on Wednesday) that the market was set to rise,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>On Thursday many of the market's leading stocks closed lower, including the chemicals and pharmaceuticals stocks and hotelier Danubius.</p>
<p>Danubius ended at 4,755 forints, down 235, while chemicals TVK fell to finish at 2,050, down 110 and Borsodchem to 6,000, down 150.</p>
<p>Pharmaceuticals Egis closed at 9,505 forints, down 315, while Richter at 11,210, down 160 and Human at 2,900, down 50.</p>
<p>Keresztesi said she expected calm trading on Friday but said she did not share the opinion of those who believed the Hungarian share market could face a long fall which would last until the next phase of the privatisation of oil company MOL in May.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not that pessimistic,&quot; Keresztesi said. &quot;Should the market fall some more it would become attractive again to trigger some rises.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
