<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="439123" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: Drugs transit trade through Kazakhstan growing.</title>
<headline>Drugs transit trade through Kazakhstan growing.</headline>
<dateline>ALMATY 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The amount of drugs smuggled through the former Soviet republic of Kazakhstan increased dramatically in the first two months of this year, a newspaper said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Police in the vast Central Asian nation have seized about 600 kg (1,320 lbs) of raw opium in the first two months of this year, already more than the 400 kg (880 lbs) confiscated in the whole of 1996, the official daily Kazakhstanskaya Pravda said.</p>
<p>Citing the Kazakh interior ministry's Drugs Control Department, the newspaper said the drugs originated mostly from Afghanistan and the Chu Valley in neighbouring Kyrgyzstan.</p>
<p>According to Arkadiusz Majszyk, regional director of the United Nations International Drug Control Programme in the Uzbek capital Tashkent, drugs trafficking along the ancient silk route has mushroomed since the 1991 Soviet collapse.</p>
<p>&quot;The volume of drugs now shipped through Central Asia is growing by at least 10 percent annually,&quot; Majszyk told Reuters.</p>
<p>Leaky borders, poorly funded police and war have proved a boon for traffickers operating out of the &quot;Golden Crescent&quot; countries of Afghanistan and Pakistan.</p>
<p>Shipments of raw opium hidden in cars and trucks make their way from war-racked Afghanistan across Tajikistan, devastated by its own four-year civil conflict and torn into medieval-style fiefdoms under the control of various armed chieftains.</p>
<p>The narcotics then travel north over the spectacular Pamir Mountains, through Kyrgyzstan's Osh Valley and on through Kazakhstan to Russia and Europe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
