<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="439442" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia Fuel Oil - Quiet, awaiting fresh directions.</title>
<headline>Asia Fuel Oil - Quiet, awaiting fresh directions.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The high sulphur fuel oil market was quiet on Thursday in thin talks with many traders sitting back awaiting for a clearer market direction.</p>
<p>A lack of physical activities and movements in the swaps market dampened sentiment and discouraged trading, traders said.</p>
<p>The 180-cst grade was offered at $101 per tonne, compared with Wednesday's offers at $98/$99 per tonne, but there was no buyer, traders said.</p>
<p>In the swaps market, fuel oil hovered around Wednesday's levels, with March last quoted at $98.50/$99.50 per tonne and April at $97.00/$98.00.</p>
<p>Singapore weekly residue stocks soared by a hefty 2.097 million barrels in the week ending March 12 to 12.692 million barrels, Trade Development Board (TDB) said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The bearish data is the highest volume seen since early May 1996 when it hit 12.909 million barrels.</p>
<p>&quot;The high TDB residues data has been expected. It's not surprising,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>&quot;The data won't have a major impact on the market but it will take quite a while to digest the stocks,&quot; he said, seeing a slight downtrend for cargo prices.</p>
<p>Despite several current maintenance turnarounds in Singapore, Thailand and more in South Korea and Japan in coming months, traders said they did not see fresh enquiries.</p>
<p>However, some traders were not pessimistic.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand should gradually pick up when the whole China enters the harvesting season (in April),&quot; said one trader. He added that not many cargoes are coming in this direction.</p>
<p>This trader, noting the $1.5 spread between March/April swaps, said: &quot;I think demand is quite all right at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>However, most traders admitted that prices in this region remained stronger than those in other regions.</p>
<p>The LSWR market remained quiet and traders considered current prices here are too high compared to alternative burning crude like Duri.</p>
<p>(Prices in dollars per tonne, unless stated)</p>
<p>MTH  FOB SIN		   BUY/SELL		PREV BUY/SELL</p>
<p> FEB  LSWR *		    16.50/17.00	   16.50/17.00</p>
<p> MAR  FUEL OIL (180 CST)    97.00/101.00	  98.00/100.00</p>
<p> MAR  FUEL OIL (380 CST)    91.00/95.00	   92.00/94.00</p>
<p> MAR  FUEL OIL SWAPS	  98.50/99.50	   98.50/100.00</p>
<p> APR  FUEL OIL SWAPS	  97.00/98.00	   96.50/97.50</p>
<p>*Dollars per barrel</p>
<p>--Singapore newsroom (+65-870 3571)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
