<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="439542" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: WPS Resources chairman to retire in June.</title>
<headline>WPS Resources chairman to retire in June.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO</dateline>
<text>
<p>WPS Resources Corp. confirmed Thursday that Daniel Bollom, 60, plans to retire as chairman and chief executive of the utility holding company at the end of June.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Green Bay, Wis.-based WPS said Larry Weyers, its president and chief operating officer, will become chief executive, although the timeframe has yet to be decided.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be earlier (than June 30), but there have been no announcements,&quot; Frank Kicsar, corporate secretary of WPS, said.</p>
<p>News of Bollom's retirement comes at a time when WPS, the parent of Wisconsin Public Service Corp., is dealing with problems at its Kewaunee nuclear power plant, which was taken out of service in September for scheduled refueling and maintenance.</p>
<p>Earlier this week the company said Kewaunee was not expected to resume operations until at least mid-June because repairs to the plant's steam generators were taking longer than expected. It was originally expected to restart by March.</p>
<p>Kewaunee is jointly owned by Wisconsin Public Service Corp., Madison Gas &amp; Electric Co. and WPL Holdings Inc.'s Wisconsin Power &amp; Light Co.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
