<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="439588" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New Burger King chief eyes international growth.</title>
<headline>New Burger King chief eyes international growth.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Zengerle</byline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fast food operator Burger King Corp. Thursday got a new chief executive, who said the company would focus on increasing its share of the international market for quick restaurant food.</p>
<p>Britain's Grand Metropolitan Plc, which owns Burger King, appointed Dennis Malamatinas to replace Robert Lowes, whose departure was &quot;a mutual decision,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>Burger King's hamburger restaurants compete fiercely with McDonald's Corp. in the United States, but Malamatinas noted that only about 20 percent of Burger King's sales come outside of North America.</p>
<p>&quot;That's my primary job, my primary focus ... We'd like to increase that,&quot; he said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Burger King, the second-largest U.S. fast food chain after McDonald's, has been gaining ground on its larger rival. Burger King's share of the U.S. quick-serve hamburger market rose to 19.2 percent last year from 18.2 percent a year earlier, while McDonald's slipped 0.2 percentage point to 42.1 percent.</p>
<p>Malamatinas said he viewed growth in Europe as the No. 1 international opportunity, followed by the Asia/Pacific and Latin American markets. &quot;Somehow, we'll have to learn how to move even faster, more aggressively,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Malamatinas, 41, was most recently executive director and president of Grand Met's International Distillers and Vintners, Asia Pacific, the company's drinks business in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>He said Burger King was in a strong position.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the company is in great shape. It is probably in the best shape it's been during its history,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The company also announced that Paul Clayton, 38, who had been senior vice president of worldwide marketing for Burger King, was appointed president of Burger King, North America, reporting to Malamatinas.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be basically providing a dual focus on the business,&quot; Malamatinas said of himself and Clayton.</p>
<p>Malamatinas declined to make specific growth projections or to discuss price-cutting in the hamburger business, recently initiated by McDonald's.</p>
<p>Several industry analysts have said recently that fast-food chicken restaurant chains, notably Boston Chicken Inc., could be the fiercest competitors for Burger King, McDonald's and other hamburger chains.</p>
<p>&quot;They certainly compete for fast-food dollars,&quot; Clayton said. But he noted Burger King's strong recent growth performance and said, &quot;We continue to take market share away from our competitors ... We're very confident about Burger King going forward.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
