<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="439505" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: TURK COMMERCE GROUPS, UNIONS OPPOSE GOVT POOL PLAN.</title>
<headline>TURK COMMERCE GROUPS, UNIONS OPPOSE GOVT POOL PLAN.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's chambers of commerce, bourses and unions on Thursday expressed opposition to a government plan to transfer the cash assets of state banks and firms to a state pool.</p>
<p>&quot;The plan to include deposits of chambers (of commerce), unions and bourses in the pool is against the law and cannot be applied. We will go to the court for annullment,&quot; said Fuat Miras, chairman of the Turkish Union of Chambers of Commerce and Bourses.</p>
<p>Officials said the prime ministry had sent a circular to chambers of commerce, unions, the capital market board and other autonomous institutions, asking them to transfer their cash to the pool. It was set up in November as a central cash management system for the state sector.</p>
<p>Some economy officials said the circular violates their constitutions.</p>
<p>&quot;They are all autonomous bodies. This amounts to seizing their assets by force and will probably be annulled by the court,&quot; said an economy official who declined to be named.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan's government is planning to transfer some 300 trillion lira to the pool under the circular, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This circular increased our pessimism over the future of democracy and the free economy. The Finance Ministry may have a cash shortage but it can finance this through domestic borrowing or can use Treasury advances,&quot; said Mehmet Yildirim, chairman of the Istanbul Chamber of Commerce.</p>
<p>Turkey put into effect the new regulations on November 1 to pool revenues of all state banks and economic enterprises centrally to help it increase control of state funds and meet its domestic debts requirements.</p>
<p>Anatolian news agency said on Thursday about 1,000 trillion lira had been pooled since November.</p>
<p>--Tulin Aygunes, Istanbul newsroom +90-212-275 08 75</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
