<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="439546" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Former Texaco executive indicted.</title>
<headline>Former Texaco executive indicted.</headline>
<byline>Gail Appleson</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former Texaco Inc. executive was indicted Thursday for alleged obstruction of justice in a private race discrimination suit, federal prosecutors said Thursday.</p>
<p>If convicted, Richard Lundwall, 55, former senior coordinator of personnel services of Texaco's finance department, would face a maximum sentence of 10 years in prison and a $250,000 fine.</p>
<p>Last week Lundwall's lawyers said prosecutors told them their client would be indicted because plea negotiations had collapsed.</p>
<p>Lundwall was first charged in November with obstruction of justice through a complaint filed by the Manhattan U.S. Attorney's Office.</p>
<p>The case against Lundwall stems from his own decision to come forward with evidence against himself and others in the discrimination case against Texaco.</p>
<p>In that class action suit, filed in 1994, a group of black employees alleged that Texaco discriminated against them in promotions and pay.</p>
<p>Lundwall had secretly taped conversations between himself and others in which they discussed destroying documents requested by the plaintiffs. When Lundwall was dismissed by Texaco in a downsizing move last summer, he gave the tapes to the plaintiffs lawyers.</p>
<p>After the tapes were made public in court proceedings, Texaco agreed to settle the case for $176.1 million. A fairness hearing on the settlement, which requires court approval, is set for March 18.</p>
<p>The indictment, which was issued by a grand jury in White Plains, N.Y., federal court, alleged that the plaintiffs' lawyers in the discrimination case learned from an August 1994 deposition of Lundwall that he and other officials kept certain records relating to Texaco's promotion and development of minority employees.</p>
<p>Those documents included &quot;Masterbooks&quot; prepared for Finance Department meetings that contained minutes of prior meetings, statistical data and long range plans for the development of minority employees.</p>
<p>After the plaintiffs' lawyers asked that the records be produced, Lundwall and others in Texaco's finance department collected the materials and agreed to withhold, conceal or destroy them, the indictment charged.</p>
<p>Lundwall's lawyers said last week that plea negotiations collapsed after the government refused to allow them to see a a report prepared for Texaco by an outside investigator.</p>
<p>After receiving the report in January, Texaco took action against executives heard on the tape, including Lundwall, whose benefits were halted.</p>
<p>Texaco's stock fell $2.50 to $100.25 on the New York Stock Exchange in late trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
