<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="43958" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. urges Turkey to help refugees from Iraq.</title>
<headline>U.S. urges Turkey to help refugees from Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Worsnip</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States was urging Turkey to help save thousands of Iraqis who worked with the Western allies in northern Iraq and are now endangered by a Baghdad-backed takeover of the region, U.S. officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We continue to talk to the Turkish government about this problem,&quot; U.S. State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said. Other officials said Washington had not yet received a satisfactory response from Ankara on the issue.</p>
<p>The people concerned have been stranded since the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP), one of the two main Kurdish factions in the area, seized control of most of northern Iraq in recent days with backing from the Baghdad government.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton said on Monday that the United States was helping &quot;those who have worked with us&quot; to flee Iraq.</p>
<p>He was answering a question about some 200 Iraqi Arabs said to have had links with the U.S. Central Intelligence Agency. But State Department officials said the true figure ran into thousands.</p>
<p>The officials did not deny that some may have had an intelligence role, but they said the majority worked on humanitarian aid programmes in what for the last five years has effectively been a Western-protected Kurdish autonomous area.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of these people are average people who live in northern Iraq. They're Kurds, they are Iraqi citizens, they're Turkmens,&quot; Burns said. &quot;They are all sorts of people who have been engaged for the last couple of years in providing medical and food relief to suffering people.</p>
<p>&quot;It's those people that we wish to help. We have a moral obligation to them and we will meet that obligation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no question that Turkey has a responsibility to help the Kurds who are fleeing,&quot; Burns added.</p>
<p>A senior U.S. official said the issue involved &quot;several thousand people and their families who worked for us, and the Turks and the British and the French in the last couple of years.&quot;</p>
<p>The official, who asked not to be identified, said many were peasants or were refugees from various cities in Iraq who left home after Iraqi President Saddam Hussein followed up his 1991 Gulf War defeat with a crackdown on dissidents.</p>
<p>&quot;We put them to work and they worked very faithfully for us ... they're just the kind of people that Saddam would love to get his hands on,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>He said Washington was asking Turkey to &quot;help us provide a place for them to seek temporary refuge so that we can help them in the long term.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. officials did not say what objections Turkey was raising to taking in the refugees. But Ankara was known to be concerned about infiltration by the PKK, a separatist Turkish Kurdish guerrilla group with bases in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>Despite some human rights concerns, the United States has broadly backed Turkey's controversial war against the PKK. But U.S. officials said the refugees they were talking about had no connection with the guerrilla group.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
