<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="439692" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Drug company's ex-CEO charged with fraud.</title>
<headline>Drug company's ex-CEO charged with fraud.</headline>
<byline>Leslie Gevirtz</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Federal prosecutors Thursday charged the former head of Astra U.S.A. with swindling his company of more than $1 million, failing to report the money on his income taxes and then trying to cover up his actions.</p>
<p>Lars Bildman, who was dismissed last April as president and chief executive of the pharmaceutical firm, &quot;used the company like a personal piggy bank,&quot; Deputy U.S. Attorney General Mark Pearlstein told a news conference.</p>
<p>Bildman, who is already facing a battery of civil allegations that he sexually harassed employees, is charged with using the money to charter yachts where prostitutes who charged up to $1,500 a day entertained him. He is also accused of using the funds to take his family to a posh British Virgin Island resort and to renovate his three homes.</p>
<p>He was scheduled for a court hearing on the 35-count indictment in Burlington, Vt., Thursday after his arrest at his chalet in the ski resort town of Killington, Vt. Pearlstein said prosecutors would argue that he be held without bail.</p>
<p>Astra U.S.A., a subsidiary of Swedish pharmaceutical giant Astra.AB, cooperated fully with the investigation, which is continuing, Pearlstein said.</p>
<p>Bildman allegedly chartered vessels from Palm Beach, Fla.-based Camper &amp; Nicholsons Yacht Brokers, according to the indictment. A call to the brokeage revealed it only offers fully crewed motor yachts and sailboats beginning with 50-foot vessels for about $16,000 a week.</p>
<p>&quot;The invoices for the chartered boats were submitted in such a fashion as to indicate that the boats were used for sales meetings,&quot; the indictment said.</p>
<p>Pearlstein said Bildman billed the company for his dalliances and vacations by claiming them to be legitimate business expenses, while the work by various contractors was &quot;buried in the cost&quot; of renovations going on at Astra U.S.A.'s corporate headquarters in Westborough, Mass.</p>
<p>Also indicted Thursday was Astra U.S.A.'s former chief financial officer, Stefan Solvell. Solvell, who left the company in the summer of 1995, is charged separately with failing to report income on his state and federal tax returns. He is also mentioned as conspiring to help Bildman bilk the company.</p>
<p>Bildman did report adjusted gross income of more than $1 million in 1993, 1994 and 1995, the indictment said. The problem, said Pearlstein, was that he failed to report the additional compensation in the form of goods and services he received without the company's knowledge. Pearlstein put that compensation at &quot;a little more than $1 million.&quot;</p>
<p>At about the same time that Businessweek magazine began investigating employees' complaints of sexual harassment as Astra U.S.A., Bildman and others at the company who were not named in the indictment allegedly began destroying documents and asked contractors who had done work on his homes to destroy their records.</p>
<p>When Astra dismissed Bildman it estimated its losses because of his actions at about $2 million. Asked about the difference in sums, Pearlstein replied, &quot;I can't comment except to say the investigation is continuing.&quot;</p>
<p>If found guilty, Bildman faces up to five years in prison and a $250,000 fine for each count of conspiracy, mail fraud, wire fraud and interstate travel for prostitution. He faces up to three years in prison and a $250,000 fine on each of the tax charges.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
