<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="439726" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT - Dollar revival or dead-cat bounce?.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Dollar revival or dead-cat bounce?.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar moved sharply higher on Thursday on technical forces having little to do with its own outlook, technical analysts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Investors dumped Swiss francs and yen, giving the dollar incidental support and lifting it from its recent range bottoms, chartists said.</p>
<p>But the greenback failed to convince analysts that it has the momentum to revisit recent multiyear highs without fresh corrective losses.</p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/Swiss was a leader, but it still looks pretty ugly,&quot; said Scott Siller at MCM CurrencyWatch.  </p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/Swiss lost support at 1.4525 before we got a surprising rebound, but I still think it's a sale under 1.4685,&quot; the MCM technical analyst added.</p>
<p>Dollar/mark followed a similar course, aided by Bundesbank council member Helmut Hesse's reported remarks that he saw no reason to intervene to cap dollar/mark. The greenback quickly rebounded from an early slump below support at 1.6920 marks.</p>
<p>&quot;Many people got caught short after the Hesse comment. It chased a lot of shorts out of the market, but that's not to say the dollar isn't toppish,&quot; said Keith Raphael, president of Crosscurrents Investment Advisory.  </p>
<p>Chartists expect the dollar to fall well short of last week's three-year high at 1.7210 marks, yielding a test of medium-term support near 1.6800-25. Dollar/Swiss could target support near 1.44, techs said.</p>
<p>Dollar/yen continues to draw residual support from the firming mark/yen cross, which for now seems content to crawl towards 72.50-55 resistance, technicians said.</p>
<p>Coming sessions could bring a test of 72.90 and 73.30, Fibonacci retracements of the decline from February's high of 75.29 to last week's low at 70.50.  </p>
<p>&quot;There's still a well-defined mark/yen bull channel,&quot; Siller said.</p>
<p>But like dollar/mark, dollar/yen is expected to hold below its February five-year high at 124.82.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the British pound sits precariously on a weekly support at $1.5970, which protects it from a two-percent move to the downside, said Raphael.</p>
<p>&quot;Sterling made only a very weak rally toward 2.73 marks today and it's vulnerable to a dip toward $1.5650 next week,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>(( --Chris Stetkiewicz, 212-859-1664 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
