<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="439898" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain says ETA suspect &quot;serious&quot; in hospital.</title>
<headline>Spain says ETA suspect &quot;serious&quot; in hospital.</headline>
<byline>Merissa Marr</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A presumed ETA member, detained on suspicion of killing a prison psychologist, was admitted to hospital in a serious condition on Thursday after two days of police interrogation, Spain's Interior Ministry said.</p>
<p>Suspected Basque separatist Fernando Elejalde arrived at a hospital in the northern city of San Sebastian with a number of fractured vertebrae and multiple contusions to the face and body, the hospital said.</p>
<p>The Interior Ministry, determined to get to the bottom of events, said it had started a probe.</p>
<p>&quot;The Interior Ministry has opened an internal investigation, which will run parallel to judicial investigations, to find out in the next 72 hours exactly what happened,&quot; the ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>Police said Elejalde, 29, was arrested on Tuesday after an extended gun battle with police as he ran from the scene of the murder of prison psychologist Javier Garcia Elosegui in San Sebastian.</p>
<p>Another attacker, a woman, fled the scene.</p>
<p>Elosegui's killing marked the seventh attack attributed to ETA (Basque Homeland and Freedom) since the beginning of the year.</p>
<p>ETA has killed some 800 people in a 29-year drive for an independent Basque state.</p>
<p>Sources involved in investigating the Elejalde case said they suspected he had sustained the injuries during his arrest as he had been hit by a car during a chase before he was captured.</p>
<p>In addition, they said he had come to blows with police during his arrest and a number of punches had been exchanged. A number of police officers had also been injured, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;But I can't explain why it took so long for him to be admitted to hospital,&quot; one source told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;I do know, though, that pain killers were administered to him after his arrest on Tuesday.&quot;</p>
<p>The Basque Nationalist Party (PNV), the leading political force in the region, demanded that Interior Minister Jaime Mayor Oreja explain the &quot;presumed torture&quot; suffered by Elejalde.</p>
<p>&quot;Independent of condemning the murder that cost the life of Elosegui, a free state cannot tolerate such presumed methods of torture which go directly against an individual's honour,&quot; the PNV said in a statement.</p>
<p>The Interior Ministry said it would present the findings of its investigation to Congress next week.</p>
<p>&quot;The results of the investigation will arrive on the Interior Minister's table in three days and we will then take the necessary and appropriate measures,&quot; a spokesman from the ministry told local radio.</p>
<p>Elejalde was arrested on Tuesday after neighbours warned police of the presence of people wearing ski masks in a street in the centre of the Basque town of San Sebastian.</p>
<p>Police arrived on the scene minutes after the shooting.</p>
<p>Elejalde fled and was pursued by three police officers. After an exchange of gunfire, police said they captured him after he was hit by a car.</p>
<p>Police have been interrogating him since then.</p>
<p>Elosegui's killing marked the seventh attack attributed to ETA since the beginning of the year.</p>
<p>ETA (Basque Homeland and Freedom) has killed some 800 people in a 29-year drive for an independent Basque state.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
