<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="439905" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Kohl says unclear what troops could do in Albania.</title>
<headline>Kohl says unclear what troops could do in Albania.</headline>
<dateline>THE HAGUE 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl said on Thursday the crisis in Albania was essentially an internal matter and it was unclear what western troops could do if sent to help restore order in the Balkan country.</p>
<p>Kohl was answering questions from reporters about Albania's request for western military aid.</p>
<p>&quot;It is quite clear that the events there are to a large extent a domestic matter. To put it quite bluntly, if you say we should send troops, then you would have to tell the soldiers what they would do there,&quot; Kohl said.</p>
<p>&quot;And if I put this question to you, which I can't answer, then you can see my response.&quot;</p>
<p>Kohl was speaking after talks with Dutch Prime Minister Wim Kok, whose country holds the European Union presidency during the first half of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;We are keeping in close contact with each other. We are not able to make any political pronouncements at the moment other than to say that the whole situation there is very worrying... but the question of how you can provide support cannot be answered,&quot; Kok told reporters.</p>
<p>Both Kohl and Kok said they wanted to see the United Nations Security Council deal with the situation as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>Albanian President Sali Berisha and all political parties had called earlier on Thursday for NATO's European members to provide the military assistance &quot;to restore the constitutional order and to preserve the country's integrity&quot;.</p>
<p>Dutch Foreign Minister Hans van Mierlo had said earlier in the day that the European Union was seriously considering Albania's request.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as I am concerned all options are open and the request deserves serious consideration,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>EU foreign ministers are due to meet this weekend in the Dutch town of Apeldoorn for informal talks which are to centre on the situation in Albania and other key foreign policy issues.</p>
<p>Albania slid further towards anarchy on Thursday as gunfire crackled around the capital of Tirana and authorities closed the main airport after a nearby military base was looted.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="THE HAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
