<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44001" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs end mostly strong, bellies end weak.</title>
<headline>CME hogs end mostly strong, bellies end weak.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME hog futures slipped from best levels but remained strong at the close on strong cash expectations into the weekend and technical fund short covering. Pork bellies fell again late as early short covering lacked followthrough, traders said.</p>
<p>Commercial demand developed in hog futures near chart support and this resulted in futures looking technically strong. Initial selling came on talk of steady to weak cash markets Wednesday, but the longer term outlook for cash into the weekend calls for a firmer cash market as packer demand looks strong, traders said.</p>
<p>Most pork products are showing a firmer undertone and pork product prices are seen rising into late September and through October, National Pork Month. Added technical demand took futures to two week highs before prices slipped on profit taking, they said.</p>
<p>Late fund rolling, commonly known as the &quot;Goldman roll&quot;, also weighed on October while lifting December. Refco notably sold October and bought December, pit sources said.</p>
<p>In hog options, Refco was also most active, selling the October 52 put/56 call strangle and selling December 57 calls early, pit sources added.  </p>
<p>Pork belly futures trade was very erratic with prices falling again late to close 1.100 cent lower to unchanged with February off most at 75.550 cents.</p>
<p>Bellies fell sharply early with prices down as much as the daily limit of 2.000 cents in May before rallying for net gains before midsession. Carryover technical pressure pushed futures down into sell stops early but prices recovered after February held support near 75.200 cents, traders said.</p>
<p>Spillover strength from hogs added to support and futures posted gains before retreating again late on scattered selling which touched off closing sell stops, they said.</p>
<p>The early short covering lacked followthrough, especially with overhanging pressure coming from continued slow demand for product and the easier cash market. Cash bellies eased at noon and expectations are for hog slaughter to increase going into the weekend, they said.</p>
<p>After the close, USDA reported estimated hog slaughter at 366,000 head, above the high end of early estimates.</p>
<p>CME also reported the weekly out-of-town movement at down 1.684 million lbs. This compared with early estimates of down 0.5 to 0.75 million lbs.</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
