<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="440086" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Mother Teresa's successor seeks prayer for courage.</title>
<headline>Mother Teresa's successor seeks prayer for courage.</headline>
<byline>Rupam Banerjee</byline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA, India 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sister Nirmala, a Hindu Brahmin who converted to Roman Catholicism, was elected on Thursday to succeed the ailing Mother Teresa as the head of her renowned religious order and immediately appealed for prayers.</p>
<p>&quot;God will give me the courage to carry out our work with the guidance of Mother Teresa,&quot; a smiling Sister Nirmala told reporters at the Missionaries of Charity headquarters in Calcutta. &quot;Please pray for me.&quot;</p>
<p>Her head covered by the order's traditional blue-trimmed white sari, the 63-year-old bespectacled scholar was elected on Thursday after an eight-week selection effort that ended with a closed-door vote by 132 senior nuns.</p>
<p>&quot;I pray that she will be able to carry out her job with God's blessings,&quot; Mother Teresa told reporters after the near-unanimous choice of Sister Nirmala was announced.</p>
<p>&quot;Please pray for her. Please pray for us,&quot; the 86-year-old Nobel Peace Prize winner said.</p>
<p>In a written statement, Mother Teresa asked for prayers to help &quot;our sisters strive to give God's tender love and care to His poor&quot;.</p>
<p>Sister Frederick, who had been considered one of the front-runners for the post of superior general and was elected the second ranking nun, said: &quot;God is always working out the best thing for us.&quot;</p>
<p>Sisters Nirmala and Priscilla, the order's spokeswoman and one of four councillors-general, appeared briefly for a photograph on a balcony with Mother Teresa, who has headed the religious order for nearly half a century.</p>
<p>They then withdrew inside the headquarters, called Mother House, where nuns could be heard singing and laughing.</p>
<p>A news conference was set for Friday morning when Mother Teresa was to turn over her administrative powers -- but not her title &quot;Mother&quot; -- to her 63-year-old successor.</p>
<p>&quot;Mother Teresa remains as Mother and foundress,&quot; the Missionaries of Charity said in a statement. &quot;Sister Nirmala is the new Superior General.&quot;</p>
<p>Sister Christine, one of the order's nuns, said: &quot;It's great that Sister Nirmala has been elected with God's will, but we will continue to have our Mother with us. We get inspiration from her and I believe Sister Nirmala with her blessings will ably lead the organisation.&quot;</p>
<p>Sister Nirmala, whose name in Sanskrit means &quot;pure&quot;, takes over a 49-year-old order that has been led since its creation by the charismatic Mother Teresa, who won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1979 and has become a symbol of devotion to the sick and poor.</p>
<p>Mother Teresa never groomed a successor to lead the order, which has 4,500 nuns in more than 100 countries.</p>
<p>Twice before the order, dependent on her leadership and ability to attract funds, refused to bow to Mother Teresa's wish to step down. But after being taken to hospital for emergency care three times last year and having undergone a heart operation, Mother Teresa said she would finally step down.</p>
<p>Sister Nirmala was born into an ethnic Nepali family in the northern Indian state of Bihar. A member of the Hindu Brahmin, or priestly, class, she converted to Catholicism at the age of 24.</p>
<p>She has a master's degree in political science and studied law before opening the order's first mission outside India, in Panama.</p>
<p>Sister Nirmala has supervised the order's centres in Europe and the United States. Since 1979, she has led the contemplative wing, in which nuns devote their lives to meditation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
