<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="440079" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Brussels Bel-20 to consolidate until next week.</title>
<headline>Brussels Bel-20 to consolidate until next week.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian shares, which fell on Thursday on the back of weaker world stock and bond markets, were expected to see further consolidation into next week, but could then rise again.</p>
<p>&quot;This is what we need, it's good for the health of the market after recent crazy runs, but then we'll go back up again,&quot; said one trader at a major Belgian bank.</p>
<p>The blue-chip Bel-20  .BFX index, which has seen 25 record closing highs so far this year, ended down 0.85 percent, or 18.79 points, at 2,191.82, with a firm 3.3 billion francs worth of Belgian shares traded.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the bourse would follow the direction of Wall Street  .DJI and European markets, but could start rising after a bout of profit-taking as more cash was expected to come into the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Brussels will follow New York, and if Wall Street continues to fall, we'll follow suit,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The focus was on bank shares as some investors took profits after recent bull runs which were spurred on by speculation of a merger in the sector, particularly between Generale Bank and rival BBL.  </p>
<p>Generale Bank closed down 1.3 percent at 13,525 and BBL ended down 0.2 percent at 8,340 francs.</p>
<p>Attention had also focused on Kredietbank which after the bourse close said 1996 group net profit up 13.5 percent, this was somewhat better than market expectations.</p>
<p>Kredietbank closed up 0.38 percent at 13,250 francs.</p>
<p>Kredietbank denied market talk that it was in merger talks with French Credit Commercial de France (CCF), adding that both banks had been &quot;good friends&quot; for many years.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the Bel-20's main loser, steel cord and wire maker Bekaert, fell 3.08 percent to 22,000 francs.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the share fell after investors decided to take profits after recent sharp rises and a weaker dollar.</p>
<p>Retailer GIB  GBIBt.RB fell 3.1 percent to 1,585 francs, with investors taking profits after recent sharp rises.</p>
<p>Another large loser, oil and chemicals group Petrofina closed down 2.43 percent at 12,050 francs, on the back of profit-taking, weaker oil prices and a lower dollar.</p>
<p>But polyurethane foam maker Recticel's preferred share jumped 9.2 percent to 441 francs after better than expected 1996 results and upgrade ratings from major Belgian institutions.</p>
<p>-- Paul de Bendern, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6813, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
