<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="440263" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Aronex plans Q2 Phase II Annamycin trials.</title>
<headline>Aronex plans Q2 Phase II Annamycin trials.</headline>
<dateline>WOODLANDS, Texas 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aronex Pharmaceuticals Inc said Thursday that based on preliminary Phase I clinical safety trials of its chemotherapy drug Annamycin, it will move to a Phase II efficacy trial in the second quarter.</p>
<p>A novel anthracycline analog, Annamycin was developed for use in patients whose cancer does not respond to available chemotherapy because they patients have developed resistance to multiple drugs.  </p>
<p>&quot;Annamycin was designed to overcome two primary limitations of anthracycline agents currently on the market: MDR (multiple drug resistance) and irreversible cardiotoxicity,&quot; Aronex President James Chubb said.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe Phase I data has provided us with a good indication of the maximum tolerated dose, potential therapeutic dose, and safety profile of Annamycin,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The drug has the potential for use against a wide variety of solid tumors, leukemias and lymphomas, the company said.  </p>
<p>Phase I dose-escalating safety trials involved 30 cancer patients who had failed all previous therapy. Patients were suffering primarily from breast cancer, lung cancer, colon cancer or melanoma, Aronex said.</p>
<p>Side effects associated with other anthracycline drugs, like cardiotoxicity, hair loss, inflammation of mucous membranes or skin reactions, were not apparent, it said.</p>
<p>Findings were consistent with preclinical trials, it said. Preclinical efficacy trials demonstrated Annamycin was very effective in reducing tumor size in several animal models growing human cancers that were resistant to doxorubicin, a widely prescribed anthracycline, it said.</p>
<p>Annamycin was believed to exert activity in drug-resistant tumors by maintaining effective concentrations inside tumor cells, Aronex said.</p>
<p>Phase II efficacy trials will be done on patients with metastatic breast cancer showing resistance to therapies, the company said.</p>
<p>((--New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WOODLANDS, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
