<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="440427" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: ROYALE BELGE BUYS UAP UNIT IN SWEDEN.</title>
<headline>ROYALE BELGE BUYS UAP UNIT IN SWEDEN.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian insurer Royale Belge SA said on Thursday it had finally achieved its long-stated strategic objective of gaining a foothold in Scandinavia after many years observing from the sidelines.</p>
<p>Chief executive officer Jean-Pierre Gerard told a news conference on the group's 1996 results it acquired the Swedish non-life business of French insurer UAP France at the beginning of 1997. Terms were not disclosed.</p>
<p>UAP France is a unit of the AXA-UAP group , which also jointly controls Royale Belge with Belgium's Groupe Bruxelles Lambert .</p>
<p>Royale Belge has long presented itself as UAP's northern expansion arm, with particular focus on the Benelux and Scandinavia, but until this acquisition the closed nature of much of the region's insurance sector had meant the goal was unfulfilled.</p>
<p>Gerard said Sweden's accession to the European Union meant the sector now presented new opportunities and he did not rule out further acquisitions.</p>
<p>&quot;For us it's an observation post on the Swedish and Scandinavian market...We will look at all opportunities that present themselves,&quot; Gerard said.</p>
<p>The Swedish non-life business of UAP had premium income of 176.4 million Swedish crowns (810 million Belgian francs) and had a profit of eight million crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a small company working in niches, such as insurance of goods being transported and products linked to the social security sector,&quot; Gerard said.</p>
<p>-- Nick Antonovics, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6817, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
