<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="440690" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FBI dismisses Navy missile theory in TWA crash.</title>
<headline>FBI dismisses Navy missile theory in TWA crash.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Federal investigators on Wednesday dismissed claims that a U.S. Navy missile shot down TWA Flight 800 off Long Island, New York, last year.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just not true,&quot; lead investigator James Kallstrom said on NBC's &quot;Today Show.&quot;</p>
<p>The assistant director of the FBI's New York office said investigators have reviewed every available radar picture of the accident and concluded there was no evidence of a missile being fired.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no missile flying up at this plane on any of the radar tapes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He also disputed claims by former presidential spokesman and television correspondent Pierre Salinger that there was a coverup of U.S. Navy involvement in the crash.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as Salinger is concerned, almost all of what he says is wrong. All I can tell you is it's wrong,&quot; Kallstrom said.</p>
<p>Salinger has scheduled a news conference for Thursday in Paris. Kallstrom said Salinger was expected to announce at that time that he had an audiotape of navy personnel expressing regret that they had shot down the TWA plane.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't believe that it exists,&quot; Kallstrom said. &quot;It's a cruel hoax. All of these people (with conspiracy theories) should get a life.&quot;</p>
<p>Kallstrom was responding to reports of evidence that a missile caused the Boeing 747 to explode in midair off New York's Long Island shortly after takeoff last July 17, killing all 230 people on board.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Salinger told the Washington Times in an interview published on Thursday that the U.S. government should &quot;reveal the truth&quot; or face Russian disclosure based on satellite photography.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't want to get the Russians involved, but unless the U.S. government cooperates, we may have to,&quot; Salinger told the newspaper.</p>
<p>Salinger and an investigative team he assembled were expected to release on Thursday a 45-page report on the TWA crash concluding that Flight 800 was &quot;shot down by a 'standard missile' fitted with a secret 'kinetic kill' or continuous rod warhead,&quot; the Times said.</p>
<p>Two Russian satellites active above the scene of the disaster had produced videotapes showing a missile hitting the TWA aircraft, according to the Salinger report.</p>
<p>Law enforcement sources said on Wednesday that the FBI had requested and obtained a copy of a tape that former United Airlines pilot Richard Russell has said also shows the plane was shot down.</p>
<p>Russell said the videotape, allegedly a copy of a Federal Aviation Administration radar tape, shows an object streaking toward the plane seconds before it exploded after leaving Kennedy Airport on a flight to Paris.</p>
<p>The retired pilot also posted an Internet message last year alleging a U.S. Navy missile was involved in the crash.</p>
<p>National Transportation Safety Board and FBI investigators have made statements indicating mechanical failure rather than a bomb or missile may have been responsible. Investigators know the centre fuel tank on the plane exploded, but so far have not been able to explain why.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
