<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44062" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wal-Mart bans Sheryl Crow album for gun-sale lyrics.</title>
<headline>Wal-Mart bans Sheryl Crow album for gun-sale lyrics.</headline>
<dateline>BENTONVILLE, Ark 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wal-Mart Stores Inc. is refusing to sell award-winning rock singer Sheryl Crow's new album because it contains an anti-violence song suggesting the giant retailer sells guns to children, a spokesman said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Wal-Mart recognises we'll take a financial hit by doing this, but to do otherwise would not be fair to our employees who work so hard to help children, not harm them,&quot; said Dale Ingram, spokesman for the largest U.S. retailer.</p>
<p>Ingram said Wal-Mart has strict policies which prohibit the sale of guns to minors.</p>
<p>&quot;For us to profit from a lyric that says we harm children willingly would be irresponsible and unfair,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The album, entitled &quot;Sheryl Crow,&quot; is due for release by A&amp;M Records on Sept. 24. Crow won three Grammy Awards in 1995 after the release of her best-selling first album &quot;Tuesday Night Music Club.&quot;</p>
<p>Large retail chains like Wal-Mart regularly ban records with lyrics they say are excessively violent or sexually explicit but Crow's songs fall into neither of those categories.</p>
<p>The offending song on the new Crow album is called &quot;Love Is a Good Thing&quot; and contains the following lyric: &quot;Watch out sister, watch out brother, Watch our children as they kill each other, With a gun they bought at the Wal-Mart discount stores.&quot;</p>
<p>Ingram said Wal-Mart did not ask Crow to edit the song but would not sell the album. However, it will continue to stock her first album.</p>
<p>Wal-Mart, which employs more than 670,000 people, has been hit with at least two lawsuits in recent years from the relatives of people killed with guns bought at its stores.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BENTONVILLE, Ark"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
