<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="440720" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. 1996 current account gap highest in nine years.</title>
<headline>U.S. 1996 current account gap highest in nine years.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. current account deficit, the broadest measure of the nation's trade performance, climbed to its highest level in nine years in 1996, the Commerce Department said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The total deficit in trade in goods and services, in investment income and in so-called unilateral transfers like direct grants to other countries rose to $165.1 billion from $148.2 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>Department officials said it was the biggest gap in total trade for any year since 1987, when there was a $167.4 billion deficit.</p>
<p>The current account is the country's most important trade statistic because it measures trade not only in merchandise and services, but also investment flows between countries.</p>
<p>In the three months from October through December, the deficit decreased to $41.4 billion from $47.9 billion in the third quarter. But that was still well above Wall Street analysts' forecast of a $38.8 billion fourth-quarter shortfall.</p>
<p>In the final three months last year, the deficits in goods and services and in investment income declined from the third quarter. But the department noted there was a bump upward in unilateral transfers because of higher U.S. government grants to Israel.</p>
<p>The fourth-quarter deficit in goods and services trade fell to $26.3 billion from $34.3 billion in the third quarter, while the shortfall on investment income was down to $2.4 billion from $4.1 billion as U.S. assets abroad increased strongly.</p>
<p>But unilateral transfers climbed to $12.6 billion in the fourth quarter from $9.5 billion in the third quarter because of the increase in grants to Israel.</p>
<p>For the full year, the department said that deficits in goods and services, in investment income and in unilateral transfers all increased from 1995.</p>
<p>There were net capital inflows to the United States last year of $218.2 billion, up from $116.6 billion in 1995. &quot;An acceleration in foreign assets in the United States accounted for the larger net capital inflows,&quot; the department said.</p>
<p>Purchases of U.S. Treasury securities, other types of securities and direct foreign investments in the United States were sharply higher last year than in 1995, Commerce said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
