<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="440913" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian bank merger only matter of time - analysts.</title>
<headline>Belgian bank merger only matter of time - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Paul de Bendern</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Belgian bank sector is moving inexorably towards concentration in the run up to European economic and monetary union, traders and analysts believe.</p>
<p>Belgium is overbanked and needs institutions large enough to serve a single European market of over 300 million people, they say.</p>
<p>Economies of scale will be important, particularly in absorbing the huge costs to the banks of introducing the single European currency, which is scheduled for launch in 1999. Merger speculation centres on Generale Bank, Belgium's largest bank, and the fourth biggest Banque Bruxelles Lambert (BBL). The rumours, which have been circulating for almost a year, resurfaced recently.</p>
<p>In January Etienne Davignon, chairman of Societe Generale de Belgique (SGB), Generale bank's parent, said a merger between the two banks was still an attractive business proposition.</p>
<p>A foreign banker based in Brussels later refocused attention on the need for concentration by saying that Belgium needed European-sized banks with assets of at least $500 billion. All four top Belgian banks would have to link up to create a bank of that size.</p>
<p>Merger talk has sparked a wave of buying of top bank shares. Generale Bank shares were down 175 francs at 13,525 on Thursday afternoon but dealers said the mark-down represented a bout of profit-taking rather than a reversal of views on the sector.</p>
<p>At earnings news conferences this week BBL and Generale Bank chiefs played their cards close to their chests, but did not completely rule out the idea of a &quot;Grande Banque Belge&quot;.</p>
<p>Philippe Liotier, chief executive officer of SGB, said in an interview this week that SGB would support a merger with BBL, although no talks were underway. That cageyness was not the reason for Thursday's slight profit-taking in bank shares, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The banks which have the most to benefit from the speculation are coming back a bit. It's not because of denials or because the market is disappointed that nothing has been announced yet,&quot; said an analyst at brokerage Petercam.</p>
<p>There were very few sellers of bank shares. &quot;Investors who are convinced of the (merger) story wouldn't sell now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the afternoon SGB was down 20 francs at 2,885 francs and BBL down 10 at 8,350.</p>
<p>Dealers said bank shares were not overvalued. Generale Bank and BBL, which have seen rises of almost 14 percent since the end of February, were not likely to suffer dramatic falls.</p>
<p>One trader said some in the market favoured a merger since it would create a bank strong enough to deal with European competition and ally with other European banks. But others said a merger would be costly and it would be difficult to blend two long-standing rivals.</p>
<p>&quot;It would take a very long time to integrate two different institutions and only show profitability in the medium to long term,&quot; said the Petercam analyst.</p>
<p>Dealers said that if a merger was on the cards it would not be announced soon because of unrest in Belgium over job losses and the inevitability that such a merger would force layoffs.</p>
<p>Belgian media have speculated that Belgian financier Albert Frere is a driving force behind a Generale/BBL merger. Frere, who controls Groupe Bruxelles Lambert (GBL), BBL's parent company, recently bought into the capital of Cie de Suez, the French group which controls Societe Generale de Belgique.</p>
<p>A merger between BBL and Generale would enable Frere to cash in on his BBL shares.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
