<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="441023" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Further tinplate mergers seen possible in Europe.</title>
<headline>Further tinplate mergers seen possible in Europe.</headline>
<dateline>DUESSELDORF 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Manufacturers of tinplated steel in Europe may restructure their operations in line with developments in the can-making industry, a statement from the producer-funded promotion agency IZW said.</p>
<p>The leading three consumers which process tinplate into can feedstock now represented two thirds of total European demand while production capacity was still fragmented, it said.</p>
<p>Packaging companies Schmalbach Lubeca /Continental Can Europe (CCE) and Pechiney announced last November they would establish a joint company for metals packaging in 1997.</p>
<p>These canstock companies were operating throughout Europe and in third countries and were able to pursue aggressive cost savings.</p>
<p>While there was only low growth potential in metal packaging demand, tinplate producers, whose number has already shrunk to seven, were still grappling with over-capacity.</p>
<p>&quot;These trends will be the greatest challenge to the tinplate industry in the next few years,&quot; the statement quoted Jost Massenberg, board member at Germany's Rasselstein Hoesch GmbH, as saying.</p>
<p>Tinplated steel has captured 55 percent of the beverage can market in Europe and its share has been rising at the expense of aluminium, which was affected by price volatility.</p>
<p>But overall European tinplate demand was merely steady at four million tonnes a year -- out of a global 16 million -- because of material savings and substitution.</p>
<p>In Germany, tinplate demand was falling.</p>
<p>Rasselstein, with a 20 percent share of the European tinplate market, merged its operations with Krupp Hoesch Stahl AG in 1995.</p>
<p>Rasselstein has been exporting 400,000 tonnes a year to third countries, which makes it the leading world exporter.</p>
<p>--Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I31000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUESSELDORF"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
