<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="441120" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: Estonian privatisation drive shifts to lower gear.</title>
<headline>Estonian privatisation drive shifts to lower gear.</headline>
<byline>Belinda Goldsmith</byline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Estonia's privatisation programme is starting to slow down with most industries now sold and a second phase of privatisation starting, the head of the Estonian Privatisation Agency (EPA) said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Director general Vaino Sarnet said around 20 medium sized businesses would be privatised this year. The details of the sale of a 51 percent slice of scrap metal exporter Estonian Metal Export Co (EMEX) were announced on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;This year about 20 medium or bigger companies will be privatised,&quot; Sarnet told Reuters in an interview in his office in the Estonian capital.</p>
<p>&quot;This is modest compared to previous years when the number was between 100 and 200.&quot;</p>
<p>The pace of privatisation in Estonia since the former Soviet Republic regained independence in 1991 has been rapid and helped fuel economic growth in the Baltic nation with Gross Domestic Product rising 4.5 percent in 1996 and seen rising up to five percent in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;This speed would likely have resulted in potentially serious political and social dislocations had it not been for the relatively dynamic private sector that started to develop in 1992, absorbing a significant proportion of labour shed,&quot; Sarnet said.</p>
<p>Preliminary figures from the EPA estimate the growth of the private sector resulted in an increase in its share of GDP to about 75 percent in mid-1996 from five-10 percent late 1991.</p>
<p>To date about 452 privatisation agreements have been signed through tender with preliminary negotiations and the total number of privatised auction objects reached 1,241.</p>
<p>There are still 50 auction objects in the sale list.</p>
<p>&quot;It can be said the privatisation of the Estonian industry is coming to an end and to be replaced by the privatisation of infrastructure and utility companies in 1997,&quot; Sarnet said.</p>
<p>He said about 70 percent of the enterprises sold by the EPA so far were bought by foreign interests.</p>
<p>By the end of March 1996 foreign owners had invested US$701 million in Estonia and owned an estimated 30-40 percent of capital in Estonian industrial and services sector.</p>
<p>&quot;The experience in Estonia has been that outsiders tended to bring modern management and marketing skills as well as the capacity to make capita investments, all of which were crucial for effective turnaround,&quot; Sarnet said.</p>
<p>Interest had been particularly strong from Finland, Sweden and Russia but interest from the U.S., Germany and Britain was starting to pick-up as the EPA embarked on the second phase of privatisation, selling infrastructure and utility companies.</p>
<p>&quot;This will really start next year because of political reasons to adopt specific laws that are necessary before these sales can go ahead,&quot; Sarnet said.</p>
<p>The list includes Estonian Railways, Estonian Energy, Tallinn Port, Estonian Oil Shale Mining Co and telecommunications holding company Estonian Telecoms.</p>
<p>U.S. power group Northern States Power Co is in the final stages of negotiations over a joint venture on Estonia's two main power stations and Sarnet said the U.S.'s Duke Power Co had been in informal talks over power distribution.</p>
<p>&quot;Several overseas companies have expressed interest in Estonian Telecom but all we can say is that no firm decision has been made yet,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>One proposal was to float 25 percent of Estonian Telecom in either Stockholm or London in 1998.</p>
<p>-- Tallinn newsroom +372 630 8400</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
