<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="441444" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul stocks end lower, blue chips lead decline.</title>
<headline>Seoul stocks end lower, blue chips lead decline.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seoul shares ended Thursday's trading lower after profit-taking in blue chips eroded earlier narrow gains, brokers said.</p>
<p>The composite index fell 6.00 points to a provisional close of 657.90. Decliners beat advancers 487 to 302. Volume was an active 32 million shares.</p>
<p>Brokers said the market's fundamental weakness caught up with trading again after Wednesday's brief rebound.</p>
<p>&quot;Fundamentally the market is at a bottom, and sentiment is what is moving the index up and down,&quot; a KLB Securities fund manager said.  </p>
<p>Preparation for Thursday's settlement deadline for March futures contracts sent blue chips climbing on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The June futures contracts closed 0.40 of a point lower at 64.15 on Thursday, while the underlying KOSPI-200 index fell 0.52 of a point to 66.31.</p>
<p>Brokers said the market was still plagued by a slowing economy, high interest rates and a weakening won.</p>
<p>Samsung Electronics declined on profit-taking after Wednesday's gains. It lost 1,200 won to 52,500. Yukong fell 400 won to 14,900, Hyundai Motor shed 500 won to 24,000, and KEPCO fell 400 won to 25,600.  </p>
<p>Individual theme-backed shares had climbed during Thursday's morning trading, but declined later as weak fundamentals overwhelmed the buying sentiment.</p>
<p>Some pharmaceutical shares, which rose on talk of new drug discoveries, fell. Han All Pharmaceuticals, which had risen to 12,000 won per share, closed 400 won lower at 11,100.</p>
<p>Shindongbang shares ended 1,400 won lower at 34,100. A company official told Reuters its hostile takeover bid for Midopa Department Store was unlikely to be settled by a compromise. Midopa lost 2,300 won to 27,600, while its parent Dainong shed 220 won to 6,900.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
