<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="441441" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Nikkei futures end sharply off, outlook poor.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Nikkei futures end sharply off, outlook poor.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Nikkei futures ended sharply lower on Thursday after falling below a key support level as sentiment turned bearish in the underlying cash market.</p>
<p>The Nikkei 225 March contract ended its last trading day on SIMEX 25 points below a long-standing support level of 17,800 points, against a previous close at 18,105.</p>
<p>The June contract lost 345 points to 17,710.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a last minute squeeze out of the March contract,&quot; said a trader with a local house, noting that both March and June hit intra-day lows just before the close.  </p>
<p>&quot;The medium-term support at 17,750-17,800 just cracked open and technically, the market looks set to go lower,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market was hit by worries about Japanese securities houses after Nomura Securities Co's disclosure last week that two of its directors had been involved in suspected illegal deals.</p>
<p>Late afternoon rumours that Daiwa Securities Co Ltd was being inspected by Japan's securities' watchdog further bruised confidence, but Daiwa told Reuters it was undergoing a routine inspection, not a special check.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think there are going to be more bad things going into the end of the month,&quot; said the trader.</p>
<p>He said the June Nikkei was likely to trade a 17,520-17,800 range on Friday, but looked set for a target of 17,350 in the medium-term.</p>
<p>The March MSCI Taiwan index contract ended at 349.8 against its opening 349.0 on volume of 685 lots.</p>
<p>-- Sonali Desai (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
