<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="441497" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan economy shows steady signs of recovery.</title>
<headline>Japan economy shows steady signs of recovery.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's economy posted steady growth in the three months to the end of December and for calendar 1996, confirming that a gradual recovery is still in motion, the government said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The nation's gross domestic product (GDP) -- total output of goods and services minus net income from overseas production -- rose a real 1.0 percent in the October-December period from the previous quarter, or an annualised 3.9 percent.  </p>
<p>This compared with a revised quarter-on-quarter GDP rise of 0.3 percent for the July-September quarter.</p>
<p>In calendar 1996, the nation's GDP -- a closely watched pointer to the health of the economy -- rose a real 3.6 percent from the previous year after a revised figure of 1.4 percent growth in 1995, the Economic Planning Agency (EPA) said.</p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters ahead of the announcement had predicted, on average, that October-December GDP would rise by 0.8 percent quarter-on-quarter. The forecasts had ranged from 0.3 percent to 1.2 percent growth. They had expected GDP to grow by more than three percent for calendar 1996.</p>
<p>Although the data confirmed that the economy was improving, economists said it was still too early to judge whether solid recovery had really taken hold.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
