<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="441569" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan stocks end at 6-year high, but only barely.</title>
<headline>Taiwan stocks end at 6-year high, but only barely.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan share prices inched up slightly to six-year high close, as hopes for an imminent end to a 47-year ban on Taiwan-China shipping outweighed profit-taking amid signs that a big 1997 rally was slowing.</p>
<p>The benchmark stock index ended with a scant 13.08 point or 0.16 percent gain at 8,268.15 after a surging as high as 8,299.14 and dipping as low as 8,179.74.</p>
<p>Thursday's close surpassed the 8,255.07 finish on March 12 to marked the index's highest close since it reached 8,569.55 on May 15, 1990. Turnover was hectic but, at T$165.1 billion, somewhat less than Wednesday's sizzling T$179.57 billion.  </p>
<p>Most major sectors fell, including textile, food and paper shares. Transports and cements gained 0.46 and 1.44 percent.</p>
<p>Transport shares were sharply higher most of the day on reports that China would allow Taiwan shippers to sail direct Taiwan-China routes, ending a 47-year-old ban, but profit-taking by short-term investors eroded the gains, brokers said.</p>
<p>Associated Transport rose to its uplimit of seven percent to T$36.7, gaining T$2.4., while Yang Ming Marine gained T$0.8 to T$38.8.</p>
<p>Chia Hsin Cement gained T$1.5 to T$31. Chien Tai cement earned T$0.9 at T$22.8, brokers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Despite resistance pressure at 8,400, investors were still confident in the market and quickly bought in when share prices eased lower at midsession,&quot; said Nomura Securities' Amy Huang.</p>
<p>Brokers said anticipation of a property rebound and direct shipping links with China staved off a downturn for the index.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors hold an optimistic view toward transport shares on the improving future of shipping links with mainland China,&quot; Chen Han-chung, manager of Yungli Securities said.</p>
<p>Investors' anticipation of a property market recovery after years of recession was the main factor behind the cement sector rise, brokers said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
