<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44168" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS - Cerus bid talk sends Paris bourse into fever.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Cerus bid talk sends Paris bourse into fever.</headline>
<byline>Pierre Tran</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Newspaper leaks, denials and what were seen as half-denials over investment company CGIP's reported bid for holding group Cerus sent the Paris bourse into overdrive on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been very detailed and accurate information in the newspapers. It's clear there have been detailed negotiations going on,&quot; a senior salesman in a large French brokerage said.</p>
<p>Although CGIP denied French newspapers reports it was preparing a public offer, it said was in talks with Italian businessman Carlo de Benedetti on other options. The market now wants to know what those options are.</p>
<p>By the close, more than 1.7 million Cerus shares traded, worth over 238 million French francs. The market viewed Cerus was still in play.</p>
<p>Index heavyweight Elf Aquitaine topped that volume, with some 706 million francs of stock traded.</p>
<p>But the market focus was firmly fixed on the unravelling Cerus story, which whipped round the Cerus stock from riser to faller and caused it to be suspended limit-down.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no smoke without fire,&quot; said one analyst. &quot;The newspaper details were too precise.&quot;</p>
<p>Cerus closed down 2.80 francs at 133, or 2.06 percent, while Valeo, in which it holds a 28 percent stake, ended up 9.10 francs at 279.60.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index closed up 21.82 points or 1.08 percent at 2,042.12. Market volume was a hefty 6.01 billion francs.</p>
<p>Some market operators expressed annoyance at the slowness of company statements from CGIP and electronics firm Sagem, which were price sensitive and released in trading hours, following the publication of newspaper reports. &quot;Don't they read the newspapers?&quot; said one peeved analyst.</p>
<p>Sagem denied newspaper reports that it had agreed to buy an eventual stake in Valeo although it had been in talks over cooperation over an electronic car.</p>
<p>The fall in Cerus shares and the retracing in Valeo stock in the light of the company statements showed the market was waiting for more information.</p>
<p>CGIP closed up 34 francs at 1,189, recovering from the morning's weakness. This morning's newspaper reports of the terms on the Cerus deal looked unfavourable to CGIP, said one broker, and the denial helped the stock regain ground.</p>
<p>The Cerus sale still looked likely as de Bernadetti needs cash for his ailing Italian businesses but it only needed the right terms, analysts said. Valeo was caught up in the horse-trading, as it is the crown jewel in the Cerus group.</p>
<p>From an industrial standpoint, Valeo would benefit from a partner such as TRW, but since there was political and commercial opposition to a U.S. buyer, CGIP was a reasonable French solution.</p>
<p>CGIP had a better investment record than Cerus, demonstrated in the sale of its stake in Paris-based packaging group CarnaudMetalbox to Crown Cork &amp; Seal Co Inc of the United States, said a broker.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
