<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="441715" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French politician urges Renault boss quit.</title>
<headline>French politician urges Renault boss quit.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior politician in France's ruling coalition said on Thursday that Renault SA chairman Louis Schweitzer had committed an &quot;irreparable mistake&quot; in the way he announced the closure of a car plant in Belgium and should quit.</p>
<p>Jean-Francois Mancel, secretary-general and number two to Prime Minister Alain Juppe in the conservative Gaullist RPR party, told Europe 1 radio that Schweitzer had &quot;committed a very serious mistake by offending human dignity&quot;.</p>
<p>The chairman of the recently-privatised car firm, expected to announce heavy losses next week, triggered political anger in Belgium and France by announcing on February 27 the closure of the Vilvoorde assembly plant in the Brussels suburbs, with the loss of 3,100 direct jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever necessities an employer may face in having to make people redundant, he must not fail to respect the employees as human beings. Coming from a very big captain of industry, this is an irreparable mistake and he should take the consequences,&quot; Mancel said.</p>
<p>Mancel, who often reflects Juppe's views, was the most senior politician to call for the resignation of Schweitzer, a former top civil servant who moved to Renault after serving as top aide to Socialist prime minister Laurent Fabius in 1984-86.</p>
<p>A Renault spokeswoman said the company had no comment on calls for Schweitzer resignation, which she called a &quot;political debate&quot;.</p>
<p>The Renault board confirmed Schweitzer's mandate as chairman last July 26 at its first meeting after the French state gave up its majority control in the company. He had been re-elected in May 1994 for five years.</p>
<p>The state is still the biggest shareholder with 46 percent but Juppe has insisted that the management is free to take business decisions without government intervention.</p>
<p>Renault was to formally notify its French works council on Thursday of plans to shed 2,764 jobs in France this year in addition to the Belgian closure. Unions have called for work stoppages at its French plants in protest.</p>
<p>The company has been reducing its staff over the past decade and last year eliminated 1,640 jobs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
