<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="441766" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU Commission agrees controversial energy tax plan.</title>
<headline>EU Commission agrees controversial energy tax plan.</headline>
<byline>Amelia Torres</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission agreed a controversial draft law on Wednesday to raise the minimum taxes on motor and heating fuels and extend the taxes to electricity and natural gas.</p>
<p>The plan is fiercely opposed by industry, particularly heavy-energy users such as the chemical and automobile sectors. EU finance ministers will have the final word -- a task far from easy since they are required to reach a unanimous decision.</p>
<p>It is widely seen as an attempt to introduce a failed carbon dioxide tax to reduce gas emissions by the back door. But European Commissioner Mario Monti, in charge of the bloc's border-free market and tax issues, said it was an unprecedented move to reform the Union's tax structure.</p>
<p>&quot;Without introducing a new tax, the proposal continues to pursue the objectives of the internal market, of greater respect for the environment and of combatting unemployment,&quot; Monti told a news conference on Tuesday evening.</p>
<p>He argued it was not a new tax because the proposal states that it should not increase the bloc's overall tax burden but that national governments should use any new revenue to cut labour-related costs.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not meant to be a new tax,&quot; he repeatedly said, seeking to sooth industry concerns.</p>
<p>The draft directive on the taxation of energy products sets a minimum tax on motor diesel of 310 European currency units ($352) per 1,000 litres from January 1, 1998, from a current 245 Ecus.</p>
<p>In most cases the actual rates in the EU's 15 states are already above the proposed new minimum. The Commission said in a statement that the new rates would represent an increase of 11 percent at the pump in Greece, nine percent in Luxembourg and seven percent in both Spain and Portugal.</p>
<p>In the case of unleaded petrol, for which the Commission proposes a minimum level of 417 Ecus, even fewer countries would be affected. But the industry argues that the proposal sets the wrong trend.</p>
<p>Monti said EU governments were free to set whatever tax they wish on leaded petrol, but it must be higher than on unleaded.</p>
<p>The plan foresees further tax increases in 2000 and 2002. But the Commission agreed that the proposed levels for 2002 were targets and would need to be confirmed as binding.</p>
<p>The proposal faced strong opposition inside the 20-member Commission, particularly from Industry Commissioner Martin Bangemann, Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan and Economic Affairs Commissioner Yves-Thibault de Silguy.</p>
<p>The two Spanish commissioners Manuel Marin and Marcelino Oreja also raised reservations fearing the tax could lead to another damaging lorry strike in Spain, similar to that of earlier this year.</p>
<p>The draft directive also foresees the introduction of an minimum tax on electricity of one Ecu per megawatt-hour in 1998. This would rise to two and three Ecus in 2000 and 2002.</p>
<p>Natural gas would also be taxed 2.9 Ecus per gigajoule in 1998 when used as a motor fuel and 0.2 Ecus for heating purposes. This is opposed by producing countries the Netherlands and Britain.</p>
<p>The Commission's proposes that EU countries may refund some or all the tax paid by firms whose energy costs are between 10 and 20 percent of their production costs. But when the relation is higher than 20 percent, national administrations are &quot;obliged to refund all the tax paid on the proportion of their energy costs in excess of 10 percent of their total production costs&quot;.</p>
<p>The new minima do not affect kerosene, which national countries must exempt from tax under international commitments currently being reviewed.</p>
<p>The Commission also leaves EU states free to exempt or tax at reduced rates renewable energy sources and biofuels.  $1 = 0.879 Ecus</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G156">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
