<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44186" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Credit Lyonnais may have 1st half profit - source.</title>
<headline>Credit Lyonnais may have 1st half profit - source.</headline>
<byline>Penny MacRae</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A source close to rescue talks between troubled French bank Credit Lyonnais and the state said on Tuesday that salvage plans under study might help the bank post a profit in the first half.</p>
<p>It was &quot;not excluded&quot; that the state-controlled bank could show a slight profit, said the source who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>The bank and the conservative government of Prime Minister Alain Juppe have been in talks for months about how to amend last year's state bailout, the second in two years, which has become a millstone around the bank's neck.</p>
<p>The government has refused any official comment on whether progress has been made in the talks and has only said that a solution to the bank's woes must be reached.</p>
<p>The government and the bank, whose downfall was the biggest banking scandal in recent French history, are in a race against time to come up with new salvage terms before Credit Lyonnais releases its results on September 26.</p>
<p>Reports say that under the scenarios being considered, most of the heavy costs imposed on the bank last year to make it bear some of the pain for its reckless past would likely be waived.</p>
<p>Under the 1995 rescue, the second in two years, the bank transferred 130 billion French francs ($25.34 billion) of shaky assets to a state-backed rescue vehicle and gave the state a 119 billion franc loan to finance the acquisition.</p>
<p>But to get the bank to share the cost of its rescue and to get the bailout approved by European Union competition authorities in Brussels, the government dictated that the bank lend the 119 billion francs at below market interest rates.</p>
<p>The bank has ended up paying twice as much to fund the loan as it collects in interest payments and, in France's morose banking climate, it has been unable to make up the shortfall. It expects the gap to cost it three billion francs this year.</p>
<p>Without help on the loan, analysts have forecast that the bank could show a first-half loss of up to two billion francs.</p>
<p>The source said the plan could either involve increasing the rate of interest on the loan, cancelling it now or in perhaps six months time.</p>
<p>If the government took on the burden of the loan retroactively to the start of 1996, the bank's first half results &quot;could be slightly positive,&quot; said one banking analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically Credit Lyonnais should have a slightly positive situation under normal earning conditions,&quot; said another Paris analyst.</p>
<p>Credit Lyonnais racked up losses of 21 billion francs between 1992 and 1994 as a result of a reckless expansion spree that briefly turned it into the world's largest bank outside Japan.</p>
<p>Helped by the clean-up of its balance sheet, it eked out a 13 million franc profit in 1995. ($1=5.129 French Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
