<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="441812" id="root" date="1997-03-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia's Coles Myer ends two-year profit slide.</title>
<headline>Australia's Coles Myer ends two-year profit slide.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's biggest retailer Coles Myer Ltd on Thursday reported a 41 percent surge in half-year earnings, its first profit rise in almost two years.</p>
<p>The result buoyed Coles' once-sinking share price, which firmed despite a weaker market, and follows a two-year nightmare of sliding profits, controversy and tight-fisted consumers.</p>
<p>Coles, which pockets nearly 18 cents in every retail dollar spent in Australia, reported a net profit of A$273.6 million (US$217 million) for half-year ended January 26, against A$194.5 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Before abnormals, net earnings leapt 23 percent to a better-than-expected A$229 million, boosting the shares 13 cents above Wednesday's close to a morning high of A$6.04 before settling back.</p>
<p>&quot;What is important are people's expectations of the turnaround now. I think that's why the stock is where it is, on anticipation of much better margins and profit,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>Coles also on Thursday gave a bullish forecast for the full year ending July 27, suggesting it expected more double-digit profit growth in the second half of 1996/97.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect similar percentage growth in second-half profit after tax (excluding property disposal profits and abnormals), subject to market conditions,&quot; Coles Myer chief executive Dennis Eck said in a statement.</p>
<p>Coles booked a net abnormal gain of A$44.6 million on the sale of properties and said it had now discarded most of its huge property portfolio. Since 1995, it has sold A$1.1 billion worth of property.</p>
<p>(AS1 = US$0.793)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
