<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44208" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian IT market growth seen sluggish in H1 1996.</title>
<headline>Italian IT market growth seen sluggish in H1 1996.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's information technology market grew only 3.3 percent in value terms in the first six months of 1996 against 3.9 percent in the same 1995 period, the industry association Assinform said.</p>
<p>&quot;This slowdown takes into account both the strong slowdown of investments in machinery and equipment as well as the drop in household consumption,&quot; Assinform Chairman Bruno Pavesi said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The levels of computerisation in Italy are still too low and demand for Information Technology is today still insufficient to reduce the gap built up with Europe,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>PC sales in Italy grew by only 3.5 percent in value terms in the first half against growth of 13.8 percent in the same 1995 period, with the sector heavily impacted by falling demand from small and medium enterprises and households, Assinform said.</p>
<p>The industry association made no mention of Olivetti's problem PC company, the source of much anguish and heavy losses for the crisis-hit IT company.</p>
<p>Assinform said that only the software and services sector posted first half growth above that in the same period last year, with an increase of 5.6 percent against 5.1 percent.</p>
<p>Assinform groups the main IT and telecoms sector industries present on the Italian market, with a combined 1995 turnover equal to 60 trillion lire and a total of over 150,000 employees.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129589</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
