<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="442023" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: LATVIA-SAULES BANK SEE MODEST 1997 GROWTH.</title>
<headline>LATVIA-SAULES BANK SEE MODEST 1997 GROWTH.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Latvia's Saules Bank said on Friday that it expected to see modest growth in both assets and profits in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Our draft budget for 1997 forsees growth of both assets and profit, but the rise will not be drastic,&quot; the bank's supervisory council chairman Yurii Shcetinin told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>He also said that Saules Bank in conjunction with Estonia's Tallinna Pank was considering setting up pan-Baltic financial service companies.  </p>
<p>Shcetinin said the bank's budget that still has to be confirmed by the board on March 29 was rather conservative.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a rather conservative budget,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Saules earlier reported a fall in profits in 1996 to 866,000 lats from 1.48 million.</p>
<p>Saules strategy for 1997 includes strengthening the bank's position on the Latvian market by providing high technology card services.</p>
<p>&quot;Through private clients, ready to use our Saules card, we would try to reach corporate clients,&quot; Shcetinin said.</p>
<p>&quot;Handling salaries payments and providing cash withdrawal, account information and payment services to card holders is a way of doing that.&quot;</p>
<p>Saules provides its own card service, with the number of automated teller machines to grow to more than 40 from 19.</p>
<p>&quot;This year Saules card holders will receive the added service of settling utility payments,&quot; Shcetinin said.</p>
<p>The Latvian banking sector now faces the competition of foreign banks as the first German and French banks have opened subsidiaries in Riga.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
