<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="442130" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada confirms appealing WTO magazine verdict.</title>
<headline>Canada confirms appealing WTO magazine verdict.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>International Trade Minister Art Eggleton announced on Friday Canada's intention to appeal a decision by a World Trade Organization (WTO) dispute panel against its protectionist policies against foreign magazines.</p>
<p>&quot;We are working together to plan our appeal strategy and to assess the full impact of this ruling on the industry,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>The panel ruled against Canada's policy on Canadian editions of U.S. magazines -- so-called split-run editions.  </p>
<p>Eggleton said that part of the appeal would be based on Canada's contention that the issue deals with services rather than products. Therefore, it should be considered on the General Agreement on Trade in Services (GATS), drawn up under the Uruguay Round of trade talks, rather than the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT).</p>
<p>&quot;This deals with advertising. It's a service,&quot; Eggleton told reporters. &quot;We have maintained all along that this is not a product.&quot;</p>
<p>A government statement said the panel allowed Canada to continue its postal subsidies of certain Canadian periodicals.  </p>
<p>But the panel found against Canada on three other issues:</p>
<p>- the prohibition against split-run magazine imports.</p>
<p>- an 80 percent excise tax on advertising in split-run magazines.</p>
<p>- differing postal rates for domestic and foreign commercial publications.</p>
<p>The 1995 Canadian law targeted Time Warner Inc's Sports Illustrated in particular by referring to split runs that started after March 26, 1993, just days before Sports Illustrated Canada first came out.</p>
<p>Sports Illustrated circumvented the split-run import ban by electronically transmitting its magazine content to a printer in Canada, thereby avoiding the Canadian border.</p>
<p>It withdrew its split-run edition from Canada in after Ottawa passed a law to discourage split-run editions.</p>
<p>The law slapped an 80 percent excise tax on advertising in split runs distributed in Canada.</p>
<p>Canada will have 60 days to appeal. The appeal panel is to give its verdict 60 to 90 days from the date of the appeal.</p>
<p>((Randall Palmer, Reuters Ottawa Bureau 613-235-6745))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
