<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44212" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: Court says Belgium, UK breaking &quot;TV without frontiers&quot; rule.</title>
<headline>Court says Belgium, UK breaking &quot;TV without frontiers&quot; rule.</headline>
<byline>Suzanne Perry</byline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Court of Justice ruled on Tuesday that Belgium and Britain were breaking the European Union's &quot;television without frontiers&quot; directive.</p>
<p>The court said Belgium's French- and Dutch-speaking regional governments had violated Directive 89/552/EEC by restricting programmes from other EU states that are carried on their cable networks.</p>
<p>It said Britain had broken the rules by claiming jurisdiction over broadcasters with a satellite uplink in Britain, even if they had their headquarters in another EU state.</p>
<p>A central principle of the &quot;TV without frontiers&quot; directive is that national governments cannot bar broadcasts that comply with the laws of the EU state that has jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Belgium's French- and Dutch-speaking governments were wrong to require cable distributors to seek prior authorisation to transmit programmes from other EU countries, the court said.</p>
<p>&quot;A prior authorisation or licensing system constitutes a serious obstacle to the free movement of broadcasts within the (EU) as provided for by the directive and has the effect of abolishing freedom to provide services,&quot; the court said in a statement.</p>
<p>The ruling does not address problems that specific broadcasters have faced in Belgium. But the laws it criticised were the same ones that have been used to bar French station TF1 from targeting advertising to the Belgian public and to try to block the VT4 channel from starting operations, a Commission legal source said.</p>
<p>Flemish authorities tried last year to ban VT4, a U.S.-Scandinavian venture based in Britain, on the grounds that only one commercial domestic broadcaster is allowed in the region. The effort was overturned by a national administrative court.</p>
<p>In Britain's case, the European court said the 1990 Broadcasting Act established the wrong criteria for determining which satellite broadcasters came under British contol.</p>
<p>The European Commission initiated the case in 1994, saying that using the satellite uplink criteria could lead to cases of double jurisdiction or of broadcasters escaping regulation.</p>
<p>It complained that Britain had refused, for example, to regulate the controversial Red Hot pornographic station, whose parent company was British, because it was beamed from the continent.</p>
<p>The ruling, however, is expected to have minimal impact in Britain, British sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;In practice, it affects only half a dozen broadcasters, none of the big ones,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>She said Britain was expecting to change its licensing regime anyway since the Culture Council agreed in its common position to revise the &quot;TV without frontiers&quot; directive where it applies to jurisdiction over broadcasters.</p>
<p>The revision would follow the thinking of the court, she said.</p>
<p>Belgian regional authorities said they expected the offending laws would be changed, although one said it could be difficult politically in the French-speaking parliament. ----</p>
<p>*Case C-222/94 Commission of the European Communities v United Kingdom</p>
<p>*Case C-11/95 Commission of the European Communities v Kingdom of Belgium</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
