<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="442139" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire rebels reject ceasefire, face resistance.</title>
<headline>Zaire rebels reject ceasefire, face resistance.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Tostevin</byline>
<dateline>GOMA, Zaire 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rebels battling toward the city of Kisangani have met stiff resistance but rebel leader Laurent Kabila has rejected calls for a truce, rebel sources and diplomats said on Friday.</p>
<p>Rebel radio said fighting between rebels and a motley army backed by Serb mercenaries and Rwandan Hutus was taking place somewhere on the road between Kisangani and Bafwasende 300 km (200 miles) to the northeast.</p>
<p>Diplomats in the Ugandan capital Kampala said Kabila met U.N. special envoy Mohamed Sahnoun in the northern Ugandan town of Gulu on Thursday but again rejected pleas for a ceasefire.</p>
<p>A regional military source said Kabila's Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire (ADFL) were also advancing towards the lakeside town of Pweto in the mineral-rich Shaba province.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been making probing attacks towards Kisangani and they have met some resistance which we cannot ignore,&quot; one rebel source in the eastern border town of Goma said.</p>
<p>In Zaire's capital Kinshasa panic ensued when soldiers seized 16 vehicles from a Belgian car company, reviving memories of nationwide army pillaging in 1991 and 1993. The government, conscious of public fears if the army's fortunes take a new turn for the worse, played down Thursday's incident.</p>
<p>A Zaire defence ministry spokesman said on Thursday Kisangani, the army's headquarters in the war zone, was quiet.</p>
<p>Military analysts say the combination of the Zairean army's better troops, Serb mercenaries and allied Rwandan Hutus might slow a rebel advance. The army, which has helicopter gunships, has sown mines around the city.</p>
<p>Diplomats in Kampala told Reuters by telephone that Kabila met Sahnoun in Gulu hosted by Ugandan President Yoweri Museveni, a regional power broker accused by Zaire of backing Kabila. But they said Kabila turned down Sahnoun's plea for a ceasefire.</p>
<p>&quot;They met in Gulu in talks chaired by Museveni but Kabila bluntly refused to commit himself to a ceasefire of any kind,&quot; a diplomat said.</p>
<p>Tired and frightened Rwandan Hutu refugees have been limping into the town of Ubundu on the Zaire River upstream from Kisangani, with tales of the weak dying on the way.</p>
<p>While Kisangani has become a focal point for the struggle, guerrillas have slipped closer to vital mines in Shaba and Kasai. A regional military source said they were closing in on the town of Pweto on Lake Tanganyika in Shaba.</p>
<p>&quot;We have detected major movements towards Pweto and the rebels are being aided by Kabila's popular support in that srea,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>Rebel Voice of the People radio in Goma on Friday said Kabalo, a Zaire river town and railway junction close to the boundary between Shaba and Kasai, had fallen.</p>
<p>&quot;Kisangani is very important, but it is only one step towards liberating the whole country,&quot; said rebel information commissioner Raphael Ngenda.</p>
<p>France called for a &quot;security framework&quot; for Zaire -- code words for a multinational force -- but diplomats said its European Union partners responded coolly. Kenya downgraded a planned March 19 mini-summit on Zaire to a preparatory meeting for a regional summit later.</p>
<p>Mobutu, who has ruled Africa's third largest country for 32 years, remained in France. He has spent most of his time in Europe since surgery for prostate cancer in August.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GOMA, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
