<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="442140" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerian navy rescues hostages on oil barge.</title>
<headline>Nigerian navy rescues hostages on oil barge.</headline>
<byline>James Jukwey</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Twenty foreigners held hostage by youths on an oil barge in Nigeria were rescued on Thursday night when the navy boarded the vessel, diplomats said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The saga has been peacefully resolved,&quot; said a senior Western diplomat who monitored the hostage-taking which began on Tuesday when youths seized the barge demanding jobs.</p>
<p>The barge, DLB1, belongs to the French oil contracting firm ETPM which announced in Paris late on Thursday that there were no longer any unauthorised people on board.</p>
<p>&quot;Throughout yesterday negotiations were held and ETPM persuaded the local community to allow the boat to go offshore,&quot; said the diplomat. &quot;It got about 10 miles into the sea to a certain point where it was easy for the Nigerian navy to board the barge at about 11 in the night (2200 GMT).&quot;</p>
<p>He said the foreigners -- 16 Frenchmen, three Britons and one American -- were well and the barge had resumed work in the oil-producing area of Nigeria.</p>
<p>&quot;There was some catering aboard and they had a hot meal,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>A Nigerian military government statement just hours before the end denied any foreigners had been taken hostage, saying the barge had been released following the intervention of security agents.</p>
<p>Communities in oil-producing areas have long been restive over lack of amenities in regions responsible for Nigeria's oil wealth. Clashes with oil companies have been common.</p>
<p>ETPM went through a similar crisis last December when 28 foreign workers, including 10 Filipinos and nine Frenchmen, were held on a barge offshore by 60 Nigerian workers demanding higher wages.</p>
<p>The latest crisis began on Tuesday when the barge was seized in the Escravos area off the midwestern oil coastal town of Warri. The barge beached on Wednesday near Warri.</p>
<p>ETPM officials said negotiations then began to free the foreigners and the barge was allowed to sail to where the navy intervened.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a very delicate situation but we told you it was going to be over soon and that is what happened,&quot; said an official. &quot;By 12 last night (2300 GMT) the barge was back afloat and everything is now fine.&quot;</p>
<p>ETPM is a joint venture between French company Lyonnaise des Eaux-Dumez and McDermott International Inc  MRD.N.</p>
<p>ETPM spokeswoman in Paris, Ariane Malzac, told French television on Thursday the Nigerian problem was linked to rivalries between local groups.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an inter-community problem...The people we employ are very well-paid. The other communities know this. They would also like to be paid by us,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
