<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="442133" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bre-X Minerals climbs on rating upgrade.</title>
<headline>Bre-X Minerals climbs on rating upgrade.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Bre-X Minerals Ltd rose on Friday after a U.S. investment firm upgraded its rating on the Calgary-based gold prospector.</p>
<p>Bre-X's stock rose 0.35 to 17.60 in afternoon turnover of 730,800 shares on the Toronto Stock Exchange. On Nasdaq, the stock was up 3/8 at 12-7/8 on 234,000 shares.</p>
<p>New York-based Lehman Brothers said earlier it raised Bre-X to outperform from neutral.</p>
<p>Lehman said the company's share price has fallen to attractive levels. The stock has been under pressure since Bre-X reached an agreement to develop the rich Busang gold field it discovered in Indonesia. Busang contains at least 71 million ounces of gold, valued at about US$25 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Although there are still uncertainties, we believe this stock will be at significantly higher levels a year from now,&quot; Lehman said in a report.</p>
<p>The agreement left Bre-X with 45 percent, New Orleans-based Freeport-McMoRan Copper &amp; Gold Inc with 15 percent, and the rest to the Indonesian government and to two Indonesian companies.</p>
<p>Since the deal was announced in mid-February, Bre-X's stock has fallen from around C$24 amid investor confusion over the company's stake in Busang.</p>
<p>Bre-X has said the company did not originally own 90 percent of the discovery and investors were mistaken to believe otherwise.</p>
<p>Bre-X and its partners are currently waiting for the Indonesian government to issue contracts of work (COW) before mine construction can begin.</p>
<p>&quot;All else being the same, if Bre-X can resolve the Merukh issue and obtain its COWs, we will raise our rating to a buy,&quot; Lehman said.</p>
<p>Indonesian businessman Jusuf Merukh is suing Bre-X for US$2 billion in a Canadian court, alleging that his company was entitled to 30 percent of Busang.</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
