<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="442356" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Primakov set for vital pre-summit talks in U.S..</title>
<headline>Primakov set for vital pre-summit talks in U.S..</headline>
<byline>Timothy Heritage</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov leaves on Saturday for talks in Washington which could be vital for shaping the outcome of next week's Russia-U.S. summit in Helsinki.</p>
<p>Russian and Western officials have been encouraged by talks in recent weeks on the main summit issue, NATO's plans to expand eastwards. Presidents Bill Clinton and Boris Yeltsin hope to announce progress after they meet on March 19 and 20.</p>
<p>Yeltsin told Russian editors compromise was possible but the summit would be the hardest since he took office in 1991.</p>
<p>Officials say Primakov's three-day visit to Washington will concentrate on the details of any breakthough on the Western alliance's enlargement plans and determine whether any progress can also be made in Helsinki on important arms control issues.</p>
<p>&quot;If they are well prepared, Clinton and Yeltsin can announce some kind of agreement. If not, they may just be announcing something rather empty,&quot; said Pavel Kandel, a foreign policy expert at Moscow's independent Institute of Europe.</p>
<p>A Western diplomat in Moscow added: &quot;The gaps are being narrowed on NATO but what exactly the progress (in Helsinki) will look like is not fully clear yet.&quot;</p>
<p>Primakov is due to meet Secretary of State Madeleine Albright on Saturday, Defence Secretary William Cohen on Sunday and Clinton on Monday. He will return to Moscow to brief Yeltsin before the summit.</p>
<p>Russian foreign ministry spokesman Gennady Tarasov said on Thursday Primakov would have proposals to offer in the row with NATO over its plans to offer membership to Moscow's former communist allies in eastern and central Europe.</p>
<p>The North Atlantic Treaty Organisation, in which the Untied States is a dominant figure, is expected to offer membership invitations to Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic in July.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia has detailed proposals on this score and Yevgeny Primakov wants detailed, businesslike talks in Washington on the basis of these proposals,&quot; Tarasov said. He gave no details.</p>
<p>Yeltsin told the Russian editors that Moscow still bitterly opposed NATO expansion and wanted the alliance to drop any plans to lure in any former Soviet republics. He ruled out concessions that would endanger Russia's defence capability.</p>
<p>Russia also says NATO should not move nuclear weapons and its military infrastructure onto new members' territory.</p>
<p>But comments by presidential press secretary Sergei Yastrzhembsky on Thursday suggested Moscow may now consider accepting an agreement mapping out future relations which is politically binding, rather than legally binding.</p>
<p>Tarasov said Primakov expected &quot;serious discussion&quot; in Washington on arms control issues to be raised at the summit.</p>
<p>&quot;The main thing here is how to guarantee observation of the basic 1972 ABM treaty. For us, this is a mandatory condition for ratification of the START-2 agreement and for deeper cuts in strategic offensive weapons,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Russia is concerned that the United States is developing weapons that may violate Anti-Ballistic Missile treaty limiting missile defence systems. Washington says it is not doing this.</p>
<p>The Russian parliament has still not ratified START-2, although it was signed in 1993 to reduce deployed warheads from about 6,000 each to no more than 3,500 each, partly because of fears that the United States will violate the ABM treaty.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S.-Russia arms control agenda is in serious trouble,&quot; said Jack Mendelsohn of the Arms Control Association, a private think-tank in the United States.</p>
<p>Tarasov said Primakov would also discuss economic issues in Washington in the hope that Clinton and Yeltsin can announce a joint initiative in Helsinki to boost economic cooperation. He did not say what the initiative might involve.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
