<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="442401" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - March 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - March 14.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the reports carried by Estonia's newspapers on Friday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- Parliament re-elected Toomas Savi chairman. Ants Kaarma was elected first chairman and Tunne Kelam second deputy chairman.</p>
<p>- The Estonian government decided to provide 3.3 million kroons of irredeemable financial aid to Russia by paying the debt of Ivangorod to Narva for water supply.</p>
<p>- The Central council of the Baltic war-time emigrants in the United States sent a letter to President Clinton, expressing concern that the Baltic countries might, at the Clinton-Yeltsin summit in Helsinki, become trade objects like in Yalta.</p>
<p>POSTIMEES</p>
<p>- A conflict between Tartu Blind People Union and the Estonian Blind People Union over the ownership of a house, culminated in a protest march, organised by the Tartu group.</p>
<p>SAONUMILEHT</p>
<p>- SAAR-poll March survey shows that 72 percent of the Estonian population suspect officials of corruption. 56 percent say that crime-fighting should be the government's first priority. Rural People's Party is the most popular political party with 16 percent followed by the Reform Party with 13 percent and the Moderates with 12 percent.</p>
<p>- Rural Union prefer Aavo Molder for agriculture minister. According to sources, Country People's Party wants Andrews Varik to have the post.</p>
<p>EESTI PAEVALEHT</p>
<p>- The Traffic Regulations Commission decided to prohibit the use of summer tyres in winter from January 1998, officials said.</p>
<p>ARIPAEV</p>
<p>- Tallinn city government wants to raise the price for drinking water to cover costs of renovating the water and sewage system.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
