<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="442548" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: With clock ticking, Taiwan deadlocks on HK ties.</title>
<headline>With clock ticking, Taiwan deadlocks on HK ties.</headline>
<byline>Lawrence Chung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Just 109 days before Hong Kong's return to China, Taiwan legislators were bitterly divided on Friday over a draft law which will govern the island's relations with Hong Kong under communist Chinese rule.</p>
<p>Legislators from three major Taiwan political parties spent Friday afternoon debating whether to refer to Hong Kong and Macau as &quot;areas&quot; or merely by their names in a split coloured by worries over Taiwan's future relations with arch rival China.</p>
<p>Taiwan is tackling with acute caution the question of what status to accord Hong Kong when it reverts to Beijing rule on July 1 after more than 150 years as a British colony.</p>
<p>The same concerns apply to Portuguese-administered Macau, which returns to China in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;We must not address Hong Kong as Hong Kong area, or Macau as Macau area because it would give those territories a position equal that of Taiwan and mainland China,&quot; said Shen Fu-hsiung of the pro-independence Democratic Progressive Party.</p>
<p>Lawmakers from the New Party, which opposes independence for Taiwan, insisted the term &quot;Taiwan area&quot; be carefully qualified so it does not imply an independent political entity.</p>
<p>&quot;I worry that if this term is not clearly defined, it would give others an impression that we want to be independent from mainland China,&quot; Lai Lai-kun of the New Party said.</p>
<p>Despite losing the mainland to Chinese communists in a civil war in 1949, Taiwan's government calls itself the Republic of China and refers to the island as the &quot;Taiwan area&quot; to distinguish it from the &quot;mainland area.&quot;</p>
<p>The aim was to put the Republic of China on an equal footing with the communist People's Republic of China, which claims sovereignty over the island and demands its reunification with the mainland.</p>
<p>Parliament vice speaker Wang Chin-ping asked for another review of the draft Hong Kong-Macau Relations Act on March 18, after legislators failed to reach agreement.</p>
<p>Of the law's 62 articles, only Article 1, a general statement explaining the law's intent, was adopted on Friday.</p>
<p>Government officials said time was running out and they wanted the law enacted before Hong Kong's handover.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope parliament can pass the law as soon as possible because there are only a few months left before Hong Kong reverts to the mainland rule,&quot; said Chang King-yuh, head of the cabinet's China policy-making Mainland Affairs Council.</p>
<p>Taiwan's parliament, where the ruling Nationalists have only a knife-edge 51 percent majority, passed the first reading of the bill in December 1996 after months of debate, but many difficult issues are holding up the second reading.</p>
<p>The bill would provide the legal framework for Taiwan's direct links with Hong Kong and Macau after their transitions, defining them as special administrative regions which will skirt Taiwan's long-standing ban on direct contacts with communist China.</p>
<p>The bill seeks to maintain Taiwan's trade, investment and cultural links with Hong Kong and Macau, officials said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
