<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44253" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French anti-racists sue Le Pen over race remark.</title>
<headline>French anti-racists sue Le Pen over race remark.</headline>
<text>
<p>PARIS, Sept 10 (reuter) - FrAnce's Movement against Racism (MRAP) said on Tuesday it was suing far-right political leader Jean-Marie Le Pen for saying that racial inequality was &quot;a fact&quot;.</p>
<p>MRAP Secretary-General Mouloud Aounit said he was taking legal action because the statement was &quot;not a slip of the tongue, but the clear and cold expression of what Le Pen has been thinking for a long time&quot;.</p>
<p>Le Pen, leader of the anti-immigrant National Front, told Europe 1 radio on Monday: &quot;To say that the races are unequal is a fact, an unremarkable statement.&quot; He cited as an example an &quot;obvious difference&quot; between white and black athletes at the Olympics.</p>
<p>&quot;We expected a kind of outcry from the government and public opinion, but I am seeing, sadly, that such statements get no notice,&quot; Aounit said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>&quot;The time has come to call a halt, or else where is this going to end?&quot; he said.</p>
<p>MRAP lawyer Pierre Meyrat, who was drafting the legal action, said Le Pen could face a fine if he were found guilty of inciting racial hatred, a crime in France.</p>
<p>The head of the French Jewish community, Henri Hadjenberg, said Le Pen's remarks were &quot;a danger for democracy&quot;. &quot;We had not heard such things in Europe since 1945,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Le Pen, who won 15 percent of the vote in last year's presidential election, has in the past denied charges of racism and anti-semitism. He sparked fury with a 1987 remark that the Nazi death camp gas chambers were &quot;a mere detail in the history of the Second World War&quot;.</p>
<p>His National Front, whose slogan is &quot;France for the French&quot;, has announced a drive to improve its image ahead of the 1998 general election in an effort to broaden its appeal.</p>
<p>But the public relations campaign was set back earlier this year when he charged that many players on the nation's soccer team were foreigners unable to sing the national anthem.</p>
<p>When informed that all on the team were indeed French citizens, he noted that some were of foreign origin and that the team would be better if all players were native Frenchmen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
