<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="442658" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries end higher on Feb inflation drop.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries end higher on Feb inflation drop.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasury prices ended modestly higher on Friday after news of an unexpectedly sharp slide in February wholesale prices made the scenario of a Federal Reserve interest rate hike later this month look less plausible.</p>
<p>The Department of Labor's Producer Price Index (PPI) fell 0.4 percent in February -- the largest drop since October of 1994 and an even more subdued reading that Wall Street expectations for a 0.1 percent decline. The drop followed a 0.3 percent PPI decline in January.  </p>
<p>The market opened little changed and saw a short-covering rally just before the PPI report was released.</p>
<p>After the PPI report came out, bond prices climbed again until profit-taking stalled the advance and trimmed it.</p>
<p>Carey Leahey, senior vice president at Lehman Government Securities Inc., said morning trade saw some hedge fund selling and very limited retail buying interest.</p>
<p>Less than an hour after the PPI report, the Federal Reserve said industrial output rose 0.5 percent in February and that 83.3 percent of the capacity of the nation's mines, factories and utilities was utilized in that production.  </p>
<p>The industrial production and capacity use data were neutral for the market. And while the wholesale data favored the inflation-fearful credit markets, Carey said it did not appreciably change people's views on Fed policy.</p>
<p>&quot;The people who thought the Fed will tighten soon, still think so,&quot; he said. &quot;Those who didn't think so, still don't. There's a lot of fence sitting in the analytical and the trading community.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The Fed has a deep dilemma here,&quot; said John Williams, managing director and chief global markets economist at Bankers Trust.  </p>
<p>Arguing for tightening is that economic growth that &quot;clearly exceeds its long run potential and tight labor markets that suggest considerable upside inflation risk,&quot; said Williams. On the other hand, &quot;there still is no evidence of price pressure at the finished goods level,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>With the economy strong, it would be &quot;a great time&quot; to execute a pre-emptive strike against inflation, Williams said.</p>
<p>&quot;But at the same time, it's especially difficult to pull the trigger when current inflation remains so tame,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Williams said the odds were slightly less than even for an official interest rate hike in March.  </p>
<p>Samuel Kahan, president of A.S.K. Financial Research Ltd., said he does not believe the Fed will tighten at its March 25 policy meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;True, they have to be ahead of the curve and pre-empt inflation, but being too early is also not good,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Neal Soss, chief economist at Credit Suisse First Boston Corp., said Fed Chairman Alan Greenspan's Humphrey-Hawkins testimony in February led the market to expect an interest rate hike. While Soss, himself, does not see an economic justification for a rate hike now, he said the Fed must raise rates to maintain its credibility.  </p>
<p>&quot;If they don't, who will listen to them ever again?&quot; said Soss. &quot;It's important to have a central bank that is credible and that credibility is based on the Fed's ability to communicate to the markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Soss predicted that in any case, the credit markets would rally on March 25, the day of the next Fed policy meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be relief across the curve, either because the Fed didn't raise rates or because it did, and it's out of the way,&quot; said Soss.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year bond ended at 96 even, up 6/32, its yield at 6.94 percent.</p>
<p>At the short end of the maturity range, three-, six- and year bill rates were all unchanged at 5.10 percent, 5.20 percent and 5.42 percent.</p>
<p>Two-year notes were unchanged at 99-15/32, yielding 6.17 percent. Five-year notes were up 2/32 to 98-28/32, yielding 6.52 percent. Ten-year notes rose 2/32 to 96-26/32, yielding 6.69 percent.</p>
<p>(( -- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1679 ))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
