<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="442808" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Applied Magnetics calls off Read-Rite bid. [CORRECTED 17:52 GMT]</title>
<headline>Applied Magnetics calls off Read-Rite bid. [CORRECTED 17:52 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Applied Magnetics Corp said the recent, sharp decline in the company's stock price has made &quot;not feasible&quot; its hostile, stock-swap takeover bid for Read-Rite Corp.  </p>
<p>&quot;Although we continue to believe the strategic rationale for this combination is compelling, we recognize that based on the current value of Applied Magnetics' common stock the transaction is not feasible,&quot; Applied chief executive Craig Crisman said in a statement.</p>
<p>In late morning NYSE trade Applied shares reacted positively to the withdrawal, adding 1-5/8 to 34-7/8.  </p>
<p>The hostile bid began when Applied announced on February 24 that it was seeking to acquire Read-Rite by exchanging shares at a ratio of 0.679 Applied share for each Read-Rite share.  </p>
<p>The takeover attempt pressured shares of both computer disk-drive component companies: Applied has fallen 25 percent since it unveiled the bid, including today's slight rebound, while Read-Rite is off 10.3 percent.</p>
<p>In late morning Nasdaq trade, shares in Read-Rite were off 1/4 to 29-1/2 before trading was halted for news dissemination.</p>
<p>Over the same time period, the Nasdaq Composite index is off 3.5 percent while the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 is down 2.1 percent.  </p>
<p>Analyst generally agreed with Read-Rite's defense that argued Applied was pursuing Read-Rite to make up for weaknesses in its production capacity and technological progress toward the next generation of disk-drive head technology.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to me they (Applied) my be in a desperate situation.  They have inductive technology and the market is going toward magnetoresistive.  Read-Rite has had some problems in the past, but is fundamentally sound,&quot; said Paul Meeks, a money manager of Jurika &amp; Voyles (corrects attribution of quote from Montgomery Securities analyst Paul Fox).  </p>
<p>Yesterday, Montgomery Securities' Paul Fox's reduction in his Applied fiscal year 1997 revenue estimate triggered a deep sell-off in the shares, which ended Thursday's NYSE regular session five points lower at 33-1/4.</p>
<p>Paul Meeks, a money manager at Oakland, Calif.-based Jurika &amp; Voyles who owns Read-Rite stock, also said before the withdrawal, &quot;It looks to me like the game is over, unless Applied steps up with a higher bid.&quot;  </p>
<p>But Applied effectively tied its own hands by announcing one week ago that it would not do a deal &quot;that is dilutive to the interests&quot; of its shareholders.</p>
<p>This meant Applied would not engage in a takeover that created a company in which the target's shareholders, in this case Read-Rite's, owned more equity than Applied shareholders.</p>
<p>&quot;If the deal does not happen, Read-Rite will be all the stronger&quot; because of its larger production capacity and advances in the area of magnetoresistive disk-drive head know-how, Meeks said.</p>
<p>&quot;Disk drive plants are becoming more and more expensive, demanding more sophisticated capital equipment. The business is brutally competitve,&quot; Meeks added.</p>
<p>((--Brendan Intindola, Wall Street Desk, 212-859-1734)).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302019">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34532">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
