<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="442845" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Exxon's Singapore plant on despite capacity warning.</title>
<headline>Exxon's Singapore plant on despite capacity warning.</headline>
<byline>David Chance</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Exxon Corp. Friday said it plans to build a $2 billion petrochemical plant in Singapore despite a warning from Moody's Investors Services that new capacity in the region would worsen the next industry downturn.</p>
<p>Exxon Chemical Co.'s 800,000 metric ton ethylene plant will provide products for other plants and will be operational in the year 2000.</p>
<p>Mobil Corp. is in the process of a feasibility study for new ethylene capacity, which if approved, would come onstream around the same time as Exxon's.</p>
<p>Ethylene is a byproduct of gasoline, used in making many chemicals.</p>
<p>Both the Exxon and Mobil plants are part of a move to tap into demand for chemicals as well as other products from the rapidly growing economies of Asia, especially from China. British Petroleum Co. Plc and Dow Chemical Co. also have announced large investment plans for the region.</p>
<p>Moody's warned Thursday that the buildup of capacity in the region could have a negative impact on the credit strength of commodity chemical producers, particularly Asian and European companies with weak raw material or technological bases.</p>
<p>&quot;In particular, if too many of the proposed projects, namely ethylene crackers and extended complexes, proceed to completion, cyclical recovery could be delayed,&quot; said Moody's analysts Joseph Princiotta and John Diaz.</p>
<p>Moody's notes that prices already are weakn in some sectors of the industry due to overbuilding and warns that large volume polyolefin plastics -- polyethylene and polypropylene -- that will be produced at the Exxon facility are at risk.</p>
<p>Warren Bisley, manager of the Exxon facility, told a news conference in Singapore that there was room for capacity in the region, but added the caveat, &quot;We must make sure that we have the lowest cost in the region&quot;.</p>
<p>Moody's notes that while greater demand from China is anticipated, South Korea and others are aggressively targeting that market and there are unique problems associated with China trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Trade with China tends to be less than smooth and its irregular buying practices increase volatility risk to global markets as its trade deficit expands,&quot; the Moody's analysts said.</p>
<p>Others are less bearish on the demand outlook for Asia. Fred Peterson at consultancy Probe Economics notes that demand in the region for chemicals is growing at 7 percent to 10 percent a year.</p>
<p>&quot;To some extent producers have little choice. They see domestic markets declining and are forced to go overseas. The problems may be felt more in countries like the U.S., Japan and Europe, which have traditionally exported to Asia and will see their markets disappear,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Peterson also noted that more oil companies are moving into the downstream chemicals sector and that polyethylene was one of the areas where there was already overcapacity.</p>
<p>&quot;The chemicals business is classic hog cycle economics. These companies have a lot of cash and they want to increase their overseas capacity,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
