<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="442896" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Soybean, coffee prices strong, oil also rises.</title>
<headline>Soybean, coffee prices strong, oil also rises.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Soybean futures led grain prices higher on Friday as speculators bet that Brazil would slap an export tax on its soybeans.</p>
<p>Coffee and oil prices also rose, helping push the Knight Ridder Commodity Research Bureau Index of 17 commodity futures up 1.87 points to close at 246.93.</p>
<p>At the Chicago Board of Trade, May soybeans closed 21 cents a bushel higher at $8.49-1/2 as professional commodity fund investors bought at least 20 million bushels.</p>
<p>&quot;The big push today was because of the rumor about Brazil imposing a three percent tax on exports,&quot; said Bill Biedermann, director of research for Allendale Inc. &quot;Funds came in and bought 10 million bushels right on the open.&quot;</p>
<p>Brazilian soybean processors and Brazil's Agricultural Ministry both denied there was any basis to the rumor. Brazil is the largest soybean exporter besides the United States and is just beginning to harvest what is expected to be a record crop.</p>
<p>&quot;It is politically absurd and unviable. The Agriculture Ministry is opposed to the idea, clearly opposed,&quot; said Favio Pereira, an adviser at the ministry's Agricultural Policy Secretariat.</p>
<p>Soybeans prices rose to 8-1/2 year highs early this week on record demand from processors. Soybeans are processed into meal, a livestock feed, and oils for food and many industrial uses.</p>
<p>But prices later dropped sharply on reports that U.S. processors were booking cargoes of South American beans to ship into the United States this spring due to lower prices.</p>
<p>At least one of those cargoes was quickly cancelled, traders said. Soybean imports into the United States, which produces half the total world crop, has been a touchy political issue with U.S. farmers in the past.</p>
<p>Corn futures also posted strong gains, with May futures closing up 6-1/4 cents a bushel at $3.04-1/2.</p>
<p>Speculators powered the gains in corn after a leading agricultural consulting firm, Sparks Companies, estimated this year's U.S. corn plantings at 80.8 million acres, slightly below the firm's previous estimate for 81.5 million.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of the buying in corn is in the December. It's normal this time of year for funds to go long new crop before spring planting and potential weather problems,&quot; said Paul Haugens, vice president of Chicago-based FIMAT Futures.</p>
<p>Coffee prices also rose, staging a recovery after dropping 10 percent in the prior two days. On Friday, May coffee futures at the Coffee Sugar and Cocoa Exchange in New York closed at 186.35 cents a pound, up 4.10 cents on the day.</p>
<p>That compared with the life-of-contract high of 209.50 cents set on March 5 and the recent low of 101.15 cents on December 6.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the tightest supplies have been in about 25 years and we're not looking at any sizable harvests,&quot; Allendale Commodities analyst Jim Cordier said. &quot;I think next week you are going to see the bulls re-attach their horns.&quot;</p>
<p>Sentiment was boosted during the trading session when popular coffee roaster and retailer Starbucks Corp. raised its prices. A medium-sized cup of Starbucks coffee was raised 5 cents to $1.20 and whole bean prices were raised 30 cents a pound.</p>
<p>&quot;We waited as long as we could to make this pricing decision, but coffee costs remained at a high level longer than expected,&quot; Starbucks said.</p>
<p>At the New York Mercantile Exchange, crude oil futures rose sharply as speculators bet on a reversal of recent sharp losses and also gained due to a power outage at London's International Petroleum Exchange that suspended activity there.</p>
<p>April crude oil closed at $21.29 a barrel, up 59 cents, April unleaded gasoline rose 1.54 cents a gallon to 65.77 cents and April heating oil rose 1.11 cents a gallon to 55.33 cents.</p>
<p>Crude oil futures had fallen 25 percent from the start of the year to last week's low below $20 a barrel. But refiners have begun to rev up operations to produce more gasoline ahead of the summer driving season, analysts said.</p>
<p>A 55-minute blank-out on London IPE screens also sent some European buyers over to the NYMEX to cover positions until their market resumed, traders said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
