<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="443183" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Cricket fever puts Sri Lanka polls on back burner.</title>
<headline>Cricket fever puts Sri Lanka polls on back burner.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lankans on Friday turned their attention from elections to a century-old tradition of cheering their favourite high school cricket team during the island's &quot;Big Match&quot; weekend.</p>
<p>Ministers, parliamentarians, stock brokers, company chairmen, senior government officials and grandfathers took their place in rival tents at Colombo's Sinhalese Sports Club grounds where St. Thomas' College is playing its arch rival Royal College in their 118th &quot;Big Match&quot; encounter.</p>
<p>The Big Match weekend marks the end of Sri Lanka's school-level cricket tournaments, and crowds take to streets in this cricket-mad country when their favourite team wins.</p>
<p>&quot;March is generally the season of the Big Matches, that juvenile homage we pay each year to the Great God of Cricket,&quot; said the government-owned Observer newspaper in a front page editorial on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;But this year it is rivalled by the battle for the local government bodies,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka goes to the polls on March 21 to elect members to local government bodies after a campaign marred by violence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
