<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="443509" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INTERVIEW -Wickes closes disaster chapter.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW -Wickes closes disaster chapter.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>British home decorating retailer Wickes Plc, which launched a survival refinancing in December, has now closed a chapter of complete disaster in its lifetime, said chief executive Bill Grimsey.</p>
<p>&quot;I think when you look at last year one of the worst years for Wickes; a complete disaster, today for me signals the close of that chapter,&quot; said Grimsey in an interview.</p>
<p>Earlier the company, whose former directors are being investigated for fraud after accounting discrepancies led to a 51 million stg overstatement of profits, reported a narrowing of its losses in 1996.</p>
<p>Pre-tax losses in 1996 shrank to 55.7 million stg from 279.30 million the previous year.</p>
<p>&quot;We performed in line with our forecasts, we have delivered what we said we would and we have off the year satisfactorily,&quot; said Grimsey.</p>
<p>He would not be drawn on when the company would be returned to profit.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see it picking up quite as it did in 1996. I think 1997 will be an okay year but nothing spectacular,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wickes reported sales up to the end of February had risen 13 percent on a like-for-like basis in Britain although in mainland Europe turnover was down five percent.</p>
<p>The company is now focusing on its strength, the heavy end of the home improvement sector in Britain and plans to sell off the mainland European business are underway, said Grimsey.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying to get closer to our customers needs but it won't be overnight. We are spending a lot of energy researching and understanding Wickes' customer base,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Tim Farrand, London newsroom +44 171 542 6437</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
