<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="443558" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey says sugar processing plans depend on price.</title>
<headline>Turkey says sugar processing plans depend on price.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's plans to turn two more of its white sugar production plants into raws processors depend mainly on the difference between whites and raws prices on international markets.</p>
<p>&quot;If the price difference between raws and whites is more than $100 (per tonne), then the conversion of the refineries into raw sugar processing units can be justified,&quot; said a senior official from state refiner Turkseker.</p>
<p>&quot;But recently the difference have been around $80 excluding freight and other costs, and that does not justify the investment at this stage,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Turkseker, which operates 25 of the 28 sugar refineries in Turkey, had plans to convert refineries in Adapazari and Susurluk, two western provinces where beet production is diminishing.</p>
<p>But officials later suspended the plan because of financial problems.</p>
<p>The official said the other factor to be considered in planning was white sugar production, which had risen to 1.85 million tonnes in 1996/97 from 1.5 million a year earlier. Beet producers expect it to rise to 2.05 million tonnes in 1997/98.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a better output this year. So we may not need the plants for some time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Turkey turned its Carsamba refinery on the Black Sea into a raws unit in 1995 with a daily processing capacity of 500 tonnes to produce whites from imported raws.</p>
<p>The plant's output was meant for export. Turkseker has exported 12,500 tonnes of its output so far.</p>
<p>The official said the Adapazari plant, the first one on the agenda, would be able to process 900 tonnes of raws a day if it became operational.</p>
<p>&quot;The cost of converting one plant is not much. It is something like 100 billion lira,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Ercan Ersoy, Ankara Newsroom 90-312-4462940</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
