<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="443503" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: European grain export optimism fades.</title>
<headline>European grain export optimism fades.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's grain trade ended the week feeling a little less optimistic about exports to non-EU destinations.</p>
<p>They still see export possibilities, and the EU is being watched closely for hints on near-future export policy.</p>
<p>Intra-EU trade has slowed, traders said.</p>
<p>French wheat prices slightly eased this week after rising sharply last week on strong export demand.</p>
<p>Maize was also weaker, in sympathy with wheat, but barley benefited from expectations Saudi Arabia may soon tap world markets again for feed barley.</p>
<p>Wheat buyers, who scrambled last week to secure goods to meet a heavy loading schedule in ports, were holding out this week, hoping to keep prices in check.</p>
<p>Intra-community business slowed down with the exception of a small trade flow to Italy.</p>
<p>News the EU raised its wheat export refund at its weekly tender on Thursday helped little although operators interpreted the move as an indication the Commission still wanted to export.</p>
<p>The EU granted licences to export 273,500 tonnes of soft wheat, raising the export rebate to 11.47 Ecus per tonne from 10.25 Ecus the previous week.</p>
<p>The wheat tonnage was less than last week but exporters welcomed the higher rebate.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a rise of more than one Ecu over last week. It indicates they want to export,&quot; one exporter said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is rather encouraging,&quot; another exporter said.</p>
<p>Among fresh business opportunities for European, notably French wheat, exporters cited a Tunisian tender for 125,000 tonnes of wheat for April, May and June and market talk Egypt may soon return to world markets.</p>
<p>Exporters said much of Friday's focus will be on the results of the Tunisian tender as shipment dates sought put French wheat in competition with other world suppliers, notably the United States, Canada and Australia.</p>
<p>Barley prices firmed as operators awaited confirmation Saudi Arabia may soon tender for barley. There was also news Iran and Cyprus were seeking optional barley.</p>
<p>Spot barley for delivery to Dunkirk, a northern port with the capacity to handle large cargoes to Saudi Arabia, firmed to 870 francs per tonne from 860 francs last week.</p>
<p>On Wednesday ONIC director-general Alain Moulinier estimated the Saudis may seek between 800,000 and 900,000 tonnes of feed-barley.</p>
<p>In January the kingdom bought 1.2 million tonnes of optional barley, with the EU getting the lion's share.</p>
<p>But within the EU, French barley is likely to face strong competition from Spanish barley, dealers warned.</p>
<p>German wheat prices are expected to stay at higher levels reached on recent export business although follow-on orders have not been seen yet, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has gone quiet this week after demand from French exporters and eastern Europe lifted prices, but European competitors are now beginning to look cheaper,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Traders reported some barley sales to Denmark.</p>
<p>German grain traders said they would not benefit from the EU's wheat award on Thursday, which they described as generous.</p>
<p>The volumes had already been contracted mostly in France for export to the Middle East, they said.</p>
<p>German wheat was not competitive for those destinations because of additional shipping costs and small ship sizes.</p>
<p>Traders saw local wheat prices underpinned by latent demand from eastern Europe over the next two months but the upside remained limited by supply pressure at trade and country merchant level and because business was slow.</p>
<p>The EU award of 52,460 tonnes of German intervention rye would damage marketing chances for free market rye.</p>
<p>UK traders called the tender mildly friendly. An easier domestic market and Sterling's move back from highs against other European currencies have helped UK wheat relative competitive position.</p>
<p>&quot;We're significantly more competitive than the French, with the currency off and the market a couple of quid (stg) lower,&quot; one said. &quot;We're not far away from Danish at the moment,&quot; another said&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not very competitive, but we're more competitive than we were at 2.77,&quot; he said, referring to sterling's highest recent rate against the German mark.</p>
<p>But coaster exports were still concentrated on done deals, with little new business, traders said.</p>
<p>The UK's domestic market remained stalemated by a shortage of grain coming off farms. &quot;Nobody's doing much off farms,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>In Spain feed and milling wheat ex-farm prices edged higher, largely in sympathy with rises in overseas markets, and in particular rises in the cost of British wheat, Spanish traders said.</p>
<p>Durum trading, however, remained subdued, with prices remaining unchanged.</p>
<p>Barley was marginally higher with a number of sales for export buoying prices.</p>
<p>Maize for immediate delivery remained largely unchanged.</p>
<p>However, demand was high for April or May delivery, and prices rose to around 23,500.</p>
<p>Italian wheat prices rose over the past week reflecting an increase in demand by consumers and an increase in prices abroad, the Italian Institute for Agriculture Studies (Ismea) said.</p>
<p>One dealer said that the increase in foreign prices was magnified by the weakening of the lira.</p>
<p>Ismea noted that the rise in durum wheat prices was also attributable to the fact that the Italian crop was starting to become scarce. The dealer noted that with only three months left in the current crop season, it is normal that prices start increasing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
