<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="443698" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Study concludes earthquakes cannot be predicted.</title>
<headline>Study concludes earthquakes cannot be predicted.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite expensive research in Japan and China to find ways to predict earthquakes, a group of scientists has concluded there is no telling when a temblor will strike, a report said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we have to confess that predicting earthquakes is something we can't do,&quot; said David Jackson, professor of geophysics at the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA).</p>
<p>He said the hope that quakes might be predicted hours, days or even months in advance should be dismissed as &quot;wishful thinking&quot; and &quot;a hopeless task.&quot;</p>
<p>Jackson, who is also science director of the Southern California Earthquake Center, co-authored an article entitled &quot;Earthquakes Cannot Be Predicted&quot; for the latest edition of Science magazine.</p>
<p>The article contains findings by Jackson and his colleagues, Robert Geller, professor of geophysics at Tokyo University; Yan Kagan, UCLA research geophysicist; and Francesco Mulargia, of Italy's Bologna University.</p>
<p>&quot;We've worked awfully hard on earthquake prediction for nearly three decades, we've checked everywhere and have turned up no promising leads on how to predict earthquakes,&quot; said Jackson.</p>
<p>&quot;It's important for the public to understand and for scientists to acknowledge, what is feasible and what is not feasible. It's time to focus the debate on what we can do about earthquakes that is constructive,&quot; he wrote.</p>
<p>Scientists can provide an assessment of long-term quake probabilities that will help long-range planning such as how to build quake-proof buildings and roads, he said.</p>
<p>Noting that Japan and China have invested heavily in research to predict temblors, Jackson said his colleagues agreed with the comments of the late Charles Richter, developer of the seismological scale that bears his name.</p>
<p>Prediction, said Richter, &quot;provides a happy hunting ground for amateurs, cranks and publicity-seeking fakers.&quot; Journalists and the public &quot;rush to any suggestion of earthquake prediction like hogs toward a full trough,&quot; Richter once wrote.</p>
<p>&quot;This comment still holds true,&quot; Jackson's scientists wrote in Science.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
