<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="443664" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FTC opens Staples case to Internet comment.</title>
<headline>FTC opens Staples case to Internet comment.</headline>
<byline>David Lawsky</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Trade Commission, wrestling with a proposed $4 billion merger of Staples and Office Depot, took the unprecedented step Friday of opening up the Internet to public comment after a Ralph Nader group petitioned it.</p>
<p>The unusual action could add a new element to the decision, in which Office Depot and Staples have sought to make their case for merger through full-page advertisements in major newspapers.</p>
<p>&quot;Awesome,&quot; said James Love of Nader's Centre for the Study of Responsive law, who had written the petititon, as he looked at the page. &quot;I believed this is the first time the FTC has ever used the Internet to seek consumer comments on a merger.&quot;</p>
<p>On Monday the commission voted 4-1 to ask a Federal District Court to block the merger of the two office superstores. Then Office Depot and Staples added a new dimension Wednesday with a highly publicised agreement to sell 63 stores to the other player in the office superstore field, OfficeMax.</p>
<p>Now the FTC is trying to decide whether to accept the divestiture and permit the deal to go through.</p>
<p>The new channel for public comment is easily reached from a link on the FTC home page at www.ftc.gov amd marks another expansion of the commission's presence on the Web, which has grown in the past year to include speeches, rulings and other information.</p>
<p>But in the past, although the FTC invited comments to its consumer complaint bureau on its Web page, it made no similar invitation on merger cases.</p>
<p>Then the Nader group asked the FTC to permit public comments on mergers, both generally and with a specific focus on the Staples case.</p>
<p>Until now public comment at the FTC has been a narrow affair. Senior officials there held the view that public comment need be considered only very late in the process, and when it was invited, there was not much. Even highly publicised cases, such as the deal that created media giant Time-Warner, drew only dozens of comments.</p>
<p>But those at senior levels of the FTC are highly aware of recent moves in other agencies to open their dockets.</p>
<p>For example, the Federal Communications Commission recently received an overwhelming record 300,000 to 400,000 e-mail comments on the possibilty that it might set a special charge for using telephone lines to access local Internet providers.</p>
<p>Telephone company officials who backed such a charge found their hopes buried by the public comment.</p>
<p>If something like that happens at the FTC, even on a much smaller level, it could provide pressure to countervail the high-profile campaign Staples and Office Depot have waged.</p>
<p>On the other hand, it may provide justification for the Commission to give the go-ahead for the merger.</p>
<p>&quot;People began writing right away,&quot; said a takeover stock specialist in New York. &quot;I personally would believe they're (the FTC) trying to justify going with the deal.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
