<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="443721" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Ambassador says 20% of Congress visited China.</title>
<headline>U.S. Ambassador says 20% of Congress visited China.</headline>
<byline>Steve James</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-03-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>With Beijing accusing U.S. congressmen on Thursday of trying to meddle in China's internal affairs, the U.S. Ambassador said as many as 100 members of Congress had recently visited China.</p>
<p>James Sasser stressed the need for Washington to develop a &quot;consistent, credible&quot; policy toward China as new Communist party leaders succeed the late Deng Xiaoping.</p>
<p>To do this, regular contacts were necessary, he said in a speech entitled &quot;Engaging China&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;About 20 percent of the U.S. Congress visited China in January,&quot; he told a meeting of mostly Chinese-American and Taiwanese businessmen.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the best expenditure of taxpayers' money...to get younger Congress members, many of whom have never been overseas, out of the United States and around the world to learn what's happening in other areas.&quot;</p>
<p>Vice President Al Gore is scheduled to become the most senior American to visit China in eight years when he arrives in Beijing later this month for meetings intended to help pave the way for an exchange of presidential visits.</p>
<p>Sasser joked that he and his wife had entertained so many visiting members of Congress lately that the couple felt like &quot;the concierges of Beijing.&quot;</p>
<p>However, earlier China was not joking when it lashed out at the United States over Hong Kong and human rights, accusing Washington of Cold War thinking and saying ignorant U.S. congressmen were trying to meddle in China's internal affairs.</p>
<p>The House wronged China on Tuesday when it approved a bill calling on Beijing to honor its promises on Hong Kong, spokesman Cui Tiankai told reporters in the Chinese capital.</p>
<p>The bill calls on China to honor its treaty with Britain which promises Hong Kong extensive autonomy after its return to Chinese rule on July 1.</p>
<p>&quot;There are some people in the U.S. Congress who know nothing about realities in Hong Kong and have no idea about China's Hong Kong policy,&quot; Cui said.</p>
<p>Sasser acknowledged that although some Congress members could teach him about China, there were &quot;a lot who are not informed and have never been ... to China.&quot;</p>
<p>The Sino-U.S. rapprochement has already had to withstand friction over alleged Chinese funding of U.S. politicians, and analysts say Hong Kong is likely to become a new diplomatic minefield as the handover nears.</p>
<p>In his address, Sasser listed the future of Hong Kong as one of the four major areas of misunderstanding between China and the United States. Noting that 37,000 U.S. citizens lived in the British colony and 800 U.S. firms had offices there, he said the Chinese leadership understood they needed &quot;the entrepreneurial genius&quot; of Hong Kong.</p>
<p>&quot;To sustain such a U.S. presence requires a society that is governed by the rule of law,&quot; the former Tennessee senator said. The other sensitive areas were human rights, nuclear proliferation and Taiwan.</p>
<p>The huge trade imbalance favoring China was also an irritant in relations and Beijing must be pressured to open up its markets, he said.</p>
<p>But Sasser said Washington supported China getting a seat on the World Trade Organization and he hoped that would lead to China being granted permanent Most Favored Nation trade status by Washington.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
