<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44380" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Strong growth seen for African franc zone.</title>
<headline>Strong growth seen for African franc zone.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The economies of the 14 African countries belonging to the franc zone should grow strongly in 1996, powered by higher exports and more import substitutes, the Bank of France forecast on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The gross domestic product (GDP) of the central African franc zone should rise by 5.5 percent in 1996 after growing by 3.1 percent last year. GDP in the west African franc zone should grow by 6.0 percent after growing 5.8 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>The central bank made the forecast in its annual review of economic prospects of France's 13 African former colonies which devalued their common French-backed CFA franc currency by 50 percent in January 1994. The 14th country in the zone, the Comoros Islands in the Indian Ocean, devalued by 33 percent.</p>
<p>France precipitated the drastic devaluation by making its aid contingent on the countries winning the backing of the International Monetary Fund. The IMF demanded they break a 46-year-old fixed parity with the franc because it made their manufacturing costs far higher than their neighbours.</p>
<p>&quot;Development of exports has been one of the most important factors contributing to the growth recovery,&quot; the Bank said. Before devaluation, the countries were plagued by zero growth.</p>
<p>&quot;Economic growth in 1996 will be driven by the same factors as in 1995 -- higher exports and development of import substitutes which are becoming more competitive against imported goods,&quot; the Bank said.</p>
<p>The Bank said a fall in inflation had bolstered competitive gains and forecast prices would rise by 3.5 percent in the zone this year, down from six percent in 1995. Inflation was running at 39 percent in 1994.</p>
<p>The bank said a jump in credit testified to the rebound in activity with loans up by nearly 16 percent in west Africa last year and nine percent in central Africa.</p>
<p>It said the countries had also made progress on the budget front with revenues up sharply as a result of economic growth, wider tax nets and better tax collection.</p>
<p>But it said the improvement was fragile and that foreign debt continued to weigh on public finances. As a result of the devaluation, the debt load at end 1994 was $49.4 billion representing of 153.2 percent of the GDP of the region against 104.9 percent in 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
