<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="443862" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germans start asking why they have no euro debate.</title>
<headline>Germans start asking why they have no euro debate.</headline>
<byline>Tom Heneghan</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slowly but not surely, Germans are starting to ask why they don't have a lively public debate about Europe's planned single currency like that in Britain or France.</p>
<p>It's not that the euro isn't mentioned at all.</p>
<p>Chancellor Helmut Kohl repeatedly reaffirms his support for European economic and monetary union (EMU). Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer declared on Friday that this was not the time to discuss delaying the ambitious project.</p>
<p>But, apart from some economists, few figures in public life ask such thorny questions. Pro-Europeanism is the motto and even suggesting a delay or a weakening of the strict criteria for EMU has been politically incorrect until now.</p>
<p>Mainstream sceptics are a tiny minority. Their concerns are now being aired more openly, but the solid consensus in Bonn looks far from being interested in change.</p>
<p>&quot;While people abroad, especially in France and Britain, discuss the sense or nonsense, advantages and disadvantages of the common currency with eloquence and passion, we seem to feel that talking or thinking about it is banned,&quot; the popular illustrated weekly Stern said this week.</p>
<p>Another weekly, Die Woche, landed on the newsstands on Thursday with a headline screaming &quot;Delay the euro!&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Like all the negative side-effects of German unification, the Maastricht treaty was made into a taboo,&quot; it wrote.</p>
<p>&quot;Whoever criticised it was either unpatriotic or anti-European and thus suspect in political circles ranging from the Christian Democrats to the Greens. The media have willingly gone along with this so far.&quot;</p>
<p>In recent months, Germany's opinion-making press has been watching with fascination as French intellectuals debate the pros and cons of the euro with typical Gallic verve. Op-ed pages have run interviews with sceptics like Emmanuel Todd or Pierre Bourdieu and analyses of the anti-Maastricht camp.</p>
<p>The strongly anti-EU tone of some British Eurosceptic politicians has blunted the impact in Germany of even moderately critical comments about the Maastricht treaty from London.</p>
<p>Polite audiences recently sat through speeches by two visiting cabinet members -- Malcolm Rifkind from the Foreign Office and Trade and Industry Secretary Ian Lang -- and left commenting how curious these islanders were.</p>
<p>Except for a few figures on the right-wing fringe, German politicians are so unanimous about the need for EMU that many say they do not want a public debate about it.</p>
<p>President Roman Herzog said as much last December.  Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel said on Thursday that &quot;the point of no return for the euro has been passed.&quot;</p>
<p>The heavy losses the Social Democrats (SPD) suffered when they tried a mildly Euro-sceptical campaign in a state election last year have convinced most in the main opposition party the issue has little voter appeal.</p>
<p>&quot;I would urge that we should not have a debate now,&quot; SPD parliamentary leader Rudolf Scharping said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>That leaves a very small circle of mainstream politicians ready for a real debate, all of them state premiers outside of Bonn like Lower Saxony's Gerhard Schroeder, Kurt Biedenkopf of Saxony or Bavarian leader Edmund Stoiber.</p>
<p>Some of Germany's influential trade unions have also begun asking worried questions about the effect the euro will have on jobs, and wondering if it should be delayed.</p>
<p>But the only others really challenging the euro are on the nationalist far-right fringe, a group no mainstream German wants to be identified with.</p>
<p>Conservative historian Arnulf Baring chided leaders like Kohl for avoiding a real debate on his pet project.</p>
<p>&quot;Kohl is so convinced of the need for the euro that he doesn't really want to discuss it with the voters,&quot; Baring wrote recently.</p>
<p>&quot;Politicians know a solid majority is against the euro but that people are convinced it will come,&quot; he wrote. &quot;The politicians take popular resignation, this lack of readiness to fight against the euro, as the start of acceptance.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
