<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="443824" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU ministers set to scrutinise Germany's EMU plans.</title>
<headline>EU ministers set to scrutinise Germany's EMU plans.</headline>
<byline>Henry Engler</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany, the linchpin of Europe's grand design for a common currency, will be in the hot seat on Monday when EU finance ministers pore over its 1997 plans to join European monetary union.</p>
<p>While both Germany's and France's economic convergence programmes will be at the top of the ministerial agenda, the focus will be squarely on Bonn's blueprint, given renewed worries over its ability to rein in public expenditure.</p>
<p>Record unemployment in Germany, totalling close to 4.8 million, has caused analysts and EU monetary officials to question whether additional spending cuts are needed to meet the country's ambitious deficit target of 2.9 percent of gross domestic product (GDP).</p>
<p>An EU source said on Friday &quot;it remains to be seen how far the Germans will have to undertake further (budget) efforts to keep in line with the numbers.&quot;</p>
<p>Details of Bonn's convergence plans include the relatively optimistic assumption that unemployment in 1997 will not exceed an average of 4.1 million.</p>
<p>But scepticism about Germany's ability to meet the Maastricht Treaty's economic targets for economic and monetary union (EMU), and the possibility of a delay to the project's 1999 start date, has been fuelled by the lack of any contingency plans from Bonn.</p>
<p>At a recent meeting of the EU's monetary committee in Brussels, numerous officials were apparently critical of the way in which Germany presented its convergence programme without any alternative scenarios should its economic assumptions not hold.</p>
<p>&quot;They delivered something really sub-standard,&quot; said one monetary source. &quot;It left all the questions open and was largely wishful thinking from back to front.&quot;</p>
<p>An added concern for some is a shift in official rhetoric over the necessity for a supplementary budget, which earlier in the year included the possibility of a spending freeze.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm worried because I don't see any decisions,&quot; said one London-based analyst. &quot;If I don't see anything soon I must draw certain conclusions.&quot;</p>
<p>German Finance Minister Theo Waigel, apparently heeding such views, said on Friday a spending freeze had not been ruled out entirely.</p>
<p>&quot;A freeze is still being discussed and is not off the agenda. But at the moment, there is no decision to impose such a freeze,&quot; Waigel told a news conference.</p>
<p>Amid such uncertainty, EU diplomats nonetheless predicted a favourable assessment of both the German and French programmes.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite all the difficulties the German authorities are committed to participate (in the single currency),&quot; one diplomat said.</p>
<p>Among the other assumptions in the 1997 German plan is 2.5 percent real GDP growth, a rise in inflation of 1.5 percent and a 6.2 percent yield on long-term government bonds.</p>
<p>Ironically for France, long accustomed to having financial markets question its commitment to EMU, there is likely to be less angst over its EMU convergence plan.</p>
<p>&quot;The figures are reliable and convincing,&quot; said another diplomat.</p>
<p>The French programme, which includes a 3.0 percent deficit-to-GDP target, also sees outstanding government debt slightly below 60 percent of output -- the Maastricht threshold.</p>
<p>For Germany, this latter EMU requirement has proven troublesome, with the trend rate edging higher over the last few years. Officials confirmed on Friday that Bonn's expectation for total debt is 61.5 percent of GDP, up from 60.7 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>According to Maastricht, a government's debt ratio must be &quot;sufficiently diminishing&quot; and approaching the 60 percent target at a satisfactory pace in order to take part in the single currency.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
