<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="444007" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Clarke sees July tax hike if Labour wins.</title>
<headline>UK's Clarke sees July tax hike if Labour wins.</headline>
<dateline>BATH, England 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Finance Minister Kenneth Clarke on Friday accused the opposition Labour Party of planning a July tax raising budget if it won the immminent general election.</p>
<p>And he warned Britons that the country would &quot;take a holiday&quot; from the liberalising trend of economic history if it elected a Labour government.</p>
<p>Clarke was making a keynote speech to a lunch for senior Conservatives ahead of the party's annual Central Council meeting in the western town of Bath.  </p>
<p>&quot;The only way to get ahead and then stay ahead is to keep reforming, keep modernising, keep adapting. And new Labour wants to say 'We stop here'. Our children, your children would never forgive us if we let them do it.&quot; Clarke said.</p>
<p>He said the Conservatives' problem was that they had been so successful in changing the economic debate in Britain that some people were willing to entrust the economy to Labour.</p>
<p>&quot;They think now the Tories have got it right, Britain can take a holiday from history under Labour, and somehow put reality on hold.&quot;</p>
<p>But Clarke added: &quot;If people vote Labour to escape from reality, they will soon have their illusions shattered. The fact is the world has become a place of constant change...there is no turning back.&quot;</p>
<p>Clarke launched a withering attack on Labour economics spokesman Gordon Brown for agreeing with his spending plans within months of the election, having spent the previous four years opposing every Conservative policy.  &quot;Is this a sinner come to repentance. No, it's new Labour on the eve of an election. Labour just will not answer straight questions.&quot;</p>
<p>He said if Labour denied themselves the privatisation proceeds the Conservatives were planning to garner, they would be forced to raise taxes.</p>
<p>&quot;What does anyone imagine (Labour leader) Tony Blair and Gordon Brown are promising a July budget for?&quot; Clarke asked. &quot;They want a July budget to put taxes up. Not just the windfall tax (on privatised utilities)... other taxes too, to fill the 12 billion stg hole in their first two years' plans.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BATH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
