<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="444188" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China takes measures to curb silk industry chaos.</title>
<headline>China takes measures to curb silk industry chaos.</headline>
<byline>Jane Macartney</byline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>China has implemented a series of measures to stop chaos in its silk industry, banning cocoon speculation among provinces, restricting silk-reeling capacity and gradually raising silk export prices.</p>
<p>&quot;This time our actions are different from ever before, we have set some clear standards and policies,&quot; Yi Hui, office director of the State Cocoon and Silk Coordinating Group, told Reuters by telephone on Friday.</p>
<p>The group, together with the State Planning Commission, issued a joint circular, ordering that all cocoon deals among provinces should be struck only through a market in Jiaxing city in southeastern Zhejiang province, he said.</p>
<p>The circular was part of a bid to prevent severe price fluctuations for cocoons that have followed disorder in inter-provincial trade and to ensure fair distribution of cocoons through a unified market, he said.</p>
<p>The transfer of cocoons from one province to another must be licensed by all levels of authorities responsible for silk, he said.</p>
<p>Cocoon shipments that lacked the necessary authorisation would be held or confiscated, Yi said.</p>
<p>Speculative dealers drove up the price of cocoons to 60,000 yuan ($7,200) per tonne by the end of last year, virtually wiping out profits for the textile sector with prices for finished product failing to keep pace, Yi said.</p>
<p>In the Jiaxing market, any cocoon deal concluded at a price above a ceiling of 45,000 yuan per tonne would be scrapped, he said, adding that this was the maximum level at which the textile sector could still make a profit.</p>
<p>Yi attributed the current cocoon shortage to the fact that farmers were still reluctant to raise silkworms after two years of over-production in 1994 and 1995.</p>
<p>China's silk industry boomed until 1993 but slipped into the doldrums from the second half of 1994 due to a price war among silk exporters and the setting up of excessive capacity at silk-reeling plants, state media has said.</p>
<p>China would cut current silk-reeling capacity by about one-third -- equivalent to the current oversupply by the first half of next year, Yi said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is somewhat difficult because of localism,&quot; he said, referring to local protectionism.</p>
<p>&quot;But anyway, the market economy decides whether silk firms survive or not... small firms will be eliminated by mergers or in other ways,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>China has raised its export price for raw silk by 9.6 percent to 25,000 yuan per tonne since last October, and would also force up export prices of finished products gradually in the next few years, Yi said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the silk industry to start a recovery this year, but for full recovery and further development, we still need a certain period of time,&quot; Yi said.</p>
<p>China, the world's biggest producer and exporter of silk, is expected to export about 75 percent of all its silk products and 10,000 tonnes of raw silk this year, he said.</p>
<p>China exported $2.5 billion worth of silk products in 1996, down by 18 percent from a year ago, Yi said.</p>
<p>($1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
