<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="444270" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL shares close lower after Dow's drop.</title>
<headline>KL shares close lower after Dow's drop.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian shares stayed weak until the close as market sentiment was depressed by a sharp drop on Wall Street overnight, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Dow's fall is pulling down the market which is still in a consolidation phase,&quot; said one institutional dealer. Overnight, the Dow Jones Industrial Average closed 160 points lower to 6,878.89.</p>
<p>Dealers said fears of an imminent U.S. interest rate hike continued to limit buying.</p>
<p>The Composite Index of 100 large-capitalised stocks ended down 7.29 points at 1,242.47.  </p>
<p>Dealers said market focus continued to be on small-capitalised second board stocks by retail punters.</p>
<p>The Second Board Index closed up 3.91 points to 661.59.</p>
<p>Rothmans led the drop in blue-chip stocks, falling 80 cents to 23.60 ringgit. Other major losers included Malayan Banking, United Engineers and Arab-Malaysian Merchant Bank.</p>
<p>KLI Holdings continued to lead activity, but the stock fell 15 cents to 5.25 ringgit at the close. Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad is to launch KLI's industrial park producing locally-made home appliances on Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
