<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="444364" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Aussie dlr surges against yen, 100 yen in sight.</title>
<headline>Aussie dlr surges against yen, 100 yen in sight.</headline>
<byline>Elaine Lies</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar on Friday surged to its highest level against the yen since 1992, and Tokyo dealers said it is highly likely to hit 100 yen soon. &quot;Given how weak the yen continues to be, and the Aussie's generally good performance across the board, I'd say 100 yen is a very realistic target,&quot; one Australian bank manager said.</p>
<p>Although the Aussie has been given a boost recently by a basically solid Australian economy, the main incentive remains the high interest rates that lure investment from overseas.</p>
<p>Friday trade saw the Aussie rise to around 98.90-95 yen, its highest level since June 1992, by late afternoon. The upward moves were driven partly by the U.S. dollar's gains against the yen and partly by buying by Japanese securities firms in connection with dual-currency bond issues, dealers said.</p>
<p>Two Australian dollar-linked dual-currency bonds were launched this week: 15 billion yen worth of yen/Australian dollar reverse dual-currency samurai bonds issued by Landesbank Rheinland-Pfalz AG, and 30 billion yen worth of yen/Australian dollar dual-currency samurai bonds issued by DSL Bank. Both are lead-managed by Nomura Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw a lot of Japanese names buying the Aussie heavily today, which tells us that Japanese operators still have a pretty good appetite for overseas investment,&quot; said Kenneth Landon, a senior currency strategist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>Other dealers said Swiss and possibly U.S. operators were also detected buying the Aussie on Friday.</p>
<p>The next important point for the Aussie is 99.05 yen, a key technical retracement level from its 1995 low of 59 yen to its 124 yen high in 1990, Landon said.</p>
<p>&quot;If we can make it above 99.05 and hold it there we'll know that this is more than just an upward correction,&quot; he said, adding that the Aussie could reach 102 yen by the end of March.</p>
<p>But others were warier, noting that the imminent close of Japan's fiscal year at the end of this month will spark some sales. &quot;We are still seeing selling interest out of Tokyo, and this may impede further rallies,&quot; said a senior dealer at one Australian bank, although he agreed the Aussie was indeed likely to touch 100 yen within the month.</p>
<p>A murky interest rate picture also makes predictions about future Aussie moves hard. Jobs data released on Thursday showed a drop of 7,200 jobs in February and an unemployment rate at 8.8 percent, suggesting the economy is still not that robust.</p>
<p>&quot;Although there are a lot of people in the market who say the most recent interest rate cut was the last, the jobs numbers were certainly bad. If we see more bad figures, talk of an interest rate cut could emerge,&quot; the bank manager said.</p>
<p>Australia's official cash rate was last cut, to 6.0 percent, in December 1996.</p>
<p>Deutsche Morgan Grenfell's Landon said the jobs figures &quot;were pretty awful. But compared to Japanese rates, Australian rates are still looking better.&quot;</p>
<p>The yield on 10-year Australian bonds was 7.9 percent by Friday afternoon, due in large part to overnight rises in U.S. Treasury bonds. By contrast, the yield on the key 182nd 10-year Japanese government bond fell to a record low of 2.190 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
