<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="444562" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: PRESS DIGEST - Singapore - March 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Singapore - March 14.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the top stories from selected Singapore newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE STRAITS TIMES:</p>
<p>- Singapore Senior Minister Lee Kuan Yew apologises unreservedly to the government and people of Malaysia for his criticism of the south Malaysian town of Johor Bru.</p>
<p>- Dhoby Ghaut area looks set to become a bustling hub.</p>
<p>- Britain's House of Commons bans pagers in parliament.</p>
<p>- Singapore Power and Singapore Technologies Telemedia team in joint venture with British Telecom and Japan's NTT Corp to bid for nation's second basic telephone licence.</p>
<p>- Singapore's direct overseas investment hits Singapore $46 billion.</p>
<p>- Corporate raider Johanes Kotjo sells entire 8.4 percent stake in United Pulp &amp; Paper for about Singapore $14.6 million.</p>
<p>THE BUSINESS TIMES:</p>
<p>- Japanese government cracks down on financial sector crimes.</p>
<p>- Fang Ai Lian, first Singapore woman to head an international accounting firm, is voted Woman of the Year 1996.</p>
<p>- Singapore and Hong Kong markets among hardest hit as regional stocks plunge.</p>
<p>- Gul Technologies' public share offer closes at 135 times subscribed.</p>
<p>- Precision machining company Micro-Machining Industries receives nod for mainboard listing.</p>
<p>- Hotel Properties Ltd beats analysts' forecasts with 51 percent jump in profit to Singapore $44.1 million.</p>
<p>- Electronics contract manufacturer Transtech Electronics targets main-board listing in August to raise Singapore $18 million.</p>
<p>- Close to two-thirds of Hong Kong-based Noble Group Ltd 10.3 million shares to go to small investors.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom 65-8703080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
