<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="444696" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: PRESS DIGEST - Portugal -- March 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Portugal -- March 14.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are leading domestic stories in Portuguese newspapers.</p>
<p>PUBLICO</p>
<p>- The economy will slow down from 1999. The government presents its Convergence Programme, which was approved yesterday in the cabinet. An average anual growth of 3.4 percent is predicted until the year 2000, although the economy will slow down after 1999.The fiscal deficit will be 1.5 percent in 1999.</p>
<p>- Pilots of state airline TAP to go ahead with strike. The president of the pilots' union Joao Soeiro told Publico the strike would start on Saturday.</p>
<p>- The government's new internationalisation programme for the economy will involve a total amount of 150 billion escudos, although new funds from the Finance Ministry are only total 35 billion.</p>
<p>DIARIO DE NOTICIAS</p>
<p>- There are hospitals where patients are waiting for an appointment more than two years and for surgery more than eight years.</p>
<p>- Portugal Telecom wants to integrate its two paging companies Contactel and Telemensagem into a single company.</p>
<p>- Since 1994, Portugal has reported to the European Union 26 fraud cases related to regional development funds.</p>
<p>DIARIO ECONOMICO</p>
<p>- Felipe Gonzalez proposes former Portuguese premier Anibal Cavaco Silva as a name to succeed eventually Jacques Santer as President of the European Commission.</p>
<p>- Foreign banks' profits in Portugal grew 48 percent in 1996 but their return on capital is low.</p>
<p>- Unions fear the privatisation of Brisa, the Portuguese Motorway Company, will lead to job losses.</p>
<p>SEMANARIO ECONOMICO</p>
<p>- EDP - the Portuguese state electricity company - made record profits in 1996 of 81.1 billion escudos, the highest of any Portuguese company.</p>
<p>--Lisbon bureau 3511-3538254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
