<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="444715" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: New EU rice system awaits decision on barley.</title>
<headline>New EU rice system awaits decision on barley.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union rice officials postponed a decision on a new rice import system until next week, a Commission official said on Friday.</p>
<p>They will await a decision by farm ministers on a proposed 30,000 tonne reduced tariff malting barley quota for the U.S., the Commmission official said.</p>
<p>A special meeting of the cereals and rice management committee has been scheduled for next Tuesday when farm ministers are due to consider the barley quota.</p>
<p>The EU cereals committee on Thursday sent the barley quota proposal to farm ministers because it remained divided with eight member states opposed.</p>
<p>The quota carrying a 50 percent tariff reduction was agreed by the Commission in world trade negotiations to compensate U.S. exporters for the loss of Austrian, Swedish and Finnish markets following enlargement of the EU in 1995.</p>
<p>The quota would benefit one U.S. brewery's European production and EU member states also want access to reduced quota barley for their brewers, a Commission official explained.</p>
<p>EU rice experts have been unable to agree for the past 18 months on a new import system of cumulative recovery for traders who overpay import tariffs.</p>
<p>Both issues are under threat of a U.S. complaint to the World Trade Organisation (WTO) to be heard on March 20.</p>
<p>&quot;The committee felt that the new rice import proposal and the malting barley quota are linked by the threat of WTO complaints and they want to wait to see what ministers decide on the barley quota,&quot; a rice millers' spokesman said.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the organisation opposed the new cumulative recovery system.</p>
<p>&quot;The management committee are waiting to see if ministers can resolve the barley quota impasse and if so then a way may be found to settle the rice question,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
