<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="444778" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany now more attractive for business - Opel.</title>
<headline>Germany now more attractive for business - Opel.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>David Herman, chief executive of General Motors Co's German unit Adam Opel AG, said recent developments in Germany were making it increasingly more attractive as a place to invest.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation in Germany has significantly improved compared to its western neighbours,&quot; Herman was quoted as saying in an interview published in the Friday edition of the Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung newspaper.</p>
<p>Herman said the recent softening of the mark, low inflation and an improved dialogue with workers and unions all added to Germany's traditional advantages, which included a good market and an environment favourable to the realisation of business projects.</p>
<p>Such factors, he said, had played a role in Opel's decision to produce its new diesel engine in its German Kaiserslautern plant. &quot;We could have built that anywhere in the world.&quot;</p>
<p>Herman nonetheless bemoaned the continued high level of non-wage labour costs in Germany and what he called rigid labour laws that, for example, make employing people on a temporary basis more difficult.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
