<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="444815" id="root" date="1997-03-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: EMU delay would have limited market impact-Dresdner.</title>
<headline>EMU delay would have limited market impact-Dresdner.</headline>
<byline>David Crossland</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Any delay in European monetary union would have only a very limited impact on financial markets and would not send the mark &quot;shooting through the roof&quot;, a management board member of Dresdner Bank AG said on Friday.</p>
<p>Gerd Haeusler, a former Bundesbank official who joined Dresdner last year, told Reuters that markets would react more calmly than many believed to a postponement if EMU criteria were not met. This would be partly because exchange rates were now better aligned than at any time since German unification in 1990.</p>
<p>Also, any mark rise would probably be stemmed because the attractiveness of the currency would be impaired if Germany failed to meet the convergence criteria, Haeusler said. Dresdner is Germany's second biggest bank.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that in the event of a postponement the effect on financial markets would be very limited,&quot; Haeusler said, contradicting comments from senior Bundesbank officials. &quot;The mark would not shoot through the roof.&quot;</p>
<p>EMU (economic and monetary union) is scheduled for launch in 1999. But Germany, beset by the highest unemployment since the 1930s, is struggling to cut its budget deficit to the level demanded from EMU entry by the Maastricht treaty.</p>
<p>Haeusler said that a trend towards greater domestic ownership of securities in European markets meant the destabilising role of foreign hedge funds, which were behind the exchange rate turbulence of 1993, had now diminished.</p>
<p>Central banks were now more likely to take exchange rates into account than they have in the past and would be more willing to counteract currency movements by changing interest rates, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the euro will come,&quot; Haeusler said. &quot;But I think it would be very difficult to push through monetary union according to the timetable if the convergence criteria were not fulfilled.&quot;</p>
<p>But Hausler made clear he did not favour a delay in the EMU launch. &quot;I would find it deplorable if major nations did not meet the criteria and a postponement thus became necessary,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Yet his comments stand in stark contrast to recent warnings from Bundesbank council members Guntram Palm and Ernst Welteke who said a delay would harm the German economy by provoking a sharp appreciation of the mark.</p>
<p>Speculation that the euro may not be launched on January 1, 1999 has mounted in recent months due to fears that Germany might not meet the budget criterion in 1997, the year on which prospective members will be judged.</p>
<p>Haeusler, who is responsible for Dresdner's business in Asia, noted that Asian investors were growing more concerned that the euro may not be as stable as the mark. The investors were also becoming more aware of the possibility that Germany might not qualify, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;I have observed since I have been travelling for Dresdner in Asia, and even before, that mark investors have been watching Europe's progress toward monetary union closely, and with a degree of scepticism,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;They are not certain that the euro will have the same quality as they were accustomed to with the mark, as it will have no track record.&quot;</p>
<p>Haeusler's comments came after the chief executive of the Hong Kong Monetary Authority, Joseph Yam, told a forum at Dresdner Bank that Asian investors were cutting back their investments in Europe because of uncertainty surrounding monetary union.</p>
<p>Under the Maastricht Treaty, a country must keep its budget deficit below three percent of its gross domestic product (GDP) to qualify.</p>
<p>Bonn aims to cut its deficit to 2.9 percent of GDP this year from 3.8 percent in 1996 but the unabated rise in unemployment is squeezing tax revenues and boosting benefit payments.</p>
<p>Haeusler identified three reasons for Germany's fiscal difficulties.</p>
<p>Firstly, the rise in exports, traditionally a trigger of domestic investment and consumer spending in German economic upturns, was failing to act as a spark in the present cycle.</p>
<p>That was because many companies were investing abroad or simply shelving investments because they were uncertain about the impact of planned tax reforms, Haeusler said.</p>
<p>Secondly, unemployment was rising steadily and thirdly, the present recovery was not boosting tax revenues as much as in past upswings because companies and individuals had become more adept at reducing their tax payments.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
