<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44496" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraqi Kurdish refugees mass at Iranian border.</title>
<headline>Iraqi Kurdish refugees mass at Iranian border.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>SAIRAN BAN, Iraq 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least 10,000 Kurdish refugees fled northern Iraq for the Iranian border on Tuesday for fear that President Saddam Hussein would regain control of their embattled region, witnesses said.</p>
<p>The refugees streamed to Sairan Ban, one of at least four border crossings where United Nations officials expected up to 75,000 Kurds to gather following the takeover of northern Iraq by a Baghdad-backed Kurdish militia faction.</p>
<p>&quot;We're afraid. We don't trust the government of Saddam Hussein,&quot; said a headmaster from the city of Sulaimaniya, which the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP), now aligned with Saddam, captured from the rival Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK) on Monday.</p>
<p>It was too early to assess what price Saddam would extract from the KDP in return for his support. But Kurdish residents were taking no chances. Many remembered the poison gas Saddam used against Kurdish villagers in 1988.</p>
<p>Sairan Ban crossing was closed, so thousands of people were backed up, hanging out of hundreds of cars that jammed a hot, dusty road from Penjwin, 30 km (18 miles) away. Tractors pulled wagons piled high with belongings.</p>
<p>They were joined by hundreds of armed PUK guerrillas on the run.</p>
<p>It was unclear whether refugees were allowed to cross anywhere. U.N. officials in Iraq near the border said they had heard of a queue extending 35 km (21 miles) from Sulaimaniya towards Chamchamal on Sunday.</p>
<p>Iran appealed for world aid for nearly 200,000 refugees.</p>
<p>In Geneva, U.N. officials said they had been assured by Iran that refugees would be allowed to cross if necessary. Other U.N. officials in Iraq said Iran was willing to create a slender buffer zone.</p>
<p>An estimated two million Kurds poured into Turkey and Iran in 1991 when Saddam crushed Kurdish and Shi'ite Moslem uprisings which erupted after Iraq's defeat at the hands of a Western alliance in the Gulf War.</p>
<p>Most of the Kurds returned to northern Iraq after the Western allies set up a safe haven and began regular air patrols to shield civilians from any attack by Baghdad.</p>
<p>In Sulaimaniya, thousands of KDP guerrillas drove around the city, waving flags. Patriotic music blared from loudspeakers. Some buildings were on fire, but there was little sign of heavy fighting.</p>
<p>U.N. officials said they would provide medical supplies to the refugees to fight dysentery, but said they had no intention of providing food or tents that allow the Kurds to settle in for a protracted stay.</p>
<p>KDP guerrillas said they took Sulaimaniya, the last PUK stronghold, on Monday evening after moving in from Halabja to the southeast.</p>
<p>Before the final attack the PUK burned its headquarters, ammunition dumps and its members' homes to deny the KDP the opportunity of looting them, a senior U.N. official said.</p>
<p>&quot;Capturing symbols is what it is all about. Burning them, looting them and putting them on TV,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Washington launched 44 cruise missiles at southern Iraq after tens of thousands of Iraqi government troops helped the KDP capture the city of Arbil on August 31.</p>
<p>There were reports after the fall of Arbil that Iraqi security forces, helped by the KDP, had rounded up and executed over 100 members of the opposition Iraqi National Congress (INC) in the city.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton said on Monday the United States was helping &quot;those who have worked with us&quot; to flee the fighting in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>The United States urged Tehran and Baghdad to stop fuelling inter-Kurdish violence in northern Iraq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAIRAN BAN, Iraq"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
