<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="445098" id="root" date="1997-03-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Hostage crisis prompts new Peru police shake-up.</title>
<headline>Hostage crisis prompts new Peru police shake-up.</headline>
<byline>James Craig</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-03-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peru's 88-day hostage crisis has sparked a new police shake-up as President Alberto Fujimori on Saturday scrapped a trip to Bolivia, whose envoy to Lima is one of 72 hostages held by Marxist rebels.</p>
<p>An Interior Ministry source said the heads of police special operations directorate DINOES and its tactical operations unit (SUAT) were transferred for poor handling of the siege at the Japanese ambassador's home, partly for leaking information to the news media.</p>
<p>&quot;They were transferred due to the closeness they have with reporters in the handling of information,&quot; said the source, who spoke on condition of anonymity. &quot;There were no secrets because everything was known.&quot;</p>
<p>DINOES head Col. Julio Santillan Valdivia and SUAT chief Col. Juan Carlos Mejia Leon were moved to desk jobs in the police Inspector General's Office, the source said.</p>
<p>Fujimori in the early days of the crisis replaced Peru's two top security chiefs, including the head of the anti-terrorist police DINCOTE, who were among the hostages.</p>
<p>Peru's government has been at odds with the foreign news media since Dec. 17, when about 20 Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels stormed the Japanese envoy's mansion and seized hundreds of VIP cocktail party guests.</p>
<p>In January, a Japanese reporter was expelled for sneaking into the residence to interview rebel chief Nestor Cerpa. Last week a foreign camaraman fled Peru citing veiled threats by intelligence agents after he spoke to hostage-takers via radio.</p>
<p>A government spokeswoman said Fujimori has put off to next week a planned three-day trip to La Paz to meet with Bolivian President Gonzalo Sanchez de Lozada, whose ambassador was reportedly showing signs of emotional breakdown as a hostage. No new date has been set for the visit.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, La Paz's ambassador Jorge Gumucio quarreled with an MRTA rebel inside the compound, a police source said. The rebel threatened Gumucio with a gun before other hostages intervened to calm things, the source said.</p>
<p>There have been frequent appeals on health grounds for the release of Gumucio, who is diabetic and has a history of heart and blood pressure problems. But the rebels have held on to the only hostage from a country other than Peru and Japan in the hope of exchanging him for MRTA members jailed in Bolivia.</p>
<p>The rebels' main demand is the release of about 400 jailed comrades, nearly all of them in Peru. Fujimori has publicly rejected the demand but speculation has risen recently that the government is privateley considering some minor releases.</p>
<p>The rebels freed most of their hostages early in the siege but are holding on to those they consider the best bargaining chips, including Fujimori's brother, two ministers, the ambassadors of Japan and Bolivia and a host of Japanese businessmen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
