<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="445199" id="root" date="1997-03-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Arafat and international envoys to talk peace.</title>
<headline>Arafat and international envoys to talk peace.</headline>
<byline>Taher Shriteh</byline>
<dateline>GAZA 1997-03-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat will meet international envoys on Saturday to try to salvage peace talks with Israel that are deadlocked over a planned Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem, PLO officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;This meeting is an invitation to save the peace process,&quot; Palestinian official Ahmed Korei said after a cabinet meeting in self-ruled Gaza late on Friday.</p>
<p>Israel's decision to build 6,500 Jewish housing units in East Jerusalem sent Arab-Israeli ties to their lowest point since the 1993 PLO-Israeli peace accord and angered Western states.</p>
<p>Israel also raised Arab ire when it unilaterally decided on the scope of a West Bank pullback that fell short of Palestinian expectations.</p>
<p>Arafat, pressed by the Americans to prevent a Palestinian backlash, initiated the meeting to be attended by U.S., Arab and European representatives at 0800 GMT on Saturday in Gaza.</p>
<p>Israel was not invited.</p>
<p>&quot;We will ask the countries that oversaw and witnessed the signing of the (Oslo) accord to fulfil their role in protecting the peace process,&quot; said Palestinian official Ahmed Abdel Rahman.</p>
<p>Arafat has said the meeting will discuss &quot;clear Israeli violations&quot; of the Israel-PLO peace agreement &quot;that undermine the peace process and threaten the whole Middle East&quot;.</p>
<p>Palestinians see Israel's decision to build at the site, called Jabal Abu Ghneim in Arabic and as Har Homa in Hebrew, as a threat to their hopes of establishing a Palestinian state with East Jerusalem as its capital. Israel views all of Jerusalem as its &quot;eternal&quot; capital.</p>
<p>Under the 1993 PLO-Israeli peace accord the future of Jerusalem and the fate of Jewish settlements in the West Bank and Gaza will be determined in 'final status' talks set to resume later this month and end in 1999.</p>
<p>The U.N. General Assembly, by a vote of 130 to two, with two abstentions, called on Israel on Thursday to abandon the planned settlement.</p>
<p>The United States and Israel cast the only negative votes on the resolution, similar to one vetoed on March 7 by the U.S. in the Security Council.</p>
<p>But the killing of seven Israeli schoolgirls by a lone Jordanian soldier on Thursday diverted much of the international criticism Israel has faced over the plan.</p>
<p>Israel again vowed on Friday to begin construction at the site next week.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no specific day but it will begin next week,&quot; Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's adviser, David Bar-Illan told Reuters on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GAZA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
