<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44515" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan divests key stake in cement firm.</title>
<headline>Jordan divests key stake in cement firm.</headline>
<byline>Suleiman al-Khalidi</byline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan, in the first major sale of a key holding in a profitable majority state-owned company, hopes to divest a 20 percent stake in Cement Factories Company to a strategic foreign partner by next November.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first experiment of its kind for Jordan on the global level to offer stock of some of the profitable companies to international firms,&quot; Mohammed Bataynah, general manager of Jordan Investment Corporation (JIC), the investment arm of the government, told Reuters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Officials say the proposed sale is the first tangible step to sell a profitable majority state-owned concern under a privatisation plan key to success of Jordan's three-year IMF directed expanded economic reforms launched this year.</p>
<p>Officials say JIC, which owns parts of over 70 public shareholding companies listed in the Amman Financial Market with an estimated market value of around 500 million dinars ($706 million), is key to the success of the government's stepped up sell-off policy of listed companies.</p>
<p>JIC will reduce its share to 29.5 percent of Jordan Cement Factories Company's total 60 million dinar equity -- down from a 49.5 percent total stake. It is however restricting the sale to internationally established cement firms.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not offering our stake to any foreign investor... we want the investor as a strategic investor who can provide the company with technical assistance and upgrade the industry, &quot; Bataynah said.</p>
<p>Jordan Cement Factories Company, one of the highest capitalised firms listed in the Amman Financial Market, with a present 3.7 percent foreign ownership, has long attracted emerging market fund buying interest.</p>
<p>The firm, with a monopoly to produce cement under a 50 year concession that ends in 2001, has posted strong earnings over the last few years. It has posted a net profit of 10 million dinars at end of 1995 on 104 million dinar of sales.</p>
<p>Jordan Cement Factories, with an expansion programme to add up to 400,000 tonnes by 1997 from a present 3.5 million tonne annual capacity, plans to meet growth in regional markets and capture a key share of the one million tonne annual Palestinian market.</p>
<p>The World Bank has helped JIC in setting the selection guidelines for the sale of the stake to a strategic partner in the cement industry, Bataynah added.</p>
<p>JIC has already approached 16 international cement firms and provided them with well-defined bidding terms to streamline the selection process among potential investors.</p>
<p>French La Farge firm, Swiss-based Holder Bank, Belgian CBR Climenteries and Japanese Mitsubishi Materials are amongst international cement producers from as far as Korea and Mexico who have been recently approached directly by JIC.</p>
<p>Bidders will have to submit separate technical and financial offers by mid-October, under a scoring system that will qualify financial offers once their technical terms are acceptable.</p>
<p>After evaluating both offers the selection process among the foreign investors was expected to be completed by mid-November.</p>
<p>Bataynah said the government was expected to step up soon sell-offs in majority state-owned concerns or selling of large stakes in key public shareholding firms listed on the AMF.</p>
<p>&quot;JIC expects the pace of privatisation to pick up by presenting potential investors with structured investment opportunities and a transparent bidding process,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Amman Newsroom +9626- 623776</p>
<p>$1 = 0.7080 dinar</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
