<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="445252" id="root" date="1997-03-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Convoy of Albanian refugee ships heads for Italy.</title>
<headline>Convoy of Albanian refugee ships heads for Italy.</headline>
<dateline>BRINDISI 1997-03-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A convoy of up to 30 merchant ships and fishing boats carrying Albanian refugees was snaking towards southeast Italy on Saturday in a sign that an exodus from anarchy in the Balkan state could be gathering pace.</p>
<p>Italian coastguards in Brindisi and Rome said 20 to 30 vessels were in the convoy, which was stretched out for about 15 miles across the Adriatic Sea and under escort.</p>
<p>&quot;The head of the convoy...is currently entering the port of Brindisi,&quot; a statement issued by coastguard headquarters in Rome said. &quot;On board, apart from the crews, are entire families of Albanian refugees.&quot;</p>
<p>A coastguard spokesman said it was not clear how many refugees were in the convoy, comprising at least three fishing boats and merchant ships which coastguard escort vessels had estimated were 50 to 100 metres long.</p>
<p>He said the flotilla was believed to have set out from the area of Durres, west of the capital Tirana. The ships were moving so slowly for safety reasons that it was expected to take several hours for all of them to reach Brindisi, he added.</p>
<p>Italy, a magnet for Albanian illegal immigrants, has sought to discourage refugees since protests sparked by the collapse of shady saving schemes erupted this month into armed insurrection in southern Albania. Unrest has now spread across the country.</p>
<p>At least 17 Albanian navy vessels, most of them small patrol boats built decades ago by the Chinese, limped into southern Italian ports under escort on Friday after crawling across the Adriatic with deserting servicemen and civilians.</p>
<p>The unfolding exodus has raised fears in Italy of a repeat of the tide of 40,000 Albanians who flocked to southeast ports on an armada of ships in 1991 after Stalinist rule crumbled in Europe's poorest state.</p>
<p>The U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) said on Friday that it had urged Italy and Albania's neighbour Greece to allow Albanians fleeing this month's turmoil to enter and stay &quot;as long as necessary&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRINDISI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
