<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="445292" id="root" date="1997-03-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Latin America must double its growth rate - IADB.</title>
<headline>Latin America must double its growth rate - IADB.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1997-03-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Latin America must double its economic growth rate to seven percent if it is to have any hope of suppressing the region's chronic poverty, Enrique Iglesias, president of the Inter-American Development Bank (IADB), said on Saturday.</p>
<p>He said in an interview with Spanish daily La Vanguardia that the region's growth could reach 4.5 to 5.0 percent in 1997, compared with 3.5 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>Iglesias, who was speaking ahead of Monday's opening of the IADB's 38th annual meeting in Barcelona, said this would not, however, be enough to benefit the people of Latin America where one in three lived in poverty.</p>
<p>&quot;In Monday's inaugural session we are going to say that this growth still is not sufficient and should be doubled to a figure of around seven percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But in some countries there were already encouraging signs, he said.</p>
<p>Recent statistics showed poverty was diminishing in countries such as Brazil where a stabilisation plan implemented in 1994 had pulled 13 million people out of the ranks of poverty.</p>
<p>&quot;It is therefore a problem that can be tackled with appropriate policies,&quot; Iglesias said.</p>
<p>Although current Latin American growth is still lower than that seen in the 1960s and 1970s, the rate is healthier and based on open economies, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We need two important things: savings must grow much more so that investment increases,&quot; he said. &quot;In addition exports still have not grown sufficiently.&quot;</p>
<p>Iglesias said governments must continue to apply and complete reforms initiated during the last decade.</p>
<p>On the region's growing unemployment, Iglesias said it was largely structural and could be resolved with higher economic growth levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The increase in unemployment has come hand in hand with a reduction in the influence of the state and with company restructuring that has involved the adoption of new technologies,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;As in Spain, it is structural and must be resolved with higher growth and expanding internal and external markets.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
