<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44523" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PLO searches for exploding Israeli spy devices.</title>
<headline>PLO searches for exploding Israeli spy devices.</headline>
<dateline>GAZA 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinians have found booby-trapped wiretapping devices in Gaza compounds that Israel handed over to the PLO in 1994, a senior Palestinian security source said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Searchers have been ploughing around the headquarters of the main Palestinian security forces in Gaza city since a policeman was killed and a telephone maintenance worker was wounded this month by one of the devices.</p>
<p>&quot;Orders have been issued to search all the facilities used by the Israeli occupation before they evacuated them,&quot; the source told Reuters. &quot;Search crews have been warned to be extra cautious because the devices are rigged to self-destruct.&quot;</p>
<p>The source said five devices were found two days ago and all exploded, although no one was hurt.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat accused Israel last week of spying on his self-rule administration.</p>
<p>Israeli security sources refused to make specific comments but one said it is natural for security forces to spy on each other.</p>
<p>Witnesses said police and telephone workers had destroyed the wall around the security forces building, which was the Israeli military headquarters before the Jewish state gave most of Gaza to the PLO in 1994 under a self-rule deal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GAZA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
