<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="445484" id="root" date="1997-03-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-SAMPDORIA STAY IN FRAME FOR CHAMPIONS' LEAGUE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SAMPDORIA STAY IN FRAME FOR CHAMPIONS' LEAGUE.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-03-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prolific young striker Vincenzo Montella scored twice as Sampdoria beat Reggiana 3-0 on Sunday to stay in the hunt for a place in next season's European Cup Champions' League.</p>
<p>Montella's fifth minute header and 68th minute penalty against the bottom club in serie A took his tally for the season to 16 goals in 17 matches and clinched Sampdoria's first league win since defeating Milan on February 2.</p>
<p>The Genoa club leap-frog over Inter into third place, four points behind Parma and the runners-up spot that guarantees qualification for the Champions' League.</p>
<p>Serie A leaders Juventus remain a cut above the rest - five points clear of Parma - following their 3-0 thrashing of Roma in a match played on Saturday in Turin.</p>
<p>Inter, beaten by Enrico Chiesa's goal at Parma in another match played on Saturday, drop to fourth, a point behind Sampdoria and level with Bologna, 2-1 winners at home to Italian Cup finalists Napoli.</p>
<p>Cagliari, fourth from bottom, fought back from a goal down to defeat Vicenza with a second-half goal from Sandro Tovalieri that kept alive their hopes of avoiding relegation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
