<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="445409" id="root" date="1997-03-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: RUGBY UNION-JOUBERT SCORES HAT-TRICK AS NATAL WIN 35-26.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-JOUBERT SCORES HAT-TRICK AS NATAL WIN 35-26.</headline>
<byline>Mark Stokes</byline>
<dateline>DURBAN 1997-03-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Natal centre Joos Joubert ran in a hat-trick of tries as last year's losing finalists beat Australian Capital Territory (ACT) 35-26 in their Super 12 match at Kings Park on Sunday.</p>
<p>But Natal, who led 23-0 at halftime, had to weather a strong performance from the ACT Brumbies in the opening and final quarters of the game to secure their second, successive win in the competition.</p>
<p>Both sides put in a series of bruising tackles in defence and also played expansively enough to score four tries apiece.</p>
<p>Despite being under considerable pressure from a committed ACT side for the opening half hour, Natal led 9-0 through three penalties from the reliable boot of full-back Gavin Lawless who went on to collect 18 points.</p>
<p>Then, largely against the run of play, Natal went further ahead with the first of Joubert's tries.</p>
<p>Sustained pressure after Natal's first genuine assault on the ACT line finally told when the powerful inside centre, cousin of injured Springbok full-back Andre Joubert, went over in the left-hand corner. Lawless converted.</p>
<p>Just two minutes later, left wing Cabous van der Westhuizen chipped ahead twice to launch a brilliant counter-attack from the kick-off and Joubert scored right under the posts.</p>
<p>Lawless then took Natal into the break with a solid 23-0 advantage after his fifth successful kick at goal.</p>
<p>ACT finally posted their first points on the board with a try in the 51st minute when lock John Langford fought his way over after the Brumbies engineered a powerful rolling maul from a line-out five metres out.</p>
<p>But, four minutes later, Joubert scored his third after an attempted George Gregan clearance rebounded off centre Jeremy Thomson for Joubert to win the race to the touchdown.</p>
<p>Although Wallaby left wing Joe Roff ran the length of the field to score after an interception, Natal flyhalf Henry Honiball laid on a fourth try for his team when he sliced through the ACT defence for replacement flanker Walter Minnaar to score.</p>
<p>ACT hooker Marco Caputo and fullback Stephen Larkham both scored tries in the last seven minutes of the match to secure the Brumbies a consolation point for scoring four tries.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Natal - Gavin Lawless; Dirkie Strydom, Jeremy Thomson, Joos Joubert, Cabous van der Westhuizen; Henry Honiball, Kevin Putt; Gary Teichmann (captain), Dieter Kriese, Wayne Fyvie (Walter Minnaar, 52nd), Mark Andrews, John Slade, Adrian Garvey, John Allan, Rob Kempson (Ollie le Roux, 52nd)</p>
<p>ACT - Stephen Larkham; Mitch Hardy, Adam Magro, Pat Howard (James Holbeck, 73rd), Joe Roff; Geoff Logan (David Knox, 42nd), George Gregan; Troy Coker, Brett Robinson, Ipolito Fenukitau, David Giffen, John Langford, Dean Zammt (Rod Moore 57th), Marco Caputo, Patricio Noriega.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DURBAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
