<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="445504" id="root" date="1997-03-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Grand Prix business may not race to flotation.</title>
<headline>Grand Prix business may not race to flotation.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The prospect of investors buying shares in Formula One motor racing receded on Sunday when the sport's top businessman told a British newspaper he had no wish to proceed at full throttle towards a flotation.</p>
<p>Bernie Ecclestone told the Sunday Times he would in any event want to retain a majority holding in the sport he at present controls. &quot;My feeling is to wait and see (about offering shares to other investors),&quot; Ecclestone said.</p>
<p>He said Salomon Brothers, the merchant bank he has hired to advise him, had told him his attitude was silly. &quot;They may have wanted to put pressure on me. One thing is for sure -- it certainly won't force me to do it,&quot; Ecclestone said.</p>
<p>The entrepreneur, president of the Formula One Constructors' Association and owner of the sport's promotion arm, has transformed Grand Prix racing into a spectacular attracting a 450 million global television audience for every event.</p>
<p>Now he stands to make some two billion pounds ($3 billion) through a flotation. But Ecclestone is already a multi-millionaire and one of the richest men in Britain, where he lives in a mansion block in Chelsea, London.</p>
<p>He said he may now delay a flotation until money starts to flow in from deals with pay television channels. These, he said, could &quot;bring in an enormous profit and give Formula One its full worth&quot;.</p>
<p>If the flotation goes ahead, it could capitalise on British investors' thirst for high-profile sports businesses.</p>
<p>Newcastle United is currently one of several top soccer clubs planning to join Manchester United and Tottenham Hotspur on the stock market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
