<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="445562" id="root" date="1997-03-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Governor offers to take over failed Polish yard.</title>
<headline>Governor offers to take over failed Polish yard.</headline>
<dateline>GDANSK, Poland 1997-03-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gdansk provincial governor Henryk Wojciechowski on Sunday offered to take over the assets of the bankrupt Gdansk Shipyard, birthplace of the Solidarity trade union, if the government assumed its debts.</p>
<p>&quot;I plan to submit an application to take over the shipyard's assets in exchange for the State Treasury taking over the enterprise's debts,&quot; he told Gdansk public radio.</p>
<p>&quot;This may now be the only chance to carry out the restructuring,&quot; Wojciechowski added.</p>
<p>The offer followed last week's street demonstration in which workers threw jars of red paint at the governor's office and blocked traffic in the Baltic port in protest against the shipyard's closure.</p>
<p>Wojciechowski accused the yard's receiver of responsibility for the protests but did no elaborate.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, the receiver announced he would dismiss the last 3,800 workers of the company which has been operating under bankruptcy laws since last August.</p>
<p>Workers have blamed the post-communist-dominated government for failing to save the shipyard -- cradle of the Solidarity trade union which brought about the collapse of communist rule in 1989.</p>
<p>The receiver had hoped to obtain a $100 million loan to keep the yard going but no bank agreed to extend it.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GDANSK, Poland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
