<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="445540" id="root" date="1997-03-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: War and illness weaken Mobutu's grip on Zaire.</title>
<headline>War and illness weaken Mobutu's grip on Zaire.</headline>
<byline>William Wallis</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1997-03-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Mobutu Sese Seko, one of Africa's longest-serving strongmen, has held power in Zaire for three decades but rebel advances and his poor health raise questions about how much longer he can do so.</p>
<p>Proclaiming himself the one symbol of national unity, he has maintained his grip on power with a blend of political acumen, military ruthlessness and the distribution amongst acolytes and opponents of his immense wealth.</p>
<p>But Zaire watchers and many Zaireans believe that a combination of ill health and a five-month offensive by rebels fighting to overthrow him have loosened the already token control his government holds over much of the country.</p>
<p>&quot;No-one, not even his doctor, knows when President Mobutu will die,&quot; one Western diplomat observed. &quot;The question for now is does he still have that Machiavellian capacity to influence events?.&quot;</p>
<p>For some, he does. &quot;The answer is yes,&quot; the diplomat said.</p>
<p>Others disagree. &quot;The Titanic is sinking and its captain is in a neck lock. It is a matter of time before the ship sinks. The question is whether Mobutu goes with his boots on or off,&quot; one Western analyst commented.</p>
<p>Mobutu, 66, has been absent from Zaire for all but a few weeks of the last eight months, recuperating from cancer surgery and radiation therapy in Europe. He is currently in France.</p>
<p>After seizing power in 1965, he was able to rely on Cold War allies to support him militarily in punishing the numerous rebellions of Zaire's turbulent post independence history.</p>
<p>But since October, when the east of the country was invaded by a combination of Zairean rebels and ethnic Tutsi forces from neighbouring countries, one-time friends such as the United States have shown little enthusiasm for coming to the rescue.</p>
<p>A motley coalition of Serb mercenaries, Rwandan Hutu militiamen and the remnants of Zaire's divided and demoralised national army is all that has stood in the way of the rebel advance -- and mostly not for very long.</p>
<p>Ironically, it may be the secret of Mobutu's past success that is his undoing.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything was done to ensure that the army is in the state it is in today. It is not a question of paying the soldiers. They simply have no morale or spirit to fight this battle,&quot; one despairing senior government official told Reuters.</p>
<p>One regional analyst says soldiers have had virtually no training since the West cut off military aide seven years ago.</p>
<p>Civilian and military authorities have failed to coordinate over the handling of the war, often with bitter recriminations.</p>
<p>&quot;No functional institutions have been created to link the civilian and military leadership. The military was always tied up with President Mobutu,&quot; the regional analyst said.</p>
<p>Zaire watchers say nurturing division -- whether among politicians or the military -- has been Mobutu's trump card.</p>
<p>He maintained rival military units to limit chances of a coup. Everyone, even his political rivals, dance to his tune.</p>
<p>Under a year ago, pundits predicted Mobutu, facing a divided political opposition, had a good chance of legitimising his rule by winning Zaire's first multiparty presidential elections.</p>
<p>Under the transitional constitution, set up after domestic and foreign pressure forced Mobutu to move towards multi-party politics, those elections should take place by July.</p>
<p>The revolt has changed that.</p>
<p>The rebel advance has created a ground-swell of support for rebel leader Laurent Kabila -- both in rebel-held areas and poor districts of the teeming capital Kinshasa.</p>
<p>&quot;His army is an army of liberation and he must free us of from the dictatorship of Mobutu,&quot; commented opposition militant Jose Wasunde, 34.</p>
<p>Others are more cautious. &quot;We do not want to leave one dictatorship only to start with another,&quot; student activist Albertos Mupa commented.</p>
<p>The fall on Saturday of Zaire's third city of Kisangani, the nerve centre of army operations, and the flight of soldiers there sent a shudder through some members of the ruling class.</p>
<p>Diplomats say that the way Mobutu handles the next phase could be critical for Zaire.</p>
<p>The rebels, who now hold one fifth of Zaire, accord Mobutu a role -- even if it is only to negotiate his own departure.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no alternative to negotiating with Mobutu,&quot; rebel information chief Raphael Ghenda said in the east.</p>
<p>Kabila hinted after the fall of Kisangani on Saturday that a face-to-face meeting with Mobutu might halt the rebel steamroller -- or as he put it &quot;constitute some kind of pause&quot;.</p>
<p>With the Kinshasa rumour mill speculating furiously about prospects for a coup, time may be running out even for that.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
