<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44560" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. defends Bosnian elections as &quot;key next step&quot;.</title>
<headline>U.S. defends Bosnian elections as &quot;key next step&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Worsnip</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The White House on Monday defended this week's elections in Bosnia, saying that delaying them, as Republican presidential nominee Bob Dole has urged, &quot;would be a mistake.&quot;</p>
<p>Last week in a speech in Dayton, Ohio, where the peace accords were hammered out, Dole called for a postponement, saying the elections would be a fraud that would &quot;make a mockery of our principles and commitment to democracy.&quot;</p>
<p>Voters in the two Bosnian entities created by the accord -- a Serb republic and a Moslem-Croat federation -- will elect joint institutions for Bosnia on Saturday, including a presidency, legislature, central bank and supreme court.</p>
<p>&quot;The elections are a key next step along the long, difficult path to a lasting peace in Bosnia,&quot; White House Press Secretary Mike McCurry said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The administration believes that postponing this week's elections in Bosnia would be a mistake,&quot; he said. &quot;Those who argue for postponement ignore what the people of Bosnia want -- and what Bosnia needs to help its hard won peace endure.&quot;</p>
<p>Critics claim the administration wants to go ahead with the vote because postponing it would signal a failure of the Dayton pact less than eight weeks before the Nov. 5 election for the White House.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said the elections were never meant to be a &quot;final examination&quot; for last year's U.S.-sponsored Dayton peace accord, which ended four years of fighting between Moslems, Serbs and Croats.</p>
<p>&quot;They were never designed to be the end of the process. In fact, in a very real sense, they're the beginning of the process,&quot; Burns told a news briefing.</p>
<p>&quot;To read some of the criticism of the elections over the weekend and last week, you would think that they were the final step,&quot; Burns said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's a fundamental truism that there needs to be a first election before there can be a second election,&quot; he added. &quot;The process of peace cannot go forward without these first elections.&quot;</p>
<p>His comments appeared clearly designed to head off criticism, almost certain to be heard after the elections, that they were a sham that had the effect only of consolidating the power of nationalist parties bent on partitioning Bosnia.</p>
<p>New York Times commentator Anthony Lewis said on Monday the vote would &quot;legitimize the nationalist fanatics who savaged the country, intensify ethnic cleansing and deprive the international community of crucial leverage to prevent further outrages.&quot;</p>
<p>The Washington Post has called for the elections to be postponed.</p>
<p>In a statement issued after the briefing, Burns rejected fears that the elections could lead to the breakup of Bosnia.</p>
<p>&quot;The elections were explicitly designed to protect the continuity of the state of Bosnia and Herzegovina,&quot; Burns said in the statement. &quot;The Bosnian Serb entity will not be allowed to secede. If its newly elected leadership attempts to do so, there will be consequences.&quot; He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>He said all candidates participating in the election had accepted rules obliging them to uphold the Dayton peace accord and the Bosnian Constitution.</p>
<p>Burns conceded, as U.S. officials have done before, that the elections would fall short of Western standards, &quot;given the fact that they do not occur in Charlottesville, Virginia, or ... Manchester, England, they occur in Bosnia, which has seen war and division and economic and social dislocation.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he was deliberately avoiding the phrase &quot;free and fair&quot; to describe them, although they could be &quot;effective and democratic.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
