<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="445641" id="root" date="1997-03-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Rating agencies - how much power do they wield?.</title>
<headline>Rating agencies - how much power do they wield?.</headline>
<byline>Colin Brinsden</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1997-03-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand is living through an uneasy waiting game familiar to many countries and corporations around the world -- a credit rating review.</p>
<p>In February, Thailand's long-term sovereign credit rating was put under review for a possible downgrade by one of the world's leading credit rating agencies, Moody's Investors Service, leaving the country's financial community on tenterhooks until the actual decision is announced.</p>
<p>If Moody's decides that the credit rating should be downgraded based on the country's economic fundamentals, the move would raise Thailand's borrowing costs and dent investor confidence in the already economically troubled nation.</p>
<p>But who are these rating agencies that wield such apparent power and can cost a country or a company millions of dollars in interest payments if they are downgraded? Who do they serve?</p>
<p>The leading two international agencies are Moody's and Standard &amp; Poor's Corporation. Both have been providing financial information for decades.</p>
<p>A borrower, be it a government or a company, has to pay for the privilege of being rated by the agencies. But the final analysis, as Moody's puts it, would serve one constituent -- the market that is lending to the borrower.</p>
<p>&quot;(The rating agencies) are much more a service than a disservice. When Australia was downgraded it did actually serve a purpose, because it reinforced the pressure on the government to make appropriate policy changes. Otherwise politicians, being politicians, would resist,&quot; said Stephen Roberts, chief economist at UBS Australia.</p>
<p>An investor in corporate debt would want to know his or her credit exposure. Investors are likely to question whether they will get back interest payments paid on their investments and the principal. Or will they be left with the equivalent of a worthless I.O.U. if the corporation runs into financial woes?</p>
<p>While the influence of credit agencies would seem weighty and a downgrading or review could raise hackles, rating changes rarely surprise the market as there was usually plenty of evidence that the changes were on the way.</p>
<p>&quot;They are essentially part of the landscape. I don't think anyone would seriously think of getting rid of them,&quot; said Bill Shields, chief economist at Macquarie Bank in Sydney.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of them have been aggressive in the commercial sense in building their own business...getting out competitive ratings, but you seem to see less of that in the last year or two,&quot; Shields added.</p>
<p>A good credit rating would open up a wider range of markets for a borrower and allow it to get the finest pricing for its funding costs based on its level of credit worthiness.</p>
<p>If that rating were downgraded, the borrower would still benefit when its financial record improved and its credit rating was subsequently upgraded.</p>
<p>Moody's decision last month to put Thailand's long-term A2 sovereign credit rating under review for a possible downgrade was prompted by concerns about a build-up of short-term foreign debt, the country's financial institutions' exposure to the shaky property sector and the rise in non-perfoming loans.</p>
<p>The move has caused much debate, particularly as rival agency S&amp;P has said it has no plans to downgrade the country.</p>
<p>Wong Yit Fan, chief regional economist of Standard Chartered Bank, said any downgrade of Thailand was not justified.</p>
<p>&quot;I've seen financial crises. I've seen banks in trouble and those problems are in Thailand. But they are not so severe as to derail the economy,&quot; he told Reuters earlier this month.</p>
<p>It is a complaint Moody's has heard before -- as early as 1909 when founder John Moody brought out a manual analysing U.S. railroads and rating their bond issues.</p>
<p>&quot;While it raised a storm of opposition, not to mention ridicule from some quarters, it took hold with dealers and investment houses...and long before 1914 it was a recognised authority,&quot; Moody later wrote of his first ratings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8395416">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
