<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44567" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mid Ocean sees continuing flight to quality.</title>
<headline>Mid Ocean sees continuing flight to quality.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mid Ocean Ltd chief executive Michael Butt said he believes the recent consolidation within the reinsurance industry reflects a &quot;flight to quality&quot; by customers seeking the safest firms to reinsure them.</p>
<p>Butt, commenting on the company's third quarter earnings in a statement, said operating results for the quarter were good and in line with expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets are increasingly competitive. However, the major consolidations taking place within the industry confirm our view that the flight to quality continues,&quot; he said. &quot;We believe this trend offers opportunities for Mid Ocean.&quot;  </p>
<p>Butt said Mid Ocean's third quarter benefited from a lack of significant catastrophe losses in the quarter. But, he said, the company experienced a negative comparison to the prior year's quarter in terms of realized investment gains and losses.</p>
<p>&quot;We continue to make progress in diversifying our book of business,&quot; he said. And, given its investment in Brockbank Group &quot;we are very pleased to see the Lloyd's reconstruction and renewal offer become unconditional.&quot;  </p>
<p>Mid Ocean is a majority shareholder in the Brockbank Group and provides corporate capital to Lloyd's syndicates managed by Brockbank's managing agency.</p>
<p>Mid Ocean reported third quarter operating earnings of $1.49 a share compared to $1.35 a year ago.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8200318">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
