<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="445633" id="root" date="1997-03-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Explorers Index falls 2.36 pct.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Explorers Index falls 2.36 pct.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1996-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Perth stockbroker Eyres Reed Ltd said its Australian Explorers Index fell 2.36 percent in the week to Friday. The All Ordinaries Index fell 0.62 percent.</p>
<p>Changes, in percent:</p>
<p>	    Mar 14  Mar 7    pct   1 Month  pct    1 Year  pct</p>
<p>Explorers 3683.6  3772.5 (-2.36) 3774.8 (-2.42)  3409.8 (+8.03) ASX Gold  1721.2  1748.6 (-1.56) 1791.4 (-3.92)  1830.3 (-5.96) All Ords  2423.2  2438.5 (-0.62) 2449.7 (-1.08)  2424.4 (-0.05) Oil &amp; Gas 1576.9  1587.7 (-0.68) 1538.9 (+2.47)  1556.2 (+1.33)</p>
<p>NOTE: The explorers index (base 500, March 1992) tracks the performance of 88 small capitalisation exploration companies.  </p>
<p>The Eyres Reed Explorer Index fell 88.9 points over the week and was particularly marked back on Friday as weakness in the broader market sapped confidence from the junior resources sector, Eyres Reed analyst Glen Colgan said in a commentary.</p>
<p>Capricorn Resources Australia NL was actively trade, up 5.5 cents to 37 cents, on further encouragement from their nickel exploration with Forrestania Gold NL. Esmeralda Exploration Ltd lifted 5.5 cents to 37.5 cents as the company moved closer to development of their Romanian tailings retreatment project.  </p>
<p>Cultus Petroluem continued its re-rating up 31 cents to A$2.77, while Kingsgate Resources Ltd was up 48 cents to A$3.28 following results from the Chatree gold project in Thailand.</p>
<p>Other improvers included Gondwana Resources NL, up 2.5 cents to 16 cents, Yardarino Mining, four cents higher at 25 cents, and Crest Resources.</p>
<p>Helix Resources Ltd continued its fall from grace. Results that were no less encouraging to those previously released from their Gawler Craton prospect, failed to meet market expectations and justify recent market capitalisation  </p>
<p>levels. Subsequently, the share price dropped 90 cents to A$3.00, taking with it many of the other junior players in the region.</p>
<p>Other falls included Noble Resources Nl, off eights cents to 30 cents, Redfire Resources, down four cents to 18 cents, Morgans Gold Mines, five cents lower at four cents, and Finders Gold Nl, off two cents at 10.5 cents.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
