<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="445825" id="root" date="1997-03-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: EU offers experts, not troops, to help Albania.</title>
<headline>EU offers experts, not troops, to help Albania.</headline>
<byline>Ian Geoghegan</byline>
<dateline>APELDOORN, Netherlands 1997-03-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union on Sunday shied away from sending troops into Albania, settling instead to offer expert military and police advisers to try and help restore order in the anarchic Balkan state.</p>
<p>EU foreign ministers meeting informally in this central Dutch country town said they would also consider providing protection for the mission if needed, but stressed it was not a military operation.</p>
<p>Ministers said in a communique they were &quot;strongly committed to helping Albania restore civilian structures and law and order&quot;, adding that outside help was needed immediately to calm tensions, particularly in and around Tirana.</p>
<p>&quot;I stress this is an advisory mission...to go to Tirana and discuss with the Albanian government civil reconstruction issues...and police and military matters,&quot; British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;It has not been concluded yet who might be in such a mission.&quot;</p>
<p>Stung by criticism of its indecision over the conflict in former Yugoslavia, several EU nations were keen to send in troops to try to prevent Albania from sinking deeper into chaos.</p>
<p>But, highlighting sharp EU divisions over what to do about the latest crisis on its Balkan doorstep, Britain, Germany and Sweden opposed sending a bigger multinational peacekeeping force in response to requests for military intervention.</p>
<p>Officials said ministers would seek United Nations blessing for the experts' mission, but this would not necessarily be a formal requirement.</p>
<p>As a first step, the EU will send a high-level mission to Tirana on Monday, led by Dutch diplomat Jan de Marchant et d'Ansembourg and including representatives from the Netherlands, Greece, Italy, the European Commission and the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE).</p>
<p>The EU also called on Albania itself to take steps towards its own reconstruction. &quot;There is a need for the Albanians to accept responsibility for rebuilding their country and society...to enable the EU to help them,&quot; the bloc said.</p>
<p>Ministers said they were ready to send humanitarian aid once it was safe enough to do so.</p>
<p>The EU statement made no mention of Albania's beleagured President Sali Berisha, whose ousting or resignation is seen by many as a first important step to defusing the crisis.</p>
<p>But Dutch Foreign Minister Hans van Mierlo told reporters that Berisha had pledged to quit if his party lost elections expected this summer.</p>
<p>&quot;This morning, he (Berisha) made a statement to the Dutch ambassador to the effect that if his party loses the upcoming elections, he would also stand down,&quot; van Mierlo said, adding he saw this as a &quot;very significant&quot; gesture.</p>
<p>Berisha is blamed by many in his country for the collapse of pyramid investment funds that bankrupted thousands and prompted widespread unrest.</p>
<p>Last week Berisha bowed to opposition demands for an all-party government and fresh elections.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="APELDOORN, Netherlands"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
