<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="445873" id="root" date="1997-03-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Hume is voters' choice for Irish president.</title>
<headline>Hume is voters' choice for Irish president.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Hill</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1997-03-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Northern Ireland peace broker John Hume would be the people's choice to succeed Irish President Mary Robinson when she steps down this year, despite his reluctance to take on the job, an opinion poll said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The poll showed that Hume, leader of the Social Democratic and Labour Party (SDLP) of Northern Ireland, was the choice of one in five voters, ahead of former Irish Prime Minister Albert Reynolds.</p>
<p>Hume said last week when Robinson announced that she would not be standing for re-election this year that he did not consider himself a candidate and would concentrate on his efforts to bring about a Northern Ireland peace deal.</p>
<p>Hume, a moderate Catholic Irish nationalist, is a member of the British and European parliaments and has been at the forefront of efforts to end a conflict which has killed 3,200 over 28 years.</p>
<p>He says he is currently trying to bring about a new ceasefire by Irish Republican Army guerrillas fighting British rule of Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>The poll, published in Irish Sunday newspapers, showed that another ex-premier, Charles Haughey, was the third most-favoured candidate for the President's job.</p>
<p>No-one has publicly announced that they want to run for the post, which is largely ceremonial but carries with it a high-profile task at home and abroad of flying the Irish flag.</p>
<p>Reynolds and Hume worked together to secure an IRA truce which was declared in August 1994 but broken in February last year when the guerrillas went back to war complaining that their Sinn Fein political wing was excluded from peace talks.</p>
<p>Reynolds' government collapsed in a scandal over legal appointments in 1994 and he stepped down as leader of the Fianna Fail party, which is now in opposition.</p>
<p>But Fianna Fail leader Bertie Ahern has pledged to give Reynolds' a role in shaping a Northern Ireland settlement if it comes to power in general elections due this year.</p>
<p>The opinion poll showed that the election was still wide open with Prime Minister John Bruton's Fine Gael party and Labour coalition partner both making up lost ground.</p>
<p>According to the poll, the lead of the Fianna Fail and Progressive Democrats opposition party over the ruling coalition has been cut to 10 points and popular satisfaction with the government has risen by nine points.</p>
<p>Fifty-one percent of those polled were satisfied with the performance of the coalition compared to 42 percent in Decemebr last year.</p>
<p>Commentators expect Bruton to call an early election to cash in on the biggest tax cuts in Irish history which were announced in a January budget. The election is due by November but commentators believe it will take place in May or June.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
