<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="445956" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>Australia: 171248 OEC - BC-TEXT-RAPID-JAPAN Commission launches ambitious trade promotion in Japan.</title>
<headline>171248 OEC - BC-TEXT-RAPID-JAPAN Commission launches ambitious trade promotion in Japan.</headline>
<text>
<p>EUROPEAN COMMISSION PRESS RELEASE: IP/97/225 DOCUMENT DATE: MARCH 17, 1997 * European Commission launches ambitious trade promotion in Japan * The European Commission is launching a major new campaign to promote European exports to Japan. The &quot;Gateway to Japan&quot; initiative will target ten sectors - including medical equipment, waste management, food drink, information technology, outdoor leisure equipment and construction material - where competitive European firms face serious obstacles in the Japanese market. The campaign is expected to help 1000 European companies market their products and services in Japan over the next four years through trade missions, trade fairs and other events. It will involve an unpredecented degree of cooperation between the EU and national trade promotion initiatives. Today's launch follows a three-year pilot phase in which the EU helped 515 companies - including British healthcare, Dutch medical equipment, French packaging and German waste management - to develop successful marketing strategies in Japan. Sir Leon Brittan will announce this to a large audience in Brussels at 18.30 today comprising delegates from the Member States, representatives of the Japan Mission to the European Union (including Ambassador Tokinoya), members of the European Parliament and representatives of various business and trade organisations. Commenting at the launch of the new campaign Sir Leon will state: &quot;The launch of the second EU Gateway to Japan campaign today builds upon the many successes of the first programme which ran from 1993 to 1996. It is an essential element of a coherent package of actions designed to enhance European presence on the Japanese market, and to take advantage of new market access opportunities arising there.&quot; &quot;There is ample evidence that a well targeted, well managed campaign can achieve very beneficial results, even in the short term. The Gateway 2 campaign should consolidate the progress already made in the existing priority sectors and open up new and existing business opportunities for companies in the four new sectors to be targeted under the new campaign.&quot; The Gateway to Japan campaign will run to the end of 2000. It targets support, both practical and financial, on ten key sectors where European companies, and in particular SMEs, are perceived to have the potential to exploit market opportunities in Japan. The campaign is designed to complement similar activities undertaken in Member States and to provide a readily recognised calling card for companies making their first tentative approaches to Japan. Some 40 key events (24 trade missions and 16 trade fairs) are planned over the four year period and are expected to make an important contribution towards reducing Europe's trade deficit with Japan. The preliminary results of the first Gateway campaign show that almost 90 % of all participants expressed satisfaction with the programme, and most of them wish to continue their involvement in Gateway 2. Over 300 companies participated in Gateway 1 sponsored events and recorded impressive sales as a direct result of their involvement (in 1996 alone average sales per company amounted to 700.000 ECU). In addition, almost 30% of participating companies have or are in the process of recruiting additional staff. The ten priority Gateway 2 sectors are: - Medical Equipment - Material Handling Equipment - Waste Management Technologies - Marine Equipment - Construction Materials - Packaging Machinery - Food - Drink - Information Technologies - Outdoor life products and equipment The first six sectors were promoted under Gateway 1 and continue under the new campaign. The last four are new sectors for the &quot;EU Gateway to Japan 2&quot; campaign Under the EU Gateway to Japan 1 campaign: - Two French packaging firms secured orders of almost 1 million ECU at an EU Gateway to Japan Trade Fair. One of these was the first non-Japanese manufacturer to win orders in its specialised market sector. - A new Dutch medical equipment company, with no existing business in Japan, secured orders in excess of ECU 500.000 as a result of EU Gateway to Japan. Japan now accounts for some 30% of its business and it expects more orders in the near future. Another Dutch company, in the building and construction sector, secured first orders worth ECU 250.000. - A Swedish marine equipment company won an initial supply order worth ECU 350.000 in the course of an EU Gateway to Japan trade mission with the real prospect of more orders to follow. - A UK healthcare firm won initial orders for ECU 130.000 and is continuing to increase its business with Japan. - Two Spanish firms in the building and construction materials sector secured initial orders totalling 300.000 ECU with further orders in the pipeline. - A German firm won orders in excess of 500.000 ECU as a result of participating in an EU Gateway to Japan trade fair. Its experience in Japan has been sufficiently positive for it to employ 3 extra personnel with plans to hire an extra three in the near future. - A German firm which participated in an EU Gateway to Japan Waste Management Technologies Trade Fair and mission secured initial orders worth over 1 million ECU. More orders are expected in the future. - A Belgian building and construction materials company secured orders worth 750.000 ECU at an EU Gateway to Japan trade mission. These are just a few examples of how small and medium sized European companies have succeeded through the EU Gateway to Japan 1 campaign. They provide examples of companies who, in the absence of the export promotion campaign, would have been unlikely to have considered Japan as a potential export market. END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
