<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446289" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-SAMPDORIA ROW WITH FEDERATION DEEPENS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SAMPDORIA ROW WITH FEDERATION DEEPENS.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sampdoria, twice referred to the Italian soccer federation's disciplinary committee for protesting against a four-match ban slapped on Yugoslav defender Sinisa Mihajlovic, completed a hat-trick on Monday.</p>
<p>The federation said it had referred the third-placed club as a whole after fans protested in Genoa on Sunday.</p>
<p>Some held up a large banner with the word &quot;Thieves&quot; on it while flyers distributed before the game against Reggiana urged Sampdoria players to tap the ball around between themselves for 30 seconds while the crowd stayed silent for a minute.</p>
<p>When the referee started the match, the Sampdoria players kept the ball to themselves in a silent stadium.</p>
<p>The club's Swedish coach Sven-Goran Eriksson commented later he thought 30 seconds might have been stretching things a bit &quot;because we're not that strong in defence&quot;.</p>
<p>But Reggiana coach Francesco Oddo was impressed after his team lost 3-0. &quot;Was it a protest?&quot; he said. &quot;I thought it was a tactic. They scored a goal after about a minute.&quot;</p>
<p>Sampdoria striker Roberto Mancini was referred to the committee last week for remarks the federation said could incite the fans to violent behaviour.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope the fans will be calm on Sunday at Marassi (stadium) but we have to be prepared for some reaction,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Before that general director Emiliano Salvarezza was referred for criticising the sporting judge who suspended Mihajlovic, a ban he called &quot;shameful and squalid&quot;.</p>
<p>Mihajlovic was suspended after he kicked the ball in the direction of a referee and insulted him after a penalty had been awarded to opponents Atalanta. Sampdoria lost the match 4-0.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
