<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446287" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: FIGURE SKATING-KWAN'S CROWN TARGETED BY 14-YEAR-OLD RIVAL.</title>
<headline>FIGURE SKATING-KWAN'S CROWN TARGETED BY 14-YEAR-OLD RIVAL.</headline>
<byline>Steve Keating</byline>
<dateline>LAUSANNE, Switzerland 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>American 16-year-old figure skater Michelle Kwan is facing the prospect of losing her world crown to a 14-year-old compatriot.</p>
<p>Tara Lipinski, from Sugar Land, Texas, is poised to triumph at the world championships here and become the youngest skater to lift the women's title.</p>
<p>Lipinski, who slipped in under the International Skating Union's new 15-year-old age restriction rule because she was already competing internationally, has taken advantage of the loophole.</p>
<p>She claimed Kwan's U.S. title last month and then followed up with another victory in the Champions Series final.</p>
<p>Before losing at the U.S. championships, Kwan had strung together nine consecutive wins and constructed an air of invincibility.</p>
<p>While that loss came as relief - she said she was tired of being a &quot;bull's eye&quot; - the defeat at the Champions Series was Kwan, who settled for second in both events, says that in the 12 months since winning the world crown she has had to make adjustments that have been more mental than physical.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know if it's so much the changing of my body, I'm trying to adjust as much as I can,&quot; said Kwan. &quot;I do know this whole year has been difficult.</p>
<p>&quot;I quess the biggest thing is trying to get my mental state back and get my head straight.&quot;</p>
<p>Although the 1.47 metres tall Lipinski had to stand on a chair to be seen during her post-qualifying skate interview, she sees her future much more clearly and according to her it doesn't include growing pains.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone goes through it, there's nothing you can do about it,&quot; said Nicole Bobek, 19, the third member of the U.S. world championship team.</p>
<p>&quot;You think what's wrong, I'm trying so hard.</p>
<p>&quot;You get taller, you're feet get bigger, you get hips and when your body changes it throws your timing off.</p>
<p>&quot;You just have to tell yourself you'll get through this, it's not going to last forever.&quot;</p>
<p>Canada's Elvis Stojko, who became the first skater to land a quadruple-triple jump two weeks ago, also had comforting words for Kwan.</p>
<p>&quot;I grew three inches and gained 20 pounds in one year, it changed my timing drastically,&quot; said Stojko. &quot;You have to have the strength and determination to pull through it.</p>
<p>&quot;I've chatted to Michelle about it and told her we've all gone through this.</p>
<p>&quot;She's growing but she's thinking a little bit more too about what's going on around her. The realization can be overwhelming.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAUSANNE, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
