<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446234" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER SHOWCASE-CELTIC AND RANGERS COULD BE FINED.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-CELTIC AND RANGERS COULD BE FINED.</headline>
<byline>Mike Collett</byline>
<dateline>GLASGOW 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rangers and Celtic could be fined by the Scottish Football Association after two players were sent off and eight booked in Sunday's ill-tempered derby followed by mayhem on the pitch after the final whistle.</p>
<p>Rangers won a scrappy match 1-0 with a goal from Dane Brian Laudrup just before halftime to move eight points clear of their arch-rivals at the top of the table and move closer to equalling Celtic's record of nine successive titles.</p>
<p>While much of the football served up will be quickly forgotten, the wild scenes at the end, the dismissals of Rangers' Mark Hateley and Celtic's Malky Mackay and eight other bookings will occupy the minds of the Scottish F.A. for a while yet.</p>
<p>The match, shown either live or in a highlights package to more than 40 countries around the world, was a poor advertisement for Scottish football and the trouble at the end could earn both clubs a hefty fine. Celtic's hot-tempered Italian striker Paolo Di Canio, whose histrionics earned him a booking during the match, had to be restrained afterwards as he tried to provoke Ranger Ian Ferguson into a fight.se in a blue shirt.</p>
<p>Di Canio was ordered to see referee Hugh Dallas after that, but his manager Tommy Burns said he had not received another yellow or red card.</p>
<p>The referee will also report Rangers to the Scottish F.A. for mimicking Celtic's pre-match huddle, with a victory huddle of their own afterwards.</p>
<p>Rangers' manager Walter Smith said been done for nothing more than a laugh.</p>
<p>&quot;There's not enough humour in football,&quot; he said afterwards.</p>
<p>As well as the players trading insults, huddling and looking to settle old scores after the final whistle, a number of fans also encroached on the pitch with one boy of about 10 looking to take on Rangers Sweden's defender Joachim Bjorklund which would have been something of a mis-match as he was less than half the defender's size.</p>
<p>The ill-temper on the pitch flared up mid-way through the second half when Hateley, on his return to Rangers after 18 months in London with Queens Park Rangers, was sent off for head-butting Celtic goalkeeper Stewart Kerr, also booked for his part in the incident.</p>
<p>Hateley, who was also sent off at Celtic in a Scottish Cup fifth round tie on the same weekend in 1991, is automatically suspended for Rangers match against Kilmarnock next week and his red card was the first given to a Rangers player in more than 100 games since goalkeeper Billy Thomson was dismissed during a 3-0 defeat by Celtic in May 1995.</p>
<p>Celtic's numerical superiority did not last long and Mackay was sent off after 80 minutes for a second bookable offence after hauling down goalscorer Laudrup. He misses Celtic's visit to Dunfermline next Saturday and was the sixth Celtic player sent off this season.</p>
<p>The match was the 11th Old Firm derby in the past 18 months and the second in the last 10 days following Celtic's 2-0 Cup win over Rangers at Celtic Park on March 6.</p>
<p>It gave Rangers, missing six first choice players, their fourth league win of the season over Celtic and moved them to within sight of the title again, but the tension, the hype and the pressure on the players to succeed made it a poor game as a spectacle and one that was ultimately decided by a mistake.</p>
<p>The only goal came when a Joerg Albertz flighted a long free-kick which dropped over Erico Annoni and Laudrup. Celtic defender Alan Stubbs moved in to head the ball back to his keeper, but his misdirected effort allowed Ian Durrant to nip in and lob the ball towards the unguarded net.</p>
<p>Mackay and Laudrup both went for the ball, with Laudrup forcing it home. He also scored the only goal when Rangers won 1-0 at Celtic in November.</p>
<p>The 7,000 or so Rangers fans were in an utter frenzy at the finish as the majority of the 50,000 slunk away into the cold, windy streets of Glasgow's East End.</p>
<p>One Rangers banner summed up what the afternoon had all been about: &quot;Champions 1997&quot; it read, and barring a total collapse in their last six matches, that is exactly what Rangers will become some time in the next month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GLASGOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
