<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446374" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: CEFTA 1996 AUTO SALES UP 39 PCT, VW OVERTAKES FIAT.</title>
<headline>CEFTA 1996 AUTO SALES UP 39 PCT, VW OVERTAKES FIAT.</headline>
<byline>Ryan Tutak</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Volkswagen AG overtook Fiat SPA to lead central Europe in new auto sales in 1996, according to a Reuters survey.</p>
<p>The region includes countries that comprise the Central European Free Trade Agreement (CEFTA) -- the Czech Republic, Hungary, Poland, Slovakia and Slovenia.</p>
<p>VW, second to Fiat in sales since CEFTA was created in 1993, rose to the top amid the region's largest market boom, which also helped South Korean conglomerate Daewoo Group emerge as the region's clear third power.</p>
<p>The survey, which Reuters updates monthly, defines autos as cars, minibuses, pickups, vans and other four-wheeled motor vehicles not over 5.0 tonnes in gross weight.</p>
<p>Overall, CEFTA sales rose 39.5 percent to 842,565 units in 1996 from 603,780 units in 1995. Sales totaled 547,428 in 1994 and 529,496 in 1993.</p>
<p>VW -- including Audi, SEAT, Skoda and VW brands -- virtually kept pace with the market, boosting sales 38.4 percent to 197,887 units in 1996 from 143,024 units in 1995.</p>
<p>In contrast, Fiat -- including Alfa Romeo, Fiat, Iveco, Lancia and several specialty brands -- lagged behind the market. It increased sales only 25.9 percent to 192,318 units in 1996 from 152,813 units in 1995.</p>
<p>Daewoo, the only other automaker to sell more than 100,000 units in CEFTA, upped sales 38.3 percent to 152,859 in 1996 from 110,497 units in 1995. The closest competitor was U.S. automaker General Motors Corp , which increased sales 64.9 percent to 67,085 units in 1996 from 40,688 units in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Regional market leadership has reflected the fact that Fiat owns the biggest car factory in the biggest market of Poland, while VW owns the second biggest car factory in the second biggest market of the Czech Republic,&quot; said Attila Havas, a researcher at the Budapest University of Economics.</p>
<p>&quot;VW outsold Fiat last year because VW's sales outside its home market outperformed Fiat's sales outside its home market,&quot; Havas added.</p>
<p>The German automotive group topped Fiat in sales in every country in the region except Poland, and analysts said VW was better prepared to exploit the strong demand for cars throughout CEFTA because it had established itself more widely than its Italian rival.</p>
<p>VW has been assembling light vehicles in Poland and Slovakia and plans to assemble cars in Hungary starting in 1998, while Fiat produces no cars in CEFTA outside Poland.</p>
<p>&quot;Competition between Fiat and VW still will be close this year, and the outcome will depend largely on the way their new models are received in the region,&quot; Havas said. &quot;Daewoo also will become increasingly important, though its objectives might be too ambitious.&quot;</p>
<p>Daewoo has announced plans to build more than 500,000 vehicles a year in central Europe by 2000 through acquisitions of state-owned automakers in the Czech Republic and Poland.</p>
<p>Most analysts doubt Daewoo can sell the entire output in the region, but the South Korean conglomerate said it plans to export significant volumes throughout former communist Europe, and some units already have been shipped to western Europe.</p>
<p>The strong growth in CEFTA sales last year has prompted mixed views among analysts and industry executives about the market's prospects this year.</p>
<p>Raz Razaq, GM Europe's vice president for sales and marketing, told Reuters that he expects new auto sales in CEFTA countries to cool to moderate levels in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;This year, Poland will grow only 10-to-15 percent, and the Czech Republic and Slovakia will grow five-to-seven-percent at best,&quot; Razaq said. &quot;These markets are maturing and stabilising. They cannot continue growing at last year's pace.&quot;</p>
<p>But others argue that the conditions for strong car sales in the region only recently have taken hold, enabling a growing number of cash-strapped consumers to buy cars.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the boom will continue,&quot; said Nick Sljivic, director of VP International, a British consultancy specialising in the auto industry in central Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;Banks and leasing institutions are offering more and more credit finance, and dealers are pushing marketing and sales efforts that are becoming more and more sophisticated,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;Everyone is giving money away in Poland especially, and it's fueling car sales.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
