<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446404" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Major kicks off British election campaign.</title>
<headline>Major kicks off British election campaign.</headline>
<byline>Alan Wheatley</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister John Major on Monday launched Britain's longest election campaign in 80 years when he ended months of uncertainty by confirming that polling day will be May 1.</p>
<p>Major, behind in the polls but in fighting form, said he relished the chance to convince voters why his Conservative Party deserved an unprecedented fifth straight term in office.</p>
<p>&quot;Elections, some people say, are tough and gruelling businesses but I think they're also a lot of fun, and I'm looking forward to going up and down the country taking the message that I believe is right for this country to everyone,&quot; Major said on the steps of his Downing Street residence.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe this election is winnable. Not only do I think it's winnable, I think I'm going to win this election... We have an 18-year record record that I am proud of,&quot; Major said.</p>
<p>Tony Blair, leader of the main opposition Labour party, spoke for most politicians when he said he was glad that the phoney war was over and campaigning could start for real.</p>
<p>&quot;We are on the verge of a new millennium...and there is so much that Britain could do. There is so much talent, resources and energy among its people and I want a new government to come in with different values, different priorities and really lead that national renewal,&quot; Blair said.</p>
<p>&quot;That is at the heart of everything we want to achieve.&quot;</p>
<p>Major later went campaigning in Luton, a town north of London with two marginal Conservative seats, and mounted the same soap box he used to great effect in the 1992 election.</p>
<p>&quot;The people will decide over the next few weeks whether they want to continue with some of the best economic news that we have had for generations or whether it will be a return to the politics of socialism that brought this country to its knees in the seventies,&quot; Major, heckled by noisy protesters, said.</p>
<p>Opinion polls suggest Britons are clamouring for a change after 18 years of unbroken Conservative rule that have galvanised the economy but, in the eyes of the ruling party's critics, also increased inequalities and bred insecurity.</p>
<p>Several recent surveys have shown the Conservatives trailing Labour by about 25 percentage points -- enough to return Blair by a landslide if replicated at the election.</p>
<p>No party in power has ever clawed back such a big poll deficit so close to a general election. Two months before the the 1992 election, the two main parties were level pegging.</p>
<p>Labour, which under Blair has ditched its socialist baggage and anchored itself in the political mainstream, needs a 4.3 percent swing to win power for the first time since 1979.</p>
<p>Major acknowledged that the changes in British life under the Conservatives had left some people bruised. But he said his party still had a job to finish.</p>
<p>&quot;We have extended opportunities and choice to many people who didn't have them before. But there are many people who still in that context are have-nots' that I'd like to turn into haves', and that is why we've set out such long-term plans on health, education welfare and other matters.</p>
<p>&quot;So if people are looking for change -- we are the change, and we'll carry forward what we've been doing for the last 18 years,&quot; the prime minister told reporters.</p>
<p>He was speaking after returning from Buckingham Palace, where he asked head of state Queen Elizabeth for formal permission to dissolve parliament and hold the election.</p>
<p>Still, the required swing would be larger than any Labour has achieved since 1945 and Blair vowed on Monday to be &quot;the eternal warrior against complacency&quot;.</p>
<p>Major immediately won support from his predecessor, Margaret Thatcher, who has often sniped from the sidelines. &quot;Stay with us and with John Major until we cross the finishing line,&quot; Thatcher told reporters outside her London office.</p>
<p>The announcement of the election fired the starting gun on what will be a 44-day campaign, the longest in 80 years, although parliament will not be dissolved until April 8.</p>
<p>Conservative strategists are sure that Labour, which has carefully tailored its message to appeal to the middle classes, will crack under the scrutiny of a long campaign.</p>
<p>But Blair is equally confident and said the contrast with the ruling party could not be clearer. &quot;It will be between a Conservative party that is an utterly disorganised shambles, that has provided very incompetent government, but has been weakly led, and a Labour party that is genuinely New Labour,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
