<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446477" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BERMUDA: NZ SPORT - Vettori named in one-day side.</title>
<headline>NZ SPORT - Vettori named in one-day side.</headline>
<text>
<p>HAMILTON, March 18 - New Zealand's new spin bowling discovery Daniel Vettori is to be blooded in the one-day arena for the first time during the three-match series against Sri Lanka which starts in Auckland on Saturday, NZPA reports.</p>
<p>Vettori, 18, was introduced to the test squad against England last month and yesterday took five for 84 to help New Zealand win the second test here against Sri Lanka, the one-day World Cup champions.  </p>
<p>He was not exposed to the Englishmen during the five-match limited overs series involving those tourists, but was today included in a 13-man squad for the forthcoming Sri Lankan series.</p>
<p>Opening batsman Blair Pocock has been omitted from the test side, which won the series 2-0 against Sri Lanka, while Canterbury allrounder Chris Harris and Wellington medium pacer Gavin Larsen return to the limited overs squad after last appearing against England.  </p>
<p>Not considered for selection was Canterbury fast bowler Geoff Allott, who has been ruled out for the rest of the domestic season because of a back injury which sidelined him shortly before the first test against Sri Lanka in Dunedin last week.</p>
<p>Allott and captain Lee Germon, who played in the last one-day match against England before being discarded, are the only absentees from the side which beat England in the last match in Wellington to square that series.  </p>
<p>Vettori will be joined by two other newcomers to the international limited overs arena in Otago batsman Matt Horne and Central Districts swing bowler Andrew Penn.</p>
<p>Horne, who made his test debut against England, missed the following one-day games because of a broken bone in his hand.</p>
<p>Penn was introduced to the national squad for the second test here where he acted as 12th man.</p>
<p>The squad has been named for the first two matches in the series.  </p>
<p>National selection panel convener Ross Dykes said this morning that Vettori, whose four tests have rewarded him with 18 wickets, had shown a growing maturity in his cricket.</p>
<p>&quot;Against England we made a decision to protect the attacking nature of his bowling by not exposing him to the one-day game, which would require him to bowl a flatter, more defensive trajectory,&quot; Dykes said.</p>
<p>&quot;Since that time he has played a significant role in the tests and shown a growing maturity in his cricket.  </p>
<p>&quot;learly he will play a major role in all forms of the game in the future and we (the selectors) believe the current successful environment is the ideal opportunity for him to experience the atmosphere of one-day internationals.&quot;</p>
<p>Dykes said that fast bowler Heath Davis, who experienced knee and achilles tendon problems during the test series against Sri Lanka, was expected to be fit for the first one-day match in Auckland.  </p>
<p>New Zealand squad: Stephen Fleming (captain), Nathan Astle, Chris Cairns, Heath Davis, Simon Doull, Chris Harris, Matt Horne, Gavin Larsen, Adam Parore, Dipak Patel, Andrew Penn, Bryan Young and Daniel Vettori.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BERMUDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
