<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446465" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Mackay to retire as Lord Chancellor.</title>
<headline>UK's Mackay to retire as Lord Chancellor.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lord James Mackay of Clashfern will step down as Lord Chancellor on age grounds after Britain's coming election, the government said on Monday.  </p>
<p>Mackay is the second member of the cabinet, after Northern Ireland Secretary Sir Patrick Mayhew, to announce his retirement at the election, which will be held on May 1.</p>
<p>Mackay, the head of the judiciary, said he was approaching the age of 70 -- the retirement age for judges set down in an act of parliament that he himself promoted.</p>
<p>&quot;I will myself reach that age in July, and I think it right that I should abide by that rule,&quot; he said in a letter to Prime Minister John Major.</p>
<p>Major thanked Mackay for his wise advice and record of great distinction.</p>
<p>&quot;You have served with enormous skill, patience and dignity as Lord Chancellor for almost 10 years -- the longest continuous service of a Lord Chancellor this century.</p>
<p>&quot;You have succeeded in combining leadership of the legal profession with a number of important reforms, which are significantly improving the administration of justice,&quot; Major said in a letter to Mackay released by his office.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom 44-171-542 7767</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
