<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446597" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FEATURE-White liberals face hostility in new South Africa.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-White liberals face hostility in new South Africa.</headline>
<byline>Richard Meares</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Helen Suzman, for years a lone voice against apartheid in South Africa's whites-only parliament, got used to hate mail from her fellow whites.</p>
<p>Now the verbal attacks are coming from within the new black establishment and the doyenne of liberalism is ruffled.</p>
<p>&quot;I am surprised at the hostility to liberals these days, even from moderates in the African National Congress,&quot; the veteran anti-apartheid campaigner told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;I expected it from the right and the far left, who have always called us 'Lenin's useful idiots', but I didn't expect it from them. It seems it is politically incorrect to be liberal.&quot;</p>
<p>Some of South Africa's new black elite are caustic in their contempt for those whites who battled the apartheid regime.</p>
<p>Suzman, who for a third of her 36 years was the only member from the liberal Progressive Party in a parliament of apartheid supporters dominated by the ruling National Party, said she frequently came across such antipathy, but named no names.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people think liberals are armchair critics striving to maintain the status quo of our own comfort and to stop radical change,&quot; said the 79-year-old, who retired from politics in 1989.</p>
<p>&quot;To me, liberalism means a set of values like individual human rights and respect of the rule of law, and non-discrimination on the basis or race, colour, religion etc.&quot;</p>
<p>In the West, conservatives often use 'liberal' disparagingly to mean someone too permissive or morally decadent.</p>
<p>In South Africa, it is also a term of contempt used by some blacks of whites whose motives they suspect or whose values they see as alien to African culture.</p>
<p>&quot;Liberalism is rooted in individualism and that is part of the problem in our society, and it is rooted in possessiveness,&quot; said Professor Ithumeleng Mosala, of the black consciousness group, the Azanian People's Organisation.</p>
<p>&quot;Instead of having a proper revolution in this country, we've had a liberal revolution and that is why blacks are still where they are today, in the gutter, and why whites are still rich.&quot;</p>
<p>He said white liberals were people &quot;who love blacks more than blacks love themselves, but who choose their blacks&quot;.</p>
<p>Liberal and leftist whites who denounced apartheid have also found themselves accused of racism by prominent blacks.</p>
<p>Last year Barney Pityana, the black head of the Human Rights Commission on which Suzman serves, accused anti-apartheid activist Dennis Davis, now an adviser to President Nelson Mandela's ANC, of racism for his criticism of the commission.</p>
<p>&quot;There is not much of a role left for white left-wing intellectuals in this country,&quot; said Davis, adding that the aim of labelling people like him racist was &quot;to get white intellectuals to shut up&quot; -- and it was working.</p>
<p>Suzman sees racial legacy, not racism itself, as a factor in the animosity from blacks who fear that committed whites want to hog credit for ending apartheid and ushering in black majority rule in 1994 under an ANC that has beat a moderate path.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't claim the kudos for the transformation but we did play a part,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;Liberals are a sort of endangered species, but as far as I am concerned we have won -- look at the constitution, the bill of rights, they are everything we stood for -- so let them rant. I am surprised, but I am not worried.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
