<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446594" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Norwich details sale of NBS shares.</title>
<headline>Norwich details sale of NBS shares.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Samgro Investment Holdings Ltd had obtained the right to place up to 19.995 million NBS Holdings Ltd shares held by Norwich at any time up to October 26 at prices between 6,262 and 6714 cents per share.</p>
<p>At the same time, Norwich Holdings S.A. Ltd had obtained the right to require Samgro to place up to a maximum of 15.495 million NBS shares on October 27 at 6,714 per share, Norwich said in a statement on Monday.</p>
<p>The announcement follows the placement by NBS of its interest in Norwich Holdings for 625 million rand last month.</p>
<p>Norwich said that while it had enjoyed a mutually beneficial alliance with NBS Holdings since the two companies obtained a cross holding at the time of the former's listing, certain of the expected synergies hoped for at the time had not materialised.</p>
<p>Norwich would use the proceeds of the disposal for the development and acquisition of new business opportunities, both locally and internationally.</p>
<p>The financial effects of the disposal would be published following the exercising of either the Samgro placement right or the Samgro placement obligation, whichever was sooner.</p>
<p>NBS Holdings, Boland Bank Holdings and the Board of Executors recently joined forces to create South Africa's fifth largest banking group.</p>
<p>Samgro Investments is the other major shareholder in NBS Boland, the pyramid company of Boland Bank.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
