<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446627" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania's Berisha faces new pressure to quit.</title>
<headline>Albania's Berisha faces new pressure to quit.</headline>
<byline>Giles Elgood</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanian opposition politician Fatos Nano on Monday joined calls for President Sali Berisha to quit following weeks of armed unrest in the Balkan country.</p>
<p>As the government sought to bring an end to the rule of the gun, a European Union delegation was due in Albania on Monday to help to end the disorder that erupted after thousands lost their savings in collapsed investment schemes.</p>
<p>U.S. marines had to beat off would-be refugees trying to push onto helicopters meant to evacuate foreigners from the port of Durres at the weekend, while thousands of Albanians desperate to flee have clashed with police.</p>
<p>Berisha, who confirmed that he would resign if his party lost elections in June, said he would ask the EU delegation to send police and economic aid to help rebuild Albania's institutions and to stabilise the economy.</p>
<p>Asked whether he would request foreign troops or police, he said in an interview with France's Europe 1 radio &quot;rather police to start with, because they will work with our police.&quot;</p>
<p>Berisha, who on Sunday announced a pardon for Nano, the leader of the opposition Socialist Party freed from prison last week, said that &quot;the situation remains critical&quot; despite a fragile calm in recent days.</p>
<p>Nano, jailed in 1993 on corruption charges which the opposition said were politically inspired, was among 51 prisoners with less than two years to serve who were pardoned by presidential decree.</p>
<p>Nano, who was briefly prime minister in 1991, has been mentioned as a possible successor to Berisha.</p>
<p>In an interview with the British Broadcasting Corporation, Nano threw his support behind the newly formed national unity government of Prime Minister Bashkim Fino as the best way of returning Albania to normality.</p>
<p>Asked about Berisha, Nano said: &quot;I would prefer personally to shake hands with him as an Albanian but not as a president.&quot;</p>
<p>Nano added: &quot;He should answer the demands of the people to step aside.&quot;</p>
<p>The EU delegation is expected to raise civil reconstruction issues and police and military matters with the new broad-based government.</p>
<p>EU foreign ministers approving the mission headed by Dutch diplomat Jan de Marchant et d'Ansembourg ruled out Albania's request for military intervention but said they were committed &quot;to helping Albania restore civilian structures and law and order.&quot;</p>
<p>The capital Tirana was generally peaceful on Monday four days after armed looters raided food depots and pilfered building sites while police all but abandoned their posts. Many shops were trading, most bread supplies were restored and bursts of gunfire were rare.</p>
<p>Tirana residents largely confined to their homes for two days last week welcomed armed high-profile security patrols aboard armoured vehicles and vans.</p>
<p>Fino issued a directive ordering government offices to resume work on Monday. But a 7 p.m. to 7 a.m. curfew remained in force and helicopters evacuating foreigners buzzed overhead throughout the weekend.</p>
<p>On a beach south of the Adriatic port of Durres, U.S. marines struck desperate Albanians with rifle butts to keep them away from helicopters ferrying Americans, Turks and Italians to Italy after weeks of turmoil.</p>
<p>Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi told reporters in the port of Brindisi that Europe would help Albania to rebuild and he urged would-be migrants to stay home.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
