<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446653" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Bosnian Croat leader condemns mosque attack.</title>
<headline>Bosnian Croat leader condemns mosque attack.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Croat president of Bosnia's shaky Moslem-Croat federation on Monday condemned a bomb attack on a mosque, calling it an attempt to poison inter-communal relations.</p>
<p>Local media said a mosque near the town of Tomislavgrad in Croat-held western Bosnia was badly damaged in a bomb explosion on Saturday night. It was the only remaining Islamic house of worship in a region dominated by Croat nationalists.</p>
<p>The incident was the latest in a tit-for-tat series of attacks on religious buildings in the federation, touched off in part by a February 10 Croat police assault on Moslem pilgrims in Mostar in which one person was shot dead.</p>
<p>&quot;The planting of an explosive device in a mosque in Stipanici, in Tomislavgrad municipality, was an act of violence that we strongly condemn,&quot; federation president Kresimir Zubak said in a statement carried by Croat media.</p>
<p>&quot;This was an insult to every honest person, to all religious communities and nations, and as such is contrary to the principles of Croat policy in Bosnia-Herzegovina and the Federation of Bosnia-Herzegovina,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The federation comprises one half of postwar Bosnia and a Serb republic entity the other.</p>
<p>&quot;Undoubtedly it was also an attempt to undermine all efforts being made to normalise relations between Croats and Bosniak Moslems and to hamper the implementation of peace and peaceful co-existence in the region.&quot;</p>
<p>Zubak called on police to investigate the bombing thoroughly and bring the perpetrators to justice.</p>
<p>The office of Bosnia's international peace coordinator, Carl Bildt, and the Sarajevo office of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe also condemned the bombing.</p>
<p>&quot;It is extremely unhelpful. We do not want to see any sort of tit-for-tat attacks on religious buildings,&quot; OSCE-Bosnia spokesman David Foley told a news conference.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
