<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446642" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Customs officers' go-slow clogs Poland's borders.</title>
<headline>Customs officers' go-slow clogs Poland's borders.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A nationwide pay protest by customs employees has caused chaos and congestion along Poland's borders including a queue of 30 kms (20 miles) at one crossing with Germany, a trade union leader said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Things are hotting up and we've had signals that some border crossings may become paralysed,&quot; Andrzej Gajda, the president of the customs employees' trade union said.</p>
<p>He said employees at most of Poland's customs offices, including an internal post at Krakow in the south of the country, were joining the action.</p>
<p>Public television showed a seemingly endless row of heavy lorries queuing at Swiecko on the border with Germany and confirmed Gajda's report that traffic was backed up for 30 km.</p>
<p>The customs officers, who held a four-hour warning go-slow on Sunday, began subjecting travellers, documents and goods to extremely slow and meticulous scrutiny at midnight, all but bringing traffic to a halt.</p>
<p>They have decided to check every other vehicle or consignment of goods rather than the usual one in 10.</p>
<p>The employees want bonuses equalling 100 percent of their basic pay to be paid direct from the state budget to ensure that it is always guaranteed.</p>
<p>The Customs Office has proposed paying the amount from a special fund, its spokeswoman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Talks between the office and the protesting trade unions, which represent about 40 percent of Poland's customs staff, broke off inconclusively on Saturday and so far no new meeting has been scheduled, she added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
