<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446719" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Defence minister says Russian nukes are reliable.</title>
<headline>Defence minister says Russian nukes are reliable.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Defence Minister Igor Rodionov assured President Boris Yeltsin on Monday that the command and control system governing Russia's nuclear missiles was reliable, the presidential press service said.</p>
<p>Rodionov's comments at a one-hour meeting in the Kremlin appeared to reverse earlier remarks in which he expressed concern that underfunding of the armed forces raised doubts about the reliabilty of Russia's nuclear weapons.  </p>
<p>&quot;As the defence minister underlined in his report, the system controlling the country's strategic nuclear forces answers all demands, is reliable and stable, which excludes the possibility of unusual situations,&quot; a presidential press service statement said.</p>
<p>The statement followed a weekend newspaper article suggesting Russia could accidentally launch a nuclear missile attack because its systems were unreliable.</p>
<p>The written statement said Yeltsin and Rodionov also discussed plans for Russia's nuclear arms, including prospects for negotiating a START-3 treaty to follow the unratified START-2 treaty with the United States cutting strategic nuclear missiles.</p>
<p>Yeltsin is due to discuss arms control with President Bill Clinton as a summit in Helsinki later this week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
