<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446867" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: More than 20 killed in combat across Colombia.</title>
<headline>More than 20 killed in combat across Colombia.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than 20 soldiers and guerrillas were killed in a weekend of battles pitting Colombia's leftist rebels against government troops, authorities said on Monday.</p>
<p>National Police and army high command reports said the worst attack came on Sunday in northeastern Arauca province where a rebel bomb, made from 110 pounds (50 kg) of dynamite, killed four policemen and left seven people seriously injured.</p>
<p>The military blamed National Liberation Army (ELN) rebels for the bomb, which exploded inside a pickup truck. ELN landmines also killed two policemen in Norte de Santander province on Saturday.</p>
<p>Three other policemen and at least one soldier were killed in other fighting and authorities said at least 11 were killed between Sunday night and Monday morning.</p>
<p>The ELN continued its dynamite attacks on Monday morning, blowing up a gas and oil pipeline in the northern oil production centre of Barrancabermeja. A police station in the oil town also fell under attack, army officials said.</p>
<p>The ELN, Colombia's second-largest guerrilla group, was founded by radical Roman Catholic priests in the mid-1960s and specialises in kidnappings and a nationwide campaign of economic sabotage.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
