<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446933" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia defense minister resigns amid controversy.</title>
<headline>Colombia defense minister resigns amid controversy.</headline>
<byline>Tom Brown</byline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-03-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian Defence Minister Guillermo Alberto Gonzalez resigned on Sunday, bowing to military pressure to step down after revealing that his congressional campaign accepted money from a reputed drug kingpin in 1989.</p>
<p>President Ernesto Samper had pledged his full support for Gonzalez on Friday, soon after the defence minister issued a statement revealing the campaign contribution from billionaire Justo Pastor Perafan, a fugitive from justice since February 1996.</p>
<p>But a government official said Samper and Gonzalez had jointly decided, in day-long talks on Sunday, that there was no alternative to his immediate resignation.</p>
<p>&quot;After a severe analysis, I consider your separation from the defence ministry the most expedient decision under the current circumstances,&quot; Samper said in his letter accepting Gonzalez's resignation. The move, he added, would help &quot;preserve Colombia's international credibility in the fight against drugs.&quot;</p>
<p>The government official consulted by Reuters said he was unable to confirm or deny reports that the military had pressed for Gonzalez's removal. But a senior military source told Reuters that armed forces commander Gen. Harold Bedoya issued a virtual ultimatum to Samper on Friday afternoon by telling him that he and other top military officials would step down if Gonzalez sought to cling to office.</p>
<p>Gonzalez, who quietly criticised the military's poor human rights record since he took office less than two months ago, had clearly angered senior army officials by publicly supporting calls for deep-rooted reform of military justice.</p>
<p>Army leaders refrained from clashing with Gonzalez over the human rights issue in public. But Bedoya and others also pointedly refused to voice their support for him on Friday, after his statement acknowledging that his campaign accepted a $3,000 donation from Perafan in 1989.</p>
<p>Gonzalez and Perafan, both in their 50s, grew up in the same town in southwest Colombia and his ties with the alleged drug lord were the focus of hard-hitting reports in the local media even before he was appointed in January to succeed Juan Carlos Esquerra, who Samper had just named as ambassador to Washington.</p>
<p>Gonzalez admitted having social dealings with Perafan in the past. But he also insisted that there was no reason to suspect him of criminal wrongdoing until last February, when a warrant was issued for his arrest on the drug-related charge of &quot;illicit enrichment.&quot;</p>
<p>Perafan's net worth is estimated by Semana, Colombia's leading news magazine, at $12 billion and he is said to have business interests in Madrid, Rome and Moscow as well as throughout Colombia. Police are currently offering a $500,000 reward for information leading to his arrest.</p>
<p>It may never be known if Gonzalez was forced out of office because of his stance on human rights, or because of his newly discovered &quot;clay feet&quot; and what congressional leader Julio Cesar Guerra Tulena described as &quot;a witch hunt&quot; when it comes to drug corruption in government.</p>
<p>Samper himself has been severely weakened by charges that he knowingly accepted millions of dollars in cocaine cash to finance his campaign for the presidency.</p>
<p>Gen. Bedoya has been left as acting defence minister and the government official, who asked not to be identified, said Samper had not yet identified any replacement for Gonzalez.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
