<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446967" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Panic hits Jakarta as high-rises sway in quake.</title>
<headline>Panic hits Jakarta as high-rises sway in quake.</headline>
<byline>Jim Della-Giacoma</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A strong earthquake rocked the Indonesian capital Jakarta on Monday afternoon, sending people scurrying out of high-rise buildings.</p>
<p>There were no immediate reports of damage or casualties.</p>
<p>Officials at the meteorological department said the earthquake was centred below the sea-bed in the Indian Ocean, some 300 km (200 miles) southwest of the teeming metropolis, home to about 10 million people.</p>
<p>It measured 6.0 on the Richter scale.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the biggest earthquake to have hit Jakarta in recent times,&quot; Taufik Rivai, head of the geophysics section in the meteorological department, told the official Antara news agency.</p>
<p>&quot;It was just lucky, the epicentre was in the Indian Ocean, and we only felt the tremors. If the quake happened on land, it would have been enough to destroy buildings,&quot; Rivai said.</p>
<p>Police in the coastal towns of West Java province facing out towards the epicentre said they had felt the earthquake but reported no damage or tidal waves.</p>
<p>&quot;The cars moved in the street, but there was no damage,&quot; a policeman on duty in the coastal town of Labuhan told Reuters by telephone. &quot;There was no tidal wave,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Antara said the earthquake was felt throughout West Java as well as in Lampung province on Sumatra and in Palembang, the capital of South Sumatra province.</p>
<p>Tall buildings in Jakarta shook when the tremor hit the city at about 3:10 p.m. (0810 GMT) and people rushed out onto the street. Building managers used public address systems urging people not to panic.</p>
<p>Traders fled the stock exchange, brokers said, but returned after about half an hour. The exchange was not officially closed despite the panic.</p>
<p>&quot;There were lots of traffic jams in the business district because all the people in those tall office buildings came out on the street,&quot; said one witness.</p>
<p>&quot;Things were really swaying out here,&quot; said a guest staying in an upper floor of the Mandarin Oriental Hotel. He said people rushed out of the building but there was no damage.</p>
<p>Other witnesses said many workers left their offices early as rumours spread of possible aftershocks.</p>
<p>However, Rivai said while aftershocks would continue, they would be of a magnitude which would not be felt by people.</p>
<p>The Indonesian archipelago, located on the edge of the geologically unstable zone known as the &quot;ring of fire&quot;, is earthquake prone.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
