<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44697" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FULL TEXT - ITT Q3 earnings forecast.</title>
<headline>FULL TEXT - ITT Q3 earnings forecast.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following is the full text of the statement ITT Corp issued on its third quarter earnings Monday. ITT shares did not immediately trade on the New York Stock Exchange Tuesday morning and were quoted with a bid of 47. The shares had traded at 49 in the third market early Tuesday, off seven from the Monday close of 56.</p>
<p>---PRESS RELEASE---------------------------------</p>
<p>NEW YORK, Sept. 9 /PRNewswire/ -- ITT Corporation (NYSE: ITT) said today that it expects its third quarter earnings to be significantly impacted by negative results in the company's gaming segment.</p>
<p>In August 1996, revenues from the Company's premium play business were significantly below August 1995, almost exclusively in Las Vegas.  Caesars Palace had a negative hold percentage in baccarat for the month.  Construction delays in the North Casino at Caesars Palace, as well as continued construction-related disruption at the Desert Inn will also have a negative impact on the quarter.</p>
<p>In addition, due to increased competition in the Tunica, Mississippi market, ITT's performance in that market is expected to be substantially below the 1995 third quarter.</p>
<p>As a result of these factors, third quarter 1996 earnings are expected to approximate pro forma 1995 third quarter results of 56 cents per share.</p>
<p>The company's remaining businesses continue to perform consistent with expectations with a particularly strong performance in the hotel segment expected in the quarter.  The company has no reason to believe that these third quarter gaming shortfalls will be offset by improved performance during the 1996 fourth quarter. SOURCE ITT Corporation</p>
<p>CONTACT: Jim Gallagher of ITT Corporation, 212-258-1261/</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
