<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="446993" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian infrastructure fund to commit $400 million.</title>
<headline>Asian infrastructure fund to commit $400 million.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Asian Infrastructure Development Company Ltd (AIDEC) expects to commit US$400 million to major infrastructure projects in Asia over the next two years, officials of the company's fund management arm said on Monday.</p>
<p>Koji Kashiwaya, chief executive officer of the AIDEC Management Company Private Ltd (AIMAC), told reporters AIDEC's capital base had increased to 48.6 billion yen from 31.2 billion yen at its inception in November 1995, with the addition of three new shareholders.</p>
<p>He said the Government of Singapore Investment Corporation (GIC), Nippon Life Insurance Company, and Chuo Trust &amp; Banking, had joined AIDEC's shareholders while Nippon Credit Bank, Tokio Marine and Fire Insurance, and Japan's Overseas Economic Cooperation Fund had increased their initial capital.</p>
<p>The GIC has committed to invest US$50 million in AIDEC and Nippon Life has committed to 5 billion yen, he said.</p>
<p>AIMAC managing director Kazuo Yoshimura said the company had already obtained approval from its investment committee to provide about US$105 million in financing for five projects in Asia.</p>
<p>The total development cost of the projects, which include a power project in Pakistan, an airport tunnel in the Philippines, toll roads in Indonesia and China, and a telecommunications project in India, is estimated to be US$3.2 billion.</p>
<p>Yoshimura said some of the financing for these projects had already been disbursed while the rest was being finalised.</p>
<p>AIDEC, incorporated in the Cayman Islands, aims to finance Asian infrastructure projects through private sector development.</p>
<p>Its other shareholders include the Asian Development Bank, Mitsubishi Heavy Industries, and Asahi Life Insurance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
