<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447083" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Salomon sells Basis Petroleum, restates profit to loss.</title>
<headline>Salomon sells Basis Petroleum, restates profit to loss.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Benkoe</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Salomon Inc. has agreed to sell its Basis Petroleum Inc. to Valero Energy Corp. for about $485 million, the companies said Monday.</p>
<p>The deal would make Valero one of the nation's largest independent refining companies, owning and operating four refineries with total capacity of about 500,000 barrels a day.</p>
<p>Salomon's sale removes a profit-bleeding thorn from its side and the deal should help management focus on core businesses this year, analysts said Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been a thorn in their side for a very long time,&quot; said Mark Boyar, president of Asset Analysis Focus. &quot;It really depressed their earnings.&quot;</p>
<p>Leslie Nelkin, an analyst at Furman Selz, estimated Basis, which refines oil and is a wholesale marketer, was costing Salomon from 50 cents to $1 a share in profit each year.</p>
<p>Salomon, holding company for Salomon Brothers investment bank, also said it will restate its fourth-quarter results to show a net loss of $62 million, reflecting an after-tax loss of $290 million from the sale.</p>
<p>The restated loss, equal to 71 cents a share, compares with a profit of $168 million, or $1.42 a share, in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>Salomon posted fourth-quarter operating income of $234 million before the Basis deal vs. $187 million a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;It should be helpful in enabling Salomon to focus on their core businesses, rather than the oil refining business,&quot; said Raphael Soifer, an analyst at Brown Brothers Harriman.</p>
<p>Salomon has been seeking to unload Basis for some time, analysts said.</p>
<p>Valero, based in San Antonio, Texas, will pay $285 million for Basis' stock and about $200 million for inventories and other working capital. The payment will be made in cash and about $120 million worth of Valero stock.</p>
<p>The acquisition puts Valero into the top five independent refiners. Valero said the purchase would not affect its plans to spin off its refining and marketing business to a separate company and merge its natural gas related services business with PG&amp;E Corp.</p>
<p>Valero plans to reduce overhead at the Basis refineries by $26 million and plans just one major upgrade at the Texas City refinery for about $50 million.</p>
<p>The primary assets of Basis include three refineries in Texas City, Texas; Houston and Krotz Springs, La., with total throughput capacity in excess of 300,000 barrels a day and an extensive wholesale marketing business.</p>
<p>Salomon's Phibro unit, which trades grains, natural gas, and oil, continues to fit more with the main business, said Richard Strauss, an analyst at Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>&quot;It's something they've made money in consistently,&quot; said Strauss. &quot;It is counter-cyclical revenue,&quot; when interest rates rise and the stock market suffers a downturn.</p>
<p>Under terms of the Basis sale, Salomon will receive payments in any of the next 10 years if the average refining margin improves above a specified level during that year. Such payments will not exceed $35 million in any year or a total of $200 million.</p>
<p>The acquisition has been approved by the boards of directors of both Valero and Salomon. The deal is expected to close in May 1997, subject to definitive agreements and other conditions.</p>
<p>Valero's stock rose 75 cents to $33.50 while Salomon fell $2 to $52.125 on the New York Stock Exchange in afternoon trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
