<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447043" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iran leader reappoints Rafsanjani to high council.</title>
<headline>Iran leader reappoints Rafsanjani to high council.</headline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran's supreme leader on Monday reappointed outgoing President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani as head of a powerful state council which will draw up long-term state policies.</p>
<p>In a statement read on state-run Tehran radio, Ayatollah Ali Khamenei also named state technocrats close to Rafsanjani and radical clerics allied to the president's centrist backers to the body for five years.</p>
<p>Khamenei also reinstated several senior conservative clerics to the Expediency Discernment Council which has the power to legislate on important matters over the head of parliament. Among them is the director of a foundation which has offered a $2.5 million bounty for anyone who kills British author Salman Rushdie.</p>
<p>Rafsanjani's reappointment appeared to give an influential future role to the outgoing president, whose term ends on August 3, as the head of the council which will also advise the Iranian spiritual leader on major national issues.</p>
<p>Rafsanjani said last month that assisting Khamenei was among the tasks he had set for himself after the end of his term. He is constitutionally barred from running in presidential elections in May after serving two consecutive terms.</p>
<p>Other members named to the council include Central Bank Governor Mohsen Nourbakhsh and Vice-President Mohammad Hashemi, the president's brother, who have been active members of a group organising Rafsanjani's moderate backers.</p>
<p>The council's main role has been to arbitrate between the parliament and the Guardian Council, a body of clerics and lawyers which vets parliamentary decisions.</p>
<p>Among hardline conservatives named by Khamenei to the council is Ayatollah Hassan Sanei, the head of the foundation which has offered the bounty for Rushdie.</p>
<p>Iranian officials have said the bounty has been set by a non-governmental foundation and has nothing to do with state policies.</p>
<p>The foundation first offered the rewards in 1989, after Iran's late spiritual leader Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini issued a religious ruling imposing the death sentence on Rushdie for allegedly blaspheming Islam in his novel &quot;The Satanic Verses&quot;.</p>
<p>Other Khamenei appointees were Abdollah Nouri and Mohammad Moussavi Khoeiniha, two leaders of a group of radical clerics and Islamist intellectuals who have moderated many of their views and become allies with Rafsanjani backers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
