<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447096" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rockwell to spin off automotive units.</title>
<headline>Rockwell to spin off automotive units.</headline>
<byline>Mark Egan</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rockwell International Corp. said Monday it plans to spin off its automotive business to shareholders, completing its transformation from a broadly diversified company to one tightly focused on electronics.</p>
<p>The spin-off, just three months after Rockwell sold its aerospace and defence business to Boeing Co. for $3.2 billion, will allow Rockwell to concentrate on businesses that have much better potential for earnings growth, industry analysts said.</p>
<p>The automotive units had 1996 sales of $3.1 billion and Rockwell said its remaining businesses will post sales of about $8 billion in fiscal 1997.</p>
<p>Based in Troy, Mich., Rockwell's automotive businesses employ about 16,000 people at plants in Iowa, Kentucky, Michigan, Ohio, North and South Carolina, Tennessee and Wisconsin, as well as locations abroad.</p>
<p>Under the spin-off, Rockwell's stockholders would receive shares in the new firm in addition to the stock they hold in Rockwell. The new shares would trade on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>After the spin-off, Rockwell will have three main businesses: semiconductor systems, electronics systems and aerospace electronics and communications, making semiconductor chips for modems and faxes, factory automation products, aircraft communications gear and navigation and flight control systems.</p>
<p>Larry Yost, president of Rockwell Heavy Vehicle Systems, will become president of the company being spun off, which makes axles, door systems, air brake parts and sunroofs.</p>
<p>&quot;Today Rockwell is comprised of two distinct businesses -- a group of leading-edge businesses serving segments of the electronics market and automotive component systems, each with significant differences in their markets, products, technologies, investment requirements and strategic growth opportunities,&quot; Chairman Donald Beall said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;After careful consideration of our business options, we're convinced that the full potential of these businesses can best be reached by operating separately,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Beall said the new company will assume about $400 million of debt and in return pay a dividend of the same size to Rockwell, leaving Rockwell essentially debt free.</p>
<p>He said that Rockwell does not expect to take a charge from the spin-off, adding that Rockwell's is not changing its goal of growing profits at about 15 percent annually.</p>
<p>Analysts said the spin-off is clearly aimed at boosting earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;The growth will certainly be in the higher technology areas,&quot; said Paul Nisbet, an analyst at JSA Research.</p>
<p>&quot;They have gotten out of defence and graphics and printing presses and now they are spinning off the automotive business. These are all relatively slow growth and slow margin areas and they are very obviously concentrating on the high growth potential, high technology, high margin type businesses,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The auto operations' plants abroad are in Australia, Brazil, Canada, China, several countries in Europe, as well as India, Japan, and Mexico.</p>
<p>Beall said the two companies will continue to cooperate closely, particularly in the area of international marketing.</p>
<p>The spin-off is subject to a ruling by the Internal Revenue Service that the transaction would be tax-free. Rockwell said it is expected to be completed by fiscal year-end at Sept. 30.</p>
<p>Rockwell's shares fell 37.5 cents to $67.50 in afternoon trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
