<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447188" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Primakov says Russia won't change on NATO.</title>
<headline>Primakov says Russia won't change on NATO.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov met U.S. President Bill Clinton Monday but said afterwards Russia would not change its opposition to NATO expansion.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia will not change its position on NATO. But Russia understands that NATO is a real force, and Russia wants to have normal relations with NATO, which would serve the cause of normalising the situation in Europe,&quot; Primakov told reporters after seeing Clinton at the White House.  </p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry said Primakov and Clinton had a &quot;good review&quot; of the issues to be addressed later this week at a summit between Clinton and Russian President Boris Yeltsin in Helsinki. Clinton and Yeltsin are expected to seek an accommodation over NATO's plan to expand into Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>Asked whether there had been any change in positions during the one-hour session between Clinton and Primkov, McCurry said &quot;there's still work to be done.&quot; But he said this did not keep the U.S.-Russian relationship from being productive.</p>
<p>&quot;There will likely continue to be some disagreements after the summit in Helsinki,&quot; McCurry told reporters. &quot;I can't imagine that we will solve all the issues that are pending.&quot;</p>
<p>McCurry said Clinton stated that &quot;the United States and Russia are in this relationship for the long haul.&quot; But, McCurry said, &quot;there is a substantial amount of work that needs to be done to clear away the residue of the Cold War period. A large part of the work of this summit will be about that.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
