<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447149" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AmEx CEO collects higher salary, bonus.</title>
<headline>AmEx CEO collects higher salary, bonus.</headline>
<text>
<p>NEW YORK, March 17 (Reuter) American Express Co chairman and chief executive Harvey Golub earned $900,000 in salary and a $1,980,000 bonus in 1996, according to the company's proxy statement for the April 28 annual meeting of shareholders.</p>
<p>In 1995, Golub's salary was $876,923 and his bonus was $1,860,000.</p>
<p>According to a report by the compensation committee of the board of directors, Golub's bonus reflected the company's return on equity of 23 pecent and earnings per share growth of 14.8 percent, excluding non-recurring items.  </p>
<p>The committee also took into account that total return to shareholders from price appreciation and dividends from the end of 1995 to the end of 1996 was 39.8 percent. Net operating income of $1.74 billion was the highest in the company's history.</p>
<p>In 1996, Golub received, in addition to other long term compensation, a non-qualified stock option to purchase 200,000 common shares at fair market value at the date of the grant. The option is exercisable in cumulative annual installments of one-third over three years.</p>
<p>The options have an exercise price of $46.25 per share and had a theoretical value on the grant date of $2,292,000. American Express sharese closed off 3/4 at 63-3/4 Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
