<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447219" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IBM to launch Intel workstations Tuesday.</title>
<headline>IBM to launch Intel workstations Tuesday.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>International Business Machines Corp said it will unveil Tuesday its much awaited low-cost workstations using Intel Corp's PentiumPro chips, at prices ranging from $3,700 to $10,000.</p>
<p>Last week, IBM executives told Reuters at the CeBIT computer show in Hanover, Germany that IBM would use Intel chips in new workstations, called IntelliStations, that will run Microsoft Corp's Windows NT operating system.</p>
<p>IBM will launch the new family at a press conference Tuesday. The workstations will be aimed at commercial, engineering and scientific markets, the spokesman said.  </p>
<p>The new workstations will compete with the low-end of IBM's current workstation family, the RS/6000, designed around the PowerPC processor and IBM's version of UNIX called AIX.</p>
<p>IBM co-developed the PowerPC chip with Motorola Inc and Apple Computer Inc. The RS/6000 workstations are more expensive, higher powered and can perform more intense mathematical calculations than the new models.</p>
<p>The new IntelliStation family will be marketed the Personal Workstation unit, a group which was formed last year and IBM's RS/6000 salesforce will also market them.  </p>
<p>Analysts said that IBM needed to embrace the Intel/Microsoft architecture in workstations, especially as some of its major PC rivals such as Compaq Computer Corp and Dell Computer Corp and others are getting into the workstation business with PentiumPro-based systems running NT.</p>
<p>&quot;The Intel chips and the NT operating environment...have become robust enough to provide a lower-cost alternative to UNIX,&quot; said Joe Clabby, an analyst with the Aberdeen Group. &quot;You have to give your customer what they are going to buy. If IBM doesn't offer it, they will buy it from someone else.&quot;  </p>
<p>IBM also said that its adoption of the Intel/Microsoft architecture is by no means a death knell for the PowerPC chip.</p>
<p>While the PowerPC chip has fallen short of its developers initial hopes, IBM said it remains committed to the PowerPC. The chip is used in many product lines, from the RS/6000 to the AS/400 minicomputer family to its SP supercomputers and now it will also become the heart of its network computer.</p>
<p>&quot;It's still a strategic architecture for IBM,&quot; a spokesman said. It also powers Apple's Macintoshes and Mac clones.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
