<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447208" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Babbitt seeks halt to Yellowstone buffalo killing.</title>
<headline>Babbitt seeks halt to Yellowstone buffalo killing.</headline>
<byline>Vicki Allen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Interior Secretary Bruce Babbitt Monday asked the state of Montana to stop shooting buffalo that stray from Yellowstone National Park while a study is done on whether they pose a disease threat to cattle.</p>
<p>Babbitt said he did not have authority to order a halt to the killing but he appealed to Montana to stop it while the study is done. Yellowstone's free-ranging herd that started the winter at about 3,500 buffalo is down to about 1,500, he told a new conference.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to see if we can call a truce to the killing that's going on,&quot; he said. He said he had asked the National Academy of Sciences to complete a study by October on chances of brucellosis-infected buffalo infecting cattle in the wild and whether buffalo, elk and other wildlife could be vaccinated against the disease.</p>
<p>More than 1,000 buffalo were shot or sent to slaughter by the state as they crossed park boundaries in search of food, and the rest died from starvation and the brutual winter, he said.</p>
<p>Ranchers fear the buffalo, some of which carry brucellosis, will spread the disease to cattle that graze on nearby federal and private land. The disease has little apparent effect on buffalo but causes cattle to abort calves.</p>
<p>Babbitt said there had never been a documented case of brucellosis being transmitted from buffalo to cattle in the wild. And he said elk, which have not been targeted by the state, also carry brucellosis.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an over-reaction and it is unnecessary,&quot; Babbitt said of the state-ordered destruction of buffalo.</p>
<p>But a spokesman for Montana Gov. Marc Racicot said the state was forced to intervene because the park has failed to manage the buffalo herd properly.</p>
<p>&quot;Montana detests being placed in the position of addressing the symptoms of Yellowstone National Park's overpopulation of diseased bison,&quot; Andrew Malcolm, Racicot's spokesman, said. &quot;Fortunately we're coming to the end of winter and there won't need to be much shooting.&quot;</p>
<p>The Agriculture Department's Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service for years has threatened to revoke the state's brucellosis-free status for cattle if they shared grazing land with the buffalo.</p>
<p>The inspection service backed off that policy this winter, but Interior Department officials said Montana has continued to destroy buffalo that leave the park.</p>
<p>Babbitt said it was against the park's philosophy to &quot;imprison buffalo&quot; in its boundaries and the adjacent federal land was intended to provide lower-elevation winter range for Yellowstone wildlife.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
