<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447388" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton pick Mondale, Kassebaum to push reform.</title>
<headline>Clinton pick Mondale, Kassebaum to push reform.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton named former Democratic Vice President Walter Mondale and former Kansas Republican Sen. Nancy Kassebaum on Monday to launch a &quot;crusade&quot; to reform the campaign finance laws this year.</p>
<p>Vice President Al Gore, stepping in for Clinton who is recuperating from knee surgery, announced that the president had named Mondale and Kassebaum to lead a public education effort to win passage of stalled reform legislation.</p>
<p>The announcement of the two former politicians comes amid major controversy embroiling Clinton and Gore over allegations their Democratic Party accepted illegal or improper campaign donations for the 1996 election.</p>
<p>Clinton has backed a bipartisan campaign reform plan sponsored in the Senate by Arizona Republican John McCain and Wisconsin Democrat Russ Feingold and a similar bill in the House by a bipartisan group to limit campaign spending and end unregulated &quot;soft money&quot; donations to political parties.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we push our crusade still further,&quot; Gore told a White House audience of civic and political leaders calling for an overhaul of the campaign reform laws.</p>
<p>&quot;We are enlisting two of America's leading public citizens, one a Republican, one a Democrat, as spokespeople for the cause of renewing our democracy,&quot; said Gore.</p>
<p>&quot;If we don't act quickly, and if we don't act in a truly bipartisan fashion, reform will fail this year as it has year in and year out,&quot; said Gore.</p>
<p>Gore noted that Clinton had wanted to be at the event but his surgery on Friday had prevented it. He said that even though Clinton &quot;is having a little trouble walking today he is committed to taking all the strides we need to reform our campaign finance system.&quot;</p>
<p>In her acceptance remarks, Kassebaum -- recently married to former Tennessee Reublican Sen. Howard Baker -- said that the drive for campaign reform should not be looked at as &quot;a diversion&quot; from the pending campaign finance investigations -- a remark echoed by Mondale.</p>
<p>She foresaw a tough job ahead in pushing the bipartisan reform measure that has not gained any steam in this Congress.</p>
<p>&quot;It isn't going to be easy to accomplish,&quot; she said. &quot;Our goal is to advance bipartisan legislation to create a level playing field (in election campaigns).&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
