<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447322" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Products Outlook - Stocks pressure gasoline.</title>
<headline>U.S. Products Outlook - Stocks pressure gasoline.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot gasoline prices in New York Harbor and the Gulf Coast should find little bullish help this week, with U.S. nearby supplies seen as plentiful versus the relatively slack demand, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>Gasoline prices continued to languish near their lowest levels since September, with U.S. Gulf conventional unleaded gasoline ending Friday at about 62.00 cents a gallon and New York Harbor conventional unleaded gasoline at about 61.50 cents.</p>
<p>Differentials were hurt by American Petroleum Institute data showing a 668,000 barrel build in gasoline stocks for the week ending March 7. The build was a turnaround from a combined draw of 5.5 million barrels seen over the previous three weeks.</p>
<p>Although total U.S. gasoline stocks remain about five million barrels below last year, the situation is a marked improvement from the 10.3 million barrel year-on-year shortfall seen during the week ending February 28.</p>
<p>&quot;Improved gasoline supplies will tend to hurt prices in the very short term,&quot; one analyst said, but added the approaching driving season and increased demand should offer increasing support several weeks farther down the road.</p>
<p>Refining margins slipped in the week ended March 8 in all regions of the country except the West Coast, according to Paul Ting, analyst with Salomon Brothers Inc.</p>
<p>East Coast margins fell from $3.29 from March 1 to $3.09 on March 8, Ting said, although the cost of West Texas Intermediate crude oil fell $0.38 to $20.54 a barrel during the same period.</p>
<p>Midwest margins fell hardest during the week, from $4.49 to $3.86, while on the Gulf Coast they slipped only slightly, from $2.75 to $2.72.</p>
<p>Boisterously healthy margins in California narrowed a bit, from $7.63 to $7.38, Ting said. But for the West Coast overall, margins widened from $5.16 to $5.73.</p>
<p>&quot;Refinery (maintenance) shutdowns on the West Coast have tightened supplies. That's helped the margins there,&quot; said Paolo Nery, of Pace Consultants in Houston.</p>
<p>&quot;Crude in California -- Alaska North Slope -- is cheaper than elsewhere, they're enjoying a discount,&quot; he added, keeping margins there at lofty, if slightly diminished, levels.</p>
<p>He said margins in California could be bolstered in coming weeks if the union for Unocal refinery workers carries through with a hinted strike threat at four Unocal refineries in the state.</p>
<p>Officials of the Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers Union (OCAW) have said Tosco plans to cut up to 150 refinery jobs after it completes the purchase of Unocal's 76 Products Co this month and shifts its headquarters to Phoenix.</p>
<p>Union officials have also criticized the medical and pension plans Tosco is offering and said support runs strong for a strike if Tosco's offer fails to satisfy union members.</p>
<p>Tosco agreed to buy 76 Products' refineries and other downstream assets from Unocal last November for $1.4 billion. 76 Products refines about 20 percent of California's gasoline, with the state's third-highest market share at 12.5 percent.</p>
<p>Prices for West Coast spot refined products were forecast steady to firmer this week, traders said, amid tightening supplies and lingering shutdowns at the region's refineries.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say it would stay firm...Everything you look at is bullish,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Several refiners remain partly shut, including Mobil's 130,000 barrel-per-day refinery south of Los Angeles, and Exxon's Benecia plant in northern California.</p>
<p>While the region's refining output began throttling back up in early March, rising 4.3 percentage points to operate at 83.8 percent of capacity, inventories continued to fall.</p>
<p>Gasoline supplies on the West Coast stood at 26.8 million barrels as of March 7, down 1.4 million barrels.</p>
<p>Traders in the Midwest expected diesel fuel basis to remain steady in the coming week but saw continued volatility in unleaded gasoline differentials in Chicago ahead of a seasonal changeover.</p>
<p>&quot;(Diesel) basis probably will be steady even though diesel inventories have come down the past ten days,&quot; one Group Three trader said.</p>
<p>The Williams system, a key barometer of stocks in the Group market, reported a 29-day supply of low sulphur diesel and 24-day supply of gasoline on hand as trade wound down for the week, traders said.</p>
<p>Chicago winter-grade unleaded gasoline demand was expected to continue to weaken after pushing bids 9.25 cents a gallon under NYMEX April unleaded ahead of the early April changeover to summer-grade specifications.</p>
<p>--New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
