<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447302" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton, Primakov to prepare for Helsinki summit.</title>
<headline>Clinton, Primakov to prepare for Helsinki summit.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Worsnip</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov headed for a key meeting with President Bill Clinton on Monday that will set the tone for a U.S.-Russian summit this week focusing on NATO expansion.</p>
<p>U.S. officials were tight-lipped ahead of the 3.00 pm EST (2000 GMT) meeting, but there was no indication substantial progress was in prospect on overcoming Moscow's opposition to plans for the eastward enlargement of the Western alliance.</p>
<p>Primakov arrived in Washington two days ago and met U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright on Saturday and Defence Secretary William Cohen on Sunday. U.S. and Russian officials had no immediate comment on either meeting.</p>
<p>At the March 20-21 summit in Helsinki, Clinton and Russian President Boris Yeltsin will be seeking an accommodation over NATO's plan to announce at a July summit in Madrid which East European countries it will invite to apply for membership.</p>
<p>Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic, which all once belonged to the Soviet-led Warsaw Pact in the communist era, are believed to be the leading candidates.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, in improving health after lengthy bouts with heart disease and pneumonia, insisted on Sunday that he would demand a legally binding treaty barring Western forces from ever deploying in eastern Europe.</p>
<p>His remarks conflicted with reports suggesting Moscow was dropping this demand. NATO is offering Russia a charter that would give it the right to close consultation on European security issues but no power to veto NATO plans.</p>
<p>U.S. officials say there is an element of bargaining in the Russian position, with Moscow holding out for concessions in other fields in return for accepting a NATO expansion plan they know the alliance is determined to pursue.</p>
<p>&quot;The Russians are going to soak this for everything they can, and we know that,&quot; one official said. &quot;I would be very surprised if they really resolved the NATO stuff at the summit.&quot;</p>
<p>The officials suggested that for this reason, a key focus this week could be on related issues of nuclear and conventional arms control that the two sides have been grappling with.</p>
<p>As a &quot;sweetener,&quot; NATO is offering Russia amendments to the 1990 Conventional Forces in Europe treaty that would block an arms buildup around Russia's borders.</p>
<p>Of even more concern to Washington is to try to break a deadlock over nuclear arms control. The 1993 START-2 strategic arms pact is stuck in the Russian Duma (parliament), many of whose deputies fear it could hurt Russian security.</p>
<p>U.S. officials have spoken of preparing for a possible START-3 accord that would go beyond the major missile cutbacks envisioned in START-2. But they say negotiations cannot start until the Duma ratifies the earlier treaty.</p>
<p>One carrot that the United States can offer Moscow is support for its membership in global economic groupings like the World Trade Organisation and the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development.</p>
<p>&quot;Why, up to now, can Russia not join various world organisations because of U.S. opposition?&quot; Yeltsin asked Monday. &quot;Why is Russia not recognised as having a market economy yet? Why? Seventy per cent is in the private sector.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
