<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447525" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Analyst cuts EU grain sowing forecast to 38 mln ha.</title>
<headline>Analyst cuts EU grain sowing forecast to 38 mln ha.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>French grain analyst Strategie Grains said on Monday it had cut its estimate for European Union grain sowings for the 1997 harvest by 100,000 hectares to 38 million hectares.</p>
<p>This would still represent a rise of three percent over 1996 sowings of 36.8 million hectares, it said.</p>
<p>Last month Strategie Grains said 1997 grain sowings would reach 38.1 million hectares.</p>
<p>Strategie Grains also predicted 1997 grain production within the European Union might rise by one percent to 206.5 million tonnes compared with 207.4 million tonnes forecast in February and a revised 204.2 million tonnes produced in 1996.</p>
<p>The analyst said that despite a lower set-aside rate, a strong rise in rapeseed and protein seeds sowings limited the rise in area sown to grain.</p>
<p>In its monthly report for March, the analyst warned that production estimates remained subject to adjustment.</p>
<p>Yield forecasts were based on a trend and would be fine-tuned in coming months in line with weather conditons.</p>
<p>The latest forecast assumed 1997/98 grain yields would decline two percent to 5.4 tonnes per hectare from 5.5 tonnes in the previous campaign.</p>
<p>Strategie Grains held its estimate for 1997/98 soft wheat output at 93.1 million tonnes. This would represent a rise of three percent over the 90.8 million tonnes produced in 1996/97.</p>
<p>Wheat sowings would rise by three percent to 14.2 million hectares and yields remain steady at 6.6 tonnes per hectare.</p>
<p>The analyst now targets barley production at 52.3 million tonnes against a previous forecast of 52.4 million tonnes and 52.5 million tonnes produced in 1996/97.</p>
<p>Barley sowings would rise by four percent to 11.8 million hectares and yields decline four percent to 4.4 tonnes per hectare.</p>
<p>Strategie Grains now puts EU maize output at 35.3 milion tonnes against 36 million tonnes forecast in February. This would represent a rise of three percent over 34.2 million tonnes produced previously.</p>
<p>Maize sowings would rise by five percent to 4.3 million hectare and yield decline one percent to 8.2 tonnes per hectare.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5432</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
