<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447579" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India says Oman gas pipeline faces problems.</title>
<headline>India says Oman gas pipeline faces problems.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>India said on Monday that a $4 billion submarine pipeline project to supply natural gas from the Gulf state of Oman had run into problems but the two countries were trying to salvage it.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confronted with the problem of technology to lay a pipeline in fairly deep waters,&quot; a foreign office spokesman told reporters, a day before Oman's Sultan Qaboos Bin Said was due to start his first official tour of India.</p>
<p>&quot;There was also the question of adequate gas reserves to warrant the project. Oman is not the world's largest depositories of gas,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The two countries signed a memorandum of understanding in 1993 to build the pipeline through the Arabian Sea separating them.</p>
<p>&quot;The two governments decided in 1996 to set up a joint committee of experts to study whether the project was feasible. That is where it stands today,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>He did not say if the issue would be taken up with Qaboos who begins his four-day visit on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Omani officials said the Gulf state was not likely to spend more money on the feasibility study.</p>
<p>&quot;We have already spent $70 to 80 million and we haven't made much headway,&quot; one Omani official told Reuters.</p>
<p>The proposed pipeline, more than 1,300 km (813 miles) long, was expected to hit a maximum depth of two miles.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
