<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447584" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Gold - Indian sub-continent prices stay subdued.</title>
<headline>Gold - Indian sub-continent prices stay subdued.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold was subdued in the Indian sub-continent in the week to Monday and dealers said they expected prices to weaken further on poor demand.</p>
<p>Bombay dealers said seasonal gold buying had not been up to market expectations while improved supplies had prompted selling.</p>
<p>In the week to Monday standard gold dropped 25 rupees per 10 grammes to 4,790 rupees.</p>
<p>Dealers said supplies had improved in the last two months following a liberal gold import policy announced by the Indian government on December 31.</p>
<p>India allowed expatriates to bring in 10 kg of gold once every six months, subject to a duty of 220 rupees per 10 grammes, against five kg permitted earlier.</p>
<p>Dealers said the measure helped boost gold supplies in January, which also coincided with the peak Indian wedding season that lasted until mid-February.</p>
<p>Low world market prices towards the end of the previous year had also prompted Indian expatriates to buy gold.</p>
<p>World markets have since recovered.</p>
<p>&quot;But sentiment in India is subdued and I am expecting gold prices to remain subdued in the coming days,&quot; said Babubhai Jain, a Bombay bullion dealer.</p>
<p>Dealers in Pakistan's main commercial centre of Karachi said they would expect gold prices to remain mixed this week in line with international price trends.</p>
<p>Gold prices in Pakistan depended on international rates, which were mixed last week, dealer Farooq Qureshi said.</p>
<p>In the week to Saturday, gold prices improved by 26 rupees per 10 grammes to 4,728 rupees on the Karachi bullion market.</p>
<p>In Dubai too, gold demand was subdued, but traders expected interest to rise in the run-up to a month-long shopping promotion which was likely to lure big jewellery and investment bar buyers to the souk.</p>
<p>&quot;Coins and jewellery are the main attraction,&quot; said a retailer, referring to the commemorative gold coin which would be minted especially for the festival, which organisers hoped would attract tourists, particularly from the Indian subcontinent, the Gulf and Europe.</p>
<p>GOLD PRICES 24 CARATS PER 10 GRAMMES IN U.S. DOLLARS</p>
<p>	     March 17/16/15*		   March 10/09*</p>
<p>BOMBAY	133.53				134.30</p>
<p>KARACHI     117.55				116.90</p>
<p>DUBAI	 113.90				113.08</p>
<p>(Conversion $=35.87 Indian rupees, 40.22 Pakistani rupees and 3.67 UAE Dirhams)</p>
<p>* Bombay prices March 17/10, Karachi March 15/09 and Dubai March 16/09</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
