<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447677" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Salomon sells Basis Petroleum, restates profit to loss.</title>
<headline>Salomon sells Basis Petroleum, restates profit to loss.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Salomon Inc. has signed a letter of intent to sell Basis Petroleum Inc. to Valero Energy Corp. for about $485 million, the companies said Monday.</p>
<p>The deal would make Valero one of the nation's largest independent refining companies, owning and operating four refineries with total throughput capacity of about 500,000 barrels a day.</p>
<p>Salomon, holding company for Salomon Brothers investment bank, also said it will restate its fourth-quarter results to show a net loss of $62 million, reflecting an after-tax loss of $290 million from the sale.</p>
<p>The restated loss, equal to 71 cents a share, compares with a profit of $168 million -- or $1.32 per diluted share and $1.42 per primary share -- in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>Salomon posted fourth-quarter operating income of $234 million, or $1.88 per diluted share, before the Basis deal, vs. $187 million, or $1.32, a year ago.</p>
<p>Valero, based in San Antonio, Texas, will pay $285 million for Basis' stock and about $200 million for inventories and other working capital. The payment will be made in cash and about $120 million worth of Valero stock.</p>
<p>The primary assets of Basis include three refineries in Texas City, Texas; Houston and Krotz Springs, La., with total throughput capacity in excess of 300,000 barrels per day and an extensive wholesale marketing business.</p>
<p>In addition, Salomon will receive payments in any of the next 10 years if the average refining margin improves above a specified level during that year. Such payments will not exceed $35 million in any year or a total of $200 million.</p>
<p>The acquisition has been approved in principle by the board of directors of both Valero and Salomon.</p>
<p>The deal is expected to close in May 1997, subject to execution of definitive agreements.</p>
<p>The acquisition is not expected to affect the timing related to Valero's announcement in January to spin off its refining and marketing business and merge its natural gas related services business with PG&amp;E Corp.</p>
<p>The spin-off and merger are still expected to be completed by mid-year.</p>
<p>Valero's stock rose 87.5 cents to $33.625, while Salomon fell $1.375 to $52.75 on the New York Stock Exchange in late morning trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
