<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447688" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Thyssen -Krupp to make takeover bid.</title>
<headline>Thyssen -Krupp to make takeover bid.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>German steel and engineering group Thyssen AG said on Monday its rival Krupp's was preparing to make a hostile takeover bid which it would defend with &quot;appropriate means.&quot;</p>
<p>The news recalled Fried. Krupp AG Krupp-Hoesch's spectacular surprise takeover of rival Hoesch AG in 1991 which combined Germany's second and third largest steel makers and led to speculation of a further consolidation in the sector.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are unconcerned about this attempt,&quot; a Thyssen spokesman told Reuters. &quot;This can only be an attempt on the part of Krupp to resolve its own considerable problems by tapping into Thyssen's reserves.&quot;</p>
<p>The spokesman added that Thyssen would use all &quot;appropriate means&quot; to counter any hostile takeover attempt and said the company had called a news conference for Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>A takeover of Thyssen by Krupp would be an &quot;incomprehensible act in the style of the Wild West&quot;, the spokesman added which would set off a restructuring programme that would cost tens of thousands of jobs.</p>
<p>Thyssen's statement followed the advance release of a report to appear in the daily Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung on Tuesday, which said Krupp was planning to make an offer to Thyssen shareholders.</p>
<p>The offer was being prepared by Deutsche Morgan Grenfell, the investment arm of Deutsche Bank, the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not comment on these rumours now,&quot; said Krupp spokesman Juergen Claassen. &quot;We will issue a press release shortly.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman for Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in London said the bank never commented on market rumours as a general policy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
