<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447664" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: TEXT - Interview with Indian finance minister.</title>
<headline>TEXT - Interview with Indian finance minister.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following is the transcript of an interview which Indian Finance Minister P. Chidambaram granted Reuters at the weekend.</p>
<p>-------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>REUTERS: On Monday you will be meeting central bank officials in New Delhi. What message will you be giving them? .</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: They will be announcing the new credit policy in the second week of April so this is an opportunity to discuss the elements of the credit policy. We also need to discuss the need to maintain price stability. I said in my budget speech that maintaining price stability is very high on the government's agenda. We also need to discuss the surge in foreign exchange inflows. Few people realise that there is a downside to these inflows. The upside, of course, is that your foreign exchange reserves appear healthier and healthier. The downside is that it has inflationary consequences. This is a matter which we will discuss. We will also discuss the offtake of credit. There is still some feeling in the market that adequate credit is not flowing for productive purposes, that interest rates are still high. We will discuss that. Non-farm credit must take off. Given the mood in industry today, it is necessary to ensure that adequate credit is made available to industry, to agriculture for productive purposes. It is a long agenda.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: On the question of inflows of dollars which have been rather strong, the central bank has been intervening to keep the rupee from appreciating. But it does have consequences on the inflation side. Do you think there is room for a depreciation of the rupee?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: We don't talk of depreciating the rupee or devaluing the rupee. As I have said, it is the market which must determine the level of the rupee. All that I think the central bank's concern is that there should not be volatility in the market.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: Do you share that concern?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: Yes, I share the concern there should not be volatility. The last time there was a high degree of volatility was in, I think, September, November of 1995. That caused problems.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: How do you prevent the inflows of dollars, then, from having an upward push on inflation?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: It all depends on what we do with the dollars. If imports rise, as we expect them to rise and they should rise, then some of these dollars will be consumed. We discuss various options.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: Do you think there is room for liberalising with respect to consumer goods imports?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: I have said it is an option. It is an option, but that has to be decided with the Ex-Im policy.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: Which will be done before the first of April?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: The new Ex-Im policy is due on the 31st of March.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: Can we expect some announcements relating to consumer goods imports between now and April 1?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: I cannot say. It is for the commerce minister to propose. Let us see what policy they come up with.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: Some critics say that by failing to curtail the oil pool deficit, you have fanned fears of inflation and a weakening of exports. One former finance minister said this could set off a shock that could create a Mexico-like situation. Will India face a Mexico-like situation because of this mounting oil subsidy bill?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: I don't know who said about Mexico-type situation, but whoever said that is simply unaware of what happened in Mexico and what happened in Mexico last year. I think we would do well to read the literature of what happened in Mexico. Let me make it very clear that India's situation is nowhere near what Mexico's situation was and will never be. The composition of our external debt is very different. Short-term debt as a proportion of our total debt is very small. We do not have the kind of dollar-denominated bonds which Mexico had. It is also worthwhile to note that Mexico came out of its crisis, came out rather rapidly, and it prepaid all its dues. In fact it prepaid them two years in advance. Therefore, while the lessons of Mexico are valuable, there's no point referring to Mexico as though Mexico's about to happen in India. There's nothing like that and I think we should put an end to such speculative and baseless criticism.</p>
<p>With regard to the oil pool account, no finance minister in the past to the best of my knowledge has addressed the oil pool account in his budget, and I don't see why I should be the exception. The reason is simple. The oil pool account is not part of the budget. It is outside the budget, and it has to be addressed by the Ministry of Petroleum, and I have no doubt that the Ministry of Petroleum will address it at a suitable moment. We have brought up the subject for discussion by inserting a paragraph in the president's address. Parliament has debated the president's address. So I'm sure this issue will be taken up at the appropriate time. I think it's incorrect to expect that the finance minister should address the oil pool account in his budget when it had never been done in the past before.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: Are you worried, though, that an eventual increase in the price of petroleum goods will fan inflation?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: I cannot say. It all depends upon whether there is a price increase, what is the price increase and when it has come.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: Turning to the convertibility of the rupee, an RBI official was recently quoted in newspapers as saying full convertibility of the rupee on capital account would have to wait until the turn of the century. Will India have to wait that long?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: Well that's his view. He's most free to express his view, but I would have liked him to withhold his view until we have the report of the committee. The reason why we've appointed the committee is to give us a road map. Let us see what the road map says. If the road map shows that the journey is short, then we will respond accordingly. If the road map shows that the journey is a long journey, then we will respond accordingly.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: But you have very healthy foreign exchange reserves right now. The current account deficit as a proportion of GDP is rather low and it is going down.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: Those are not the only two criteria. There are other criteria. The fiscal deficit must be brought under control and above all, inflation must be brought under control. I think there are other criteria before we move to full capital account convertibility.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: Are you worried about the level of real interest rates in this country and their impact on industrial growth?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: They're lower now than what they were in June (1996) when we took over. In June, real interest rates were as high as 17 or 18 percent. Today real interest rates are perhaps close to about eight or nine percent. Industry feels they are still high, but others tell me that it is possible for industry to work and produce even at such interest rates. After all, interest is a small proportion of the total cost. But as a principle I would like interest rates to soften.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: What do you mean, &quot;as a principle&quot;?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: I think industry will be competitive, or to be more accurate, more competitive if interest rates are lower. Japan's interest rates are so low that it gives them a tremendous advantage even in the starting block.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: Is this something that you will be discussing with the RBI on Monday?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: Yes, I've said so, that one of the things we will discuss is interest rates, and the possibility of interest rates coming down a bit.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: The IMF has said that unless the country makes deeper cuts in the fiscal deficit, debt and interest payments could spiral upwards, and that that could force the country to increase its reliance on foreign savings. And that in turn could lead to a wider current account deficit and deteriorating debt indicators. Eventually an external debt crisis would become unavoidable. Is this the scenario which you see for India?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: That's out of a text book. Running a government cannot be according to a text book. I don't visualise that scenario. I visualise a scenario where we will make a fiscal correction as rapidly as possible, control inflation and maintain price stability, at the same time stimulate growth as well as appropriate large amounts of money for social sector programmes.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: Are you saying that the IMF is not attuned to the reality here?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: IMF's dharma (belief) is to read out of textbooks.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: How about Moody's, then. Moody's very recently said that India's unstable political environment, directionless economic policies and a deterioration in its macroeconomic balances had led Moody's to take an unfavourable outlook on the nation's sovereign rating. How do you respond to this attack on your policies?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: I think Moody's rating's wrong. I mean whoever gave them the inputs must have given it to them at least four months ago. I believe Moody's has since admitted, privately as well as publicly, that what they have put out does not amount to a critique of India's policies of reforms, and they have also admitted that it does not take into account the reforms that have been announced and put in place since December 1996. It is quite evident that Moody's did not even take into account the budget.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: On the trade side, you have served as commerce minister in the past. You are very aware of the trade situation, that exports and imports are rather sluggish. What can the government do to spur trade. Wouldn't a weaker rupee help?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: A weaker rupee would help the exporter but a weaker rupee would hurt many others. I don't think we can look at it only from the point of view of the exporter. World trade has been sluggish. World demand has been sluggish in calendar 1996. To some extent that has affected the year's export growth. But I expect imports to pick up this year, as well as exports to pick up.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: This year meaning 1997/98?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: Calendar 1997, 1997/98. But I think the Ministry of Commerce would do well to do some micro-management of important sectors. There is only so much you can do at the macro level. Once that is done I think it is important to sit with key players in each sector -- shrimps, garments, tea, engineering goods, gems and jewellery -- sit with each sector, look at their problems and try to find a solution to their problems. A little more micro-management may help.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: There is only so much you can do, then?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: There is only so much you can to at the macro level, but at the micro level you can do much more, if the DGFT's (Directorate General of Foreign Trade) officials are helpful, cooperative, go out of their way to help exporters. So much can be done at the micro level.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: One of the criticisms that has been levelled at the budget which you announced last month is that it did not lure enough foreign investors into infrastructure, notably power. Why did you not offer more in the budget to try to solve the problems related to infrastructure?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: Offer what? We've offered them what can be offered. Capital goods can be imported in the power sector with 20 percent duty. Power is considered infrastructure. For the domestic producer of capital goods, we've allowed deemed export benefits. What more can we offer to the foreign or domestic investor through a budget? There is a policy in place, put out by the Ministry of Power that guarantees a return of 16 percent. What more does the investor want?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: I suppose they want less bureaucracy, but that's not your job.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: Well if I can get rid of the bureaucracy through a budget speech, then I'll make a budget speech every other day. The bureaucracy is here. What does the budget have to do with dealing with the bureacracy.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: Let's talk about something you do have responsibility over, and that is taxes. There have been some ambitious cuts in tax rates. Some critics have said that there is no way that tax revenues, across the board, as has been projected, can rise. What is your response to this criticism?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: My critics said the same thing in 1996/97, that I will not be able to meet the fiscal deficit. In fact we did. We maintained the fiscal deficit at the promised five percent. What I've projected for 1997/98 is not so ambitious. On the four major taxes -- income tax, corporate tax, excise duties and customs duties -- the growth that is projected is only 15.5 percent. And that's quite consistent with past experience and past trends. We're confident that we will get the revenues as projected. In fact the criticism that I have given away revenues is completely misplaced. There have been larger give-aways in previous years. These so-called give-aways are based on conventional calculations. The reality is different. Revenue buoyancy makes up more than what has been given away by conventional calculations. This happened in the past, the remote past, the recent past. There is no reason why the 1997/98 budget should not achieve its target of revenues.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: How do you explain a coalition government with communist parties in it advocating tax cuts which help the middle class?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: What is wrong with that? The middle class are good savers. Household savings in this country is about 17 percent. They are our best savers. And I am already on record that we must reward savers and tax spenders, and we've just done that.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>REUTERS: Your budget was widely acclaimed in business circles. Now some politicians in the Congress, the Left and the BJP (Bharatiya Janata Party) have begun sniping. Will the budget package make it through parliament without being dismantled?</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>CHIDAMBARAM: I think so. I think so. I think political parties are bound to find fault with this or that aspect of the budget. But I think what will eventually prevail is the overall public perception of the budget. And that I believe is defined or determined in the first 48 or 72 hours. And I believe MPs and their political constituencies know that by and large the people have received the budget very well. They see it as growth-oriented. They see it as employment creating. No new burden will be put on the poor. And above all it has injected a new mood of confidence in the people. This will get reflected in the debate. I believe the budget will pass.</p>
<p>--------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>-- Nelson Graves, New Delhi newsroom +91-11 301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
