<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447642" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India interest rate trend is downwards - RBI chief.</title>
<headline>India interest rate trend is downwards - RBI chief.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reserve Bank of India (RBI) governor C. Rangarajan said on Monday that the recent decline in short-term interest rates could influence other, longer maturities to fall.</p>
<p>Rangarajan told reporters in the capital that he believed that as the inflation rate falls, interest rates will also decline.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think I've said many times that the short-term rate of interest has been coming down,&quot; he said after a meeting with Finance Minister P. Chidambaram.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a perceptible decline in the short-term rate. It could filter to the other maturities as we go along. And I also believe that as the inflation rate comes down, normal rates of interest will also come down,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Rangarajan said foreign exchange reserves had been steadily increasing and were crossing the previous high. &quot;It is almost at $20.8 billion today,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He was asked if he was concerned that the rise in foreign currency reserves would fuel inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the impact of the increase of foreign currency assets is on the money supply,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore we will have to take a view as we go along whether the expansion in reserve money which is consistent with 16 percent rate of growth is exceeded or not,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In which case, we will have to undertake some sterilisation operations to offset the inflationary impact of the inflow of foreign exchange assets,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think these decisions will have to be taken as we go along. It depends on the order of increase in foreign assets. It depends on the net RBI credit to the central government,&quot; the central bank governor said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the net RBI credit to the central government is low, then it is possible to absorb these assets without having an adverse effect on money supply,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rangarajan said bank deposits had risen by some 550 billion ($15.5 billion) in the current year, which he called a very substantial increase.</p>
<p>&quot;Competition is there but there is greater confidence in the banking system. People are putting money in the banking system. I think they are becoming competitive. They have a credibility, standards which are higher,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rangarajan said his meeting with Chidambaram focused on &quot;the major implications of the budget, about the credit policy in general&quot;. ($1 = 35.87 rupees)</p>
<p>-- New Delhi newsroom +91-11 301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
