<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="44788" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Human factor possible cause in Russian plane crash.</title>
<headline>Human factor possible cause in Russian plane crash.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Investigators have not found any technical fault in a Russian passenger plane that crashed on a Norwegian Arctic island killing all 141 people on board, the Norwegian news agency NTB said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It quoted Jon Pran, Norwegian head of investigation, as saying the human factor or a navigational error could have caused the disaster in which the TU-155 slammed into a mountain on Spitzbergen on August 29.</p>
<p>An initial study in Moscow of the flight and voice recorders showed the aircraft's engines, hulls and wings had functioned properly, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There was nothing to say about the aircraft,&quot; Pran said. &quot;It means we don't have to carry out a costly investigation of the whole plane.&quot;</p>
<p>He cautioned the findings were the result of an initial probe and that it was too early to conclude what caused the crash.</p>
<p>&quot;However, the most probable cause of the accident was either the human factor or some error in the navigational equipment,&quot; he said. &quot;It is clear that the pilots were able to work right up until the moment the accident occurred.&quot;</p>
<p>NTB said a Norwegian specialist had returned from Moscow with the results of the examination of the flight recorder, which provides flight data, and the voice recorder, which tapes pilots' communications. The boxes were found within days of the crash and flown to Moscow.</p>
<p>Norwegian experts, who will be reinforced later in the week by a Russian specialist on Tupolev flight instruments and navigation, will now compare the findings from Moscow with the results of the crash site investigation, NTB said.</p>
<p>The plane was flying miners, some with families, from Moscow to work when it crashed shortly before it was due to land at Norway's Longyear airport.</p>
<p>Norway governs Spitzbergen but shares the island's coal resources with Russia under a treaty dating back to 1925.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
