<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="447939" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Euro stocks mixed as confidence undermined.</title>
<headline>Euro stocks mixed as confidence undermined.</headline>
<byline>Leonard Santorelli</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>European shares started the week in an uncertain mood on Monday but most bourses fell as a weakening dollar undermined the confidence left by Wall Street's rally on Friday.</p>
<p>The dollar fell in early trade after figures showed  the Japanese trade surplus rose in February for first time in over two years. Economists said it might signal a change of the tide and bring about friction with overseas trade partners. The mixed performance in equity markets came despite a dramatic turnaround on Friday which saw London, Frankfurt and Paris ending with gains as U.S. economic data eased worries about an early rise in interest rates.</p>
<p>In London, Europe's biggest bourse, stocks were particularly weak because the shares of a large batch of of companies were diluted as they were declared ex-dividend.</p>
<p>London's FTSE 100 index was down 0.8 percent points in early transactions as major companies such as Wellcome, HSBC and B.A.T Industries went ex-dividend.</p>
<p>The market was seen little moved by talk that the government was likely to confirm a May 1 election but analysts said attention was likely to focus in coming weeks on the lengthy election campaign and opinion polls.</p>
<p>The decision to call a poll could remove one element of uncertainty from the market's mind, dealers said, though the opposition Labour party -- traditionally seen as less friendly to business interests -- is riding high in the opinion polls.</p>
<p>&quot;There is talk of issues such as higher corporation taxes under Labour but there will be delight (once) the election has been called,&quot; said one senior trader.</p>
<p>In Frankfurt, floor trade edged ahead slightly but was unable to follow-through on last Friday's rally as the weaked dollar dimmed prospects for exporters.</p>
<p>The DAX-30 index of leading German shares rose 9.98 points to 3,369.27 by midmorning but the IBIS DAX electronic trading system lost 36.57 points to 3,365.72.</p>
<p>&quot;There's nothing to trade on at the moment. The dollar is softer but not greatly changed, and Bunds (government bonds) are pretty steady,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Some traders saw the risk of some consolidation in the market. &quot;Our trading range for the week is between 3,275 and 3,475,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Paris was hit hardest by the downturn in sentiment. The blue-chip CAC-40 index down over one percent in early dealings.</p>
<p>Traders said investors were concerned about the volatility of the markets and trade was likely to be cautious ahead of U.S. housing starts on Tuesday and inflation data on Wednesday.</p>
<p>On currency markets, the dollar fell by one pfennig and weakened against the yen in thin trade.</p>
<p>A 6.5 percent rise in Japan's February trade surplus, its first rise in over two years, had little net impact overnight. But analysts said the widening surplus with the United States, up 12.3 percent February, could prove a drag on the dollar against the yen.</p>
<p>&quot;The trade surplus rise is an issue and clearly sets the stage for U.S. action and will keep the focus on dollar/yen in the short-term,&quot; said Tim Fox, treasury economist at Standard Chartered Bank in London.</p>
<p>The weak yen was cited as the reason for the increase in Japan's surplus but analysts said the rising surplus could work to push the yen higher in the coming months.</p>
<p>The dollar was also weaker against the martk. Dealers said overall trade was quiet with much of the market focus on key German economic data due this week with the February IFO survey and February cost of living due Thursday.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1030 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was quoted at 1.6873 marks and 123.37 yen, compared with Friday's late European levels of 1.6972 marks and 123.45 yen.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1030 GMT</p>
<p>LONDON - The FTSE-100 index was down 32.5 points at 4,391.8.</p>
<p>PARIS - The CAC-40 was down 26.38 points at 2,619.24.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - The 30-share DAX index was up 9.98 points at 3,369.27.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold was fixed at $352.05 an ounce, compared with $352.75 at the close on Friday. Silver was at $5.26, compared with $5.31 on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
