<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="448059" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Fundamentals decisive for crown - Asbrink.</title>
<headline>Fundamentals decisive for crown - Asbrink.</headline>
<byline>Fredrik Dahl</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish Finance Minister Erik Asbrink, reiterating that he was not particularly worried about the crown's recent weakness, predicted on Monday that strong economic fundamentals would have an impact on the currency.</p>
<p>Asbrink, speaking at a press conference during a meeting of European Union finance ministers, said the Swedish economy would be decisive for the crown's development in the long run.</p>
<p>&quot;And the fundamentals continue to develop in the right direction,&quot; Asbrink said. &quot;I am not particularly worried.&quot;</p>
<p>Public finances continue to improve, the inflation rate is among the lowest in the EU and the current account surplus has grown, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the fundamental development,&quot; he said. &quot;This will also come through, has already come through and will continue to come through when we look at foreign exchange and bond market developments.&quot;</p>
<p>Asbrink said fluctuations on the currency and bond markets were natural although this did not mean that he was indifferent to what was happening.</p>
<p>&quot;In the longer term the dominant development is; lower interest rates and reduced interest rate margins and a strengthening of the crown,&quot; he said. But he acknowledged that this had not been the trend in the last few months.</p>
<p>There was a continuing improvement in public finances and the government stood by its target to reduce the deficit to below three percent of gross domestic product in 1997 and to reach balance the following year, Asbrink said.</p>
<p>The crown, which had already hit its lowest point for a year on Friday, continued to weaken on Monday to trade at a 12-month low of 4.5920 against the mark but later recovered to 4.5760 by 1610 gmt.</p>
<p>The crown has slowly weakened since last autumn.</p>
<p>Asbrink said it was difficult to see any obvious reasons for Friday's fall. He said there had been talk about an &quot;American analysis&quot; which had been negative for Sweden.</p>
<p>Denmark's Den Danske Bank said on Monday the impact on Sweden's financial markets of nervousness about economic and monetary union had been exaggerated since it was unlikely that Sweden would join at the planned 1999 start.</p>
<p>However, the bank forecast that the crown would remain weak even though economic fundamentals favoured a strengthening.</p>
<p>Investment bank Salomon Brothers said last weeks' crown decline had made an easing of monetary policy less likely.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
