<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="448148" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Highlights of Monday's Commission briefing.</title>
<headline>Highlights of Monday's Commission briefing.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of the midday briefing by the European Commission on Monday:</p>
<p>Spokesman Joao Vale de Almeida said the Commission's midday briefing had been put forward to 1145/1045 GMT instead of 1200/1100 GMT on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Vale de Almeida said Commissioners Padraig Flynn and Mario Monti and the High Level Group for the Free Movement of Persons Chairwoman Simone Veil would hold a joint news conference at 1200/1100 GMT on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Vale de Almeida said European Commissioner Bonino would follow with a news conference on the fisheries promotion campaign.</p>
<p>Spokesman Peter Guilford said the Commission had launched a &quot;Gateway to Japan&quot; promotion campaign for European exports to Japan. He said the campaign aimed to help EU companies market their products and services to Japan principally through trade fairs and trade missions.</p>
<p>Spokeswoman Barbara Nolan said the EU presidency had asked the EU social partners representatives to agree on a social code of conduct in terms of information and consultation in multinational situations before the next formal Social Affairs Council to be held on April 17.</p>
<p>She also said the Commission had accepted the EU Presidency's invitation to examine the impact of Community aid on companies' decisions to invest or disinvest and to examine the possible need for conciliation mechanisms that parties could call on to settle transnational industrial disputes.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>The Commission released the following documents:</p>
<p>- IP/97/225: Commission launches ambitious trade promotion in Japan.</p>
<p>- IP/97/226: EU and South Africa make progress in negotiations for a bilateral agreement.</p>
<p>- IP/97/227: The Commission imposes the dissolution of UIP's Pay-TV distribution joint venture.</p>
<p>- Speech/97/62: Opening speech by Commissioner Joao de Deus Pinheiro at EU/ACP joint assembly.</p>
<p>- Memo/97/27: Madagascar.</p>
<p>- European Social Fund: Employment - NOW: New employment opportunities for women.</p>
<p>- European Social Fund: Employment - YOUTHSTART: New paths to employment for young people.</p>
<p>- European Social Fund: Employment - INTEGRA: Routes to integration and employment for the socially excluded.</p>
<p>- European Social Fund: Employment - HORIZON: Better employment opportunities for people with disabiliies.</p>
<p>- European Social Fund: ADAPT: The future of work, the work of the future.</p>
<p>- CEN - CENELEC - ETSI: European standards - A win-win situation.</p>
<p>- ME97/17.3: Midday Express.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
