<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="448178" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German CDU executive backs Bluem pensions plan.</title>
<headline>German CDU executive backs Bluem pensions plan.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leaders of Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU) on Friday gave their backing to a plan based on Labour Minister Norbert Bluem's proposals to reform Germany's generous state pensions scheme.</p>
<p>Leaders attending a meeting of the CDU executive said there were only two votes against the Bluem proposal, which envisages cutting state pensions to 64 percent of average net wages by 2030 from around 70 percent now.</p>
<p>Those votes went to an alternative, tax-financed &quot;citizens pension&quot; plan proposed by Saxony state premier Kurt Biedenkopf.</p>
<p>The Kohl government is embarking on pensions reform to cope with the &quot;greying&quot; of Germany's 80 million population without letting costs get out of hand.</p>
<p>Under the amended Bluem plan, pension funds will be topped up from 1999 by 15 billion marks a year in tax revenues, which would enable a reduction in pensions contributions which this year reached a record 20.3 percent of wages.</p>
<p>Party leaders had last week rejected Bluem's proposal to set up a tax-financed &quot;family fund&quot; to cover non-welfare items borne by those now paying compulsory pensions contributions.</p>
<p>The CDU will put the pensions reform to a mini-party conference next Wednesday. Legislation will have to wait, however, until a common position has been thrashed out by the three parties in Chancellor Helmut Kohl's ruling coalition.</p>
<p>-- Bonn newsroom, 49-228-26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
