<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="448130" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Minting euro coins to cost Europe 2 bln Ecus.</title>
<headline>Minting euro coins to cost Europe 2 bln Ecus.</headline>
<byline>Nick Antonovics</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Minting the eight euro coins due to replace national coinage after 2002 will cost the European Union's 15 member states the equivalent of two billion Ecus, the director of Belgium's mint said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an approximation. The final cost will depend on the materials used for the coins,&quot; Romen Coenen told Reuters.</p>
<p>Countries participating in monetary union would have to bear the costs themselves. Belgium would have to replace around 2.5 billion coins, he said.</p>
<p>EU finance ministers meet on Monday to finalise the design and metal content of the coins. Their decision is due to be ratified at the EU's Amsterdam Summit in June.</p>
<p>Coenen said some countries, led by Sweden, opposed the use of nickel because it could cause skin allergies.</p>
<p>Costs would also depend on how many new coins are minted. Mint directors believed each country would have to produce 65 percent of the volume of coins outstanding at the end of 1997 in time for the euro's introduction, Coenen said.</p>
<p>They estimated that by then electronic money, such as the Proton card developed by Belgium's banks or the Mondex card developed in Britain, would have replaced around 20 percent of coins in circulation.</p>
<p>&quot;That's an average. It will be higher and lower, depending on the country,&quot; said Coenen.</p>
<p>Mint directors have also estimated 15 percent of outstanding coinage had been irretrievably lost or damaged.</p>
<p>&quot;The 35 percent gives us a margin to play with depending on demand for the euro coins after 2002,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Under an agreement reached by EU leaders at the Madrid Summit in December 1995, euro notes and coins will gradually replace national monies from January 1, 2002 -- three years after European economic and monetary union (EMU) is itself due to start.</p>
<p>New and old currencies are expected to circulate together during a transition period while old money is progressively withdrawn.</p>
<p>Coenen said, however, the whole timetable could be threatened if the countries that are to take part in the first wave of EMU are not chosen by June 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;It's important that each country begins minting the coins by June next year. If we don't start then everything will be in question because we won't be able to meet the deadline,&quot; said Coenen. &quot;The politicians are aware of this.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6817, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
