<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="448107" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German DAX closes bourse weaker as dollar softens.</title>
<headline>German DAX closes bourse weaker as dollar softens.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares closed slightly lower in bourse trade on Monday as the softer dollar meant they were unable to follow the post-bourse rally that occurred on Friday after Wall Street moved to higher levels.</p>
<p>The DAX-30 index of leading German shares closed 8.30 points, or 0.25 percent, down at 3,350.99 in early dealings. The IBIS DAX electronic trading system, on which Friday's rally had materialised, meanwhile lost 54.69 points to 3,349.60.</p>
<p>&quot;There's nothing to trade on at the moment. The dollar is softer but not greatly changed, and Bunds are pretty steady,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>The dollar traded at just under 1.6900 marks throughout bourse trade as speculation grew that Europe's monetary union project would be delayed -- a development seen as positive for the mark.</p>
<p>Some traders saw the risk of some consolidation in the market over the next few days. &quot;Our trading range for the week is between 3,275 and 3,475,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Others noted however that with little going on in the market at the moment, it was difficult to get any meaningful feeling of the current mood among investors.</p>
<p>Chemicals group Henkel fell 2.70 marks to 90.80 trade after reporting an increase in 1996 profits that dealers said was nonetheless under some expectations.</p>
<p>Machinery maker Deutz surged 3.60 marks, a full 28 percent, to 16.60 after reporting that following a wide restructuring its 1996 net profit would likely be above 800 million marks -- compared to the 1.1 billion mark loss of 1995.</p>
<p>Among other notable gainers, tyre-manufacturer Continental rose 1.12 marks, around three percent, to 36.52 after giving details of an improved manufacturing process.</p>
<p>Continental said earlier it had devised a &quot;modular manufacturing process&quot; that will slash inventory and other overhead costs. It said savings could be in the range of 50-70 million marks a year.</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom slipped 40 pfennigs to 36.50. It had earlier said it was making no comment on a British newspaper report that it was considering buying a 14 percent stake in British telecom group Cable &amp; Wireless.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
