<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="448357" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Paris trip unrelated to daughter's - NZ minister.</title>
<headline>Paris trip unrelated to daughter's - NZ minister.</headline>
<dateline>TAURANGA 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Embattled Consumer Affairs Minister Robyn McDonald has confirmed her daughter is about to travel to France but says it has nothing whatever to do with her much-criticised trip to Paris, the New Zealand Press Association reported on Monday.</p>
<p>Rumours have been circulating in McDonald's home town of Katikati that the European trip had coincided with her daughter Amy being enrolled at a Paris finishing school, NZPA said.</p>
<p>But the NZ First list MP described the rumours as rubbish and said she resented her family being dragged into the wrangle.  </p>
<p>McDonald shot into the limelight last week when it was revealed she spent $27,300 of taxpayers' money on first class flights to Paris and London. On Saturday she revealed the full cost of the trip would be in the vicinity of $40,000.</p>
<p>But the MP was adamant the only reason for the trip was to do business on behalf of the New Zealand Government.</p>
<p>&quot;My trip was to work and I spent five days at the conference then flew to London, I didn't have time for anything else while I was there,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>McDonald said her daughter had been invited to stay in a village on the French border on the absolute understanding she took the equivalent of a &quot;pressure-cooker&quot; language course when she was there.</p>
<p>&quot;She was left money for her education in a trust by her godfather and that will fund the trip along with a concession gained through my husband's 25 years' work with Air New Zealand. At the moment though she is still at home.&quot;</p>
<p>As far as the government trip was concerned, McDonald said she had done nothing wrong, had been completely honest about her intentions and now wished the whole thing would go away.  </p>
<p>&quot;The trip was passed by Prime Minister Jim Bolger, Deputy Prime Minister and treasurer Winston Peters and cabinet and I turned down an offer to take my husband because of the cost to the taxpayer.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't need to travel. We travel every year and I've been to Paris and London. I could think of a hundred other places I would rather go with my husband and family,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>McDonald was the only politician on the list of speakers and panelists at the OECD conference she attended in Paris.</p>
<p>Others were senior officials from consumer affairs and commerce agencies.  </p>
<p>Consumer Affairs Ministry general manager Keith Manch, who also attended, was reported at the weekend as saying there were people at the conference with deputy minister titles but these were appointed officials rather than politicians.</p>
<p>He said it was primarily attended by officials but also by a large number of people from the private sector, consumer organisations and non-governmental agencies.</p>
<p>McDonald is also senior citizens minister and earns in the vicinity of $115,000 a year.</p>
<p>She once worked as an international flight attendant.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAURANGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
