<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="448392" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ's Birch says no optimum savings rate set.</title>
<headline>NZ's Birch says no optimum savings rate set.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand government had not determined the ideal rate of savings it would like to see, Finance Minister Bill Birch said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The ideal is as high as you can get it. But we have not addressed an optimum level of savings,&quot; he said, in answer to questions after a speech to the SBC Warburg Investor Group.</p>
<p>The coalition government will hold a referendum in September on the introduction of compulsory retirement savings. A group of officials are designing the scheme which, if approved, would be implemented in July 1998.  </p>
<p>The coalition agreement between the conservative National Party and the nationalist New Zealand First aimed to increase New Zealand's national savings rate.</p>
<p>The most recent statistics available show household savings were 5.2 percent of disposable income in 1995.</p>
<p>Asked to explain New Zealand's low level of savings, Birch said it was partly due to the way it was measured (with New Zealanders having a high level of home ownership) and partly due to the environment.  </p>
<p>&quot;Public provision of retirement income may be sending the wrong signals and that is something we should look at as we develop the referendum,&quot; Birch said.</p>
<p>&quot;What I am totally convinced of is that offering tax incentives is not a good way to encourage savings.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the high level of overseas ownership of government debt issues was a vote of confidence by international investors and also reflected New Zealanders' willingness to invest offshore. -- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
