<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="448643" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan stocks surge yet again to 6-year high close.</title>
<headline>Taiwan stocks surge yet again to 6-year high close.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan share prices surged through resistance at 8,400 points on Monday to yet another six-year high, though some brokers warned of growing technical vulnerability in the liquidity-driven rally.</p>
<p>The weighted index advanced 135.11 points or 1.63 percent to close at its intra-day high of 8,426.42.</p>
<p>Monday's close surpassed the 8,291.31 finish on March 15 to marked the index's highest close since it reached 8,569.55 on May 15, 1990. Turnover was a sizzling T$176.88 billion.</p>
<p>Blue chip electronics jumped 2.99 percent while the plastics sector gained 2.29 percent gain.  </p>
<p>&quot;Today's sharp gains show investors are confident that the market's bull run will continue. It means very little to tell them where the peak is,&quot; said Joe Chiou, a Taiwan Securities Investment analyst who feels the index has more room to rise.</p>
<p>Some brokers had expected the index to consolidate at 8,400, questioning whether the long rise reflected fundamental value.</p>
<p>&quot;This is nothing but a liquidity-driven rally. Money is abundant and people are always looking for their next target,&quot; Chen Han-chung of Yungli Securities said.</p>
<p>Ben Lee of Nomura Securities was cautious. &quot;Technically it is time for a correction,&quot; Lee said.  </p>
<p>The index has risen an impressive 23.5 percent in 1997, making it one of the best performing markets in the world.</p>
<p>Monday's close also represented a 70.5 percent rise compared with a year ago, when rival China was mounting war games and missile tests near Taiwan during the island's March 1996 direct presidential election in a bid to intimidate Taiwan voters not to drop an official pledge to reunify with the mainland.</p>
<p>High-technology shares remained the market's stars, with semiconductor maker United Microelectronics up by the daily seven percent limit to T$54.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
