<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="448818" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Argentina to tap int'l mkts for $1.5 bln in Q2.</title>
<headline>Argentina to tap int'l mkts for $1.5 bln in Q2.</headline>
<dateline>BARCELONA, Spain 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Undersecretary of Finance Miguel Kiguel said on Monday Argentina would seek to raise about $1.5 billion in new financing on international markets during the second quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>On the domestic side, Argentina would try to raise between $500 million and $1.0 billion in the second quarter and introduce a five-year dollar-denominated BONTE Treasury bond.</p>
<p>Kiguel, speaking to reporters on the fringes of the annual meeting of the Inter-American Development Bank, said Argentina would only tap the markets after they calmed down from recent upsets.</p>
<p>&quot;We won't go out before the markets stabilise,&quot; Kiguel said.  </p>
<p>Kiguel said that if Argentina meets its second-quarter targets, it will have completed 70 percent of its $8.5 billion foreign borrowing programme for 1997 and nearly half of its $3.5 billion domestic borrowing programme.</p>
<p>Argentina, which has been keen on diversifying into other foreign currencies for its debt issuance, could turn to European markets such as the peseta or lira as well as to the yen market.</p>
<p>Kiguel said that each individual issue could be for between $150 million and $300 million for terms of between seven and ten years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BARCELONA, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
