<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="448859" id="root" date="1997-03-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: PRESS DIGEST - France - March 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - France - March 17.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are leading stories in this morning's Paris newspapers.</p>
<p>LES ECHOS</p>
<p>-- Foreign trade Minister Yves Galland explains in interview reform of public works contracts designed to simplify tenders and choice of suppliers and curtail bribery.</p>
<p>-- Bollore Technologies chairman Vincent Bollore reaffirms committment to keeping subsidiary Delmas despite rumours.</p>
<p>LA TRIBUNE</p>
<p>-- Over 50,000 people demonstrated in Brussels on Sunday against planned shut-down of a Renault assembly plant in Belgium.</p>
<p>-- Credit Mutuel chairman Etienne Pflimlin says in interview banks with a mutual status provide return on equity in line with other banks, and calls for a restructuring of the state-owned sector.</p>
<p>-- Credit Lyonnais earned 1.2 billion francs, pre-tax for 1996 on financial market activities.</p>
<p>-- Matra does not rule out a partnership with Cie des Signaux, Dasa or Aerospatiale ahead of bid for Thomson-CSF, which is being privatised.</p>
<p>-- State-owned insurer CNP seeks to sort out labour conflict this week. State recapitalisation not ruled out ahead of stock-exchange listing.</p>
<p>LE FIGARO-ECONOMIE</p>
<p>-- Caisse des Depots managing director Philippe Lagayette to continue modernisation process, seek some internationalisation.</p>
<p>LIBERATION (Economic section)</p>
<p>-- European Renault workers unite for jobs.</p>
<p>THE INTERNATIONAL HERALD TRIBUNE</p>
<p>-- EU refuses to send troops to Albania, approves small unit of advisers.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5381</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
