<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="448971" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cuban exiles say CNN is the &quot;Castro News Network&quot;.</title>
<headline>Cuban exiles say CNN is the &quot;Castro News Network&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Zengerle</byline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Miami's Cuban exile community criticized CNN's debut broadcast from Cuba on Tuesday, saying it was impossible for the U.S. cable television network to present a balanced view from the Communist-ruled island.</p>
<p>Miami radio listeners quickly passed judgment, labelling CNN the &quot;Castro News Network.&quot;</p>
<p>Telephone lines at Spanish-language stations were jammed by critical callers almost as soon as the broadcast began on Monday evening with a live report from Havana.</p>
<p>Cuban-Americans said Cable News Network might intend to provide balanced coverage of Cuban politics, but would inevitably be used by President Fidel Castro's government to support its agenda.</p>
<p>Ninoska Perez, host of a Spanish-language radio broadcast and a spokeswoman for the staunchly anti-Castro Cuban-American National Foundation, questioned why CNN had not put Cuban dissidents on the air during its initial broadcast.</p>
<p>The bureau opened by CNN correspondent Lucia Newman is the first permanent office of a U.S. media outlet in Cuba in 28 years.</p>
<p>&quot;She showed yesterday a little kid with the typical communist propaganda ... but why didn't she mention that same kid gets a ration card ... they can only get milk up to (age) seven years? That's the kind of thing that would really reflect the kind of country that Cuba is,&quot; Perez said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's too early to tell how accurate they are going to be ... If they are balanced, it is going to be great,&quot; said Jaime Suchliki, a professor of Latin American history at the University of Miami.</p>
<p>But, he added: &quot;I also think the Cuban people should be allowed to see it.&quot;</p>
<p>For the U.S. government, allowing CNN to open a bureau in Cuba was not enough to establish a free flow of information.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no press freedom at all,&quot; Assistant Secretary of State for Inter-American Affairs Jeffrey Davidow said at an international press freedom conference in Panama City.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that Castro still intends to limit the number of foreign media and prevent international media from distributing information within Cuba itself is a testament to the Cuban government's fear of a free press,&quot; Davidow said on Monday after the CNN broadcast.</p>
<p>Cuba gave CNN, an Atlanta-based division of Time Warner Inc., permission to open a bureau in November. CNN is the first U.S. news organization with a permanent bureau on the Communist-ruled island since 1969.</p>
<p>The Clinton administration also granted permission to nine other U.S. news organizations to apply to operate in Cuba, but only CNN has been authorized by the Cuban government so far.</p>
<p>The other media are ABC, CBS, Univision, the Miami Herald, Dow Jones News Services, Cuba Info, the Chicago Tribune and the Sun-Sentinel of Fort Lauderdale, Florida.</p>
<p>Cuban news organizations are barred from having bureaux in the United States, which last year stiffened its long-standing economic embargo against Cuba.</p>
<p>Non-U.S. media have been allowed to operate in Cuba for many years, including Reuters, Agence-France Presse, Notimex, EFE, El Pais, the Financial Times of London and the British Broadcasting Corp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
