<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="448970" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: School-based health centers expanding.</title>
<headline>School-based health centers expanding.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>More communities are establishing school-based health centers, part of a trend to increase children's access to basic medical care, a study found Tuesday.</p>
<p>The number of school-based centers rose by more than 50 percent in two years and now surpasses 900, according to the Making the Grade program, which works on developing such centers. The program is funded by the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation and administered by George Washington University.</p>
<p>Taking school-based care well beyond the traditional school nurse, the health centers on school property provide an array of on-site medical and mental health services.</p>
<p>&quot;School-based health centers have been endorsed by community leaders, educators, public officials and health care providers,&quot; Making the Grade director Julia Lear said.</p>
<p>&quot;I suspect that what we're reporting today is only the first wave of a dramatic upsurge in making health care more accessible for children,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Most of the centers are paid for with state and local funds, but in some cases local hospitals and insurance companies are chipping in because community-based care can keep children out of costly emergency rooms.</p>
<p>For instance, in Florida the North Broward Hospital District is sponsoring 10 school centers. &quot;We've found that the uninsured and underinsured populations in our county are growing much faster than our ability to keep up with their acute care needs,&quot; said hospital district chief executive officer Will Trower.</p>
<p>&quot;We've created school-based health centers to allow us to deliver more primary and preventive care and keep kids out of emergency rooms,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
