<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="448980" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Judge clears way for Orange County suit vs. S&amp;P.</title>
<headline>Judge clears way for Orange County suit vs. S&amp;P.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA ANA, Calif. 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A federal judge refused on Tuesday to throw out Orange County, Calif.,'s $500 million lawsuit against Standard &amp; Poor's Corp in a ruling that could limit the rating agency's ability to use the First Amendment as a legal defense, county attorneys said.</p>
<p>In a split decision, U.S. District Judge Gary Taylor in Santa Ana affirmed the bankruptcy court's denial of S&amp;P's motion to dismiss the county's claim for breach of contract.</p>
<p>&quot;The county has adequately pled a breach of contract action not governed by the First Amendment's actual malice standard,&quot; Taylor said in the written decision.  </p>
<p>The judge, on the other hand, dismissed the county's professional negligence cause of action, but told the county it could refile the claim. County attorney Michael Swartz said the county planned to re-plead that claim in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;The county is very pleased,&quot; Swartz said of the ruling. &quot;It clears the way for the lawsuit to proceed.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that Taylor's decision on the breach of contract claim would limit the ability of the rating agency to assert First Amendment protections as a defense in the lawsuit.</p>
<p>S&amp;P declined to comment on the ruling.  </p>
<p>&quot;We've received the ruling and are reviewing it and our options,&quot; an S&amp;P spokeswoman in New York said.</p>
<p>Orange County filed for protection under Chapter 9 of the Federal Bankruptcy Code in December 1994 after sustaining investment losses of more than $1.6 billion. The southern California county emerged from bankruptcy last June.</p>
<p>But just before the unprecedented bankruptcy came to an end, the county sued McGraw-Hill Cos Inc's S&amp;P unit in U.S. Bankruptcy Court, alleging breach of contract and professional negligence. The county lawsuit seeks $500 million.  </p>
<p>The lawsuit alleged that S&amp;P's ratings had assured the county and the public that former county Treasurer Robert Citron was &quot;conservatively and safely&quot; managing county funds.</p>
<p>Last August, S&amp;P filed court papers seeking dismissal of the county claims in the suit on the grounds that its credit ratings were protected by the First Amendment.</p>
<p>In December, the bankruptcy court rejected S&amp;P's motion to dismiss the lawsuit. The bankruptcy court judge said S&amp;P's &quot;broad-based argument for dismissal of the complaint based on alleged First Amendment protections is without merit.&quot;  </p>
<p>S&amp;P appealed to the District Court, where most of the county's bankruptcy-related lawsuits are now being heard.</p>
<p>In Tuesday's ruling, Taylor affirmed the bankruptcy court decision in part by upholding its denial of the motion to dismiss the breach of contract claims.</p>
<p>&quot;The county argues correctly S&amp;P is not entitled to heightened First Amendment protection simply because of its status as a financial publisher,&quot; Taylor wrote.</p>
<p>Taylor, however, reversed the bankruptcy court's professional negligence decision.  </p>
<p>The county argued that its professional negligence claim stems from services S&amp;P provided in its capacity as a financial analyst.</p>
<p>But Taylor said the &quot;complaint fails to distinguish between S&amp;P's activities as an advisor to the county and its constitutionally protected expression.&quot;</p>
<p>Taylor gave the county 20 days to amend its professional negligence claim.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA ANA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
