<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449090" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Barshefsky urges compromise on trade legislation.</title>
<headline>Barshefsky urges compromise on trade legislation.</headline>
<byline>Donna Smith</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky said Tuesday that trade negotiation legislation should not be derailed by a dispute over labor and environmental issues and urged lawmakers to compromise.</p>
<p>&quot;We simply have to forge a consensus on this subject which eluded us in 1994 and 1995,&quot; Barshefsky told the House Ways and Means trade subcommittee. &quot;I have been consulting broadly with members of Congress, business, labor and environmental groups and will continue to do so.&quot;</p>
<p>So-called fast-track trade legislation would allow U.S. trade officials to negotiate an expansion of the North American Free Trade Agreement to include Chile and other trade deals without fear they will later be changed by Congress.</p>
<p>An effort to win fast-track authority from Congress faltered in late 1995 after the White House and Republican-led Congress failed to agree on authority to negotiate labor and environmental issues.</p>
<p>Barshefsky expressed concern that fast-track legislation would be lost in a larger debate over NAFTA and whether Americans were benefitting from the deal that joins Mexico, Canada and the United States in a trading bloc.</p>
<p>Failure to enact such legislation would hand America's global trade competitors a major victory, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our competitors would like nothing better than for us to sideline ourselves, debating NAFTA and our relationship with Mexico for several more years while they move ahead,&quot; she said. &quot;It would be a serious, self-inflicted wound.&quot;</p>
<p>Critics of NAFTA have voiced concern about expanding the agreement to include Chile before fixing what they see are problems with the trade pact.</p>
<p>Barshefsky said the focus of the debate should be on global trade and not problems between the United States and Mexico that are due to sharing a common border.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of the issues in the Mexico debate relate to our shared and unique border,&quot; Barshefsky said. &quot;They do not address the need to seize the trillions of dollars in global infrastructure opportunities in Asia to be created in the next decade. They do not give us the tools to continue cutting European agricultural subsidies.&quot;</p>
<p>She argued that while U.S. lawmakers argued the virtues of free trade and fast track legislation, trade competitors were forming new alliances and moving quickly into South American markets.</p>
<p>&quot;In this post cold war economy, countries are creating exclusive trade alliances to the potential detriment of U.S. prosperity and leadership,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Barshefsky said that China is making a big push for trade with Latin America to make sure that key countries are &quot;receptive to its broader global agenda as a rising power&quot; in the World Trade Organization and other global organizations.</p>
<p>She said Japan has also undertaken high level efforts to enhance commercial ties with Latin America.</p>
<p>But while Barshefsky urged lawmakers to enact fast track legislation, she said the administration was not yet ready to unveil its own proposed bill. She told the panel that administration officials were continuing negotiations with members of Congress on a proposed bill.</p>
<p>She told reporters after the hearing that the administration hoped to get proposed legislation to Congress relatively soon.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it's months away, I think we are looking at a shorter time frame than that,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
