<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449176" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Republicans say separate tax bill possible.</title>
<headline>U.S. Republicans say separate tax bill possible.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senate and House Republican leaders said Tuesday they are committed to a tax cut but differ on the process that will be used to reach their goal and whether it will be included as part of the overall effort to balance the budget.</p>
<p>Speaking to reporters after an hour-long private meeting, they said it was possible a tax cut measure could be brought up separately from the spending cuts and policy changes for the rest of government required to reach a balanced budget by 2002.  </p>
<p>Asked by reporters if a tax bill could be considered separately after Congress passes legislation to balance the budget, Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott replied this was one of the alternatives open.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a number of options and that is one option that we will certainly consider,&quot; Lott said.</p>
<p>Lott appeared at a news conference with House Speaker Newt Gingrich, Republican of Georgia, and other House and Senate Republican leaders.</p>
<p>The Republicans again called on President Clinton to submit a revised balanced budget. &quot;We have been trying now to get a balanced budget plan the president promised,&quot; Gingrich said. &quot;There is no leadership,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Asked if he agreed with Gingrich that tax cuts should be put off until the budget is balanced, Lott said they were in agreement that tax relief is needed for American families and that tax changes could provide help for the economy. &quot;The process of how we get there is something we are still looking at,&quot; Lott of Mississippi said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
