<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449214" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: BOXING-GERMAN ROCCHIGIANI USED BANNED DRUG IN TITLE BOUT.</title>
<headline>BOXING-GERMAN ROCCHIGIANI USED BANNED DRUG IN TITLE BOUT.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>German boxer Graciano Rocchigiani tested positive for a banned drug when he lost to compatriot Dariusz Michalczewski in a controversial World Boxing Organisation (WBO) light-heavyweight title bout last August, German doping officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Traces of the banned stimulant ephedrine were found in Rocchigiani's urine after the fight in Hamburg on August 10, said Wilhelm Schaenzer, head of Cologne's respected drug-testing laboratory.</p>
<p>Rocchigiani, who is due to fight American John Scully in a non-title fight in Berlin on Saturday, faces a possible three-month ban.</p>
<p>But Schaenzer was very critical of the way boxing authorities had handled the affair since the B-test -- the second examination of the urine which is used to confirm the presence of the drug -- has yet to be analysed.</p>
<p>&quot;The B-test has to be concluded within three months. I told the German professional boxing association (BDB) about the test with plenty of time,&quot; Schaenzer told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;When I asked about it again they told me it was with the international federation.&quot;</p>
<p>BDB officials were not immediately available to comment on the affair on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Rocchigiani was angry with the fight verdict and lodged an appeal after the bout ended in confusion.</p>
<p>Rocchiagiani, clearly ahead on points, landed a left hook which floored his fellow German in the seventh round, but the blow came after the referee had ordered the pair to break.</p>
<p>Rocchigiani said he did not hear the instruction. After 15 minutes of consultations, WBO officials declared Michalczewski the winner, to jeers and whistles from the crowd.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
