<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449584" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: White S.African farmers campaign against crime.</title>
<headline>White S.African farmers campaign against crime.</headline>
<byline>Juliette Saunders</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>White South African farmers on Tuesday took to the country's roadways to protest against crime and promised to carry their &quot;nice warning&quot; further if President Nelson Mandela's government does not act.</p>
<p>Disrupting traffic with slow processions in trucks and tractors along main routes countrywide, several hundred disgruntled farmers converged around towns and cities calling mainly for a government clampdown against crime in rural areas.</p>
<p>&quot;We are really tired of attacks not only against farmers but all assaults against (black) rural communities -- I think the whole country is tired of criminals,&quot; Pieter Gous, president of a provincial farmers' union, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a tiny little pinprick. It is a small warning, a nice warning, to government: please act. Otherwise we will go to the next step. Every time it will be a little more disruptive,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At least 70 farmers were killed last year in hundreds of attacks on farms and smallholdings throughout the country and farmers' unions say the unending wave of attacks has led to despair among rural communities.</p>
<p>A new militancy has become evident in particularly hard-hit areas such as the Free State region where white farmers have threatened to institute &quot;rough justice&quot;. Officials were reported as saying this meant hanging murderers and rapists from trees.</p>
<p>In KwaZulu-Natal, the Zulu heartland where whites mostly farm sugar cane as well as cattle, timber and maize, farmers outraged by a weekend assault on a local family have vowed to &quot;kneecap&quot; two suspected attackers and to withhold their taxes.</p>
<p>Maxwell Mulaudzi, a spokesman for South African police minister Sydney Mufamadi, told Reuters farmers should not be tempted to take the law into their own hands.</p>
<p>&quot;It is unacceptable to take to vigilanteeism. Government is spending 1.2 billion rand ($271 million) just on crime prevention this year. It's not a just a question of saying we are dealing with crime. Resources have been dedicated to deal with the problem.&quot;</p>
<p>Gous said Tuesday's street protests were also aimed at government policies towards commercial farming and the recent scrapping of a diesel fuel levy for farmers.</p>
<p>&quot;Government is totally, totally unsympathetic. Commercial farming is getting zero support from government -- not even moral support,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mandela's land affairs and agricultural minister, Derek Hanekom, who has previously chided farmers for their objections to planned laws on land tenure, told a news briefing in Cape Town that the farmers would achieve nothing with their protest.</p>
<p>&quot;While one doesn't want to dismiss these issues... if the protest action causes public inconvenience then I don't think this is an effective action to obtain greater public sympathy or government sympathy,&quot; Hanekom told reporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
