<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449534" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada's once mighty Conservatives seek revival.</title>
<headline>Canada's once mighty Conservatives seek revival.</headline>
<byline>Paul Simao</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's once powerful Conservative Party unveiled on Tuesday a platform of tax cuts, job creation and a balanced budget in a bid to emerge from the political doldrums in an election expected this year.</p>
<p>Conservative leader Jean Charest told a media briefing that he would fight the election -- which could be held as early as June -- on the key issues of jobs and taxes.</p>
<p>He pledged to cut income taxes by 10 percent, reduce unemployment insurance premiums by C$5 billion ($3.64 billion) and create one million jobs by the year 2005.</p>
<p>Charest, a 38-year-old Quebecker, was one of only two Conservatives returned to Parliament in the last election in 1993 when the Conservatives were crushed after nine years in office.</p>
<p>The Conservatives won 168 of 295 House of Commons seats in the 1988 election under Brian Mulroney. But years of unpopular economic policies and the failure to resolve a constitutional dispute with French-speaking Quebec eventually made Mulroney one of Canada's most reviled leaders ever.</p>
<p>Charest was a minister under Mulroney and Kim Campbell, Canada's first female prime minister, who served briefly as Conservative leader before leading the party to defeat.</p>
<p>Charest's proclaimed election platform drew quick fire from the Reform Party, the larger of Canada's two right-wing parties and from Liberal Finance Minister Paul Martin.</p>
<p>&quot;It simply doesn't add up,&quot; Martin said in Ottawa.</p>
<p>&quot;It's simply not possible to cut taxes by a massive amount such as they are suggesting, transfer tax points to the provinces...and at the same time balance the budget, without something giving,&quot; Martin said.</p>
<p>Reform leader Preston Manning questioned Charest's credibility and described the platform as &quot;warmed-over Mulroney baloney.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The Tories had nine years in government to deliver on their promise of jobs, balanced budgets, tax cuts and a revitalized federation,&quot; Manning told business leaders in the southern Ontario city of Oshawa.</p>
<p>He asserted that Reform's platform of balancing the federal budget before cutting taxes was more credible than Charest's economic program.</p>
<p>Reform holds all but one of its 50 seats in Western Canada, a former Conservative stronghold.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
