<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449526" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks end lower as bank issues weaken.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks end lower as bank issues weaken.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>CHANGE				    CHANGE</p>
<p>TSE	  6129.28    -25.26   HI 6153.33	    LO  6126.60</p>
<p>DJI	  6938.11    -17.37   GOLD (LONDON)   US$346.30 -5.10</p>
<p>FTSE100    4356.80    -16.50   GOLD (NY-COMEX) US$350.10 +2.10</p>
<p>NIKKEI    18445.20   +391.70   LME CASH NICKEL US$7774  -246.0</p>
<p>CANDLR	1.3731		 LME CASH ALUM   US$1609.0 -31.0</p>
<p>CAN 30-YR   108.80     -0.50   BRENT CRUDE     US$20.28  +0.75</p>
<p>--------------------MARKET COMMENT----------------------------</p>
<p>* Toronto stocks closed lower on Tuesday, dragged down by a weaker Wall Street and falling bank issues. * Eye on U.S. consumer price index numbers due out on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Toronto stocks ended weaker in brisk turnover on Tuesday, pulled down by weakness on Wall Street and a tumbling financial sector.</p>
<p>The Toronto Stock Exchange's key 300 Composite Index lost 25.26 points to 6129.28. Trading was active as 106.6 million shares worth C$1.8 billion changed hands.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones Industrial Average fell 58.92 points to 6896.56 and Canada's banking group dropped almost one percent.</p>
<p>Montreal-based portfolio consultant Ron Meisels said Toronto's market had traded in a narrow range recently as investors debated a possible hike in U.S. interest rates.  </p>
<p>Once rates go up, bond yields increase and bond prices drop, attracting investors who then sell interest-sensitive issues such as banks. The bearish players believe rates will rise, while others think Canada's key index will sustain only a temporary setback before resuming its upward march.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel there has been a constant fight recently between the bulls and the bears,&quot; Meisels said. He forecast Toronto would soon reverse its downward trend as investors hunted for bargains.</p>
<p>Of Toronto's 14 sub-indices, nine fell, led by consumer products, base metals, banks and transports. Gaining groups included conglomerates, oils and golds.</p>
<p>Declining stocks outnumbered advances 561 to 397, while 299 traded unchanged.</p>
<p>-- HOT STOCKS --</p>
<p>* Wascana Energy Inc topped Toronto actives after Tuesday's news that Canadian Occidental Petroleum Ltd said it planned a C$20.50 share all-cash bid for Wascana. Wascana jumped 1.10 to 20.45 on 15.8 million shares and Canadian Occidental rose 1.70 to 25.15.</p>
<p>Wascana was seeking a white knight after a hostile bid from Talisman Energy Inc.</p>
<p>((Lydia Zajc, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
