<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449676" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria lev closes flat after rangebound trade.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria lev closes flat after rangebound trade.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bulgarian lev closed at 1,580-1,590 per dollar in thin interbank volume, little changed from 1,580-1,600 at the opening and flat on the previous close as dollar demand and supply were balanced, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Trade was lacklustre and rangebound throughout the day. The lev closes virtually unchanged from the opening,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Dollar supply came mainly from final clients aiming to improve lev liquidity under expectations of ongoing lev stability following a financial accord with the International Monetary Fund (IMF), traders said.</p>
<p>The central bank was seen buying dollars to boost its forex reserves ahead of the introduction of a tough fixed exchange rate mechanism, the currency board, and to prevent sharp lev gains amid the increased dollar supply, dealers said.</p>
<p>Central bank officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>The interim government and the IMF mission on Monday said they had reached an accord under which Bulgaria is to receive around $650 million to stabilise its shattered economy over the next year.</p>
<p>The IMF mission for Bulgaria leader Anne McGuirk said on Monday a currency board system would be introduced in June to restore confidence in the lev.</p>
<p>-- Anastas Petrov, Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 981 8569</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
