<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449697" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech shares edge lower but upward correction seen.</title>
<headline>Czech shares edge lower but upward correction seen.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech PX50 fell further on Tuesday edging ever closer to the psychologically important 550 mark where dealers say they expect to see stronger support.</p>
<p>The PX50 fell 5.1 points, 0.91 percent, to 553.3 while the RPIX fell 14.2 points, 1.22 percent, to 1,148.1.</p>
<p>Once again the major issues were at the forefront of the decline but dealers said they were beginning to look cheap and some predicted an upward correction later in the week.</p>
<p>&quot;All the blue chips look very attractive...they look very cheap,&quot; said Radim Bajgar of ING Barings. &quot;I definitely think the PX50 will get pretty good support around 550,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Although the index's most heavily capitalised share SPT Telecom lost 41 crowns to 3,399 on the bourse, Bajgar said that there had been more demand on the over-the-counter market where it was trading around 3,385/3,415.</p>
<p>&quot;Gradually during the day, I saw some demand for SPT and there arose some demand for CEZ,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Power utility CEZ, which is the second most heavily weighted share on the PX50, closed down nine crowns to 1,031.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
