<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449628" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa urged to step up import control.</title>
<headline>S.Africa urged to step up import control.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa should cut back on its international airports and border posts if it wanted to combat smuggling and customs duty evasion, South African Revenue Services commissioner Trevor van Heerden said on Monday.</p>
<p>Briefing the parliamentary finance committee, Van Heerden said South Africa currently had 35 so-called international airports and more than 100 border posts.</p>
<p>SARS had recommended that these be reduced to a maximum of 10 international airports and between 16 and 17 border posts &quot;so that we can properly control the flow of goods into the country&quot;.</p>
<p>About 87 percent of all trade flowed in and out of the 16 to 17 border posts.</p>
<p>Van Heerden said that SARS was liaising with officials from neighbouring states, business organisations and other government departments to ensure that the closure of some border posts would not disrupt commercial traffic.</p>
<p>He said that British and American officials had been helping upgrade the customs and excise division, which had been neglected for many years.</p>
<p>The percentage of cargo that was physically examined had risen to three percent from 1.5 percent, compared to the international norm of five percent.</p>
<p>SARS chief executive Piet Liebenberg said that the scanners that it had been planned to use in international airports to check imports had proved to be too sophisticated for the department to use until it was substantially upgraded. Discussions would again be held with the French suppliers later this year.</p>
<p>Van Heerden said that the cuts in ad valorem duties announced in the budget would help reduce smuggling and fraud, especially involving consumer items such as radios and cameras.</p>
<p>He said that the department was considering the introduction of minimum values which would be used as guidelines in the clearance of goods.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment people are bringing in electrical goods at absolutely ridiculous prices (to minimise customs duty),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>SARS would first target electrical goods, followed by textiles. Industry sources had indicated that up to 95 percent of electrical goods brought into the country were either smuggled in or drastically under-declared, he said.</p>
<p>Van Heerden said that customs officials had recently made several seizures of smuggled goods, mainly clothing, which would be put out to tender on the condition that they were not sold locally.</p>
<p>-- Parliamentary office +27 21 403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
