<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449731" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: High-caps send Bucharest bourse turnover higher.</title>
<headline>High-caps send Bucharest bourse turnover higher.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Orders which accumulated over the weekend doubled turnover on the Bucharest stock exchange to 2.3 billion lei on Tuesday.</p>
<p>First-tier stocks Azomures SA fertiliser maker and chemical plant Oltchim SA dominated trading, taking a combined 92 percent of turnover and seeing price rises in strong buying interest.</p>
<p>&quot;Interest was on the heavyweights as usual, with greater emphasis on Oltchim,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Azomures had 582.7 million lei in turnover and closed 50 lei stronger at 1,250. Oltchim traded more than 1.0 million shares on turnover of 1.5 billion lei and put on 230 lei to end the day at 1,330.</p>
<p>Demand for the other shares was light, with four stocks having no trade.</p>
<p>Policolor SA dye maker concentrated some investor interest, scoring a turnover level of some 57 million, but it inched down 10 lei to close at 1,280.</p>
<p>Two unofficial indices -- the VAB and the BIG -- rose from the previous session by 7.13 percent and respectively 6.98 percent.</p>
<p>Bucharest Investment Group brokerage house, which computes the BIG, said it had started compiling an index for the first tier, called BIG-first tier, since the higher listing category opened late in January.</p>
<p>That index, released for the first time on Tuesday, was 1,389.02 points, some 10 percent up on the previous session. Its base is 1,000 points.</p>
<p>		Mar 18  Mar 13  Week's change  1997 high   1997 low</p>
<p> VAB-Index  438.3   409.1    +4.9 pct	   555.9	262.0</p>
<p> BIG-Index  449.48  420.15   +3.6 pct	   557.56     266.43</p>
<p>-- Luli Popescu, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
