<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449728" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Finance Minister Livshits heads back to Kremlin.</title>
<headline>Finance Minister Livshits heads back to Kremlin.</headline>
<byline>Julie Tolkacheva</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alexander Livshits, dropped this week by President Boris Yeltsin as Finance Minister, fell victim to the non-payments crisis choking the Russian economy.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, facing growing social discontent over unpaid wages, installed his top aide and former privatisation chief Anatoly Chubais as Finance Minister and first deputy premier in charge of the economy in a new cabinet charged with carrying out thorough reforms to revitalise the economy.</p>
<p>Livshits moves back to the Kremlin as deputy head of Yeltsin's administration, Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Livshits, 50, moved to the Kremlin in 1992 as part of a team of young reformers around former Prime Minister Yegor Gaidar.</p>
<p>He became Yeltsin's chief financial adviser in 1994 and was appointed Finance Minister and Deputy Prime Minister after Yeltsin won last summer's presidential election.</p>
<p>He proved himself a close ally of Yeltsin, giving almost daily news conferences about the government's plans to pay off wage and pension arrears during the election campaign.</p>
<p>The wage arrears are part of a vicious circle, in which companies do not pay each other's bills, salaries or taxes and pension contributions to the government, while the government does not pay wages and pay company bills.</p>
<p>Non-payment of wages become a major issue in last year's presidential election, and Livshits spearheaded a campaign to pay them off.</p>
<p>But they have built up again. At the end of February they totalled 50.24 trillion roubles ($8.9 billion), with 10.33 trillion owed by the government.</p>
<p>By December tax arrears had reached 70.5 trillion roubles.</p>
<p>But Livshits also presided over Russia's successful return to international capital markets, with a heavily oversubscribed debut Eurobond last November, and a mark Eurobond this month.</p>
<p>The owlish, bespectacled Livshits was one of the few members of the cabinet with an evident sense of humour, and his relaxed, smiling manner contrasts strongly with the wooden or pugnacious style affected by other Russian politicians.</p>
<p>In one television interview he produced a toy parrot acquired on a recent foreign trip, which could be programmed to repeat a message. Livshits said he would install it in his office to cackle &quot;There is no money&quot; at his visitors.</p>
<p>Livshits, who studied mathematics and economics at the prestigious Moscow Economics Institute, wrote his thesis on former U.S. President Ronald Reagan's economic policies.</p>
<p>He is married with two daughters and one grandaughter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
