<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449759" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Economists doubt Russian GDP figures.</title>
<headline>Economists doubt Russian GDP figures.</headline>
<byline>Julie Tolkacheva</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Official Russian figures show that the economy has started to recover from a seven-year slump but economists said on Tuesday that government statistics may be over-optimistic.</p>
<p>The State Statistics Committee (Goskomstat) said on Monday gross domestic product and industrial output had grown in February year-on-year for the second month running, with GDP up 0.9 percent in February after 0.1 percent in January.</p>
<p>If the trend continues it would end the recession which started in 1990 and has seen Russia's economy contract to less than two thirds of its size in 1991 when the Soviet Union fell apart.</p>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin, faced with growing social discontent about unpaid wages and pensions, promised this month that the economy would grow by up to two percent this year.</p>
<p>He has put a group of dynamic young liberal reformists led by former privatisation tsar Anatoly Chubais and Nizhny Novgorod governor Boris Nemtsov into a new cabinet charged with carrying out economic reforms which can deliver sustainable high growth.</p>
<p>The World Bank, in a report issued on Monday, said Russia could hope for annual growth rates in the medium term of six percent, although it forecast zero growth this year and two percent growth only in 1998.</p>
<p>By the end of last year the Russian economy had reached levels last seen in 1979.</p>
<p>But independent economists doubt that the economy is now growing as strongly as Goskomstat says or officials forecast.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy is growing,&quot; Al Breach, an economist with the Russian-European Centre for Economic Policy told Reuters. &quot;It bottomed out in the middle of last year, but the actual growth rates quoted now are dubious.&quot;</p>
<p>Another economist, who asked not to be named, said the growth figures published so far this year reflected changes in Goskomstat's methodology.</p>
<p>Goskomstat had revised its estimate of the share of the untaxed shadow or black economy in total GDP to 25 percent from 20 percent, he said.</p>
<p>While Goskomstat was wise to incorporate estimates for the black economy, it should not have increased the estimate so sharply and should have publicised the change, he said.</p>
<p>Alexei Ponomarenko, deputy head of Goskomstat's national accounts department, said the committee had not made major changes to its methods.</p>
<p>&quot;There were no fundamental changes,&quot; he said. &quot;There were some trifling ones, but they did not account for the growth.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the shadow economy was taken into account when calculating production in different sectors and suggested that maybe the size of the black economy had been increased there.</p>
<p>Troika Dialog chief economist Pavel Teplukhin said Goskomstat's former methodology had failed to take full account of the shadow economy.</p>
<p>But the committee should have re-calculated 1996 figures using the new methodology to make them comparable.</p>
<p>If that had been done the economy so far would be showing zero growth, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
