<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449797" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - March 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - March 18.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Croatian newspapers on Tuesday.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- U.N. administrator of Eastern Slavonia Jacques Klein hands over to local Serbs a list of 150 suspected war criminals put together by the Croatian government.</p>
<p>- INA oil company leaves behind in Albania several million dollars worth of equipment. Will the armed guards be able to protect it?</p>
<p>- Jacques Klein: The way Tudjman sees it, the Serbs are guaranteed their safety in the Croatian Danube region and thus can remain in the area.</p>
<p>- Economy minister Davor Stern expects foreign investment to double in 1997 from $280 million it totalled in 1996.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- Schools in Eastern Slavonia to coordinate their work with the rest of the country in autumn.</p>
<p>- State statistics bureau estimates the 1996 gross domestic product (GDP) at $18.8 billion although the final figure will be available in a month, says its head Ivan Rusan.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- Small businesses to be loaned 20 million marks through new Zagrebacka Banka credit lines.</p>
<p>- Austrian investor INB interested in buying a 51-percent stake in Dubrovnik's war-damaged hotel Belvedere, which would also require a 39 million mark investment into its rebuilding. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
