<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449807" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: FEATURE - Bulgarian recovery prospects improve with IMF deal.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Bulgarian recovery prospects improve with IMF deal.</headline>
<byline>Thalia Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new agreement with the IMF offers Bulgaria's shattered economy the prospect of relief from its heavy debt burden and four-digit annual inflation.</p>
<p>The programme announced on Monday includes a $510 million one-year standby accord, $148 million to buy grain, and a rescue package for ailing banks.</p>
<p>The government which takes office after elections next month will introduce a strict fixed exchange rate regime in June to restore confidence in the collapsing lev.</p>
<p>&quot;This opens the door for everything,&quot; said Krassen Stanchev, director of the Institute for Market Economics, a private think-tank. &quot;Now the Bulgarian government is on the move, and they have to fulfil the same requirement as the (former ruling) Socialists -- to start privatising.&quot;</p>
<p>DEAL PAVES WAY FOR HELP FROM OTHER LENDERS</p>
<p>The agreement will pave the way for fresh financing from other donors, and talks on a rescheduling of Bulgaria's debt to the Paris Club of government creditors.</p>
<p>Bulgaria relies on external lending to meet foreign debt payments of $1 billion a year. The interim cabinet has already asked the Paris Club to roll over a $50 million payment.</p>
<p>The IMF suspended disbursements last year because of the former Socialist government's failure to meet reform targets.</p>
<p>That government was toppled by mass protests last month and its prime minister Zhan Videnov has been barred from travelling abroad pending investigation of his role in sanctioning big wheat exports in 1995 which led to the present grain crisis.</p>
<p>IMF mission leader Anne McGuirk said the programme would need to be supported by strong budget and monetary policy, but would also provide for wage and pension increases and assistance for those hardest hit by soaring prices.</p>
<p>PRIVATISATION TO ACCELERATE</p>
<p>&quot;There is also a strong commitment in the programme to structural reforms, in particular an ambitious privatisation programme both with regard to the banking system and the enterprise sector,&quot; she told a news conference on Monday.</p>
<p>Deputy prime minister and industry minister Alexander Bozhkov said the agreement put privatisation revenue at $300 to $350 million over the next year.</p>
<p>A consultative group of lenders will meet in Brussels in the first week of April to discuss financing commitments for the programme, and the agreement should go before the IMF board the following week.</p>
<p>The IMF said a first disbursement of $180 million would be released soon after the IMF board approved the agreement.</p>
<p>CURRENCY BOARD TO BE IMPLEMENTED AFTER ELECTIONS</p>
<p>The new accord was drawn up with the interim cabinet, in office until after April 19 general elections. The mission met political parties to ensure the programme would be continued after the elections.</p>
<p>The favourite to win a majority in the new parliament is the Union of Democratic Forces and its coalition allies, whose mass protests ousted Videnov's government in February, two years before the end of its term.</p>
<p>&quot;It is no secret that the agreement guarantees financial stability, stability on the (domestic) foreign exchange market, which means there will be no new shocks and it will provide an opportunity to solve some of the people's main economic problems,&quot; said UDF leader Ivan Kostov.</p>
<p>The UDF has shown commitment to trade liberalisation and accelerated privatisation, needed to haul the country out of economic collapse. Bulgaria suffers the lowest foreign investment in the region, amounting to $1 billion since 1989.</p>
<p>McGuirk said measures would be taken to overhaul Bulgaria's banking system before a currency board was introduced.</p>
<p>Insolvency cases are pending against 14 banks and panicked depositors withdrew nearly $1 billion dollars last year.</p>
<p>&quot;We agreed on immediate steps to strengthen any weaknesses in the state banks and we have agreed financing resources of about $50 million that would be available in the period immediately ahead,&quot; McGuirk said.</p>
<p>Monthly inflation hit 242.7 percent in February as the lev tumbled to historic lows of 3,000 to the dollar. It has recovered to around 1,600 to the dollar now. Finance Minister Svetoslav Gavriiski said he expected monthly inflation of below 50 percent in March.</p>
<p>The new parliament will have to pass a state budget and legal amendments to allow the introduction of the currency board mechanism, which matches levs in circulation to central bank foreign currency reserves, severely restricting a government's financial policy and preventing it from printing money.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
