<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="449968" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: South Korean president's son to stand in hearings.</title>
<headline>South Korean president's son to stand in hearings.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's ruling and opposition parties agreed on Tuesday to make President Kim Young-sam's son testify before parliament over alleged misdeeds connected with the Hanbo loan scandal.</p>
<p>A parliamentary official said floor leaders of the two parties, meeting to prepare for 45 days of hearings on the scandal which begin on Wednesday, also agreed that the proceedings would be televised.</p>
<p>Kim Hyun-chul, President Kim's second son who was embroiled in accusations he traded favours and meddled in state affairs, apologised on Monday and said he was ready for punishment if he had done wrong.</p>
<p>His father apologised for the scandal on television last month, saying he felt shame that his son had been dragged into the scandal involving $5.8 billion in loans to Hanbo Steel Co.</p>
<p>The opposition alleges that Hyun-chul, who holds no official post, peddled influence to help win loans for Hanbo. They also accuse him of playing a key role in administration appointments.</p>
<p>A trial of 10 people charged over the Hanbo collapse opened on Monday in a Seoul criminal court.</p>
<p>Former home affairs minister Kim Woo-suk has been charged with bribery and Hanbo founder Chung Tae-soo with fraud, issuing bad cheques and violating laws on trust and savings companies.</p>
<p>Also in the dock on corruption charges were three top bankers, four legislators -- three of them close Kim aides and one from the opposition -- and Chung's chief accountant, who was charged with embezzlement.</p>
<p>All defendants are now in custody.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
