<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45008" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Davids sees higher 96/97 profits.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Davids sees higher 96/97 profits.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grocer Davids Ltd said on Tuesday it was confident of greater profits in the 1996/97 year and beyond as the full benefits of the QIW merger emerged.</p>
<p>&quot;The past year has seen continued growth and development of the company on many fronts. I am confident of even greater growth and profits during fiscal 1997, continuing through fiscal 1998 as the full benefits of the QIW merger benefits emerge,&quot; executive chairman John David said in Davids' results for 1995/96.  </p>
<p>Earlier Davids reported an 11.7 percent higher net profit of A$51.77 million in the year to June 30, 1996 and set a five cents per share final dividend, taking the total dividend to a steady 10 cents.</p>
<p>There were no abnormal items. Analysts had forecast net profit before abnormals to rise to about A$53.6 million. Davids said that since the acquisition of QIW and its subsidiary Composite Buyers Ltd, there had been a net reduction in the number of 751 employees. &quot;Expected annual savings from this reduction alone is in excess of A$30 million. Further inventory savings are estimated to be A$60 million,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>Davids said the company had embarked on a surplus asset realisation programme.</p>
<p>&quot;Real estate valued at A$50 million is currently on the market,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Davids also said wholesale trading conditions were tough, but were showing signs of improvement.</p>
<p>Davids said its food service operations continued to grow ahead of grocery industry trends and its liquor market sales business continued to have outstanding growth.</p>
<p>Davids shares were up five cents at A$1.74 at 2.20 pm (0420 GMT). -- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
