<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="450053" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton laments cycle of &quot;political destruction&quot;.</title>
<headline>Clinton laments cycle of &quot;political destruction&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Laurence McQuillan</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton on Tuesday deplored the cycle of &quot;political destruction&quot; he said claimed Anthony Lake, his first choice to run the CIA.</p>
<p>Administration officials said acting CIA Director George Tenet was Clinton's likely choice to replace Lake, who abruptly withdrew from consideration on Monday, saying he was tired of the poisonous atmosphere in Washington.</p>
<p>Tenet drew quick praise from Senate Republican Majority Leader Trent Lott, who said: &quot;Barring something I don't know about, it looks like he would be a good choice.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton, calling a small group of reporters to the Red Room of the White House, said he planned to move quickly to name a replacement but complained about the mental gauntlet presidential nominees faced.</p>
<p>&quot;For too long we have allowed ordinary political processes and honest disagreements among honourable people to descend into political sniping, then into political revenge, and too often that results in political destruction,&quot; said Clinton, resting his injured leg on a footstool.</p>
<p>Clinton said he had been prepared to fight for Lake, his former national security adviser, for as long as it took to win him Senate confirmation, but Lake was concerned about the effect of a protracted confirmation fight on the CIA.</p>
<p>&quot;I think he was afraid the longer this went on ... the more it would damage the agency,&quot; said the president, who is recovering from knee surgery and sat in a chair with his right foot on a stool. He summoned reporters to hear his personal statement on a nomination withdrawal that stunned Washington.</p>
<p>Lake said he feared the agency and his own integrity would be damaged by a prolonged pounding from Republican senators on issues ranging from his knowledge of questionable White House fund-raising practices to his failure to divest himself of some stock and U.S. policy in Bosnia.</p>
<p>Sen. Richard Shelby, chairman of the Senate Intelligence Committee and Lake's leading antagonist, insisted he &quot;ran a fair hearing,&quot; and added, &quot;I was never out to get Mr. Lake.&quot;</p>
<p>He said his tough scrutiny was driven by a desire to confirm that &quot;proper person for this very important job.&quot;</p>
<p>But the Democratic vice-chairman of the committee, Sen. Robert Kerrey of Nebraska, strongly disagreed, saying &quot;I do not believe the ... process that Tony Lake went through was fair.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think we've got to be careful that whoever's sent up here gets due process, a reasonable hearing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The early betting line on replacements focused on Tenet, who has been acting agency director pending Lake's expected arrival. He has already gone through the rigours of winning Senate confirmation as the CIA's deputy director.</p>
<p>Republican leader Lott told reporters he had talked with White House officials on the issue and Tenet was &quot;one of the ones I have the impression they are considering ... It is clear to me they are working aggressively.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I am not promoting him,&quot; Lott added. &quot;It is one of the names that has been mentioned.&quot;</p>
<p>Officials said another person under consideration was Deputy Attorney General Jamie Gorelick, who is leaving the Justice Department but who is known as a strong administrator.</p>
<p>Another name mentioned was Frank Wisner, the U.S. ambassador to India and son of one of the CIA's founders and most celebrated intelligence officers.</p>
<p>Clinton has had a star-crossed history when it comes to choices for director of central intelligence. His next choice will be his fifth nominee for the post in as many years.</p>
<p>&quot;We certainly don't want to go through this again, and neither does the president,&quot; said one senior official who had tried to help Lake through the confirmation process.</p>
<p>Lake, 57, was nominated to succeed John Deutch, who left in December. Lake condemned the confirmation process as &quot;nasty and brutish but not short,&quot; a play on a famous aphorism about primitive life by philosopher Thomas Hobbes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
