<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="450031" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korean gold prices slip despite supply squeeze.</title>
<headline>S.Korean gold prices slip despite supply squeeze.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean gold prices have slipped this week in line with the international trend and despite a squeeze on local supplies, traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said maintenance work at the facilities of two major producers and the volatility in the foreign exchange market, which has caused several bullion houses to halt gold imports fearing currency losses, has tightened available supply.</p>
<p>&quot;There are several bullion houses which have halted gold imports on worries over losses on the volatile foreign exchange rates,&quot; a dealer with LG Metals said.  </p>
<p>Compounding the bullion market's woes has been a dip in demand for gold in March -- traditionally the start of the peak wedding season consumption period.</p>
<p>Gold producer LG Metals' daily selling price for the precious metal, which is regarded as a benchmark for the local bullion wholesale market, fell on Tuesday to 10,250 won per gram from 10,280 won a week ago.</p>
<p>The company's silver price rose slightly to 164 won from 163 won the previous week.</p>
<p>&quot;We heard there had been some production slowdowns at Korea Zinc and LG Metals,&quot; one dealer said.  </p>
<p>An official with Korea Zinc said the company had completed regular maintenance at its facility by the end of February.</p>
<p>Traders said Korea Zinc's March silver production would fall by 30 percent because of the maintenance activities. The company's silver output totalled 141 tonnes in 1996, down from 203 tonnes a year earlier.</p>
<p>Korea Zinc's gold supply, which included imported bullion, surged to 21 tonnes in 1996 from 3.6 tonnes the previous year.</p>
<p>Company officials did not elaborate on the reasons behind the changes in output.</p>
<p>LG Metals Corp also cut its sales turnover during March due to a small problem in its production lines late in February.</p>
<p>Officials at LG Metals said the company's production was now back on stream.</p>
<p>LG Metals expects its gold supply, including imported bullion, to rise about 16 percent to 80 tonnes in 1997, compared with 68.9 tonnes in 1996.</p>
<p>The company's silver supply, including imports of the white metal were expected to rise nearly 10 percent to 240 tonnes in 1997 from 218.7 tonnes last year.  </p>
<p>The telegraphic transfer selling rate for customers, posted by the Korea Exchange Bank, fell by 15.30 won to 883.30 won against the dollar from 878.00 won a week ago.</p>
<p>The rate is regarded as a benchmark of local foreign exchange rates for companies.</p>
<p>Traders said the won's continuing sharp decline against the dollar, which has pushed up gold prices overall in domestic currency terms, and the general economic slowdown in South Korea has effectively capped domestic demand despite the start of the March wedding season.  </p>
<p>&quot;Domestic demand in March is less than that of the same period last year, even though it is the wedding season,&quot; one bullion dealer said.</p>
<p>(US$ = 883.30 won)</p>
<p>-- Jae Hur, Seoul Newsroom (822) 727 5651</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
