<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="450191" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US spot resids firm on crude rally, Gulf HSFO talk.</title>
<headline>US spot resids firm on crude rally, Gulf HSFO talk.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot residual fuel oil grades firmed Tuesday on a rally in crude futures and interest in high-sulphur materials in the Gulf Coast market.</p>
<p>&quot;It's strictly off the back of crude,&quot; said one Houston resid trader when asked about the factor behind today's rise.</p>
<p>NYMEX April crude settled up $1.14 at $22.06 a barrel on technicals and delivery disruption on the Mississippi River.</p>
<p>Market sources said supplies of high-sulphur grades in the Gulf were tight with producers waiting for stronger prices.</p>
<p>&quot;People are holding for prices to come up. People are sitting on inventory,&quot; said one Gulf Coast dealer.  </p>
<p>In the U.S. Gulf, three percent sulphur grade was talked up to $13.75 a barrel with offers heard as high as $14.00. Three percent paper was quoted at $14.00-20. USG one percent was pulled to $14.50, the upper end of Monday's range.</p>
<p>NYH HSFO were assessed higher with three percent edging up to $13.25-50. The 0.3 percent high pour grade held at $16.75.</p>
<p>NYH one percent physical prices climbed 25 cents to $15.75-16.00. One percent paper rose to $16.10-25 from Monday's $15.75-16.00.</p>
<p>Forecasts of cold weather along the East Coast this week moved swing natural gas prices higher again.</p>
<p>At the New York City gate, day-ahead gas prices firmed to $2.37-2.44 per million British thermal units or $15.12 a barrel equivalent from Monday's $2.29-2.34 or $14.80/bbl.</p>
<p>But natgas at Henry Hub, the NYMEX delivery point, fell sharply to $1.90/mmBtu or 11.97/bbl from Monday's $2.00/mmBtu or $12.60/bbl equivalent.</p>
<p>Spot resid activity is expected to resume toward normal level as participants return from the National Petroleum Refiners Association conference in San Antonio, Texas.</p>
<p>((--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
