<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="450145" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New controversy over White House access for donors.</title>
<headline>New controversy over White House access for donors.</headline>
<byline>Michael Posner</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A fresh controversy over special access for political donors hit the White House on Monday with a report that a controversial oil man visited President Bill Clinton despite National Security Council objections.</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry confirmed the &quot;bare bones&quot; of a Wall Street Journal report that Lebanese-born international oil man and Democratic donor Roger Tamraz visited Clinton in the White House four times despite objections raised about him by an NSC official in 1995.</p>
<p>McCurry said the White House counsel was looking into the legal issues raised by the access given Tamraz, who was promoting a controversial pipeline project from the Caspian Sea to Turkey.</p>
<p>The report said then-Democratic Party Co-chairman Donald Fowler asked NSC official Sheila Heslin to back off her objections to White House visits by Tamraz. Fowler then was told by a higher-ranking NSC official to &quot;knock it off&quot; and stop pestering NSC workers, the report said.</p>
<p>Tamraz and his company, Tamoil Inc., had donated $177,000 to national and state Democratic parties in 1995 and 1996.</p>
<p>The incident was the latest controversy dogging the White House involving party donors getting White House access, including stays in the Lincoln bedroom, coffees and receptions with Clinton before the 1996 election.</p>
<p>The Journal reported NSC official Heslin had recommended to her superiors in June 1995 that Tamraz, a naturalised U.S. citizen, should have no more White House meetings because there was no compelling foreign policy reason for them.</p>
<p>Tamraz reportedly had sought from her either support for his pipeline or assurance it would not oppose the pipeline, which would have cut through Armenia and Arzebaijan, but the Journal said Heslin told him Washington could not endorse it.</p>
<p>That December, the paper said, party leader Fowler had asked her to drop her opposition to letting Tamraz meet with Clinton, saying he had helped the United States in the past and he would have the CIA send her a document on him.</p>
<p>In a statement late on Monday, acting CIA Director George Tenet said reports &quot;suggesting improper contacts and inquiries between Democratic National Committee and CIA officials are extremely serious and are being thoroughly investigated.&quot;</p>
<p>Tenet said he had directed the CIA inspector general on March 13 to investigate the circumstances surrounding these or any other inappropriate contacts. He also ordered notification of the congressional intelligence oversight committees.</p>
<p>&quot;The integrity of the intelligence community is a critical ingredient in how we accomplish our mission,&quot; he said. &quot;Any inappropriate intrusion into the intelligence process cannot and will not be tolerated.&quot;</p>
<p>After getting a CIA document, the Journal said, Heslin protested the incident to White House officials and superiors as &quot;highly irregular.&quot; One of them, deputy National Security Council director Nancy Sodeberg, told Fowler &quot;to knock it off&quot; and stop pestering her.</p>
<p>&quot;Yet despite Ms. Heslin's warnings and Ms. Sodeberg's tongue lashing, the businessman was allowed to attend four more meetings with the president in the White House,&quot; the paper said, quoting administration officials.</p>
<p>The paper said Fowler recalls telephoning the White House but &quot;says his memory is foggy on whom he talked with and on mentioning the CIA.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier, trying to promote a stalled campaign finance reform plan in Congress, Clinton named former Democratic Vice President Walter Mondale, until recently his ambassador to Japan, and former Kansas Republican Sen. Nancy Kassebaum Baker to lead a &quot;crusade&quot; to educate the public on campaign reforms.</p>
<p>The announcement was made at a White House ceremony by Vice President Al Gore, who stood in for Clinton following his knee surgery, and said that although the president &quot;is having a little trouble walking today, he is committed to taking all the strides we need to reform our campaign finance system.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
