<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="450285" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cable TV could gain from digital TV - US FCC chief.</title>
<headline>Cable TV could gain from digital TV - US FCC chief.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cable television may have a chance to win over viewers and advertisers from broadcast TV if broadcasters do not pursue high-definition digital TV, the head of the Federal Communications Commission said Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm beginning to wonder if broadcasters really want these DTV licenses,&quot; FCC Chairman Reed Hundt told a convention of the National Cable Television Association in New Orleans, referring to the digital TV licenses the FCC is set to award TV stations.</p>
<p>Hundt said that as long as TV stations believe the future of broadcast TV is analog transmission, &quot;they are putting the 'franchise' up for grabs. So what an opportunity cable has to grab the franchise away.&quot;</p>
<p>Hundt said the franchise refers to the &quot;core package of the most popular TV channels and the most popular way to deliver them.&quot;</p>
<p>Hundt has called on TV broadcasters to begin digital transmission -- which offers crystal-clear images and CD-quality sound -- within a year in selected major markets, once stations get the DTV licenses.</p>
<p>Broadcasters say more time is needed.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm beginning to wonder if broadcasters really want these DTV licesnes,&quot; Hundt said.</p>
<p>&quot;If broadcsaters won't launch digital television quickly, then DTV is going to be a failure,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Before long a huge majority of TV sets will definitely be receiving digital TV. Satellite is there. Cable is on its way -- moving to digital faster as (satellite TV) poses more of a threat. If broadcasters wait, it'll be too late,&quot; Hundt said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
