<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="450280" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: OPTIONS - Dlr/mark decline buoys front end vols.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - Dlr/mark decline buoys front end vols.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Implied volatilities for dollar/mark options, particularly the shorter dates, blipped up in U.S. trading as the market was caught off guard by the greenback's sharp slide below 1.6750 marks, dealers said.</p>
<p>They noted that many traders had become short gamma and short downside strikes lately because of a widely held view that the dollar's recent decline from February highs above 1.72 marks was just a correction of its two-year-long uptrend that had accelerated in the early part of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was not expecting the dollar collapsing, that fast anyway,&quot; said a U.S. bank trader in California.  </p>
<p>Implied volatility for one-month dollar/mark rose to 9.65/9.85 percent, up a quarter point from European midsession levels and half a point from late Monday levels.</p>
<p>One-week jumped a full point from European levels to 9.5/10.5 percent as the dollar plunged through 1.6800 marks and 1.6750 marks without a significant rebound. On the other hand, the back end was lagging, with one-year volatility at 9.75/9.95 percent, up 0.2 point.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's been favoring mark puts pretty much since the beginning of the year, so we had a lot of people short the downside of the dollar,&quot; the California trader added.  </p>
<p>Risk-reversals, which reflect pricing differentials between puts and calls, were turning in favor of mark calls, at least at the front end.</p>
<p>One-month 25-delta dollar/mark stood at 0.1/0.3 percent bid for mark calls against around par in late Monday trade.</p>
<p>A U.S. bank trader in Chicago said a fall in dollar/Swiss franc after a recent technical break below a rising trendline in the 1.45 to 1.46-franc area led the way down for dollar/mark.</p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/Swiss usually leads the way whether on the upside or the downside,&quot; he noted.  </p>
<p>&quot;When you have to call into question is when you have a big move in dollar/mark and dollar/Swiss isn't quite following...but in this case, it's definitely a dollar move to the downside,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>One-month dollar/Swiss volatility rose to 11.0/11.3 percent from Monday's 10.6/10.9.</p>
<p>Dollar/yen volatilities were also slightly firmer despite a relatively narrow range-trading in spot.</p>
<p>Traders said volatilities inched up in sympathy to dollar/mark amid a generally nervous environment ahead of the March 25 Federal Open Market Committee meeting.  </p>
<p>The dollar gradually eroded from overnight highs near 124 yen but stayed above 122 yen, still well clear of critical support and resistance levels at 120 and 125 yen.</p>
<p>&quot;At this point, we're pretty much in the middle of the range,&quot; the California trader said. &quot;It's not like we're endangering any strong support levels.&quot;</p>
<p>One-month dollar/yen volatility rose 0.2 point to 9.8/10.0 percent, while one-month gained half a point to 8.7/9.7.</p>
<p>One-month 25-delta risk reversal, which had briefly flipped toward yen puts late last week, was back in favor of yen calls at 0.0/0.3 percent.</p>
<p>((Chicago Derivatives Desk 312-408-8750))</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
