<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="450349" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FORECAST - Gasoline stocks seen steady in API data.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Gasoline stocks seen steady in API data.</headline>
<byline>Harry Milling</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A mixed demand picture for gasoline is expected to have offset a slight increase in output, yielding little change in gasoline stocks in this evening's oil inventory data from the American Petroleum Institute (API), traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It depends on how you look at it. Most people are expecting an increase in (crude) runs, but while overall demand could be strong, it could be sightly skewed due to flooding in the Midwest,&quot; said Ed Kevelson, director of refined products with Paribas Futures in New York.  </p>
<p>Ritterbush expects demand to have stayed as seasonally strong as it has been over the past several weeks. At March 7, implied demand was 7.5 million barrels a day (bpd) and 7.9 million barrels a day as of February 28.</p>
<p>Tonight's data reflects the week ended March 14.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, crude stocks were seen building between one million and three million barrels. Dealers expected increased imports from West Africa to have been eaten up slightly by greater crude runs. The refinery utilization rate was expected to rise between 0.50 to 0.75 percentage point as refineries exited winter maintenance.  </p>
<p>Distillate stocks, which include heating oil and gasoline, were seen showing a seasonal draw of between one million and two million barrels. At winter's end, refineries typically shift production toward gasoline at the expense of distillates ahead of the summer driving season.</p>
<p>-- New York Energy Desk, 212-859-1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
