<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="450406" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TWA aiming to get restructuring back on track.</title>
<headline>TWA aiming to get restructuring back on track.</headline>
<dateline>ST. LOUIS, Mo. 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trans World Airlines Inc., reporting a loss for the quarter and full year, said Tuesday it was taking actions to revive its restructuring plan, which stalled last year following the mysterious crash of one of its planes last summer.</p>
<p>TWA reported a 1996 loss of $284.8 million, including special charges of $85.9 million, or $7.27 a share, on revenues of $3.55 billion. In 1995 TWA lost $227.5 million on revenues of $3.32 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The tragic loss of TWA Flight 800 in July had an unquantified but significant negative business impact,&quot; TWA Chairman Gerald Gitner said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1996, TWA experienced an interruption in the process of rebuilding our airline,&quot; he said. &quot;We believe we have made the decisions that were needed to address the problems that plagued TWA's operations in the last half of 1996. We intend to continue to make and implement these decisions in the months ahead.&quot;</p>
<p>These actions include implementing a flight schedule that can be flown reliably with available aircraft and personnel, and replacing older, less efficient L-1011 and B-747 aircraft with more efficient B-757 and B-767 planes, the airline said.</p>
<p>TWA is also refining its route system, implementing a new business plan for John F. Kennedy International Airport in New York and enhancing service at its major domestic hub, Lambert-St. Louis International airport, Gitner said.</p>
<p>In addition, TWA said it will introduce new marketing programmes later this year.</p>
<p>Reviewing 1996, Gitner said that during the summer TWA tried to expand its route system by flying used aircraft that were new to the company.</p>
<p>This was a mistake, he said, as it led to reliability problems and increased maintenance and crew expense. Flights were cancelled, customers were inconvenienced and revenue was lost.</p>
<p>In July TWA Flight 800 crashed in the waters off New York's Long Island, killing all 230 people on board the Boeing 747. The cause of the crash has yet to be determined.</p>
<p>TWA said steep fuel costs also pressured its profits last year. Fuel costs rose 27.6 percent over the 1995 level to $585.2 million.</p>
<p>Commenting on 1997 operations to date, Gitner noted that fuel costs had moderated and TWA has seen some improvement in operational performance and schedule reliability.</p>
<p>For the fourth quarter TWA had a loss of $258.6 million, or $5.56 a share, on revenues of $803.3 million. In the year-earlier quarter, TWA lost $27.8 million, or 84 cents a share, on revenues of $804.6 million.</p>
<p>The 1996 fourth-quarter loss included charges to earnings of $85.9 million, including a non-cash charge of $53.7 million from planned retirement of L-1011 and B-747 planes.</p>
<p>Salaries, wages and benefits costs in 1996 increased 11.1 percent over the year earlier due to an increase in the average number of employees and overtime costs, TWA said.</p>
<p>TWA also reported its operating cost per available seat mile rose to 9.34 cents in the 1996 fourth quarter and 8.76 cents for the full year 1996 compared with 8.20 cents and 8.12 cents in the respective 1995 periods.</p>
<p>Passenger revenue per available seat mile totalled 6.95 cents in the 1996 fourth quarter and 7.58 cents for the year 1996, compared with 7.34 cents and 7.48 cents in the respective 1995 periods.</p>
<p>TWA stock was down 25 cents at $6.40625 on the American Stock Exchange in morning trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. LOUIS, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
