<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="450517" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. hopes for more positive Russian attitude - Cohen.</title>
<headline>U.S. hopes for more positive Russian attitude - Cohen.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kearns</byline>
<dateline>FT. IRWIN, Calif. 1997-03-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Cohen said on Monday that Russia knows NATO will be enlarged despite its objections and called on Moscow to stop exaggerating the threat it thinks this poses.</p>
<p>&quot;My own sense is that they recognise enlargement will take place,&quot; he told reporters travelling with him to watch war games in the California desert.</p>
<p>&quot;They don't accept it&quot; but &quot;they understand it,&quot; he said in advance of this week's summit meeting in Helsinki between President Bill Clinton and Russian President Boris Yeltsin.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not sure there will be an agreement&quot; in Helsinki, Cohen said, adding that &quot;we have to deal with their legitimate fears&quot; about NATO expansion, due to begin in July.</p>
<p>Yeltsin is strongly opposed to NATO's embrace of Eastern European countries formerly in the Soviet sphere of influence, seeing it as an attempt to isolate and threaten Russia.</p>
<p>But Cohen said that over time, Russia's fears, which he labeled &quot;exaggerated,&quot; should fade away.</p>
<p>&quot;Anything is possible as long as leaders look at it in a positive way, not in a negative way,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cohen said he met for more than two hours with Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov at the Pentagon this weekend to discuss NATO expansion and described the session as positive, despite Yeltsin's recent statements blasting the plan.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought he was very impressed with the quality of the presentation,&quot; Cohen said, adding that the United States side had &quot;taken great pains to not pose (expansion) as an offensive threat to Russia itself. We tried to deal with their legitimate apprehensions.&quot;</p>
<p>Cohen was en route to the Army's National Training Centre in the Mojave Desert to watch a new high technology-equipped brigade engage the Army's best combat units.</p>
<p>The brigade, the Experimental Force based at Ft. Hood, Texas, has been trained in using the latest in sophisticated battlefield technology, equipped with $250 million in satellites, drone planes, electronic troop locaters, computers and communications gear.</p>
<p>&quot;We are transforming the Army from the Industrial Age to the Information Age,&quot; said Army Chief of Staff Dennis Reimer, who was escorting Cohen.</p>
<p>&quot;Technology is turning over every 18 months or so,&quot; he said. &quot;All I want is an honest evaluation.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that in the long run the now-costly technology will become cheaper and save money if it works to change the way battles are fought.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FT. IRWIN, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
