<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="450614" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: FOCUS - EU, U.S. swap charges over banana trade row.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - EU, U.S. swap charges over banana trade row.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union and the United States on Tuesday swapped angrily-worded charges of distortion and misrepresentation in a multi-billion dollar trade row over EU banana import policies.</p>
<p>The exchange came in statements issued by the two powers as a World Trade Organisation (WTO) panel prepared to issue interim findings on a U.S. complaint that Brussels was violating open trading rules with its controversial banana regime.</p>
<p>In Brussels, the EU said the economies of Caribbean banana-producing countries would be devastated if the panel found against the regime, which extends preferential treatment to bananas from former European colonies.</p>
<p>U.S. arguments against the policy, which has also been challenged by some EU member states, were &quot;at a minimum groundless and indeed aim at distorting the reality&quot; of the regime and the impact of its abolition, the statement declared.</p>
<p>If successful U.S. strategy &quot;would lead directly to the destruction of the Caribbean banana industry&quot; and provoke severe hardship and political instability in a region already struggling against deprivation, it said.</p>
<p>But a counter-statement from Washington distributed by the U.S. WTO mission in Geneva said the Brussels document contained &quot;numerous fallacies&quot; and ignored special advantages the regime gave to EU-based banana marketing companies.</p>
<p>The import-licencing system that forms part of the 1993 regime, the U.S. statement said, had deprived U.S. banana distribution companies Chiquita and Dole of half of their business in the EU.</p>
<p>Four Latin American countries which have joined the U.S. complaint -- Ecuador, Honduras, Guatemala and Mexico -- &quot;are fighting for fair access to the European market,&quot; it added, arguing that Washington was not targeting Caribbean states.</p>
<p>There was no immediate word on the findings of the three-man panel, which has been studying the case since last May.</p>
<p>Its first, or interim, report was expected to be delivered later on Tuesday to the EU and U.S. trade missions as well as to the missions of the four Latin American countries, who say their exports to the EU have fallen by 27 per cent since 1993.</p>
<p>After all six have responded, the panel will issue a final report. Either side can challenge this before an appeals body, extending the process for several more months before the entire WTO membership decides whether to adopt the report.</p>
<p>Panels under the WTO's predecessor, the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT), twice found against earlier versions of the EU regime, but Brussels avoided action by blocking adoption -- as it was allowed to do under GATT rules.</p>
<p>In the WTO, if an appeal also goes against the EU it would be compelled to alter its policies, or pay compensation to the United States and the four Latin American banana producers to the value of the trade lost.</p>
<p>The regime is part of the system of trade preferences granted by Brussels to countries of the Africa, Caribbean and Pacific (ACP) group under their 1993 Lome Convention.</p>
<p>But the Caribbean banana producers of Belize, Surinam, Jamaica and the Windward Islands would be the worst hit if the system had to be abandoned, according to industry officials in the region.</p>
<p>The United States says it is not against preferences for poor Caribbean countries, but argues that the EU regulations are designed mainly to favour domestic banana growers and companies and were driven by politics rather than economics.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CARIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
