<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="450695" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Sobhraj wants France's Verges to fight his case.</title>
<headline>Sobhraj wants France's Verges to fight his case.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Notorious criminal Charles Sobhraj has asked French lawyer Jacques Verges, who defended Nazi war criminal Klaus Barbie and international guerrilla Carlos, to help fight his case, his lawyer said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have approached Jacques Verges to take up his case with the French authorities,&quot; Rajan Bakshi, Sobhraj's lawyer in the Indian capital, told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;I sent him (Verges) a fax and he replied that he is willing to take the case but he would need Sobhraj's authorisation for starting the proceedings,&quot; Bakshi said.</p>
<p>Sobhraj, whose exploits across Asia have been the subject of two books, spent more than 20 years in a high-security Indian jail before being released on bail last month. He was immediately detained on grounds he lacked proper papers.</p>
<p>Sobhraj was first arrested in India for holding up a hotel jewellery shop in 1971. He was later charged with a long string of crimes including murder, serving time for some and winning acquittal in others.</p>
<p>Born to an Indian father and a Vietnamese mother, Sobhraj claims that he is a French citizen. India has said it intends to deport Sobhraj to France, which is studying his record and nationality claims before issuing travel documents.</p>
<p>The controversial Verges represented Venezuelan-born international guerrilla Carlos the Jackal and former Gestapo chief Klaus Barbie, nicknamed the &quot;Butcher of Lyon&quot;.</p>
<p>Barbie was sentenced to life imprisonment in 1987 and died in a French jail in 1991.</p>
<p>Spirited out of Sudan by French counter-espionage in 1994, Carlos is awaiting trial in the Paris prison La Sante.</p>
<p>He had been convicted in his absence by a French court and sentenced to life in prison for the 1975 killings of two secret service agents in Paris. He is also being investigated over a total of six bombings and killings in France.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
