<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="450618" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: KLM to add 2nd Zaragossa freighter flight.</title>
<headline>KLM to add 2nd Zaragossa freighter flight.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>KLM Cargo said it was poised to add a second weekly freighter frequency between Zaragosa in northern Spain and Amsterdam, in anticipation of a French weekend truck ban, effective March 24.</p>
<p>Truckers are allowed to return back to their home location. But after the ban comes into force vehicles, weighing more than 7.5 tonnes, will be banned from French roads between 2200 local (2100 gmt) Saturday until the same time on Sunday.</p>
<p>Early-February, KLM Cargo began testing out a week-end freighter service on the route, using a 30 tonne-capacity Belfast aircraft, wet-leased from Heavylift, in anticipation of the ban.</p>
<p>&quot;This service has proved to be a thorough success and for this reason we are now planning a second frequency using a five-pallet, 22-tonne capacity Lockheed Hercules wet-leased from Southern Air Transport,&quot; KLM Cargo's Paris-based Operations manager, Southern Europe, Simon Groenenboom, told Reuters.</p>
<p>While the service  had been launched in response to the forthcoming truck ban, KLM had been planning this kind of operation for some time, Groenenboom said.</p>
<p>The Belfast freighter service had enabled KLM Cargo to make its usual connections from Schiphol for ex-Iberia airfreight to destinations worldwide while it also allowed an efficient throughput of import traffic.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly, there is a considerable  difference in costs between airborne feeders and trucking but this has to be weighed against the impact of having lorries laid up for 24 hours, the impact of which is the failure to meet customers requirements of delivering their airfreight Monday mornings.&quot;</p>
<p>KLM Cargo was pondering whether to introduce the Hercules freighter service from March 29 but this would depend on the level of demand, Groenenboom said.</p>
<p>&quot;Volumes are traditionally down the Easter weekend so a likelier launch-date for the Hercules is the following weekend.&quot;</p>
<p>The contingency flights would enable KLM Cargo to cover its markets in Spain and Portugal, notably Porto and Lisbon and for import traffic to south-west France, Toulouse and Bordeaux in particular, Groenenboom added.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, KLM Cargo is close to finalising its plans for an airlift operation to beat the French truck ban.</p>
<p>&quot;We are convinced that a dedicated freighter is the best solution. The problem has been finding the right type of aircraft - ideally a Boeing 747F - and we are currently in negotiations with two companies on this very point. We also need to decide on an Italian gateway for the service and it is probably a choice between Milan and Bologna. A possible start-up is the weekend of the April 5/6.&quot; - Reuters Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax+5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
