<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45064" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: IMF says endorses Philippine monetary policy.</title>
<headline>IMF says endorses Philippine monetary policy.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Monetary Fund on Tuesday rejected as false Manila newspaper reports which said the IMF was worried over discrepancies in Philippine economic data.</p>
<p>&quot;A number of reports in this morning's press attributed views to the IMF. These reports are false,&quot; a statement from the IMF's Manila office said.</p>
<p>Several Manila newspapers reported on Tuesday that the IMF was concerned about discrepancies in economic data provided by the government.</p>
<p>The reports, quoting unnamed sources, said an IMF team due to arrive in Manila this week for a routine review of the economy would look into abrupt changes in the monetary programme and balance of payment figures.</p>
<p>&quot;References to IMF concerns about abrupt changes in monetary policy and conflicting data have absolutely no basis in fact,&quot; the IMF statement said.</p>
<p>The IMF team's visit is a regularly scheduled mission covering economic developments and prospects in the Philippines, it said.</p>
<p>The Philippines is under a three-year IMF programme which ends next year.</p>
<p>&quot;The IMF endorses the monetary policy of the authorities that has and continues to remain well within the agreed programme framework,&quot; the statement said.  </p>
<p>A separate report released by the Asian Development Bank (ADB) on Tuesday pointed out &quot;unusually large&quot; errors in the Philippines' 1995 balance of payments data.</p>
<p>The Manila-based bank said it was not possible to gauge the full extent of the miscalculation and ADB economist Srinivasa Madhur told a news conference data problems were common in the initial stages of a country's economic liberalisation programme.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8934</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
