<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="451194" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: GAN bail-out bill could overshoot -paper.</title>
<headline>GAN bail-out bill could overshoot -paper.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The French government's rescue of state-owned insurer Groupe des Assurances Nationales (GAN) could cost 10 billion francs ($1.8 billion) more than the 20 billion francs which has been earmarked, according to GAN's former chairman, the British daily Financial Times said on Monday.</p>
<p>The government plan puts the bill at 20 billion francs -- a capital injection of 11 billion and nine billion for estimated losses on property asset sales -- but the precise cost of the overhaul will only be known once property sales are completed.</p>
<p>The newspaper said &quot;an official close to the discussions over the rescue&quot; had acknowledged that the total bill could be as high as 25 billion, but equally come in as low as 15 billion.</p>
<p>The finance ministry declined to comment beyond saying none of its officials had made comments on a possible overshoot.</p>
<p>The government announced the rescue on February 27, saying the group had ran up losses of 35 billion since 1992, mainly because of troubles at its UIC property unit.</p>
<p>It hopes to immunise the insurance arm and CIC banking subsidiary from UIC and privatise those two businesses &quot;during the course of 1997&quot;, according the Finance Minister Jean Arthuis.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452 ($ = 5.704 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
