<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45169" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan group rebuilds lighthouse on disputed isle.</title>
<headline>Japan group rebuilds lighthouse on disputed isle.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese rightists said on Tuesday they have rebuilt a makeshift lighthouse on an East China Sea island at the centre of a sovereignty dispute among Tokyo, Beijing and Taipei.</p>
<p>Six members of the Tokyo-based Nihon Seinen-sha (Japan Youth Federation) sailed to the Senkakus, known in Chinese as the Diaoyu Islands, and repaired an aluminium lighthouse on Monday, a spokesman for the group said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not a new one. The lighthouse we built in July was damaged by a typhoon last month,&quot; the spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;So that was repaired,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Japanese coastguards dispatched a helicopter to the island earlier on Tuesday and spoted the lighthouse.</p>
<p>&quot;We confirmed that the lighthouse was standing,&quot; a spokesman for the Maritime Safety Agency said.</p>
<p>Tokyo has effectively supported the right-wing group's moves to bolster Japan's claim to the islands, mobilising patrol boats to repel private Taiwan vessels that have tried to reach the islands in recent days.</p>
<p>The Senkakus, a group of small uninhabited islands, lie in the East China Sea west of Japan's Okinawa island, northeast of Taiwan and east of China's southeastern Fujian coast.</p>
<p>Japan's persistent moves to assert sovereignty over the islands have angered Chinese in Taiwan, Hong Kong, Macau and on the Chinese mainland, uniting the regions despite their own political differences.</p>
<p>Rivals China and Taiwan, which separately challenge Japan's claim to the islands, have condemned the construction of the lighthouse and demanded its immediate removal.</p>
<p>Tokyo's claim dates to 1895, when Japan defeated China and seized Taiwan and other territories. China has claimed sovereignty over the islands for centuries.</p>
<p>A poll published on Monday showed that 69 percent of 982 Taiwanese interviewed by the mass-circulation United Daily News said they wanted Taipei to send vessels to protect the islands.</p>
<p>Taiwan has no diplomatic ties with Japan, which recognises only Beijing's communist government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
