<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="451666" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai Farmers, Siam Commercial fall on downgrade.</title>
<headline>Thai Farmers, Siam Commercial fall on downgrade.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of Thai Farmers Bank Plc and Siam Commercial Bank Plc dropped in late morning trade on Tuesday after Standard and Poors' (S&amp;P) Corp downgraded their credit ratings, brokers said.</p>
<p>By 0415 GMT, Thai Farmers Bank was down three baht to 114 on the most active trade of 129 million baht. Siam Commercial Bank dipped two baht to 130.</p>
<p>&quot;Both shares were nearly stable early before the S&amp;P announcement triggered heavy selling on the stocks,&quot; said one broker at Nava Finance.  </p>
<p>Rating agency S&amp;P said on Tuesday it has downgraded the credit ratings of Thai Farmers and Siam Commercial to BBB-plus/A2 from A-minus/A2.</p>
<p>It said the rating downgrades of Thai Farmers and Siam Commercial reflected the need for further provisions which would significantly affect the banks' profitability and capital levels.</p>
<p>S&amp;P said its rating outlook for the two banks had been changed to negative from stable.</p>
<p>&quot;The rating actions recognise Standard and Poor's concerns about the deteriorating condition of Thailand's financial sector, which has come under increasing pressure with the downturn in the property market and a slowdown in the economy,&quot; the rating agency said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the downgrading of both banks' credit ratings will raise their cost of foreign borrowings and affect their earnings.</p>
<p>-- Anuchit Nguyen (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
