<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="451797" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: PRESS DIGEST - Spain - March 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Spain - March 18.</headline>
<text>
<p>Headlines from major national newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>EL PAIS</p>
<p>- Interior Minister Mayor Oreja and judge both said the ETA suspect, prisoner Fernando Elejalde, was not tortured</p>
<p>- Ex Banesto vice president Arturo Romani says now Conde told cabinet about the payment of 600 million pesetas</p>
<p>- Figueras bus accident (close to the western border city of Girona) reveals illegal trafficking of immigrants</p>
<p>EL MUNDO</p>
<p>- Interior Minister Mayor Oreja accused PNV of putting at risk the democracy's credibility</p>
<p>- Catalonia's CiU's leader Jordi Pujol gave Aznar three weeks to 'float free' the financing of the health</p>
<p>ABC</p>
<p>- Interior Minister Mayor Oreja dismantled pro ETA campaign, backed by PNV</p>
<p>CINCO DIAS</p>
<p>- Euroadvance (Kohl and Chirac reiterated their committment) and Euroregress (peseta stable, but with some back, bonos and stocks down)</p>
<p>- Telefonica down a 3.61 percent fearing Retevision's connection tariff</p>
<p>EXPANSION</p>
<p>- Telefonica doubled its pressure on the government to break Retevision</p>
<p>- Strong fall in the markets due to uncertainties in Europe and in the U.S.</p>
<p>- German and France draw strict plan to enter EMU</p>
<p>- BBV, the stock preferred by investment trusts</p>
<p>GACETA DE LOS NEGOCIOS</p>
<p>- The Peseta and the lira, victims of German instability</p>
<p>- Spain's public TV RTVE made more VAT deductions than allowed, and risks bitter sanctions</p>
<p>-- Madrid Newsroom, + 341 585 8340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
