<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="451763" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>QATAR: Qatar Rasgas expects first gas onshore in 1998.</title>
<headline>Qatar Rasgas expects first gas onshore in 1998.</headline>
<dateline>DOHA 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ras Laffan Liquefied Natural Gas Company (Rasgas) expects first gas from its offshore North Field concession to be delivered to its planned gas liquefaction plant at Ras Laffan industrial city at the end of 1998, Rasgas managing director Neil Kelley said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>This is three months ahead of schedule, he said in an interview at the sidelines of a gas conference in Doha.</p>
<p>The gas would be stripped of condensate and then injected back into state-owned Qatar General Petroleum Corp's (QGPC) existing North Field concession, he said.</p>
<p>Rasgas, the second of Qatar's liquefied natural gas (LNG) projects, was on schedule to supply its first cargo of liquefied natural gas (LNG) to Korea Gas Corp in July 1999 under an 4.8 million tonne supply contract.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident we can meet that date,&quot; Kelley said.</p>
<p>State-owned Qatar General Petroleum Corp has 63 percent stake in Rasgas with U.S. Mobil Corp 25 percent, Japan's Itochu 3.5 percent, Nissho Iwai 3.5 percent and an undeclared South Korean entity five percent.</p>
<p>Rasgas aims to produce ten million tonnes a year of LNG at its site using four production trains. Initial capacity will be five million tonnes based on two trains, said Kelley.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DOHA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="QATAR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
