<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="451886" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: PRESS DIGEST -Switzerland - March 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST -Switzerland - March 18.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights from Swiss newspapers on Tuesday:</p>
<p>NEUE ZUERCHER ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- The Swiss government plans to revise laws governing the Swiss National Bank, requiring it to pass on more of its profit to the cantons and the central government in future.</p>
<p>- Switzerland wants to pass laws mandating a 10 percent reduction of carbon dioxide emissions by the year 2010.</p>
<p>- Ares Serono, the third largest pharmaceuticals group in Switzerland, reported an 18.7 percent rise in 1996 sales to $805 million. Its net profit rose 82 percent to $53.5 million.</p>
<p>- Zurich Insurance Group acquired a minority stake in Thai Metropole Insurance Co. Ltd. in Thailand.</p>
<p>- The European Commission is investigating whether or not the takeover of the French reinsurance firm SAFR by Swiss Reinsurance violates competition laws.</p>
<p>TAGES ANZEIGER</p>
<p>- The Swiss government approved a 1.5 billion Swiss franc defense budget for 1997 and confirmed that defense spending will continue to decline as the government looks to reach its 1990 goal of a 32 percent spending cut by the year 2000.</p>
<p>- Societe de Surveillance (SGS) posted a 12.4 percent 1996 sales increase to 2.954 billion Swiss francs. Net profit rose by 14 percent to 262.7 million Swiss francs.</p>
<p>- A total of 18,116 new cars were sold in Switzerland in February, 6.5 percent fewer than in February 1996.</p>
<p>- SAirGroup is taking over the Belgian Restobel Group.</p>
<p>JOURNAL DE GENEVE</p>
<p>- United Nations Secretary General Kofi Annan presented a restructuring plan which calls for the elimination of some 1,000 U.N. jobs, 200 of which will be in Geneva.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
