<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="451942" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Euro bourses weaken despite Wall St comeback.</title>
<headline>Euro bourses weaken despite Wall St comeback.</headline>
<byline>David Stamp</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>European bourses weakened on Tuesday despite a spectacular comeback on Wall Street overnight, with investors reluctant to follow suit due to the recent wild swings of the U.S. market.</p>
<p>The dollar was generally steady after dipping below 1.69 marks but eased against the yen after the Japanese government announced plans to improve land sales.</p>
<p>On the share markets, the Dow Jones Industrial Average closed up 20.02 points at 6,955.48 on Monday, recovering from a loss of more than 80 points earlier in the day.</p>
<p>But investors in Europe, where markets tumbled on Monday, are still worried that the U.S. central bank will raise interest rates when its Federal Open Market Committee meets on March 25.</p>
<p>London had the additional worry of a long election campaign after Prime Minister John Major announced on Monday that Britons would go to the polls on May 1.</p>
<p>At mid morning the FTSE-100 index was down 20.6 points at 4,352.7.</p>
<p>&quot;Wall Street's performance will be a bit of a relief,&quot; said the head of equity trading at one brokerage. But he added: &quot;With the election looming there is going to be plenty of uncertainty over the next six weeks.&quot;</p>
<p>The election date came as no surprise to markets, but with the opposition far ahead in opinion polls, traders began to contemplate life under a Labour government.</p>
<p>Financial markets are traditionally hostile to Labour, but leader Tony Blair has dragged the party towards the centre and made efforts to woo the business community.</p>
<p>But Blair has not won over the entire financial community with his promises of no return to traditional Labour policies of &quot;tax and spend&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an incredible lead Labour has got,&quot; said a senior trader at a U.S. securities house. &quot;People will start to think about the amount of interference that is going to take place under a Labour government.&quot;</p>
<p>The trader also attributed the weak start to the fact that U.S. bonds had failed to follow the Dow rally. &quot;Bonds are still deteriorating and that is still the key as far as we are concerned,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Other European equity markets were likewise weak. In Paris the CAC-40 index was 14.71 lower at 2,573.67 after tumbling two percent on Monday while in Germany, the DAX shed 17.21 points to 3,333.78.</p>
<p>Paris traders were wary of Wall Street and said weak European bonds and a softer dollar could hit sentiment.</p>
<p>Frankfurt was dominated by one subject. &quot;Our main topic of conversation is the possible takeover of Thyssen by Krupp,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Shares in steel giant Thyssen AG and Hoesch-Krupp were suspended by the German stock exchange.</p>
<p>Thyssen said in a statement late on Monday that Krupp planned a hostile takeover and that it would use &quot;all appropriate measures&quot; to ward off its rival.</p>
<p>Traders said that following the suspensions, Thyssen shares were changing hands in unofficial trade at around 395 marks each, well above the 346.80 in bourse trade on Monday.</p>
<p>On foreign exchange markets, the dollar edged below 1.69 marks and 123 yen. The yen was seen as firm after the announcement of a Japanese government scheme to improve land sales plus comments from a Bank of Japan (BOJ) official which the market interpreted as a check on falling long-term interest rates.</p>
<p>But dealers were cautious. &quot;The market may be reading too much into the BOJ comments and the land liquidity plans. The market is getting increasingly nervous into the financial year-end,&quot; said a German bank dealer.</p>
<p>By mid morning, the dollar was at 1.6898 marks, marginally down from 1.6901 in European trading late on Monday, while it eased to 122.96 yen from 123.63.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1000 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was quoted at 1.6898 marks and 122.96 yen, compared with Monday's late European levels of 1.6901 marks and 123.63 yen.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS at 1000 GMT</p>
<p>LONDON - The FTSE-100 index was points at 4,3.</p>
<p>PARIS - The CAC-40 was points at 2,5.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - The 30-share DAX index was points at 3,3.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold was at $347.40 an ounce, compared with $350.25 at the close on Monday. Silver was at $5.21, compared with $5.23.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
