<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="451903" id="root" date="1997-03-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Fokus proposes merger with BnB.</title>
<headline>Fokus proposes merger with BnB.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norway's fourth largest bank, Fokus Bank ASA, said on Tuesday it had proposed a merger with Bolig og Naeringsbanken, a Trondheim-based bank.  </p>
<p>Fokus proposed an exchange ratio of 3.3 shares in Fokus Bank for each share in BNB, also known as BNbank, but with 20 percent of the consideration paid in cash.</p>
<p>Based on Fokus' share price on Monday of 58.50 crowns, the exchange ratio equals a price on BNbank of 179.85 crowns per share and 10 crowns in dividend, Fokus said in a statement.</p>
<p>BNbank closed at 167 crowns on Monday on the Oslo Bourse.  </p>
<p>&quot;Fokus Bank has today sent a letter to the Board of Directors in BNbank proposing a merger between the two banks,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>It said the joint bank would have total assets of about 60 billion crowns and be a leader in targeted regions.</p>
<p>With BNbank, Fokus would confirm its position as fourth largest bank in Norway. It is also the third largest commercial bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The merger will result in substantial cost and income synergies and a broader shareholder base with a large Norwegian component,&quot; Trondheim-based Fokus said.</p>
<p>&quot;Headquartered in Trondheim, the merged unit will have a large customer base to which it will be able to offer a broad range of financial solutions,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Fokus Bank is seeking a friendly, negotiated merger between equal parties. BNbank will be a vital part of the merger company's operation. The proposal means that BNbank's operation will be carried on after the merger, as a subsidiary of Fokus Bank,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Fokus last month said 1996 pre-tax operating profits rose 7.7 percent to 462 million crowns from a year earlier thanks to successful regional banking which emphasizes local expertise and decentralised authorities.</p>
<p>Managing Director Bjarne Borgersen at the time also said the entire banking industry faced considerable competitive challenges, which implicated changes and restructuring.</p>
<p>--Rolf Soderlind, Oslo newsroom +47 22 42 50 41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
