<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45194" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Daiwa, Nikko, Yamaichi seen to cut forecasts-paper.</title>
<headline>Daiwa, Nikko, Yamaichi seen to cut forecasts-paper.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Daiwa Securities Co Ltd, Nikko Securities Co Ltd and Yamaichi Securities Co Ltd are expected to lower their forecasts for parent current profit in the six months to September 30, a Japanese business daily said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Nihon Keizai Shimbun said half-year parent current profits at Daiwa and Nikko would be smaller than those of the same period a year ago. It said Yamaichi may not be able to post any current profit in the half-year period.</p>
<p>Many second-tier securities houses may post half-year losses in 1996/97, the paper said.  </p>
<p>The paper said the poor business performances were due to a sluggish stock market.</p>
<p>But it said industry leader Nomura Securities Co Ltd would post a larger half-year parent current profit than in the same period last year due to an expected rise in profits from bond trading.</p>
<p>The paper saw Daiwa's half-year parent current profit at 25 billion yen against an actual profit of 27.5 billion yen a year ago. It expects Nikko's half-year parent current profit at 20 billion yen, against an actual profit of 25.5 billion yen a year ago.  </p>
<p>The paper said Yamaichi would post nil half-year parent current profit. The company had a half-year parent current profit in 1995/96 of 5.2 billion yen.</p>
<p>Nomura would post half-year parent current profit of 50 billion yen in 1996/97 against half-year profit of 32.1 billion yen a year ago, the paper said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
