<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="452234" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA BASKETBALL-JORDAN BEATS SONICS IN OT IN REMATCH OF FINALS.</title>
<headline>NBA BASKETBALL-JORDAN BEATS SONICS IN OT IN REMATCH OF FINALS.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>It was a rematch of last year's NBA Finals and the outcome was the same -- Michael Jordan beat the Seattle SuperSonics again.</p>
<p>Jordan scored 32 points, pulled down a career-high 18 rebounds and sank the game-winning free throws with three seconds left in overtime to give the Bulls an 89-87 victory.</p>
<p>Jordan made 12-of-13 free throws, including six in overtime as he drew three fouls from 1996 Defensive Player of the Year Gary Payton.</p>
<p>&quot;In reality, our defence really won the game for us,&quot; Jordan said. &quot;We weren't able to score, but we were able to make sure they didn't score either.&quot;</p>
<p>Payton was fouled by Jordan with 16 seconds left but made just one free throw that tied the game at 87-87. Jordan then drew a very questionable foul call on Payton and made both free throws for the victory.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Jordan) lost the ball and I didn't foul anybody,&quot; said Payton, who had 14 points, 14 assists and 12 rebounds for his third career triple-double. &quot;We did a great job and played great defence. It's heartbreaking for us. I hope we get a chance to play them again.&quot;</p>
<p>Seattle's Hersey Hawkins, who scored 23 points, missed a three-pointer at the buzzer. He had made consecutive treys to give the Sonics an 86-83 lead with 1:15 to play.</p>
<p>Shawn Kemp added 16 points for Seattle, which led for nearly the entire game. Luc Longley had 16 points and Dennis Rodman grabbed 17 rebounds for the Bulls.</p>
<p>In New York, Patrick Ewing had 22 points and 10 rebounds and the Knicks held Vancouver scoreless for the final 9:05 in a 98-73 thumping of the Grizzlies.</p>
<p>John Starks scored 16 points, Allan Houston added 14 and Charles Oakley tallied 10 and 15 rebounds as New York handed hapless Vancouver its 14th consecutive defeat.</p>
<p>Pete Chilcutt scored five points during a 10-2 run to pull the Grizzlies within 83-73 with 9:05 remaining, but the Knicks scored the game's final 15 points to move within a half game of first-place Miami in the Atlantic Division.</p>
<p>In Phoenix, Rodney Rogers scored 11 of his 21 points in the fourth quarter as the Los Angeles Clippers beat the Suns 121-111 in a battle for the last playoff berth in the Western Conference.</p>
<p>Darrick Martin added 20 points and Charles Outlaw chipped in 19 for Los Angeles. Malik Sealy had 15 points and Loy Vaught added 14 and 18 rebounds for the Clippers.</p>
<p>Kevin Johnson scored 37 points for the Suns, who blew an opportunity to tie the Clippers in the race for the eighth and final playoff spot in the West.</p>
<p>In Portland, Kenny Anderson had 22 points and eight assists and Rasheed Wallace added 15 points as the Trail Blazers beat the Sacramento Kings 92-87 for their 10th consecutive victory.</p>
<p>Arvydas Sabonis chipped in with 13 points and nine rebounds for the Blazers, who are enjoying their longest win streak since taking 16 in a row at the end of the 1990-91 season.</p>
<p>Mitch Richmond scored 29 points and Corliss Williamson had 10 for Sacramento, which suffered its sixth straight loss.</p>
<p>In Toronto, Marcus Camby scored 16 of his 36 points in the first quarter and Damon Stoudamire recorded a triple-double as the Raptors beat the Philadelphia 76ers 117-105.</p>
<p>Camby shot 16-of-25 from the field to better his previous career-best of 29 points. Stoudamire had 30 points, 12 assists and 10 rebounds for his third career triple-double.</p>
<p>Doug Christie added 20 points and 10 rebounds for the Raptors, who led by as many as 23 points. Allen Iverson had 26 points and 10 assists and Derrick Coleman added 25 points and 16 rebounds to lead the Sixers.</p>
<p>At Indiana, Reggie Miller scored 18 of his 27 points in the first half and Rik Smits had 17 in the third quarter as the Pacers beat the Minnesota Timberwolves 115-97.</p>
<p>Dale Davis recorded 23 points and 13 rebounds, Smits finished with 21 points and Mark Jackson dished out 17 assists for Indiana.</p>
<p>James Robinson tallied 26 points and Kevin Garnett had 20 for Minnesota.</p>
<p>At New Jersey, Clyde Drexler scored 23 points and Sedale Threatt scored 10 of his 15 in the fourth quarter as the Houston Rockets ended the Nets' upset string with a 97-89 win.</p>
<p>Drexler also had 12 assists in just his second game back after missing more than five weeks with a strained left hamstring. The Rockets are still without Charles Barkley.</p>
<p>Jim Jackson and Kendall Gill had 20 points apiece and Eric Montross grabbed 18 rebounds for New Jersey, which was coming off huge upsets of Chicago and New York but could not make it three in a row.</p>
<p>In Dallas, Calbert Cheaney's layup with 1.5 seconds remaining lifted the Washington Bullets to an 86-85 victory over the Mavericks.</p>
<p>Michael Finley hit a long jumper to put Dallas ahead 85-84 with 12.4 seconds to play. But Chris Webber hit a cutting Cheaney for the winning shot.</p>
<p>Webber scored 20 points and Juwan Howard added 17 and 14 rebounds for Washingtnley led Dallas with 18 points.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
