<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="452367" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Brent ends 7 cts firmer after NYMEX-driven spi.</title>
<headline>IPE Brent ends 7 cts firmer after NYMEX-driven spi.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE Brent crude futures  closed seven cents higher on Wednesday after a dizzying ride on the back of a rally in U.S. markets, traders said.</p>
<p>Front month May Brent collapsed to settle at $20.32 a barrel after powering briefly to a high of $20.84 an hour before the close. The contract had traded between $20.21 and 20.35 for much of the session.</p>
<p>The NYMEX rally, attributed variously to technical strength, bullish stock data and supply worries, helped IPE Brent break effortlessly above resistance at $20.50, $20.56 and 20.74 in the space of half an hour.</p>
<p>&quot;We're now out of the range we've been in for the past month,&quot; a Brent futures trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Tomorrow will show whether we are going to try to build volume at this level to prepare for another break to the upside or whether we're going to settle into this higher range.&quot;</p>
<p>Some traders attributed Brent's rally to the continuing closure to marine traffic of a two-and-a-half mile section of the Mississipi near Baton Rouge after a bage accident late on Monday.</p>
<p>London traders said they had heard rumours that the closure had affected the ability of a U.S. producer to make marine shipments.</p>
<p>New York traders said the rally was based mainly on technical factors.</p>
<p>Traders attributed Brent's late retreat to talk that fund buying seen earlier had dried up or to perceptions of oversupply despite publication earlier on Wednesday of bullish U.S. stock data.</p>
<p>The front-month Brent/WTI spread finished at $1.51. NYMEX unleaded gasoline last traded 0.32 cent at 67.80 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>April gas oil closed $3.00 a tonne stronger at $175.00 having briefly toyed with $176.75, which attracted some selling pressure. &quot;Gas oil is looking comfortable at these higher numbers and the market is waiting for these levels to be confirmed,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Outright volume was viewed as thin. Support for April was seen at $174, today's low with selling interest likely to kick in around $176.25.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 7646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
