<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="452391" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Caribbean states voice alarm over WTO banana draft.</title>
<headline>Caribbean states voice alarm over WTO banana draft.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Caribbean countries voiced alarm on Wednesday at reports that a World Trade Organisation (WTO) dispute panel had found that a European Union banana regime favouring their imports violates open trading rules.</p>
<p>Diplomats said in Geneva on Tuesday that an interim report from the three-man panel in effect favoured a complaint by the United States and four Latin American states that the EU regime discriminated against their marketing companies and producers.</p>
<p>The report, issued after nearly 10 months of deliberations, recommended that the WTO's Dispute Settlement Body (DSB) ask Brussels to bring the regime into line with its obligations under global trade accords, they added.</p>
<p>The Caribbean Banana Exporters Association which represents growers in Belize, Jamaica, Surinam and the Windward Islands noted press reports about the panel decision with alarm.</p>
<p>It said in a statement that there would be provision for appeal against the ruling, when this is issued in its final form.</p>
<p>Meanwhile it said that it could not understand how the United States could reconcile its action with a &quot;professed concern for the well-being of their Caribbean neighbours&quot;.</p>
<p>The statement also called it &quot;bizarre and regrettable&quot; that the WTO would not show the draft panel ruling to countries where economies risked destruction as a result of it.</p>
<p>The finding, which has to be confirmed in a final report to be issued publicly once comments have come in from all six countries involved, will come as a bitter blow to small Caribbean banana-producing states, trade analysts said.</p>
<p>They and the EU have argued that unless the preferences they enjoy for exports of the fruit to the European market are maintained, their economies will collapse under competition from the much larger-scale banana industry of Latin America.</p>
<p>According to the diplomats, the panellists from Hong Kong, Switzerland and Australia found that the 1993 EU regime ran against several articles of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT) and against a linked services accord (GATS).</p>
<p>Once the report has been finalised, the EU can ask the DSB's Appellate Body for a review. But if that finding goes against it, under the tough WTO rules Brussels will have to fall in with the recommendations or face WTO-approved sanctions.</p>
<p>Alternatively, it could maintain the regime but pay compensation to the United States and the four Latin American countries -- Ecuador, Guatemala, Honduras and Mexico -- to the value of the trade they are losing because of it.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CARIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
