<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="452403" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE cracked fuel oils firmer, but drifts from high.</title>
<headline>NWE cracked fuel oils firmer, but drifts from high.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>NWE cracked fuel oil prices were firmer in line with crude on Wednesday, but traders said that apart from some light play on the barge market trade was thin.</p>
<p>High sulphur barges continued to get extra lift from cargo pricing in early trade but this support faded later and prices drifted off early highs.</p>
<p>High sulphur barges traded several times at $91 a tonne fob refinery Rotterdam helped by one trader's cargo pricing strategy, but prices settled back to value around $89 later.</p>
<p>Antwerp liftings were on offer at slightly weaker levels to Rotterdam with several players seen long of product at the port.</p>
<p>High sulphur cargoes firmed around $3 per tonne to value around $88 cif NWE early but trade was thin and a slight softening in crude pulled off some of the gain.</p>
<p>Traders said there was little fresh demand from end-users at these higher levels and firm prices for fob stems in NWE continued to limit arbitrage options into the Mediterranean where recent Eastern arbitrage has drawn on supplies.</p>
<p>The low sulphur barge and cargo markets remained in the doldrums. Outright prices strengthened with crude but the high/low sulphur spread widened with low sulphur's rise limited by slack buying interest.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
