<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="452511" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>TANZANIA: Tanzania and Zanzibar agree on VAT introduction.</title>
<headline>Tanzania and Zanzibar agree on VAT introduction.</headline>
<byline>Mark Dodd</byline>
<dateline>DAR ES SALAAM 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mainland Tanzania and union partner Zanzibar islands have agreed to coordinate the timing and rate for a Value Added Tax (VAT) launch scheduled for July 1998, a senior IMF official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Zanzibar has come on board with VAT. The understanding is Zanzibar will adopt the same timetable and same rate,&quot; said Festus Osunsade, the senior representative for the International Monetary Fund (IMF) in Tanzania.</p>
<p>The rate for Tanzania's VAT was expected to be in close proximity to rates operating in Kenya and Uganda of 15 percent and 17.5 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>&quot;It will eliminate so called nuisance taxes. Once you have VAT, it means no more stamp duty, hotel levy and single transaction tax,&quot; Osunsade said.</p>
<p>Combined, the three taxes total more than 30 percent.</p>
<p>Osunsade said the agreement to harmonise VAT followed a week of high-level discussions between senior IMF officials, Tanzania and Zanzibar. Zanzibar is semi-autonomous but forms part of the United Republic of Tanzania.</p>
<p>He said the agreement on VAT marked an important development and would help to prevent the re-emergence of an infamous channel of tax evasion known locally as the &quot;Zanzibar route.&quot;</p>
<p>Harmonisation of import tarriffs was agreed to earlier this year. The &quot;Zanzibar route&quot; thrived by offering importers a lower tax rate than the official rate in force on the mainland.</p>
<p>&quot;The Zanzibar route was also used to evade taxation because there are no pre-shipment inspection agencies like SGS (Societe Generale Surveillance) in Zanzibar,&quot; said a government parliamentary report into corruption, dated September 1996.</p>
<p>The only pre-shipment inspection applies to government goods and not those intended for the private sector.</p>
<p>In 1964, following a bloody revolution, Zanzibar and Pemba islands joined with the republic of Tanganyika to form the United Republic of Tanzania.</p>
<p>Taxation has emerged as a major political issue in Tanzania. Local manufacturers complain that the tax system is too complicated and offered little incentive for the creation of thriving home-grown industries.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the IMF's deputy director for fiscal affairs, Jeffry Davis and other senior IMF officials held talks with Tanzanian President Benjamin Mkapa to discuss a wide range of economic issues including taxation.</p>
<p>The talks focused on recent lobbying efforts by the local business community for tax concessions and a draft bill designed to appease their concerns. The IMF is known to be concerned that the bill in its present form contained what one official described as &quot;too many giveaways.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAR ES SALAAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TANZANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
