<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="452534" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Lebanese families flee Zaire city to S.Africa.</title>
<headline>Lebanese families flee Zaire city to S.Africa.</headline>
<byline>Lesley Wroughton</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of 25 Lebanese women and children were evacuated from Zaire's second largest city Lubumbashi to South Africa overnight as rebels of Laurent Kabila closed in on the copper capital.</p>
<p>Lebanon's ambassador to South Africa said more nationals were expected to arrive at Johannesburg's Lanseria Airport by private charter on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We helped to evacuate 25 women on Tuesday. It is up to them if they want to leave, we didn't ask anyone to leave,&quot; Ambassador Charbel Stephan told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It is mainly women and children being evacuated. Many of them say the rebels are about 200 km (125 miles) outside Lubumbashi,&quot; Stephan said.</p>
<p>The evacuees were staying with relatives or friends while their transfer papers were being processed.</p>
<p>Stephan said South African immigration authorities had given the group until March 25 to stay in South Africa after which they would either return to Zaire, by which time the situation around Lubumbashi would have become clearer, or to Lebanon.</p>
<p>There are 5,000 registered Lebanese nationals in Zaire with a community of 300 families in Lubumbashi, mostly commercial traders.</p>
<p>Many of the families who landed in South Africa said they were afraid of government soldiers who looted businesses and homes as they fled areas before rebel occupation.</p>
<p>Rebels on Monday said they were within 400 km (250 miles) of the Lubumbashi in the southern mineral-rich area of Shaba, later confirmed by officials in neighbouring Zambia.</p>
<p>On Wednesday the rebels warned government soldiers in the city and at Kikwit, 500 km (300 miles) east of the capital, to lay down their weapons.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Zambia, which shares a land and water border with Shaba, said on Wednesday it was ready to evacuate its diplomatic staff from Lubumbashi if the security situation there worsened.</p>
<p>It has eight diplomatic staff in Lubumbashi and the same number in Kinshasa.</p>
<p>&quot;We are monitoring the situation very closely, and when the time comes, we will move in,&quot; foreign affairs spokesman Kimbala Meleke told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It shouldn't be too long from now before we move in,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The civil war in Zaire has seen thousands of Zaireans crossing the border into Zambia. There are currently about 3,000 Zairean refugees camped in Zambia.</p>
<p>The Red Cross said the number of refugees kept fluctuating as some Zaireans crossed the border only to seek entry to safer parts of Zaire from the Zambian side.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very difficult to say how many Zairean are in the country at any given time,&quot; Zambia Red Cross secretary general Chipo Lungu said.</p>
<p>African leaders have gathered in the Kenyan capital Nairobi for talks on Wednesday on the Zaire crisis with Zaire's Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo, who is under pressure from both rebel advances and a parliamentary vote to oust him.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
