<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="452544" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Fair growth seen swelling S.Africa all-share index.</title>
<headline>Fair growth seen swelling S.Africa all-share index.</headline>
<byline>Melanie Cheary</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's all-share stock index, feeding off another year of reasonable economic growth, should rise some 13.5 percent by end-1997 and by a further 22 percent by end-1998.</p>
<p>Equity strategists polled by Reuters also said that the index's rise could be further spurred in 1998 by the government's macro-economic strategy kicking in later this year and lower interest rates.</p>
<p>But they added that Wall Street would still hold sway over the fate of local shares and no number of positive economic fundamentals could fully counter the negative impact for South African industrial stocks should Wall Street plunge.</p>
<p>&quot;All things being equal, and if Wall Street doesn't collapse and create turbulence in the financial markets, then we've got a reasonable chance of things going well. We could be in for even further growth by the end of 1998, even 25 percent,&quot; said David Shapiro, a director at Societe Generale Frankel Pollak.</p>
<p>The poll showed the index's 1997 closing level between 7,800 and 8,650 points with the mean pinning it at 8,130 points.</p>
<p>The all-share index closed off 26.9 on March 18 at 7,085.5 points.</p>
<p>It was seen ending 1998 at a level between 9,500 and 10,500 points with the mean at 9,936 points.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the economic conditions are settling down. There are one or two concerns, but by the second half things should be in place to call it a better 1997,&quot; Shapiro said.</p>
<p>Strategists said that while the level of the country's gold and foreign exchange reserves, the high level of credit extension and lack of job creation remained cause for concern, forecasts for the economy have so far been positive.</p>
<p>&quot;Economic fundamentals are fairly good. We expected a 2.4 percent GDP growth rate this year which is of course down on last year, but it is still a fairly good performance,&quot; said Johann Rossouw, chief economist at stockbroker Huysamer Stals.</p>
<p>Announcing the 1996/97 budget last week, Finance Minister Trevor Manuel said GDP was expected to grow 2.5 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals has painted a more upbeat picture, saying the economy could again expand by close to three percent in 1997 after 3.1 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>Looking ahead to 1998, equity strategists were more bullish.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is a year of consolidation. But I think the opinion is that perhaps in the second half of the year one is looking for a decrease in interest rates and also for the economy to start biting a little more,&quot; Shapiro said.</p>
<p>Strategists added that the stockmarket had underperformed in 1996 compared to other economic sectors and that much of the early growth this year could be due to catching up.</p>
<p>They said growth in the second half of the year could speed up due to some discounting in terms of a better expected 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;The combination of these two aspects with the fairly good expected GDP performance of this year will boost the overall index up,&quot; Rossouw said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
<p>For poll details see  EQUITYPOLL11</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
