<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="452669" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia builds gold stocks but can Moscow afford it?.</title>
<headline>Russia builds gold stocks but can Moscow afford it?.</headline>
<byline>Lynnley Browning</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's Central Bank said on Wednesday it aimed to boost its gold stocks by nearly 25 percent a year in a move dealers said was mildly bullish for bullion markets but which raised questions about how it could be done.</p>
<p>Deputy chairman Sergei Aleksashenko said the bank, which had around 400 tonnes of gold at the end of January, aimed over 1997 and 1998 to increase its bullion reserves by 90 tonnes a year, Interfax news agency said.</p>
<p>The statement is a policy change for Russia, which in recent years has exported the shrinking amounts of gold it mines to finance and bolster painful economic reforms.</p>
<p>The gold price rose only 30-40 cents to around $349 an ounce on the news. But dealers were still happy at the thought of supplies staying snug and tight in the Russian Central Bank and not flooding markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Any news which means gold is not going to come on to the market is mildly bullish and the price went up a little on this,&quot; one London-based dealer said.</p>
<p>Aleksashenko said nothing about exports, leaving analysts wondering how Russia could afford to go without selling an extra $1 billion in gold a year.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a fairly major policy change,&quot; said Roger Chaplin, mining analyst at T Hoare &amp; Co in London. &quot;Up until now Russia has sold gold -- they've sold all their stockpiles down.</p>
<p>&quot;The big question is, can Russia afford to do that?&quot;</p>
<p>Russia can barely afford to finance gold production, and domestic commercial banks are screaming to get involved once the tightly-regulated sector is liberalised.</p>
<p>But Aleksashenko said the Central Bank would for now remain the sole buyer of gold and that bullion exports by commercial banks were unreasonable.</p>
<p>The Central Bank's 400 tonnes include gold transferred  from the separate strategic Goskhran reserves -- making the central bank home to 90 percent of Russian gold reserves, Aleksashenko said.</p>
<p>Russia was the fifth largest gold producer in 1995 when it produced over 142 tonnes compared with 158 tonnes the previous year, according to market research group Gold Fields Mineral Services.</p>
<p>But the domestic gold supply story has looked increasingly sad in recent years, as output plunges, miners are paid late and stockpiles shrink.</p>
<p>Russian 1996 gold output is variously pegged at 124 tonnes by the precious metals department at the now-defunct Industry Ministry and at a lowly 100 tonnes by the State Statistics Committee. Industry sources say the latter's figures underreport the situation.</p>
<p>But the secrecy and uncertainty shrouding Russian bullion and other stockpiles still keeps markets on their toes. Russia's other precious metals, like platinum and palladium, are veiled in much more secrecy than gold.</p>
<p>Still, dealers have not forgotton the shock of discovering that Russia's gold reserves in the 1980s -- put by Western intelligence organisations at a whopping 3,000 or so tonnes -- were really a lowly 150-200 tonnes.</p>
<p>The Central Bank's acquisition target follows January comments by its deputy press director Natalya Khomenko that gold was not leaving the country.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Central Bank may be trying to bolster its reputation abroad but declined to speculate if this was part of Moscow's push on to Eurobond markets, or of its plans to make the rouble fully convertible.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the bank) needs some international credibility -- when you have gold, you have a very hard currency,&quot; Chaplin said, adding that in this sense, Moscow was taking the same approach as European central banks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
