<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="452696" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Slower zloty crawl possible when exports pick up.</title>
<headline>Slower zloty crawl possible when exports pick up.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland may consider slowing the crawling devaluation of the zloty once export growth begins catching up with fast growing imports, Finance Minister Marek Belka said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If rates of import and export growth start converging we might...consider following the budget plan in this (zloty devaluation rate) respect,&quot; Belka told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>The zloty is now being devalued at a monthly rate of one percent against a basket of five western currencies, which translates into an annual devaluation of 12.7 percent while the 1997 budget assumes a 9.1 percent annual rate of devaluation.  </p>
<p>Exchange rate decisions including those on the crawling devaluation rate are made by central bank in consultation with the finance minister and the economy minister.</p>
<p>Belka said January current account data was a promising signal despite showing a gaping $1.48 billion trade deficit as exports grew 10 percent year-on-year despite a stronger dollar.</p>
<p>But he added the signal of export growth picking up needed to be confirmed over a longer period before any decisions could be made.</p>
<p>In January exports were 9.7 percent higher than in January 1996 while imports were 41 percent higher. In the whole of 1996 Polish exports grew 6.7 percent while imports rose 31.9 percent.</p>
<p>Both the finance ministry and the central bank have said that as long as import growth continued to outpace that of exports there was no room for a slower zloty crawl and the domestic currency's real appreciation.</p>
<p>The 1997 budget assumes that the trade gap will widen to $9 billion from last year's $8.2 billion but several analysts say a wider deficit of $12 billion or more is possible.</p>
<p>-- Tomasz Janowski +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
