<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45264" id="root" date="1996-09-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Sept 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Sept 10.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-09-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Tuesday morning's Austrian newspapers.</p>
<p>DER STANDARD</p>
<p>- German insurance giant Allianz shows renewed interest in Austria's Creditanstalt if Finance Minister Viktor Klima reopens bidding. Klima still has to check Friday's last-minute bid from the consortium led by EA-Generali. Die Erste savings bank is also interested in the new tender.</p>
<p>- Industrial Economos' pre-tax loss dropped to 21.9 million schillings in the first half of 1996 after a loss of 10.1 million the previous year.</p>
<p>- Jam producer Adolf Darbo AG manages turnaround to pre-tax profit of 8.5 million schillings in the first half from last year's pre-tax loss of 6.1 million schillings. The turnaround is largely due to higher exports.</p>
<p>- Austria's first private mobile phone provider max.mobil threatens to take legal action against the federal Post and Telekom if the latter does not pay its licence fees worth four billion schillings to the government.</p>
<p>KURIER</p>
<p>- Austria Tabak's sales increased 8.3 percent in the first half due to growing exports, but sales in Austria fell due to cheap duty-free shops along Austria's borders.</p>
<p>- Boehler-Uddeholm chief Claus Raidl says the steelmaker may shed jobs if demand in its key markets continues falling.</p>
<p>- Insurer s-Lebensversicherungen, a unit of Austrian Sparkassen, life insurance sales jumped 215 percent in the first half. Premium earnings climbed to 4.4 billion schillings.</p>
<p>DIE PRESSE</p>
<p>- Optimism in Austrian industry is improving due to higher demand of late. Investments are planned, although there could be more job losses.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
