<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="452640" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>LITHUANIA: Lithuanian shares ease as investors mull dividends. [CORRECTED 16:35 GMT]</title>
<headline>Lithuanian shares ease as investors mull dividends. [CORRECTED 16:35 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>VILNIUS 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lithuanian shares eased in light trade on Wednesday as investors mulled low dividends and waited for the results from a spate of shareholders' meetings, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Lintin A index fell 17.91 points to 2,587.41 in central market trade of 1.8 million litas.</p>
<p>Trade in several companies has been suspended pending shareholders' meetings and dealers said investors were holding their breath waiting for the outcomes.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices seem to have stabilized, but these meetings will have an impact on share prices,&quot; Robertas Birzinskas of Vilniaus Bank's brokerage company told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are a bit hesitant right now because dividends have not been very high, even on shares from companies with good profits,&quot; said Arvydas Kvietkauskas of Hermis Bank's brokerage firm.</p>
<p>&quot;Even Vilniaus Bank's proposed dividends are not so high despite its good results,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Vilniaus Bank announced on Monday that it planned to retain most of its 24.4 million litas 1996 net profit within the company.</p>
<p>Vilniaus Bank's ordinary shares were one of the session's casualties, falling almost ten percent to 234.00 litas in light trade of only 4,680 litas.</p>
<p>Its preferential shares were unchanged at 1,600 litas and turned over 46,400 litas.</p>
<p>Hermis Bank's shares were unchanged at 190.00 litas in relatively high demand, turning over almost 522,000 litas.</p>
<p>Lithuania Gas rose to 2.37 litas from 2.35 litas in trade of almost 276,000 litas. (Corrects share movement)</p>
<p>Block trades turned over only 68,000 litas.</p>
<p>--Ed Stoddard, Vilnius newsroom +370 2 22 35 18</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VILNIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LITHUANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
