<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="452737" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - March 19.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - March 19.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>24 CHASA</p>
<p>-- The European Union and other lenders will provide additional support of up to $500 million following Bulgaria's financial accord with the International Monetary Fund, EU External Affairs commissioner Hans van den Broek said. @</p>
<p>-- Leaders of Bulgaria's main political parties pledged their backing for the International Monetary Fund programme and President Petar Stoyanov appealed to Bulgarians to get to work to make it succeed.</p>
<p>-- Electricity prices will rise 25-30 percent from April 1, Bulgaria's Energy minister Georgi Stoilov said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's biggest oil refinery Neftochim said it would halt production of two grades of leaded petrol and will produce another one instead from April 1 in line with European standards. @</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's cabinet approved a compensation of $250 per person for people laid off from closed state loss-making plants, National Labour Exchange director Milcho Dimitrov said.</p>
<p>-- Two German and one Greek company have submitted bids for a 51 percent stake in Bulgaria's cement producer Zlatna Panega, the Construction ministry said. Zlatna Panega's annual output is around 900,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's foreign trade turnover fell to $8.8 billion in 1996 from $10.2 billion in 1995, Trade minister Daniela Bobeva said. @</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's Social care ministry, trade unions and the National Statistics Institute agreed to set up an additional consumer price index based on a smaller basket of 573 basic goods to be used only in revisisons of wages and pensions, Social care minister Ivan Neikov said.</p>
<p>TRUD</p>
<p>-- Passenger railway fares will rise 2.5 times from March 20, Bulgarian State Railways said. @</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's state Bulbank would provide $50-60 million for stabilisation of local banks in line with a financial accord with the International Monetary Fund, Prime minister Stefan Sofianski said.</p>
<p>PARI</p>
<p>-- The Bulgarian National Bank said it restored its practice of calculating a daily lev/dollar fixing irrespective of daily traded volumes due to the relative lev stability on the local interbank market in March. @</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria and the International Monetary Fund (IMF) agreed that Bulgarian commercial banks should reach six percent capital to risk assets ratio by the end of this year instead of the 12 percent previuosly proposed by the IMF.</p>
<p>STANDART</p>
<p>-- The European Union (EU) was expected to abolish visa charges for Bulgarians as a first step towards easing travelling of Bulgarians to the EU member countries, EU External Affairs commissioner Hans van den Broek said.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 981 8569</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
