<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45285" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa Saldanha Steel project on track - director. [CORRECTED 12/9 14:00 GMT]</title>
<headline>S.Africa Saldanha Steel project on track - director. [CORRECTED 12/9 14:00 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Construction of the Saldanha Steel project was underway and on track to begin production in January 1998 within the 4.5 billion rand budget, deputy project director Ras Alberts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In a presentation to parliament's environment affairs committee, Alberts rejected media reports that cost overruns and falling steel prices threatened the project's viability.</p>
<p>The project is a joint venture between Iscor and the Independent Development Corp (IDC) (Corrects from Independent Development Trust, IDT).</p>
<p>&quot;At this point in time, we will complete the project within the 4.5 billion in July 1995 rands,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The current slump in world steel prices would not undermine the viability of the controversial plant being built near an iron ore terminal in Saldanha Bay and close to the ecologically sensitive Langebaan Lagoon, north of Cape Town, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Steel prices are cyclical and the company expects that the current slump will have ended before we begin production in 1998. But we will make a profit even at current prices,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Alberts declined to answer a question during his presentation on how Saldanha Steel had qualified for a 1.6 billion rand tax incentive, but promised a written response.</p>
<p>He told Reuters later that in terms of the tax incentive, Saldanha Steel would be obliged to export its full 1.25 million-tonne annual production of hot-rolled coils, which would be marketed in one to eight millimetre forms.</p>
<p>Downstream beneficiation, which could include independent pipe-making and galvanising plants planned alongside the steel mill, also would have to focus on export, he said.</p>
<p>Alberts denied media allegations of a deal for Saldanha Steel to take over production from Iscor's Vanderbijlpark facility, saying the companies would operate in competition.</p>
<p>Logistics and environment manager Alex Holmes said the company would meet all the environmental obligations imposed by the provincial administration as conditions for approval of the plant, which was opposed by environmental watchdogs.</p>
<p>He said the company would use a daily average of 12,600 cubic metres of water from the nearby Berg River and a previously untouched underground lake.</p>
<p>Dry-cooling arrangements that would cost 3.5 million rand a year to operate had cut the water requirement by 10,000 cubic metres a day.</p>
<p>Holmes said the plant would not dump any effluent, but would produce slag products that could be sold to other industries and 40 tonnes a day of solid waste that would have to be disposed of in a licenced facility.</p>
<p>He said the company would be able to meet the environmental requirement that it could survive a storm of the severity encountered only once in 20 years without waste spillage.</p>
<p>Twenty-two boreholes and a downwind monitoring facility would guard against ground and air pollution, he said.</p>
<p>-- Cape Town newsroom, +27 21 403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
