<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="452862" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Twin blast injures five in northeast Colombia.</title>
<headline>Twin blast injures five in northeast Colombia.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two bombs exploded in northeast Colombia early on Wednesday, injuring five people, in the latest dynamite attacks by leftist guerrillas, police said.</p>
<p>The blasts in downtown Bucaramanga, Santander province, came on the same day that President Ernesto Samper and National Police chief Gen. Rosso Jose Serrano were scheduled to visit the city.</p>
<p>&quot;Terrorism has arrived in our city. This marks the escalation of a wave of bombings in the east of the country,&quot; said city mayor Carlos Ibanez.</p>
<p>A police spokesman said two men were captured shortly after the explosions, which damaged the premises of a cattle ranchers' association and the chamber of commerce.</p>
<p>He said the National Liberation Army (ELN), Colombia's second largest rebel group set up by radical Roman Catholic priests in the mid-1960s, was thought to be behind the attacks.</p>
<p>The attacks came 24 hours after two car bombs exploded in Cucuta, in neighbouring Norte de Santander province, in which an 18-month-old girl died.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
