<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453038" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan King blasts Kabariti for &quot;failing as PM&quot;.</title>
<headline>Jordan King blasts Kabariti for &quot;failing as PM&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Suleiman al-Khalidi</byline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>King Hussein of Jordan launched a fierce attack on outgoing Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti on Wednesday, saying he was a failure who sought publicity to the detriment of his job.</p>
<p>King Hussein, accepting Kabariti's letter of resignation, accused him of cultivating a flamboyant media image at the expense of state matters and said Kabariti had let him down.</p>
<p>&quot;I have not been accustomed to writing such letters to heads of my government when they resign,&quot; the king told Kabariti in a letter carried by the state news agency Petra.</p>
<p>&quot;You chose ... to emphasise the prime minister's media image in every problem and issue,&quot; the king said. &quot;My excuse for you was that you were exhausted to the point of leaving the essential matters for which I had chosen you to tackle in the first place.&quot;</p>
<p>King Hussein said it was Kabariti's unwillingness to admit failure which prompted him to depart from his customary grace in responding to resigning prime ministers.</p>
<p>&quot;Only God is above wrong doing but the lucky and aware person is the one who admits a mistake, not the person who insists on justifying it,&quot; the king said.</p>
<p>There was no word of personal thanks in the long letter to Kabariti for his 13-month premiership.</p>
<p>Kabariti's supporters say he was a bold decision maker whose active reformist policies ran up against resistance from entrenched interests and rival old guard politicians.</p>
<p>His dismissal on Wednesday came as a surprise to many and King Hussein said up until just a few days ago Kabariti's name &quot;was in the forefront of the names of candidates to carry the responsibility in the coming days.&quot;</p>
<p>But the king said a visit to an orphanage three weeks ago with Kabariti had opened his eyes to what he said was Kabariti's lack of concern for society's most vulnerable members.</p>
<p>The visit prompted him to ...&quot;question whether it was the same youthful man whom I had chosen to head the government over others,&quot; the king said.</p>
<p>The king was so moved by the conditions of the orphans that he ordered them to be moved into his guest house palace.</p>
<p>&quot;What most pained me was your coming to the defence of the tragic situation of the social welfare institutions and the minister's performance, and his defence of his achievements that did not change the picture I had seen,&quot; the king said.</p>
<p>The king said that he was again appalled when after telling Kabariti of his decision to dismiss him on Tuesday it was ... &quot;the crying minister's image in front of you that moved you more that the image of the children and their suffering.&quot;</p>
<p>Kabariti declined to give reasons for his dismissal but suggested it was connected to a recent flare-up of tensions with Israel. &quot;It is Jordan's fate always to be in the centre of events and storms,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In reply to Kabariti's complaint that he was fought by a ...&quot;small group which defended narrow interests&quot; ... the king told him he was an intolerant hypocrite.</p>
<p>&quot;When when you talk about the virtues of democracy ... and what your government achieved ... and then your criticism of a small group that has opposed your view ... this contradicts the basis of democracy and freedom which allows the other view,&quot; the king told Kabariti.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
