<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453100" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. High Court allows endangered species lawsuit.</title>
<headline>U.S. High Court allows endangered species lawsuit.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A unanimous Supreme Court ruled Wednesday that ranchers and irrigation districts may sue under the endangered species law to block the government from cutting their water allocations to save endangered fish.</p>
<p>The justices overturned a federal appeals court ruling that the ranch operators and two water districts in Oregon did not fall within the &quot;zone of interest&quot; of the Endangered Species Act and therefore could not bring the lawsuit.</p>
<p>The ranchers argued that cutting their water allocations to maintain higher reservoir levels for fish would harm their businesses and property values. The case represented a test of a new tactic used by business and private property rights advocates to try to curb the government's efforts to protect endangered wildlife when it causes economic losses.</p>
<p>Private interests have used different avenues such as safeguards against government &quot;taking&quot; of private property or suing to block government actions to protect species. But this time they sued under the Endangered Species Act itself, using its &quot;citizen suit&quot; provision.</p>
<p>The federal government argued that the provision was meant to be an avenue for lawsuits on enforcing the law to protect wildlife that previously limited its use to environmentalists.</p>
<p>But the Supreme Court, in a decision written by Justice Antonin Scalia, ruled against the government's position. He said the ranchers and water districts had legal standing to seek judicial review of the government's opinion that the project might affect two endangered species of fish.</p>
<p>The Interior Department wanted to limit the release of water from the Klamath Irrigation Project near the Oregon-California border to protect the endangered fish, the Lost River sucker and the shortnose sucker.</p>
<p>The lawsuit previously had been dismissed, but the Supreme Court reinstated it and sent the case back to the lower court so the lawsuit can go forward.</p>
<p>Property rights advocates said the decision opened another path to challenge the Endangered Species Act, and said it could speed up court cases.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically if their interests or property rights are affected by the Endangered Species Act, they'll be able to have their day in court. Not allowing someone to proceed under the ESA forced use of other avenues under other laws that could take decades,&quot; Barry Hodge, general counsel for Defenders of Property Rights, said.</p>
<p>Heather Weiner, of the Sierra Club Legal Defence Fund, said the decision likely will result in more lawsuits filed over the Endangered Species Act, but she said it did not necessarily give industry and property rights groups an edge over environmentalists.</p>
<p>&quot;Our position has always been that citizens ought to have equal access to the courts,&quot; Weiner said. &quot;The irony is that these industry groups have spent tens of millions of dollars to try to deprive us of that access.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
