<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453151" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Los Angeles County braces for welfare ruling.</title>
<headline>Los Angeles County braces for welfare ruling.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Attorneys for Los Angeles County have warned the board of supervisors that an appeals court panel is likely to rule against the county in a welfare case that could cost it up to $160 million, county attorneys said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A panel of the state court of appeal in Los Angeles heard arguments in late February in a case that will determine whether the county is liable for the payment of retroactive benefits to county general relief welfare recipients, whose grants were reduced by $73 from 1993 to 1995.</p>
<p>The panel is expected to rule in the coming weeks.  </p>
<p>&quot;Based upon the questions posed by the three-member panel, we anticipate that the court's forthcoming decision will be adverse to the county,&quot; County Counsel De Witt Clinton said in a February letter to supervisors, released on Wednesday.</p>
<p>County attorneys said they were working with the chief administrator on proposals to cope with the court's ruling.</p>
<p>In 1993, a class action lawsuit, dubbed the Gardner case, was filed by the Western Center on Law and Poverty and other public interest law firms on behalf of Los Angeles County general relief recipients. The lawsuit demanded that the county maintain the level of welfare benefits.  </p>
<p>The state trial court refused to issue a preliminary injunction against the county. But the trial court decision was reversed by the court of appeal in 1995.</p>
<p>In 1996, attorneys for the welfare recipients asked the trial court to order the county to repay those recipients whose benefits were reduced in 1993, 1994 and 1995.</p>
<p>The trial court agreed, ordering the county to pay retroactive benefits to more than 100,000 general relief recipients.</p>
<p>The county appealed the trial court decision back to the state court of appeal, which is now considering the matter.  </p>
<p>Attorneys involved in the case said the county could be liable to pay up to $160 million if it loses the case. The amount the county would be forced to pay would depend on the number of welfare recipients that file claims.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
