<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453206" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ConAgra agrees to pay $8.3 mln fine in grain mishandling case.</title>
<headline>ConAgra agrees to pay $8.3 mln fine in grain mishandling case.</headline>
<dateline>OMAHA, Neb. 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>ConAgra Inc. pleaded guilty Wednesday to federal charges that its Peavey Co. adulterated, misgraded and misweighed grain at grain elevators and agreed to pay $8.3 million in penalties, ConAgra and the government said.</p>
<p>The Omaha, Neb.-based diversified food company pleaded guilty in U.S. District Court in Terre Haute, Ind., to charges involving 12 small and medium-size grain elevators over a four-year period ending in 1992.</p>
<p>&quot;ConAgra used several schemes to defraud farmers and grain buyers to increase their own grain inventories and profits,&quot; the U.S. Agriculture Department said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Soybeans were purposefully misgraded, allowing ConAgra to pay less to the farmer yet sell at higher rates; water was added to grain inventories ... adding to its weight and increasing profits when the grain was sold; and ConAgra significantly misweighed grain being sold to end users ... shipping less grain than for which they were paid,&quot; the department said.</p>
<p>In addition, &quot;gratuities&quot; were given to government-licensed grain samplers, who allowed elevator employees to substitute better-quality grain samples for poor-quality grain, the department said.</p>
<p>The penalty included a criminal fine of about $4.4 million, a reimbursement of $450,000 to the U.S. Agriculture Department for unearned storage payments and expenses associated with the investigation, and about $3.45 million as compensation for criminal profits, the department said in a statement.</p>
<p>The $8.3 million penalty is in addition to an earlier civil settlement of more than $2 million that was reached between ConAgra and a group of Indiana farmers, the department said.</p>
<p>The agency said four former ConAgra managers also agreed to plead guilty to criminal charges. The company said no one charged in the case works for Peavey or ConAgra today.</p>
<p>Peavey is an independent operating company and part of ConAgra Trading and Processing Cos., a division of ConAgra.</p>
<p>&quot;We regret the conduct at the facilities involved,&quot; Thomas Manuel, president of ConAgra Trading and Processing Cos., said in a statement. &quot;We offer no excuses and we've made it very clear that we do not tolerate such conduct.&quot;</p>
<p>ConAgra said it and Peavey have acted to decrease the likelihood of similar problems in the future, and Peavey has put into effect compliance programmes and training for all employees.</p>
<p>ConAgra said it entered into a compliance agreement with the Agriculture Department tha t it said will result in no administrative actions being taken against the company.</p>
<p>The agreement requires the implementation of several compliance programmes at grain elevators. Many of those programmes are already in place.</p>
<p>The Agriculture Department said the charges amounted to violations of the U.S. Grain Standards Act, the U.S. Warehouse Act and the U.S. Food, Drug and Cosmetics Act.</p>
<p>The department said the settlement with ConAgra culminates a four-year investigation by a task force headed by the agency's Office of Inspector General.</p>
<p>Peavey operates 76 U.S. elevators.</p>
<p>ConAgra's stock rose 75 cents to $56.75 in consolidated trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OMAHA, Neb."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
