<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453214" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Western may need partner to top Tyco bid.</title>
<headline>Western may need partner to top Tyco bid.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Intindola</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Western Resources Inc may need a partner if it wants to retake the offensive in its hostile bid for ADT Ltd, analysts and investment bankers said.</p>
<p>Western's stock and cash offer of $3.5 billion, or $22.50 a share, is competing against Tyco International Ltd's friendly stock agreement, worth $29 per share, or a total of $5.6 billion.  </p>
<p>The Tyco deal, disclosed Monday, is structured as a reverse merger, which neutralizes Western's &quot;dissenter rights,&quot; or its option to take cash for its ADT shares at a court-supervised appraisal. As a result, Western's best hope of prevailing is to top Tyco's offer, investment bankers and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Outside of Western offering $30 per share, or a considerably raised cash component, which I don't think they can do, they would have to find a big partner,&quot; said Jeffrey Kessler, a Lehman Brothers analyst who follows ADT, which installs and services electronic security systems.  </p>
<p>Under a complex arrangement, Tyco agreed to merge with a unit of ADT; the ADT parent company would then be renamed Tyco International Ltd, Tyco said.</p>
<p>Dissenter rights allow shareholders who disagree with a proposed merger to go to court to obtain an appraised market value of their shares. They then would be offered cash for their stock based on that appraisal.</p>
<p>If Western had such rights and took cash for its shares, it could destroy the pooling-of-interest accounting, a condition necessary for the Tyco deal to proceed.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Tyco agreement is much closer to our valuation of what ADT is worth, which is far more than $22.50 per share, because ADT is moving from being an electronic security company to one providing a gateway to the home to control all kinds of sensors,&quot; Kessler said.</p>
<p>Western, a Kansas-based utility company, already owns 27 percent of ADT, or 38.3 million shares. It acquired the stake in multiple transactions for $589 million, which equals a cost basis of $15.40 per share, a Western spokesman said.  </p>
<p>With its ADT stake, Western also stands to walk away with an estimated $500 million gain under the current offer by Tyco, a diversified maker of industrial and commercial products.</p>
<p>While the sources did not know of any ongoing discussions between Western and other possible partners, they said companies that would make the most sense as co-bidders include Ameritech Corp and MCI Communications Corp.  </p>
<p>Ameritech could join Western in sweetening its offer for ADT, though any cooperation would have to be structured around limitations imposed on Ameritech's buying additional alarm-monitoring companies, as mandated in the Telecommunications Act of 1996, according to analysts and attorneys.</p>
<p>While Ameritech is barred from acquiring additional companies such as ADT, it is allowed to acquire select assets of electronic alarm businesses, according to a Washington attorney who helped write the act while on the staff of the House Commerce Committee.  </p>
<p>Ameritech can &quot;grow the business, acquire customer lists and so forth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Western and Ameritech have declined to comment on a possible joint bid for ADT.</p>
<p>A partnership with MCI would expand an existing relationship initiated when Western acquired Westinghouse Security. The latter provides home and business security monitoring bundled with other MCI telephone services.</p>
<p>An MCI spokesman declined to comment on the speculation, but said the company &quot;is not aggressively marketing the security products at this time.&quot;</p>
<p>((--Wall Street Desk, 212-859-1734))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
