<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453250" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX crude ends off in late session profit-taking.</title>
<headline>NYMEX crude ends off in late session profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX crude abruptly turned negative late session and ended lower Wednesday on profit-taking after a rally in oil prices pushed crude up almost $1.75 a barrel in two days.</p>
<p>&quot;We had some late session profit-taking by longs, so they could get out of the way before tomorrow's expiry. We had gone up in a hurry,&quot; said a New York crude trader.</p>
<p>April crude ended two cents a barrel lower at $22.04 after rising as much as 59 cents to $22.65. Mid-session, bullish oil inventory data and barge shipment delays pushed spot crude through resistance levels, triggering buy stops, dealers said.  </p>
<p>But, by late session, traders said some refiners started to roll positions from April crude to May ahead of the April contract expiry Thursday.</p>
<p>Some refined product shipments from the U.S. Gulf have been delayed due to the closure late Monday of a two-and-a-half mile section of the Mississippi River near Baton Rouge, Lousiana. A string of barges had collided late Monday with a bridge. After the market's close Wednesday, the U.S. Coast Guard said the area had been reopened.</p>
<p>April gasoline ended up 0.48 cent at 67.96 cents a gallon. April heating oil ended up 0.11 cent at 56.29 cents a gallon.  </p>
<p>&quot;I saw a lot of refiner selling in gasoline,&quot; said Gerald Samuels, managing director at ARB Oil, noting gasoline ended off its session high of 69.00 cents.</p>
<p>The profit-taking set in after larger-than-expected draws in refined product stocks helped extend a rally in oil prices that had started with heavy short covering on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Tuesday evening, the American Petroleum Institute (API) said gasoline stocks fell 4.3 million barrels for the the week ended March 14 when traders had expected inventory to be about steady with the week before.</p>
<p>Distillate stocks, which include heating oil and diesel, fell 3.5 million barrels, when an average of trader estimates called for a draw of 1.25 million barrels.</p>
<p>The short covering rally in crude Tuesday and part of Wednesday follows the CFTC Futures Committment of Traders report that reflects positions as of March 11 showing a small speculators had acquired significant short positions in crude.</p>
<p>Tuesday's short covering had decreased open interest in crude by 4,071 lots, which means crude will need to rely on newly found technical strength for price gains short term, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market should go back to $23.00. Technically the market is strong short-term,&quot; said Jake Bernstein, president of MBH Commodity Advisors.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, spot crude had broken trendline resistance on the April chart that lay around $20.50 and that extends from the April contract high of $25.30 on January 9. The same level also reprsented 50 percent retracement from the contract high to April's seven-month low of $19.86.</p>
<p>-- Harry Milling, New York Energy Desk, 212-859-1761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
