<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453222" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE cocoa ends sharply lower as specs liquidate.</title>
<headline>CSCE cocoa ends sharply lower as specs liquidate.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE cocoa futures posted heavy losses for the second day in a row on Wednesday, as a late round of speculative long liquidation drove prices toward session lows, trading sources said.</p>
<p>Most-active May futures fell $28 a tonne on the day, to $1,431, after ranging from $1,464 to $1,430. July finished down $27, to $1,458, while the back months closed $20 to $30 lower.</p>
<p>&quot;The small specs who bought this market are getting nervous,&quot; one trader said. &quot;The market is calming down. People are now just looking to buy the dips at best.&quot;</p>
<p>After prices surged to seven-month highs on Monday, traders said sentiment turned after a sharp increase in speculative long positions and a reassessment by broker GNI of the 1996/97 Ivorian cocoa crop.</p>
<p>GNI said Tuesday that arrivals data pointed to a total Ivorian 1996/97 cocoa crop of at least 1.1 million tonnes, which would indicate a rise of 150,000 tonnes on GNI's last projection in January.</p>
<p>Traders ignored the latest Ghana's weekly cocoa purchase figures which tailed off, saying a slow was to be expected during this time of the season.</p>
<p>Purchases were 2,428 tonnes in the 20th week ending February 27, down from 5,702 the week before. The cumulative amounted to 294,216 lots.</p>
<p>Technically, dealers said May near-term support was pegged at $1,425, then $1,418-$1,415. A major downside target was seen at a chart gap between $1,403 and $1,395.</p>
<p>Volume reached an estimated 8,191 lots, down from Tuesday's official tally of 10,128 lots.</p>
<p>((--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
