<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453204" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Albright to visit N.Carolina as Helms' guest.</title>
<headline>Albright to visit N.Carolina as Helms' guest.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright will visit North Carolina next week in a bipartisan gesture to Republican Sen. Jesse Helms, a staunch foe of many of her policies, the State Department said Wednesday.</p>
<p>She will attend a lunch in Charlotte Tuesday hosted by the Jesse Helms Centre, then travel to the town of Wingate, where the centre is located, and give a joint news conference with the North Carolina senator, spokesman Nicholas Burns said.</p>
<p>Burns told a news briefing that at the invitation of Helms, chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, Albright would later have dinner at Wingate University with him and members of his family and give a policy speech there.</p>
<p>Earlier in the one-day trip she will meet U.S. troops at the Camp Lejeune military base.</p>
<p>&quot;She's doing it, obviously, because on the one hand, she believes it's very important to travel around the United States and speak to the American people about foreign policy ... and she thinks it's a very good display of bipartisanship,&quot; Burns said.</p>
<p>The deeply conservative Helms has opposed Clinton administration policies ranging from payment of arrears to the United Nations to ratifying the Chemical Weapons Convention.</p>
<p>But he took a chivalrous attitude toward Albright at her confirmation hearings in January and her nomination passed the Senate without opposition.</p>
<p>Burns denied a reporter's suggestion that Albright was &quot;kowtowing&quot; to Helms by spending a day with him. But he added: &quot;He's a very powerful man. And a lot of what we need to do will go through his committee.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;She felt that by honouring Senator Helms, by going there, by spending a day with him, she would send a clear and unmistakable signal that she wants to do business with the Republican majority in the Congress,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Albright is seeking to counter a perceived isolationist trend in the U.S. public by promoting foreign affairs around the country. Her first trip outside Washington after her appointment was to Houston, Texas, in January.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
