<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453314" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Consumer prices up modestly before rate-setting session.</title>
<headline>Consumer prices up modestly before rate-setting session.</headline>
<byline>Alver Carlson</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The government said Wednesday that consumer prices rose more than expected last month, but the increase was not big enough to set off alarms just days before policy-makers decide whether to boost interest rates to control inflation.</p>
<p>The Labour Department said the Consumer Price Index edged up a slightly higher-than-expected 0.3 percent in February following a 0.1 percent gain in January.</p>
<p>Analysts said the modest increase did not offer any definitive clues about what the Federal Reserve's policy-making Federal Open Market Committee might do about interest rates at its meeting next week.</p>
<p>&quot;For those looking for some resolution of the Fed's dilemma, today's report was almost the worst possible outcome -- not weak enough or strong enough to tell the market or the Fed anything new,&quot; said economist David Orr of First Union Corp. in Charlotte, N.C.</p>
<p>Analysts said the increase in the CPI was not great enough to suggest that runaway prices may prompt a surge in inflation, but it was also not small enough to decisively head off a potential pre-emptive rate hike by the Fed.</p>
<p>Consumer and wholesale prices were expected to be a featured topic at the the central bank's session Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Fed has not raised interest rates in more than two years, but Chairman Alan Greenspan has warned recently of inflationary risks, primarily due to low unemployment.</p>
<p>Many analysts say a small rate hike by the Fed would not take much steam out of a buoyant economy and might carry the current expansion into its seventh year.</p>
<p>Bond prices had climbed just before the report's release, anticipating a smaller 0.2 percent consumer price rise because last week's report on wholesale prices showed actual price declines for a second straight month during February.</p>
<p>But the bond price gains were erased on disappointment that consumer prices were a shade higher than expected as the yield, which moves in an opposite direction to prices, rose to 6.98 percent.</p>
<p>Prices also fell sharply on the New York Stock Exchange and the the Nasdaq market.</p>
<p>John Snyder, executive vice president of Boston-based John Hancock Funds, said global competition, plentiful commodities and a strong dollar were keeping a lid on prices, but the greater threat for potential inflation came from wage rises in a tight labour market.</p>
<p>A Fed rate increase sooner rather than later might settle markets by ending some uncertainty about the central bank's policy intent by establishing it is forward-looking, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Long term, it's the right move, demonstrating to the markets that the Fed remains vigilant about keeping inflation firmly under control -- even if it isn't yet visible,&quot; Snyder said.</p>
<p>With often-volatile food and energy costs left out, the so-called core rate of consumer price rises, which economists believe more closely follows underlying inflation trends, rose only 0.2 percent after being up 0.1 percent in January.</p>
<p>David Kelly, managing director of Primark Decision Economics Inc. in Boston, noted there have been recent declines in imported oil prices and other commodities that augur well for muted price rises this year.</p>
<p>But the Fed must have a longer time horizon for policy changes, which raises the possibility of a small rate hike next week, Kelley suggested.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the ghost of inflation future they're worried about, not the ghost of inflation present,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Labour department said that gasoline prices, which had risen 0.7 percent in January, were flat last month while home fuel oil prices declined 1.9 percent.</p>
<p>Food price increases were led by fresh vegetables, but this was partially offset by declines in some meat costs.</p>
<p>The department said costs for transporation slipped 0.1 percent following a fall of 0.2 percent in January, while entertainment rose 0.2 percent. Airline fares were off 2.6 percent.</p>
<p>Housing prices rose 0.3 percent for the second month in a row while medical costs increased 0.2 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
