<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453362" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Views vary at IMF conference on likely euro impact.</title>
<headline>Views vary at IMF conference on likely euro impact.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Rich Miller, Economics Correspondent</p>
<p>The drive to create a zone of currency stability within Europe with the 1999 launch of monetary union could paradoxically lead to greater volatility in foreign exchange markets outside.</p>
<p>That was one of the fears frequently expressed at a two-day conference on European monetary union run by the International Monetary Fund here.</p>
<p>&quot;The incidences of (currency) misalignments could become more frequent and more damaging,&quot; IMF Managing Director Michel Camdessus told the conference of academics, government and Fund officials.</p>
<p>That is because of an expected shift away from a world monetary system dominated by a single currency, the U.S. dollar, to a bipolar or tripolar one, with an enhanced role for the new European currency and perhaps the Japanese yen.</p>
<p>Attendees at the conference were divided over how the foreign exchange markets will react to the introduction of Europe's new currency, the euro, on Jan. 1, 1999.</p>
<p>Some, including influential private economist Fred Bergsten, argued that the euro could rise sharply, but others were sceptical given the economic problems facing Europe.</p>
<p>There was surprisingly little discussion at the conference -- at least publicly -- over what the markets are fretting about now -- the possibility of a delay in the launch of EMU.</p>
<p>The markets have been abuzz recently with rumors that the Jan. 1, 1999 start of EMU will be delayed because of the difficulties that many countries, particularly Germany, face in meeting the Maastricht budget criteria for this year.</p>
<p>Camdessus came out strongly against any delay and suggested that there was room for intepretation in the tough criteria to allow the ambitious project to go ahead.</p>
<p>But a senior German Finance Ministry official said he could not exclude the possibility that the launch of European monetary union might be delayed, but added he did not think that was likely.</p>
<p>&quot;For me, the most likely outcome is that we will start on time,&quot; Klaus Regling, Director General for European and International Financial Relations at the Ministry, said. &quot;But we can't exclude the other possibility.&quot;</p>
<p>Bank of Canada Deputy Governor Paul Jenkins even argued that a delay in EMU would not necessarily disrupt financial markets if it was handled correctly.</p>
<p>&quot;If a delay in the start of EMU is seen as supporting Europe's long-run economic fundamentals, it would not necessarily lead to financial instability, provided ... that countries continued to credibly commit to sustainable policy adjustment,&quot; Jenkins said.</p>
<p>While there may not have been much public hand wringing at the conference over the threat of a delay to EMU, there was more than enough concern expressed about what its actual launch might mean for the markets and the world economy.</p>
<p>Bergsten, who heads the Institute for International Economics think tank here, predicted a massive $500 billion to $1 trillion shift in official currency reserve and investor portfolios into the euro over the next few years.</p>
<p>Much of that shift could come at the expense of the dollar, currently the world's premier currency.</p>
<p>&quot;We will move quite promptly into a bipolar international monetary system,&quot; Bergsten said, adding, &quot;The euro will be a strong currency from the outset.&quot;</p>
<p>He argued that Europe will become more insular after EMU and thus more prone to &quot;benign neglect&quot; of its currency.</p>
<p>&quot;The likelihood is increased volatility and potentially large misalignments from time to time,&quot; Bergsten said.</p>
<p>George Alogoskoufis from Athens University agreed with much of what Bergsten said and predicted that the euro would &quot;overshoot &quot; and rise too far, hurting European exporters.</p>
<p>Daniel Cohen, an academic in France, also saw the risk of increased currency volatility after the euro's launch, in part because Europe will be less worried about its trade position.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
