<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453430" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: R.R. Donnelley taps Emerson V.P. to be chairman, CEO.</title>
<headline>R.R. Donnelley taps Emerson V.P. to be chairman, CEO.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>R.R. Donnelley &amp; Sons Co., whose chairman and chief executive left last year to become president of AT&amp;T Corp., said Wednesday that Emerson Electric Co. executive William Davis would assume those posts.</p>
<p>The 133-year-old specialist publishing company said Davis, 53, would become chief executive immediately and then become chairman following Donnelley's March 27 directors meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;Bill is a dynamic, profit-driven executive with outstanding leadership, marketing and operating skills, and a proven record of value creation,&quot; acting Chairman and CEO John M. Richman said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;His outside perspective is an ideal complement to the unparalleled printing expertise of R.R. Donnelley's existing management team, and his strong leadership will be central to executing -- and accelerating -- the solid strategic plans we have in place today.&quot;</p>
<p>Donnelley said Davis has more than 30 years of broad experience in a number of management, marketing, and strategic planning positions.</p>
<p>Davis, most recently senior executive vice president of Emerson, spent the past 20 years at the company, assuming increasingly senior management positions.</p>
<p>As senior executive vice president he had responsibility for all corporate management and organisational development activities at Emerson. During his tenure Davis was responsible for developing or leading eight global joint ventures.</p>
<p>Davis, a 1965 graduate of Princeton University, spent 12 years at Sears, Roebuck and Co., working in the areas of merchandise management, store management and personnel.</p>
<p>Donnelley, which was founded in Chicago in 1864, manages, reproduces and distributes print and digital information for the publishing, retailing, merchandising and information technology markets. It had sales of $6.6 billion last year.</p>
<p>Richman, a Donnelly outside director, had served as acting chairman and CEO since October, when John Walter resigned to become president and chief operating officer of AT&amp;T. He will remain on the Donnelley board, the company said.</p>
<p>Donnelly's stock added $1.75 to $32.125 in morning trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
