<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453631" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian edible oil prices ease on crop arrivals.</title>
<headline>Indian edible oil prices ease on crop arrivals.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian domestic edible oil prices fell 600 to 700 rupees per tonne in the past 10 days as arrivals of the summer oilseeds crop increased, industry officials and traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Edible oil prices softened during the last 10 days because summer arrivals picked up,&quot; Navinbhai Shah, president of Bombay Oilseeds and Oil Exchange Ltd, told Reuters.</p>
<p>India harvests two oilseeds crops a year, with most output from the winter crop. The summer crop is sown in November and harvest starts from late February.</p>
<p>The Central Organisation for Oil Industry and Trade (COOIT) has forecast the 1996/97 (November-October) oilseeds crop at 21.26 million tonnes, up from 20.98 million in the previous season.</p>
<p>COOIT has forecast the summer oilseeds crop at 9.35 million tonnes, down from 9.55 million the previous year. However, the Agriculture Ministry has forecast the summer crop at 9.7 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Traders said groundnut was quoted at 33,500 rupees per tonne, down from around 34,200 rupees 10 days earlier. Palm olein oil was quoted at 27,600 rupees per tonne against 28,200.</p>
<p>&quot;Import arrivals have slowed down,&quot; Shah said. He said more than 150,000 tonnes of sunflower oil from Argentina and the United States had already arrived.</p>
<p>A senior COOIT official told Reuters on Sunday sunflower oil imports in 1996/97 (November-October) are expected to rise to 450,000 tonnes from 120,000 tonnes in the previous period.</p>
<p>He said contracts for nearly 200,000 tonnes of sunflower imports had been signed and deals for another 250,000 were expected in the rest of the season. ($1 = 35.9 rupees)</p>
<p>--Sambit Mohanty New Delhi newsroom +91-11 301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
