<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="453890" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Vickers cautious despite profits rise.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Vickers cautious despite profits rise.</headline>
<byline>Greg Mahlich</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vickers Plc announced an 11 percent rise in annual profits on Wednesday but the Rolls-Royce cars to Challenger tanks manufacturer warned that progress in 1997 could prove somewhat pedestrian.</p>
<p>It said heavy investment in the automotive division and sterling's recent strength were both factors which could drag on this year's performance.</p>
<p>The company meanwhile said Germany's Bayerische Motoren Werke AG (BMW) was likely interested in Rolls-Royce but said the car division was not for sale.</p>
<p>Profits in 1996 increased to 83.3 million pounds ($132.4 million) before tax on sales up 4.7 percent at 1.97 billion pounds. The company raised the final dividend 0.2 pence to 4.5p, making a seven percent increase for the year to 7.2p on a similar increase in earnings, to 16.7p a share.</p>
<p>The cautious statement and conservative payout disappointed investors and by 1330 GMT the share price was down 18-1/2p at 242-1/2 pence.</p>
<p>&quot;The figures were just a bit lacklustre and the dividend left a bit to be desired,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Vickers said it was &quot;unusually difficult&quot; to foresee the trend of sales and profits in 1997 because of the effects on export orders and earnings of the rise in sterling which began last autumn.</p>
<p>&quot;1996 represented a competent performance for the Vickers Group as a whole,&quot; chairman Sir Richard Lloyd said in his results statement.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;Because of the effects on export orders and earnings of the rise in the trade-weighted value of sterling against other currencies which began last autumn, it is unusually difficult to foresee the trends of sales and profits in 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>However, the firm said a better performance should be achieved on a two-year view in the light of the company's investment programme.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's pretty steady progress,&quot; chief executive Sir Colin Chandler told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a lot of investment going on in the company and the fruits of that investment don't kick in straight away so we are looking for steady growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chandler said he believed Rolls-Royce could now survive as an independent carmaker having spent heavily on modernising the business in the last five years.</p>
<p>He confirmed speculation that Germany's bmw has had its eyes on taking over Rolls, but said BMW knew a takeover bid would be rejected.</p>
<p>BMW was recruited two years ago to take over Rolls' engine requirements but it is widely believed that the German firm would like to add the world's most famous luxury cars to its stable of marques, which already includes Britain's Rover Group.</p>
<p>&quot;I think BMW are interested,&quot; Chandler told Reuters. &quot;I would not deny that at all and neither would they but the point is we are not selling. We spent a lot of money in the business in 1991/92 in both trading losses and in restructuring it. Our shareholders want to get that back and that's our job, to drive it for shareholder value which I think we are doing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Operating profits from the automotive division, which includes the Cosworth high performance auto engines specialist, fell 10 percent to 37.6 million pounds on a four percent rise in sales to 418.5 million.</p>
<p>Roll-Royce increased sales by 12 percent to 1,744 cars last year but margins were slightly down.</p>
<p>Chandler said Rolls aimed to increase profitability by concentrating on selling more bespoke versions of its cars, but overall margins were likely to be &quot;fairly steady&quot; in 1997 because of further development spending.</p>
<p>A new car would be ready for launch some time within the next three years, but the company was not ready to announce a date yet because it could effect sales of the current range, he said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile operating profits at Vickers' military division rose 2.1 million pounds to 18 million pounds in 1996, on sales down 8.5 million pounds at 345.2 million.</p>
<p>But the division continued to keep a lid on potential profits from its contract to supply 386 Challenger 2 tanks to the British Army until acceptance trials are completed.</p>
<p>Production is now running at a rate of about 100 tanks a year, with the tanks going into storage for the British Army pending delivery to regiments, which is expected after April 1998.</p>
<p>Vickers hit problems with the turret system but the latest field trials in southern England were going well, Chandler said, and he expected final trials to be completed in October this year.</p>
<p>Now Vickers needed to secure further sales to sustain production after the last British Army tanks are delviered in 2000.</p>
<p>Chandler was hopeful that existing customer Oman might confirm a follow-on order for 18 more Challengers later this year. It is also competing with U.S. and French rivals for big orders from Saudi Arabia and Qatar, but these are not expected to be decided before 1998.</p>
<p>Operating profits at Vickers third biggest division, Propulsion Technology, jumped by 6.9 million pounds last year to 24 million on sales up 22.7 percent at 292.4 million, boosted by aerospace components and its Kamewa Group marine propulsion business, which makes waterjets for high speed ferries.</p>
<p>Sales at the ailing medical equipment division fell 4.4 million pounds to 118.5 million pounds but operating profits picked up slightly, to 1.6 million pounds from 900,000 in 1995 but further work needed to be done, Chandler said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have clearly got a turnaround job going on there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
