<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454155" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Calif. doctors told they may discuss marijuana.</title>
<headline>Calif. doctors told they may discuss marijuana.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>California's largest doctors' association said on Tuesday it is advising its 35,000 members that they may talk to their patients about the benefits and risks of using marijuana as a medical treatment.</p>
<p>But the California Medical Association (CMA) warned doctors that they could face federal sanctions if they write a recommendation for marijuana or otherwise help patients to obtain the drug.</p>
<p>The CMA drew up the guidelines to help doctors find their way through the legal minefield created by the California voters' approval last November of a medical marijuana initiative called Proposition 215.</p>
<p>The controversial measure makes it legal under state law for sick people to grow and possess marijuana for medical use when recommended by a doctor. Supporters say marijuana can help ease the pain of AIDS, cancer, glaucoma and other serious illnesses.</p>
<p>Clubs operating in San Francisco and other California cities supply marijuana to people who have a doctor's recommendation to use it for a medical reason.</p>
<p>But the Clinton administration has said that marijuana remains illegal under federal law and has pledged to sanction doctors who prescribe marijuana under the California measure and a similar measure passed by Arizona voters.</p>
<p>&quot;Research indicates that a physician can violate federal law by issuing a prescription for a substance, such as marijuana, for which federal law recognises no medicinal uses,&quot; the CMA guidelines said.</p>
<p>If a doctor gives a patient a note to enable the patient to obtain marijuana or cooperates by telephone with a supplier of medical marijuana &quot;federal prosecutors may argue the physician has 'created the means' by which the patient obtains marijuana,&quot; the guidelines said.</p>
<p>In that case, a doctor could face federal criminal liability or other federal sanctions, they said.</p>
<p>But the CMA said it believed a doctor could give a patient scientific evidence about possible health risks and benefits of marijuana for use in the patient's condition.</p>
<p>It recommends the doctor tell the patient that the doctor cannot lawfully recommend that the patient obtain marijuana for medical use and that possession of marijuana, even for medical purposes, is illegal under federal law.</p>
<p>The CMA guidelines appear to follow the position set out by the federal government in a letter to the CMA last month. In that letter, government officials said federal law did not prevent a doctor from merely discussing with a patient the &quot;risks and alleged benefits&quot; of the use of marijuana to relieve pain.</p>
<p>But it said doctors may not intentionally provide patients with oral or written statements to enable them to obtain controlled substances in violation of federal law.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
