<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454140" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - March 19.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - March 19.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following stories were reported in Wednesday's electronic version of The Wall Street Journal:</p>
<p>* Cable &amp; Wireless is contemplating a takeover bid for Sprint and has held talks with France Telecom, which owns 10 percent of the U.S. telecommunications firm, people familiar with the talks said. Sources said no formal offer had been made yet.</p>
<p>* Clinton seeks bipartisan talks in an attempt to pave the way for a balanced budget deal this spring.</p>
<p>* Texaco, Shell Oil agree to merge their refining and marketing operations in the midwest and western United States. The deal could expand if they reached a pact with Saudi Arabia, which also owned refining assets with Texaco.</p>
<p>* Big three U.S. automakers would build roughly as many cars and trucks in the second quarter as they did a year ago.</p>
<p>* February housing starts rose 12.2 percent, helped by warmer weather.</p>
<p>* Novell appointed Sun Microsystems chief technology officer Eric Schmidt as its chairman and chief executive officer.</p>
<p>* A $23-billion merger deal between Bell Atlantic and NYNEX could face more delays but PacTel and SBC were seen moving closer to closing their merger deal.</p>
<p>* TWA's fourth quarter loss widened, hurt by higher fuel costs, maintenance costs and operating performance.</p>
<p>* PepsiCo is expected to be named the official soft drink of Major League Baseball. Whitman was expected to name Robert Cushing president of its Pepsi bottling unit.</p>
<p>* The Dow Jones industrials fell 58.92 to 6896.56 and the Nasdaq composite dropped 10.09 to 1269.34.</p>
<p>* Canadian Occidental agreed to buy Wascana Energy for $1.2 billion.</p>
<p>* Marriott International to sell Host Marriott 29 retirement centers for $227 million cash and $313 million in notes and assumed debt.</p>
<p>* Contract talks between AMR's American Airlines and its pilots ended without a deal but negotiators hoped to reach an agreement in fresh talks.</p>
<p>* Adobe Systems intends to issue dividends based on its investments in technology start-ups.</p>
<p>* Credit Markets: Bonds end little changed, marking time in nervous anticipation of February's consumer price index release -- the last key economic report before next week's meeting of Federal Reserve policy makers.</p>
<p>* Heard on the Street: Don't look now but a bear market may have already descended upon technology stocks. Could that spell more trouble ahead for the rest of the market?</p>
<p>((New York newsdesk 212-859-1610))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
