<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454151" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Heart disease is world's top killer - researchers.</title>
<headline>Heart disease is world's top killer - researchers.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Drawbaugh</byline>
<dateline>ANAHEIM, Calif 1997-03-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Heart disease is replacing infectious disease as the leading cause of death worldwide, reflecting lifestyle changes in less developed countries and a gradual ageing of the world's population, researchers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're seeing a full-blown epidemic in Eastern Europe and we're looking at the developing world as the next target for this,&quot; said Dr. Thomas Pearson of the M.I. Bassett Research Institute in Cooperstown, New York, in a presentation at an American College of Cardiology conference.</p>
<p>Statistics are sketchy because only about a third of the roughly 50 million annual deaths worldwide are documented. But Pearson estimated that in 1990, cardiovascular disease caused about 25 percent of all deaths in less developed nations and 50 percent in the developed world.</p>
<p>By 2020, as many as 34 percent of underdeveloped nations' deaths will be related to cardiovascular disease, with the industrialised world holding at about 50 percent, Pearson said, citing forecasts based on statistics from the World Bank and the World Health Organisation.</p>
<p>&quot;As the world moves away from very young ... with higher mortality rates to older age distributions, it moves toward a dominance of noncommunicable diseases. Undernutrition and the infectious diseases of childhood are being replaced as the main health problems by cancer, chronic pulmonary disease, psychiatric disorders and, above all, cardiovascular diseases,&quot; said Dean Jamison, a University of California-Los Angeles economist.</p>
<p>Although it remains the leading cause of death in the industrialised world, heart disease has declined in North America, Western Europe and Japan. But it is growing so rapidly elsewhere that during the mid-1980s, it supplanted infectious disease as the world's leading killer, said Dr. Thomas Ryan of the Boston University School of Medicine.</p>
<p>Only in sub-Saharan Africa are infectious diseases still the leading killer. In Eastern Europe, rapid increases in deaths from cardiovascular disease have contributed to a decline in life expectancy, researchers said.</p>
<p>Pearson said several causes of the epidemic included high birth rates and increasing life expectancy, the growth in disposable income, cigarette smoking, high fat and cholesterol foods and reduced exercise.</p>
<p>Simple, low-cost measures such as introducing aspirin or beta-blockers for hypertension, discouraging smoking and promoting exercise, could have huge impacts in less developed countries, Ryan said.</p>
<p>Once primarily a U.S. event, the College of Cardiology gathering this week drew specialists from around the world.</p>
<p>Doctors also revealed at the conference that the risk of heart attack is 40 percent higher between 6 a.m. and noon than during the rest of the day and night. The changes that occur in the body in the morning, including rising heart rate and blood pressure, are similar to those triggered by the heavy physical exertion that often leads to heart attacks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WORLD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANAHEIM, Calif"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
