<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454105" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FORECAST-Further swelling seen in Jan US trade gap.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Further swelling seen in Jan US trade gap.</headline>
<byline>Noah Barkin</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Healthy U.S. demand for foreign goods, persistent economic sluggishness abroad and seasonal factors probably led to another widening in the U.S. trade deficit in January.</p>
<p>&quot;The trade deficit has been increasing on a trend basis and until the U.S. economy really slows down we don't expect it to decline,&quot; said Chris Iggo, chief economist at BZW Securities.  </p>
<p>Wall Street economists are calling for a modest swelling of the U.S. trade gap to $10.7 billion in January from $10.29 billion in December. The report is scheduled to be released by the Commerce Department on Thursday, March 20 at 0830 EST/1330 GMT.</p>
<p>Economists said that historical seasonal patterns suggest that exports slow and overall deficits grow in January and the first quarter of the year as a whole.</p>
<p>On top of this, many expect a natural retracement of the export strength seen in the early stages of the fourth quarter.  </p>
<p>John Rothfield, an international economist at Nationsbanc in Chicago, said a demand growth recovery in key trading partners Mexico and Canada during the fourth quarter of 1996 boosted overall fourth quarter exports.</p>
<p>He expects exports to come down for a second consecutive month in January and a corresponding widening in the overall trade gap. If the export numbers come in according to his estimates, Rothfield said analysts would be forced to revise down their forecasts for first quarter U.S. growth.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking for the balance to deteriorate to $11.2 billion with a risk of a higher deficit,&quot; said John Rothfield.  </p>
<p>&quot;There were some reasons to expect an increase in exports in the fourth quarter, but generally export growth probably overshot and we suspect exports could come off their high levels in January,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In December, the U.S. trade gap shot up on record imports, driving the shortfall in total goods and services trade for all of 1996 to an eight-year peak.</p>
<p>The December deficit climbed 29.6 percent to $10.29 billion as imported oil costs soared. Overall imports for December grew by 1.5 percent to a record $81.68 billion, while exports declined by 1.6 percent to $71.4 billion.  </p>
<p>While the politically sensitive deficit with Japan decreased by 1.2 percent to $4.27 billion in December, economists said they are not hopeful for further improvement in January.</p>
<p>&quot;A key point to watch is the deficit with Japan because their trade numbers are suggesting their surplus with the U.S. is starting to rise,&quot; said BZW's Iggo.  </p>
<p>&quot;We haven't seen that in the U.S. economic numbers yet and unless there's something very wrong with how trade is being measured between the two countries we should expect to see January's report starting to show an increased deficit with Japan,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Japan's overall customs-cleared trade surplus fell in January, but its bilateral surplus with the U.S. rose substantially on a year-over-year basis, due mainly to higher sales of cars.  </p>
<p>In February numbers released on Monday, Japan reported that its overall surplus rose -- by 6.5 percent year-over-year -- for the first time since November of 1994, while its surplus with the U.S. grew by 12.3 percent to 407.35 billion yen.</p>
<p>Economists shied away from attributing any widening in the overall U.S. deficit to the dollar, which strengthened by roughly 4.7 percent against the yen in January and by 6.3 percent against the mark during the month.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say it's a little early to talk about a big dollar impact from this but it's not too early to think about it,&quot; said Richard Koss, international economist at MFR Inc.</p>
<p>((-- N.A. Treasury Desk 212-859-1673))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
