<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454221" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Renault set to report huge loss for 1996.</title>
<headline>Renault set to report huge loss for 1996.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>French carmaker Renault SA is expected to report a huge 1996 loss on Thursday, its first loss in a decade, after its car and truck divisions ran into the red.</p>
<p>Industry analysts expect the company to show a loss of between 4.5 billion and six billion francs for 1996, including at least 2.4 billion francs in restructuring provisions.</p>
<p>Renault cautioned last month that its 1996 results would be &quot;significantly negative&quot; and would include a 2.4 billion franc charge to close the Vilvoorde assembly plant in Belgium.</p>
<p>They will probably also include a smaller charge for nearly 2,800 job cuts planned this year in France.</p>
<p>The company had sounded a previous profit warning, saying its 1996 operating loss would be greater than market estimates, which then ranged from a loss of 1.3 to 1.6 billion francs.</p>
<p>Analysts now expect a loss at the car division of around three billion francs and a loss of 600 to 650 million for the truck operation, with only the financial services unit showing a gain, estimated at between one and 1.3 billion francs.</p>
<p>&quot;The worse their results, the more they will be able to create a crisis atmosphere,&quot; which would help them push through the plant closure and job cuts that have sparked an outcry in Europe, one analyst said.</p>
<p>He said he did not expect Renault to pile more charges on the 1996 results. &quot;If they drip something out that wasn't flagged, that would create difficulties from a PR perspective.&quot;</p>
<p>But another analyst said, &quot;It makes sense for them to throw as much in as possible -- throw in the kitchen sink. The market's expecting a big loss so why disappoint the market?&quot;</p>
<p>He said the estimates bandied about were &quot;not analysis but guesswork&quot;.</p>
<p>Renault reported a profit of 2.14 billion francs for 1995 but said its car division lost more money in the second half of the year than it earned in the first half, resulting in a full-year loss for the division of 1.71 billion francs.</p>
<p>The car branch has been battered by a fierce price war that broke out in Europe, eroding the industry's profit margins, just as Renault was launching the new line of Megane cars that it was hoping would improve its product mix and boost profits.</p>
<p>The company's performance deteriorated last year, when a downturn in the U.S. and European truck industries drove its commercial vehicle business into the red as well.</p>
<p>One analyst predicted a group operating loss of 4.75 billion francs, noting that the restructuring charges would probably be included under operating expenses.</p>
<p>Renault's last annual loss was for 1986, when it reported a loss of 5.85 billion francs. In the two preceding years, it lost 23.5 billion francs in the company's worst post-war crisis.</p>
<p>In the past 10 years, Renault's workforce has dropped by 40,000 workers to just under 141,000 at the end of 1996.</p>
<p>-- Christine Tierney, Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5362</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
