<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454259" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's Euromobiliare, Credem to merge.</title>
<headline>Italy's Euromobiliare, Credem to merge.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian investment house Euromobiliare said on Wednesday it intended to merge with Credito Emiliano bank (Credem) which has a 54 percent stake in it.</p>
<p>The board of Euromobiliare had decided to start the process to merge the two houses and take the name of Credem for the resulting company, it said in a statement.</p>
<p>Credem's board will examine the proposal at a meeting on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;While not producing any substantial change in the current operational and managerial organisation of the bank, the operation represents the evolution of the Credem group towards the market,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>As well as leading to simplification and rationalisation of the group's structure, the merger would improve its access to capital markets and broaden its shareholder base.  </p>
<p>Euromobiliare's board said it had decided to ask investment bank Mediobanca to evaluate the two companies with the aim of formulating a share swap rate to put to the boards by June.</p>
<p>Extraordinary shareholder meetings were expected in July to approve the merger and the operation was expected to be concluded by September.</p>
<p>It said the merger did not affect operational companies Euromobiliare SIM, Euromobiliare Corporate Finance, Euromobiliare Investimenti SIM, Euromobiliare Fondi and Euromobiliare Fiduciaria, through which Credem intended to continue development and consolidation of its activities in the movable asset and merchant banking sectors.</p>
<p>The statement said Euromobiliare made a net profit of 6.39 billion lire in 1996 following a loss in 3.63 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>The company proposed paying a dividend, for the first time in five years, of 50 lire per ordinary share and 375 lire for ordinary shares resulting from conversion from savings shares.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +392 66129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
