<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454249" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Western investors want bigger quoted Baltic firms.</title>
<headline>Western investors want bigger quoted Baltic firms.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Lannin</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Baltic states attract Western investors but before the markets of Latvia, Lithuania and Estonia can really take off they need bigger and better quoted companies, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the big investors would like to come ... but cannot find anything to buy,&quot; James Oates, the director of Union Banque Suisse for central and eastern European equities, told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>He was speaking at a conference on investing in the Baltic states held in the Finnish capital.</p>
<p>Analysts said Western investors were pleased with the macro-economic picture in the Baltic countries which show steady economic growth and slowing rates of inflation. The three countries are desperate for more investment after quitting the former Soviet Union in 1991.</p>
<p>Estonia and Latvia both have balanced government budgets while Lithuania has said its deficit will remain below two percent of gross domestic product.</p>
<p>Latvian bourse president Uldis Cerps said the major momentum for stock market growth would come from privatisations.</p>
<p>The Latvian government has pledged to complete privatisations by 1998 with gas, electricity and shipping companies. A commercial bank would also be privatised. All these companies would be listed.</p>
<p>&quot;We really believe that major growth in 1997 will come from public privatisations,&quot; Cerps said.</p>
<p>He said that the Latvian market's capitalisation would rise above one billion dollars in 1997 from the present $378 million.</p>
<p>Union Banque Suisse's Oates said investors on the Baltic markets were niche players rather than major international investment funds.</p>
<p>&quot;It will need much bigger companies, basically the utilities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Alain Bourrier, manager of the Baltic Republic Fund for French bank Societe Generale, said that the quality of stocks in Latvia and Lithuania was not good for large Western investors.</p>
<p>He also said that Estonia, although attractive for Western players, was too bank dominated.</p>
<p>&quot;We need more industrial companies,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>All three Baltic states have lively stock markets, although turnovers are small compared to the West.</p>
<p>In Estonia, considered the most liquid and active of the markets, turnover was 2.3 billion kroons in 1996 (around $190 million), tiny when compared with world markets.</p>
<p>But the Baltic bourses are still new. The Estonian market only opened in May 1996, Latvia in mid-1995 while Lithuania has been running since September 1994.</p>
<p>Western investors said increasing interest in the Baltic markets, considered one market by many foreigners due to their small size, would be helped by greater co-operation between the bourses of the three countries.</p>
<p>The Latvian and Estonian central depositories have already signed a co-operation deal under which investors can buy and sell in one country and settle in the other. They hope to persuade the Lithuanian central depository to sign up to the agreement.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BALTST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
