<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454203" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Sonofon to invest 500 mln Dkk in GSM in 97.</title>
<headline>Sonofon to invest 500 mln Dkk in GSM in 97.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish telecoms operator Sonofon said on Wednesday that it would invest 500 million crowns in improving and expanding its existing nationwide GSM mobile telephone net in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to improve quality and we still have capacity problems,&quot; Joern Lindegaard, executive in GN Store Nord, which has a 53.5 percent stake in Sonofon, said at an investors' meeting.</p>
<p>Earlier Sonofon was one of four successful bidders awarded Danish DCS-1800 mobile telephone licenses by Denmark's National Telecom Agency.</p>
<p>Lindegaard said he estimated that investment in the DCS-1800 mobile telephone network in combination with the existing GSM net could run up to four billion crowns over the next ten years.</p>
<p>Sonofon said investment was required on new tele-infrastructure to successfully launch a new total mobility concept for customers, making fixed-line telephony unnecessary.</p>
<p>Sonofon is the main competitor of former monopoly Tele Danmark in mobile telephones with over 500,000 subscribers.</p>
<p>Earlier Tele Danmark, which also won a new DCS licence, said it planned to invest 600 million crowns in a new mobile telephone system by the year 2000.</p>
<p>-- Soeren Linding Jakobsen, Copenhagen newsroom +45 33 969653</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
