<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454376" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Latam, Caribbean form finance ministers' club.</title>
<headline>Latam, Caribbean form finance ministers' club.</headline>
<dateline>BARCELONA, Spain 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Latin American and Caribbean countries agreed on Wednesday to create a finance ministers club to discuss informally economic and financial issues, Chilean Finance Minister Eduardo Aninat said.</p>
<p>Aninat told Reuters that ministers and other officials from 14 countries representing the whole region had supported Chile's proposal to establish an informal group that will meet at least once a year to talk about the nuts and bolts of economic policy.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea is to meet with no ties on, no communiques, agreements or formalities ... to explore ideas about what we finance ministers are facing,&quot; he said in an interview on the fringes of the Inter-American Development Bank's annual meeting.  </p>
<p>Chile's proposal was backed by Argentina, Bolivia, Brazil, Colombia, Costa Rica, Ecuador, Mexico, Panama, Paraguay, Peru, Trinidad and Tobago, Uruguay and Venezuela.</p>
<p>Costa Rica represented Central America while Trinidad and Tobago represented the Caribbean nations in the IADB.</p>
<p>The finance ministers' club is due to hold its first meeting on December 3 in Santiago, Chile, Aninat said. Mexico's Finance Minister, Guillermo Ortiz, offered to host a second round in 1998 in Cancun.</p>
<p>In their talks the ministers will analyse issues from various angles, from the design of policies, to how to deal with congress, or how to build popular support for their measures.</p>
<p>&quot;For instance, in the first meeting Argentina and Chile will talk about tax reform, how such a reform is carried out, what happened to each of us when we undertook it, what is going on now and what we expect for the future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Other issues they are bound to tackle were social programmes, public financing and budget management.</p>
<p>In their breakfast meeting in Barcelona the officials heard Brazilian Planning Minister Antonio Kandir talk about the political groundwork needed to carry out economic reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;Personally, I think it is very desirable to start generating an institutional memory of our own agendas, our own concerns about the delicate balance of combining economic reforms and their political implementation,&quot; Aninat added.</p>
<p>Chile's Finance Ministry will set up a secretariat for the club, which will also have technical support from the office of the IADB's chief economist, Ricardo Hausmann.</p>
<p>-- Peter Bate, IADB newsroom +34 4 424 2657+</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BARCELONA, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
