<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454349" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Demand, prices to drive EU wheat sales - EU official.</title>
<headline>Demand, prices to drive EU wheat sales - EU official.</headline>
<byline>Paule Bonjean</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union will continue to export wheat this season on condition that there is adequate demand and that prices implied by subsidies at a weekly tender are reasonable, a senior European Commission farm official said.</p>
<p>&quot;All I can say is that if there are markets, I expect the Commission will look at offers placed by operators and assess if they are interesting,&quot; Michel Jacquot, the EU's farm budgetary and financial affairs director, said in a telephone interview from Brussels.</p>
<p>Exporters estimate the EU could potentially export a further 1-1.5 million tonnes. But they fear that target might not be reached, arguing that export refunds are too low to allow EU wheat to compete against other world supplies.</p>
<p>Jacquot, whose responsibilities include the management of farm export subsidies, said &quot;We will export if there are markets.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It is not our intention to let prices fall. That would be absurd.&quot;</p>
<p>Jacquot was referring to the level of subsidies exporters need to bridge the gap between EU wheat prices and world prices. But he did not say what subsidy level the Commission would consider satisfactory.</p>
<p>Jacquot said the European Union did not plan to end the 1996/97 campaign with a large wheat stock in its intervention stores.</p>
<p>Since the start of the season the EU has exported around 8.4 million tonnes of soft wheat grain out of an estimated record crop of 91 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The campaign officially ends on June 30, but the allocation of new export licences traditionally come to a halt by early May, when new and cheaper U.S. supplies become available.</p>
<p>Jacquot said last Thursday's award at the weekly tender indicated the EU was ready to sell its wheat on world markets.</p>
<p>&quot;We sold last week. This shows we are on the right track,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Last Thursday the EU granted licences to export 273,500 tonnes of soft wheat with refunds up to 11.47 Ecus per tonne, a level seen as valuing French wheat around $155 per tonne.</p>
<p>Jacquot declined to estimate total EU soft wheat exports for 1996/97. He said only that the EU had set an informal export target in line with commitments taken under the GATT trade accord to curb subsidised exports and with budget constraints.</p>
<p>Other officials have placed the Commission's original target for the campaign at up to nine million tonnes.</p>
<p>Last Thursday an EU official said the EU had started the season with an informal wheat export goal of 8.0 to 9.0 million tonnes and that the target appeared easily reachable.</p>
<p>Asked about talk that Saudi Arabia might soon tap world markets for feed barley, Jacquot said &quot;we will see&quot;, adding the EU would also end the campaign with low intervention stocks for this grain.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
