<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454387" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish shares close lower on volatile debt market.</title>
<headline>Swedish shares close lower on volatile debt market.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish shares ended lower on Wednesday, depressed by a choppy debt market.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a volatile market that is watching interest rate development,&quot; a trader said. &quot;In addition, you have the (U.S.) Fed meeting next week which makes it extra nervous.&quot;</p>
<p>The exchange's general index fell 0.45 percent to 2,671.96 in fairly active turnover of 5.39 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Heavyweights telecoms group Ericsson and drugs major Astra fell and pulled indices lower. Ericsson dropped 6.5 crowns to 254.5 crowns and Astra shed three to land at 352 crowns by the close.</p>
<p>But automotive group Volvo rose 5.5 crowns to 190.5 crowns after announcing that it would redeem five percent of shares at a 40 crown premium above market price. Volvo also announced that Hakan Frisinger would become its new chairman, replacing Bert-Olof Svanholm who has died.</p>
<p>The forestry and investments sectors were the only ones edging higher, up 0.18 percent and 0.47 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>Forestry group MoDo rose 7.5 to 237 crowns and investment company Industrivarden climbed 14 crowns to 409 crowns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
