<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454399" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: FIRST HUNGARY FUND MAY FLOAT NABI, BIOREX IN 1997.</title>
<headline>FIRST HUNGARY FUND MAY FLOAT NABI, BIOREX IN 1997.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The First Hungary Fund (FHF), a venture capital investor, is looking to float two Hungarian companies in its portfolio, biotech company Biorex and busmaker North American Bus Industries Ltd (NABI), later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We would float Biorex on the London Stock Exchange (LSE) and NABI on the Budapest bourse and the London OTC market,&quot; the fund's chairman and CEO Peter Rona told Reuters.</p>
<p>The FHF was set up in 1989 to invest in unlisted companies, make them more profitable and, where appropriate, bring them to market listing.</p>
<p>Rona said the Biotex flotation depended on human tests currently underway in Britain and Hungary for a new product, Bimoclomol, a treatment for diabetic complications.</p>
<p>&quot;The tests will be completed in June 30,&quot; he said. &quot;If they are successsful, as we believe they will be, then we will seek the listing.&quot;</p>
<p>The FHF set up a UK company BRX Research and Development Company Ltd last year as a holding company for 100 percent of Biorex shares.</p>
<p>Rona said the decision to issue Biorex shares in London was based on the LSE's Chapter 20 regulation encouraging the listing of hi-tech companies.</p>
<p>&quot;(It demands) some tangible results from your research, stability of management and the existence of an identifiable research programme,&quot; he said. &quot;You don't have to be profitable, you don't need an earnings history, and you don't have to have a product on the market -- Biorex fits Chapter 20.&quot;</p>
<p>Rona said the decision to float NABI was based on a turnaround in the company's fortunes over the last two years, during which a combined 1994/95 loss of $3 million has been turned into a $3.7 million 1996 after-tax profit.</p>
<p>&quot;The company is growing very fast, it's turning away orders,&quot; he said, adding that NASI now accounted for 15 percent of the U.S. bus market and expected 1997 net income of over $5 million.</p>
<p>-- Duncan Shiels, Budapest newsroom, +361 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
