<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454527" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bradford &amp; Bingley to double member benefit package.</title>
<headline>Bradford &amp; Bingley to double member benefit package.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mutually owned Bradford &amp; Bingley Building Society said on Wednesday it planned to double its members' benefit package to 100 million pounds ($159 million) on an annualised basis.</p>
<p>The home loan and savings society said the programme to distribute profits to members, which ran at one million pounds per week in 1996, had reduced annual profit after tax to 56.6 million pounds from 107.7 million in 1995. At the same time, the society increased its assets by nearly nine percent to 17 billion pounds. </p>
<p>Bradford &amp; Bingley, which unlike some other building societies has no plans to convert to bank status as a Plc, said its sole objective was to meet the needs of its members. It reduces profit levels by giving members lower mortage interest rates and higher savings rates.</p>
<p>&quot;Making lower profits than a Plc is not a problem for a mutual with substantial reserves. Indeed for a strong mutual, it is desirable,&quot; the society said in its results statement.</p>
<p>The first result of the incresed distribution programme will be a &quot;significant&quot; across-the-board increase in savings rates, which will take effect from March 24, and at its annual meeting in April, the society will outline a new &quot;loyalty package&quot; to reward existing borrowers.</p>
<p>Bradford &amp; Bingley chairman Lindsey Mackinley said in the statement, &quot;With 900 million pounds ($1.4 billion) in reserves, the society is in good shape to meet the challenges which lie ahead. Our commitment to mutuality is unswerving.&quot;</p>
<p>($ = 0.628 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
