<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454719" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: China/Vietnam row over gas rich area, analysts.</title>
<headline>China/Vietnam row over gas rich area, analysts.</headline>
<byline>Neil Fullick</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Natural gas is at the centre of a row between China and Vietnam over a Chinese oil rig operating in waters both countries claim, industry analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The territorial waters the two countries claim overlap to the south and west of China's Hainan island and Beijing has found gas on both sides of the island.</p>
<p>Further recent discoveries by China have raised the exploration potential of the region and that may be the reason Hanoi has suddenly started making a fuss, the analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;They have never raised protests about this area before,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>China's Kan Tan III, which analysts said is a semi-submersible oil rig, is operating south of Hainan in waters also claimed by Vietnam.</p>
<p>Just 50 km away is China's Yacheng 13-1 field, discovered in the 1980s. It has confirmed reserves of 3.4 trillion cubic feet of gas, and is operated by Atlantic Richfield Co (ARCO) of the United States in undisputed waters.</p>
<p>From Yacheng 1-13, a pipeline feeds gas to Hong Kong, bringing international prices, and to the domestic market of Hainan, which has a mixture of industry, agriculture and tourism.</p>
<p>But China has also made smaller discoveries near where its rig is now operating -- called Block 113 by Vietnam -- which it might try to link to the bigger field, the analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a series of small gas discoveries and there is a pipeline with spare capacity. The discoveries are not big, but as a cluster together they might make commercial sense,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>Another said China has drilled three wells within the area defined by Block 113. The first two wells hit gas. The third was dry, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I should imagine the Chinese are drilling more appraisal wells,&quot; he said of the Kan Tan III's current activities.</p>
<p>Last weekend, Vietnam protested against the rig's presence. Hanoi said it had formally protested to Beijing and demanded the rig's immediate withdrawal.</p>
<p>The official Vietnam News Agency said Vietnam's coastguard had cautioned the vessel repeatedly, but said the warnings had been ignored.</p>
<p>Beijing said the vessel was operating in Chinese waters, in a region it calls the Ledong prospect area. Its activities were normal and above reproach, China said.</p>
<p>A source at the China National Offshore Oil Corp (CNOOC), which oversees all of China's offshore exploration and production operations, said the Kan Tan III started drilling on March 8.</p>
<p>He declined to say how long the ship would be in position, but analysts said it would typically take several months for one or two more wells to be completed.</p>
<p>China is also developing the Dong Fang-1 field to the west of Hainan, in an area claimed by Vietnam as well. China says it has confirmed reserves of 2.8 trillion cubic feet.</p>
<p>In 1974, Beijing called it a &quot;hands off&quot; area for Vietnam and aims to pipe the gas to a fertilizer complex on Hainan.</p>
<p>--Singapore Newsroom (+65 870 3081)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
