<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="454860" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Small Thai construction firm PAE thinks big.</title>
<headline>Small Thai construction firm PAE thinks big.</headline>
<byline>Anchalee Koetsawang</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Small Thai construction concern PAE (Thailand) Plc, hit by the moribund building market, has big plans for the energy and petrochemical sectors to boost revenue in coming years.</p>
<p>The company's diversification plan comes in response to the current Thai economic downturn and massive cuts in government spending that would pressure the construction sector.</p>
<p>Tanakom Skulthai, PAE's deputy managing director, told Reuters that a unit of the company and Zurn Industries of the United States had recently launched a joint venture to explore opportunities in the energy sector.</p>
<p>The venture, called Operational Energy Group, would provide operation and maintenance, commissioning and training services for power plants being built under the state-run Electricity Generating Authority of Thailand's (EGAT) programmes.</p>
<p>The venture just sealed a $40 million deal with Industrial Power Co, a unit of real estate developer Hemaraj Land Development Plc, to maintain and operate Industrial Power's power plant for six years, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The power industry has hot potential. There will be around 72 independent power plants in the next two to three years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>PAE's strategy for 1997 is to secure power plant contracts for both mechanical works -- the company's area of expertise-- and maintenance, Tanakom added.</p>
<p>Under the Independent Power Producers and Small Power Producers programmes, private companies build, produce and sell power to EGAT's grids.</p>
<p>Tanakom said PAE also hoped to get construction contracts in at least three plants under the programmes, two of which already involved its partner Zurn Industries.</p>
<p>To bolster its base in the energy sector, PAE also set up a joint venture with Ohio-based HRSG Co to manufacture heat-recovery equipment used in power and petrochemical plants.</p>
<p>Analysts said although PAE was generally regarded by many investors as an uninspiring stock, it was a relatively solid medium-sized construction firm.</p>
<p>The company's core business is construction, especially mechanical engineering work. It is also in communications, industrial services and trading.</p>
<p>&quot;The stock was unattractive to many investors due to lack of trading liquidity. This is mainly because the firm barely makes splashy headlines as its contracts involve mostly mechanical deals which don't provide sensational figures,&quot; said analyst Athibhumi Visavavej, at Dhana Siam Finance and Securities.</p>
<p>However, the low-profile company was one of few construction firms which enjoyed positive net profit growth -- 6.8 percent -- while other major firms saw growth fall in bearish 1996.</p>
<p>The company reported an unaudited 1996 net profit of 149.4 million baht on revenue of 2.30 billion baht ($885 million) against 148.3 million baht and 1.60 billion baht in 1995.</p>
<p>It has targeted 2.8-3.0 billion baht in revenue this year.</p>
<p>Dhana Siam's Athibhumi said his firm was recommending a hold on PAE versus a sell on most other construction firms.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the company has a good potential and professional management, its unaudited 1996 net is well below expectation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Moreover, the company does not have that many major projects in hand. We will upgrade the stock to buy if it secures major deals that would assure improved earning,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
