<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="455127" id="root" date="1997-03-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICA'S VOLKSWAGEN STRIKE CONTINUES.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICA'S VOLKSWAGEN STRIKE CONTINUES.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1997-03-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>German automaker Volkswagen's plant in South Africa's Eastern Cape remained shut for a second day on Wednesday following a strike by about 4,500 workers over the firm's cost-cutting measures, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing has changed. The company's position remains as it was yesterday (Tuesday) that the plant is closed and it will remain closed until there is an assurance from the union that their members will return to work,&quot; Volkswagen's spokesman Raymond Hartle told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Uitenhage plant has a daily output of around 320 vehicles valued at about 16 million rand, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;I can say since yesterday (Tuesday) the company has certainly lost about 24 million rand,&quot; Hartle said.</p>
<p>The strikers, belonging to the National Union of Metalworkers of South Africa (NUMSA), downed tools on Tuesday at the Uitenhage plant protesting against the company's move to have those who lease its cars contribute to insurance costs.</p>
<p>They also complained about the stricter enforcement of the company's absenteeism policy and the introduction of stringent quality control measures at the plant's paint shop, the company said.</p>
<p>Hartle said there had been lengthy talks between Volkswagen and the union late on Tuesday, but there had yet been no resolution of the impasse.</p>
<p>&quot;The talks last night were certainly taking place in a cordial atmosphere, but as the union is still reporting back to its members, it is difficult to say what mandate they might give it. This is an illegal stoppage and the plant is closed,&quot; Hartle said.</p>
<p>NUMSA officials were not available for comment early on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Ellis Mnyandu, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
