<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="455232" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Right Mgmt sees Q1 EPS below expectations.</title>
<headline>Right Mgmt sees Q1 EPS below expectations.</headline>
<dateline>PHILADELPHIA 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Right Management Consultants Inc Thursday said that, due to lower than anticipated revenue, it expects to report earnings below expectations for its first quarter ending March 31, 1997.</p>
<p>The company expects it will report net income for the first quarter in the range of $650,000 to $1,050,000, or $0.10-$0.15 per share after the impact of a restructuring charge of about $400,000 to $600,000, or $0.06 to $0.09 per share, net of taxes.</p>
<p>The First Call consensus is $0.39 for the first quarter.  </p>
<p>The company said the restructuring charge will consist primarily of severance payments and remaining lease costs related to reductions in force and office closures. The company expects revenue for the quarter of about $29 million.</p>
<p>For the year-ago quarter, the company reported net income of $2,409,000, or $0.36 per share, on total company revenues of $32,455,000.</p>
<p>&quot;Revenue results for the first quarter project to be less than expected, necessitating an adjustment of company cost structures by reducing staff and closing some satellite offices that are underperforming, or are redundant due to acquisitions. We announced and began a formal implementation of a realignment of our business in mid-January 1997 and we believe when fully implemented by the end of this quarter, this realignment will position us to focus the organization more effectively for growth,&quot; said Richard Pinola, chairman and chief executive officer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83951">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHILADELPHIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
