<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="455503" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: SKALA STEPS UP EFFORTS TO GAIN CLIENTS.</title>
<headline>SKALA STEPS UP EFFORTS TO GAIN CLIENTS.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian retailer Skala Aruhazi Kft, main member of Skala group , said it was stepping up its efforts to gain regular clients as it does not share analysts' optimism about a recovery in consumption.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite optimistic forecasts I don't really think that Hungarian consumption will grow,&quot; the diversified retailer's managing director Janos Halasz told a news conference on Thursday.</p>
<p>Skala Aruhazi's regular customer system, to be fully operational by October, is expected to generate extra revenues for the company, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect hundreds of millions of forints in additional turnover against tens of millions of forints in costs,&quot; Halasz said. &quot;We aren't impatient, the most important is to have a loyal clientele,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Regular clients participating in the system as a result of a six-month recruitment programme starting on March 25, will receive different benefits from October in all of Skala Aruhazi Kft's department stores.</p>
<p>Analysts expect Hungary's Gross Domestic Product (GDP) to rise by around two and a half percent in 1997, after a flat growth last year, propelled by rising investments and recovering consumption.</p>
<p>In its preliminary unconsolidated 1996 earnings report, Skala said Skala Aruhazi Kft generated 8.81 billion forints sales revenues compared to 7.29 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>The group's total unconsolidated revenue amounted to 12.59 billion forints in 1996 from 10.79 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>On the Budapest Stock Exchange Skala shares remained untraded on Thursday but closed at 1,800 forints on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
