<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="455646" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: WIC family hails court ruling.</title>
<headline>WIC family hails court ruling.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The family that founded WIC Western International Communications Ltd on Thursday applauded an appeal court ruling that upheld their control of the broadcaster.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very happy with the outcome,&quot; said Emily Griffiths, matriarch of the family. &quot;WIC has been preoccupied for too long on this matter.&quot;</p>
<p>CanWest Global Communications Corp and two former WIC directors appealed a decision by a lower court that effectively blocked CanWest's C$636 million takeover bid for WIC last year.  </p>
<p>The British Columbia Court of Appeal rejected their arguments on Thursday. That decision was in line with expectations.</p>
<p>Winnipeg, Manitoba-based CanWest said it would not appeal the ruling. CanWest vice president Leonard Asper said the company would continue to hold its 15 percent stake in WIC's non-voting Class B shares and seek to build a more &quot;meaningful&quot; relationship with WIC's management.</p>
<p>CanWest and the former WIC directors were challenging WIC's two-tier share structure.  </p>
<p>That structure allows the Griffiths family to control WIC by virtue of owning most of its voting Class A shares even though the family holds only about seven percent of the company's total equity. The appeal sought to have voting rights awarded to non-voting shareholders.</p>
<p>A ruling in favor of CanWest would have made WIC vulnerable to a takeover bid, analysts said. CanWest recently purchased another block of WIC non-voting B shares, bringing its holding to 15 percent. It said it believed itself to be the company's biggest holder of the B shares.  </p>
<p>WIC has faced mounting shareholder unrest amid complaints the company has performed poorly and is unresponsive to stockholders.</p>
<p>The Griffiths family said in their statement that the company was &quot;one of Canada's largest and most innovative communications company.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The Griffiths family want to see WIC continue to grow and prosper for the benefit of all shareholders,&quot; Emily Griffiths said. WIC owns some of the most valuable properties in Canadian broadcasting including eight television, 12 radio stations and a share of Canada's CTV network.</p>
<p>((Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
