<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="455627" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: RTRS-Cricket-South Africa bravely face series whitewash.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Cricket-South Africa bravely face series whitewash.</headline>
<byline>Andy Colquhoun</byline>
<dateline>CENTURION, South Africa 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa go into the third and final test against Australia at Centurion Park on Friday staring down the barrel of their first home series whitewash this century.</p>
<p>Hansie Cronje's men trail Australia 2-0 after defeats in Johannesburg and Port Elizabeth and a third defeat would link them with the South African side of 1898/99 who lost a three-test series to Lord Hawke's touring MCC team.  </p>
<p>&quot;If we lose three-nil, we lose three-nil -- that's the reality -- it's not a fear,&quot; said South Africa coach Bob Woolmer.</p>
<p>&quot;Hopefully we will get one back but Australia are a good side. The reality is that their number four and five batsmen share 140 tests between them and you can add all our caps together as many times as you like and you won't get that number.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a very talented team but at test match level we are still short of experience.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;We haven't finalised that yet,&quot; said Woolmer. &quot;But you can pontificate about systems and batting orders until the cows come home but the only thing that we need is for our young batters to fire.&quot;</p>
<p>With Shaun Pollock absent with a hamstring strain either Lance Klusener or left arm fast bowler Brett Schultz is likely to come in as a straight replacement in the one certain change to the side who lost in Port Elizabeth on Monday.</p>
<p>Australia's greatest enemy may be complacency. After clinching their recent home series with West Indies they lost the fifth test by 10 wickets inside three days in Perth.  </p>
<p>&quot;It would be disappointing to perform badly at Centurion Park but there is always that danger,&quot; said skipper Mark Taylor.</p>
<p>&quot;Port Elizabeth was a big win and it is going to be hard to get the guys up again. Very hard.&quot;</p>
<p>Australia won a low-scoring match in Port Elizabeth after South Africa at one stage held a 188-run lead with all their second innings wickets in hand.</p>
<p>&quot;We showed we are a pretty good cricket team after being down and out at one point in Port Elizabeth,&quot; said Taylor, who has been battling a long form slump.  </p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the last two test matches we have won the really big days.&quot;</p>
<p>Taylor has failed to reach 50 in his last 18 test innings and has not even reached 20 in his last nine. However, he reiterated he would open the innings once again.</p>
<p>Fast bowler Glenn McGrath is expected to play despite a foot injury, but will likely miss the subsequent seven-match one-day series.</p>
<p>Australia are expected to field an unchanged team.</p>
<p>Squads:  </p>
<p>South Africa (from) - Gary Kirsten, Adam Bacher, Jacques Kallis, Daryll Cullinan, Hansie Cronje (captain), Brian McMillan, Dave Richardson, Lance Klusener, Allan Donald, Paul Adams, Brett Schultz, Pat Symcox.</p>
<p>Australia (from) - Mark Taylor (captain), Matthew Hayden, Matthew Elliott, Mark Waugh, Steve Waugh, Greg Blewett, Michael Bevan, Ian Healy, Shane Warne, Glenn McGrath, Jason Gillespie, Paul Reiffel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CENTURION, South Africa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
