<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="455659" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Quebec's deficit battle angers separatist allies.</title>
<headline>Quebec's deficit battle angers separatist allies.</headline>
<byline>Robert Melnbardis</byline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Quebec's separatist government is in a bitter fight with many of its key supporters as it seeks to juggle its drive for independence with the need for deep spending cuts.</p>
<p>Next Tuesday, the Parti Quebecois government will introduce what analysts predict will be the most painful budget in Quebec history, slashing spending by C$2.3 billion ($1.7 billion) in the fiscal year beginning on April 1.</p>
<p>&quot;The big government deficits have been around for 20 years and in that time there certainly has never been such a dramatic cost-cutting exercise,&quot; said Simon Prevost, an economist at Mouvement Desjardins, Quebec's big credit union group.</p>
<p>The cuts, which follow similar ones in the fiscal year just ending, will rock the already hard-hit health and education sectors in the French-speaking province of 7.3 million people.</p>
<p>They have put the government of Premier Lucien Bouchard on a collision course with the big public sector unions which have been stalwart supporters of Quebec's independence drive.</p>
<p>The province's 440,000 public service employees are on the front lines of the government's battle against Quebec's direct debt of C$76 billion ($55.5 billion) and its annual budget deficit of C$3.3 billion ($2.4 billion).</p>
<p>A showdown with the unions could cost the government vital support in a provincial election expected next year and in another referendum on separation that might follow as soon as 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Bouchard) is certainly running a risk, but he doesn't have much of a choice,&quot; said Louis Balthazar, a political science professor at Laval University in Quebec City. &quot;Something has to be done to reduce the deficit, especially in the context of a province that aspires to sovereignty.&quot;</p>
<p>Quebec's vocal Separatists lost a referendum on sovereignty by just one percentage point in October 1995, when the independence option and Bouchard's popularity were at all-time peaks.</p>
<p>Popular support for sovereignty has since slipped below 50 percent and the premier has been burned in effigy and faced labor demonstrations against his plans to cut government services further.</p>
<p>Bouchard's dilemma was that he has committed his government to eliminating the deficit by 1999-2000, while trying to maintain fierce nationalistic sentiment and the momentum of the independence movement.</p>
<p>But political analysts and economists all noted that bitter fiscal medicine was needed in Quebec, which has lagged other Canadian provinces in acting to restore its fiscal health.</p>
<p>&quot;For Mr. Bouchard, straightening out the economy comes before the promotion of sovereignty. If he does not succeed with the first task, he will have great difficulty convincing Quebeckers of the viability of sovereignty,&quot; said Benoit Pelletier, a constitutional law professor at Ottawa University.</p>
<p>Quebec's nurses, teachers, and other public employees, including managerial civil servants, will bear the brunt of the government's austerity measures as Quebec tries to reduce its C$20 billion ($14.6 billion) annual payroll costs by C$832 million ($607 million).</p>
<p>A midnight Wednesday deadline for reaching an agreement between the unions and the government over 15,000 job cuts planned by July 1 passed without an agreement. Negotiations continued on Thursday and the government has said it was prepared to introduce legislation forcing the cuts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
