<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="455881" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenia investment funds expect listing in autumn.</title>
<headline>Slovenia investment funds expect listing in autumn.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenian investment funds that participated in the country's massive privatisation process said on Thursday they expected some of the funds to be listed on the over-the-counter (OTC) market in Ljubljana.</p>
<p>&quot;We can expect the first funds to be listed in the second half of the year, presumably autumn,&quot; Roman Ambroz, director of Prvi Investicijski Sklad, a fund established by investment company Nacionalna Financna Druzba, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The green light for the listings was given on Tuesday, when the state Securities' Market Agency said funds would be able to be listed on the OTC market without any special requirements.</p>
<p>&quot;We decided to approve the listings in order to enable trading of funds' shares. We believe the price of their shares would thus rise above the one on the grey market,&quot; said Igor Kusar, director of the Securities Market Agency.</p>
<p>On the grey market shares of investment funds are currently being traded at about 10 percent of their nominal value only.</p>
<p>Under Slovenia's privatisation scheme, which started in 1994 and involved some 1,500 companies, every citizen received a voucher whose value varied according to age, ranging from 100,000 tolars ($651) for people under 18 to 400,000 tolars for people over 48.</p>
<p>Holders could place their vouchers directly into companies or into 72 investment funds that later exchanged them for shares of companies that have been privatised.</p>
<p>Some 86 percent of Slovenians have already spent their privatisation vouchers that expire at the end of June this year.</p>
<p>The funds have so far collected some 300 billion tolars ($2.0 billion) of privatisation vouchers or about 53 percent of all vouchers issued.</p>
<p>But funds have only managed to exchange about a third of vouchers collected for shares, mainly due to the slow pace of the privatisation process where funds can only buy shares once the sale to employees and the public is completed.</p>
<p>&quot;Because of the fact that the funds only managed to exchange about a third of the vouchers for companies' shares, demand in the funds' shares will be low, while the price will also remain quite low -- at about 20 percent of their nominal value,&quot; Toni Apollonio, an analyst at bank A banka said.</p>
<p>He said a lot of people were expected to sell fund shares as soon as they are listed as those who placed their vouchers in funds were already disappointed by getting no dividends and no possibility to sell their shares so far.</p>
<p>Analysts said the funds were not expected to be able to exchange the majority of their vouchers for shares this year, partly due to the fact that privatisation vouchers issued exceeded the amount of capital available by 136 billion tolars.</p>
<p>&quot;The state said it would cover this spread by offering additional state capital for vouchers by the end of this year,&quot; said Andrej Urbas, president of the management board of the Association of Investment Companies. -- Marja Novak, Ljubljana newsroom, 386-61-125-8439</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
