<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45582" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. stocks seen lower, Motorola warns on Q3.</title>
<headline>U.S. stocks seen lower, Motorola warns on Q3.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street stocks are expected to open lower on Wednesday, jolted by a warning from semiconductor and telecommunications equipment giant Motorola Inc that its third quarter earnings were likely to disappoint.</p>
<p>Analysts said the comment was likely to post an early challenge to stocks, recalling that in July, Motorola's surprisingly weak earnings helped trigger a sharp sell-off that hit technology stocks particularly hard.  </p>
<p>However, analysts stopped short of calling for a re-enactment of the widespread selling pressure based on this quarter's comments.</p>
<p>&quot;It was Motorola that helped shake up the market in July but since then it appears that the market has already digested most of the problems,&quot; said Larry Wachtel, market analyst at Prudential Securities.</p>
<p>Helping to offset the warning are several factors, analysts said, including Motorola's underperformance during the broader market's late summer recovery, an indication that investors remained aware of the company's problems.  </p>
<p>Continued strength in the dollar is also expected to offer some support, said analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;Are we in for a major decline? I don't think so,&quot; said Peter Cardillo, director of research at Westfalia Investments. &quot;I suspect we're in for a lower opening but the stronger dollar should support bonds and that will help.&quot;</p>
<p>One other glimmer of hope could come from Tuesday's book-to-bill index, which rose to 0.90 in August from a revised 0.86 in July. Though still fairly weak, the index's improvement during a seasonally slow month was a positive development for the troubled semiconductor sector.  </p>
<p>Motorola specifically cited continued weakess in semiconductor unit demand and pricing in its profit warning.</p>
<p>At 1200 EDT/1600 GMT, the Federal Reserve will release its Beige Book economic survey.  The report is expected to show hints of tighter labor markets but tame inflation numbers for finished goods.</p>
<p>In Tokyo, stocks moved a trace higher in lackluster trade. The Nikkei-225 Average rose 11 points to 20,571.</p>
<p>U.S. stocks were little changed in London, with markets on hold ahead of the Fed's Beige Book report.  The FTSE-100 index fell 16.6 points to 3899.5.  </p>
<p>The dollar was steady in Tokyo but pushed above the key 110 yen level in European trade, where it also eased against the German mark.</p>
<p>Bonds softened in early trade.  The benchmark 30-year U.S. Treasury fell 11/32 to yield 7.14 percent.</p>
<p>The S&amp;P 500 index future fell 2.05 points to 663.05.</p>
<p>Sam Zell, whose company Manufactured Home Communities Inc is trying to acquire Chateau Properties Inc, is arguing Chateau's top executives have a conflict of interest in deciding which of three bids to accept for the company, the New York Times Marketplace column reports.  </p>
<p>Zell argues that the executives are more concerned with avoiding taxes than with getting the best offer, the column states.</p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal's Heard on the Street column reports that many money managers are focusing on seeking out the best acquirers in the ever-consolidating banking industry as investment choices.</p>
<p>-- Wall Street desk, 212-859-1730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
