<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="455859" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenia's Nafta Lendava 1996 net loss narrows.</title>
<headline>Slovenia's Nafta Lendava 1996 net loss narrows.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenia's sole refinery Nafta Lendava said on Thursday 1996 net losses narrowed 297 million tolars to 798 million tolars ($5.2 million) due to lower costs and higher productivity.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not been able to return to black figures because of the high price of raw materials and the low price of petrol, which is controlled by the government,&quot; Nafta's spokesman Stefan Prsa told Reuters.</p>
<p>Nafta Lendava is 55 percent owned by gasoline trader Petrol, which is expected to be listed on the Ljubjlana stock exchange soon.</p>
<p>Petrol prices in Slovenia are among the lowest in Europe, with a litre of unleaded petrol costing 78.4 tolars ($0.51).</p>
<p>&quot;The 1997 business figures will depend on the government's moves regarding the price of petrol,&quot; Prsa said.</p>
<p>In 1996, Nafta refined 480,000 tonnes of crude oil, down from 513,000 the previous year, while the company plans to refine some 526,000 tonnes in 1997.</p>
<p>Nafta has been facing serious problems since the end of January when its main crude oil supplier Croatian INA stopped delivering oil in order to supply its own refinery in Sisak.</p>
<p>Until January, some 65 percent of Nafta's supplies came from Croatia, while the rest was imported from Arab countries and the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>The company said it would replace Croatia's oil by increasing imports from its other existing markets. -- Novica Mihajlovic, Ljubljana newsroom, 386-61-125-8439</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
