<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="455950" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Cuba slams Nicaragua for backing anti-Castro exile.</title>
<headline>Cuba slams Nicaragua for backing anti-Castro exile.</headline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cuba accused Nicaragua on Thursday of malice and lack of scruples for having invited an anti-Castro Cuban exile to join Managua's delegation to this month's U.N. human rights commission session in Geneva.</p>
<p>A Cuban foreign ministry statement said Cuba &quot;will make the corresponding response to this manoeuvre at the most appropriate time, in the most appropriate place and in the most appropriate way.&quot;</p>
<p>Ministry spokeswoman Marianela Ferriol, who read the statement at a regular weekly news briefing, did not elaborate on what such a response might consist of.</p>
<p>Nicaragua, whose relations with Havana have been edgy since the leftist Sandinista government lost power in 1990, has invited exile Luis Zuniga to accompany its delegation to Geneva. Zuniga is a member of the powerful Miami-based exile group the Cuban American Foundation, which opposes President Fidel Castro's government.</p>
<p>The Cuban statement said Nicaragua's move to include him on its delegation was &quot;unscrupulous, malicious, apart from lacking in originality.&quot;</p>
<p>The Cuban statement did not even name Zuniga, but called him &quot;a little personality from the Cuban counter-revolutionaries in Miami,&quot; and also called him a &quot;confessed terrorist from Miami's gangster world.&quot;</p>
<p>The statement added that until now it had been the United States that made such gestures. Washington, long Cuba's political enemy, is consistently Havana's main adversary at the annual U.N. human rights commission meetings, sponsoring a resolution condemning the island's rights record.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
