<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="455961" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil coffee exporters pleased with ACPC decision.</title>
<headline>Brazil coffee exporters pleased with ACPC decision.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Bulloch</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A decision by key members of the Association of Coffee Producing Countries (ACPC) to recommend an increase in the supply of arabica coffee to the world market was a responsible move, an exporter official said</p>
<p>&quot;I think the ACPC is reacting correctly to the needs of the world market,&quot; said Oswaldo Aranha, president of the Brazilian Coffee Exporters Federation.</p>
<p>The ACPC technical committee agreed today to recommend a previous decision to reduce exports of arabica coffee by 300,000 60-kg bags in the first half of this year be revoked and that an additional 200,000 bags be released.</p>
<p>The full ACPC council has to ratify the decision when it next meets in May but this is seen as just a formality.</p>
<p>Although the committee did not discuss the quota distribution among arabica producer countries, traders anticipated the extra quota would mainly be taken up by Central American countries, believed to anticipated third quarter sales given the recent high prices.</p>
<p>&quot;This will not have any effect on the market as Colombia is not going to be able to fill its quota so the overall quota for arabicas will be little changed,&quot; said Jair Coser, president of leading exporter Unicafe.</p>
<p>Earlier in the day a delegate from Costa Rica said there was a proposal to re-introduce an export quota program with a trigger price mechanism from May but there was no mention of the proposal at the end of the meeting.</p>
<p>This was welcomed by traders who were concerned that a return to a trigger-price mechanism similar to former market interventions by the International Coffee Organisation would send the wrong signal to consuming nations.</p>
<p>&quot;This would just complicate things at a time when we should be trying to make things simpler,&quot; one exporter said.</p>
<p>&quot;Moreover Brazil does not have the controls to be able to control exports, turn on and off supply, in the same way as for example Colombia,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>There is already some pressure within Brazil to do away with export quotas completely in 1997/98 (July/June).</p>
<p>Last week the Brazilian Association of Coffee Exporters sent a letter to Mauricio Assis, the head of the primary commodities department at the Industry and Commerce Ministry, asking for the immediate suspension of export quotas given current price levels, said Abecafe president Jorge Esteve.</p>
<p>Other exporters however thought it would not be wise to remove the export quota system altogether but that it could be used to set export targets, not limits.</p>
<p>The immediate problem facing Brazilian exporters is how to cope with an internal market which is refusing to allign itself with international prices.</p>
<p>Coffees which should be around 205 reais per bag based on the New York market are being offered by producers at around 220 reais, dealers said.</p>
<p>Exporters with immediate commitments are having to pay up but the firm domestic market could take its toll on sales in the coming months, dealers said.</p>
<p>On the export market, Santos brokers Wolthers &amp; Associates quoted speciality 17/18s coffees at 13 over New York for May/June shipment, fine 17/18s at three over and Swedish qualities at five under.</p>
<p>In the domestic market, Santos brokers Escritorio Carvalhaes on March 20 quoted fine-to-extrafine Mogiana/Minas green beans at 215/218 reais per 60 kg against 223/225 on March 13.</p>
<p>-- Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 5074151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
