<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456014" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Gorbachev - eight of 10 Russians in dire poverty.</title>
<headline>Gorbachev - eight of 10 Russians in dire poverty.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Up to 80 percent of Russians live in dire poverty and current policies favour only 10 percent of the people, former Soviet President Mikhail Gorbachev said in an Argentine newspaper interview published on Thursday</p>
<p>&quot;Sixty percent of the Russian population lives in absolute poverty according to official data. We believe the rate is higher and may be as much as 80 percent,&quot; Gorbachev told La Nacion newspaper during a visit to Buenos Aires.</p>
<p>&quot;Only 10 percent of the population are being favoured. With this setup, things cannot go well,&quot; he said, predicting that with President Boris Yeltsin winning &quot;only three percent&quot; in  opinion polls, Russia would soon reach the breaking point.</p>
<p>&quot;It's possible that civilian society could erupt,&quot; said the man who introduced the former Soviet Union to glasnost (openness) and perestroika (restructuring) only to see the reforms get bogged down in economic problems.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't like saying these things but there are people who have not been paid their wages for six months. There are 22 million people unemployed. That is a very dangerous burden,&quot; Gorbachev said.</p>
<p>The former president is visiting Argentina as president of the environmental group Green Cross, founded in Japan in 1993. He met Argentine President Carlos Menem on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
