<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456138" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Fake credit card syndicate smashed in Hong Kong.</title>
<headline>Fake credit card syndicate smashed in Hong Kong.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's anti-corruption watchdog on Thursday claimed a second victory in less than a week, saying it had smashed a fake credit card syndicate and arrested 13 people.</p>
<p>The Independent Commission Against Corruption (ICAC) said 187 counterfeit credit cards and equipment used to manufacture them were seized from two premises in Kowloon district in an operation that began on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Genuine credit card data was also found, it said.</p>
<p>The ICAC said four of the suspects were released on ICAC bail but the remainder were still in custody as investigations continued.</p>
<p>The arrests come after the anti-graft body uncovered a major horse race fixing and illegal bookmaking scandal earlier this week which shook the territory's elite horse-racing circle.</p>
<p>The ICAC said the credit card syndicate had contacts in China, Macau, Taiwan and Malaysia and was believed to have obtained the data by bribing staff at a five-star hotel and several retailers in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>The syndicate was estimated to have caused some HK$500,000 (US$65,000) in losses to Hong Kong companies, although potential losses were estimated at around HK$5 million ($650,000), it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150108">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
