<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456109" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZIER sees less upward pressure on NZ dollar.</title>
<headline>NZIER sees less upward pressure on NZ dollar.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand Institute of Economic Research said on Friday new monetary policy settings meant there was probably less potential for upward pressure on the exchange rate in the longer term.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank (RBNZ)'s inflation target band was widened in December by the new National-New coalition government to 0-3 percent from 0-2 percent.</p>
<p>The NZIER noted that the bank explicitly acknowledged in December 1996 it was prepared to see interest rates fall if the currency continued to rise.  </p>
<p>It forecast the currency's Trade-Weighted Index would ease slightly throughout 1997 as price pressures eased.</p>
<p>&quot;However, we have assumed that the Reserve Bank will tighten monetary policy in early 1998 in anticipation of inflationary effects from the mid 1998 tax cuts,&quot; the NZIER said.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result the TWI rises from mid 1998 through to mid 1999, when it begins to fall again. However, in comparison with recent rises in the TWI, the projected rise in 1998 is muted.&quot;  </p>
<p>The NZIER's working assumption in preparing its forecasts was that the compulsory superannuation scheme proposed by the new coalition government would not go ahead. A referendum on the issue is scheduled for September.</p>
<p>If the scheme gets the go ahead, the tax cuts planned for July 1998 will be used instead as the first contribution to the scheme.</p>
<p>The NZIER said another factor constraining the rise in the TWI was the expanding current account deficit, which would be reflected in higher domestic demand for overseas currency, putting downward pressure on the New Zealand dollar.  </p>
<p>The NZIER forecast the Reserve Bank would be successful in keeping underlying inflation within its target band, since underlying inflation peaked at 2.4 percent in March 1999.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
