<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456224" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Senate rebukes Mexico on drugs, seeks reforms.</title>
<headline>U.S. Senate rebukes Mexico on drugs, seeks reforms.</headline>
<byline>William Scally</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Senate on Thursday approved legislation criticising Mexico's performance in the anti-drug war and listing goals for stepping up its efforts.</p>
<p>The measure was a compromise drafted in cooperation with the Clinton administration, which had opposed a House of Representatives vote last week to overturn President Bill Clinton's finding that Mexico has fully cooperated in fighting drugs.</p>
<p>Clinton ruled on February 28 that Mexico was a reliable ally in the war against drugs, a step required to spare it U.S. economic sanctions.</p>
<p>Congressional critics insist Mexico did not merit such a declaration and the House voted to overturn it, suspending its rebuke for 90 days to give Mexico time to improve its record.</p>
<p>The House vote infuriated Mexico and the Senate agreed to a softer step which has no practical effect.</p>
<p>After a week of intense wrangling, however, it is quite possible no Senate resolution will stand. Congress as a whole is required to act on certification within 30 days of Clinton's finding, meaning the House would also have to approve the Senate version this week, before a scheduled two-week recess, and it is already loaded with commitments.</p>
<p>The Senate measure criticises the Mexican anti-drugs effort as inadequate on several points and requires Clinton to report by September 1 on progress by the U.S. and Mexican governments to improve matters.</p>
<p>That date is well after the Mexican elections in July.</p>
<p>Approved by a vote of 94-5, the measure requires progress on dismantling drug trafficking organisations, on strengthening bilateral cooperation and border enforcement and on denying safe havens to traffickers.</p>
<p>The measure had been watered down to accommodate administration concerns that a harsh indictment of Mexico could torpedo the very cooperation that is being sought.</p>
<p>Negotiations between key senators and administration officials led by Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin had gone into full bore after the House vote to overturn Clinton's &quot;certification&quot; of Mexico as a reliable drug ally.</p>
<p>Sen Dianne Feinstein, a California Democrat and one of three senators leading the negotiations with the administration, told the Senate that inadequate progress by Mexico would leave &quot;no alternative but to fuel up for another Mexico certification battle next year.&quot;</p>
<p>Opponents of the legislation argued that Clinton, by certifying a country that clearly was not cooperating fully, had failed to abide by the law.</p>
<p>Voting against the measure were Republicans Sam Brownback of Kansas, Tim Hutchinson of Arkansas, Bob Smith of New Hampshire, Craig Thomas of Wyoming and Democrat Robert Torricelli of New Jersey.</p>
<p>The Senate measure lists a number of specific failures in Mexico's anti-drugs effort and concludes: &quot;There has been ineffective and insufficient progress in halting the production and transit through Mexico of illegal drugs.&quot;</p>
<p>It says that much of the cocaine used in the United States comes from Mexico, that there is evidence that Mexican institutions are affected by &quot;significant corruption&quot; and that Mexico has yet to fully implement new law against organised crime and money laundering.</p>
<p>It says Mexican drug cartels operate with impunity and Mexico has not honoured any U.S. requests to extradite Mexican nationals indicted in the United states on drug charges.</p>
<p>The requested presidential report would detail progress by the two governments on dismantling drug trafficking organisations, on strengthening bilateral cooperation and border enforcement and on denying safe havens to traffickers.</p>
<p>It would have to detail actions on crop eradication, money laundering and criminal screening of law enforcement officers.</p>
<p>It calls for information on progress by the United States in anti-drug education, international drug interdiction and deployment of 1,000 additional immigration patrol agents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
