<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456330" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</title>
<headline>Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain and oilseed exports reported by USDA and private export sources.</p>
<p>CORN SALE - The Commodity Credit Corp of the U.S. Agriculture Department said it bought 4,620 tonnes of No. 2 or better yellow corn for donation to Guatemala. It paid $130.89 per tonne, FOB, to Cargill Inc. Shipment is for April 3-27.</p>
<p>WHEAT SALE - The United States is providing Sri Lanka $10 million in long-term, low-interest aid to buy about 55,000 tonnes of wheat, the U.S. embassy in Colombo said. The quantity represents some six percent of the country's annual wheat imports, it said in a statement.  </p>
<p>SOY TENDER - The Taichung division of Taiwan's Breakfast Soybean Procurement Association has delayed to Friday its planned Thursday tender for 54,000 tonnes of soybeans and eliminated the United States as a source, traders said. The tender, which had specified U.S. or Argentine soybeans when announced on Wednesday, was revised to include Brazil as a possible source.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDER - France will hold a tender on March 26 to sell 3,000 tonnes of soft wheat to Iraq via the Rome-based World Food Programme, national grain office ONIC said. The wheat is for shipment in bulk and in bags between April 8 and April 30.</p>
<p>- Iraq is tendering on March 21 for another 50,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat for May shipment, the exporters said.</p>
<p>- India's State Trading Corporation (STC) has tendered for 50,000 tonnes of wheat imports for arrival in the post-monsoon season from September onwards, a senior STC official told Reuters on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>CORN TENDER - Taiwan's Members Feed Industry Group has moved to Friday a tender initially set for Thursday for up to 112,000 tonnes of U.S. No.2 or Argentine corn, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>VEGOIL TENDER - Egypt was seeking up to 45,000 tonnes of assorted vegetable oils for delivery in May 1997. The deadline for all bids was on April 2.</p>
<p>BARLEY TENDER - The South African Wheat Board said it was offering 25,150 tonnes of feed grade barley for export sale no later than April 30.  </p>
<p>RICE TENDER - Syria seeks 12,000 tonnes of white rice for shipment between April 20 and May 20, a company spokesman said. April 8 is the final date for bids, and results will be announced on April 16.</p>
<p>- Costa Rica will seek on March 19 a total of 30,000 tonnes optional origin rough rice which would likely be from the United States or Argentina, U.S. exporters and trade sources said.  </p>
<p>MARKET TALK - Malaysia will be looking to buy at least 90,000 tonnes of corn for the May/July period but its buyers are shying away because prices remain a shade too high, regional traders said....Taiwan grain buyers estimated on Thursday that a disease-linked ban on pork exports would cause the island's imports of feed corn to fall by about one-fifth....South Africa's maize crop will be almost two million tonnes smaller than last season, dashing hopes of another bumper harvest and strong export earnings for the country.</p>
<p>((Doris Frankel 312-983-7305))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
