<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456453" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Maytag unveils new Neptune washer.</title>
<headline>Maytag unveils new Neptune washer.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Maytag Corp on Thursday unveiled its new horizontal-axis washing machine, the Neptune washer, in New York City.</p>
<p>In a company presentation which featured the Maytag lonely repairman shown on TV advertisements and TV moms from such popular shows as the Brady Bunch and the Jeffersons, the new washer was touted as being &quot;the washer of the new millenium&quot; by Lloyd Ward, President of Maytag Appliances.  </p>
<p>The company said the machine will be released for retail sale about July of this year, and the household model will be priced at around $999 for the washer and $499 for the accompanying dryer.</p>
<p>Company officials said that the Neptune washer had already been introduced for the commercial market three weeks ago.</p>
<p>According to the company, the new washer treats clothes more gently than current conventional washers, can clean stains better, has the largest capacity of any residential washer in the market today and uses less energy and water.</p>
<p>The company said the Neptune washer uses 65 percent less energy than conventional washers and 40 percent less water.</p>
<p>The new Neptune washer is a front load washer with a tub that tilts upwards.  According to the company, it spins faster than conventional washers and thus gets better water extraction.</p>
<p>The Neptune washer tumbles clothes in and out of a shallow pool of water rather than agitating them in a full tub.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
