<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456428" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: State bank, insurance regulators seek coordination.</title>
<headline>State bank, insurance regulators seek coordination.</headline>
<dateline>PHOENIX 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>State bank regulators, seeking to let state-chartered banks sell insurance in a manner comparable to that of national banks, have begun meeting with their counterparts in state insurance regulation, a regulator said Thursday.</p>
<p>Under recent federal court rulings and agency policies, federally-chartered banks are expected to dramatically expand their insurance sales.  State insurance regulators in many states had previously thwarted those efforts but the new rulings allow federal regulators to supersede overly restrictive state laws.  </p>
<p>State-chartered banks cannot always rely on the same rulings, however.</p>
<p>The Conference of State Bank Supervisors has moved to protect state banks by meeting with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, Earl Manning, Missouri's commissioner of finance, said.</p>
<p>The state banking group &quot;fully supports the sale of insurance by financial institutions,&quot; he said at a meeting of the Independent bankers Association of America here.  &quot;States should not pass laws that restrict such sales or discriminate against state banks to the advantage of national banks.&quot;  </p>
<p>The two groups of state regulators met for the first time recently and plan to hold an ongoing series of meetings, Manning said.  The bank supervisors have also discussed their concerns with the National Association of State Legislators, he said.</p>
<p>State bank regulators generally favor expansion of bank powers, Manning said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the goal of state bank supervisors to support the expansion of banking powers to the extent that additional products and services can be offered without endangering the safety and soundness of individual banks or the state banking system,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Aaron Pressman((--202-898-8312))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHOENIX"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
