<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456480" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYC FY 97 budget not hit by court ruling - Hevesi.</title>
<headline>NYC FY 97 budget not hit by court ruling - Hevesi.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York City Comptroller Alan Hevesi said Thursday he did not expect the city's fiscal 1997 budget to be hurt by a court ruling rejecting the Giuliani Administration's plan to sell the city water system.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on the current borrowing plan, the city should have no problems with its capital plan this year,&quot; Hevesi said in prepared remarks.</p>
<p>The city had planned to fund a range of capital projects with $1 billion of the $2.3 billion it would have captured by selling the water and sewer system.  </p>
<p>Around $600 million of the $1 billion was budgeted for fiscal 1997, and $400 million for fiscal 1998, according to a city source who declined to be named.</p>
<p>The city's latest borrowing plan calls for selling up to $2.7 billion of bonds before the end of June. Hevesi said this should take care of current needs.</p>
<p>But now the Giuliani Administration will have to close an even bigger budget gap in fiscal 1998, which starts July 1. That gap was previously estimated at about $1.45 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;They need to find (another $400 million),&quot; said the city source.  </p>
<p>Spokesmen for the Mayor Rudolph Giuliani did not return telephone calls seeking comment.</p>
<p>Hevesi had blocked the city from selling the water and sewer system it has owned for 150 years, saying he would decline to approve the bonds needed to finance it.</p>
<p>The comptroller was sued by the Giuliani Administration, which took the battle to the state's highest court. The state Court of Appeals today ruled that the Water Finance Authority could only sell bonds for water projects and corporate purposes.</p>
<p>Hevesi noted that last summer he proposed a number of ways for the Giuliani Administration to make up the $1 billion shortfall, including using funds from planned sales of assets for pay-as-you-go-capital.</p>
<p>Giuliani is counting on selling the midtown Colisium for $200 million, as well selling the United Nations Plaza Hotel and city-owned garages.</p>
<p>Hevesi said the mayor could use a recent $250 million transfer from the Metropolitan Transportation Authority that is being paid for with city debt.</p>
<p>((--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
