<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456468" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: &quot;Partial birth&quot; abortion bill heads for House vote.</title>
<headline>&quot;Partial birth&quot; abortion bill heads for House vote.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Zabarenko</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>After impassioned debate, a controversial bill to ban what opponents call &quot;partial birth&quot; abortion headed for a vote in the House of Representatives on Thursday, despite President Bill Clinton's vow to veto it.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a subject that is heartbreaking to all of us,&quot; Representative Dick Armey, a Texas Republican, said as the debate began. The question, Armey said, was &quot;whether this nation can tolerate or must it ban a particular procedure by which the life of a child is snuffed out.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton vetoed an identical bill last year, saying that it lacked a crucial clause allowing the procedure to be performed in cases where the life or health of the pregnant woman was at risk. The current measure provides only for cases where the woman's life is in jeopardy.</p>
<p>In a statement released Wednesday, the White House said the new bill contained &quot;the same serious flaws&quot; as the one approved by Congress last year and said Clinton would veto it for the same reasons.</p>
<p>&quot;By refusing to permit women, in reliance on their doctors' best medical judgment, to use this procedure when their lives are threatened or when their health is put in serious jeopardy, the Congress has fashioned a bill that is consistent neither with the Constitution nor with sound public policy,&quot; Clinton said in his 1996 veto message.</p>
<p>The procedure involves the partial extraction of the foetus feet-first, the subsequent suctioning out of the foetal brain and removal of the foetus.</p>
<p>The issue has sparked heated debate, with abortion rights proponents faulting the proposed ban as unconstitutional and abortion foes calling the procedure itself barbaric.</p>
<p>Opponents complained that the bill's backers were trying to push it through quickly without the opportunity for them to offer alternatives or amendments.</p>
<p>&quot;This vote today is about the value of women's health,&quot; Representative Nita Lowey, a New York Democrat, said. &quot;The (Republican) leadership won't go along ... this leadership doesn't want to ban this procedure; they want a political issue.&quot;</p>
<p>The bill would impose fines or potential imprisonment of up to two years, and allows the maternal father or grandparents, if the mother is under 18, to file a civil lawsuit against the doctor for monetary damages equalling three times the cost of the abortion procedure.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
