<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456596" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Annan irked at delay over Angola unity government.</title>
<headline>Annan irked at delay over Angola unity government.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Goodman</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.N. Secretary-General Kofi Annan expressed regret on Thursday that a much-delayed government of national unity had still not been formed in Angola and mainly blamed the failure of officials of the former UNITA rebel movement to arrive in Luanda, the capital.</p>
<p>Establishment of a new government was originally scheduled for Jan. 25 but postponed several times, most recently until March 20. Its formation would mark the culmination of a 1994 peace accord signed in Lusaka, Zambia, by the government of President Jose Eduardo dos Santos and UNITA, ending years of civil war.</p>
<p>&quot;I find it regrettable that, despite determined and intensive efforts, the government of unity and national reconciliation has not yet been established,&quot; Annan said in a report to the Security Council.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a matter of very serious concern that its formation has again been postponed, owing primarily to the failure of UNITA to send all its officials to Luanda as previously agreed.&quot;</p>
<p>Annan, who is on an African trip and is due in Angola on Saturday, said the repeated delays were having a negative effect on implementation of major aspects of the peace process. These included the normalisation of state administration throughout the country and the demobilization of UNITA personnel not needed for a new integrated army.</p>
<p>&quot;This situation is seriously undermining the credibility of the peace process and should not be allowed to continue,&quot; Annan said.</p>
<p>&quot;I realise that the patience of the international community is wearing thin,&quot; he said, adding he intended visiting Angola from March 22 to 25 to assess the situation and impress on the parties the need to establish the national unity government without delay.</p>
<p>Although UNITA had confirmed it would send all its representatives to Luanda between March 15 and 17, some began arriving only on the evening of the latter date, Annan said.</p>
<p>By March 19, only 43 of 70 UNITA deputies had reached the capital, including some who had been there since February, while seven out of 11 officials designated to fill posts in the new government had arrived.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
