<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456578" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German DAX index blasted by Greenspan comments.</title>
<headline>German DAX index blasted by Greenspan comments.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares hit intraday lows in post-bourse electronic trade on Thursday after U.S. Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan signalled that the central bank was inching towards raising interest rates.</p>
<p>The IBIS DAX index ended at 3,247.03 points, down 58.69 points or 1.78 percent, having earlier fallen 2.21 percent to 3,232.57 points after the Greenspan comments.</p>
<p>In prepared testimony to Congress' Joint Economic Committee, Greenspan said the economy retains a &quot;great deal of vigor&quot; and the jobs market is strong.</p>
<p>The central bank's policy-making Federal Open Market Committee meets on Tuesday to consider raising short-term rates for the first time in over two years. The dollar went higher against the mark on the news.</p>
<p>Earlier the DAX-30 index ended at 3,264.67 points, down 1.55 percent.</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom was the heaviest-traded stock in afternoon trade, ending the day up 50 pfennigs at 36.70 marks.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone is reckoning on a rate increase in the U.S. next week. But I think what we are seeing at the moment could best be described as a healthy consolidation, and I don't think a serious correction is on the cards,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Sentiment was also muted in advance of Friday's triple-witching options expiry. March DAX DTB futures, due to expire then, fell 65 points to 3,244 points, which had a negative effect on the cash market.</p>
<p>The big corporate news of the day was the return to trade of steel/engineering groups Thyssen AG and Krupp-Hoesch after two days of suspension related to Krupp's attempts to produce a merger of their steel businesses.</p>
<p>Krupp ended up 15.56 percent at 312 marks, while Thyssen ended up 8.59 percent at 374.10 marks, making them two of the biggest gainers in afternoon IBIS trade.</p>
<p>Drugs group Schering AG climbed early on amid continued positive reaction to its move on Wednesday to raise its forecast for 1997 results.</p>
<p>However it was the subject of profit-taking later on and ended down 80 pfennigs at 161.50 marks.</p>
<p>Other shares in the pharmaceutical/drugs sector performed well in the afternoon, with Gehe ending up one mark, 0.83 percent.</p>
<p>Banks also took a hammering later on, with Deutsche Bank ending down 3.44 percent, or 3.11 marks at 87.40 marks, while carmaker Volkswagen ended down 33.90 marks, or 3.74 percent, at 872 marks.</p>
<p>The banks also took a hammering later on, with Deutsche down 3.11 marks at 87.40 marks and Commerzbank down 76 pfennigs at 45.15 marks.</p>
<p>--Clifford Coonan, Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
