<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45667" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLISH ECONOMY POISED FOR HIGH, STABLE GROWTH - IMF.</title>
<headline>POLISH ECONOMY POISED FOR HIGH, STABLE GROWTH - IMF.</headline>
<byline>Jan Strupczewski</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's economy is on a path of high and stable economic growth with inflation likely to fall to a single digit by the year 2000, the International Monetary Fund's (IMF) representative in Poland said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Marcus Rodlauer told a news conference presenting the IMF's annual report that Poland, after a seven percent gross domestic product (GDP) rise in 1996, could sustain a growth rate of five to six percent.</p>
<p>&quot;All the ingredients now appear to be there for a quiet, nice and soft landing into a more stable and still very high rate of growth,&quot; Rodlauer said.</p>
<p>The IMF report notes Poland's fast 1995 GDP growth was unbalanced, because it was driven mainly by exports and investment while domestic demand remained subdued.</p>
<p>&quot;Towards the end of the year, however, there had been signs of a pickup in real wages and consumer confidence,&quot; the report's chapter devoted to Poland said.</p>
<p>The report was scheduled for issue on Friday but prematurely released by Polish news organisations on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Sustainable growth of five to six percent should not be a problem,&quot; Rodlauer said.</p>
<p>He said the government target of bringing down year-on-year inflation to a single digit by 2000 from 20.4 percent in July and 21.6 percent in December 1995 was realistic, but would require removing structural reasons for price grotwh, such as wage indexation.</p>
<p>&quot;With inflation it is a more complicated story, but single digit targets are achievable by 2000,&quot; Rodlauer said.</p>
<p>&quot;...The relation to growth...depends...on what you do with the structural reasons for inflaton. So if the issues of wage indexation and other sources of inflation are gradully addressed it will not take an unduly tight monetary or fiscal policy to bring inflation down,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The report said reducing inflation in Poland had proved more difficult than anticipated.</p>
<p>&quot;(The IMF's board of) directors believed that further reduction of inflation should be the top priority for macroeconomic policy,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>IMF directors also wrote that to curb price growth Poland should consider allowing the zloty more flexibility within its 14-percent trading band around the central bank's parity rate.</p>
<p>&quot;While the crawling peg regime had served Poland well in the past, Directors generally considered that a more flexible exchange rate policy could increase the effectiveness of monetary policy and bring about lower inflation,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>The zloty is currently devalued against a basket of five western currencies, in a mechanism called the crawling peg, by one percent a month to compensate for high inflation, running at 20.4 percent in July.</p>
<p>IMF directors praised Poland for keeping its budget deficit below three percent of GDP in 1995 but emphasised the importance of making further progress, the report said.</p>
<p>They welcomed the progress made in mass privatisation, trade and exchange reform, but urged the authorities to &quot;encourage broad reform of social security... and a timely completion of the restructuring and privatisation of commercial banks.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
