<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456666" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German politicians slam repatriation of Bosnians.</title>
<headline>German politicians slam repatriation of Bosnians.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A cross-party group of German politicians on Thursday criticised the country's policy of forced repatriation of thousands of Bosnian refugees and urged the Germany's 16 regional states to rethink the plans.</p>
<p>&quot;The Interior Ministry conference decision in autumn 1996 to send all refugees living in Germany back by the end of 1997 has shown itself to be completely unrealistic,&quot; a delegation from parliament's interior affairs committee said in a statement.</p>
<p>The delegation, which visited Bosnia in January, called on the interior ministers of the states meeting in Munich on Friday to discuss the issue and set new criteria for the repatriation of refugees.</p>
<p>Germany plans to repatriate 90,000 refugees in the so-called &quot;phase one&quot; category -- single adults and married couples without children -- by July 1.</p>
<p>Those remaining -- families with children -- will be ordered to leave starting in the middle of the year.</p>
<p>Germany took in 400,000 refugees from former Yugoslavia, more refugees than the rest of the European Union combined and had hoped more would return home of their own accord.</p>
<p>But the group said the repatriation should be organised so that the unstable situation in Bosnia was not made worse by an influx of homeless returnees.</p>
<p>It said many refugees who had returned to Bosnia of their own free will were registering with the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) after trying to find accommodation and necessities from the Bosnian authorities.</p>
<p>The group said each individual case should be tested separately and it called for special protection for those who would be in a minority group if they returned home, those in mixed marriages and those who suffered particular hardships.</p>
<p>Germany and its regional states, haunted by memories of World War Two and its aftermath, at first welcomed Bosnian war refugees with open arms, providing shelter and about 1,000 marks ($590) per family per month.</p>
<p>But the cash-strapped states decided last October to force the refugees to leave unless they volunteered to go. Since then 60 people have been forcibly repatriated, the government said in a reply to a parliamentary question.</p>
<p>The United Nations said only 250,000 of the total 2.1 million uprooted Bosnians had returned home by the end of last year, despite the right to return being central to the DAyton peace treaty which ended 43 months of war in Bosnia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
