<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456665" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: Court says Brussels Convention applies to child support bid.</title>
<headline>Court says Brussels Convention applies to child support bid.</headline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Court of Justice said on Thursday jurisdiction rules under the Brussels Convention apply to individuals seeking child support from a parent living in another member state.</p>
<p>Jackie Farrell, an Irish woman, sought child support in an Irish court from a Belgian resident, James Long. Farrell invoked a provision of the international agreement on jurisdiction which permits creditors to seek child support from a non-resident, in the applicant's place of domicile.</p>
<p>Long argued Farrell does not meet the definition of a maintenance creditor, because she had not obtained an order from the Irish court recognizing her as such.</p>
<p>The court said the intention of the drafters of the Convention was to protect an applicant for child support, generally considered the weaker party in proceedings, by providing an alternative basis for jurisdiction.</p>
<p>The court said the fact that the applicant had not previously obtained a judicial decision recognizing entitlement to child support did not affect the drafters' intention.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>EXCERPTS FROM THE JUDGMENT</p>
<p>(Original language of the case: English)</p>
<p>&quot;Brussels Convention - Article 5(2) - Definition of &quot;maintenance order&quot;&quot;</p>
<p>Case C-295/95</p>
<p>Reference from the Circuit Court, County of Dublin, for a preliminary ruling in the proceedings pending before that court between</p>
<p>Jackie Farrel</p>
<p>and</p>
<p>James Long</p>
<p>on the interpretation of article 5(2) of the Brussels Convention on Jurisdiction and the Enforcement of Judgments, as amended</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE COURT hereby rules</p>
<p>The first limb of article 5(2) of the Brussels Convention on Jurisdiction and the Enforcement of Judgments, as amended, must be interpreted as meaning that the term &quot;maintenance creditor&quot; covers any person applying for maintenance, including a person bringing a maintenance action for the first time.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
