<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45662" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: RADIO ROMANIA AFTERNOON HEADLINES AT 1 PM.</title>
<headline>RADIO ROMANIA AFTERNOON HEADLINES AT 1 PM.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Radio Romania news headlines:</p>
<p>* In Bucharest, schools will resume courses on October 1, instead of September 16, due to numerous cases of viral meningitis and poor sanitation in many of them, mayor Victor Ciorbea told a news conference.</p>
<p>He said city hall is allocating 1.0 billion lei for improvement of hygienic conditions until October 1.</p>
<p>* But Education ministry state secretary Romulus Pop said all schools would reopen on September 16, except those which have poor sanitary equipment or no running water.</p>
<p>He said ministry would release a decision on Friday.</p>
<p>* Lower Chamber of Deputies discussed bill to control dignitaries' fortune, part of an anti-corruption set of bills on a priority agenda in parliament.</p>
<p>Bill settles that fortune statements are confidential and can only be requested when there is evidence of illicit assets.</p>
<p>It also stipulates that parliament can demand president in office to make his assets statement.</p>
<p>* Cabinet met for weekly session to debate preparations ahead of November 3 elections and autumn farming campaign.</p>
<p>* Romania-Hungarian friendship treaty will be signed on September 16, in western city of Timisoara, at 1230 local (0930 GMT), by Premier Nicolae Vacaroiu and counterpart Gyula Horn, foreign ministry spokesman Sorin Ducaru said.</p>
<p>He said talks between President Ion Iliescu and Premier Horn would follow.</p>
<p>* Yugoslav Prime Minister Radoje Kontic is expected to make a working visit to Romania on September 20 to sign tourism, industry, culture and transport accords.</p>
<p>Kontic will be accompanied by a group of businessmen.</p>
<p>* No voter's cards have been distributed so far in Bucharest, Adrian Duta, head of government's elections secretariat, said. ($=3,177 lei) -- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
