<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456819" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India to seek bids for deep water oil/gas fields.</title>
<headline>India to seek bids for deep water oil/gas fields.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>India is preparing a fresh list of geological blocks, including its deep water regions, for bids from global oil firms, a government official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are carving out 35 blocks in consultation with ONGC (Oil and Natural Gas Corp ) and others,&quot; Avinash Chandra, adviser, exploration, ministry of petroleum and natural gas told a Bombay seminar on deep water oil exploration.  </p>
<p>&quot;The details would be announced soon,&quot; he said. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>In the 1970s and 1980s, when India focused on traditional onshore exploration, the reserve accretion was 18 to 30 million tonnes a year, Chandra said.</p>
<p>&quot;As we moved offshore, it (reserve accretion) is 10 times higher,&quot; he said. The shift from shallow to deep waters will lead to similar boost in India's reserves, he predicted.</p>
<p>The Bombay High field in shallow waters off the western coast now contributes the bulk of India's oil production.</p>
<p>Chandra said India's sedimentary basins were among the least explored in the world, a fact not widely known abroad.</p>
<p>He said the new exploration policy announced earlier this month provided a level playing ground for national and global firms. It was no longer mandatory to offer a 30 percent ownership to national oil firms in joint ventures.</p>
<p>&quot;No blocks are reserved for national oil firms,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>ONGC chairman B.C. Bora said his firm could think of joining hands with foreign firms for new blocks if it won them.</p>
<p>He said foreign firms may not be interested in joint ventures with ONGC for fields it was operating as these were subject to the state-fixed &quot;administered pricing mechanism.&quot;</p>
<p>The new exploration policy assures international price of oil and gas only for new discoveries.</p>
<p>Bora said the first two structures drilled in the east coast in the early 1980s were in depths of over 200 metres.</p>
<p>Two small discoveries made on the eastern continental slope could not be developed due to adverse logistics and high costs.</p>
<p>&quot;We are re-examining these now, for development by using cost-effective technology,&quot; Bora said.</p>
<p>An area of 1.4 million square km in water depth of 200-2,000 metres has been marked out as interesting for hydrocarbons.</p>
<p>&quot;The demand for petroleum products is anticipated to cross over 100 million tonnes per annum by the turn of the century, against an estimated likely annual indigenous production of 35 to 40 million tonnes,&quot; ONGC chairman said.</p>
<p>-- Shyam Kumar, Bombay energy desk +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
