<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456851" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian companies, government take issue with U.S.</title>
<headline>Canadian companies, government take issue with U.S.</headline>
<byline>Heather Scoffield</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's federal government and airline industry took issue on Thursday with the U.S. Federal Aviation Administration's move to charge planes for flying through U.S. airspace.</p>
<p>&quot;The American fees were not brought in with consultation at the level we thought would be appropriate,&quot; Transport Minister David Anderson told reporters.</p>
<p>Anderson said he would take up the matter with U.S. Transportation Secretary Rodney Slater in Washington on Friday.</p>
<p>The FAA said on Tuesday it submitted for public comment a plan to charge user fees to aircraft flying through U.S. airspace that did not take off or land in the United States.</p>
<p>The FAA said the rule, to be implemented on May 19, was consistent with international practices and was expected to generate about $90 million in fees for fiscal 1998.</p>
<p>Canada-to-Canada overflights in the United States were granted deferral of the fees until Oct. 1.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't dispute the right of the U.S. to recover its costs. They're entitled to do that,&quot; said John Crichton, president of the Air Transport Association of Canada, which represents Canadian commercial air carriers.</p>
<p>&quot;But there have been a whole bunch of important hoops that have been ignored here,&quot; Crichton said on Thursday in a telephone interview. &quot;What we strongly dispute is the process they've chosen.&quot;</p>
<p>Chrichton said the FAA had not followed international standards of consulting with users, discussing charges and providing notice of the changes.</p>
<p>&quot;They should defer this,&quot; Crichton said. &quot;It means tens of millions of dollars for Canadian air carriers.&quot;</p>
<p>Canada also charges for overflights, but U.S. aircraft crossing Canadian airspace on their way to another U.S. destination are exempt.</p>
<p>Anderson would not say if Canada would remove its exemption for U.S. flights if U.S. officials were not flexible on the user fees. He said American flights used Canadian space as much as Canadians used U.S. space.</p>
<p>We'd like to think we could avoid a war of escalating fees,&quot; said  Jeff Angel, a spokesman for Canadian Airlines International Ltd., Canada's second biggest airline.</p>
<p>Angel said that only two of his company's flights would be affected by the fees. He could not estimate the fees.</p>
<p>Canada's biggest carrier, Air Canada, was hopeful the FAA would agree to changes.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it would be realistic to hope for a total exemption,&quot; said spokeswoman Nicole Couture-Simard in Montreal. &quot;But we can hope for modifications.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
