<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="456861" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American, pilots meet to flesh out new labor pact.</title>
<headline>American, pilots meet to flesh out new labor pact.</headline>
<byline>Robert Trautman</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>American Airlines and its pilots union met Thursday to flesh out details of their tentative contract agreement aimed at ending a lengthy labour dispute and averting a strike next month.</p>
<p>No details of the tentative accord reached on Wednesday were announced, and there were no indications whether the deal was more or less favourable for the pilots than recommendations issued Wednesday by the Presidential Emergency Board that was created to press the two sides to come to terms.</p>
<p>Negotiators for American, a unit of AMR Corp., and the Allied Pilots Association met to iron out details before the deal is presented to the union's board on Friday.</p>
<p>APA said the deal was an &quot;agreement in principle&quot; and that more work needed to be done before it could be presented to the union's board.</p>
<p>Donald Carty, president of American, the nation's second-largest airline, said after the deal was reached on Wednesday: &quot;We are pleased to have a deal.  While it does not give us all we had hoped for, we very much wanted to resolve this matter.&quot;</p>
<p>The emergency board, formed by President Clinton on Feb. 15, called for a 6.5 percent pay raise along with stock options and job protection for APA pilots when American buys new, small commuter jets for its regional carrier, American Eagle.</p>
<p>Wages and who will fly the new jets -- APA pilots or lower-paid Eagle pilots -- have been the key issues in the dispute that erupted briefly into a strike at midnight on Feb. 14, which was ended when President Clinton formed the emergency board.</p>
<p>Who flies the new jets has remained a contentious issue.</p>
<p>Aside from the parties directly involved, Boeing Co. also has a vital interest in the talks. American has agreed to buy new Boeing jets worth $6.5 billion, but only if the pilots ratify a new contract.</p>
<p>Even if the union's board approves the contract, ratification by its 9,300 members remains far from certain.</p>
<p>The board approved a tentative contract last Sept. 2 by a vote of 10-8, but 61 percent of the pilots turned it down in January, which led to the negotiations and the brief strike last month before Clinton stepped in.</p>
<p>Clinton's action forced the pilots back to work for 60 days while the emergency board tried to forge a settlement and present it to the two sides.</p>
<p>The &quot;cooling off&quot; period was extended to April 28, when the APA will be free to strike. Then, only Congress can send the pilots back to work, with a law to require the pilots to accept the recommendations or enter binding arbitration.</p>
<p>The emergency board's proposed 6.5 percent pay increase matched American's last offer but also included options for pilots to buy AMR stock at a discount. The pilots had sought a pay raise of 11 percent.</p>
<p>On commuter jet cockpit rights, the APA wanted its pilots -- who earn an average of $120,000 a year -- to fly them, but American wanted them flown by $35,000-a-year Eagle pilots.</p>
<p>The APA said it was concerned that American would put Eagle's new, longer-range commuter jets on some of the longer routes now flown by American.</p>
<p>American says it needs the lower-paid pilots to fly Eagle jets to compete with other low-cost regional carriers.</p>
<p>To meet some of these concerns, the emergency board recommended that American agree to restrictions on the number of regional jets flown, the routes they fly and airports served.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
