<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45704" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RTRS-FOCUS-Nazi gold return talk fails to excite Gold market.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FOCUS-Nazi gold return talk fails to excite Gold market.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The bullion market ignored speculation over the fate of gold looted by Nazi Germany, since any return of gold held by Switzerland would be complicated and time consuming, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;No-one's talking about it. These guys will argue about it for years,&quot; said Ted Arnold, metals analyst at broker Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>The gold price, hovering around $383 per ounce, has barely moved since Britain disclosed in a report on Tuesday that Switzerland only turned over to Allied powers a small fraction of the gold it acknowledged buying in World War Two.</p>
<p>This spurred the Jewish community to renew calls on Switzerland to restore stolen gold to Nazi survivors and their descendants.</p>
<p>&quot;The pure logistics of tracing the original holders would be such that if anything is done it is going to take forever and a day,&quot; said Rhona O'Connell, metals analyst at broker T. Hoare and Company.</p>
<p>&quot;Now If I were a private individual who stood to inherit a half a tonne of gold I might well be tempted to sell some of it, but the prospects of that happening in the foreseeable future have to be nil to zero,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>The British report, citing a U.S. government account, said that the director of the Swiss National Bank said during post-war negotiations with the Allies that Swiss banks held $500 million of gold when the war ended -- $6.5 billion at today's prices.</p>
<p>Gold prices have been steadily crumbling since a frenzied rally pushed the market to six-year highs around $418 per ounce in February.</p>
<p>Over the past few weeks, speculators have been disappointed that U.S. strikes on Iraq have failed to rouse the market and are fearing the International Monetary Fund may approve a plan on Friday to sell some of its bullion reserves to finance aid to poor countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
