<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="457036" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: MERITA SEES SCANT DEMAND FOR 2004 BOND IN AUCTION.</title>
<headline>MERITA SEES SCANT DEMAND FOR 2004 BOND IN AUCTION.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Merita Bank said the current negative market sentiment was likely to dampen interest in Thursday's auction of the Finnish 9.50 percent serial 2004 bond.</p>
<p>&quot;Recent market unrest is mainly driven by EMU speculation. We view the current situation as too risky and do not recommend participation,&quot; Merita said in a pre-auction comment on Thursday.</p>
<p>From a fundamental point of view, Merita said the auction would be a clear buying opportunity.</p>
<p>&quot;The monetary policy outlook in Europe is still strongly supportive of bond markets,&quot; Merita said.</p>
<p>Improving government finances together with an extremely good liquidity situation for institutional investors should be supporting the bond market, Merita said.</p>
<p>&quot;Furthermore, there is hardly any doubt that Finland would be among the first countries (joining EMU) if EMU starts on time,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>At 1220/1020 GMT, the 2004 bond yield was quoted at 5.92 percent, up 12 basis points from Wednesday's 5.80 percent close.</p>
<p>The auction results are due after 1330/1130 GMT. In the previous auction on February 13, the State Treasury raised 3.03 billion markka at a yield of 5.46 percent.</p>
<p>-- Veera Heinonen, Helsinki newsroom + 358-9-680 50 240,</p>
<p>			     news@ Reuters.fi</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
