<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="457166" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: N.Express looks to Europe for expansion.</title>
<headline>N.Express looks to Europe for expansion.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>National Express Group Plc, which announced a 45 percent jump in profits on Thursday, said it is now looking for similar opportunities to take over public transport services in mainland Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking around Europe at the moment in terms of buses, coaches, airports and trains, and watching closely and trying to get in early,&quot; chief executive Phil White told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;There are targets in sight but I want to keep them to myself at the moment,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;They (other European governments) seem to be a bit behind the UK but they are certainly moving towards a more deregulated, privatised system,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>National Express earlier reported pretax profits rose to 60.1 million pounds last year from 41.5 million in 1995 on sales up 51 percent at 482.5 million pounds.</p>
<p>The firm now ranks as one of Britain's largest train operators, having netted five of the 25 passenger service franchises awarded by the British government over the last year to complete its railways privatisation programme ahead of the election on May 1.</p>
<p>Franchisees are now on test to prove to politicians and passengers opposed to the break-up of the former British Rail network that they can improve services and to allay investor concerns that the opposition Labour Party would give the train operators a rough ride if it wins the election.</p>
<p>But White said he was confident that National Express could work with Labour and saw no comparisons with rival bus and trains operator Stagecoach Holdings Plc which is already on a political collision course over its management of the South West Trains (SWT) franchise.  </p>
<p>Shares in Stagecoach, a former darling of the stock market, have plunged this month after SWT enraged passengers by cancelling hundreds of services on its commuter lines into London because staff cuts had left many trains driverless.</p>
<p>White said such propblems could have been avoided. National Express has cut its own workforce by 20 percent to around 1,170 staff on its Midland Mainline and Gatwick Express franchises since they were taken over without any losses in service.</p>
<p>&quot;Done in the right way, you should not have any problems and certainly we haven't,&quot; he told Reuters.  </p>
<p>&quot;We talk to a lot of politicians,&quot; he said.  &quot;We think we have got a feeling as to what they want and at the end of the day if it is a Labour government I think they are more interested in quality than going back to the old network with its high subsidies which will cost them a fortune.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think if operators like ourselves show that we are willing to reinvest our profits back into the business a Labour government will be well pleased,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The firm said Midland Mainline and Gatwick Express made 2.097 million pounds in operating profits on 108.48 million pounds of income in their eight months with National Express last year.</p>
<p>Passenger traffic on Midland Mainline increased by nine percent last year and National Express has promised new fares, products and promotions to increase demand further.</p>
<p>Traffic on Gatwick Express, which operates the fast rail link between central London and Gatwick airport, saw a three percent increase in passenger numbers last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Gatwick Express and Midland Mainline were very pleasing because they exceeeded budget expectations and also showed quite substantial traffic growth,&quot; White said.</p>
<p>This year the company has been awarded a further three train franchises, Scotrail, Central Trains and North London Railways.</p>
<p>-- Greg Mahlich, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
