<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45714" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Oil nears $24 a barrel as Iraq tension rises.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Oil nears $24 a barrel as Iraq tension rises.</headline>
<byline>Mark Thompson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil prices soared to their highest level since the Gulf War on Wednesday on news Iraq fired at a U.S. fighter planes flying over the north of the country.</p>
<p>World benchmark Brent Blend crude hit $23.82 a barrel -- the highest prompt price on London's International Petroleum Exchange since January 1991's $31.20 posted in the heat of Operation Desert Storm -- before easing back to $23.61 by 1534 GMT, still 73 cents above Tuesday's close.</p>
<p>Brent left its previous post-Gulf War high of $23.30 in its wake as Middle East tension mounted and the possibility of Iraq returning to the oil market after a six-year absence receded even further, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Brent jumped 20 cents on the news. We get more mileage out of an Iraqi gallon than any other,&quot; said Charles Gray of brokers Prudential Bache.</p>
<p>A senior U.S. defence official, who requested anonymity, told Reuters one or two surface-to-air missiles were fired at two U.S. fighters at 0758 GMT after they were illuminated by Iraqi radar.</p>
<p>&quot;The oil-for-food deal looks like a receding possibility. Maybe it will have to be 1997 before it's resurrected,&quot; said UBS' oil analyst Geoff Pyne.</p>
<p>The deal was supposed to allow Baghdad to sell $2 billion worth of oil over six months to raise funds for much-needed humanitarian supplies but it was suspended after Iraqi troops moved into Kurdish areas last week, drawing U.S. retaliatory strikes against targets in the south of the country.</p>
<p>&quot;While there is still a fair chance of further military action, the U.N. cannot deploy its personnel to monitor the limited oil sale. This is the real short-term issue that should concern the markets,&quot; said brokers GNI in a daily market report.</p>
<p>The U.S. said on Tuesday that air defence installations damaged in last week's attacks were being rebuilt and warned of further military action.</p>
<p>&quot;We have made it clear to Saddam that if he rebuilds air defences and threatens our missions over the no-fly zone...we will take action,&quot; Pentagon spokesman Ken Bacon said.</p>
<p>While further military action over Iraq poses little significant threat to the region's key oil supplies in Saudi Arabia, Iran and Kuwait, it should continue to deprive a thirsty market of 600-700,000 barrels per day (bpd) of Iraqi crude exports covered by the May 20 U.N. deal.</p>
<p>Italy said earlier this week it wanted the Security Council to make clear that Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali should go ahead with the oil-for-food deal to relieve the suffering of the Iraqi people.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously this sort of action takes the winds out of the sails of the Italians and the French...a market which is fairly tight should remain tight,&quot; said Gray.</p>
<p>In anticipation of resumed Iraqi oil sales, some refineries had allowed their stocks to run low and subsequently had to scramble to cover requirements at higher prices.</p>
<p>Industry data released on Tuesday showed U.S. crude stocks fell by more than 6.5 million barrels in the key Gulf Coast and East Coast refining regions last week.</p>
<p>Heating oil stocks, of increasing importance as the northern hemisphere winter approaches, rose by three million barrels but remain at just 70 percent of levels this time last year in the key northeast U.S. market.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>						    Sept 11	Sept 10</p>
<p>						  (1534 GMT)     (close)</p>
<p>    Dated Brent				 $23.45	 $22.71</p>
<p>    IPE London Brent futures (Oct)	$23.61	 $22.88</p>
<p>    NYMEX light crude futures (Oct)     $24.77	 $24.12</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
