<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="457255" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed Chairman Greenspan again rattles stock market.</title>
<headline>Fed Chairman Greenspan again rattles stock market.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stock prices fell Thursday after Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan hinted that he was inching toward raising interest rates, possibly as early as next week.</p>
<p>Shortly before 11 a.m. EST, the Dow Jones industrial average was off 50.23 points at 6,827.45. In the broader market, declining issues beat advances 3-1.</p>
<p>In the bond market, the 30-year Treasury bond was off 7/32, and its yield jumped to 7.01 percent from Wednesday's close of 6.99 percent.</p>
<p>In prepared testimony to the Joint Economic Committee of Congress, Greenspan said that the economy retains &quot;a great deal of vigor&quot; and the jobs market is strong.</p>
<p>Joseph Barthel, chief investment strategist at Fahnestock &amp; Co., said Greenspan has managed a 50 basis point rise in the long bond yield since his comments about &quot;irrational exhuberance&quot; in December.</p>
<p>&quot;He is using his jawboning capacity to get markets to move. Whether he has to put an exclamation mark on it by raising rates is debatable,&quot; Barthel said.</p>
<p>The Federal Reserve's policy-making Federal Open Market Committee meets on Tuesday to consider raising short-term interest rates for the first time in nearly two years.</p>
<p>Much of Greenspan's testimony seemed aimed at preparing lawmakers -- who have often been critical of Fed policy in the past -- for the possibility of a rate increase as soon as next week.</p>
<p>At next week's meeting, the FOMC will have to judge whether the strong pace of the economic expansion will continue and what impact that might eventually have on inflation, Greenspan said.</p>
<p>In addition to Greenspan's comments, the Dow was also suffering from a sell-off in stock of Philip Morris, which lost 4-5/8 to 117-3/8.</p>
<p>Philip Morris sank on news that state attorneys general are close to a settlement with Liggett, the tobacco unit of Brooke Group Ltd. Brooke Group shares were up 1/2 at 4-3/4.</p>
<p>&quot;Philip Morris has weathered these kinds of events before, so one can argue it will survive again,&quot; Barthel said. &quot;The big story for the company is international growth and not problems at home and how they will affect domestic growth.&quot;</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index was off 0.55 point at 1,248.74 and the American Stock Exchange index slipped 0.99 to 590.80.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
