<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="457211" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Israeli envoy to discuss peace proposal with Egypt.</title>
<headline>Israeli envoy to discuss peace proposal with Egypt.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli envoy Dore Gold arrived in Cairo on Thursday and said he would have talks with Egyptian officials on a new proposal about the peace process.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat arrived at about the same time, while Lebanese Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri and Syrian Foreign Minister Farouq al-Shara left for home after their own talks with Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak.</p>
<p>Gold, foreign policy adviser to Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, told reporters at Cairo airport: &quot;I'm here to convey a message from Israel to Egypt and we have a very new propsoal about the peace process to discuss with Egypt.&quot;</p>
<p>But Egyptian Foreign Minister Amr Moussa, in one of the strongest statements on the crisis, said Israel could not expect to go on tricking the Arabs with fine sounding promises and called on Israeli leaders to take note.</p>
<p>&quot;Don't underestimate Arab intelligence and don't play games with us,&quot; Moussa said. &quot;We cannot be deceived with any shining and sugar-coated promises...the weight of which we know,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Cairo is at the centre of intensive talks on Thursday on Israel's decision to go ahead with building a Jewish settlement in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The visitors came to see Mubarak as a new row broke out in Israeli-Palestinian relations over an Israeli proposal to bypass interim withdrawals from the West Bank.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SYRIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
