<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45725" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Massive volcano eruption overdue, says scientist.</title>
<headline>Massive volcano eruption overdue, says scientist.</headline>
<byline>Paul Mylrea</byline>
<dateline>BIRMINGHAM, England 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The world is long overdue for a huge volcanic eruption, 1,000 times more violent than the explosion of Pinatubo in the Philippines five years ago, a leading British scientist said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We may well be living on borrowed time,&quot; Professor Bill McGuire told Britain's annual science festival.</p>
<p>Studies of geological records show such events, which have devastating effects on the world's climate, dramatically cooling the temperature as fine debris reflects back the sun's rays, occur twice every 100,000 years.</p>
<p>The last was at Toba in Indonesia 70,000 years ago. That eruption shot 1,750 cubic miles (2,800 cubic kilometres) of debris into the atmosphere, dropping the earth's surface temperature 10 or 12 degrees Centigrade, sparking an ice age.</p>
<p>&quot;Statistically, we're way overdue for the next one,&quot; said McGuire, who has spent much of his career studying volcanoes such as Etna and Vesuvius in Italy.</p>
<p>McGuire warned that even without the &quot;big one&quot;, eruptions around the world were causing large loss of life and economic disruption, much of it needlessly.</p>
<p>&quot;Volcanic eruptions can't be prevented, but the effects can be mitigated much better,&quot; McGuire told Reuters at the British Association science festival in Birmingham, central England.</p>
<p>Only around 100 of the 500 or 600 known active volcanoes were currently being monitored. Most of those not monitored were in the developing world, he said.</p>
<p>Modern monitoring did not even have to be expensive, he said, with satellites already orbiting the globe. Schemes being pioneered in the Philippines and Indonesia using local inhabitants had also shown results, he said.</p>
<p>But educating local authorities and residents of the risks of building homes near volcanoes was also essential.</p>
<p>McGuire said the failure to get the message across to authorities in Nevado del Ruiz, Colombia, before the 1985 eruption there led to the needless death of 25,000 people, buried under an avalanche of volcanic mud.</p>
<p>Current danger zones include the Caribbean island of Montserrat, a British colony, where 15,000 residents have been evacuated since an eruption began last year. The worst danger is at Vesuvius, near Naples.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BIRMINGHAM, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
