<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="457229" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>YEMEN: Yemen's oil output set to rise - minister.</title>
<headline>Yemen's oil output set to rise - minister.</headline>
<byline>Barry May</byline>
<dateline>SANAA 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil production in impoverished Yemen, counting on increased income to allow further economic reforms agreed with the International Monetary Fund, will rise next year, the country's oil minister said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Mohammad Said al-Attar, who is also one of four deputy prime ministers in the government which is seeking re-election next month, said total oil production would rise to 420,000 barrels per day (bpd) in 1998, possibly increasing to 450,000.</p>
<p>Yemen, a relatively small independent producer outside the Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC), now pumps an average of 385,000 bpd, rising to 405,000 bpd in some months, Attar said.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential is 480,000, we hope,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview. &quot;We have a lot of demand now. There is a rush,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Prospects were very good, particularly in Yemen's third-largest oilfield, Jannah, Attar said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're very conservative in our figures and we don't want to exaggerate,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He forecast world oil prices would remain at $19-$22 per barrel in the near future.</p>
<p>President Ali Abdullah Saleh's coalition government, which diplomats in Sanaa expect to be returned to office in the April 27 election, is counting on increased oil revenue and a new liquefied natural gas project to rescue Yemen from its status as the Middle East's poorest state.</p>
<p>The country is credited with making good progress in economic reforms agreed with the IMF in 1995, but Western diplomats say more needs to be done.</p>
<p>The government removed all exchange controls last year and has succeeded in slashing inflation.</p>
<p>Subsidies on wheat and fuel have yet to be eliminated, however. Diplomats say action is expected after the election.</p>
<p>The World Bank estimates Yemen will be one of the region's fastest-growing economies this year with gross domestic product likely to grow at a rate of 6.6 percent in real terms.</p>
<p>Attar said production in Yemen's two largest oil fields, Masila and Marib, was 185,000 bpd and 175,000 bpd respectively.</p>
<p>He said production in Jannah would rise to 52,000 bpd later this year and &quot;we're certain of 70,000 next year.&quot; Output in Jannah is now 22,000 bpd.</p>
<p>Attar also said Yemen was still discussing price and financing for a contract to maintain the country's only oil refinery, in the southern port of Aden.</p>
<p>&quot;We have received three offers. We are still discussing the problem of price and particularly financing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Oil ministry official Abdullah Bisher said a decision on the tender would be made at the end of March.</p>
<p>Yemeni investors laid the cornerstone of a new 100,000 bpd refinery, the country's first private venture, at Ras Isa in Hudaidah province, 230 km (140 miles) west of Sanaa, last October.</p>
<p>The Aden refinery is more than 40 years old and sustained damage during the 1994 civil war between the north and south.</p>
<p>It was designed to handle 170,000 bpd but because of its age and configuration its runs are limited to 100,000 bpd. Attar said current throughput was 70,000-80,000 bpd.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANAA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YEMEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
