<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="457550" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: B.Midland says Lon-Brussels traffic up 4pct in '96.</title>
<headline>B.Midland says Lon-Brussels traffic up 4pct in '96.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Midland recorded four percent traffic growth last year on its London Heathrow to Brussels route, Chairman Sir Michael Bishop told a news conference on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The route Heathrow-Brussels is growing again. It's been largely unaffected by the Eurostar train,&quot; Bishop said in reference to the London-Brussels train service running through the Channel tunnel operated by Eurotunnel Plc.</p>
<p>&quot;Even before the tunnel fire, our traffic to Brussels was growing again,&quot; he said, adding that last year saw a &quot;quite satisfying&quot; four percent growth.</p>
<p>Last November's fire in one of the Channel tunnels caused a partial shutdown and reduced services.</p>
<p>Bishop said he thought the point-to-point time taken on the train was still too long to threaten air services.</p>
<p>He also played down the threat of the no-frills service offered jointly on the route by Virgin Express and Sabena Sabena, the Belgian carrier owned 49.5 percent by Swissair.</p>
<p>&quot;It's quite clear from experience so far that Virgin Express is a very different product to the one provided by British Midland and by our other competitors. The regular passengers are coming to both of us rather than going for the no-frills service,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On Virgin's market share, Bishop said: &quot;The volumes are going up but I imagine that the yields are very low.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom 32 2 287 6800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
