<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="457685" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares firmer despite profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares firmer despite profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Istanbul shares firmed in mixed trade on Thursday in positive sentiment despite profit taking which erased part of the earlier gains, brokers said.</p>
<p>The IMKB National-100 closed at 1,649, up 13 points, or 0.79 percent from Wednesday, but down from an early high of 1,659. Gains totalled 10 percent so far this week after last week's 3.88 percent rise prompted by fading political tension.</p>
<p>Trade volume firmed to 45.48 trillion lira ($363.1 million) from Wednesday's 41.5 trillion ($330.9 million).</p>
<p>&quot;The market aimed to overcome the 1,650 index level. There was some recovery following the early afternoon sales in state firms, utilities and Koc group companies,&quot; said Koray Cervatoglu from Baran securities.</p>
<p>Privatisation hopes which enlivened this week due to a Thursday meeting of the Higher Board of Privatisation had spurred demand in state firms since Monday. Lively activity in utilities and Koc group firms was also reported this morning.</p>
<p>The Board, meeting for the first time since mid-January is expected to approve 19 sell off tenders whose negotiations were finalised in December and January. Total value of the best bids in these tenders were $881.7 million.</p>
<p>Also expected to be discussed at the meeting is bluechip flat steel maker Eregli. Only two bids from local groups were received in the January tender for the block sale of a 30-40 percent state share in Eregli.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
