<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="457701" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Jardine Matheson cites problems as 1996 net falls.</title>
<headline>Jardine Matheson cites problems as 1996 net falls.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jardine Matheson Holdings Ltd said on Thursday that 1996 net profits fell to US$300.2 million and blamed a string of problems for the drop.</p>
<p>The results for the year to December 1996 compared with 1995's net profit after tax and outside interests of US$420 million.</p>
<p>The company cited various problems in 1996, including the disposal of its Sizzler restaurant chain in Australia, the repositioning of Australian and British retail operations and a US$26 million charge for regulatory breaches at Jardine Fleming Investment Management.</p>
<p>&quot;The actions we have taken to refine and strengthen our businesses should enable us to maintain a steady trading result in 1997, and we look forward to improved earnings growth coming through in subsequent years,&quot; chairman Henry Keswick said in a statement.</p>
<p>At the heart of the vast Jardine empire, Jardine Matheson holds just under 60 percent of Jardine Strategic Holdings Ltd, which in turn owns 36 percent of Jardine Matheson.</p>
<p>Jardine Strategic on Thursday unveiled 1996 attributable profits of US$301.9 million, compared to US$291.7 million in 1995.</p>
<p>Jardine Strategic, the group's listed holding company, also said it would offer shareholders a bonus issue of put warrants on a one-for-20 basis, exerciseable at US$3.80 on July 7.</p>
<p>Jardine Strategic owns 52 percent of retailer Dairy Farm International Holdings Ltd, 23 percent of motor distributor Cycle &amp; Carriage, 51 percent of hotelier Mandarin Oriental International Ltd and 32 percent of property group Hongkong Land Holdings Ltd.</p>
<p>Jardine Matheson owns 75 percent of motor distributor Jardine International Motor Holdings Ltd, 50 percent of securities arm Jardine Fleming and 100 percent of trading and services group Jardine Pacific.</p>
<p>Jardine Pacific's profit from underlying businesses came to US$94 million, down seven percent, mainly due to weaker performances by its Pizza Hut operations and to a difficult Thai market, the company said.</p>
<p>Other group companies have reported either falls in core net profits -- Dairy Farm and Jardine International Motor Holdings -- or relatively low rises -- Hongkong Land and Mandarin Oriental.</p>
<p>Earlier, there were signs that sometimes tense relations between Jardine, whose founding was tied up with Hong Kong's birth as a British colony, and China were on the mend.</p>
<p>Jardine Fleming said on Thursday it had been appointed as underwriter for a large Hong Kong listing by a Chinese company after three years of exclusion from such deals.</p>
<p>&quot;From where I sit we did have a more difficult period in our relations with China two or three years ago, but there has been a steady improvement over time,&quot; Jardine Matheson managing director Alasdair Morrison told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>But he said the group had spent &quot;a lot of time explaining our commitment to Hong Kong, our commitment to developing our business in mainland China&quot; to the Chinese government.</p>
<p>Jardine Matheson holds assets of more than US$10 billion in Hong Kong and is the largest private sector employee in the territory with 60,000 staff, he said.</p>
<p>China resumes sovereignty over Hong Kong on July 1 after more than 150 years of British rule.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
