<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="457817" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE- Northern Ireland: ballot-box tussle on loyalty.</title>
<headline>FEATURE- Northern Ireland: ballot-box tussle on loyalty.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>In Northern Ireland voters spurn the left-right politics that dominate election campaigns on the British mainland. Elections are a battleground of conflicting national loyalties.</p>
<p>Most Britons will consider the records of the ruling Conservatives and opposition Labour Party on unemployment, education, inflation and Europe before casting their vote on May 1. The skeletons of class politics still exert a powerful influence. In Northern Ireland, the Union with Britain is the issue, pure and simple. Guerrilla war, not class war, is on everyone's mind.</p>
<p>Protestants support the British link. Catholics want it broken. Politics intertwines with religion in an explosive, often bloody, mix that has defied resolution for 25 years.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not about bread and butter issues. It's about the Union,&quot; said John White, a key figure in the Ulster Democratic Party, the political arm of a banned pro-Union or Loyalist guerrilla group.</p>
<p>&quot;It's difficult to get beyond that,&quot; agrees political scientist Graham Walker.&quot;There's no shortage of people who are concerned about other issues, but getting these other issues on to the wider political agenda -- that's the problem.&quot;</p>
<p>Protestant and Catholic parties are vying for the region's 18 seats, one more than in the last election following boundary changes, in the 659-seat lower House of Commons.</p>
<p>Britain spends tens of millions of pounds (dollars) each year to keep Northern Ireland afloat but the main parties are reluctant to get enmeshed in the province's sectarian politics.</p>
<p>Labour refuses to run candidates. The Conservatives have made an occasional foray but with little impact.</p>
<p>POLITICAL COMPLEXITIES</p>
<p>Northern Ireland is dominated by parties that never hold an office of government but, with the vagaries of Britain's parliamentary voting system, can hold a government to ransom.</p>
<p>Unionists representing the Protestant majority, dominated by the Ulster Unionist Party (UUP), have 13 seats. The main Catholic Social Democratic and Labour Party (SDLP) has four.</p>
<p>The Unionists have held the key to the survival of Prime Minister John Major's government, as its majority disappeared, for the past six months.</p>
<p>For centuries, the wood-panelled chambers of parliament have been haunted by what the British dubbed &quot;the Irish Problem&quot; and the Irish pointedly called &quot;the National Question&quot;.</p>
<p>Clustered on the backbenches among English, Scottish and Welsh legislators, the latter-day successors to famous filibustering Nationalist orators and booming Unionist leaders share a distinctive &quot;Ulster&quot; accent, but little else.</p>
<p>Frozen sectarian voting patterns mean the real ballot box battle in May will be within the opposing religious factions rather than between them.</p>
<p>&quot;This general election is a significant struggle for the soul of Unionism and the soul of nationalism,&quot; said Walker who lectures at Queen's University in Belfast.</p>
<p>Protestants see parliament as a protector of their religion and British citizenship, which they say are under attack.</p>
<p>Catholic Nationalists want to use parliament to achieve peaceful constitutional change and an equality they assert was denied them by a now-defunct Protestant local assembly.</p>
<p>Catholic Republicans in Sinn Fein, the political arm of the banned Irish Republican Army, say a rare seat for them would bolster their demand for immediate entry to peace talks with Britain.</p>
<p>But even if elected, Sinn Fein will boycott the chamber, refusing to swear an oath of loyalty to the British monarch.</p>
<p>Paradoxically, Sinn Fein can field candidates in the election but are banned from multi-party talks on the political future of the province until the IRA declares another ceasefire.</p>
<p>Unionist parties, despite intense rivalry, are expected to have unofficial pacts not to split the Protestant vote in key vulnerable seats in order to fend off any nationalist challenge.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein says a nationalist alliance could scoop eight seats in a Unionist body blow redrawing the political landscape.</p>
<p>FIGHT FOR CATHOLIC VOTE</p>
<p>But the gloves are off in the battle for the Catholic vote. The SDLP declares it will make no trade-off with Sinn Fein while the IRA is bombing and shooting after breaking a ceasefire in February 1996.</p>
<p>Walker says Sinn Fein president Gerry Adams might be elected in West Belfast. &quot;Given that he is the main figurehead, it would be a propaganda coup.&quot;</p>
<p>West Belfast's SDLP incumbent, Joe Hendron, is defiant. &quot;I am obviously under some pressure, I have always have been, but I expect to be re-elected,&quot; he said. In 1992, Hendron won 43.6 percent of the vote; Adams got 42.1 percent.</p>
<p>PERCEPTION OF CONSERVATIVES, LABOUR</p>
<p>Northern Ireland's parties voice no preference but accept that Labour is tipped to form the next national government.</p>
<p>Protestants fear Labour might get too cosy with the SDLP but say with relief that party leader Tony Blair seems &quot;steady&quot; on Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>Catholics have a traditional sympathy with Labour but suspect it has watered down what they used to regard as a pro-Irish nationalist stance.</p>
<p>They have no love for Major although many feel Conservatives have a better record in breaking new ground on Northern Ireland policy.</p>
<p>Major himself brokered the latest attempt to solve the apparently insoluble Irish question in 1993.</p>
<p>Blair's plans for devolving power to Scotland could have a spin-off for a Labour government's Northern Ireland policy but not yet, according to Walker. &quot;I think his instinct with Northern Ireland would be to do nothing drastic in the short-term but, obviously, to encourage dialogue.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
