<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="457857" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Cochlear sees growth below industry.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Cochlear sees growth below industry.</headline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cochlear Ltd, the world leader in hearing implants, said on Thursday it did not expect to be able to meet forecast international annual industry growth of 15-18 percent, but to grow itself at 11-13 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The industry we believe is demonstrating a capacity to grow at 15-18 percent,&quot; managing director Catherine Livingstone told a Securities Institute of Australia briefing here.</p>
<p>&quot;The global competition is helping to grow the market but the competition is becoming more aggressive so Cochlear's growth is less than that, about 11-13 percent,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>Livingstone said the company was very excited about the performance and potential of its new product, Nucleus 24, currently in field trials in Europe and Australia.</p>
<p>Expected to be cleared by the United States Food and Drug Administration (FDA) in mid-1988, the product would help Cochlear maintain its competitive edge, she said.</p>
<p>A further innovation was the development of an ear level processor for the implant, advancing on the traditional body-worn unit, which would appeal to people with severe hearing impairments once accustomed to wearing hearing aids, she said.  </p>
<p>Livingstone said Cochlear's main competitors did not have such a device, but were expected to match it within a year. &quot;We are going through very much a transitional period, this half, introducing the Nucleus 24 system....&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;It certainly sets us up for growth once we get through the (launch) program, but the program itself a major undertaking by the company,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Cochlear, which currently has 70-75 percent of the world hearing implant market, is facing growing competition from Advance Bionics in the United States, estimated to have 15 percent of the market and Med-El in Austria with 10 percent  </p>
<p>share.</p>
<p>The Sydney-based company reported an 11.8 percent fall in net profit to A$4.52 million for the first half of 1996/97, attributable to foreign exchange losses and the impact of the cut in research and development tax concessions.</p>
<p>It has forecast a flat year, with full year earnings in the range of A$10.5 to A$10.9 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The extent to which we will achieve that will depend on our growth (in system sales),&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Cochlear shares closed one cent lower at A$3.78.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
