<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="457923" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai T-bill repo ends down, spots mixed.</title>
<headline>Shanghai T-bill repo ends down, spots mixed.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Contracts on the treasury bill repurchase market in Shanghai closed mostly down on Thursday mainly due to a plunge in the domestic A share market, traders said.</p>
<p>The annual rate for the most active seven-day contract fell to 14.01 percent from 16.20 percent on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Total turnover of the six-contract market rose sharply to 12.05 million lots from 3.99 million on Wednesday. One lot is 1,000 yuan face value of treasury bills.</p>
<p>Traders said the sharp falls in the domestic A shares prevented the repo rates from rising.  </p>
<p>But the day's two new A share issues, Zhejiang Zhen Yuan and Ningbo Hai Yun on the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock exchanges, increased fund demand on the repo market and pushed turnover up sharply, local traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The rates will continue to fall on Friday and rebound early next week on the new A share issues,&quot; a second trader said.</p>
<p>There will be two more A share issues early next week.</p>
<p>Contracts on the T-bill spot market in Shanghai ended mixed on Thursday on consolidation, traders said.  </p>
<p>The most active three-year bond that will mature in August 1999 rose to 105.15 yuan from 104.94 yuan, on turnover of 426 million yuan compared with 483 million yuan on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Combined volume of the nine-contract market rose to 1.13 million lots from 1.05 million lots on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Traders said the market would continue to consolidate at current levels because the active A share markets attracted funds from the spot market and prevented spots from rising greatly.</p>
<p>But the spots would rise in the long term with China's domestic inflation rates falling, traders said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
