<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45790" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks end higher, eye of U.S. data.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks end higher, eye of U.S. data.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toronto stocks finished higher on Wednesday, rising along with Wall Street ahead of key U.S. economic data due out later this week.</p>
<p>The TSE 300 Composite Index rose 13.29 points to close at 5160.41 in turnover of 96.98 million shares valued at C$1.17 billion ($853 million).</p>
<p>Advancing stocks outnumbered declines 479 to 394 with 302 issues ending flat.</p>
<p>Ira Katzin, an investment adviser with Richardson Greenshields of Canada Ltd., said investors are concerned that signs of a slowing U.S. economy will mean weaker corporate earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;But offsetting that is the feeling that if the U.S. economy is slowing down, then interest rates will ease off a little bit,&quot; Katzin said.</p>
<p>He added the picture will become clearer with U.S. consumer and producer price data due on Thursday and Friday.</p>
<p>Toronto's 14 sub-groups were evenly split. The energy group led the strong side, adding 53 points after oil prices rallied on news that Iraq fired missiles at U.S. jets today.</p>
<p>October Brent closed up US$0.70 at US$23.59 per barrel after earlier reaching post-Gulf War highs.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Gulf Canada Resources Ltd. closed up 0.45 at 8.90, a new 52-week high. Takeovers also pushed several oil stocks higher.</p>
<p>Morgan Hydrocarbons Inc. added 0.25 to 4.35 after the company said it has received unsolicited expressions of interest.</p>
<p>Gardiner Oil &amp; Gas Ltd. jumped 2.20 to 11.70 after the company agreed ot a friendly takeover bid from Poco Petroleums Ltd. late Tuesday.</p>
<p>* Fairfax Financial Holdings Ltd. continued its recent climb after a major acquisition. Fairfax soared 13 to 250, a new high.</p>
<p>* In the loss column, Molson Cos Ltd. class A fell 0.30 to 20.20 after brewer said it is not considering a share buyback despite shareholder pressure.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
