<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="457990" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan pork export ban seen slashing corn imports.</title>
<headline>Taiwan pork export ban seen slashing corn imports.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan grain buyers estimated on Thursday that a disease-linked ban on pork exports would cause the island's imports of feed corn to fall by about one-fifth.</p>
<p>&quot;Corn imports will drop significantly,&quot; one buyer said.  </p>
<p>A survey of five major Taiwan grain importers found that all expected significant reductions in corn imports, with most estimating the downturn at about 1.2 million tonnes or 19 percent of the island's annual imports of 6.5 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Taiwan has been importing almost all of its corn from the United States, although recent high U.S. prices have prompted some importers to look to alterative sources in South America, particularly Argentina.  </p>
<p>The cabinet-level Council of Agriculture announced on Thursday that it was banning all exports of fresh and frozen pork temporarily due to an outbreak of the deadly and highly contagious foot and mouth disease among pigs in nine counties.</p>
<p>Japan, which is Taiwan's largest pork export market, has strict rules against importation of pork from regions known to be affected by the disease and was expected to impose its own ban on shipments from Taiwan, experts said.</p>
<p>Japan has been importing 16,000 tonnes of fresh and frozen pork from Taiwan a month despite imposition of an &quot;emergency&quot; import tariff to limit imports and protect local breeders.  </p>
<p>Taiwan's pork exports to Japan alone comprise about 69 percent of the island's total pork exports.</p>
<p>The Taiwan council estimated that Taiwan breeds 14 million hogs per year. According to a 1994 survey, the industry was worth T$89 billion (US$3.24 billion), or about 20 percent of Taiwan's farm market and 60 percent of the livestock sector.</p>
<p>Taiwan's pork industry employs 700,000 people, including 100,000 pig farmers, the council said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42210">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
