<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="457975" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: LME copper to test US$2,380, Chinese demand strong.</title>
<headline>LME copper to test US$2,380, Chinese demand strong.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three-month copper prices on the London Metal Exchange (LME) will probably test resistance at US$2,380 a tonne, largely on the back of strong Chinese interest, traders said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We expected three-month copper prices to stay in a range between $2,320 and $2,380 a tonne. Therefore, the next move is to go up and test the resistance level,&quot; a trader with a local brokerage firm said.</p>
<p>The trader said the strong bounce by copper from $2,300 a tonne late on Wednesday showed Chinese demand was still alive and constructive.  </p>
<p>However, zinc prices were seen falling on technical factors as the trade pulled back from an overbought situation, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market needs some kind of adjustment period in order to gather energy for a further climb,&quot; said another local broker.</p>
<p>Brokers said they also expected prices to decline because the gap between $1,254 and $1,262 a tonne needed to be filled.</p>
<p>Zinc climbed to a 4-1/2 year high earlier in the week at more than $1,300 a tonne before sliding back to its current level. It closed on Wednesday at $1,296 a tonne.  </p>
<p>A futures broker said the zinc market was heavily overbought with the 14-day relative strength index (RSI) for three-month zinc standing at 74.80 percent.</p>
<p>The market generally considers an RSI of 70 or more as overbought and 30 or less as oversold.</p>
<p>LME three-month aluminium was nearly unchanged in quiet Asian trade on Thursday from the previous day's London trade at $1,647/$1,651 a tonne.</p>
<p>-- Jae Hur, Seoul Newsroom (822) 727 5651</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
