<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="457931" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan noncommittal on China's hijacker pledge.</title>
<headline>Taiwan noncommittal on China's hijacker pledge.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan welcomed rival China's offer on Thursday to repatriate a Taiwan hijacker, but said it needed formal notice from Beijing before the matter could be handled further.</p>
<p>Jonathan Liu, a director of the cabinet's Mainland Affairs Council, flatly declined to make any commitment with respect to Beijing's demand that Taipei return 16 mainland hijackers, most of whom are serving prison terms in Taiwan.  </p>
<p>&quot;This will be positive for our future talks on hijacker repatriation,&quot; Liu said, referring to semi-official talks with Beijing stalled since mid-1995. &quot;But we will not act until we receive formal notice from the Association for Relations Across the Taiwan Strait.&quot;</p>
<p>The association is Beijing's semi-official body for handling contacts with Taiwan, which Beijing has regarded as a renegade province since a civil war split them in 1949.</p>
<p>After the hijacking of a Taiwan commercial jet to the mainland city of Xiamen on March 10, Taiwan publicly offered to repatriate two mainland hijackers who had served out their prison terms, asking that Beijing return the Taiwan hijacker.</p>
<p>China's official Xinhua news agency announced on Thursday that Beijing planned to send back the Taiwan man, Liu Shan-chung, after further investigation, but demanded that Taiwan return all 16 mainland hijackers in exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
