<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45800" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian CEOs say economy poised for growth.</title>
<headline>Canadian CEOs say economy poised for growth.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of Canada's leading chief executives said on Wednesday that the Canadian economy was poised for growth in jobs and incomes into 1997, but that more needed to be done to ensure sustained economic growth and a higher standard of living.</p>
<p>At a roundtable discussion, members of the Business Council on National Issues said record investment by the Canadian private sector, combined with improving government finances, had dramatically reduced inflation and interest rates.  </p>
<p>The council's policy committee said Canada's export sector was the big winner so far, with gains in auto and other transportation equipment, high-technology products, metal and minerals and various services. It said that while 1997 might see slowing growth in the United States, Canadian exporters should benefit from faster growth in other markets.</p>
<p>Economic growth at home, which had been lackluster, was building momentum on the strength of private-sector job creation, with about 200,000 new jobs this year and more than one million since 1992, the council said.  </p>
<p>It said expansion and investment in the export sector, rising tourism and the sharp plunge in interest rates should lead to faster economic growth and job creation over the next year and to a strong current account performance.</p>
<p>The chief executives agreed that more needed to be done if Canadians wanted to foster reliable and sustained economic growth, robust creation of jobs and a steadily increasing standard of living for all Canadians.</p>
<p>They called for cooperation in public debt reduction, an end to deficit financing and a commitment to modernize and simplify taxes.  </p>
<p>&quot;We, like many other Canadians, are appalled by the lack of opportunites and financial burdens facing young people today,&quot; said council chairman Guy Saint-Pierre. &quot;Governments must start investing in our children's future instead of borrowing from it.&quot;</p>
<p>The council said Canada's governments must restore faith in the Canada Pension Plan through sweeping reforms of the public retirement fund, including higher contribution rates, tighter eligibility for disability benefits, more efficient administration and an increase in the retirement age.</p>
<p>The group also called for a simplification of government regulation, progressive environmental policies and a renewal of the Canadian federation against the uncertainty of Quebec sovereignty.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau  (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
