<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="458178" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Clinton, Yeltsin seek big thaw in snowy Finland.</title>
<headline>Clinton, Yeltsin seek big thaw in snowy Finland.</headline>
<byline>Simon Haydon</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton and Kremlin leader Boris Yeltsin arrive in snowy Finland on Thursday for a summit that has run into trouble before it starts over NATO's plans to expand into Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>Clinton, temporarily confined to a wheelchair after a freak accident last week, arrives first, followed shortly afterwards by the Russian president who is back to his jaunty self after severe heart problems late last year.</p>
<p>The two men, who have not seen each other for 11 months, will talk first in the evening over dinner with Finnish President Martti Ahtisaari and then hold full talks on Friday.</p>
<p>Washington and Moscow have enjoyed increasingly warm relations since the end of the Cold War but a chilly tone has crept into preparations for the Helsinki summit as the two nations argue about NATO.</p>
<p>Kremlin spokesman Sergei Yastrzhembsky told reporters NATO plans to bring Moscow's former satellites into the military alliance would be the biggest mistake it made in the eight years since the Cold War ended.</p>
<p>&quot;President Yeltsin and the Russian leadership are convinced that NATO's plans to expand to the east, if realised, could be the West's biggest strategic mistake since the end of the Cold War,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Despite the tough eve-of-summit rhetoric from both sides, Russian and American officials were leaving enough room for compromise, at least in other areas.</p>
<p>NATO enlargement tops the summit agenda, but Moscow and Washington also plan to discuss arms control and Russia's troubled transition to a market economy.</p>
<p>&quot;I think, much as I would like to be wrong, that we have been robbed to a certain extent of the most valuable achievement of the period since the Cold War -- trust,&quot; Yastrzhembsky said.</p>
<p>&quot;The very discussion of NATO expansion eastwards has already cast a shadow to a certain extent over relations between the West and Russia, the U.S. and Russia.&quot;</p>
<p>Before leaving Washington, Clinton said NATO enlargement was a top priority and that he wanted a robust partnership with Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;We are adapting NATO to take on new missions, enlarging NATO to take in new members, strengthening NATO's partnership with non-members and seeking to build a robust partnership between NATO and Russia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Russian and U.S. officials say possible progress on arms control and economic issues could salvage the summit if NATO becomes an insurmountable obstacle.</p>
<p>There is likely to be more Western help on offer to support Russia as it tackles organised crime and economic reforms.</p>
<p>Clinton expressed optimism about Yeltsin's latest government changes.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm encouraged by the new economic theme President Yeltsin announced this week. It underscores Russia's commitment to continued reform,&quot; said Clinton.</p>
<p>Yeltsin has shaken up his cabinet in a move clearly aimed at re-establishing his authority after his long illness and bringing market-oriented economic reformers into senior positions.</p>
<p>&quot;Now the challenge is to create a climate that actually attracts more investment and promotes more trade so that Russia will have real economic growth,&quot; said Clinton.</p>
<p>He and Yeltsin would &quot;discuss the steps that both of us will take to create that climate&quot;.</p>
<p>Clinton met senior advisers to study the implications of the Kremlin changes before making his remarks to reporters at the White House.</p>
<p>The wheelchair-bound U.S. leader, who underwent knee surgery last Friday after suffering a torn tendon when he stumbled on some stairs, arrived at Andrews Air Force Base in a specially equipped white van.</p>
<p>Clinton, preceded by his doctor carrying a set of crutches, was rolled on to a platform elevator and lifted aboard Air Force One for the overnight flight to Helsinki.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
