<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="458217" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Protests mark start of German steel merger talks.</title>
<headline>Protests mark start of German steel merger talks.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of steel workers at Germany's two largest steel groups continued protests on Thursday ahead of talks between Krupp and Thyssen about a landmark steel merger.</p>
<p>The talks, due to begin later in the day, were unexpected after Fried. Krupp AG Hoesch-Krupp launched a surprise hostile takeover bid for its larger rival Thyssen AG, sparking protest from workers, the press and politicians.</p>
<p>Thyssen, in order to avert an all-out takeover, has agreed to begin talks with Krupp about merging their steel units Thyssen Stahl AG and Krupp Hoesch Stahl AG.</p>
<p>Krupp rocked the consensual-style relationship between Germany's corporate, financial and political elite this week with its surprise offer to pay 435 marks, a 25 percent premium, for Thyssen shares in a rare hostile takeover.</p>
<p>Shares in both companies were suspended from trade on Tuesday and Wednesday but restarted on the IBIS electronic trading system on Thursday. Thyssen shares climbed to 390.50 marks compared to their March 17 IBIS close of 344.50, while Krupp stock was at 306 marks against 270 marks.</p>
<p>Fearing massive job losses in the wake of a merger, steel workers, trade unions and some politicians fiercely attacked Krupp's advances and vowed to continue to protest job cuts.</p>
<p>Walter Riester, deputy president of IG Metall metal workers union, sharply attacked Krupp and Deutsche Bank for attempting a hostile takeover.</p>
<p>&quot;With these Wild West methods they are trying to establish conditions that are common in America. But that is a different economic and social system,&quot; Riester said.</p>
<p>Steel production at Krupp was halted by worker protests ahead of an employee meeting in Dortmund at which management will inform workers about a possible steel merger with Thyssen AG, a works council spokesman said.</p>
<p>Plant operations had been run down to emergency levels as workers prepared for a march to the meeting, which several thousand of them are expected to attend.</p>
<p>Meanwhile production at Thyssen's Duisburg steelworks was also hit as about 1,000 Thyssen workers downed tools to attend the Krupp meeting in a show of solidarity with Krupp workers, works council officials said.</p>
<p>Workers at Krupp and Thyssen have staged stoppages for the past three days.</p>
<p>The meeting of Krupp and Thyssen officials for merger talks is the result of political brokering by the government of North Rhine-Westphalia state.</p>
<p>The Social Democratic (SPD) state premiere Johannes Rau and his economics minister Wolfgang Clement were surprised by the takeover bid and, fearing greater job losses in a region already hit by high unemployment, sought to limit the damage.</p>
<p>North Rhine-Westphalia finance minister Heinz Schleusser ehoed union protests and criticised banks for their involvement in the hostile takeover attempt.</p>
<p>&quot;It is certainly alienating that bank representatives sit on the supervisory board of Thyssen on the one hand, and on the other hand are working on strategies that are directed against the company,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hans-Olaf Henkel, president of the Federation of German Industry (BDI), dismissed what he called the &quot;partially hysterical&quot; attacks on Krupp.</p>
<p>&quot;Mergers are normal,&quot; said Henkel. &quot;We have to get used to takeovers; they could make sense.&quot;</p>
<p>Welcoming the talks between Krupp and Thyssen, he said the merger of the steel activities of the two companies could have broader implications for German industry.</p>
<p>&quot;This will lead to a greater competitiveness of the German steel industry,&quot; said Henkel, adding that the concentration of the steel industry in other countries such as France and Britain led to considerable cost advantages.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, 49 228 26097 150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
