<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="458320" id="root" date="1997-03-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia searches for missing Busang geologist.</title>
<headline>Indonesia searches for missing Busang geologist.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian rescuers resumed searching on Thursday for Filipino geologist Michael de Guzman, who fell out of a helicopter on his way to the huge Busang gold property in East Kalimantan that he helped discover.</p>
<p>Search And Rescue (SAR) officials said de Guzman, chief geologist for Calgary-based Bre-X Minerals Ltd, fell from about 800 feet (240 metres) on Wednesday morning after the back door of the Alouette 3 helicopter burst open.</p>
<p>The Busang motherlode, estimated by Bre-X to contain at least 80 million ounces of gold currently worth around $25 billion, is the biggest gold find this century.</p>
<p>&quot;The search operations resumed this morning after being halted at sunset yesterday,&quot; a SAR official based in Samarinda, capital of East Kalimantan, told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>A senior executive of the public relations company that represents the joint venture company set up to develop the Busang property said de Guzman was presumed dead.</p>
<p>The SAR official said the helicopter had been chartered by Bre-X from PT Indonesia Air Transport and was piloted by Captain Eddy Tursono, who was accompanied by an engineer.</p>
<p>&quot;The helicopter was chartered by Bre-X and had flown from Balikpapan to Samarinda, where it stopped to refuel. It then took off for Busang with all three on board,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the helicopter was about 25 nautical miles from Samarinda when the back door flung open.</p>
<p>&quot;The pilot looked back and de Guzman was missing,&quot; he said. &quot;The pilot then circled the area for about 20 minutes but could not find de Guzman. The pilot was then ordered by the Samarinda airport authority to return.&quot;</p>
<p>The official said the local military command in East Kalimantan was conducting searches on the ground, which he described as swampy.</p>
<p>Bre-X chief executive David Walsh told Reuters from Calgary: &quot;It's very tragic and he will be remembered as a fine geologist.&quot;</p>
<p>Bre-X reached an agreement with Indonesian partners and the U.S. mining giant Freeport McMoRan Copper and Gold Inc to develop Busang.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
