<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="458358" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-SCOTLAND COACH BROWN STANDS BY HIS MEN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SCOTLAND COACH BROWN STANDS BY HIS MEN.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Scotland manager Craig Brown named a virtually unchanged squad on Friday for his side's home World Cup qualifying matches against Estonia and Austria.</p>
<p>Rangers goalkeeper Andy Goram is sidelined through injury and Celtic defender Jackie McNamara is dropped despite starting Scotland's last two matches.</p>
<p>Otherwise Brown has remained loyal to the players he bitterly criticised after their 0-0 draw with Estonia in Monaco last month.</p>
<p>Scotland face Estonia in Kilmarnock on March 29, three days before they play Austria at Celtic Park.</p>
<p>Their last match against Estonia, played in Monaco, was a replay of their now infamous match in Tallinn last October which was abandoned after three seconds.</p>
<p>Estonia refused to take the field after the kick-off time was brought forward following Scottish complaints about floodlighting.</p>
<p>Scotland head European qualifying group four with eight points from four matches. Austria and Estonia have both played a game fewer and have seven and four points respectively.</p>
<p>Squad for both matches:</p>
<p>Goalkeepers - Neil Sullivan (Wimbledon), Jim Leighton (Hibernian), Scott Howie (Motherwell)</p>
<p>Defenders - Colin Calderwood (Tottenham Hotspur), John Collins (Monaco), Colin Hendry (Blackburn), Brian McAllister (Wimbledon), Alan McLaren (Rangers), Tommy Boyd (Celtic), Tosh McKinlay (Celtic)</p>
<p>Midfielders - Craig Burley (Chelsea), Billy McKinlay (Blackburn), Scott Gemmill (Nottingham Forest), Gary McAllister (Coventry), Paul McStay (Celtic), Ian Ferguson (Rangers), Paul Lambert (Borussia Dortmund)</p>
<p>Forwards - Kevin Gallacher (Blackburn), Duncan Ferguson (Everton), John McGinlay (Bolton), John Spencer (Queens Park Rangers), Eoin Jess (Coventry), Ally McCoist (Rangers), Darren Jackson (Hibernian)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
