<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="458600" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian actor Graham Greene in brush with police.</title>
<headline>Canadian actor Graham Greene in brush with police.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian actor Graham Greene, an Oscar nominee for his role in &quot;Dances With Wolves&quot;, was in a hospital on Friday after a standoff with police in which he threatened to kill himself, authorities said.</p>
<p>Police said no charges would be laid against Greene since no weapons were involved in the incident on Thursday, which ended peacefully after the actor agreed to a psychiatric assessment.</p>
<p>&quot;The police conversed with (Greene) over several hours at which time the matter was resolved without incident,&quot; York Regional Police Sgt. John Sheldon said in a phone interview. &quot;(He) was taken to York County Hospital where he was admitted for psychiatric assessment.&quot;</p>
<p>Sheldon said Greene had been &quot;despondent over matters involving family and friends.&quot;</p>
<p>Police surrounded Greene's house in Georgina, a town about 65 km (40 miles) north of Toronto, after reports that the actor had guns in the house and was suicidal.</p>
<p>Greene was alone in the house during the standoff.</p>
<p>His agent, Celia Chassels, declined to comment on the incident.</p>
<p>The actor, best-known for portraying native North Americans in films, television and on stage, was nominated for a best supporting actor Academy Award for the 1990 film &quot;Dances With Wolves,&quot; which won the Oscar for best picture.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
