<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="458758" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: EU warns Slovakia on free trade pact with Russia.</title>
<headline>EU warns Slovakia on free trade pact with Russia.</headline>
<byline>Jan Krcmar</byline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union on Friday warned Slovakia against concluding a free trade agreement with Russia, saying the deal could jeopardize its future EU memberhip.</p>
<p>External Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan told Slovak industrialists such an agreeement would have a negative effect both on Bratislava's relations with the EU and neighbouring Czech Republic.</p>
<p>&quot;...if Slovakia wishes to pursue the plan for a Free Trade Agreement (FTA) with the Russian Federation...it should do so with a view...on the disruptive effects it could have on the smooth adoption by Slovakia of the EU's Common Commercial Policy when, and if, it joins the Union,&quot; Brittan said.</p>
<p>&quot;Indeed, since the EU does not at present have an FTA with Russia itself, Slovakia would have to renounce any such agreement if it was to join the EU,&quot; Brittan added.</p>
<p>Slovakia, currently an associate EU member, applied for full EU membership in the summer of 1995.</p>
<p>Slovak Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar has spoken out several times in favour of an FTA with Russia. An FTA has also been the subject of bilateral discussions between Slovak and Russian trade officials.</p>
<p>Brittan said that in his talks with Meciar earlier in the day, the Slovak Prime MInister had assured him that an FTA with Russia was not topical, but that if it became so Slovakia would consult first with the EU.</p>
<p>Brittan said the EU and Russia were both pushing for Russia's membership in the World Trade Organisation (WTO) which would enable Slovakia and Moscow to regulate their trade relationship in a way fully compatible with WTO obligations and conform more easily with the EU common commercial policy.</p>
<p>&quot;I would strongly urge Slovakia to endorse this approach and not proceed with any plans for for a Slovak-Russian FTA until Russian membership in the WTO has been secured,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Brittan praised Slovakia's economic performance, which he called &quot;impressive&quot;, but reiterated concerns by the EU, the United States and other western institutions over Slovakia's foot-dragging on the path towards full democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;The impression does persist that the democratic institutions of Slovakia still have the scope to become more mature and fully developed,&quot; Brittan said.</p>
<p>&quot;I would strongly urge that the non-economic criteria for EU membership are taken very seriously by all those who are interested in Slovakia's European vocation,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
