<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45885" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Agreement reached on Commonwealth visit to Nigeria.</title>
<headline>Agreement reached on Commonwealth visit to Nigeria.</headline>
<dateline>ABUJA 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Commonwealth delegation said on Wednesday it has reached broad agreement with Nigeria's military government on sending a ministerial team to the African state.</p>
<p>&quot;The framework and modalities for a CMAG (Commonwealth Ministerial Action Group) visit to Nigeria have been discussed and general agreement reached. We are optimistic the CMAG visit will take place,&quot; a statement from the four-man delegation in the Nigerian capital said.  </p>
<p>The team, led by deputy secretary general K. Srinavasan was sent to Nigeria after Commonwealth ministers turned down a previous invitation when Abuja imposed strict conditions on who it would have been allowed to meet.</p>
<p>&quot;Dates have been proposed by the Nigerian authorities for the visit, naturally this will require consultations amongst CMAG members' ministers, which will begin after the Commonwealth delegation returns to London,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Nigeria has repeatedly said the only question for discussion is Nigeria's suspension from the 53-member organisation of Britain and its former colonies. But Commonwealth ministers, concerned about human rights, want broader talks, focussing on the military's plans to return civilian rule and numerous political detainees.</p>
<p>Nigeria was suspended from the Commonwealth in November after the hanging of author Ken Saro-Wiwa and eight other minority rights activists for murder in spite of international appeals for clemency.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COMWH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABUJA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
