<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="458907" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Poll shows eccentric Bogota mayor highly popular.</title>
<headline>Poll shows eccentric Bogota mayor highly popular.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bogota Mayor Antanas Mockus, a quirky &quot;anti-politician&quot; who said he was stepping down this week to run for the presidency, got a lift from the first public opinion poll published since his announcement.</p>
<p>The snap poll in Friday's editions of El Espectador newspaper was conducted by the National Consultancy Centre on Thursday. It showed that Mockus was the second most popular public figure in the capital behind Prosecutor-General Alfonso Valdivieso.</p>
<p>The telephone survey was based on interviews with 600 Bogota residents and it is less clear what sort of grass-roots support Mockus might be able to muster in the countryside. It showed that he enjoys a 73 percent approval rating among Bogotanos and only Valdivieso would garner more votes in the capital if presidential elections were held today.</p>
<p>Valdivieso, a respected anti-drug crusader, has been mulling a possible presidential candidacy for months. His apparent indecision has been widely criticised and prompted some pundits to brand him the &quot;Hamlet of the Andes.&quot;</p>
<p>Interior Minister Horacio Serpa, President Ernesto Samper's right-hand man, is widely expected to announce his candidacy for the presidency but the poll showed Mockus easily defeating the firebrand populist, 49 percent to 31 percent.</p>
<p>Mockus, the son of Lithuanian immigrants and a former university rector, is a self-described &quot;neo-anarchist&quot; and &quot;anti-politician&quot; with a passion for mathematics and metaphysics. He is known for public antics that have included baring his backside in public, using mimes as traffic cops and getting married in the tiger cage of a local circus.</p>
<p>Political analysts have attributed his popularity in the past to a growing sense of disgust with politics as usual fuelled at least in part by the prolonged political crisis stemming from charges that Samper's 1994 election campaign was partly bankrolled by drug traffickers.</p>
<p>Analysts say the &quot;Mockus Phenomenon&quot; also reflects a need for deep-rooted change in a country torn by drugs and political violence where two traditional parties, Samper's Liberals and the opposition Conservatives, have jealously guarded their power since a 1948-57 civil war that left 300,000 people dead.</p>
<p>Mockus, who has no political affiliation or party, announced on Wednesday that he will step down from the mayor's office within two weeks to launch his presidential campaign.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
