<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="458908" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuela PDVSA post-tax profits up 40 pct in 96.</title>
<headline>Venezuela PDVSA post-tax profits up 40 pct in 96.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Venezuelan state-owned oil giant Petroleos de Venezuela (PDVSA) saw its post-tax profits jump 40 percent in 1996 to $4.495 billion on a seven percent output capacity rise to 3.416 million barrels per day (bpd), the company said in a statement Friday.</p>
<p>PDVSA said the record results reflected a drive to cut costs and increase efficiency, and higher world oil prices which rose by about 20 percent in the year.  </p>
<p>Oil output capacity hit a 25-year record due to PDVSA's efforts to compensate for a natural 23 percent per year decline in field production, the statement said.</p>
<p>Net revenues rose 38 percent to $15.047 billion.</p>
<p>Heavy investment in oil exploration yielded a nine percent rise in proven oil reserves to 72.574 billion barrels. Gas reserves stood at 143 billion cubic feet.</p>
<p>PDVSA said investments in profit-sharing oil exploration contracts, involving private capital, began in 1996 and are expected to reach $1 billion.</p>
<p>Investment in oilfields operated by private companies was $956 million in 1996, and output from these fields reached 190,000 bpd by the end of the year.</p>
<p>PDVSA refined an average of 2.095 million bpd of oil in 1996, of which 1.205 million was in Venezuela (including the Isla Curacao refinery), 632,000 bpd was in the United States and 258,000 bpd in Europe.</p>
<p>The company sold a total of 2.752 million bpd of oil on international markets, 215,000 bpd above 1995. Of this, light and medium crude accounted for 1.207 million bpd, up nine percent, while heavy and extra-heavy crude totalled 770,000 bpd.</p>
<p>Venezuelan crude oil sales totalled 1.977 million bpd, of which 1.110 million bpd went to international customers, 693,000 bpd to PDVSA overseas affiliates and 174,000 bpd to the Isla Curacao refinery.</p>
<p>PDVSA said it sold 775,000 bpd of refined products, 57,000 bpd above 1995.</p>
<p>The United States bought 60 percent of Venezuelan crude and products sales in 1996, totalling 1.613 million bpd. Exports to the rest of the Americas rose by 35 percent to 816,000 bpd.</p>
<p>Total domestic hydrocarbon sales totalled 650,000 bpd, one percent below 1995, but domestic liquid product sales fell six percent to 354,000 bpd.</p>
<p>((-- Tom Ashby, Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
