<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="458999" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Fifty Buenos Aires province cops fired.</title>
<headline>Fifty Buenos Aires province cops fired.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some 50 police officers from Buenos Aires province were fired on Thursday, a week after Gov. Eduardo Duhalde put the entire force on notice they could be fired due to charges of corruption and brutality.</p>
<p>The private DyN news agency quoted the province's Security Secretariat as saying all 50 agents, including four precinct chiefs and two deputy chiefs, had legal proceedings against them.</p>
<p>Last week, Buenos Aires Gov. Eduardo Duhalde, a 1999 presidential hopeful, summoned 1,000 top officers for a dressing-down and a warning that he was putting all 48,000 agents in the force that he was putting them on &quot;dispensable&quot; status, meaning they could be fired.</p>
<p>His threat followed a series of probes showing massive corruption in the provincial force and opinion polls revealing widespread popular fear of the police -- a scenario which analysts say could thwart Duhalde's presidential ambitions.</p>
<p>Officers have been caught trafficking drugs, four have been indicted for involvement in a 1994 bomb attack on a Jewish centre that killed 86 people and there has been case after case of police brutality ranging from beatings to youngsters killed by trigger-happy officers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
