<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="459058" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Small banks taking on more credit risk - regulator.</title>
<headline>Small banks taking on more credit risk - regulator.</headline>
<dateline>PHOENIX 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Small banks are taking more risks in lending, in part due to weaker lending standards, the Comptroller of the Currency's office discovered in a survey of 2,300 national community banks.</p>
<p>At the end of 1996, 18 percent of small banks had increased their credit risks the survey said based on information collected by bank examiners.</p>
<p>But only three percent of banks were classified as having overall &quot;high levels&quot; of credit risk. Credit risk is a measure of the possibility that a bank's borrowers could default on their loans.  </p>
<p>The results caught the attention of Comptroller Eugene Ludwig, who plans to issue a warning on the matter to community banks in a speech on Saturday at the annual meeting of the Independent Bankers Association of America.</p>
<p>While some of the increased credit risk has come from healthy sources such as greater loan demand in an expanding economy, Ludwig said he is concerned that some of the risk has come from lax underwriting standards.  </p>
<p>&quot;At least some of this growth in credit risk is a result of a weakening in underwriting standards, where banks feel pressured to continue booking loans in an increasingly competitive environment,&quot; Ludwig said in a prepared text of the Saturday speech.</p>
<p>&quot;Now is not the time for any bank to cut corners on its underwriting standards or its internal controls,&quot; Ludwig said. &quot;Now is the time, however, to make sure you have the necessary controls in place to recognize credit problems early and take appropriate action to manage these problems.&quot;  </p>
<p>Last week, the comptroller's office issued an advisory to banks on recommended loan underwriting standards and portfolio credit risk managment.</p>
<p>The OCC's small bank survey also found that just two percent of banks had a high level of interest rate risk, a measurement of possible losses from unexpected interest rate movements. That risk was seen increasing at another two percent of banks.</p>
<p>((-- Aaron Pressman 202 898-8312))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHOENIX"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
