<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="459311" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian government to set cigarette prices.</title>
<headline>Indonesian government to set cigarette prices.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's finance minister has issued a new regulation authorising the customs and excise department to set retail prices of cigarettes from April 1.</p>
<p>The ruling, a copy of which was obtained by Reuters on Friday, states that cigarette producers and importers can now only propose the retail prices for their products.</p>
<p>Analysts said the aims of the regulation seemed unclear, adding that it lacked detail and that they needed time to study the ruling.</p>
<p>Cigarette firms listed on the Jakarta Stock Exchange were affected by the news.</p>
<p>Hanjaya Mandala Sampoerna was down 350 rupiah to 11,000 rupiah on a volume of 295,000 shares in early afternoon trading on Friday, while Gudang Garam was down 275 rupiah to 10,075 rupiah with 431,000 shares traded.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know what impact this ruling will have on retail prices and on the bottom lines of cigarette companies,&quot; one analyst with Singapore-based firm said. &quot;But my initial feeling is that the move will have some impact on earnings.&quot;</p>
<p>The ruling also states companies producing cigarettes have to allocate at least 10 percent of their profit from the retail price to distributors and traders, but gave no details.  </p>
<p>It said, however, cigarette firms should include the 10 percent when calculating their proposed retail prices.</p>
<p>The ruling also states that when retail prices exceed by 10 percent the price stated on the government sticker attached to cigarette packs, cigarette companies have to include this factor in their proposed retail prices.</p>
<p>It said the retail prices proposed by cigarette companies for their products could not be lower than prevailing prices.</p>
<p>The ruling, however, did not change the excise duty structure on tobacco products, which is based on retail prices.</p>
<p>It also said that the government would classify cigarette companies in accordance to their annual output level and whether they used machines or other means to make cigarettes.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
