<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45945" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: FOCUS - Lek lifts languishing Ljubljana bourse.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Lek lifts languishing Ljubljana bourse.</headline>
<byline>Marja Novak</byline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Newly-listed shares of drugmaker Lek gave a much-needed boost to Ljubljana's flagging bourse on Wednesday, lifting it from a record low amid hopes the issue may help lure more foreign money to Slovenia.</p>
<p>The two percent gain in the leading SBI index halted a 5.2 percent tailspin earlier in the week when investors were panicked by rumours of trouble at market heavyweight Dadas.</p>
<p>&quot;As expected Lek's shares rose immediatelly after trading started and pulled the whole market up,&quot; said Mateja Gubanec, a trader at &quot;A&quot; bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Lek could lure more foreign investors to the market than any other company on the Ljubljana bourse so far,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Ljubljana-based Lek, one of Slovenia's top-10 companies, controls more than a quarter of the country's drug market, while more than 70 percent of its production is exported.</p>
<p>Some market participants, however, voiced doubts that Lek's sparkling performance alone could manage to pull the Ljubljana bourse out of its months-long depression.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a good time for new shares to be listed. The market is very depressed because of a series of shocks that have hit it since February and that may push the new shares down as well,&quot; said Karmen Cerar, a trader at brokerage Poteza.</p>
<p>The bourse's blues began in February when Slovenia's Payment Agency said listed publisher Mladinska Knjiga Zalozba and pharmaceutical trader Salus should significantly increase the state's stake in their shareholder structure, claiming irregularities during the firms' 1990 and 1991 privatisations.</p>
<p>Just one month later, the Securities Market Agency started procedures to ban brokerage Dadas from trading, accusing it of rigging prices by trading among its affiliated companies.</p>
<p>Since then, shares of Dadas have fallen more than 95 percent, and market players doubt they will ever recover.</p>
<p>The latest shock for already jittery investors came in July when bank Komercialna banka Triglav was closed down because of mounting liquidity problems.</p>
<p>Lek on Wednesday listed 1.7 million shares issued in the company's 1994 privatisation process, taking its total market capitalisation to 92.7 percent of the firm's equity base.</p>
<p>The company joined 14 other newly privatised firms that have been listed on the primary and over-the-counter (OTC) markets of the Ljubljana bourse since the beginning of the year. Another 18 newcomers are expected by year-end.</p>
<p>Lek's new issue shares ended the day at 13,970 tolars on volume of 8,678 shares, accounting for 85 percent of the market's total turnover.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
