<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="459679" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Yeltsin bounces back at Helsinki summit.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin bounces back at Helsinki summit.</headline>
<byline>Timothy Heritage</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>From the first firm step off his new presidential plane to his strong final handshake with U.S. President Bill Clinton, Boris Yeltsin proved at the Helsinki summit that he is well and truly back.</p>
<p>His finger-wagging performance at the closing news conference capped a performance which left little doubt the 66-year-old Russian president is once more in command after months of illness.</p>
<p>&quot;I can tell you he feels great. He looks great,&quot; Clinton said after Yeltsin declared the news conference closed with a loud &quot;spasibo&quot; (thank you) and a broad smile.</p>
<p>But Yeltsin's achievements are unlikely to satisfy everyone.</p>
<p>His political foes may dismiss the summit agreements as richer in promises than substance and accuse him of being softer on NATO expansion plans at the summit than he had promised.</p>
<p>He has moved Russia closer to a deal that may end in Russia having a seat at the top table at NATO meetings and a voice, but not a veto, in European security matters.</p>
<p>But nationalists and communists could be suspicious of a wording which may signal that Yeltsin has dropped his previous insistence on a legally binding document, rather than one that is only politically binding and ratified by parliaments.</p>
<p>Communist Party leader Gennady Zuyganov, pre-empting any agreements at the summit, made clear in Moscow that he was not about to praise his politicial sparring partner.</p>
<p>&quot;Boris Nikolayevich (Yeltsin) has not had any victories for a long time, except over his own people and country,&quot; Zyuganov told reporters. &quot;I don't believe in his international successes. Everything he does is linked to destruction.&quot;</p>
<p>Despite this, Yeltsin won a personal battle at Helsinki, showing he is fit again after spending the best part of eight months out of the Krmelin with heart problems followed by pneumonia which delayed his return.</p>
<p>His spokesman portrayed him as standing firm over NATO's plans to expand into eastern Europe, which Moscow says would threaten its security. At the same time Yeltsin said he had come in search of compromise and in the interests of peace.</p>
<p>He stood firm, spoke clearly and handled questions well at the final news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Nyet, minutochku! (No, wait a minute!),&quot; he butted in confidently at the news conference in typical fashion, taking over a question apparently directed for Clinton.</p>
<p>Gone was the president of a few weeks ago who looked much thinner after his illness, spoke weakly and appeared short of breath. Clinton's own predicament, confined to a wheelchair after knee surgery, helped highlight Yeltsin's health.</p>
<p>After a government reshuffle this week, and now a convincing performance in Helsinki, Yeltsin looks strong politically.</p>
<p>He was further boosted by U.S. pledges to help get Russia in to important financial institutions and to raise Russia's status at meetings of the Group of Seven industrial powers.</p>
<p>But despite the reported rapprochement at the summit, many problems lie ahead in relations with the United States.</p>
<p>Even agreement to reduce nuclear weapons may not go down well in all quarters at home. Some nationalists regard the nuclear missiles as a means to guarantee Moscow a higher profile in world diplomacy.</p>
<p>&quot;So long as we possess nuclear rockets and forces of nuclear deterrence...dialogue with our opponents can proceed very concretely, as it would have done 10 years ago,&quot; Alexei Mitrofanov, a nationalist deputy, said in Moscow before the summit ended.</p>
<p>Yeltsin can still not afford to look weak over NATO and tough rhetoric will continue as the alliance issues invitations to some eastern European countries this summer. Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic may be first in line.</p>
<p>Russian officials made clear Moscow would fiercely oppose any plans to offer NATO membership to former Soviet republics such as Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Ukraine and Belarus.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
