<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="45968" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Analysts not swayed by Sporitelna layoffs.</title>
<headline>Analysts not swayed by Sporitelna layoffs.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Equities analysts on Wednesday said news that the primary Czech savings bank, Ceska Sporitelna a.s., would shed 5,500-7,500 jobs from its workforce of nearly 20,000 would have little positive effect on its share price.</p>
<p>&quot;That announcement will have only a minor influence on the price,&quot; said Michal Snobr, analyst at AKRO Capital. &quot;What (Sporitelna) is missing is some comprehensive plan of a rehabilitation.&quot;</p>
<p>Sporitelna's investment banking chief Pavel Makovec said on Thursday that Sporitelna would lay off 1,000 staff next year and 2,000 in 1997, from the current workforce of roughly 19,500, and eventually 5,500-7,500 jobs</p>
<p>Makovec said Sporitelna would also continue to gradually close some of its current 1,800 branches.</p>
<p>Sporitelna shares closed unchanged on the Prague Stock Exchange Wednesday at 350 crowns.</p>
<p>Analysts have said Sporitelna, still 45 percent state owned, has been hindered by a bloated workforce, and an inefficient branch network.</p>
<p>The bank ploughed its full 1995 profit of over nine billion crowns into reserves against risky credit on the suggestions of independent auditors.</p>
<p>The bank, which was the primary savings bank where most every Czech deposited money during Communism and is still the country's largest in terms of retail deposits, had about 2,700 branches at its peak.</p>
<p>Analysts said that current shareholders were still trying to firm their position in the bank, but the stock was still overpriced.</p>
<p>&quot;Fundamentally Sporitelna (shares) should be about 350 crowns,&quot; said Jan Bilek, broker at RC&amp;I.</p>
<p>-- Radek Narovec, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
