<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="459712" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Finland's bizarre Elvis lover serenades summit.</title>
<headline>Finland's bizarre Elvis lover serenades summit.</headline>
<byline>Sara Henley</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A bespectacled Finnish professor with a cult following and a bizarre hobby made a mark on the U.S.-Russian summit on Friday, dedicating his latest recording of Elvis Presley hits in Latin to &quot;Boris and Bill&quot;.</p>
<p>Professor Jukka Ammondt, a specialist in the history of literature from the University of Jyvaskyla, dedicated songs like &quot;Glauci Calcei&quot; (Blue Suede Shoes) &quot;Mella Fella&quot; (Money Honey) and &quot;Ursus Taddeus&quot; (Teddy Bear) to U.S. President Bill Clinton and Russian President Boris Yeltsin.</p>
<p>Belting out his antique versions of Elvis in a Helsinki nightclub, he dedicated &quot;Quate, crepa, rota&quot; (Shake, Rattle and Roll) to Yeltsin and said the 66-year-old Kremlin chief was a &quot;rocking grandfather&quot;.</p>
<p>And he suggested Clinton should sing &quot;Ne Saevias&quot; (Don't be Cruel) to his Russian counterpart, in the spirit of partnership evident at the Helsinki summit.</p>
<p>Ammondt, who refuses to give his age although he appears to be around 50, insisted the combination of Latin and rock 'n roll was particularly appropriate for U.S.-Russian summitry.</p>
<p>&quot;Latin used to unite the western world, and today rock unifies the western world,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a neutral language, without bias.&quot;</p>
<p>The professor, who has also recorded Latin versions of tango songs, has been described as &quot;the most well-known Finn in America&quot; after he recently turned up with his songs in Memphis, Elvis's birthplace and still a shrine to his fans.</p>
<p>Sporting a white suit with scarlet cummerband and black patent shoes, he hopped and gyrated amid flashing disco lights and stage-mist, belting his way through the classics of rock.</p>
<p>For wheelchair-bound Clinton, who injured his knee last week, and Yeltsin, who is recovering from illness, the best title may be &quot;Nunc distrahor&quot; (All Shook Up).</p>
<p>One line: &quot;Manibus tremo, tremo genibus/Ambobus non sto nunc pedibus&quot;, translates as &quot;My hands are shaky and my knees are weak/I can't seem to stand on my own two feet&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
