<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="459762" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: U.S., Russia pledge new round of START talks.</title>
<headline>U.S., Russia pledge new round of START talks.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States and Russia said on Friday they would immediately embark on another round of nuclear arms reduction talks once Moscow has ratified the START-2 treaty.</p>
<p>In a joint statement after their summit, presidents Bill Clinton and Boris Yeltsin said they had reached an understanding that &quot;once START-2 enters into force, the U.S. and Russia will immediately begin negotiations on a START-3 agreement&quot; that will bring their nuclear arsenals to a level of 2,000-2,500 strategic warheads per side by the end of 2007.  </p>
<p>Clinton told a news conference that the new treaty, START-3, would mean that the United States and Russia would finally complete a reduction in both sides' Cold War arsenals of more than 80 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;These are dramatic and very substantial results and I'm very pleased with them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>However, Yeltsin's pledge to get the START-2 treaty through the Russian parliament first may be difficult to fulfil.</p>
<p>The parliament is dominated by Yeltsin's communist and nationalist opponents, who have refused so far to ratify the deal because they say it puts Russia at a strategic disadvantage.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
