<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460126" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Coffee market digests ACPC news, turns to Colombia.</title>
<headline>Coffee market digests ACPC news, turns to Colombia.</headline>
<byline>Jalil Hamid</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The coffee market struggled to cling on to slight gains on Friday after players digested news producers decided to lift arabica exports.</p>
<p>Traders said attention was being shifted to a possible transport workers strike in Colombia.</p>
<p>In a surprise move, the Association of Coffee Producing Countries (ACPC) agreed at a technical meeting on Thursday to release an additional 200,000 bags of washed arabica coffee to the world market in the first half of 1997.</p>
<p>The group also decided to revoke a previous decision to reduce exports of arabica coffee by 300,000 bags during the same period. This brings the total of additional exports to 500,000 bags.</p>
<p>New York-traded arabica futures trimmed gains on a sell-off after the news hit the market minutes before Thursday's close.</p>
<p>But the New York market was hardly moved in early business on Friday. &quot;The news has probably been built into the market,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>By 1535 GMT, May arabica futures were traded just 0.60 cents up at 169.75 cents a lb. In London, the robusta futures was just $10 higher at $1,665 a tonne basis May.</p>
<p>Market attention is now turned to Colombia where the  truck drivers union is due to meet on Saturday to set the date for the start of a new nationwide strike.</p>
<p>The union argued that transport companies had reneged on an agreement worked out to end the cripping 11-day strike last October which virtually paralysed all road freight and sent coffee prices rocketing.</p>
<p>Dockworkers at Colombia's main port of Buenaventura have also threatened new strike action which could begin in less than a month if no deal is reached.</p>
<p>Analysts continued to take opposing views on the ACPC move to raise arabica exports, with some saying that the amount appeared to be small considering the huge amount of coffee that had been shipped in the last two or three months.</p>
<p>Others said the additional arabica coffee may not be enough to relieve the supply crunch. Some also believe that the newly released coffee has probably been already sold and that Thursday's decision makes it formal.</p>
<p>One European trader said some sellers were finding it hard to sell top quality washed arabicas as most European roasters were well covered in the nearbys.</p>
<p>Brazilian traders said on Thursday the extra quota would mainly be taken up by the Central American countries, believed to anticipated third quarter sales given the recent high prices.</p>
<p>One European roaster said: &quot;500,000 bags would not make any difference, anyway the producers can afford to do so as prices are good.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The question now is what happens after the current export programme runs out at the end of June. Will the ACPC retain the quotas?&quot;</p>
<p>Robusta producers, faced with ample supplies, welcomed the ACPC move on arabicas.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a step in the right direction,&quot; said Derek Watson, adviser to the Indonesian Coffee Exporters Association. &quot;It's absolutely sensible, cautious and a predictable reaction. The ACPC did not wish to stand in the way of Colombia and other mild producers.&quot; -- London newsroom +44 171 542 4985</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
