<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460120" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: THE PROTEUS COLUMN - French flirt with free market.</title>
<headline>THE PROTEUS COLUMN - French flirt with free market.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE PROTEUS COLUMN</p>
<p>Valiant but vanquished, France is turning its back on centuries of dirigisme to loosen the state's grip on the economy, under mounting pressure from trade partners -- and a few multi-billion-dollar misadventures of its own.</p>
<p>It may be a long way from matching the &quot;free-market&quot; ways of rivals like the United States and Britain, but privatisation of state enterprise and market liberalisation are no longer words which trouble France's ruling elite.</p>
<p>Increasingly intense competition from the emerging &quot;tiger&quot; economies of Asia as well as the demands of a single market and creating a single currency in the European Union have sent France on this course.</p>
<p>Corruption and political patronage are under fire. A growing number of investigations have been launched into the chiefs of both public and private firms while financial debacles have hit state flagships such as Credit Lyonnais bank and state-controlled insurer GAN.</p>
<p>Among the latest reforms, the centre-right government said on Thursday it was proposing legislation to fight corruption in the awarding of public works contracts, partly to &quot;end the climate of permanent suspicion&quot;.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Jean Arthuis also announced plans to change corporate takeover rules, which would bring the system more in line with France's &quot;anglo-saxon&quot; partners, where hostile bids for companies are far more freqent.</p>
<p>Credit Lyonnais and GAN have required hugely expensive state rescues after strategies which the government has described as reckless.</p>
<p>Credit Lyonnais on Thursday announced a small profit for 1996 and predicted a strong rise in profits in 1997. But the state still faces a big bill for cleaning up its past mistakes, which could total over 130 billion francs ($23 billion).</p>
<p>Among many in the firing line of legal inquiries is former Credit Lyonnais boss Jean-Yves Haberer, appointed by the late Socialist President Francois Mitterrand with a mission to make the bank the biggest in the world.</p>
<p>He headed the bank between 1988 and 1993 during an expansion which briefly did make it the biggest bank outside Japan but is now blamed for bringing the bank to its knees. The government is also planning to spend 20 billion francs on GAN after losses in the collapsed property sector. Both cases have given the government ammunition to denounce the failings of state intervention, pursue a campaign of privatisation with greater zeal and commit itself more resolutely to ending of state-command.</p>
<p>Arthuis has vowed to privatise Credit Lyonnais and GAN once he sorts out their finances, describing the GAN saga as a &quot;grim adventure for the state-administered economy&quot;. He has also said the state needs to reassess its role as shareholder and supervisor of state groups, which presents a potential conflict of interest.</p>
<p>He is expected to tackle soon one of France's most traditional of institutions -- the Treasury -- via a shake-up which newspapers suggest could bring in private sector executives to sharpen the performance of state companies.</p>
<p>				--OO0OO--</p>
<p>THE PROTEUS COLUMN is an insight piece produced by Reuters journalists based on their own research and interpretations. While it aims to be as accurate and incisive as possible, it should not be taken to reflect the views of Reuters Ltd.</p>
<p>	   **************************************</p>
<p>THE PROTEUS COLUMN appears in the GLOBAL INSURANCE NEWS SUMMARY every weekday on Reuters Insurance Briefing.</p>
<p>For enquiries, contact -</p>
<p>Gordon Mackenzie, Editor, London</p>
<p>Tel: 44 171 542 2770</p>
<p>Fax 44 171 542 2583</p>
<p>e-mail gordon.mackenzie@reuters.com</p>
<p>John Sanders, News Editor, London</p>
<p>Tel: 44 171 542 2769</p>
<p>e-mail john.sanders@reuters.com</p>
<p>		****************************************</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
