<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460138" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: EMS/Mark off worst levels, helped by dollar decline.</title>
<headline>EMS/Mark off worst levels, helped by dollar decline.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The mark rose off its lows on its European crosses as dollar/mark came under pressure from pre-weekend position squaring into the European close.</p>
<p>The mark pushed back above 1,000 per lire after having hovered below this key psychological level for most of the session as the dollar eroded support at 1.6860 marks.</p>
<p>But dealers expected the dollar's decline - and the mark's recovery on the croses - to be limited amid expectations that U.S. interest rates will be raised next week.</p>
<p>Remarks by German Finance Minister Theo Waigel saying Germany was on course to cut its borrowing sufficiently to qualify for European monetary union seemed to have little impact on the European currencies.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market is completely punch drunk with EMU comments,&quot; Brian Hilliard, chief economist at Societe Generale Strauss Turnbull in London said. &quot;There's nothing of substance to add to the discussion at present and it will react to these remarks when it's got nothing better to do.&quot;</p>
<p>Waigel also said the EMU timetable would be determined by meeting the Maastricht criteria and these would be interpreted in a strict and narrow way in order to achieve a high degree of sustained convergence.</p>
<p>The Italian government announced it would slash 15.5 trillion lire off its deficit in a mini-budget due by Easter.</p>
<p>Better-than-expected Italian inflation data on Thursday gave Italian bond futures a boost and the Bund/BTP spread narrowed to 180 basis points aftewr touching as high as 215 this week.</p>
<p>The Italian March consumer price inflation rate is predicted to fall to 2.2 percent year-on-year from 2.4 percent in February according to analysts estimates after data from seven Italian cities. Final March CPI will be released on April 7.</p>
<p>The inflation picture across the continent looked benign as German February producer prices were flat, up 0.6 percent year-on-year and Irish February producer prices were down 0.3 percent, down 2.1 percent year-on-year.</p>
<p>Dollar/mark shed some of its gains in late trade here. The dollar was boosted initially by Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan's speech on Thursday, which was seen as preparing the market for the Federal Reserve to raise U.S. interest rates at next week's Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting.</p>
<p>However, pre-weekend position squaring and short-term profit-taking robbed the dollar off its strength into the European close.</p>
<p>Ahead of the weekend analysts said they expected traders to focus on the FOMC meeting and unwind speculative positions taken earlier this week.</p>
<p>&quot;You're ahead of a week with an FOMC meeting in it and very little on the German data front so there's nothing from the domestic side that's going to be pushing the mark up,&quot; said Alison Cottrell, international economist at Paine Webber here. The Swiss franc weakened further after an initial slide when Swiss National Bank board member Bruno Gehrig said the central bank was maintaining its generous monetary policy. He also said the central bank was prepared to intervene unlimitedly if the Swiss franc was boosted sharply by EMU uncertainty.</p>
<p>Swiss M0 money supply was reported up 1.9 percent in February from fourth quarter 1996 and up 7.9 percent on an annualised basis.</p>
<p>At 1520 GMT mark/lira was trading at 1001.30/60, little changed from 1001.50/95 at the European close on Thursday and off a session low at 998.75.</p>
<p>Mark/Swiss was at 0.8627/29 versus 0.8580/82 Thursday.</p>
<p>--Tara FitzGerald, London newsroom +44 171 542 6762</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
