<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460365" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - March 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - March 21.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Times reported the following business stories Friday:</p>
<p>* First Bank System agrees to buy U.S. Bancorp in a $9 billion stock swap.</p>
<p>* Ligget, a unit of Brooke Group acknowledged that smoking was addictive and caused cancer, and said companies have marketed cigarettes to children as young as 14, as part of litigation settlement with 22 U.S. states.</p>
<p>* U.S. Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan hinted he would raise U.S. interest rates next week as a precaution to keep the country's expansion on track.</p>
<p>* A Federal jury awarded a defunct securities firm $222.7 million in damages in a libel suit against Dow Jones, publishers of the Wall Street Journal.</p>
<p>* The U.S. trade deficit rose to $12.7 billion in January and the gap with China rose 36 percent. The dollar overcame early weakness caused by the report.</p>
<p>* The $22 billion merger between NYNEX and Bell Atlantic was approved by New York State Regulators, although NYNEX was ordered to improve its customer service by hiring employees and spending $500 million.</p>
<p>* The Dow industrials closed at 6,820.28, off 57.40 points, pushed lower by fears of higher rates and a strong dollar. Treasury prices were mixed.</p>
<p>* News Analysis: Another strike by AMR's American Airlines pilots looks unlikely.</p>
<p>* Delta announced an exclusive aircraft supply pact with Boeing for the next 20 years and an initial order for 106 aircraft worth $6.7 billion, with options to buy another 124 jets.</p>
<p>* A judge ruled that Dow Chemical, which owns half of Dow Corning, was not liable for medical problems Michigan women claimed arose from silicone gel breast implants.</p>
<p>* Under a more aggressive broadcast industry timetable, about 43 percent of U.S. households could receive digital high-definition television in the next 18-24 months.</p>
<p>* Federal investigators expanded their search of medical offices in El Paso, Texas, taking documents from doctors affiliated with local hospitals operated by Columbia/HCA Healthcare.</p>
<p>* Chile's successful pension plan has become a model for other countries.</p>
<p>New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
