<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46037" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Warsaw bourse seeks longer sessions from Q4.</title>
<headline>Warsaw bourse seeks longer sessions from Q4.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Warsaw bourse plans to lengthen its sessions by one hour in the fourth quarter, the financial daily Parkiet reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The bourse has proposed that trade begin half an hour earlier and end half an hour later than at present, the paper quoted the exchange's president Wieslaw Rozlucki as saying.</p>
<p>Rozlucki said the bourse also proposed to brokerage houses that continuous trade begin after the regular single price auction session ends instead of the two running concurrently.</p>
<p>&quot;On Monday we sent a letter to brokerage houses with the proposal for a new bourse set-up. We want...to divide the (single price auction) fixing from continuous trade,&quot; Rozlucki was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>According to the change, the regular bourse session would begin at 1030 local time and end at 1200, when continuous trade would begin. Continuous trade would end at 1330 local time.</p>
<p>Continuous prices would be allowed to fluctuate based on their same-day fixing.</p>
<p>The bourse will wait until September 28 for the brokerages' reply, which are likely to accept the proposal, Parkiet said.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
