<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460434" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Investment plan for Russia on table at Helsinki talks.</title>
<headline>Investment plan for Russia on table at Helsinki talks.</headline>
<byline>Philippa Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Boris Yeltsin and Bill Clinton discussed a comprehensive plan to boost U.S. investment in Russia on Friday and Moscow pressed Washington for membership of the developed world's economic clubs.</p>
<p>Talks on NATO and arms control dominated Friday's summit between the American and Russian presidents. But over lunch, the economy held sway.</p>
<p>The two debated &quot;assistance for the transition occurring in the Russian Federation, how international financial institutions can be helpful,&quot; White House spokesman Mike McCurry said.</p>
<p>Washington has said it is prepared to help support several billion dollars of investment into Russia's fledgling market economy if Moscow can improve the climate for investors.</p>
<p>That proposal, trade barriers against Russian goods and Moscow's bid to join various international economic groups were the likely burning issues at the lunchtime talks.</p>
<p>Maxim Boiko, deputy head of the Kremlin administration, said Russia had got rid of central planning over the past five years and urged the West to take this into account.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a question above all of recognising Russia as a country with a market economy, which carries important consequences both for Russia's entry into the Paris Club, the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) and other international organisations,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>Russia wants to join the Paris Club, which groups government creditors, to help it claim back some of the money it is owed by Third World countries granted soft loans during the communist era.</p>
<p>&quot;The other side of the issue is the expansion of some forms of Russian-American cooperation including attracting investment ...and removing barriers against Russian producers,&quot; Boiko said.</p>
<p>A U.S. official has said that Clinton would press for significant changes in Russia's legal and tax treatment of commercial properties and investments.</p>
<p>For his part, the U.S. president was prepared to offer &quot;a package of incentives for U.S. investors to respond to those changes&quot;, the official said.</p>
<p>These included the possibility of increased availability of guarantees for Russian investment from institutions such as the U.S. Export-Import bank, another official said.</p>
<p>One issue under discussion leading up to the summit was the U.S. Jackson-Vanik amendment which bars Most Favoured Nation trading status for any country that does not have open emigration policies, a category into which Russia has historically fallen.</p>
<p>Details of the talks have been kept under wraps and there has been no word on this and no indication of progress towards full membership for Russia of any of the clubs it wants to join.</p>
<p>Washington stresses it cannot speak for all the existing members of the various organisations, but U.S. officials have heralded a bigger role for Russia in consultations with the Group of Seven (G7) leading industrial nations.</p>
<p>Core economic matters would still be restricted to the seven but the tendency towards more consultation on political issues like terrorism, international crime and weapons of mass destruction was set to continue, one U.S. official said.</p>
<p>Both U.S. and Russian officials, highly sensitive to Russia's desire for formal membership, may begin a process of dropping the &quot;7&quot; from &quot;G7&quot;, instead referring to the next meeting as The Denver Summit rather than the Denver G7 Summit.</p>
<p>&quot;You are not going to see any G-7 signs in Denver, because for us this is the Denver summit,&quot; said another U.S. official.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
