<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460416" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Low key Russian first lady avoids summit spotlight.</title>
<headline>Low key Russian first lady avoids summit spotlight.</headline>
<byline>Abigail Schmelz</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Naina Yeltsin was given a low-key tour of Helsinki on Friday as her husband talked superpower politics, avoiding the limelight she would have endured if U.S. first lady Hillary Clinton had been in Finland.</p>
<p>&quot;If Hillary Clinton had been here, it would have been a whole different thing,&quot; a Finnish foreign ministry spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>There were no fashion displays or dramatic action for the homely Mrs Yeltsin, who does not appear to relish the public eye nearly as much as her predecessor Raisa Gorbachev, who became a fashion icon and adorned magazine covers.</p>
<p>A wooden and stiff-looking Naina, evoking memories of the long line of Kremlin wives preceding her who were kept from the public eye, was shown a senior citizens' activity centre and a kindergarten in the centre of the Finnish capital.</p>
<p>Wearing a pale colored suit and shaking hands formally with Finnish pensioners, a solemn Naina was outclassed in the charisma stakes by cheerful Finnish first lady, Eeva Ahtisaari, who was accompanying her.</p>
<p>After Russian songs by a silver-haired choir and a Finnish folk dance by the children, Naina travelled in a mini-van to the countryside home of Finnish artist Akseli Gallen-Kallela, a friend of Russian writer Maxim Gorky.</p>
<p>Naina, 65, braved icy winds on her way to Helsinki's central market, where she sampled a piece of cold smoked reindeer meat, which she described as &quot;delicious.&quot;</p>
<p>It has been reported that Naina is travelling mainly to keep an eye on her husband's health. Yeltsin underwent heart bypass surgery in November and then developed pneumonia, although he has since bounced back to health.</p>
<p>Clinton has been confined to a wheelchair following a stumble last week and has undergone emergency surgery to repair a torn tendon in his knee.</p>
<p>In Finland, which trod a delicate east-west tightrope during the Cold War, the Russian first lady's visit was taken by some ordinary Finns as a peace offering in a city where buildings still show shell marks from Soviet World War Two bombs.</p>
<p>&quot;I have fought twice against Russia,&quot; said Niilo Tarvajarvi, a gnarled former soldier at the pensioners' daycare centre. &quot;Her visit means peace for Finland and especially for Europe and the world.&quot;</p>
<p>Mariana Tikka, a employee at the centre, said she was surprised by Naina's stature. &quot;She was very tiny, just like a statue. But she had very warm eyes and a nice smile,&quot; she told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;And she loved that song about the Volga,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>In marked contrast to the staid activities of Naina Yeltsin, U.S. first lady Hillary Clinton's six-nation trip of Africa -- which kept her away from Helsinki -- has seen her portrayed her as a politically-aware, fashionable and ambitious feminist.</p>
<p>Dozens of international journalists and television crews follow her every move while on Friday a few local camera crews tagged along behind Russia's first lady.</p>
<p>Unlike Raisa Gorbachev, Naina's motherly image has made her very popular in Russia. Before Gorbachev, Kremlin wives were rarely even seen in public as personality cults around Soviet leaders were perceived as damaging.</p>
<p>Last week well-wishers sent her over a million roses for her birthday, according to the Russian news agency Itar-Tass, which appeared to be employing a little poetic license to elevate the status of the modest Naina. 211346 GMT mar 97</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
