<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460513" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Renault does not see truck unit sale - paper.</title>
<headline>Renault does not see truck unit sale - paper.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Renault chairman Louis Schweitzer said in a newspaper interview that the group did not envisage a sale of the industrial vehicles unit, Renault V.I., which lost money last year and is expected to lose money again this year.</p>
<p>Asked by the afternoon newspaper Le Monde whether Renault was considering a sale of the business, Schweitzer said, &quot;No. It's an important activity for us and we've had it for 80 years...But on the other hand, the car operation can't be expected to subsidise it.&quot;</p>
<p>Renault expects its car division to break even in 1997 after losing money the past two years.</p>
<p>&quot;Renault V.I. is currently less profitable than its Scandinavian competitors. But the costs in France and Spain are more favourable than those in Germany and Sweden. We need to do with the truck business what we did for the cars -- promote an image of quality and make Renault V.I. less dependent on France and Spain,&quot; he said. Forty percent of Renault V.I. sales are in France.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a gruelling task. Our new Premium model line should help us. Renault V.I. also needs a strategy of cooperation with Mack (Trucks), its suppliers, its competitors,&quot; he said. &quot;But we don't expect Renault V.I. to break even in 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>The company said on Thursday that Renault V.I. would be the focus of accelerated cost-cutting measures in 1997, but Schweitzer told reporters they would not consist of &quot;spectacular operations&quot;.</p>
<p>Renault V.I. owns Mack Trucks of the United States. The company said Mack was profitable last year, but Renault V.I.'s operating loss came to 705 million francs ($124 million).</p>
<p>Its Scandinavian rivals are Volvo and Scania.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452 ($ = 5.704 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
