<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460658" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenian shares end 5-day slide, seen recovering.</title>
<headline>Slovenian shares end 5-day slide, seen recovering.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenian shares reversed a five-day losing streak on Friday, closing marginally firmer, but ending the week five percent lower.</p>
<p>The blue-chip SBI index rose 3.09 points to 1,321.24. Overall seven shares rose, seven fell, two were unchanged and 10 untraded. Turnover recovered to 64.6 million tolars from 46.9 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Today there was some optimism on the market. Everyone is expecting foreign buyers to return,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>He cautioned, however, that if foreign buying failed to materialise the SBI index could resume its downward trek.</p>
<p>&quot;(In that instance) prices could continue falling until the index reaches about 1,156 points, which was the level at the start of the year and represents the first psychological limit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Last month the central bank blocked internatinal buying with a ruling that foreigners had to open special custody accounts if they wanted to trade securities. Since then the SBI index has fallen 20.2 percent and investors have limited their buying to a few selected stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment shares in food makers Kolinska and Droga seem to be the best medium and long-term investment due to the good business results of the two companies,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>On Friday, financial consultancy Dadas was the top gainer, up 9.86 percent to 8,470 tolars on volume of 1,267 shares.</p>
<p>Bank UBK was the leading decliner, down 10 percent to 5,400 tolars on volume of 2,015 shares. Traders said UBK could fall further on expectation of poor business results.</p>
<p>Issue A of drug company Lek had the highest turnover. Its shares fell 1.55 percent to 26,080 tolars on volume of 672 shares. -- Marja Novak, Ljubljana newsroom, 386-61-125-8439</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
