<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460657" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: SAAB, ELECTROLUX SPEARHEAD HUNGARY FIGHTER DEAL BID.</title>
<headline>SAAB, ELECTROLUX SPEARHEAD HUNGARY FIGHTER DEAL BID.</headline>
<byline>Duncan Shiels</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's Saab and Electrolux , both owned by the Wallenberg sphere, announced plans on Friday to invest several hundred million dollars in Hungary and to create up to 20,000 jobs.</p>
<p>The investment is part of offset deals related to Saab's bid to sell Gripen JAS 39 fighter aircraft to Hungary through a consortium with British Aerospace .</p>
<p>&quot;Under our plan 'Source Hungary' we will build a new Hungarian infrastructure for subcontracting by small amd medium sized companies,&quot; Saab president and CEO Bengt Halse told Reuters after opening Gripen's new Budapest office.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly the investment involves several hundred million dollars and in terms of jobs we are talking about something like 5,000 direct jobs and maybe 20,000 indirect jobs.&quot;</p>
<p>The inauguration of the Gripen office coincided with the opening on Friday of a new $15 million Electrolux chest freezer plant at Jaszbereny, 80 kilomteres (50 miles) south of the capital.</p>
<p>Saab is competing with a number of aircraft makers to replace Hungary's fleet of Soviet MiG-21s and MiG-23s which will be obsolete by the end of the century.</p>
<p>Most analysts believe the two most likely candidates are Lockheed's F16, either new or used, and the Gripen.</p>
<p>Also in the race are McDonnell Douglas/Northrop's F-18 and Dassault's Mirage 2000-5 while Russia's state arms agency Rosvooruzhenie was also reported last month to be considering offering Su-27s, Su-30s and Su-39s.</p>
<p>The fighter procurement tender had been due for publication last summer but Hungary postponed the decision until after a decision by NATO on expansion, expected in July 1997.</p>
<p>Halse stressed that the &quot;Source Hungary&quot; programme was linked to Gripen's prospects of winning the fighter tender.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a lot of money, that's why it has to be linked to making a business like Gripen in Hungary,&quot; he said,</p>
<p>&quot;If we have a business which will take us into a long-term relationship with the country's government, then this will be one of the deal-makers in making these long-term investments.&quot;</p>
<p>Helse added the Saab/BAE consortium was also preparing a financial package to put to the Hungarian government which would be &quot;extremely attractive&quot; but declined to give details.</p>
<p>The Wallenberg group was the first to sign an industrial offset deal with the Hungarian government in September 1995 to purchase Hungarian-made goods as part of a possible deal to buy JAS 39 fighters.</p>
<p>Hungary signed similar deals with General Electric Trading and with Lockheed Martin Corp of the United States earlier this year.</p>
<p>Electrolux Hungary's president Tibor Kertesz, told Hungary Electrolux's part of the &quot;Source Hungary&quot; programme was worth nine billion forints ($51 million) over the next two to three years and aimed to increase the Hungarian-made content of its Hungarian plants from 35 percent to over 50 percent.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom +361 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
