<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46068" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexican stocks close down on profit-taking, Dow.</title>
<headline>Mexican stocks close down on profit-taking, Dow.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican stocks closed lower Tuesday in a session marked by profit-taking and a sluggish Dow Jones, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was very weak, and it did follow the Dow today. There was heavy profit-taking. We think it will continue to adjust until it reaches the 3,250-point level,&quot; said Francisco Blanco, director of equity analysis at the Arka brokerage.</p>
<p>&quot;We're in the consolidation period we needed for the bolsa to gather strength for a rally,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The blue chip IPC index closed down 31.92 points, or 0.96 percent, at 3,309.27.</p>
<p>Volume was a mediocre 70.1 million shares traded. A total of 106 stocks changed hands, with losers outnumbering winners 52 to 29, while 25 were unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;Volume is still low, both domestic and foreign traders are staying on the sidelines,&quot; a floor trader said.</p>
<p>Prospects of interest rate cuts at Tuesday evening's primary auction did not seem to motivate stock traders, either, traders said.</p>
<p>Financial group GFInver ACP series headed the percentage leaders, gaining 10 centavos (1 cent) to 1.10 pesos (15 cents).</p>
<p>&quot;There was speculative buying of that financial stock. There's talk again of an alliance with Santander, but that's been going on for a while. Let's see if something does happen this time,&quot; said a floor trader.</p>
<p>Holding company Accelsa A2 series led the winners' list for most of the session due, analysts said, to its favourable outlook for 1997 and what was felt to be a cheap share price. Accelsa A2 closed up 66 centavos (9 cents) up at 13.16 pesos ($1.74).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
