<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460686" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Pregnant Irish prisoner to fight British election.</title>
<headline>Pregnant Irish prisoner to fight British election.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1997-03-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Roisin McAliskey, a pregnant Irishwoman held in England while Germany tries to extradite her for questioning about an IRA attack, will contest a seat in Britian's general election, her mother said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Bernadette McAliskey, who held the Mid-Ulster seat as a radical Catholic nationalist from 1969 to 1974, said her eight-month pregnant daughter would stand as an independent on May 1 to highlight her plight and try to have her baby in freedom.</p>
<p>But her hopes of victory received a setback when the main Catholic SDLP group rejected an appeal for it and its Sinn Fein rival to stand down so she might secure united Catholic support in one of Northern Ireland's 18 seats.</p>
<p>And a spokeswoman for the Home Office, Britain's interior ministry said there was no legal reason why McAliskey should not stand for parliament but there was also no reason why she should be freed if elected.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking at whether any facilities could or should be made available to her if she decides to stand,&quot; the spokeswoman added.</p>
<p>Bernadette McAliskey, under her maiden name Devlin, caused a sensation in 1969 when she won the same seat at the age of 22. She became the youngest woman ever elected to the British parliament but lost the seat in 1974.</p>
<p>Roisin McAliskey, 25, is in London's Holloway prison pending extradition to Germany for questioning about an Irish Republican Army (IRA) attack on a British military base at Osnabrueck last year. She denies being involved.</p>
<p>Her detention has been widely criticised by the Irish government and Catholic politicians and Bernadette McAliskey accused Britian of anti-Irish racism by refusing bail to Roisin.</p>
<p>She said if her daughter were granted bail by April 16 when election candidates must submit their nominiation papers &quot;then the situation would obviously change.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;On nomination day, if Roisin is in prison, that seat will be needed to get her out,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The Home Office said it was unclear if Roisin would be released if she was nominated as a candidate. Electoral law only states people cannot stand as candidates if they are imprisoned for more than 12 months.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the moderate Social Democratic and Labour Party said its candidate would not withdraw, saying it was critical for voters to be given the opportunity to express their views on wider political issues.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein, the political arm of the outlawed IRA which is fighting to oust Britain and unite the province with Ireland, reacted more cautiously by suggesting three-way talks with McAliskey's family and the SDLP.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course the SDLP's attitude will have a direct bearing on Sinn Fein's decision,&quot; said its Northern Ireland chairman, Gearoid O'Hara.</p>
<p>Protestant &quot;Unionist&quot; parties, representing the 60 per cent pro-British majority, traditionally win most of the seats in the province.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
