<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460732" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BRITISH SPORTS SHOPS SCORE IN LATEST FASHION CRAZE.</title>
<headline>BRITISH SPORTS SHOPS SCORE IN LATEST FASHION CRAZE.</headline>
<byline>Jane Merriman</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The transformation of football shirts and trainers into hot fashion for teenagers made British sports retailers stock market champions last year, with premium ratings and surging share prices.</p>
<p>Blacks Leisure Group Plc, whose shares sprinted to the top of the league in 1996, is one of the main beneficiaries of the boom in branded sportswear, and is planning an ambitious programme of new store openings.</p>
<p>Industry analysts estimate Britain's 3.0 billion pound ($4.9 billion) sportswear and leisurewear market will continue to expand and predict it will have grown by about 20 percent by the year 2000, boosting retailers such as Blacks, and recently floated rivals John David Sports Plc and JJB Sports Plc.</p>
<p>The only dark cloud on the horizon is if the current mania for Umbro replica football shirts, Nike trainers or Adidas &quot;three stripe&quot; favoured by pop group Oasis's Liam Gallagher fades.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no sign of people getting bored with sports as fashion yet,&quot; said one industry analyst, &quot;It still remains a lucrative market which is clearly growing at the expense of traditional childrens clothing and footwear.&quot;</p>
<p>Blacks' chief executive Simon Bentley believes it has a broad enough spread of businesses to protect it if fashion suddenly shifts. And he says expansion will not be allowed to stretch the group financially. &quot;We want to keep gearing very low,&quot; he told Reuters, saying the group did not want gearing to be higher than the 15 percent at the year end.</p>
<p>SHARES RISING</p>
<p>Blacks shares have risen about 10 fold over the past 13 months and the stock is trading on a multiple of about 20 times annual earnings. J-D Sports and JJB Sports command even higher ratings.</p>
<p>Analysts are predicting Blacks can make profits of more than nine million pounds for the year to the end of February, a huge jump from 2.1 million in the previous financial year. Sales in the 44 weeks to January 4 1997 were up 22 percent on a like for like basis, and up 45 percent overall.</p>
<p>Massive investment by major sportswear manufacturers promoting their brands has spurred demand, as well as the growing commercialisation of sport and high profile events such as Euro96.</p>
<p>Bentley said sportswear has been around for a long time, but now the brands Blacks sells are seen as street fashion for a target market of 12-24 year olds. &quot;It's not because there's been an unbelievable increase in sports participation -- it's because our products are being perceived as fashion.&quot;</p>
<p>CONTRAST WITH OLYMPUS</p>
<p>The success of Blacks and the other retailers contrasts starkly with the failure of market leader Olympus, originally owned by Sears Plc, which tried unsuccessfully to promote is own brands to win higher margins.</p>
<p>Blacks plans to open about 40 stores in the coming financial year, giving the group 80 First Sport stores, which sell the football kits and other branded sportswear. But there is scope to do more.</p>
<p>&quot;Experienced retailers in the UK tell me that...one reaches maximum capacity at a figure approaching 300 stores,&quot; Bentley said, adding though that this was clearly a long way off.</p>
<p>Blacks Leisure, which sells outdoor equipment and the new ActiveVenture chain, offering branded leisurewear such as Timberland and Kickers, give Blacks greater diversity than some of its competitors, Bentley said.</p>
<p>&quot;With the broader base of businesses that we've got...that would put us in a better position if times ever got any harder.&quot;</p>
<p>The steady climb of the sports retailers' shares was interrupted briefly when Britain's competition watchdog, the Office of Fair Trading, said it was investigating sports goods manufacturers on price fixing. But fears were soothed when it appeared the investigation would not include mainstream sportswear such as the replica football kits.</p>
<p>&quot;My personal knowledge of our own relationship with suppliers is they do not in any way attempt to fix prices,&quot; Bentley said.</p>
<p>Football clubs and manufacturers have been attacked in the British press for changing their kits too often, forcing parents to fork out 40 pounds every time a club introduces a new strip (shirt).</p>
<p>There were complaints from fans when the England team changed its strip in January, just after parents had bought their kids the old kit for Christmas.</p>
<p>Bentley said some unexpected changes were unfortunate, but most teams had a predictable cycle of three kits over a two year period.</p>
<p>($ = 0.613 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I45100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFAS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
