<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460737" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Don't over-report human mad cow' disease - experts.</title>
<headline>Don't over-report human mad cow' disease - experts.</headline>
<byline>Maggie Fox</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Publicly reporting every suspected case of the human form of mad cow disease could exaggerate the extent of the illness, the scientists who discovered it said on Friday.</p>
<p>Creutzfeldt Jakob Disease (CJD) was still too hard to diagnose, especially the new variant identified one year ago and linked to bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE or mad cow disease), they said.</p>
<p>Robert Will of the National CJD Surveillance Unit in Edinburgh and colleagues said they still wanted to continue examining all possible cases -- they just saw no reason for the figures to be published.</p>
<p>&quot;Four of the 37 referred cases have been classified as new variant CJD and one as probable new variant CJD,&quot; they wrote in a letter to the Lancet medical journal.</p>
<p>With the 10 cases reported last March, that makes only 14 confirmed cases of the new CJD variant out of 37 suspect cases.</p>
<p>The government currently publishes confirmed and probable CJD cases as identified by the Edinburgh unit. There had been calls for all referrals to the unit to be reported as well.</p>
<p>James Ironside, one of the letter's authors, rejected the idea. &quot;Because the rate of pickup from the referred cases is so low...it would be potentially misleading,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In a commentary, the Lancet accused some British newspapers of exaggerating the spread of CJD, saying &quot;confusion and panic&quot; surrounded the announcement last year of the new variant.</p>
<p>Some of the patients referred with what their doctors thought might be CJD actually got better, which shows how hard the always-fatal illness is to diagnose, Ironside said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>CJD, which like BSE causes spongelike lesions in the brain, can only be positively diagnosed with a brain biopsy or autopsy after death. The same goes for the new variant, which attacks younger people and which scientists say probably comes from having eaten BSE-infected beef.</p>
<p>Ironside and colleagues are working now to see if a tonsil biopsy could be useful. &quot;If that turns out to be helpful then we could proceed to suggest this as a diagnostic test,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another letter in this week's Lancet describes using magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) to look for the characteristic brain damage in a victim of the classic, one-in-a-million, form of CJD.</p>
<p>Researchers at University Hospitals in Leeuven, Belgium said the MRI showed &quot;gross deformities&quot; in the 68-year-old victim's brain. Autopsy confirmed she died of CJD.</p>
<p>Ironside said his team was currently evaluating MRIs taken on all suspected CJD cases. &quot;This is an area we are interested in,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
