<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460880" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Hongkong Land aims more China projects.</title>
<headline>Hongkong Land aims more China projects.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hongkong Land Holdings said on Friday its projects in China were focused in Beijing, where it expected to get involved in a development project this year.</p>
<p>&quot;In China, our efforts currently are focused in Beijing. We hope in 1997 to bring a development project in there forward,&quot; Hongkong Land managing director Percy Weatherall told reporters.</p>
<p>It hoped to finalise a deal on an office development in China this year, he added two days after the company announced 1996 net profits of US$649 million.  </p>
<p>Hongkong Land was also eyeing more water treatment projects in China through its 33-percent owned China Water Co.</p>
<p>&quot;We are involved in one project in Shenyang and are pursuing new opportunities within China on the water front. I strongly expect in 1997 we will get involved in several projects and we will be supporting this company with fresh equity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Weatherall said another city in China where the company was keen to do business was Shanghai, highly likely to develop into a financial centre and a good market for Hongkong Land as a high portion of its tenants were from the finance sector.  </p>
<p>In Singapore, Hongkong Land expected its office and retail development, Esplanade Mall, to be ready in 2000. Development and the purchase of the site totalled US$430 million.</p>
<p>In Indonesia, the company has a stake of 20 percent in a second toll road project which runs east of Jakarta, connecting Cikampek to Padalarang.</p>
<p>Construction would start around April-May 1998 and the investment was expected to start paying dividends in 2003, Weatherall said.  </p>
<p>Its US$30 million investment in the existing Indonesian Tangerang-Merak toll road was expected to start paying dividends in 2002, he said.</p>
<p>While Hongkong Land was expanding into transportation and water, it did not see these contributing more than 5-10 percent of the company's revenue and profit in the next five years, finance director Ian Durant said.</p>
<p>Weatherall said the company was looking at opportunites in power projects and &quot;recognised telecommunications as an interesting area&quot;.</p>
<p>--Singapore newsroom (65-8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
