<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460876" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine grain buyers sidelined by high prices.</title>
<headline>Philippine grain buyers sidelined by high prices.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine grain importers will probably be glued to the sidelines next week and adopt a wait-and-see attitude because of high prices of U.S. wheat and soybeans, traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be shying away from the market,&quot; said an official from a local flour mill in Manila.</p>
<p>&quot;We've talked to the millers and most of them are leaving for the holidays,&quot; said one trader, refering to the long Easter holidays in the Philippines next week.  </p>
<p>With U.S. wheat prices so high, Philippine flour mills have turned to supplies from Canada, where they recently bought 35,000 tonnes of Canadian spring and soft wheat for May shipment.</p>
<p>Philippine firms buy most of their wheat and soybean from the United States. On average, they buy about 20,000 tonnes of soybean and some 120,000 tonnes of wheat a month.</p>
<p>The National Food Authority (NFA) said it expects no further negotiations for any rice or corn imports next week.  </p>
<p>It said a ship from Vietnam had begun unloading 10,500 tonnes of rice while a vessel from China began unloading 27,198 tonnes of yellow corn in Manila.</p>
<p>Another ship from Vietnam was scheduled to start unloading its cargo of 7,300 tonnes of rice on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Department of Trade and Industry said prices of local hard flour remained unchanged at 290 pesos per 25-kilogram bag while soft flour was seen steady at 260 pesos per 25 kg bag.</p>
<p>The average retail price of yellow corn in the local market slipped from 10.79 pesos a kg to 10.77 while white corn also dropped slightly to 10.94 pesos from 10.95 per kg.  </p>
<p>(US$1=26.30 pesos)</p>
<p>- Manila Newsroom 632-841-8937, fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
