<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46083" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine Congress postpones tax bill vote.</title>
<headline>Argentine Congress postpones tax bill vote.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-09-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's ruling Peronist Party was unable Wednesday to obtain quorum in the lower house of Congress to approve a key tax bill and postponed the vote until next week, Peronist officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;We were unable to get quorum today,&quot; Jorge Matzkin, head of the ruling party in the Chamber of Deputies, told reporters. &quot;But there is the political will and I believe that next week we will be able to vote.&quot;  </p>
<p>There were few Peronist deputies in the chamber and members of the leading opposition parties and provincial parties refused to enter because of the shortage of ruling party congressmen there.</p>
<p>However, Matzkin said he was sure the ruling party would back the measures next week.</p>
<p>&quot;At least in the Peronist bloc (deputies) are fully convinced,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Following are details of the proposed fiscal package that is designed to head off an estimated $6.6 billion deficit this year:</p>
<p>* 46 percent increase in tax on diesel.</p>
<p>* 12 percent increase in gasoline tax.</p>
<p>* 28.6 percent rise in tax on natural gas.</p>
<p>* 10 percent tax increase on diesel vehicles.</p>
<p>(The Deputies' Budget Committee removed an article making fuel tax hikes non-shareable with provinces, leaving it to the Senate to vote on Economy Minister Roque Fernandez's request for this revenue to go exclusively to the central government.)</p>
<p>* Increase in income tax for companies, to 33 percent from 30 percent and for wage-earners on more than $10,000 a month, to 35 percent from 30 percent.</p>
<p>* An increase in the share of personal wealth tax going to the provinces, to 56 percent from 10 percent.</p>
<p>* Authorization for a $4.0 billion increase in government indebtedness for this year.</p>
<p>-- Gary Regenstreif, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 541 318-0618</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
