<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="460985" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: South Korean parliament probes corporate collapse. [CORRECTED 08:04 GMT]</title>
<headline>South Korean parliament probes corporate collapse. [CORRECTED 08:04 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Moon Ihlwan</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's parliament on Friday kicked off a probe into the collapse of Hanbo Steel Co, and the opposition said it suspected influence-peddling in the failure of another leading steelmaker this week.</p>
<p>Three more units of the Sammi Group filed for court receivership after the steelmaking flagship of the nation's 26th biggest industrial conglomerate went under with huge debts on Tuesday a Sammi spokesman said (corrects by deleting reference to $5.8 billion).</p>
<p>Sammi Steel Co, the country's largest specialty steel products maker, and its trading arm Sammi Corp were declared insolvent on Thursday.</p>
<p>Sammi's failure has sparked fears of a domino effect of bankruptcies, particularly among smaller companies vulnerable to credit tightening.</p>
<p>Seoul share prices plummeted, with the main index falling 2.0 percent to 630.02 in early Friday afternoon trading.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe Sammi's default is another example of a sleazy politics-business alliance,&quot; said spokeswoman Park Sun-suck of the main opposition National Congress for New Politics.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have to include the collapse of Sammi in the special parliamentary investigation,&quot; she told Reuters.</p>
<p>A 19-member National Assembly committee, formed to look into a loans-for-bribes scandal involving Hanbo Steel, visited the steelmakers' main plant in the southwestern city of Tangjin at the start of a 45-day probe.</p>
<p>Ten people, including a former cabinet minister, close aides to President Kim Young-sam, bankers and Hanbo's founder, are on trial for bribery over the scandal.</p>
<p>However, the National Congress believes the main culprits have not been brought to justice.</p>
<p>The opposition has accused the president's son, Kim Hyun-chul, of peddling influence in giving loans to Hanbo.</p>
<p>State prosecutors exonerated Hyun-chul last month after a probe into how Hanbo managed to obtain massive loans for a dodgy project on a tiny capital base.</p>
<p>On Monday, Hyun-chul apologised for creating a furore, agreed to testify in the parliamentary probe and said he was ready for punishment if he had done wrong.</p>
<p>The National Congress and United Liberal Democrats said they would grill the younger Kim not only over Hanbo but also about allegations that he meddled in state affairs and that he pressured banks to provide loans to Sammi.</p>
<p>The younger Kim played an important role in his father's election in 1992 but has no position in the administration.</p>
<p>&quot;Sammi's failure is the second Hanbo incident,&quot; United Liberal spokesman Ahn Taik-soo said. &quot;The government will have to look into the matter immediately.&quot;</p>
<p>Sammi Steel was staggering under liabilities of 1.45 trillion won ($1.64 billion) at the end of 1996 against assets of 1.53 trillion won, according to company figures. Opposition politicians said well over the half the total loans were provided since 1992 when it ran into trouble.</p>
<p>Financial analysts said Sammi's collapse highlighted a mountain of bad debt amassed by domestic banks after decades of reckless lending. Foreign lenders are now shying away from South Korean financial institutions.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Kang Kyong-shik said on Friday that companies that could not stand by themselves must be liquidated.</p>
<p>&quot;We must bravely liquidate companies that are operating on the margins,&quot; he said in a statement, referring to firms being propped up.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
