<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46101" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia's industrial output down sharply - gov't.</title>
<headline>Colombia's industrial output down sharply - gov't.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombia's industrial production excluding coffee processing fell 0.59 percent in the first half of 1996 compared with a booming 4.38 percent growth during the first six months of 1995, the National Statistics Department (DANE) said.</p>
<p>Including coffee processing, it said industrial production grew a feeble 0.26 percent compared with 2.34 percent growth in the first half of last year.  </p>
<p>Employment in the industrial sector mirrored the sharp slowdown in growth, dropping 2.81 percent during the first half, the DANE said.</p>
<p>It said some of the hardest hit industries included those involved in the production of heavy machinery and electrial appliances, a sector that suffered negative growth of 3.5 percent in the first half.</p>
<p>Producers of crude oil derivatives, including gasoline were hit by 12.92 percent negative growth, while leather tanneries saw their output shrink by 14.08 percent.  </p>
<p>DANE gave no reason for the drop in growth, but a closely watched survey released on Tuesday by the National Association of Industrialists (ANDI) cited &quot;insecurity&quot; and violence stemming from Colombia's guerrilla war as the top problem affecting industries across the country.</p>
<p>The survey also cited the political crisis that erupted last year over charges that President Ernesto Samper's 1994 election campaign was partly financed by drug lords.</p>
<p>ANDI's independent survey said industrial production in the first seven months of 1996 had fallen 2.0 percent from the same period last year. -- Tom Brown, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
