<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="461184" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel fears violence, has tough line on West Bank.</title>
<headline>Israel fears violence, has tough line on West Bank.</headline>
<byline>Colleen Siegel</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1997-03-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel poured security forces into Jerusalem on Friday fearing tension over its building of a new Jewish settlement in the city's Arab half could ignite clashes.</p>
<p>In the West Bank flash point of Hebron, about 50 youths marched toward the Israeli-controlled centre of town in the morning and hurled rocks at soldiers.</p>
<p>Likely to fuel Palestinian anger, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu vowed Palestinians would not get &quot;a significant percentage&quot; of the West Bank in the three stages of an Israeli pullback scheduled before a final peace deal.</p>
<p>He urged skipping the interim deal and moving to accelerated final talks as a way to avoid conflict over the pullbacks.</p>
<p>Jerusalem's Israeli police chief Yair Yitzhaki said his men &quot;deployed in force&quot; -- Israel Radio said there were 2,500 police in the city. Yitzhaki urged restraint on all sides.</p>
<p>&quot;There is tension, a situation we call gasoline vapors in the air. We will make every effort not to let them ignite the street...Restraint is the best word...I hope we see this on the other side too,&quot; Yitzhaki said.</p>
<p>Palestinians enraged by the start on Tuesday of a 6,500-unit Jewish housing project in Arab East Jerusalem threw petrol bombs and rocks at Israeli soldiers on Thursday near Bethlehem in the West Bank.</p>
<p>Israeli troops responded with rubber bullets and tear gas in clashes reminscent of a six-year uprising ended by the 1993 interim peace deal the PLO charges the right-wing Netanyahu government has violated. One Palestinian was wounded and 14 suffered from tear gas inhalation.</p>
<p>Netanyahu said his proposal to bypass three interim Israeli troop withdrawals from the West Bank to complete &quot;final status&quot; talks within six months, nearly two years earlier than planned, would remove the need to waste time over the redeployments.</p>
<p>&quot;With these redeployments it is already clear on the side of the Palestinians that the idea that we'd give them each time 20 or 30 percent or a significant percentage...that is not realistic,&quot; Netanyahu told Israel Radio.</p>
<p>&quot;That won't work with the government, not with my government,&quot; he said. &quot;I propose going to another process.&quot;</p>
<p>The Palestinians rejected Netanyahu's proposal, revealed on Wednesday, as a trick to deflect world attention from the new Jewish settlement. The United States said it may have value.</p>
<p>Under the interim peace deals, highly sensitive issues such as the future of Jerusalem and Jewish settlements are to come up only in &quot;final status&quot; talks.</p>
<p>Palestinians have also rejected Israel's unilateral decision that the first pullback would constitute only nine percent of West Bank land now under some Israeli control. Israel earlier handed over eight major West Bank towns and much of the Gaza Strip to Palestinian rule.</p>
<p>Final status peace talks did not resume on March 17 as had been planned because of the Israeli moves on settlement and redeployment.</p>
<p>Israel's Maariv daily said on Friday Netanyahu would recognise a Palestinian state -- without an army -- in up to half of the West Bank. It said some Jewish settlements might be dismantled to prevent them being &quot;islands&quot; in such a state.</p>
<p>&quot;I am against a Palestinian state...I have no intention and I am not taking down any settlement,&quot; Netanyahu told the radio.</p>
<p>Maariv quoted Netanyahu as saying: &quot;If the Palestinians insist on their demands, there will be no agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>Israel captured Arab East Jerusalem with the rest of the West Bank and the Gaza Strip in 1967. It vows never to cede any part of Jerusalem. Palestinians want East Jerusalem as capital of a future state in the West Bank and Gaza.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
