<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46118" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico's Ahmsa sees steel exports dropping this yr.</title>
<headline>Mexico's Ahmsa sees steel exports dropping this yr.</headline>
<dateline>MONTERREY, Mexico 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Steelmaker Altos Hornos de Mexico SA (Ahmsa) expects to export 940,000 tonnes of steel this year, down from 1.07 million tonnes last year, said Enrique Gasca Neri, corporate marketing director of Grupo Acerero del Norte, the company which controls Ahmsa.  </p>
<p>&quot;We estimate our exports will be 940,000 tonnes, about 34 percent of total outpout, compared to 1.07 million tonnes in 1995, or 50 percent of output,&quot; Gasca said in a telephone interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>Gasca said Ahmsa exports to 35 countries.</p>
<p>&quot;We managed to enter attractive markets like Japan,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ahmsa was trying to make inroads into markets in the United States and Central and South America, he added.  </p>
<p>Gasca said the effect U.S. anti-dumping duties on steel exports was low as &quot;we can export almost all of our products there, except for flat slabs, which we don't export.&quot;</p>
<p>Ahmsa exports just 3,000 tonnes of flat slabs worldwide, Gasca said.</p>
<p>Gasca also predicted that the world steel cycle will rebound in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The steel cycle is at a low ... but prices are beginning to pick up in the United States, which points to a recovery,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>International prices for hot-rolled steel, Ahmsa's best-selling product, have fallen between 25 and 30 percent in dollar terms over the last 12 months, according to analysts.</p>
<p>In Mexico, &quot;demand is weak, although co-exports (products manufactured with steel components) have increased, but are less competitive because of inflation and the sliding peso,&quot; Gasca said.</p>
<p>-- Daniel Prez, Monterrey newsroom, +528 345-7617</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTERREY, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
