<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="461200" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O.Licht - Daily sugar report.</title>
<headline>F.O.Licht - Daily sugar report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from commodity statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>SUGAR - World market for March 20, 1997</p>
<p>White sugar futures in London pushed higher in afternoon trade with May ending at $307.90 per tonne, up $2.40 on the day. August was up $2.10 at $306.70 per tonne. Trade buying in London, coupled with commission house crosses, provided the impetus for the rise on the whites but profit-takers then moved in to cap the gains. Arbitrage trading was reported to be light as most sellers were thought to be waiting above the market, at $69 and $70 basis May.</p>
<p>Raw sugar futures in New York settled firmer but well off the highs amid brisk activity. Dealers attributed gains to technically driven local and fund short covering coupled with a lack of selling in early activity. Spot month May closed up 0.15 cent at 10.90 cents/lb, having ranged from 11.01 to 10.70 cents. The outer months settled 0.11 to 0.06 firmer. Despite today's gains May closed below the weeks's high of 10.93 cents/lb reached on Monday. Technically, the contract will need to get above 11.10 cents/lb to attract more substantial buying, dealers said. Support in May was pegged at 10.68 cents/lb. Fresh physical offtake will be needed to jolt the market out of its present range.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>AUSTRALIA - Sugar exports in January 1997 amounted to 209,734 tonnes, raw value, down from the December tonnage of 269,798 tonnes but up on the January 1996 volume of 195,426 tonnes. This brought cumulative exports in the first eight months of 1996/97 (June/January) up to 3.584 mn tonnes, still slightly below last year's 3.645 mn tonnes.</p>
<p>Total exports in 1995/96 amounted to 4.177 mn tonnes compared to the record high of 4.479 mn tonnes attained in 1994/95. Major countries of destination in June/January 1996/97 were South Korea with 615,749 tonnes raws against 605,695 tonnes, Canada with 615,545 tonnes, up from 467,769 tonnes, Japan with 496,776 tonnes compared to 652,878 tonnes and Malaysia with 496,758 tonnes compared to 570,203 tonnes.</p>
<p>White sugar exports picked up again in January reaching an overall total of 29,442 tonnes compared to 17,530 tonnes in January 1996. This brought cumulative white sugar exports in June/January 1996/97 up to 154,534 tonnes, slightly up on last year's 153,124 tonnes.</p>
<p>Major countries of destination so far in 1996/97 were New Zealand with 41,862 tonnes, up from 12,000 tonnes, Indonesia with 39,586 tonnes against 19,734 tonnes and Sri Lanka with 19,500 tonnes compared to 5,489 tonnes.</p>
<p>MALAYSIA - Sugar imports in 1996 are likely to break last year's record of 1.033 mn tonnes. Total arrivals in November 1996 amounted to 99,975 tonnes, raw value, sharply up on last year's 62,605 tonnes. This brought cumulative imports in the first eleven months of 1996 (January/November) up to 1.004 mn tonnes compared to 940,650 tonnes in the like period the previous year. Total imports in 1995 reached 1.033 mn tonnes compared to 959,518 tonnes in 1994.</p>
<p>Major countries of origin in January/November 1996 were Australia with 543,337 tonnes raws against 550,245 tonnes, Thailand with 366,600 tonnes, up from 274,205 tonnes and South Africa with 47,274 tonnes against nil.</p>
<p>Tolling activity in Malaysia still seems to be subdued with total exports in November 1996 reaching no more than 6,554 tonnes, down from 12,743 tonnes in November 1995. This brought cumulative exports in January/November 1996 up to 98,526 tonnes against 110,838 tonnes in the like period the previous year. Total exports in 1995 amounted to 123,561 tonnes compared to 159,525 tonnes in 1994.</p>
<p>Major countries of destination in January/November 1996 were Singapore with 58,265 tonnes against 16,129 tonnes and Indonesia with 23,330 tonnes, up from 10,573 tonnes.</p>
<p>TENDERS</p>
<p>Syria's General Foreign Trade Organization for Chemicals and Foodstuffs (GEZA) has issued a tender to buy 13,000 tonnes of white sugar and 13,000 tonnes of raws, a company spokesman said. March 26 was set as the final date to receive price offers and the two amounts should be shipped between April 15 and May 15. Results of the tender would be announced on March 27, it was added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
