<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="461302" id="root" date="1997-03-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: European markets weather Greenspan fallout.</title>
<headline>European markets weather Greenspan fallout.</headline>
<byline>Malcolm Davidson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>European stock and bond markets regained some of their nerve on Friday as investors spotted buying opportunities following Thursday's turmoil, but interest rate worries looked set to dominate a volatile day.</p>
<p>The chairman of the U.S. Federal Reserve, Alan Greenspan, sparked Thursday's big selloff by hinting once more at an impending rise in U.S. interest rates.</p>
<p>But many European share and bond markets recouped some losses in early trading, although dealers warned they expected a volatile day with the expiry of index futures and options contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;We've held up fairly well so far, mainly thanks to the bond market,&quot; one London dealer said. &quot;But everybody remains nervous and I would be surprised if we saw a lot of volume.&quot;</p>
<p>Share markets were helped in part by the dollar, which was firm against the mark and yen following the support it got from Greenspan's remarks ahead of next Tuesday's meeting of the Fed's policy-setting open market committee.</p>
<p>A stronger dollar helps European exporters and was cited by Paris traders as one of the main factors behind a leap of more than 1.2 percent in France's blue chip CAC-40 index.</p>
<p>It was a similar story in Frankfurt, where the DAX 30 index was up 0.7 percent in early floor trade, and across many other bourses. Rises at Europe's smaller bourses ranged from 1.5 percent in Amsterdam by 5:15 a.m. EST to 0.6 percent in Stockholm and 0.3 percent in Milan.</p>
<p>The exception among major stock markets was London, where the FTSE 100 was down another 0.26 percent at 4,247 points after slumping 74 points Thursday.</p>
<p>BAT Industries Plc was the main focus among individual stocks after a U.S. legal deal by Liggett Group Inc sent U.S. tobacco shares sharply lower on Thursday. BAT shares were 12 pence lower at 477 but well off their lows early in the day.</p>
<p>Traders said a recovery in bond markets on both sides of the Atlantic was supporting equities.</p>
<p>British and German government bond markets both edged higher in early trade, tracking the overnight rebound in U.S. Treasuries, although the market remained nervous following Greenspan's comments.</p>
<p>&quot;We're seeing a bit of a squeeze after T-bonds did a bit better overnight and with (German) Bunds doing so well,&quot; one senior British bond salesman said. &quot;There is some money coming in to the market but I think most people really want to wait until next week,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tuesday's meeting of the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) dominated foreign exchange thinking in the absence of major economic data, with Greenspan's comments adding to expectations of a quarter point rate rise .</p>
<p>Greenspan, who has repeatedly spooked the markets in recent weeks, acnowledged the current benign inflation outlook in the U.S. but highlighted the potential of inflation and reiterated the Fed's pre-emptive stance on monetary policy.</p>
<p>&quot;The comments from Greenspan appear to greenlight a move higher on Tuesday,&quot; said Tim Fox, treausury economist at Standard Chartered Bank in London. &quot;Greenspan had a clear way to dampen rate hike speculation and he didn't.&quot;</p>
<p>By 5:15 a.m. EST the dollar was trading at 1.6908 marks and 123.36 yen compared with 1.6916 marks and 123.74 yen in late European trade on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar might not make much headway ahead of the FOMC but it's being buoyed by Greenspan's comments, which weren't as neutral as we expected,&quot; said Peter Wood, a currency trader at Bank of Boston in London.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
