<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="461473" id="root" date="1997-03-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-ITALY CALL UP UNCAPPED STRIKERS FOR WORLD CUP SQUAD.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ITALY CALL UP UNCAPPED STRIKERS FOR WORLD CUP SQUAD.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1997-03-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serie A leading goalscorer Filippo Inzaghi of Atalanta and Juventus reserve strikers Michele Padovano and Christian Vieri, all uncapped, were included on Saturday in the Italy squad for World Cup qualifiers against Moldova and Poland.</p>
<p>Following their 1-0 win against England at Wembley last month, Italy and England are level on nine points at the top of European Group 2, but the Italians have a game in hand.</p>
<p>For the matches against Moldova in Trieste on March 29  and against Poland in Chorzow on April 2 coach Cesare Maldini was obliged to make changes because of injuries to Lazio striker Pier Luigi Casiraghi and Juventus striker Alessandro Del Piero.</p>
<p>Maldini has given himself an extra option in attack by naming three replacements for the two injured players with Gianfranco Zola of Chelsea, Enrico Chiesa of Parma and Fabrizio Ravanelli of Middlesbrough also in the squad.</p>
<p>Maldini is likely to favour starting with the experienced attack of Zola and Ravanelli, with the others on standby.</p>
<p>Maldini is well familiar with both Vieri and Inzaghi, the revelation of the season as leading goalscorer on the 18 mark, since he picked Vieri 19 times and Inzaghi 14 times for Italy Under 21 sides in recent seasons.</p>
<p>By comparison with the squad named for the England qualifier, only Internazionale player Salvatore Fresi is missing.</p>
<p>Considered a defender by Maldini, Fresi has recently been selected as a midfielder by Inter coach Roy Hodgson and this may have influenced his omission.</p>
<p>With the exception of the attack, the sides to face Moldova and Poland seem sure to be very similar to that which beat England.</p>
<p>Dino Baggio, Demetrio Albertini, Angelo Di Livio and Roberto Di Matteo are the first choice candidates in midfield with Maldini's son Paolo likely to be partnered by Ciro Ferrara, Fabio Cannavaro and Alessandro Costacurta in defence with Angelo Peruzzi in goal.</p>
<p>The game against Moldova in Maldini's home town of Trieste will be his third in charge of Italy since replacing controversial coach Arrigo Sacchi in mid-December.</p>
<p>Squad:</p>
<p>Goalkeepers: Angelo Peruzzi (Juventus), Francesco Toldo (Fiorentina)</p>
<p>Defenders: Ciro Ferrara (Juventus), Alessandro Costacurta (AC Milan), Alessandro Nesta (Lazio), Fabio Cannavaro (Parma), Paolo Maldini (AC Milan), Antonio Benarrivo (Parma), Christian Panucci (Real Madrid)</p>
<p>Midfielders: Angelo Di Livio (Juventus), Roberto Di Matteo (Chelsea), Demetrio Albertini (AC Milan), Dino Baggio (Parma), Diego Fuser (Lazio), Amedeo Carboni (AS Roma), Stefano Eranio (AC Milan)</p>
<p>Strikers: Christian Vieri (Juventus), Filippo Inzaghi (Atalanta), Michele Padovano (Juventus), Fabrizio Ravanelli (Middlesbrough), Gianfranco Zola (Chelsea), Enrico Chiesa (Parma).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MOLDV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
