<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="461558" id="root" date="1997-03-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Bored Albanians scavenge ships, naval base.</title>
<headline>Bored Albanians scavenge ships, naval base.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>SARANDE, Albania 1997-03-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A young man inhales on a massive joint and pulls a gas mask down over his face to trap the smoke.</p>
<p>Bathed in sunlight pouring in through an open hatch, he sits on metal crates of anti-aircraft machine-gun bullets in the darkened hold of an Albanian frigate docked at Limion naval base in the southern port of Sarande.</p>
<p>Anti-aircraft rounds the size of a forearm roll back and forth on the deck as the ship pitches back and forth in the water. The man stands, lifts his mask and laughs manically as he urinates on the ammunition.</p>
<p>Limion and its ships have been abandoned to looters and children.</p>
<p>Two torpedo boats lie half-submerged at the dock. The remainder of the fleet -- two torpedo boats, two light frigates and two patrol boats -- have been scavenged and vandalised.</p>
<p>Stores of sea mines, torpedoes and depth charges lie in unlocked bunkers where youths play, mindless of the danger.</p>
<p>The children have lost their interest in guns and ammunition after several weeks of anarchy. They paw through the warehouses listlessly, like they've seen and done it all.</p>
<p>Signal flags, flares, personnel records, sea charts, machine-parts, vacuum tubes for ancient ship-to-shore radios and bits of naval uniform are strewn across the base.</p>
<p>Dairy cows roam the compound munching on grass, their bells jangling against the rhythmic lapping of water and an occasional scream of excitement from the young hooligans.</p>
<p>&quot;I have lived in Sarande for more than twenty years and I can't believe what I'm seeing with my own eyes at this base,&quot; exclaimed 53-year old Vangjel Xhani as he surveyed the scene from the dock.</p>
<p>&quot;These were old ships when they were given to Albania by China, but they were always spotless and perfectly maintained. Like any country we took pride in our Navy.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Now the ships are finished. This place is frightening. It is a naval base without sailors, without officers, without adults really. Think of the wealth that has been destroyed and abandoned here. It is like the world has ended.&quot;</p>
<p>Albanian society has frayed to such an extent in the south that children in coastal towns routinely fish with hand grenades and battle tanks are used to rip bank vaults from their foundations in daylight robberies.</p>
<p>The proximate cause of this latest outbreak of madness in the Balkans was the collapse of a number of pyramid schemes.</p>
<p>Many Albanian families were bankrupted and the populace, blaming President Sali Berisha for its troubles, took its anger out on the government.</p>
<p>Albanian army, navy and police units in the south dissolved overnight under the weight of public hostility.</p>
<p>A wave of looting and arson followed, directed especially at military facilities and public buildings. Violence between individuals has remained at a minimum, but most other markers of civil order have disappeared.</p>
<p>&quot;The only reason our people have not started killing one another is because they are very poor and more interested for the moment in trying to get rich,&quot; said Akil, an unemployed attorney in Sarande.</p>
<p>&quot;Once it becomes certain to them that we have wasted our chance for a better future for many years to come, they will want a new scapegoat. Berisha will be gone and the people will start blaming one another. That will be the dangerous time.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARANDE, Albania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
