<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="461520" id="root" date="1997-03-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CENTRAL AFRICAN REPUBLIC: Fresh Bangui clash, three killed.</title>
<headline>Fresh Bangui clash, three killed.</headline>
<dateline>BANGUI 1997-03-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>African peacekeepers in the Central African Republic opened fire on Saturday, killing three mutineers and wounding several others, a spokesman for the multinational force said.</p>
<p>The clash was the most serious since President Ange-Felix Patasse and his rivals agreed an African-mediated peace plan in January to end the country's third army mutiny in under a year.</p>
<p>The commander of the InterAfrican Surveillance Mission for the Bangui Accords MISAB, General Nkili Edjo, said in a statement that unit had acted in self-defence and stressed the neutrality of the force.</p>
<p>He warned all sides in the conflict against undermining the peace accords by force.</p>
<p>&quot;This warning is not in out direction only, it is addressed to all parties to the conflict,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nkili expressed regret at the incident and appealed to civilians not to rally to armed groups and allow themselves to be used as human shields against peacekeepers.</p>
<p>The spokesman told Reuters that the peacekeepers, who took over from French troops last month to act as a buffer between the rival forces, had opened fire after mutineers tried to loot petrol.</p>
<p>Nkili's statement referred to &quot;an armed and uncontrolled group&quot; and said that it had opened fire on peacekeepers protecting a petrol pumping operation.</p>
<p>Residents said the sound of gunshots, including heavy weapons fire, could be heard in the capital for much of the day. Calm returned later.</p>
<p>The first mutinies last April and May began over pay and conditions but turned into a campaign to oust Patasse, a northern civilian who won 1993 presidential elections.</p>
<p>The latest mutiny, which began on November 15, degenerated into ethnic bloodshed. French troops, in the country under a defence pact, restored order.</p>
<p>The conflict pitted the mutineers, mainly southerners from the minority Yakoma tribe of former military ruler Andre Kolingba, against Patasse's presidential guard.</p>
<p>All eight soldiers and 11 civilians still detained after the latest unrest were released on March 17 under an amnesty.</p>
<p>The amnesty, signed by Patasse, gave all mutineers until March 30 to hand over their weapons or fail to qualify.</p>
<p>Patasse formed a government of national unity under the peace deal but his supporters hold the main portfolios. Friction has continued between Patasse and the mutineers.</p>
<p>Witnesses had reported sporadic gunfire from rebel strongholds earlier this month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGUI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CENTRAL AFRICAN REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
