<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="461503" id="root" date="1997-03-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Lennon's son bids with the rest at Beatles sale.</title>
<headline>Lennon's son bids with the rest at Beatles sale.</headline>
<byline>Tara FitzGerald</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Julian Lennon, son of murdered Beatles star John Lennon, joined hundreds of fans around the globe on Saturday to bid at auction for some of his father's possessions.</p>
<p>Around 200 took part in the London end of an international Beatles memorabilia auction held in Tokyo and beamed around the world on television.</p>
<p>Julian Lennon, 33, bidding through his business manager in London, outbid Japanese businessmen and others to buy his father's black cape and an Afghan coat he wore on the cover of the &quot;Magical Mystery Tour&quot; album sleeve.</p>
<p>Business manager John Cousins said the items would go to a rock and roll museum in Ohio, in the United States. He narrowly missed obtaining Julian Lennon's third selected item -- one of the Beatles' early collarless stage suits.</p>
<p>Organised by Bonhams auction house in London, the event was the first to be entirely devoted to Beatles memorabilia and the first to be broadcast on television internationally.</p>
<p>&quot;Short of doing an auction in the South Pole you couldn't get much further apart than this. We have linked together two different continents and two different languages and their unifying feature was the love of a British pop group,&quot; said auctioneer Alexander Crum Ewing.</p>
<p>One man who had come to sell the Steinway piano on which Lennon composed the hit song &quot;Imagine&quot; failed to sell it but bought the run-down Liverpool house where Ringo Starr was born for $21,140.</p>
<p>Cliff Cooper, the owner of a chain of British record stores, said he snapped it up &quot;because it was cheap, basically&quot;, adding he intended to refurbish it and rent it out.</p>
<p>Cooper already owns a wooden coffer, a portable radio and an electric fire which belonged to John Lennon.</p>
<p>Bonhams said the sale was an &quot;astonishing success&quot; but some British buyers said they felt they had been treated as &quot;second class citizens&quot; during the bidding, as the time delay meant they were getting left behind bidders in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Crum Ewing said some hiccups were to be expected with a project on this scale.</p>
<p>Bidding in Japan had already been under way for several minutes before London buyers were aware it had started, and Crum Ewing was forced to ask the Japanese to restart bids for the first item, Sir Paul McCartney's birth certificate.</p>
<p>The auction, entitled &quot;Beatles for sale&quot;, put up over 300 lots, ranging from McCartney's school maths book to John Lennon's custom-made Mercedes Benz limousine. The total for all sales, including buyers' premiums, was around $1.33 million, after forecasts of around $1.6 million.</p>
<p>The satellite link betweeen London and Tokyo was cut off after only three hours while bidding continued for a further three hours via audio link. Auction organisers said they had not anticipated how long it would take.</p>
<p>The auction had been dogged by controversy from the start as McCartney obtained an injunction against Bonhams on Friday to halt the planned sale of his handwritten lyrics to hit song &quot;Penny Lane&quot; and doubts were cast over the authenticity of one of his guitars, which sold for $202,800.</p>
<p>Bonhams shrugged off charges of disappointment or lack of faith in their sale.</p>
<p>&quot;It is Paul McCartney's guitar.  We believe it is and we are glad to say our buyers believe it as well no matter what anyone else says,&quot; said Crum Ewing, naming it as the best sale of the day.</p>
<p>He estimated that around three-quarters of the buyers had come from the Japanese side.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
