<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="461724" id="root" date="1997-03-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Yeltsin adds EU to list of clubs he want to join.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin adds EU to list of clubs he want to join.</headline>
<byline>Philippa Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1997-03-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian President Boris Yeltsin said on Saturday Moscow wanted to join the European Union as part of its attempt to come in from the cold of post communist Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;(Russia) is also aiming to be recognised finally as a full European state and we are also prepared to join the European Union,&quot; he told reporters after a meeting in Helsinki with Finnish President Martti Ahtisaari.</p>
<p>Central and eastern european states, struggling to revive economies hit by the collapse of central planning, have been clamouring to join the queue at the doors of the EU.</p>
<p>But Moscow has not formally applied for membership and several European officials have expressed doubts that Russia -- the world's largest country -- would ever be able to join.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the European Commission, the EU's executive body, said on Saturday the organisation had taken note of Yeltsin's unexpected declaration and that it might be discussed at the Council of EU foreign ministers on Monday.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's call came amid a strong diplomatic push by Moscow for greater integration in the international economic community.</p>
<p>On Friday, President Bill Clinton agreed at a summit in the Finnish capital to help Yeltsin push for Russian membership of world economic bodies like the Paris Club of government creditors and the World Trade Organisation (WTO).</p>
<p>Russia is some way from meeting the conditions for membership of both those bodies but is making the most of the West's desire not to leave Moscow feeling left out as NATO prepares to bring in some former East Bloc states.</p>
<p>Washington's pledge to help Russia gain entry to the WTO and Paris Club and to have a fuller role at meetings of the Group of Seven industrial nations was implicitly aimed at soothing Moscow's concerns over NATO expansion plans.</p>
<p>Clinton said the summit had not changed NATO's plans, which are expected to involve issuing invitations to Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic at its July summit in Madrid.</p>
<p>Yeltsin continues to say he is against NATO expansion, but agreed with Clinton to seek a separate Russian deal with the alliance -- implicitly accepting that expansion will go ahead.</p>
<p>But Russia remains implacably opposed to NATO membership by former Soviet republics, although Yeltsin failed to persuade Clinton to back his bid for NATO to commit itself on this.</p>
<p>Ahtisaari, whose country joined the EU in 1995, said he saw the remark in the context of heightened tensions between Russia and the former Soviet Baltic states over Moscow's insistence that the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation leaves them out.</p>
<p>&quot;I was not surprised because he mentioned the same thing to me in our private meeting,&quot; he said. &quot;I think it reflected the point he wanted to make that he...saw it as normal that the Baltic states were also looking for membership in the European Union.&quot;</p>
<p>Moscow has always been far more accepting of other state's efforts to join the EU than the military alliance. Earlier this month, the Kremlin described Russian-EU relations as &quot;key to strengthening security and stability on the continent&quot;.</p>
<p>The EU has signed deals with former eastern bloc countries, who are desperate for the trading benefits which go with greater integration, and held out the prospect of eventual membership to 10 of them.</p>
<p>Moscow has also signed a partnership and cooperation agreement with the EU designed to forge commercial and other links and to liberalise trade but the EU but does not see it as leading towards Russia joining the 15-nation body.</p>
<p>&quot;We take note of Russian President Yeltsin's declaration. One should be reminded that we do have a partnership and cooperation agreement which was signed in Corfu the 24th of June 1994. It has not been ratified yet, but our relations are based on that,&quot; a Commission spokesman told Reuters in Brussels.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
