<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="461864" id="root" date="1997-03-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BOXING-HERNANDEZ TAKES TITLE FROM AZUMAH NELSON.</title>
<headline>BOXING-HERNANDEZ TAKES TITLE FROM AZUMAH NELSON.</headline>
<dateline>CORPUS CHRISTI, Texas 1997-03-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Genaro Hernandez refused an opportunity to win a world title by disqualification then scored a split decision victory over longtime champion Azumah Nelson to claim the World Boxing Council super featherweight crown.</p>
<p>Hernandez used superior speed to dominate the 38-year-old three-time world champion from the outset and appeared in control until the fight took a strange turn at the end of the seventh round.</p>
<p>As the bell sounded to end the seventh Nelson was moving in for a punch and the veteran fighter delivered the blow seconds after the bell.</p>
<p>The late punch caught Hernandez in the throat, decking the 30-year-old challenger.</p>
<p>A point was deducted from Nelson, but WBC president Jose Sulaiman ruled that if Hernandez was unable to continue he would be awarded the title by disqualification of the champion from Ghana.</p>
<p>After a break of some five minutes so the American challenger could recover, Hernandez decided to fight on rather than take the title the easy way.</p>
<p>&quot;They told me I could have won,&quot; Hernandez said. &quot;But I wanted to finish. He is a great champion and I have too much respect for the sport.&quot;</p>
<p>Hernandez finished the bout, winning it 118-110 and 116-114 on two of the three judges' cards. The third judge gave the fight to Nelson 115-114.</p>
<p>The scores by two of the judges were much closer than the fight appeared as Hernandez beat a slower Nelson to the punch with consistancy throughout the bout.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a very satisfying win,&quot; said Hernandez, who improved to 35-1-1. &quot;I respected him but had to go after him.&quot;</p>
<p>Nelson, who fell to 39-4-2, said he was not sure if this was his last fight.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know,&quot; he said when asked if he was ready to retire. &quot;Let me go home and think about it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GHANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CORPUS CHRISTI, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
