<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="461838" id="root" date="1997-03-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>COSTA RICA: SOCCER-COSTA RICA HAND THE U.S. ANOTHER DEFEAT.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-COSTA RICA HAND THE U.S. ANOTHER DEFEAT.</headline>
<dateline>SAN JOSE 1997-03-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States' hopes of reaching the 1998 World Cup finals suffered a setback on Sunday when they lost 3-2 to Costa Rica, the second time they have been beaten by the Central Americans in the qualifiers.</p>
<p>The U.S. twice came from behind before being sunk by a Ronald Gomez goal 15 minutes from the end in the six-team final stage of the CONCACAF qualifying tournament.</p>
<p>Mexico, the United States and Costa Rica all have four points, the U.S. having played a game more, and Jamaica one point. Canada have lost their first two games and El Salvador have yet to play. Three teams qualify for France.</p>
<p>Costa Rica also beat the U.S. 2-1 in a tumultuous match in the semifinal stage of the competition in November when the North Americans complained they were harassed and badly treated.</p>
<p>The Costa Rican federation was later fined $7,000 by FIFA but on Sunday, with security reinforced, U.S. coach Steve Sampson congratulated the local fans in the 23,000 crowd on their behaviour.</p>
<p>And Sampson gave full credit to his opponents. &quot;The speed and the commitment of the Costa Rican players were first class,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Costa Rica dominated most of the match, their skilful forwards causing constant misery for the U.S. defenders. Despite this, the home team's leaky defence nearly allowed their opponents to escape with a point.</p>
<p>Hernan Medford, who played for Costa Rica in their only appearance at the World Cup finals in 1990, put the home side ahead in the tenth minute but Eric Wynalda equalised 12 minutes later.</p>
<p>In the 32nd minute, Mauricio Solis put the home side back ahead with a powerful shot.</p>
<p>But Solis turned villain in the second half when his pass was intercepted by substitute Roy Lassiter, who ran onto to equalise in the 68th minute.</p>
<p>Gomez's 76th minute match winner was a simple tap-in after defender Harold Wallace dribbled through a flat-footed U.S defence.</p>
<p>Costa Rica: 1-Hermidio Barrantes, 2-Harold Wallace, 4- Ronald Gonzalez, 16-Austin Berry, 3-Luis Antonio Marin, 14-Benjamin Mayorga, 8-Mauricio Solis, 6-Wilmer Lopez, 7-Ronald Gomez, 9-Paulo Cesar Wanchope (5-Ronald Chaves, 75), 17-Hernan Medford (10-Jafet Soto, 63).</p>
<p>United States: 18-Kasey Keller, 3-Eddie Pope (4-Mike Burns, 65), 22-Alexi Lalas, 2-Anthony Sanneh, 12-Jeff Agoos, 6-John Harkes, 5-Thomas Dooley, 13-Cobi Jones, 21-Claudio Reyna (19-Peter Vernes, 75), 9-David Wagner (15-Roy Lassiter, 46), 11-Erick Wynalda.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN JOSE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COSTA RICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
