<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="462046" id="root" date="1997-03-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Palm Sunday brings renewed hope of hostage talks.</title>
<headline>Palm Sunday brings renewed hope of hostage talks.</headline>
<byline>James Craig</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1997-03-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Roman Catholic faithful on Palm Sunday tried to rally the spirits of 72 hostages held by Peruvian rebels amid hope that talks to end the 96-day crisis at the Japanese ambassador's home may soon resume.</p>
<p>Parishioners from a working-class Lima district wore Biblical costumes and held a procession, complete with palm fronds and a man dressed as Jesus riding a donkey around the mansion in a show of support for the captives.</p>
<p>&quot;We ask for forgiveness for the captors and freedom for the hostages,&quot; said Mario Valencia, 36, who played Jesus.</p>
<p>He led about 60 people playing the roles of shepherds, the Three Kings, Mary, Joseph and other religious figures, down streets surrounding the diplomatic compound reciting passages from the New Testament.</p>
<p>Hostages have spent Christmas and New Year's as captives of about 20 Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) rebels and appear likely to spend Easter, next Sunday, that way too.</p>
<p>Archbishop Juan Luis Cipriani, a mediator in the tense standoff between security forces and the MRTA, entered the home, towing a suitcase behind him, and spent two hours inside apparently delivering mass.</p>
<p>A local human rights umbrella group said the mass hostage- taking marred Peru's human rights in 1996 despite a decline in the number of people killed in political violence last year.</p>
<p>The National Human Rights Coordinator, in its annual report obtained by Reuters on Sunday, condemned the takeover as &quot;reprehensible&quot; and in violation of &quot;principles established under international humanitarian law.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This reprehensible act, although isolated, reminds us that even though they are weak and without public support, subversive groups continue to operate in different parts of the country,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>President Alberto Fujimori spent Sunday in the Amazon lowland town of Pucallpa a day after the government announced it was ready to renew talks with hostage-takers.</p>
<p>&quot;We are ready and hoping that at any moment the talks can resume,&quot; said government negotiator Domingo Palermo, who was accompanying Fujimori on Saturday on a visit to Lima's shanty- towns.</p>
<p>Other signs emerged on Saturday of progress in efforts to resolve the siege peacefully as the three-man mediation panel met for two hours with the rebels.</p>
<p>Cipriani told reporters afterward the rebels gave renewed assurances they would not hurt their captives -- a VIP list of cabinet ministers, ambassadors and businessman.</p>
<p>&quot;We have received again from the MRTA a commitment to care for and treat respectfully all the hostages,&quot; Cipriani told reporters late on Saturday, but added: &quot;We want to see them free. We don't want just more conversations.&quot;</p>
<p>Local newspapers reported on Sunday that Cipriani also called on the world community to offer suggetions for ending the crisis, and one observer painted a gloomy picture.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is one of total apathy,&quot; political analyst Raul Gonzales said.</p>
<p>Still, there were signs mediators were steering talks away from the rebels' main demand of freedom for 450 jailed comrades -- a demand flatly rejected by Fujimori.</p>
<p>First, Cipriani met for more than two hours with Cuban Ambassador Pedro Diaz, whose country along with the Dominican Republic has offered asylum to the hostage-takers.</p>
<p>Cipriani said he was only bidding goodbye to the ambassador before he returned to Havana, but the meeting prompted speculation they were working out asylum details.</p>
<p>The rebels blasted into a gala reception at the house on Dec. 17, and took hundreds of guests hostage, then released most in the days following the takeover.</p>
<p>Fujimori flew on Saturday with the Japanese envoy's wife to Pucallpa to distribute Japanese-donated blankets and clothes to flood victims, her first public activity since being released.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
