<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="462145" id="root" date="1997-03-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURMA: Security tight in Rangoon after mosque vandalised.</title>
<headline>Security tight in Rangoon after mosque vandalised.</headline>
<dateline>RANGOON 1997-03-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burma's military government said on Sunday it had tightened security at mosques around Rangoon as religious unrest spread to the capital for the first time since similar trouble broke out last weekend in Mandalay.</p>
<p>More armed troops and police were posted around the city after a group of about 50 Buddhist monks vandalised a mosque at Kanbe in the northeastern quarter of Rangoon on Saturday.</p>
<p>The monks attacked the mosque, which was under renovation, with sticks and stones, then fled before police arrived.</p>
<p>Mandalay is still under an 8 p.m. to 4 a.m. curfew imposed last weekend when monks went on a rampage in the city, attacking several mosques and launching street protests after reports that a Buddhist girl had been raped by a Moslem man.</p>
<p>Analysts said they were concerned at the spread of the violence to Rangoon and noted that it was sparked to some extent by the growing number of mosques in the capital.</p>
<p>If attacks on Moslem places of worship were not controlled quickly they could start major religious strife, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;We understand very well what is happening at the moment and this is not a proper way of solving any problem,&quot; said a retired Buddhist officer.</p>
<p>&quot;We are all desirous of peace regardless of our religions. Without peace we are all in for trouble,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>A leader of the Burmese Moslem community told Reuters that urgent consultations were being held with the minister for religious affairs, Lieutenant Myo Nyunt, and with comunity leaders to restore calm after the mosque attack.</p>
<p>&quot;We have met with the minister for religious affairs and we are holdings meetings to discuss the situation,&quot; said Hadji U Thein, chairman of the Islamic Religious Affairs Council, the most influential Moslem organisation in the country.</p>
<p>He declined to comment further and there was no statement on the latest incident from Buddhist religious authorities.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the ruling State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC) said: &quot;Appropriate security measures to prevent similar incidents from taking place have been taken around mosques in townships. The situation in Rangoon is calm and we will protect the Moslem community.&quot;</p>
<p>He blamed elements out to disrupt Burma's pending entry into the seven-member Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) later this year and those seeking to destabilise Burma.</p>
<p>&quot;We suspect they will now try to cause trouble between the Buddhists and Hindus next. We have contacts with ASEAN and other Moslem countries, and they have been told of the situation here,&quot; the spokesman added.</p>
<p>Burma is about 90 percent Buddhist and about four percent of the population is Moslem. Monks play a key role in this deeply Buddhist country and have in the past lent their support to political and social causes.</p>
<p>The All-Burma Moslem Union, a group associated with Burmese exile groups based at the Burma-Thai border, accused the SLORC of being behind the latest Buddhist-Moslem strife and said it had systematically caused trouble for the Moslem community.</p>
<p>&quot;The SLORC has always discriminated against the Moslems. They call them 'Kala', or aliens with no nationality,&quot; ABMU president Ra Sak said by telephone.</p>
<p>Last December, SLORC troops tore down a mosque in Nabu village in southwest Burma, and in January, a mosque in western Jaidong town was blown up, he said.</p>
<p>He noted that police arrived only after the Kanbe mosque had been vandalised by the monks on Saturday. &quot;If the SLORC continues to use Buddhist monks as their proxy to oppress Moslems, an all-out religious war could break out,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RANGOON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
