<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="462199" id="root" date="1997-03-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Sudan opposition dismisses Bashir's mediation talk.</title>
<headline>Sudan opposition dismisses Bashir's mediation talk.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1997-03-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Sudanese opposition group on Sunday dismissed Khartoum's support for foreign mediation to end the government's war with rebels, saying it must first recognise the conflict as an internal problem.</p>
<p>National Democratic Alliance (NDA) spokesman Farouq Abu Eissa responded at a news conference to President Omar Hassan al-Bashir's remarks on Saturday that he welcomed a mediation offer by the United Arab Emirates.</p>
<p>&quot;It was an intangible statement, because he is still talking about insubstantial things,&quot; he said. &quot;He should start with realising the root of the problem is between...the NDA and the Sudan government on the issue of democracy and peace.</p>
<p>&quot;If he doesn't talk about it and continues to talk about the invasion of foreign forces, that is nonsense.&quot;</p>
<p>Bashir seized power in a coup in 1989. The Sudan People's Liberation Army (SPLA) has been fighting since 1983 for greater autonomy for the Christian and animist south from the Moslem Arabised north.</p>
<p>Bashir told a news conference before leaving Abu Dhabi on Saturday that he discussed the mediation initiative with UAE President Sheikh Zaid bin Sultan al-Nahayan and &quot;reiterated to his highness that Sudan welcomed his offer&quot;.</p>
<p>Bashir said the conflict in Sudan had &quot;three dimensions -- the dispute with the northern opposition, the insurgency issue in the south and outside aggression from Ethiopia and Uganda&quot;.</p>
<p>Sudan has accused Eritrea, Ethiopia and Uganda of direct military involvement in the rebel offensive launched in early January by the SPLA and allied opposition forces. The three states deny any involvement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
