<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="462289" id="root" date="1997-03-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Megret denies saying immigrants pollute France.</title>
<headline>Megret denies saying immigrants pollute France.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1997-03-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leader of the extreme-right National Front party on Sunday denied telling a U.S. newspaper that immigrants &quot;pollute&quot; French identity -- a remark that outraged anti-racism groups.</p>
<p>Bruno Megret, deputy to Front leader Jean-Marie Le Pen, said his remarks had been mistranslated.</p>
<p>The New York Times quoted him on February 12 as saying the party wanted to send Arabs, Africans and Asians home &quot;because they pollute our national identity and take our jobs&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I said that immigration calls our national identity into question,&quot; Megret said. &quot;It came back to France as 'polluting' our national identity.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I wonder why French journalists have to go to articles that appeared abroad to inform the French people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Megret's wife Catherine became the fourth National Front mayor last month by winning municipal elections in the southern town of Vitrolles.</p>
<p>Last week, the French League against Racism and Anti-Semitism (LICRA) said it was taking legal action against Megret for racial defamation over his comments in the New York Times, also printed in the International Herald Tribune.</p>
<p>Megret, calling the Front the &quot;great alternative&quot; to mainstream parties, said the party wanted to enter the National Assembly &quot;massively&quot; in elections in a year's time.</p>
<p>Le Pen won 15 percent of the vote in 1995 presidential elections but the party has no seats in parliament.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
