<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46225" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Sept 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Sept 12.</headline>
<text>
<p>NIHON KEIZAI SHIMBUN</p>
<p>A Nihon Keizai Shimbun survey of 2,285 companies shows the companies have increased their total capital investment for the business year ending March 1997 by seven percent from a year earlier, helped by an increase in investments made by the car and food industries as well as telecommunications companies.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Nippon Telegraph and Telephone Corp (NTT) plans to cut its workforce by 35,000, including 25,000 employees who will be reassigned to NTT's affiliated companies.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Export-Import Bank of Japan is to sign a $403 million loan contract on Thursday to fund part of a $1.2 billion power plant project in China. This would make it the first time for the bank to extend a loan without Chinese government guarantees. Mitsubishi Corp and Mitsubishi Heavy Industries Ltd have jointly won the order.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Toshiba Corp has developed a blue-purple semiconductor laser designed for next-generation digital video disc (DVD) systems. Toshiba plans to commercialise the product in two years.  </p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Furukawa Electric Co Ltd and Nichimen Corp have agreed to start a copper foil business in Taiwan as early as this month in cooperation with a Taiwanese company. The venture plans to invest about 7.5 billion yen to build a plant in Taiwan.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Toyota Motor Corp is targeting annual domestic sales of 2.5 million vehicles, or about 45 percent of total domestic demand, in the year 2000.  </p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Kyocera Corp plans to sell a new personal digital assistant (PDA) that can be accessed through a local area network (LAN), by the end of March 31, 1997.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Kawasaki Steel Corp and Mitsui &amp; Co Ltd are to begin steel bar production with two companies in the Philippines. The venture will be capitalised at about 16 billion yen and aims to start production from January 1999.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
