<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="46226" id="root" date="1996-09-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks close firm after recent big losses.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks close firm after recent big losses.</headline>
<byline>Rajan Moses</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's depressed stock market partially recouped nine consecutive days of losses to finish higher on Wednesday, helped by heavy buying from a private sector rescue fund, brokers said.</p>
<p>The stock index, which hit a three-year-low on Tuesday, ended up 14.13 points, or 1.44 percent, at 996.16 after a brief flirt above the psychological 1,000-point level.</p>
<p>The market's rise, viewed by some analysts as a technical rebound from recent losses, was assisted by funds from a 15.7 billion baht (US$628 million) private sector rescue fund, which entered the market to help shore up prices, brokers said.</p>
<p>Some market analysts and brokers cautiously predicted a further small advance on Thursday if buying continued from the fund, which was set up in August by the Thai Bankers Association and brokers to help revive the market.</p>
<p>&quot;The index is expected to rise, but only slightly on Thursday due to continued buying by the private sector rescue fund,&quot; said Thaneit Khantigaroon of Ekachart Finance and Securities.</p>
<p>The fund, managed by several private fund managers, surprised local participants on Friday in its first major attempt to bolster prices. When announced in August it was originally 21 billion baht but has since been whittled down.</p>
<p>The rescue fund began operating after heightened speculation that some finance and securities firms, especially smaller ones, may have been hit by defaults by smaller investors unable to top up their stock margin loans, the brokers said.</p>
<p>The rumours, which hit the market on Friday, have forced the exchange, several finance firms and the central bank to declare them unfounded.</p>
<p>But despite their denials, speculation persisted and has driven down share prices of local finance firms, traders said.</p>
<p>Signs of weakness in the Thai economy and a no-confidence debate against Thai prime minister Banharn Silpa-archa set for September 18 have also weighed on the market and caused some anxiety for investors, analysts said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the central bank moved again to dispell fears about the health of smaller finance firms.</p>
<p>Bank of Thailand (BOT) spokeswoman Kleo-thong Hetrakul told Reuters that it had asked commercial banks to relieve pressure on smaller finance firms by not recalling loans granted to them earlier.</p>
<p>But the baht, which was a victim of devaluation rumours in the past week, fell sharply late in the day as the U.S. dollar surged abroad. It fell to 25.388/25.393 to the dollar at 1023 GMT on Wednesday against 25.354/25.359 late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The midrate at which the baht was fixed by BOT on Wednesday was at an eight-week low of 25.37 to the dollar.</p>
<p>The central bank also said it had injected 10 billion baht into the money market to ease liquidity. The overnight interbank rate fell in response to the injection, sliding to 11.50-12.00 percent late from 12.00 percent earlier.</p>
<p>($1 = 25 baht)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
