<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="462322" id="root" date="1997-03-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Ex-minister hurt in Bangladesh strike.</title>
<headline>Ex-minister hurt in Bangladesh strike.</headline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1997-03-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Riot police and para-military forces on Sunday patrolled streets and guarded key installations as an opposition-led strike virtually halted life across Bangladesh, witnesses said.</p>
<p>The strike, called by the main opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) of former prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia, shut businesses and kept transport off the roads.</p>
<p>Strike enforcers, many carrying sticks and wearing headbands, marched on the streets of Dhaka, and set off dozens of home-made bombs and firecrackers, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Former home (interior) minister Abdul Matin Chowdhury, leading a group of pickets, was hit by a stone while passing by offices of the ruling Awami League and was taken to hospital bleeding from the head, witnesses said.</p>
<p>BNP sources said Chowdhury was beaten by police.</p>
<p>Officials in Chittagong reported sporadic bomb blasts and noisy demonstrations during what they called a crippling strike in the port city.</p>
<p>Other main cities including Khulna and Rajshahi were also in the grip of the strike, local reporters said.</p>
<p>Rail and air traffic operated but with fewer passengers, transport officials said.</p>
<p>In Dhaka, hundred of government employees either walked to their offices or took pedal rickshaws, which operated in defiance of the strike. Many senior officials stayed in their offices overnight.</p>
<p>The BNP called the eight-hour strike for Sunday, a working day in mainly Moslem Bangladesh, in its first major attempt to destabilise the eight-month-old government of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina.</p>
<p>Hasina took office last June after defeating the BNP in a general election in which both the BNP and Hasina's Awami League accused each other of vote-rigging, but which was billed as free and fair by local and international monitors.</p>
<p>The BNP says the strike is intended as a protest against what it views as the government's failure to provide for the basic needs of citizens in this poor nation and against Hasina's warmer ties with rival India, which the BNP sees as a plot to surrender Bangladeshi sovereignty.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
