<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="462538" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: HUNGARY FX DEALERS DETECT NO EFFECT FROM RATE RISE.</title>
<headline>HUNGARY FX DEALERS DETECT NO EFFECT FROM RATE RISE.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's forint ended Monday morning little changed against the dollar in quiet trade apparently unaffected by the central bank's surprise decision to raise six-month commercial bank deposit rates.</p>
<p>At midday, the forint stood at 176.90/95 against the U.S. unit, compared to an opening level of 176.86/91 and weakened slightly against the currency basket to 15 fillers from the central bank's (NBH) resistance level.</p>
<p>The NBH on Monday raised the rate at which it accepts deposits from the commercial banks for six months to 21.00 percent from 20.75, breaking the trend of the central bank's almost regular monthly rate cuts in the past few months.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't notice any effect from the central bank decision,&quot; said Istvan Gere of ING Bank. &quot;Trade was very quiet, but the forint did weaken a little against the currency basket, probably due to a one-off customer order.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said they expect little change in the afternoon.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to remain quiet, with the dollar/mark the main factor,&quot; said Noemi Koppendorfer of Magyar Hitel Bank.</p>
<p>The NBH fixed the dollar at 176.95 at midday.</p>
<p>The forint floats within the NBH's 4.5 percent intervention band against a currency basket made up 30 percent of the dollar and 70 percent of the mark.</p>
<p>-- Duncan Shiels, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
