<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="462576" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: ICI shares hit two-year lows on downgrades.</title>
<headline>ICI shares hit two-year lows on downgrades.</headline>
<byline>David Holmes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in British chemical giant Imperial Chemical Industries Plc touched a two-year low on Monday as analysts dropped earnings estimates amid talk of continuing pricing pressures on the group.</p>
<p>ICI shares ended the day were down 14 pence at 688-1/2 in volume of 4.4 million shares, after earlier touching a low of 680p -- the lowest since March 1995.</p>
<p>Dealers said the latest round of downgrades followed briefings with the company on trading in the first quarter.</p>
<p>HSBC James Capel analyst David Ingles said a hoped-for improvement in trading conditions during the first quarter of the year had not materialised.</p>
<p>Instead, pricing pressures continued in a range of basic materials such as PTA and PET -- used in making plastics -- and titanium dioxide, used to give whiteness to paint and paper products.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone knows they had a pretty awful start to the year and it's not going to get better overnight,&quot; said Ingles. &quot;I do think prices are beginning to make progress but it's just not being shown yet in ICI's results.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman for ICI declined comment on the latest downgrades.</p>
<p>He said any briefings for analysts would have been part of normal contacts with the company before the start of its &quot;closed&quot; season, when official comment is effectively barred in the run-up to results. ICI reports first quarter results on April 24.</p>
<p>Capel's Ingles lowered his 1997 pre-tax, pre-exceptional profit estimate to 600 million pounds from 750 million and cut his 1998 forecast to 800 million pounds from 900 million.</p>
<p>Ingles, who repeated a &quot;sell&quot; rating on ICI shares, also expects ICI to take a 100 million restructuring charge in both years.</p>
<p>At SBC Warburg analysts cut their current-year estimate to 565 million pounds from 635 million while rating the stock a &quot;buy,&quot; and at NatWest analysts said their forecasts &quot;look vulnerable&quot; and repeated a &quot;hold&quot; rating.</p>
<p>ICI shares have underperformed the All-Share index by 22 percent in the last six months and 34 percent over the past 12 month period.</p>
<p>However, Ingles said the disappointing performance by ICI should not necessarily reflect on the rest of the chemical sector. &quot;A lot of the second line chemical shares are looking very good value,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>ICI continues to be hit by its exposure to a weak plastics market, where profits and sales last year were affected by a combination of weak demand and overcapacity.</p>
<p>In PET, where prices fell around 30 percent in 1996, overcapacity is expected to continue to keep prices weak this year. ICI has a share of around eight percent of the world PET market.</p>
<p>Earnings last year were also hit by sudden downturns in prices of titanium dioxide and intermediate chemicals.</p>
<p>Analysts said sterling's strength is also weighing on the company, both in translational terms and in terms of the group's competitive position.</p>
<p>Although most of the UK chemicals industry is expected to benefit from a more benign outlook on feedstock prices this year, ICI is a feedstock manufacturer as well as end user.</p>
<p>The group has a declared aim of revamping its portfolio to move into higher margin, less cyclical businesses, building up its position in areas like polyurethanes, acrylics, performance chemicals and paints.</p>
<p>However, analysts said such businesses are in demand and come with a high price tag.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
