<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="462667" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Shell hit by trouble in Nigeria in local feud.</title>
<headline>Shell hit by trouble in Nigeria in local feud.</headline>
<byline>Eniwoke Ibagere</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil giant Shell said on Monday 126 staff and contractors, all Nigerians, were being held at oil intallations overrun at the weekend by villagers involved in a dispute with a Niger delta local government.</p>
<p>Shell, often the target of environmental protests in Nigeria, said it had passed on a list of demands to the Delta State government but had not been asked to mediate and had not requested government help to remove the protestors.</p>
<p>Villagers on Monday agreed to release six of the detained staff who were injured in the attack and they were due to be removed to a nearby town early on Tuesday, Shell said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've had useful dialogue with the communities and they've agreed to release those injured,&quot; a company spokesman told Reuters in Lagos.</p>
<p>&quot;We have sent boats with food and other supplies to them and the injured will arrive our offices in Warri on Tuesday morning. Others will remain there until we end negotiations as peacefully as possible,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Nigerian unit of Royal Dutch group's Shell said it planned a peaceful resolution to the feud between two villages in the oil-rich Niger Delta which led to its shutting operations there.</p>
<p>The company said the occupation forced Shell to reduce crude oil production by about 100,000 barrels per day (bpd), or five percent of total Nigerian production, but exports were not affected.</p>
<p>With output of 2.15 million bpd, Nigeria is the fifth largest producer in the Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC).</p>
<p>The Anglo-Dutch oil giant, which produces about half the country's total, has suffered regular disruption to its Nigerian operations in the past from community disturbances and sabotage but increased local investment had cut losses in recent years.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a short-term and isolated problem but all the same we aim for a peaceful solution so that we resume operations,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Acts of sabotage in protest at the company's environmental record led Shell to withdraw from the Niger delta's Ogoniland in 1993 and has still to return.</p>
<p>In 1994, Shell Western Division headquarters in Warri was surrounded by local protestors seeking greater benefits from oil output in their region.</p>
<p>The company's operations in Nigeria came under the limelight after the exceution by the Nigerian authorities in 1995 of Ogoni opposition leader Ken Saro-Wiwa, who had led a campaign against the company's environmental policies.</p>
<p>The latest trouble began at the weekend when villagers from the rival Ogidigben and Ogbe-Ijoh communities stormed Shell's flowstations in the area, protesting the military government's relocation of the municipal council headquarters.</p>
<p>There has been no comment from government on the issue.</p>
<p>World oil prices on Monday were unmoved by the news of reduced Nigerian production, benchmark Brent Blend crude oil trading down 24 cents at $19.75 a barrel.</p>
<p>Feuds are common among villages in Nigeria, Africa's largest producer of oil.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
