<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="462663" id="root" date="1997-03-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Avenor shares rise on takeover speculation.</title>
<headline>Avenor shares rise on takeover speculation.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1997-03-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Avenor Inc rose in brisk trade on Monday after the forestry company confirmed it was approached by Domtar Inc about a possible merger last week.</p>
<p>Avenor rose to 24 in early dealings before pulling back to trade 1.35 higher at 23.90 on 399,703 shares. Domtar shares gained 0.10 to 11.70 in light volume.</p>
<p>&quot;I guess it's because Domtar was written up in the Wall Street Journal saying it could take a piece of Avenor or Repap,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm hearing bits and pieces. I think there's an (analysts') meeting on Wednesday, which could sort of clarify what's going on,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Avenor said in a statement today that a senior executive of Domtar approached Avenor, indicating that Domtar wanted to pursue negotiations with Avenor &quot;with a view to enter into a pre-merger agreement within 72 hours.&quot;</p>
<p>The newspaper report on Monday cited speculation that Domtar could be looking at acquiring all or part of Avenor and Repap amid doubts that the Avenor-Repap deal would close on schedule on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Avenor confirmed that Domtar made an overture, but said it turned away the suitor so it could focus on its soon to close acquisition of Repap Enterprises Inc.</p>
<p>Avenor said the Domtar offer was to be based on a market to market exchange ratio, and conditional on the merger with Repap being approved by Avenor and Repap shareholders.</p>
<p>Denis Aubin, Avenor chief financial officer, told Reuters in a telephone interview he did not feel Domtar was likely to make a hostile bid.</p>
<p>He said that considering a proposal from Domtar would be a distraction from the Repap deal. But he did not rule out looking at discussions with Domtar once the Repap deal closed.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly we would have to see what are the merits of an association with Domtar after the Repap transaction as to whether or not it fits our strategic direction and whether or not it creates shareholder value,&quot; Aubin said.</p>
<p>Repap shares were up 0.16 at 2.58 in trade of 134,600 shares early in the session.</p>
<p>If the merger with Repap closed as scheduled, Avenor said it could mull significant strategic deals in its two primary businesses -- newsprint and coated white papers.</p>
<p>&quot;It is Avenor's intention to examine such alternatives as soon as possible following completion of the merger with Repap with a view to enhancing shareholder value,&quot; Avenor said.</p>
<p>((Sarah Edmonds, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100, E-mail sarah.edmonds@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1997</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1997-03-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1997-03-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
